{
  "newspaper_id": "lankadeepa-lk",
  "url": "https://www.lankadeepa.lk/latest_news/රට-පනින්න-හැදූ-10-ක්-තලෙමන්නාරමේදී-අල්ලයි/1-618271",
  "time_ut": 1660723551,
  "original_lang": "si",
  "original_title": "රට පනින්න හැදූ 10 ක් තලෙමන්නාරමේදී අල්ලයි",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "10 people who tried to jump the country are caught in Talemannar",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "The Navy said that 10 people suspected of trying to illegally migrate from Sri Lanka to a foreign country by sea were arrested in the sea area off the Kurusapadu area of ​​Talemannar.",
        "During a special search operation last night (16), the P175 Coastal Patrol Vessel belonging to the Sri Lanka Naval Ship Buwaneka of the North Central Naval Command observed and inspected this suspicious dinghy and there it was said that the dinghy was trying to migrate illegally from Sri Lanka to a foreign country by sea. The Navy said the dinghy was taken into custody by the Navy along with the two operators, four males above the age of 18, two females and four below the age of 18.",
        "The Navy stated that the persons taken into the custody of the Navy were identified as residents of Pesale, Urumale, Kilinochchi and Kantale and the persons were handed over to the Thalemannar Police for further legal proceedings."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "10",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "Talemannar",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Navy",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "10",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kurusapadu",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "last night",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "16",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "P175 Coastal Patrol",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the North Central Naval Command",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Navy",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Navy",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "two",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "four",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "the age of 18",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "two",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "four",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Navy",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Navy",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Pesale",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Urumale",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kilinochchi",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kantale",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Thalemannar Police",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "රට පනින්න හැදූ 10 ක් තලෙමන්නාරමේදී අල්ලයි",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "නීති විරෝධීව මුහුදු මාර්ග ඔස්සේ මෙරටින් විදෙස් රටකට සංක්‍රමණය වීමට උත්සහ කළ බවට සැකකෙරෙන පුද්ගලයන් 10 දෙනෙකු තලෙමන්නාරම කුරුසපාඩු ප්‍රදේශයට ඔබ්බෙන් වූ මුහුදු ප්‍රදේශයේදී අත්අඩංගුවට ගත් බව නාවික හමුදාව පැවසීය.",
        "උතුරු මැද නාවික විධානයේ ශ්‍රී ලංකා නාවික නෞකා බුවනෙක ආයතනයට අයත්  පී 175 වෙරළබඩ මුර යාත්‍රාව ඊයේ (16) රාත්‍රියේ කළ විශේෂ සෝදිසි මෙහෙයුමකදී මෙම සැකකටයුතු ඩිංගි යාත්‍රාවක් නිරීක්ෂණය කර පරීක්ෂා කළ බවත් එහිදී නීති විරෝධී ලෙස මුහුදු මාර්ගයෙන් මෙරටින් විදෙස් රටකට සංක්‍රමණය වීමට උත්සාහ කළ බවට ඩිංගි යාත්‍රාවේ ක්‍රියාකරුවන් දෙදෙනා සමඟ වයස අවුරුදු 18 ට වැඩි පිරිමි පුද්ගලයන් සිව්දෙනෙකු, කාත්තාවන් දෙදෙනෙකු සහ වයස අවුරුදු 18 ට අඩු සිව්දෙනෙකු  ඇතුළු පුද්ගලයන් 10 දෙනෙකු සමඟ එම ඩිංගි යාත්‍රාව නාවික හමුදා භාරයට ගත් බවත් නාවික හමුදාව කීය.",
        "නාවික හමුදා භාරයට පත් පුද්ගලයින් පිරිස පේසාලේ, ඌරුමලේ, කිලිනොච්චි සහ කන්තලේ යන ප්‍රදේශයන්හී පදිංචිකරුවන් බවට හඳුනා ගත් බවත් එම පිරිස ඉදිරි නීතිමය කටයුතු සඳහා තලෙමන්නාරම පොලිසිය වෙත භාරදුන් බවත් නාවික හමුදාව සඳහන් කළේය."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "10",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "තලේමන්නාරම",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "නාවික",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "10",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "කුරුසපාඩු",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "අවසන් රාත්රිය",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "16",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "P175 වෙරළ මුර සංචාරය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "උතුරු මැද නාවික විධානය",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "නාවික",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "නාවික",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "දෙක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "හතර",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "වයස අවුරුදු 18",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "දෙක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "හතර",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "නාවික",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "නාවික",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "පේසාලේ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඌරුමලේ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "කිලිනොච්චි",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "කන්තලේ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "තලේමන්නාරම පොලිසිය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "நாடு தாவ முயன்ற 10 பேர் தலைமன்னாரில் பிடி!",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "இலங்கையில் இருந்து கடல் மார்க்கமாக வெளிநாட்டுக்கு செல்ல முயன்றதாக சந்தேகிக்கப்படும் 10 பேர் தலைமன்னார் குருசபாடு கடற்பரப்பில் வைத்து கைது செய்யப்பட்டுள்ளதாக கடற்படையினர் தெரிவித்துள்ளனர்.",
        "நேற்றிரவு (16) இடம்பெற்ற விசேட தேடுதல் நடவடிக்கையின் போது, ​​வடமத்திய கடற்படை கட்டளையின் இலங்கை கடற்படை கப்பலான புவனேகாவிற்கு சொந்தமான P175 கரையோர ரோந்து கப்பலானது இந்த சந்தேகத்திற்கிடமான டிங்கி கப்பலை அவதானித்து ஆய்வு செய்த போது, ​​அங்கு இருந்து சட்டவிரோதமாக இடம்பெயர்வதற்கு டிங்கி முயற்சிப்பதாக தெரிவிக்கப்பட்டுள்ளது. 18 வயதுக்கு மேற்பட்ட நான்கு ஆண்கள், இரண்டு பெண்கள் மற்றும் 18 வயதுக்குட்பட்ட 4 பேருடன் டிங்கி கப்பல் கடற்படையினரால் கைது செய்யப்பட்டதாக கடற்படையினர் தெரிவித்தனர்.",
        "கடற்படையினரால் கைது செய்யப்பட்டவர்கள் பேசாலை, உருமலை, கிளிநொச்சி மற்றும் கந்தளாய் ஆகிய பகுதிகளைச் சேர்ந்தவர்கள் என அடையாளம் காணப்பட்டதாகவும், மேலதிக சட்ட நடவடிக்கைகளுக்காக தலைமன்னார் பொலிஸாரிடம் ஒப்படைக்கப்பட்டதாகவும் கடற்படை தெரிவித்துள்ளது."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "10",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "தலைமன்னார்",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "கடற்படை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "10",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "குருசபாடு",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "நேற்று இரவு",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "16",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "P175 கடலோர ரோந்து",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "வட மத்திய கடற்படை கட்டளை",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "கடற்படை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "கடற்படை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இரண்டு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "நான்கு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "18 வயது",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இரண்டு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "நான்கு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "கடற்படை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "கடற்படை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "பேசலே",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "உருமலே",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "கிளிநொச்சி",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "கந்தளே",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "தலைமன்னார் காவல்துறை",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}