{
  "newspaper_id": "virakesari-lk",
  "url": "http://www.virakesari.lk/article/131808",
  "time_ut": 1658225419,
  "original_lang": "ta",
  "original_title": "ஜனாதிபதிப் பதவிக்கு மூவரின் பெயர்கள் முன்மொழிவு",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Three names were proposed for the presidency",
      "author": "T. Saranya",
      "body_lines": [
        "The names of three members of Parliament to fill the vacant post of President following the resignation of former President Gotabaya Rajapaksa were proposed in Parliament today (19).",
        "Accordingly, the names of Acting President and Prime Minister Ranil Wickramasinghe, Member of Parliament Dalus Alagaperuma and Member of Parliament Anurakumara Dissanayake were proposed.",
        "Leader of Opposition Sajith Premadasa proposed the name of Member of Parliament Dulles Alagaperuma and Member of Parliament (Professor) Honorable G.L. Peiris suggested it.",
        "Ranil Wickramasinghe's name was proposed by Speaker of Parliament and Minister Dinesh Gunawardena, and Member of Parliament Manusha Nanayakkara seconded it.",
        "Similarly, the name of Member of Parliament Hon'ble Anurakumara Dissanayake was proposed by Member of Parliament Hon'ble Vijitha Herath and Member of Parliament (Finance) Harini Amarasuriya seconded it.",
        "Parliamentary Secretary Thammika Dasanayake announced that the nominations of these three candidates have been accepted for the next presidential post under the Presidential Elections (Special Elections) Act No. 2 of 1981.",
        "Accordingly, tomorrow (20) one of these three will be elected as the next president by the votes of the members of parliament.",
        "The former President had sent his resignation letter to the Speaker on the 14th. Accordingly, on the 16th, the Parliament was convened and the Secretary General of the Parliament informed the Parliament that there was a vacancy in the post of President and it was announced that nominations from the members of Parliament would be accepted to fill the vacancy. Accordingly today (19) the nominations for the post of President were accepted."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Three",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "three",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Gotabaya Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "19",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickramasinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament Anurakumara Dissanayake",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Opposition Sajith Premadasa",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Dulles Alagaperuma",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickramasinghe's",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Dinesh Gunawardena",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament Manusha Nanayakkara",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Parliament Hon'ble Anurakumara Dissanayake",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament Hon'ble Vijitha Herath",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament (Finance",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "three",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Presidential Elections (Special Elections)",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "2",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "1981",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "tomorrow",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "20",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the 14th",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the 16th",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "19",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "ජනාධිපති ධුරය සඳහා නම් තුනක් යෝජනා විය",
      "author": "T. Saranya",
      "body_lines": [
        "හිටපු ජනාධිපති ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ මහතා ඉල්ලා අස්වීමෙන් පුරප්පාඩු වූ ජනාධිපති ධුරය සඳහා මන්ත්‍රීවරුන් තිදෙනෙකුගේ නම් අද (19) පාර්ලිමේන්තුවේදී යෝජනා විය.",
        "ඒ අනුව වැඩබලන ජනාධිපති සහ අගමැති රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ, පාර්ලිමේන්තු මන්ත්‍රී ඩලස් අලගපෙරුම සහ පාර්ලිමේන්තු මන්ත්‍රී අනුරකුමාර දිසානායක යන මහත්වරුන්ගේ නම් යෝජනා විය.",
        "විපක්ෂ නායක සජිත් ප්‍රේමදාස මහතා විසින් පාර්ලිමේන්තු මන්ත්‍රී ඩලස් අලගපෙරුම මහතාගේ නම යෝජනා කළ අතර පාර්ලිමේන්තු මන්ත්‍රී (මහාචාර්ය) ගරු ජී.එල්. පීරිස් යෝජනා කළේය.",
        "පාර්ලිමේන්තුවේ කථානායක හා අමාත්‍ය දිනේෂ් ගුණවර්ධන මහතා විසින් රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතාගේ නම යෝජනා කළ අතර පාර්ලිමේන්තු මන්ත්‍රී මනූෂ නානායක්කාර මහතා එය ස්ථිර කළේය.",
        "එසේම පාර්ලිමේන්තු මන්ත්‍රී ගරු අනුරකුමාර දිසානායක මහතාගේ නම පාර්ලිමේන්තු මන්ත්‍රී ගරු විජිත හේරත් මහතා විසින් යෝජනා කළ අතර පාර්ලිමේන්තු මන්ත්‍රී (මුදල්) හරිනි අමරසූරිය මහත්මිය එය ස්ථිර කළාය.",
        "1981 අංක 2 දරන ජනාධිපතිවරණ (විශේෂ මැතිවරණ) පනත යටතේ මීළඟ ජනාධිපති ධුරය සඳහා මෙම අපේක්ෂකයින් තිදෙනාගේ නාමයෝජනා පිළිගෙන ඇති බව පාර්ලිමේන්තු ලේකම් තම්මික දසනායක නිවේදනය කළේය.",
        "ඒ අනුව හෙට (20) දිනයේදී මෙම තිදෙනාගෙන් කෙනෙකු මීළඟ ජනාධිපතිවරයා ලෙස මන්ත්‍රීවරුන්ගේ ඡන්දයෙන් තේරී පත් වනු ඇත.",
        "හිටපු ජනාධිපතිවරයා පසුගිය 14 වැනිදා සිය ඉල්ලා අස්වීමේ ලිපිය කථානායකවරයා වෙත යවා තිබුණි. ඒ අනුව පසුගිය 16 වැනිදා පාර්ලිමේන්තුව කැඳවා ජනාධිපති ධූරයේ පුරප්පාඩුව පවතින බව පාර්ලිමේන්තු මහලේකම්වරයා පාර්ලිමේන්තුවට දැනුම් දුන් අතර එම පුරප්පාඩුව සඳහා මන්ත්‍රීවරුන්ගේ නාමයෝජනා භාර ගන්නා බව ද ප්‍රකාශ කළා. ඒ අනුව අද (19) ජනාධිපති ධූරය සඳහා නාමයෝජනා භාර ගන්නා ලදී."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "තුන්",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "තුන්",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "19",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තු අනුරකුමාර දිසානායක",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "විපක්ෂයේ සජිත් ප්‍රේමදාස",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඩලස් අලගපෙරුම",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහගේ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "දිනේෂ් ගුණවර්ධන",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තු මනූෂ නානායක්කාර",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තු ගරු අනුරකුමාර දිසානායක මැතිතුමා",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තු ගරු විජිත හේරත් මැතිතුමා",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව (මුදල්",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "තුන්",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජනාධිපතිවරණ (විශේෂ මැතිවරණ)",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "2",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "1981",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "හෙට",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "20",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "14 වැනි",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "16 වැනි",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "19",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "ஜனாதிபதிப் பதவிக்கு மூவரின் பெயர்கள் முன்மொழிவு",
      "author": "T. Saranya",
      "body_lines": [
        "முன்னாள் ஜனாதிபதி கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ஷவின் இராஜினாமாவை அடுத்து வெற்றிடமான ஜனாதிபதிப் பதவிக்கு மூன்று பாராளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர்களின் பெயர்கள் இன்று (19) பாராளுமன்றத்தில்  முன்மொழியப்பட்டு வழிமொழியப்பட்டன.",
        "அதற்கமைய, பதில் ஜனாதிபதி மற்றும் பிரதமர் ரணில் விக்ரமசிங்க, பாராளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர் டலஸ் அழகப்பெரும மற்றும் பாராளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர் அனுரகுமார திசாநாயக்க ஆகியோரின் பெயர்கள் இவ்வாறு முன்மொழியப்பட்டன.",
        "பாராளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர் டலஸ் அழகப்பெருமவின் பெயரை எதிர்க்கட்சித்தலைவர் சஜித் பிரேமதாச முன்மொழிந்ததுடன், பாராளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர் (பேராசிரியர்) கௌரவ ஜீ.எல். பீரிஸ் அதனை  வழிமொழிந்தார்.",
        "ரணில் விக்ரமசிங்கவின் பெயரை பாராளுமன்ற சபை முதல்வரும் அமைச்சருமான தினேஷ் குணவர்தன முன்மொழிந்ததுடன், பாராளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர் மனுஷ நாணாயக்கார அதனை வழிமொழிந்தார்.",
        "அதேபோன்று பாராளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர் கௌரவ அனுரகுமார திசாநாயக்கவின் பெயரை பாராளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர் கௌரவ விஜித ஹேரத் முன்மொழிந்ததுடன், பாராளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர் (கலாநிதி) ஹரிணி அமரசூரிய அதனை வழிமொழிந்தார்.",
        "இந்த வேட்பாளர்கள் மூவரினதும் வேட்புமனுக்கள் 1981 ஆம் ஆண்டின் 2 ஆம் இலக்க ஜனாதிபதித் தோ்தல்கள் (சிறப்பேற்பாடுகள்) சட்டத்துக்கு அமைய அடுத்துவரும் ஜனாதிபதி பதவிக்காக ஏற்றுக்கொள்ளப்பட்டதாக பாராளுமன்ற செயலாளர் நாயகம் தம்மிக்க தசநாயக்க அறிவித்தார்.",
        "அதற்கமைய நாளை (20) இந்த மூவரில் ஒருவர் அடுத்துவரும் ஜனாதிபதியாக பாராளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர்களின் வாக்குகளால் தேர்தெடுக்கப்படவுள்ளார்.",
        "கடந்த 14 ஆம் திகதி முன்னாள் ஜனாதிபதி தனது இராஜினாமாக் கடிதத்தை சபாநாயகருக்கு அனுப்பிவைத்திருந்தார். அதற்கமைய கடந்த 16 ஆம் திகதி பாராளுமன்றத்தை கூட்டி ஜனாதிபதி பதவியில் வெற்றிடம் ஏற்பட்டுள்ளதாக பாராளுமன்ற செயலாளர் நாயகம் பாராளுமன்றத்துக்கு அறிவித்ததுடன், அந்த வெற்றிடத்தை நிரப்புவதற்கு பாராளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர்களிடமிருந்து வேட்புமனுக்கள் ஏற்றுக்கொள்ளப்படுவதாக அறிவிக்கப்பட்டது. அதன்படி இன்று (19) ஜனாதிபதிப் பதவிக்கான வேட்புமனுக்கள் ஏற்றுக்கொள்ளப்பட்டன."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "மூன்று",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "மூன்று",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "19",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம் அனுரகுமார திஸாநாயக்க",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "எதிர்க்கட்சியான சஜித் பிரேமதாச",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "டல்லஸ் அழகப்பெரும",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்கவின்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "தினேஷ் குணவர்தன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்ற மனுஷ நாணயக்கார",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்ற கௌரவ அனுரகுமார திஸாநாயக்க",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்ற கௌரவ விஜித ஹேரத்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம் (நிதி",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "மூன்று",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜனாதிபதி தேர்தல்கள் (சிறப்பு தேர்தல்கள்)",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "2",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "1981",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "நாளை",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "20",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "14வது",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "16 ஆம் தேதி",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "19",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}