{
  "newspaper_id": "ada-derana-lk",
  "url": "http://www.adaderana.lk/news/84535/woman-arrested-over-pushing-slpp-supporters-into-beira-lake-remanded",
  "time_ut": 1661423220,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Woman arrested over pushing SLPP supporters into Beira Lake remanded",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Woman arrested over pushing SLPP supporters into Beira Lake remanded",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "The Colombo Magistrate’s Court today ordered to remand until September 01 a woman who was arrested in relation to the incident of pushing a group of Sri Lanka Podujana Peramuna (SLPP) supporters into the Beira Lake at Slave Island on May 09.",
        "The order was issued when the case was taken up before Colombo Fort Magistrate Thilina Gamage today (25).",
        "Accordingly, the magistrate who ordered the woman to be remanded in custody until September 01, further ordered her to be produced in an identification parade following a request made by the police."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "SLPP",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "Beira Lake",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "The Colombo Magistrate’s Court",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "September 01",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Podujana Peramuna",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Beira Lake",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "Slave Island",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "May 09",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Colombo Fort Magistrate",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "Thilina Gamage",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "25",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "September 01",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "ශ්‍රී ලංකා පොදුජන පෙරමුණේ ආධාරකරුවන් බේරේ වැවට තල්ලු කිරීම සම්බන්ධයෙන් අත්අඩංගුවට ගත් කාන්තාවක් රිමාන්ඩ්",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකා පොදුජන පෙරමුණේ ආධාරකරුවන් පිරිසක් මැයි මස 09 වනදා කොම්පඤ්ඤවීදියේ බේරේ වැවට තල්ලු කිරීමේ සිද්ධිය සම්බන්ධයෙන් අත්අඩංගුවට ගත් කාන්තාවක් සැප්තැම්බර් 01 වනදා දක්වා රක්ෂිත බන්ධනාගාර ගත කිරීමට කොළඹ මහේස්ත්‍රාත් අධිකරණය අද නියෝග කළා.",
        "එම නඩුව අද (25) කොළඹ කොටුව මහේස්ත්‍රාත් තිළිණ ගමගේ මහතා ඉදිරියේ කැඳවූ අවස්ථාවේදී මෙම නියෝගය නිකුත් කර ඇත.",
        "ඒ අනුව අදාළ කාන්තාව සැප්තැම්බර් 01 වැනිදා දක්වා රක්ෂිත බන්ධනාගාරගත කිරීමට නියෝග කළ මහේස්ත්‍රාත්වරයා පොලිසිය කළ ඉල්ලීමකට අනුව ඇය හඳුනාගැනීමේ පෙරට්ටුවකට ඉදිරිපත් කරන ලෙස වැඩිදුරටත් නියෝග කළේය."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "SLPP",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "බේරේ වැව",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "කොළඹ මහේස්ත්‍රාත් අධිකරණය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "සැප්තැම්බර් 01",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "පොදුජන පෙරමුණ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "බේරේ වැව",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "කොම්පඤ්ඤවීදිය",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "මැයි 09",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "කොළඹ කොටුව මහේස්ත්‍රාත්",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "තිළිණ ගමගේ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "25",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "සැප්තැම්බර් 01",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "SLPP ஆதரவாளர்களை பெய்ரா ஏரிக்குள் தள்ளிய வழக்கில் கைது செய்யப்பட்ட பெண் விளக்கமறியலில் வைக்கப்பட்டுள்ளார்",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "ஸ்ரீலங்கா பொதுஜன பெரமுனவின் (SLPP) ஆதரவாளர்கள் குழுவை மே 09 ஆம் திகதி கொம்பனித்தீவில் உள்ள பெய்ரா ஏரிக்குள் தள்ளிய சம்பவம் தொடர்பில் கைது செய்யப்பட்ட பெண்ணை செப்டம்பர் 01 ஆம் திகதி வரை விளக்கமறியலில் வைக்க கொழும்பு நீதவான் நீதிமன்றம் இன்று உத்தரவிட்டுள்ளது.",
        "இந்த வழக்கு இன்று (25) கொழும்பு கோட்டை நீதவான் திலின கமகே முன்னிலையில் எடுத்துக்கொள்ளப்பட்ட போதே இந்த உத்தரவு பிறப்பிக்கப்பட்டுள்ளது.",
        "இதன்படி, குறித்த பெண்ணை எதிர்வரும் செப்டெம்பர் மாதம் 01ஆம் திகதி வரை விளக்கமறியலில் வைக்குமாறு உத்தரவிட்ட நீதவான், பொலிஸாரின் கோரிக்கைக்கு அமைய அவரை அடையாள அணிவகுப்பில் ஆஜர்படுத்துமாறு மேலும் உத்தரவிட்டார்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "எஸ்.எல்.பி.பி",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "பெய்ரா ஏரி",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "கொழும்பு மாஜிஸ்திரேட் நீதிமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "செப்டம்பர் 01",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "பொதுஜன பெரமுன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "பெய்ரா ஏரி",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "அடிமை தீவு",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "மே 09",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "கொழும்பு கோட்டை நீதவான்",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "திலின கமகே",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "25",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "செப்டம்பர் 01",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}