{
  "newspaper_id": "lankadeepa-lk",
  "url": "https://www.lankadeepa.lk/news/’’පක්ෂ-මාරු-කිරීම-හෝ-කඩේ-යාම-මගේ-සිලබස්-එකේ-නැහැ’’/101-618809",
  "time_ut": 1661516339,
  "original_lang": "si",
  "original_title": "’’පක්ෂ මාරු කිරීම හෝ කඩේ යාම මගේ සිලබස් එකේ නැහැ’’",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "\"Switching parties or shopping is not on my syllabus\"",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "Mr. Ranjan Ramanayake, the former Minister of State who was pardoned by the President, stated in Colombo today (26) that he has not changed, he is not afraid and that switching parties or going shopping is not in his syllabus.",
        "Mr. Ramanayake also stated that he regretted that he was not able to comment in front of the media as per his old habits, having received a conditional pardon.",
        "He said this while attending a press conference at the opposition leader's office in Marx Fernando Mawatha, Colombo, that although he has lost that freedom as he spoke freely, he will carry his voice against fraud and corruption to the best of his ability.",
        "Mr. Ramanayake also mentioned that more attention will be paid to art activities in the coming period.",
        "He also said that he would like to thank President Ranil Wickremesinghe, Justice Minister Wijedasa Rajapaksa and everyone else for the freedom given to him.",
        "Mr. Ramanayake also said that he would like to express his gratitude to all the artists and politicians who dedicated themselves to him during the very difficult period of imprisonment due to the Corona epidemic.",
        "Mr. Ramanayake further said that he has a lot of love from the people and he will not lose that love given by the people for the privilege of blessings."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Ranjan Ramanayake",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "State",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Colombo",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "26",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Ramanayake",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Marx Fernando Mawatha",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Colombo",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Ramanayake",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the coming period",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Justice",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Wijedasa Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Ramanayake",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Corona",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Ramanayake",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "’’පක්ෂ මාරු කිරීම හෝ කඩේ යාම මගේ සිලබස් එකේ නැහැ’’",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "තමන් වෙනස් වී, බිය වී හෝ  නොමැති බවත් පක්ෂ මාරු කිරීම හෝ කඩේ යාම තමන්ගේ සිලබස් එකේ නොමැති බවත් ජනාධිපති සමාව ලැබූ හිටපු රාජ්‍ය අමාත්‍ය රංජන් රාමනායක මහතා කොළඹ දී අද (26) ප්‍රකාශ කළේ ය.",
        "කොන්දේසි සහිත සමාවක් හිමිවූ තමන්ට පරණ පුරුදු  විදිහට මාධ්‍ය හමුවේ අදහස් දැක්වීමට නොහැකි වීම පිළිබඳ කනගාටු වන බවත් රාමනායක මහතා සඳහන් කළේය.",
        "නිදහසේ කථා කළ තමන්ට ඒ නිදහස අහිමි වුවත් හැකි උපරිමයෙන් වංචාවට දූෂණයට එරෙහිව තමන් ගෙන ගිය හඬ ගෙන යන බවත් කොළඹ මාක්ස් ප්‍රනාන්දු  මාවතේ විපක්ෂ නායක කාර්යාලයේදී  මාධ්‍ය හමුවකට එක්වෙමින් ඔහු මේ බව පැවසීය.",
        "ඉදිරි කාලය තුළ කලා කටයුතු වෙනුවෙන් වැඩි නැඹුරුවක් සිදුකරන බවත් රාමනායක මහතා එහිදී සඳහන් කළේය.",
        "තමන්ට ලබාදුන් නිදහස සම්බන්ධයෙන් ජනාධිපති රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ, අධිකරණ අමාත්‍ය විජේදාස රාජපක්ෂ යන මහත්වරුන් ඇතුළු සියලු දෙනාටම ස්තුතිය පුද කරන බවත් ඔහු එහිදී පැවසීය.",
        "එමෙන්ම කොරෝනා වසංගතය වැළඳී බන්ධනාගාර ගතව ඉතා අසීරු සමයේ දී සිට  තමන් වෙනුවෙන් කැපවී  ක්‍රියා කළ දේශපාලඥයන් කලාකරුවන් ඇතුළු සියලු දෙනාට ස්තූතිය පළකරන බවත් රාමනායක මහතා පැවසීය.",
        "තමන්ට ජනතාවගෙන් විශාල ආදරයක් හිමිව ඇති බවත් කිසිදු අවස්ථාවක වරදාන වරප්‍රසාද වෙනුවෙන් ජනතාව ලබාදුන්  එම ආදරය අහිමි කර ගන්නේ නැතැයිද රාමනායක මහතා තවදුරටත් කීවේය."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "රන්ජන් රාමනායක",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "රජයේ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "කොළඹ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "26",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "රාමනායක",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "මාක්ස් ප්‍රනාන්දු මාවත",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "කොළඹ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "රාමනායක",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉදිරි කාලය",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "යුක්තිය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "විජේදාස රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "රාමනායක",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "කොරෝනා",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "රාමනායක",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "\"கட்சிகளை மாற்றுவது அல்லது ஷாப்பிங் செய்வது எனது பாடத்திட்டத்தில் இல்லை\"",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "தான் மாறவில்லை, தமக்கு அச்சமில்லை, கட்சி மாறுவதோ, கடைக்குப் போவதோ தனது பாடத்திட்டத்தில் இல்லை எனவும் ஜனாதிபதியினால் மன்னிக்கப்பட்ட முன்னாள் இராஜாங்க அமைச்சர் திரு.ரஞ்சன் ராமநாயக்க இன்று (26) கொழும்பில் தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "நிபந்தனைக்குட்பட்ட மன்னிப்பைப் பெற்றதன் மூலம் பழைய வழக்கப்படி ஊடகங்கள் முன் கருத்துத் தெரிவிக்க முடியாமல் போனதற்கு வருந்துவதாகவும் திரு.ராமநாயக்க குறிப்பிட்டார்.",
        "சுதந்திரமாகப் பேசியதால் அந்தச் சுதந்திரத்தை இழந்தாலும் மோசடிக்கும் ஊழலுக்கும் எதிராகத் தன்னால் இயன்றவரை குரல் கொடுப்பேன் என கொழும்பு மார்க்ஸ் பெர்னாண்டோ மாவத்தையில் உள்ள எதிர்க்கட்சித் தலைவர் அலுவலகத்தில் நடைபெற்ற ஊடகவியலாளர் சந்திப்பில் கலந்துகொண்டு கருத்துத் தெரிவிக்கையிலேயே அவர் மேற்கண்டவாறு தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "எதிர்வரும் காலங்களில் கலை நடவடிக்கைகளில் அதிக கவனம் செலுத்தப்படும் எனவும் திரு ராமநாயக்க குறிப்பிட்டுள்ளார்.",
        "தனக்கு வழங்கப்பட்ட சுதந்திரத்திற்காக ஜனாதிபதி ரணில் விக்ரமசிங்க, நீதி அமைச்சர் விஜேதாச ராஜபக்ஷ உள்ளிட்ட அனைவருக்கும் நன்றியை தெரிவித்துக் கொள்வதாகவும் அவர் கூறினார்.",
        "கரோனா தொற்றுநோய் காரணமாக மிகவும் கடினமான சிறைவாசத்தின் போது தமக்காக தங்களை அர்ப்பணித்த அனைத்து கலைஞர்கள் மற்றும் அரசியல்வாதிகளுக்கு தனது நன்றியைத் தெரிவித்துக் கொள்வதாகவும் திரு ராமநாயக்க தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "தமக்கு மக்கள் மீது அதிக அன்பு இருப்பதாகவும், ஆசீர்வாதத்தின் பாக்கியத்திற்காக மக்கள் வழங்கிய அந்த அன்பை இழக்க மாட்டேன் என்றும் திரு.ராமநாயக்க மேலும் தெரிவித்தார்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ரஞ்சன் ராமநாயக்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "நிலை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "கொழும்பு",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "26",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ராமநாயக்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "மார்க்ஸ் பெர்னாண்டோ மாவத்தை",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "கொழும்பு",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ராமநாயக்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "வரும் காலம்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "நீதி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "விஜேதாச ராஜபக்ஷ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ராமநாயக்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "கொரோனா",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ராமநாயக்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}