{
  "newspaper_id": "daily-ft-lk",
  "url": "https://www.ft.lk/news/Gotabaya-s-popularity-wave-destroyed-Sri-Lanka-Sajith/56-739223",
  "time_ut": 1661730095,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Gotabaya’s popularity wave destroyed Sri Lanka: Sajith",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Gotabaya’s popularity wave destroyed Sri Lanka: Sajith",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "Says those who voted for Pohottuwa en masse responsible for country’s destruction",
        "Claims he is content with not accepting posts in current Govt.",
        "Opposition Leader Sajith Premadasa says Sri Lanka got swept up by the ‘Gotabaya popularity wave’ that eventually led to its destruction.",
        "“The country was caught up in the popularity wave of Gotabaya Rajapaksa and today the whole country has been destroyed by that wave,” he said.",
        "Premadasa blamed the majority of the people for going along with that wave to vote in the Sri Lanka Podujana Peramuna. “6.9 million voted at the Presidential election while 6.8 million voted at the general election to bring this clan into power. After voting for the Pohottuwa en masse they are now rejecting all 225 MPs in Parliament,” he said.",
        "Premadasa pointed out that even in crisis situations leaders of the past such as his own father Ranasinghe Premadasa, J.R Jayawardene, Lalith Athulathmudali and others were able to develop the country. “Till recently many of the people remained as political slaves. They were yes-men of Mahinda Rajapaksa. They are responsible for this destruction,” he said.",
        "Premadasa made these remarks at a Samagi Jana Balawegaya party meeting held yesterday in Minuwangoda.",
        "Premadasa told those gathered at the meeting that he refused to accept any positions from a President that was rejected by the people. “I have no regrets and I am content with the decision made regarding that,” he said. According to him, despite rampant corruption such as when procuring coal, the current government is only keen on carrying out political games.",
        "Commenting on the ongoing crisis, Premadasa said the issue faced by the country cannot be resolved in a matter of months. “Everyone must be prepared to understand this. People cannot be tricked through fairy tales anymore,” he added.",
        "“When I understood the crisis in this country and said we should immediately go for an election for a new mandate, certain parties laughed at me in disdain. Today they are out on the roads calling for elections,” Premadasa said.",
        "Premadasa claimed he forewarned of all the dangers before the country but the Government merely responded by ridiculing him. “As a result of that the whole country has suffered a tragic fate,” he said."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Gotabaya",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "Sri Lanka",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "Sajith",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Pohottuwa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Govt",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sajith Premadasa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Gotabaya Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "Podujana Peramuna",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "6.9 million",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "6.8 million",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Pohottuwa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "225",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Premadasa",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ranasinghe Premadasa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "J.R Jayawardene",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Mahinda Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Samagi",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Jana Balawegaya",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "yesterday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Minuwangoda",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "Premadasa",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "months",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Today",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Premadasa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Premadasa",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "ගෝඨාභයගේ ජනප්‍රිය රැල්ල ලංකාව විනාශ කළා: සජිත්",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "පොහොට්ටුවට ඡන්දය දුන් පිරිස රට විනාශයට වගකිව යුතු බව කියයි",
        "වත්මන් රජයේ තනතුරු භාර නොගැනීමෙන් තමා සෑහීමකට පත්වන බව ප්‍රකාශ කරයි.",
        "විපක්ෂ නායක සජිත් ප්‍රේමදාස මහතා පවසන්නේ 'ගෝඨාභය ජනප්‍රිය රැල්ලෙන්' ශ්‍රී ලංකාව ගසාගෙන ගොස් අවසානයේ එය විනාශයට පත් කළ බවයි.",
        "ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂගේ ජනප්‍රියතා රැල්ලට රට අහුවෙලා අද ඒ රැල්ලට මුළු රටම විනාශ වෙලා ඉවරයි.",
        "එම රැල්ල සමඟ ශ්‍රී ලංකා පොදුජන පෙරමුණට ඡන්දය දීමට යාම ගැන ප්‍රේමදාස මහතා බහුතරයකට දොස් පැවරීය. “ජනාධිපතිවරණයේදී ලක්ෂ 69ක් ඡන්දය දුන් අතර මහ මැතිවරණයේදී ලක්ෂ 68ක් ඡන්දය දුන්නේ මේ වංශය බලයට ගෙන ඒමටයි. පොහොට්ටුවට සමූහ වශයෙන් ඡන්දය දීලා දැන් පාර්ලිමේන්තුවේ මන්ත්‍රීවරුන් 225 දෙනාම ප්‍රතික්ෂේප කරනවා,” ඔහු පැවසීය.",
        "තම පියා වන රණසිංහ ප්‍රේමදාස, ජේ.ආර්. ජයවර්ධන, ලලිත් ඇතුලත්මුදලි වැනි අතීතයේ සිටි නායකයන් අර්බුදකාරී අවස්ථාවලදී පවා රට සංවර්ධනය කිරීමට සමත් වූ බව ප්‍රේමදාස පෙන්වා දුන්නේය. මෑතක් වන තුරුම බොහෝ මිනිසුන් දේශපාලන වහලුන් ලෙස සිටියා. ඔව්හු මහින්ද රාජපක්ෂගේ මිනිසුන්ය. මේ විනාශයට ඔවුන් වගකිව යුතුයි,” ඔහු පැවසීය.",
        "ප්‍රේමදාස මහතා මේ අදහස් පළ කළේ මිනුවන්ගොඩදී ඊයේ පැවැති සමගි ජන බලවේගය පක්ෂ රැස්වීමකදීය.",
        "ප්‍රේමදාස රැස්වීමට රැස්ව සිටි පිරිසට ප්‍රකාශ කළේ ජනතාව ප්‍රතික්ෂේප කළ ජනාධිපතිවරයකුගෙන් කිසිදු තනතුරක් භාර ගැනීම තමන් ප්‍රතික්ෂේප කරන බවයි. \"මට කිසිම පසුතැවිල්ලක් නැති අතර ඒ සම්බන්ධයෙන් ගත් තීරණය ගැන මම සෑහීමකට පත්වෙනවා,\" ඔහු පැවසීය. ඔහුට අනුව ගල් අඟුරු ලබා ගැනීම වැනි දූෂණ විශාල වශයෙන් සිදු වුවද වත්මන් ආණ්ඩුව උනන්දු වන්නේ දේශපාලන සෙල්ලම් කිරීමට පමණි.",
        "පවතින අර්බුදය පිළිබඳව අදහස් දක්වමින් ප්‍රේමදාස කියා සිටියේ රට මුහුණ දී සිටින ප්‍රශ්නය මාස කිහිපයකින් විසඳිය නොහැකි බවයි. “මෙය තේරුම් ගැනීමට සෑම කෙනෙකුම සූදානම් විය යුතුය. තවදුරටත් සුරංගනා කතාවලින් ජනතාව රවටා ගත නොහැකි බව ඔහු වැඩිදුරටත් පැවසීය.",
        "“මම මේ රටේ අර්බුද තේරුම් අරගෙන අලුත් ජනවරමක් සඳහා වහාම මැතිවරණයකට යා යුතුයි කියන විට ඇතැම් පාර්ශ්ව මට උපහාසයෙන් හිනා වුණා. අද ඡන්දෙ ඉල්ලලා පාරට බැහැලා.” ප්‍රේමදාස කීවේය.",
        "ප්‍රේමදාස කියා සිටියේ රට ඉදිරියේ ඇති සියලුම අනතුරු පිළිබඳව තමා කලින්ම අනතුරු අඟවා ඇති නමුත් රජය එයට ප්‍රතිචාර දැක්වූයේ ඔහුට සමච්චල් කිරීමෙනි. එහි ප්‍රතිඵලයක් ලෙස මුළු රටම ඛේදනීය ඉරණමකට ගොදුරු වී ඇති බවද ඔහු පැවසීය."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ගෝඨාභය",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "සජිත්",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "පොහොට්ටුව",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "රජය",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "සජිත් ප්‍රේමදාස",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "පොදුජන පෙරමුණ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "මිලියන 6.9 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "මිලියන 6.8 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "පොහොට්ටුව",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "225",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ප්‍රේමදාස ය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "රණසිංහ ප්‍රේමදාස",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "J.R ජයවර්ධන",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "මහින්ද රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "සමගි",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජන බලවේගය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඊයේ",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මිනුවන්ගොඩ",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "ප්‍රේමදාස ය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "මාස",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ප්‍රේමදාස ය",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ප්‍රේමදාස ය",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "கோட்டாபயவின் புகழ் அலை இலங்கையை அழித்தது: சஜித்",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "பொஹொட்டுவவுக்கு வாக்களித்தவர்களே நாட்டின் அழிவுக்குக் காரணம் என்கிறார்கள்",
        "தற்போதைய அரசாங்கத்தில் பதவிகளை ஏற்காமல் திருப்தி அடைவதாகக் கூறுகிறார்.",
        "இலங்கையை ‘கோத்தபாய பிரபல்ய அலை’ இழுத்துச் சென்று இறுதியில் அழிவுக்கு இட்டுச் சென்றதாக எதிர்க்கட்சித் தலைவர் சஜித் பிரேமதாச தெரிவித்துள்ளார்.",
        "நாடு கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்சவின் பிரபல்ய அலையில் சிக்கி, இன்று முழு நாடும் அந்த அலையால் அழிந்துவிட்டது என அவர் தெரிவித்துள்ளார்.",
        "ஶ்ரீலங்கா பொதுஜன பெரமுனவுக்கு வாக்களிக்க பெரும்பான்மையான மக்கள் அந்த அலையுடன் இணைந்து சென்றதாக பிரேமதாச குற்றம் சுமத்தியுள்ளார். “6.9 மில்லியன் மக்கள் ஜனாதிபதித் தேர்தலில் வாக்களித்த அதேவேளை, பொதுத் தேர்தலில் 6.8 மில்லியன் மக்கள் இந்தக் குலத்தை ஆட்சிக்குக் கொண்டுவருவதற்காக வாக்களித்துள்ளனர். பொஹொட்டுவவுக்கு மொத்தமாக வாக்களித்த பின்னர் தற்போது பாராளுமன்றத்தில் உள்ள 225 எம்.பி.க்களையும் நிராகரித்து வருகின்றனர்” என அவர் கூறினார்.",
        "தனது சொந்த தந்தையான ரணசிங்க பிரேமதாச, ஜே.ஆர் ஜயவர்தன, லலித் அத்துலத்முதலி போன்ற கடந்த கால தலைவர்களான நெருக்கடி நிலைகளிலும் கூட நாட்டை அபிவிருத்தி செய்ய முடிந்ததாக பிரேமதாச சுட்டிக்காட்டினார். “சமீப காலம் வரை மக்கள் பலர் அரசியல் அடிமைகளாகவே இருந்தனர். அவர்கள் மகிந்த ராஜபக்சவின் ஆம் ஆட்கள். இந்த அழிவுக்கு அவர்களே காரணம்,'' என்றார்.",
        "மினுவாங்கொடையில் நேற்று இடம்பெற்ற சமகி ஜன பலவேகய கட்சியின் கூட்டமொன்றில் பிரேமதாச இதனைத் தெரிவித்துள்ளார்.",
        "மக்களால் நிராகரிக்கப்பட்ட ஜனாதிபதியின் பதவிகளை ஏற்க மறுத்ததாக பிரேமதாச கூட்டத்தில் கூடியிருந்தவர்களிடம் கூறினார். \"எனக்கு எந்த வருத்தமும் இல்லை, அது தொடர்பாக எடுக்கப்பட்ட முடிவில் நான் திருப்தி அடைகிறேன்,\" என்று அவர் கூறினார். அவர் கூறுகையில், நிலக்கரி கொள்முதல் போன்ற ஊழல்கள் தலைதூக்கிய போதிலும், தற்போதைய அரசாங்கம் அரசியல் விளையாட்டுகளில் மட்டுமே ஆர்வம் காட்டி வருகிறது.",
        "தற்போது நிலவும் நெருக்கடி குறித்து கருத்து தெரிவித்த பிரேமதாச, நாடு எதிர்நோக்கும் பிரச்சினைக்கு சில மாதங்களில் தீர்வு காண முடியாது. \"இதை புரிந்து கொள்ள அனைவரும் தயாராக இருக்க வேண்டும். இனியும் விசித்திரக் கதைகள் மூலம் மக்களை ஏமாற்ற முடியாது” என்று அவர் மேலும் கூறினார்.",
        "“இந்த நாட்டில் ஏற்பட்டுள்ள நெருக்கடியை நான் புரிந்துகொண்டு, உடனடியாக ஒரு புதிய ஆணைக்காக தேர்தலுக்கு செல்ல வேண்டும் என்று கூறியபோது, ​​சில கட்சிகள் என்னை ஏளனமாக சிரித்தன. இன்று அவர்கள் தேர்தலுக்கு அழைப்பு விடுத்து வீதிகளில் இறங்கி உள்ளனர்” என்று பிரேமதாச கூறினார்.",
        "பிரேமதாச, நாட்டிற்கு முன்னால் உள்ள அனைத்து ஆபத்துக்களையும் முன்கூட்டியே எச்சரித்ததாகவும், ஆனால் அரசாங்கம் அவரை கேலி செய்வதன் மூலம் பதிலளித்ததாகவும் கூறினார். இதன் விளைவாக முழு நாடும் ஒரு சோகமான விதியை சந்தித்துள்ளது,\" என்று அவர் கூறினார்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "கோட்டாபய",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "இலங்கை",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "சஜித்",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "பொஹொட்டுவ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "அரசு",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "சஜித் பிரேமதாச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "பொதுஜன பெரமுன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "6.9 மில்லியன்",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "6.8 மில்லியன்",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "பொஹொட்டுவ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "225",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பிரேமதாச",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரணசிங்க பிரேமதாச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜே.ஆர் ஜெயவர்த்தனே",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "மஹிந்த ராஜபக்ஷ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "சமகி",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜன பலவேகயா",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "நேற்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "மினுவாங்கொட",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "பிரேமதாச",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "மாதங்கள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "பிரேமதாச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பிரேமதாச",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}