{
  "newspaper_id": "ada-lk",
  "url": "https://www.ada.lk/breaking_news/විරෝධතාකරුවන්ට-එරෙහිව-ජීව-උණ්ඩ-භාවිතයට-විපක්ෂයේ-පක්ෂ-නායකයෝ-එරෙහිවෙති/11-395409",
  "time_ut": 1657764890,
  "original_lang": "si",
  "original_title": "විරෝධතාකරුවන්ට එරෙහිව ජීව උණ්ඩ භාවිතයට විපක්ෂයේ පක්ෂ නායකයෝ එරෙහිවෙති",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Opposition party leaders oppose the use of live ammunition against protesters",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "Mr. Mano Ganesan, Member of Parliament, said that the opposition party leaders were against giving approval for the use of live bullets against the protestors.",
        "Mr. Mano Ganesan said on his Twitter account that the leaders of Vipakya protested in the party leaders' meeting held yesterday under the chairmanship of Speaker Mahinda Yapa Abeywardena.",
        "He says that the three armed forces commanders and the Inspector General of Police were also present for this party leader meeting."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Mano Ganesan",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Mano Ganesan",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Twitter",
            "label": "PRODUCT"
          },
          {
            "text": "Vipakya",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "yesterday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Mahinda Yapa Abeywardena",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "three",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Inspector General of Police",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "විරෝධතාකරුවන්ට එරෙහිව ජීව උණ්ඩ භාවිතයට විපක්ෂයේ පක්ෂ නායකයෝ එරෙහිවෙති",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "විරෝධතාකරුවන්ට එරෙහිව සජීවී උණ්ඩ භාවිත කිරිම සඳහා අනුමැතිය ලබාදීමට විපක්ෂයේ පක්ෂ නායකයන් එරෙහි වූ බව පාර්ලිමේන්තු මන්ත්‍රී මනෝ ගනේෂන් මහතා පවසයි.",
        "කථානායක මහින්ද යාපා අබේවර්ධන මහතාගේ ප්‍රධානත්වයෙන් ඊයේ පැවැති පක්ෂ නායක රැස්වීමේදී විපක්යේ පක්ෂ නායකයන් ‌මෙසේ විරෝධය දැක්වූ බව මනෝ ගනේෂන් මහතා සිය ට්විටර් ගිණුමෙන් පවසයි.",
        "මෙම පක්ෂ නායක රැස්වීම සඳහා ත්‍රිවිධ හමුදාපතිවරුන් හා පොලිස්පතිවරයාද ඒක්වූ බව ඔහු පවසයි."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Mano Ganesan",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Mano Ganesan",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ට්විටර්",
            "label": "PRODUCT"
          },
          {
            "text": "Vipakya",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඊයේ",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මහින්ද යාපා අබේවර්ධන",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "තුන්",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "පොලිස්පති",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "போராட்டக்காரர்களுக்கு எதிராக வெடிமருந்துகளை பயன்படுத்துவதை எதிர்கட்சி தலைவர்கள் எதிர்க்கின்றனர்",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "ஆர்ப்பாட்டக்காரர்களுக்கு எதிராக நேரடி தோட்டாக்களை பயன்படுத்துவதற்கு அனுமதி வழங்குவதற்கு எதிர்க்கட்சித் தலைவர்கள் எதிர்ப்பு தெரிவிக்கின்றனர் என பாராளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர் திரு.மனோ கணேசன் தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "சபாநாயகர் மஹிந்த யாப்பா அபேவர்தன தலைமையில் நேற்று நடைபெற்ற கட்சித் தலைவர்கள் கூட்டத்தில் விபாக்கிய தலைவர்கள் எதிர்ப்பு தெரிவித்ததாக மனோ கணேசன் தனது டுவிட்டர் தளத்தில் தெரிவித்துள்ளார்.",
        "இந்தக் கட்சித் தலைவர் சந்திப்பில் முப்படைத் தளபதிகள் மற்றும் பொலிஸ் மா அதிபர் ஆகியோரும் கலந்துகொண்டதாக அவர் கூறுகிறார்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Mano Ganesan",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Mano Ganesan",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ட்விட்டர்",
            "label": "PRODUCT"
          },
          {
            "text": "விபாக்யா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "நேற்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "மஹிந்த யாப்பா அபேவர்தன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "மூன்று",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்ஸ்பெக்டர் ஜெனரல் ஆஃப் போலீஸ்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}