{
  "newspaper_id": "daily-mirror-lk",
  "url": "https://www.dailymirror.lk/breaking_news/Tuna-export-scam-Lakshadweep-MP-his-nephew-under-CBI-scanner/108-239789",
  "time_ut": 1656126741,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Tuna export scam: Lakshadweep MP, his nephew under CBI scanner",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Tuna export scam: Lakshadweep MP, his nephew under CBI scanner",
      "author": "",
      "body_lines": [
        "India's Lakshadweep MP Mohammed Faizal has come under the CBI scanner in connection with alleged irregularities in the export of tuna fish to Sri Lanka.",
        "The central agency is also investigating Faizal’s nephew Abdul Razzak and a Colombo-based company identified as SRT General Merchants Importer and Exporter.",
        "A CBI team of about 25 officials and the Lakshadweep administration’s vigilance officials have been engaged in conducting a ‘joint surprise check’ exercise on different departments of the Lakshadweep administration. These departments include the Lakshadweep Co-operative Marketing Federation (LCMF), the Fisheries Department, the Public Works Department, the Khadi Board and the Cooperative Society and Animal Husbandry Department.",
        "According to the CBI, some public servants of the LCMF, in collusion with some public representatives and government servants, caused loss to the LCMF in the matter of the export of tuna fish to SRT General Merchants without following the requisite tender process and other formalities.",
        "The CBI alleged that the LCMF procured a large amount of tuna fish from local fishermen using MP Faizal’s influence. The tuna fish procured in this manner was exported by the LCMF to SRT General Merchants, but the company did not make payments, the CBI said. According CBI sources, Faizal’s nephew Razzak is an office bearer of SRT.",
        "Speaking to The Indian Express, Faizal said: “I don’t know, really (about the CBI probe)… The fish was sold to SRT as the buyers had offered very good price… The (cooperative marketing)  federation identified a buyer in Lanka and he offered very good raters. But the buyer backed out later due to some intervention by Thoothukudi middlemen. As a result, 250 MT fish was left with the federation to dispose of. Then, there was a local auction and Thoothukudi middlemen bought it. There is no corruption in it. Let them enquire it, the truth will come out.”"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "CBI",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "India",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Mohammed Faizal",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "CBI",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Faizal",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Abdul Razzak",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Merchants Importer",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Exporter",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "CBI",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "about 25",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Lakshadweep",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "Lakshadweep",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "Marketing Federation",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Fisheries Department",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Public Works Department",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Khadi Board",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Cooperative Society and Animal Husbandry Department",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "CBI",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "LCMF",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "CBI",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Faizal",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "CBI",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "CBI",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Faizal",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "SRT",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "The Indian Express",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Faizal",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "CBI",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "SRT",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Thoothukudi",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "250",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Thoothukudi",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "ටූනා අපනයන වංචාව: CBI ස්කෑනරය යටතේ ඔහුගේ බෑණනුවන් වන ලක්ෂද්වීප් මන්ත්‍රී",
      "author": "",
      "body_lines": [
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවට ටූනා මත්ස්‍ය අපනයනයේදී සිදුවූ බව කියන අක්‍රමිකතා සම්බන්ධයෙන් ඉන්දියාවේ ලක්ෂද්වීප් පාර්ලිමේන්තු මන්ත්‍රී මොහොමඩ් ෆයිසාල් CBI ස්කෑනර් පරීක්ෂණයකට ලක්ව තිබේ.",
        "මධ්‍යම ඒජන්සිය ෆයිසාල්ගේ බෑණනුවන් වන අබ්දුල් රසාක් සහ SRT General Merchants Importer and Exporter ලෙස හඳුනාගෙන ඇති කොළඹ පදනම් කරගත් සමාගමක් පිළිබඳවද විමර්ශනය කරයි.",
        "නිලධාරීන් 25 දෙනෙකුගෙන් පමණ සමන්විත CBI කණ්ඩායමක් සහ ලක්ෂද්වීප් පරිපාලනයේ සුපරීක්ෂාකාරී නිලධාරීන් ලක්ෂද්වීප් පරිපාලනයේ විවිධ දෙපාර්තමේන්තු වල 'ඒකාබද්ධ විස්මිත පරීක්ෂාව' අභ්‍යාසයක නිරත වී ඇත. මෙම දෙපාර්තමේන්තු වලට ලක්ෂද්වීප් සමුපකාර අලෙවි සම්මේලනය (LCMF), ධීවර දෙපාර්තමේන්තුව, පොදු වැඩ දෙපාර්තමේන්තුව, Khadi මණ්ඩලය සහ සමුපකාර සමිතිය සහ සත්ව පාලන දෙපාර්තමේන්තුව ඇතුළත් වේ.",
        "CBI ට අනුව, LCMF හි සමහර රාජ්‍ය සේවකයින්, සමහර මහජන නියෝජිතයින් සහ රජයේ සේවකයින් සමඟ හවුල් වී, අවශ්‍ය ටෙන්ඩර් ක්‍රියාවලිය සහ අනෙකුත් විධිවිධාන අනුගමනය නොකර SRT General Merchants වෙත ටූනා මාළු අපනයනය කිරීමේ කාරණයේදී LCMF වෙත පාඩුවක් සිදු කර ඇත.",
        "ෆයිසාල් මන්ත්‍රීවරයාගේ බලපෑමෙන් දේශීය ධීවරයින්ගෙන් එල්සීඑම්එෆ් විශාල ටූනා මසුන් සපයා ගත් බවට CBI චෝදනා කළේය. මෙලෙස සපයාගත් ටූනා මාළු LCMF ආයතනය විසින් SRT General Merchants වෙත අපනයනය කර ඇතත් එම සමාගම මුදල් ගෙවා නොමැති බව CBI පවසයි. CBI මූලාශ්‍රවලට අනුව, ෆයිසාල්ගේ බෑණනුවන් වන රසාක් SRT හි නිලධාරියෙකි.",
        "The Indian Express වෙත අදහස් දක්වමින් ෆයිසාල් මෙසේ පැවසීය: “ඇත්තටම (CBI පරීක්ෂණය ගැන) මම දන්නේ නැහැ... ගැනුම්කරුවන් ඉතා හොඳ මිලක් ලබා දුන් නිසා මාළු SRT වෙත විකුණුවා... (සමුපකාර අලෙවිකරණ)  සම්මේලනය ලංකාවේ ගැණුම්කරුවෙකු හඳුනා ගත්තා. ඔහු ඉතා හොඳ ශ්‍රේණිගත කරන්නන් ඉදිරිපත් කළේය. නමුත් තූත්තුකුඩි අතරමැදියන්ගේ යම් මැදිහත් වීමක් මත ගැනුම්කරු පසුව පසුබැස්සේය. එහි ප්‍රතිඵලයක් ලෙස මත්ස්‍ය මෙට්‍රික් ටොන් 250ක් බැහැර කිරීමට සම්මේලනයට ඉතිරි විය. ඉන්පසුව දේශීය වෙන්දේසියක් පැවති අතර තූතුකුඩි අතරමැදියන් එය මිලදී ගෙන ඇත. එහි කිසිම දූෂණයක් නැහැ. ඔවුන්ට එය විමසීමට ඉඩ දෙන්න, සත්‍යය එළියට එනු ඇත."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "CBI",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මොහොමඩ් ෆයිසාල්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "CBI",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ෆයිසාල්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "අබ්දුල් රසාක්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "වෙළඳුන් ආනයනකරු",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "අපනයනකරු",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "CBI",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "25 ක් පමණ",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ලක්ෂද්වීපය",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "ලක්ෂද්වීපය",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "අලෙවිකරණ සම්මේලනය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ධීවර දෙපාර්තමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "පොදු වැඩ දෙපාර්තමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Khadi මණ්ඩලය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "සමුපකාර සමිතිය සහ සත්ව පාලන දෙපාර්තමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "CBI",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "LCMF",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "CBI",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ෆයිසාල්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "CBI",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "CBI",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ෆයිසාල්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "SRT",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දියන් එක්ස්ප්‍රස්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ෆයිසාල්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "CBI",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "SRT",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ලංකා",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "තූතුකුඩි",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "250",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "තූතුකුඩි",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "சூரை மீன் ஏற்றுமதி ஊழல்: லட்சத்தீவு எம்.பி., அவரது மருமகன் சி.பி.ஐ",
      "author": "",
      "body_lines": [
        "இலங்கைக்கு சூரை மீன் ஏற்றுமதி செய்ததில் முறைகேடுகள் நடந்ததாகக் கூறப்படும் வழக்கில் இந்தியாவின் லட்சத்தீவு நாடாளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர் முகமது பைசல் சிபிஐ விசாரணையின் கீழ் வந்துள்ளார்.",
        "மத்திய ஏஜென்சி பைசலின் மருமகன் அப்துல் ரசாக் மற்றும் SRT ஜெனரல் மெர்ச்சண்ட்ஸ் இறக்குமதி மற்றும் ஏற்றுமதியாளர் என அடையாளம் காணப்பட்ட கொழும்பை தளமாகக் கொண்ட நிறுவனம் மீதும் விசாரணை நடத்தி வருகிறது.",
        "சுமார் 25 அதிகாரிகள் கொண்ட சிபிஐ குழுவும், லட்சத்தீவு நிர்வாகத்தின் விஜிலென்ஸ் அதிகாரிகளும் லட்சத்தீவு நிர்வாகத்தின் பல்வேறு துறைகளில் ‘கூட்டு திடீர் சோதனை’ நடத்தும் பணியில் ஈடுபட்டுள்ளனர். இந்தத் துறைகளில் லட்சத்தீவு கூட்டுறவு விற்பனை கூட்டமைப்பு (LCMF), மீன்வளத் துறை, பொதுப்பணித் துறை, காதி வாரியம் மற்றும் கூட்டுறவு சங்கம் மற்றும் கால்நடை பராமரிப்புத் துறை ஆகியவை அடங்கும்.",
        "சிபிஐயின் கூற்றுப்படி, LCMF இன் சில பொது ஊழியர்கள், சில பொது பிரதிநிதிகள் மற்றும் அரசு ஊழியர்களுடன் கூட்டு சேர்ந்து, SRT பொது வணிகர்களுக்கு டுனா மீன்களை ஏற்றுமதி செய்த விவகாரத்தில், தேவையான டெண்டர் செயல்முறை மற்றும் பிற சம்பிரதாயங்களைப் பின்பற்றாமல் LCMF க்கு நஷ்டத்தை ஏற்படுத்தினர்.",
        "எம்பி பைசலின் செல்வாக்கைப் பயன்படுத்தி உள்ளூர் மீனவர்களிடமிருந்து எல்சிஎம்எஃப் அதிக அளவு சூரை மீன்களை வாங்கியதாக சிபிஐ குற்றம் சாட்டியது. இவ்வாறு கொள்முதல் செய்யப்பட்ட சூரை மீன் LCMF ஆல் எஸ்ஆர்டி ஜெனரல் மெர்ச்சண்ட்ஸ் நிறுவனத்திற்கு ஏற்றுமதி செய்யப்பட்டது, ஆனால் நிறுவனம் பணம் செலுத்தவில்லை என்று சிபிஐ தெரிவித்துள்ளது. சிபிஐ ஆதாரங்களின்படி, ஃபைசலின் மருமகன் ரசாக் எஸ்ஆர்டியின் அலுவலக அதிகாரி.",
        "தி இந்தியன் எக்ஸ்பிரஸ்ஸிடம் பேசிய பைசல் கூறினார்: “எனக்குத் தெரியாது, உண்மையில் (சிபிஐ விசாரணை பற்றி)… வாங்குபவர்கள் நல்ல விலையை வழங்கியதால், மீன் SRT க்கு விற்கப்பட்டது… (கூட்டுறவு சந்தைப்படுத்தல்)  கூட்டமைப்பு இலங்கையில் ஒரு வாங்குபவரை அடையாளம் கண்டுள்ளது. மேலும் அவர் நல்ல மதிப்பீட்டாளர்களை வழங்கினார். ஆனால் தூத்துக்குடி இடைத்தரகர்களின் சில தலையீட்டால் வாங்குபவர் பின்னர் பின்வாங்கினார். இதனால், 250 மெட்ரிக் டன் மீன்கள் கூட்டமைப்பிடம் அப்புறப்படுத்த விடப்பட்டன. அப்போது, ​​உள்ளூர் ஏலம் விடப்பட்டு, தூத்துக்குடி இடைத்தரகர்கள் வாங்கினர். இதில் ஊழல் இல்லை. அவர்கள் விசாரிக்கட்டும், உண்மை வெளிவரும்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "சிபிஐ",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "இந்தியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "முகமது பைசல்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "சிபிஐ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பைசல்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "அப்துல் ரசாக்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "வணிகர்கள் இறக்குமதியாளர்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஏற்றுமதியாளர்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "சிபிஐ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "சுமார் 25",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "லட்சத்தீவு",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "லட்சத்தீவு",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "சந்தைப்படுத்தல் கூட்டமைப்பு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "மீன்வளத் துறை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "பொதுப்பணித்துறை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "காதி வாரியம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "கூட்டுறவு சங்கம் மற்றும் கால்நடை பராமரிப்பு துறை",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "சிபிஐ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "LCMF",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "சிபிஐ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "பைசல்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "சிபிஐ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "சிபிஐ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "பைசல்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "SRT",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இந்தியன் எக்ஸ்பிரஸ்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "பைசல்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "சிபிஐ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "SRT",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "தூத்துக்குடி",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "250",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "தூத்துக்குடி",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  },
  "title": "Tuna export scam: Lakshadweep MP, his nephew under CBI scanner",
  "body_lines": [
    "India's Lakshadweep MP Mohammed Faizal has come under the CBI scanner in connection with alleged irregularities in the export of tuna fish to Sri Lanka.",
    "The central agency is also investigating Faizal’s nephew Abdul Razzak and a Colombo-based company identified as SRT General Merchants Importer and Exporter.",
    "A CBI team of about 25 officials and the Lakshadweep administration’s vigilance officials have been engaged in conducting a ‘joint surprise check’ exercise on different departments of the Lakshadweep administration. These departments include the Lakshadweep Co-operative Marketing Federation (LCMF), the Fisheries Department, the Public Works Department, the Khadi Board and the Cooperative Society and Animal Husbandry Department.",
    "According to the CBI, some public servants of the LCMF, in collusion with some public representatives and government servants, caused loss to the LCMF in the matter of the export of tuna fish to SRT General Merchants without following the requisite tender process and other formalities.",
    "The CBI alleged that the LCMF procured a large amount of tuna fish from local fishermen using MP Faizal’s influence. The tuna fish procured in this manner was exported by the LCMF to SRT General Merchants, but the company did not make payments, the CBI said. According CBI sources, Faizal’s nephew Razzak is an office bearer of SRT.",
    "Speaking to The Indian Express, Faizal said: “I don’t know, really (about the CBI probe)… The fish was sold to SRT as the buyers had offered very good price… The (cooperative marketing)  federation identified a buyer in Lanka and he offered very good raters. But the buyer backed out later due to some intervention by Thoothukudi middlemen. As a result, 250 MT fish was left with the federation to dispose of. Then, there was a local auction and Thoothukudi middlemen bought it. There is no corruption in it. Let them enquire it, the truth will come out.”"
  ],
  "translate": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Tuna export scam: Lakshadweep MP, his nephew under CBI scanner",
      "author": "",
      "body_lines": [
        "India's Lakshadweep MP Mohammed Faizal has come under the CBI scanner in connection with alleged irregularities in the export of tuna fish to Sri Lanka.",
        "The central agency is also investigating Faizal’s nephew Abdul Razzak and a Colombo-based company identified as SRT General Merchants Importer and Exporter.",
        "A CBI team of about 25 officials and the Lakshadweep administration’s vigilance officials have been engaged in conducting a ‘joint surprise check’ exercise on different departments of the Lakshadweep administration. These departments include the Lakshadweep Co-operative Marketing Federation (LCMF), the Fisheries Department, the Public Works Department, the Khadi Board and the Cooperative Society and Animal Husbandry Department.",
        "According to the CBI, some public servants of the LCMF, in collusion with some public representatives and government servants, caused loss to the LCMF in the matter of the export of tuna fish to SRT General Merchants without following the requisite tender process and other formalities.",
        "The CBI alleged that the LCMF procured a large amount of tuna fish from local fishermen using MP Faizal’s influence. The tuna fish procured in this manner was exported by the LCMF to SRT General Merchants, but the company did not make payments, the CBI said. According CBI sources, Faizal’s nephew Razzak is an office bearer of SRT.",
        "Speaking to The Indian Express, Faizal said: “I don’t know, really (about the CBI probe)… The fish was sold to SRT as the buyers had offered very good price… The (cooperative marketing)  federation identified a buyer in Lanka and he offered very good raters. But the buyer backed out later due to some intervention by Thoothukudi middlemen. As a result, 250 MT fish was left with the federation to dispose of. Then, there was a local auction and Thoothukudi middlemen bought it. There is no corruption in it. Let them enquire it, the truth will come out.”"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "CBI",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "India",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Mohammed Faizal",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "CBI",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Faizal",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Abdul Razzak",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Merchants Importer",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Exporter",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "CBI",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "about 25",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Lakshadweep",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "Lakshadweep",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "Marketing Federation",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Fisheries Department",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Public Works Department",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Khadi Board",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Cooperative Society and Animal Husbandry Department",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "CBI",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "LCMF",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "CBI",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Faizal",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "CBI",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "CBI",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Faizal",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "SRT",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "The Indian Express",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Faizal",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "CBI",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "SRT",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Thoothukudi",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "250",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Thoothukudi",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "ටූනා අපනයන වංචාව: CBI ස්කෑනරය යටතේ ඔහුගේ බෑණනුවන් වන ලක්ෂද්වීප් මන්ත්‍රී",
      "author": "",
      "body_lines": [
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවට ටූනා මත්ස්‍ය අපනයනයේදී සිදුවූ බව කියන අක්‍රමිකතා සම්බන්ධයෙන් ඉන්දියාවේ ලක්ෂද්වීප් පාර්ලිමේන්තු මන්ත්‍රී මොහොමඩ් ෆයිසාල් CBI ස්කෑනර් පරීක්ෂණයකට ලක්ව තිබේ.",
        "මධ්‍යම ඒජන්සිය ෆයිසාල්ගේ බෑණනුවන් වන අබ්දුල් රසාක් සහ SRT General Merchants Importer and Exporter ලෙස හඳුනාගෙන ඇති කොළඹ පදනම් කරගත් සමාගමක් පිළිබඳවද විමර්ශනය කරයි.",
        "නිලධාරීන් 25 දෙනෙකුගෙන් පමණ සමන්විත CBI කණ්ඩායමක් සහ ලක්ෂද්වීප් පරිපාලනයේ සුපරීක්ෂාකාරී නිලධාරීන් ලක්ෂද්වීප් පරිපාලනයේ විවිධ දෙපාර්තමේන්තු වල 'ඒකාබද්ධ විස්මිත පරීක්ෂාව' අභ්‍යාසයක නිරත වී ඇත. මෙම දෙපාර්තමේන්තු වලට ලක්ෂද්වීප් සමුපකාර අලෙවි සම්මේලනය (LCMF), ධීවර දෙපාර්තමේන්තුව, පොදු වැඩ දෙපාර්තමේන්තුව, Khadi මණ්ඩලය සහ සමුපකාර සමිතිය සහ සත්ව පාලන දෙපාර්තමේන්තුව ඇතුළත් වේ.",
        "CBI ට අනුව, LCMF හි සමහර රාජ්‍ය සේවකයින්, සමහර මහජන නියෝජිතයින් සහ රජයේ සේවකයින් සමඟ හවුල් වී, අවශ්‍ය ටෙන්ඩර් ක්‍රියාවලිය සහ අනෙකුත් විධිවිධාන අනුගමනය නොකර SRT General Merchants වෙත ටූනා මාළු අපනයනය කිරීමේ කාරණයේදී LCMF වෙත පාඩුවක් සිදු කර ඇත.",
        "ෆයිසාල් මන්ත්‍රීවරයාගේ බලපෑමෙන් දේශීය ධීවරයින්ගෙන් එල්සීඑම්එෆ් විශාල ටූනා මසුන් සපයා ගත් බවට CBI චෝදනා කළේය. මෙලෙස සපයාගත් ටූනා මාළු LCMF ආයතනය විසින් SRT General Merchants වෙත අපනයනය කර ඇතත් එම සමාගම මුදල් ගෙවා නොමැති බව CBI පවසයි. CBI මූලාශ්‍රවලට අනුව, ෆයිසාල්ගේ බෑණනුවන් වන රසාක් SRT හි නිලධාරියෙකි.",
        "The Indian Express වෙත අදහස් දක්වමින් ෆයිසාල් මෙසේ පැවසීය: “ඇත්තටම (CBI පරීක්ෂණය ගැන) මම දන්නේ නැහැ... ගැනුම්කරුවන් ඉතා හොඳ මිලක් ලබා දුන් නිසා මාළු SRT වෙත විකුණුවා... (සමුපකාර අලෙවිකරණ)  සම්මේලනය ලංකාවේ ගැණුම්කරුවෙකු හඳුනා ගත්තා. ඔහු ඉතා හොඳ ශ්‍රේණිගත කරන්නන් ඉදිරිපත් කළේය. නමුත් තූත්තුකුඩි අතරමැදියන්ගේ යම් මැදිහත් වීමක් මත ගැනුම්කරු පසුව පසුබැස්සේය. එහි ප්‍රතිඵලයක් ලෙස මත්ස්‍ය මෙට්‍රික් ටොන් 250ක් බැහැර කිරීමට සම්මේලනයට ඉතිරි විය. ඉන්පසුව දේශීය වෙන්දේසියක් පැවති අතර තූතුකුඩි අතරමැදියන් එය මිලදී ගෙන ඇත. එහි කිසිම දූෂණයක් නැහැ. ඔවුන්ට එය විමසීමට ඉඩ දෙන්න, සත්‍යය එළියට එනු ඇත."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "CBI",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මොහොමඩ් ෆයිසාල්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "CBI",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ෆයිසාල්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "අබ්දුල් රසාක්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "වෙළඳුන් ආනයනකරු",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "අපනයනකරු",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "CBI",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "25 ක් පමණ",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ලක්ෂද්වීපය",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "ලක්ෂද්වීපය",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "අලෙවිකරණ සම්මේලනය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ධීවර දෙපාර්තමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "පොදු වැඩ දෙපාර්තමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Khadi මණ්ඩලය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "සමුපකාර සමිතිය සහ සත්ව පාලන දෙපාර්තමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "CBI",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "LCMF",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "CBI",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ෆයිසාල්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "CBI",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "CBI",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ෆයිසාල්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "SRT",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දියන් එක්ස්ප්‍රස්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ෆයිසාල්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "CBI",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "SRT",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ලංකා",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "තූතුකුඩි",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "250",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "තූතුකුඩි",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "சூரை மீன் ஏற்றுமதி ஊழல்: லட்சத்தீவு எம்.பி., அவரது மருமகன் சி.பி.ஐ",
      "author": "",
      "body_lines": [
        "இலங்கைக்கு சூரை மீன் ஏற்றுமதி செய்ததில் முறைகேடுகள் நடந்ததாகக் கூறப்படும் வழக்கில் இந்தியாவின் லட்சத்தீவு நாடாளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர் முகமது பைசல் சிபிஐ விசாரணையின் கீழ் வந்துள்ளார்.",
        "மத்திய ஏஜென்சி பைசலின் மருமகன் அப்துல் ரசாக் மற்றும் SRT ஜெனரல் மெர்ச்சண்ட்ஸ் இறக்குமதி மற்றும் ஏற்றுமதியாளர் என அடையாளம் காணப்பட்ட கொழும்பை தளமாகக் கொண்ட நிறுவனம் மீதும் விசாரணை நடத்தி வருகிறது.",
        "சுமார் 25 அதிகாரிகள் கொண்ட சிபிஐ குழுவும், லட்சத்தீவு நிர்வாகத்தின் விஜிலென்ஸ் அதிகாரிகளும் லட்சத்தீவு நிர்வாகத்தின் பல்வேறு துறைகளில் ‘கூட்டு திடீர் சோதனை’ நடத்தும் பணியில் ஈடுபட்டுள்ளனர். இந்தத் துறைகளில் லட்சத்தீவு கூட்டுறவு விற்பனை கூட்டமைப்பு (LCMF), மீன்வளத் துறை, பொதுப்பணித் துறை, காதி வாரியம் மற்றும் கூட்டுறவு சங்கம் மற்றும் கால்நடை பராமரிப்புத் துறை ஆகியவை அடங்கும்.",
        "சிபிஐயின் கூற்றுப்படி, LCMF இன் சில பொது ஊழியர்கள், சில பொது பிரதிநிதிகள் மற்றும் அரசு ஊழியர்களுடன் கூட்டு சேர்ந்து, SRT பொது வணிகர்களுக்கு டுனா மீன்களை ஏற்றுமதி செய்த விவகாரத்தில், தேவையான டெண்டர் செயல்முறை மற்றும் பிற சம்பிரதாயங்களைப் பின்பற்றாமல் LCMF க்கு நஷ்டத்தை ஏற்படுத்தினர்.",
        "எம்பி பைசலின் செல்வாக்கைப் பயன்படுத்தி உள்ளூர் மீனவர்களிடமிருந்து எல்சிஎம்எஃப் அதிக அளவு சூரை மீன்களை வாங்கியதாக சிபிஐ குற்றம் சாட்டியது. இவ்வாறு கொள்முதல் செய்யப்பட்ட சூரை மீன் LCMF ஆல் எஸ்ஆர்டி ஜெனரல் மெர்ச்சண்ட்ஸ் நிறுவனத்திற்கு ஏற்றுமதி செய்யப்பட்டது, ஆனால் நிறுவனம் பணம் செலுத்தவில்லை என்று சிபிஐ தெரிவித்துள்ளது. சிபிஐ ஆதாரங்களின்படி, ஃபைசலின் மருமகன் ரசாக் எஸ்ஆர்டியின் அலுவலக அதிகாரி.",
        "தி இந்தியன் எக்ஸ்பிரஸ்ஸிடம் பேசிய பைசல் கூறினார்: “எனக்குத் தெரியாது, உண்மையில் (சிபிஐ விசாரணை பற்றி)… வாங்குபவர்கள் நல்ல விலையை வழங்கியதால், மீன் SRT க்கு விற்கப்பட்டது… (கூட்டுறவு சந்தைப்படுத்தல்)  கூட்டமைப்பு இலங்கையில் ஒரு வாங்குபவரை அடையாளம் கண்டுள்ளது. மேலும் அவர் நல்ல மதிப்பீட்டாளர்களை வழங்கினார். ஆனால் தூத்துக்குடி இடைத்தரகர்களின் சில தலையீட்டால் வாங்குபவர் பின்னர் பின்வாங்கினார். இதனால், 250 மெட்ரிக் டன் மீன்கள் கூட்டமைப்பிடம் அப்புறப்படுத்த விடப்பட்டன. அப்போது, ​​உள்ளூர் ஏலம் விடப்பட்டு, தூத்துக்குடி இடைத்தரகர்கள் வாங்கினர். இதில் ஊழல் இல்லை. அவர்கள் விசாரிக்கட்டும், உண்மை வெளிவரும்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "சிபிஐ",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "இந்தியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "முகமது பைசல்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "சிபிஐ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பைசல்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "அப்துல் ரசாக்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "வணிகர்கள் இறக்குமதியாளர்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஏற்றுமதியாளர்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "சிபிஐ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "சுமார் 25",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "லட்சத்தீவு",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "லட்சத்தீவு",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "சந்தைப்படுத்தல் கூட்டமைப்பு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "மீன்வளத் துறை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "பொதுப்பணித்துறை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "காதி வாரியம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "கூட்டுறவு சங்கம் மற்றும் கால்நடை பராமரிப்பு துறை",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "சிபிஐ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "LCMF",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "சிபிஐ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "பைசல்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "சிபிஐ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "சிபிஐ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "பைசல்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "SRT",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இந்தியன் எக்ஸ்பிரஸ்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "பைசல்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "சிபிஐ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "SRT",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "தூத்துக்குடி",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "250",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "தூத்துக்குடி",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}