{
  "newspaper_id": "virakesari-lk",
  "url": "http://www.virakesari.lk/article/132048",
  "time_ut": 1658489740,
  "original_lang": "ta",
  "original_title": "காலிமுகத்திடல் போராட்டகார்கள் மீது அடக்குமுறை : யாழில் போராட்டத்திற்கு அழைப்பு",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Crackdown on eviction protesters: Call for protests in Yall",
      "author": "Vishnu",
      "body_lines": [
        "A protest protest has been called for Saturday 23rd tomorrow in Jaffna in protest against the attack in Kalimugat.",
        "Ramalingam Chandrasekaran, Jaffna district organizer of People's Liberation Front, said that the protest will be held at Jaffna Central Bus Station tomorrow Saturday at 1 pm under the theme \"We will strongly condemn the barbaric attack of Ranil-Rajapakshas on Golbase protestors\".",
        "In the media conference held today 22nd Friday at Jaffna Media Center",
        "Tamil Social Democratic Party leader Suku Comrade, Northern Regional Coordinator of Electricity Service Union K. Ilangumaran, Nallur Socialist Youth Sang organizer K. Saravanan, Parutthura Socialist Youth Sang organizer S. Ganesaruban Agiyoor attended and gave a call for this protest.",
        "Troops and policemen entered the Kotakokama area of ​​Kalimukhatidal and removed the sheds there and attacked the protesters. So this protest has been called to condemn this attack."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Saturday 23rd tomorrow",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Jaffna",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kalimugat",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Ramalingam Chandrasekaran",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Jaffna",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "People's Liberation Front",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Jaffna Central Bus Station",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "tomorrow",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Saturday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "1 pm",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ranil-Rajapakshas on Golbase",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "today 22nd Friday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Jaffna Media Center",
            "label": "FAC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Tamil Social Democratic Party",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Suku Comrade",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Northern Regional Coordinator of Electricity Service Union K. Ilangumaran",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "K. Saravanan",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Kotakokama",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "නෙරපා හැරීමේ විරෝධතාකරුවන් මර්දනය කිරීම: යාල්හි විරෝධතා සඳහා කැඳවුම්",
      "author": "විෂ්ණු",
      "body_lines": [
        "කාලිමුගට් ප්‍රහාරයට විරෝධය පළ කරමින් හෙට 23 වැනි සෙනසුරාදා යාපනයේදී විරෝධතා උද්ඝෝෂණයක් කැඳවා තිබේ.",
        "\"ගෝල්බේස් විරෝධතාකරුවන්ට රනිල්-රාජපක්ෂලාගේ ම්ලේච්ඡ ප්‍රහාරය අපි තරයේ හෙළා දකිමු\" යන තේමාව යටතේ හෙට සෙනසුරාදා පස්වරු 1 ට යාපනය මධ්‍යම බස් නැවතුම්පොළේදී මෙම විරෝධතාව පැවැත්වෙන බව ජනතා විමුක්ති පෙරමුණේ යාපනය දිස්ත්‍රික් සංවිධායක රාමලිංගම් චන්ද්‍රසේකරන් මහතා පැවසීය.",
        "ඒ අද 22 සිකුරාදා යාපනය මාධ්‍ය මධ්‍යස්ථානයේ පැවති මාධ්‍ය සාකච්ඡාවේදීය",
        "දෙමළ සමාජ ප්‍රජාතන්ත්‍රවාදී පක්ෂයේ නායක සුකු සහෝදරයා, විදුලි සේවා සංගමයේ උතුරු ප්‍රාදේශීය සම්බන්ධීකාරක කේ. ඉලංගුමරන්, නල්ලූර් සමාජවාදී තරුණ සංගමයේ සංවිධායක කේ.සරවනන්, පරුත්තුර සමාජවාදී තරුණ සංගමයේ සංවිධායක එස්. ගනේසරුබන් ආගියූර් යන මහත්වරු සහභාගී වී මෙම විරෝධතාවයට කැඳවීමක් කළහ.",
        "කලිමුඛතිඩාල් ප්‍රදේශයේ කොටකෝකාම ප්‍රදේශයට ඇතුළු වූ භට පිරිස් සහ පොලිස් නිලධාරීන් එහි තිබූ මඩු ඉවත් කර විරෝධතාකරුවන්ට පහර දුන්හ. එබැවින් මෙම ප්‍රහාරය හෙළා දකිමින් මෙම විරෝධතාව කැඳවා තිබේ."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "හෙට 23 සෙනසුරාදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "යාපනය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "කලිමුගට්",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "රාමලිංගම් චන්ද්‍රසේකරන්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "යාපනය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "මහජන විමුක්ති පෙරමුණ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "යාපනය මධ්‍යම බස් නැවතුම්පොළ",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "හෙට",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "සෙනසුරාදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ප.ව",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "රනිල්-රාජපක්ෂලා ගෝල්බස් එකේ",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "අද 22 සිකුරාදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "යාපනය මාධ්‍ය මධ්‍යස්ථානය",
            "label": "FAC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "දෙමළ සමාජ ප්‍රජාතන්ත්‍රවාදී පක්ෂය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "සුකු සහෝදරයා",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "විදුලිබල සේවා සංගමයේ උතුරු ප්‍රාදේශීය සම්බන්ධීකාරක කේ. ඉලංගුමරන්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "කේ.සරවනන්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "කොටකොකාම",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "காலிமுகத்திடல் போராட்டகார்கள் மீது அடக்குமுறை : யாழில் போராட்டத்திற்கு அழைப்பு",
      "author": "Vishnu",
      "body_lines": [
        "காலிமுகத்திடலில் இடம்பெற்ற தாக்குதலுக்கு எதிர்ப்பு தெரிவித்து யாழ்ப்பாணத்தில் நாளை 23 ஆம் திகதி சனிக்கிழமை கண்டன போராட்டமொன்றுக்கு அழைப்பு விடுக்கப்பட்டுள்ளது.",
        "\"கோல்பேஸ் போராட்டகாரர்கள் மீதான ரணில் - ராஜபக்ஷாக்களின் காட்டுமிராண்டித்தனமான தாக்குதலை வன்மையாக கண்டிப்போம்\" எனும் தொனிப்பொருளில் யாழ்ப்பாணம் மத்திய பேருந்து நிலையத்தில் நாளை சனிக்கிழமை  மதியம் ஒரு மணிக்கு இந்த போராட்டம் இடம்பெறுமென மக்கள் விடுதலை முன்னணியின் யாழ் மாவட்ட அமைப்பாளர் இராமலிங்கம் சந்திரசேகரன் தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "யாழ் ஊடக அமையத்தில் இன்று 22 ஆம் திகதி வெள்ளிக்கிழமை  இடம்பெற்ற ஊடக சந்திப்பில்",
        "தமிழர் சமூக ஜனநாயக கட்சியின்   தலைவர் சுகு தோழர், மின்சார சேவைச் சங்கத்தின் வடமாகாண இணைப்பாளர் க.இளங்குமரன், நல்லூர் சோசலிச இளைஞர் சங்க அமைப்பாளர் கே.சரவணன், பருத்தித்துறை சோசலிச இளைஞர் சங்க அமைப்பாளர் ச.கணேசரூபன் ஆகியோர் கலந்து கொண்டு இந்த போராட்டத்திற்கான அழைப்பை விடுத்தனர்.",
        "காலிமுகத்திடல் கோட்டாகோகம பகுதிக்குள்  நுழைந்த முப்படையினர் மற்றும் பொலிஸார் அங்கிருக்கும் கொட்டகைகளை அகற்றியதுடன் போராட்டகாரர்களும் தாக்கப்பட்டனர். ஆகவே இந்த தாக்குதலை கண்டிக்கும் வகையிலேயே இந்த போராட்டத்திற்கு அழைப்பு விடுக்கப்பட்டுள்ளது."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "நாளை 23ஆம் தேதி சனிக்கிழமை",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "யாழ்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "காலிமுகத்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ராமலிங்கம் சந்திரசேகரன்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "யாழ்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "மக்கள் விடுதலை முன்னணி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "யாழ்ப்பாணம் மத்திய பேருந்து நிலையம்",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "நாளை",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சனிக்கிழமை",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "மதியம் 1 மணி",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "கோல்பேஸில் ரணில்-ராஜபக்ஷ",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இன்று 22 வெள்ளிக்கிழமை",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "யாழ் ஊடக மையம்",
            "label": "FAC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "தமிழ் சமூக ஜனநாயக கட்சி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "சுகு தோழர்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "மின்சார சேவை சங்கத்தின் வடக்கு பிராந்திய இணைப்பாளர் கே.இளங்குமரன்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "கே.சரவணன்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "கொட்டகோகம",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}