{
  "newspaper_id": "ada-lk",
  "url": "https://www.ada.lk/breaking_news/ජනපතිගේ-විශේෂ-නියෝජිතයා-ලෙස-පරිසර-ඇමති-සෞදි-අරාබියට/11-395030",
  "time_ut": 1656736215,
  "original_lang": "si",
  "original_title": "ජනපතිගේ විශේෂ නියෝජිතයා ලෙස පරිසර ඇමති සෞදි අරාබියට",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Environment Minister to Saudi Arabia as the special representative of the President",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "As a special representative of President Gotabhaya Rajapaksa, Environment Minister Nasir Ahmed is scheduled to leave for Saudi Arabia today (02). He is scheduled to visit Saudi Arabia until the 5th.",
        "Abdullah A.A., Officer-in-Charge of the Embassy of Saudi Arabia in Sri Lanka. Mr. Orkobi, Minister of Foreign Affairs Prof. G.L. These facts were revealed when Mr. Peiris met.",
        "In this meeting, he explained the current economic situation including the fuel crisis in Sri Lanka and the negative impact it has on all sectors of Sri Lanka.",
        "The Minister also insists that it is an extremely urgent matter to provide ways for energy cooperation with the Kingdom of Saudi Arabia.",
        "Also, Environment Minister Naseer Ahmed asked the officer in charge to provide facilities for his ongoing visit to Saudi Arabia.",
        "Abdullah A.A., the officer in charge of the Saudi Embassy, ​​emphasized on the importance of the bilateral relationship between Sri Lanka and Saudi Arabia. Mr. Orkobi assured Sri Lanka of all possible support in this regard."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Saudi Arabia",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Gotabhaya Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Nasir Ahmed",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Saudi Arabia",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "02",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Saudi Arabia",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "5th",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Abdullah A.A.",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Saudi Arabia",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Orkobi",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Foreign Affairs",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "G.L.",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Peiris",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the Kingdom of Saudi Arabia",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Naseer Ahmed",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Saudi Arabia",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Abdullah A.A.",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Saudi",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Saudi Arabia",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Orkobi",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "ජනපතිගේ විශේෂ නියෝජිතයා ලෙස පරිසර ඇමති සෞදි අරාබියට",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "ජනපති ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ මහතාගේ විශේෂ නියෝජිතයෙක් ලෙස පරිසර අමාත්‍ය නසීර් අහමඩ් මහතා අද (02දා) සෞදි අරාබිය බලා පිටත්ව යාමට නියමිතය. ඔහු එළැඹෙන 05 දා තෙක් සෞදි අරාබියේ සංචාරය කිරීමට නිමිතව තිබේ.",
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ සෞදි අරාබියේ තානාපති කාර්යාලයේ කාර්ය භාර නිලධාරී අබ්දුල්ලා ඒ.ඒ. ඔර්කොබි මහතා විදේශ කටයුතු අමාත්‍ය මහාචාර්ය ජී.එල්. පීරිස් මහතා හමුවූ අවස්ථාවේදී මෙම කරුණු අණාවරණය විය.",
        "මෙම හමුවේ දී, ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ ඉන්ධන අර්බුදය ඇතුළුව වර්තමාන ආර්ථික තත්ත්වය සහ එමඟින් ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ සියලු ක්ෂේත්‍රයන් කෙරෙහි ඇති කෙරෙන ඍණාත්මක බලපෑම පිළිබඳව විස්තර කළේය.",
        "සෞදි අරාබි රාජධානිය සමඟ බලශක්ති සහයෝගීතාව සඳහා මාර්ග සලසා ගැනීම අතිශයින් හදිසි කාරණයක් බවද අමාත්‍යවරයා පැවැසිය.",
        "එසේම පරිසර අමාත්‍ය නසීර් අහමඩ් මහතා සෞදියේ නිරතවන සංචාරය සඳහා පහසුකම් සලසන ලෙසද කාර්ය භාර නිලධාරිවරයාගෙන් ඉල්ලා සිටියේය.",
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකා - සවුදි අරාබියානු ද්විපාර්ශ්වික සබඳතාව හා බැඳුණු වැදගත්කම පිළිබඳව අවධාරණය කළ සවුදි තානාපති කාර්යාලයේ කාර්ය භාර නිලධාරි අබ්දුල්ලා ඒ.ඒ. ඔර්කොබි මහතා, මෙම අවස්ථාවේ දී ශ්‍රී ලංකාවට හැකි සෑම සහයෝගයක්ම ලබා දෙන බවට සහතික විය."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "සවුදි අරාබිය",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "නසීර් අහමඩ්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "සවුදි අරාබිය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "02",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "සවුදි අරාබිය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "5 වැනි",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "අබ්දුල්ලා ඒ.ඒ.",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "සවුදි අරාබිය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඔර්කොබි",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "විදේශ කටයුතු",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජී.එල්.",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "පීරිස්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "සෞදි අරාබියේ රාජධානිය",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "නසීර් අහමඩ්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "සවුදි අරාබිය",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "අබ්දුල්ලා ඒ.ඒ.",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "සෞදි",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "සවුදි අරාබිය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඔර්කොබි",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "ஜனாதிபதியின் சிறப்பு பிரதிநிதியாக சவுதி அரேபியாவிற்கு சுற்றுச்சூழல் அமைச்சர்",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "ஜனாதிபதி கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ஷவின் விசேட பிரதிநிதியாக சுற்றாடல் அமைச்சர் நசீர் அஹமட் இன்று (02) சவூதி அரேபியா செல்லவுள்ளார். அவர் வரும் 5ம் தேதி வரை சவுதி அரேபியா செல்ல உள்ளார்.",
        "இலங்கைக்கான சவூதி அரேபியா தூதரகத்தின் பொறுப்பதிகாரி அப்துல்லா ஏ.ஏ. திரு. ஓர்கோபி, வெளியுறவு அமைச்சர் பேராசிரியர் ஜி.எல். பீரிஸை சந்தித்த போது இந்த உண்மைகள் வெளிப்பட்டன.",
        "இந்தச் சந்திப்பில், இலங்கையில் ஏற்பட்டுள்ள எரிபொருள் நெருக்கடி உள்ளிட்ட தற்போதைய பொருளாதார நிலைமை மற்றும் இலங்கையின் அனைத்துத் துறைகளிலும் அது ஏற்படுத்தும் பாதகமான தாக்கங்கள் குறித்தும் விளக்கமளித்தார்.",
        "சவுதி அரேபியாவுடன் எரிசக்தி ஒத்துழைப்புக்கான வழிகளை வழங்குவது மிகவும் அவசரமான விஷயம் என்றும் அமைச்சர் வலியுறுத்துகிறார்.",
        "மேலும், சுற்றாடல் அமைச்சர் நசீர் அஹமட், தனது சவூதி அரேபியாவிற்கு விஜயம் செய்வதற்கான வசதிகளை ஏற்படுத்தித் தருமாறு பொறுப்பதிகாரியிடம் கேட்டுக்கொண்டார்.",
        "இலங்கைக்கும் சவூதி அரேபியாவுக்கும் இடையிலான இருதரப்பு உறவின் முக்கியத்துவம் குறித்து சவுதி தூதரகத்தின் பொறுப்பதிகாரி அப்துல்லா ஏ.ஏ. திரு. ஓர்கோபி இலங்கைக்கு இந்த விடயத்தில் சாத்தியமான அனைத்து ஆதரவையும் உறுதியளித்தார்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "சவூதி அரேபியா",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "கோத்தபாய ராஜபக்ச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "நசீர் அகமது",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "சவூதி அரேபியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "02",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "சவூதி அரேபியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "5வது",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "அப்துல்லா ஏ.ஏ.",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "சவூதி அரேபியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஓர்கோபி",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "வெளிநாட்டு விவகாரங்கள்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜி.எல்.",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "பீரிஸ்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "சவுதி அரேபியா இராச்சியம்",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "நசீர் அகமது",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "சவூதி அரேபியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "அப்துல்லா ஏ.ஏ.",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "சவுதி",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சவூதி அரேபியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஓர்கோபி",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}