{
  "newspaper_id": "lankadeepa-lk",
  "url": "https://www.lankadeepa.lk/latest_news/‘‘ඇමැතිවරුන්ටත්-නිලධාරින්ටත්-දැක්මක්-නෑ‘‘/1-619150",
  "time_ut": 1662043679,
  "original_lang": "si",
  "original_title": "‘‘ඇමැතිවරුන්ටත් නිලධාරින්ටත් දැක්මක් නෑ‘‘",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "\"Ministers and officers have no vision\"",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "Sri Lanka Ramanya Maha Nikaya Deputy Leader Gatambe Rajopavanaramadhapati Kappetiyagoda Sirivimala Thero said that the ministers do not have proper vision and do not take advice from those who have vision.",
        "There is no order in the work. Messing up all the work. Anunahimi said that problems have arisen in the agriculture sector because people who have knowledge about this and have feelings about this are not consulted.",
        "This was said at the time of the visit of the officials of the All Ceylon Agricultural Consultants Federation regarding the destruction of 3 Yala Maha Kannas due to the problems that have arisen in the current agriculture sector and the proper availability of pesticides and fertilizers."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ramanya",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Maha Nikaya",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sirivimala Thero",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Anunahimi",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the All Ceylon Agricultural Consultants Federation",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "3",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Yala Maha Kannas",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "‘‘ඇමැතිවරුන්ටත් නිලධාරින්ටත් දැක්මක් නෑ‘‘",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "ඇමතිවරුන්ට නිසි දැක්මක් නැති බවත් දැක්මක් ඇති අයගෙන් උපදෙස් නොගන්නා බවත ශ්‍රී ලංකා රාමඤ්ඤ මහා නිකායේ අනු නායක ගැටඹේ රාජෝපවනාරාමාධපති  කැප්පෙටියාගොඩ සිරිවිමල හිමියෝ පැවැසුහ.",
        "කරනවැඩවල පිළිවෙලක් නෑ. සියලු වැඩ අවුල් කරගෙන. මේ ගැන දැනීමක් ඇති මේ ගැන හැගීමක් ඇති මේ සම්බන්දව ඕනකම්ක ඇති අයගෙන් උපදෙස් ගැනිමක් නොකරන නිසා කෘෂිකර්ම කේෂ්ත්‍රෙය් ගැටලු පැන නැගි ඇති බවද අනුනාහිමියෝ පැවැසූහ",
        "වත්මන් කෘෂිකර්ම ක්ෂේත්‍රයේ උද්ගතවි ඇති ගැටලු නිසා යළ මහ කන්න 3 ක් විනාශ විම හා පලිබොධ නාශක හා පොහොර නිසියාකාරව ලබා ගැනිම ඇතුලු කරුණු සම්බන්දව සමස්ථ ලංකා කෘෂිකර්ම උපදේශකවරුන්ගේ සම්මේලනයේ නිලධාරින්   අනු නායකහිමියන් බැහැදැකි අවස්ථාවේදි මේ බව පැවසිය."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "රමන්‍යා",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මහා නිකාය",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "සිරිවිමල හිමි",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "අනුනාහිමි",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "සමස්ත ලංකා කෘෂිකර්ම උපදේශක සම්මේලනය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "3",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "යාල මහා කන්නස්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "\"அமைச்சர்களுக்கும் அதிகாரிகளுக்கும் தொலைநோக்கு பார்வை இல்லை\"",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "அமைச்சர்களுக்கு சரியான பார்வை இல்லை எனவும், பார்வை உள்ளவர்களிடம் ஆலோசனை பெறுவதில்லை எனவும் ஸ்ரீலங்கா ராமன்ய மகா நிகாய பிரதித் தலைவர் கட்டம்பே ராஜோபவனாராமதபதி கப்பெட்டியகொட சிறிவிமல தேரர் தெரிவித்துள்ளார்.",
        "வேலையில் ஒழுங்கு இல்லை. அனைத்து வேலைகளையும் குழப்புகிறது. இதுபற்றி அறிவும் உணர்வும் உள்ளவர்களிடம் கருத்து கேட்காததால் விவசாயத்துறையில் பிரச்னைகள் ஏற்பட்டுள்ளதாக அனுனாஹிமி கூறினார்.",
        "தற்போதைய விவசாயத் துறையில் ஏற்பட்டுள்ள பிரச்சினைகளாலும் பூச்சிக்கொல்லி உரங்கள் உரிய முறையில் கிடைக்காமையாலும் 3 யால மகா கன்னங்கள் அழிவடைந்தமை தொடர்பில் அகில இலங்கை விவசாய ஆலோசகர்கள் சம்மேளன அதிகாரிகள் வருகை தந்த போதே இவ்வாறு தெரிவிக்கப்பட்டது."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரமன்யா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "மகா நிகாயா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "சிறிவிமல தேரர்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "அனுநஹிமி",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "அகில இலங்கை விவசாய ஆலோசகர்கள் கூட்டமைப்பு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "3",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "யால மகா கண்ணாஸ்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}