{
  "newspaper_id": "tamil-mirror-lk",
  "url": "https://www.tamilmirror.lk/செய்திகள்/140க்கும்-அதிகமான-வாக்குகளைப்-பெறுவார்/175-300568",
  "time_ut": 1658035751,
  "original_lang": "ta",
  "original_title": "140க்கும் அதிகமான வாக்குகளைப் பெறுவார்",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "He will get more than 140 votes",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "Former Minister Vajira Abeywardhana has said that the acting President Ranil Wickremesinghe will get more than 140 votes in the presidential election to be held in Parliament.",
        "He said that he is leading discussions with other parties including the Sri Lanka Podujana Peramuna as the United National Party's secretary.",
        "He said that he will get more votes and be elected as the President and take office with the blessings of all.",
        "If Ranil Wickremesinghe is elected as the 9th Executive President of Sri Lanka, he will make Sri Lanka the best country in Asia. He will make it the best country in the world.",
        "He said that because the leader has 50 years of experience in politics, there should be no mistrust and panic on him."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "more than 140",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Vajira Abeywardhana",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "more than 140",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "Podujana Peramuna",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the United National Party's",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "9th",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "Asia",
            "label": "LOC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "50 years",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "ඔහු ඡන්ද 140 කට වඩා ලබා ගනී",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "වැඩබලන ජනාධිපති රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතා පාර්ලිමේන්තුවේදී පැවැත්වෙන ජනාධිපතිවරණයේදී ඡන්ද 140කට වඩා වැඩි ප්‍රමාණයක් ලබාගන්නා බව හිටපු අමාත්‍ය වජිර අබේවර්ධන මහතා පැවසීය.",
        "එක්සත් ජාතික පක්ෂයේ ලේකම්වරයා ලෙස තමන් ශ්‍රී ලංකා පොදුජන පෙරමුණ ඇතුළු අනෙකුත් පක්ෂ සමඟ සාකච්ඡා කරමින් සිටින බවද ඔහු කියා සිටියා.",
        "වැඩි ඡන්ද ප්‍රමාණයක් ලබාගෙන සියලු දෙනාගේම ආශිර්වාදය ඇතිව තමා ජනාධිපතිවරයා ලෙස තේරී පත්වී ධූරයේ වැඩ භාරගන්නා බවද හෙතෙම පැවසීය.",
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ 9 වැනි විධායක ජනාධිපතිවරයා ලෙස රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතා තේරී පත් වුවහොත් ඔහු ශ්‍රී ලංකාව ආසියාවේ හොඳම රට බවට පත් කරනු ඇත. ඔහු එය ලෝකයේ හොඳම රට බවට පත් කරයි.",
        "නායකයාට දේශපාලනයේ වසර 50 ක පළපුරුද්දක් ඇති බැවින් ඔහු කෙරෙහි අවිශ්වාසයක් හෝ කලබලයක් ඇතිකර ගත යුතු නැති බවද ඔහු පැවසීය."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "140 ට වැඩි",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "වජිර අබේවර්ධන",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "140 ට වැඩි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "පොදුජන පෙරමුණ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "එක්සත් ජාතික පක්ෂයේ",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "9 වැනි",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "ආසියාව",
            "label": "LOC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "අවුරුදු 50 යි",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "140க்கும் அதிகமான வாக்குகளைப் பெறுவார்",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "பதில் ஜனாதிபதி ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க பாராளுமன்றத்தில் நடத்தப்படவுள்ள ஜனாதிபதித் தேர்தலில் 140க்கு அதிகமான வாக்குகளைப் பெறுவார் என முன்னாள் அமைச்சர் வஜிர அபேவர்தன தெரிவித்துள்ளார்.",
        "தான் ஐக்கிய தேசியக் கட்சியின் தவிசாளர் என்ற ரீதியில் ஸ்ரீ லங்கா பொதுஜன பெரமுன உள்ளிட்ட ஏனைய கட்சிகளுடன் கலந்துரையாடல்களை முன்னெடுத்து வருவதாகத் தெரிவித்துள்ளார்.",
        "எனவே அதிக  வாக்குகளைப் பெற்று ஜனாதிபதியாக தெரிவு செய்யப்படுவதுடன், சகலரதும் ஆசிர்வாதத்துடன் பதவியேற்பார் என்றார்.",
        "அவ்வாறு ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க  இலங்கையின் 9ஆவது நிறைவேற்றதிகார ஜனாதிபதியாக தெரிவு செய்யப்பட்டால் இலங்கையை ஆசியாவின் அதி சிறந்த நாடாக மாற்றுவார். உலக நாடுகளில் சிறந்த நாடாகவும் மாற்றுவார்.",
        "ஏனெனில் அரசியலில் 50 வருடம் அனுபவம் உள்ள தலைவ.ர் அவர் மீது எவ்வித அவநம்பிக்கயும் பீதியும் கொள்ள கூடாது என்றார்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "140க்கு மேல்",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "வஜிர அபேவர்தன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "140க்கு மேல்",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "பொதுஜன பெரமுன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஐக்கிய தேசியக் கட்சியின்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "9வது",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆசியா",
            "label": "LOC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "50 ஆண்டுகள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}