{
  "newspaper_id": "lankadeepa-lk",
  "url": "https://www.lankadeepa.lk/latest_news/කැසිනෝ-වලට-බදු-ගහනකොට-ධම්මිකට-රිදෙන්නේ-ඇයි-/1-616013",
  "time_ut": 1657193059,
  "original_lang": "si",
  "original_title": "කැසිනෝ වලට බදු ගහනකොට ධම්මිකට රිදෙන්නේ ඇයි?",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Why does taxing casinos hurt arteries?",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "United National Party General Secretary Palitha Range Bandara said why Minister Dhammika Perera has silver when Prime Minister Ranil Wickremesinghe is going to take steps to collect taxes from non-tax paying casino and gambling businessmen.",
        "Mr. Range Bandara said that since Prime Minister Ranil Wickremesinghe, as the Finance Minister, presented a cabinet paper last Monday to update the Casino and Gambling Ordinance to combat the racket carried by casino and gambling businessmen by evading government taxes, Mr. Range Bandara said.",
        "Mr. Range Bandara asked Mr. Dhammika Perera what is the basis for asking Mr. Ranil Wickramasinghe to step down from the position of Finance Minister, less than a week after he was sworn in as the Minister.",
        "The UNP General Secretary mentioned this in a special statement to the media."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "United National Party",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Palitha Range Bandara",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Dhammika Perera",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Range Bandara",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "last Monday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Range Bandara",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Range Bandara",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Dhammika Perera",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickramasinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Finance",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "less than a week",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "UNP General",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "කැසිනෝ වලට බදු ගහනකොට ධම්මිකට රිදෙන්නේ ඇයි?",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "බදු නොගෙවන  කැසිනෝ සහ සූදූ ව්‍යාපාරිකයින්ගෙන්  බදු අයකර ගැනීමට අග්‍රාමාත්‍ය රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතා පියවර ගැනීමට යන විට  අමාත්‍ය ධම්මික පෙරේරා මහතාට රිදී ඇත්තේ මන්දැයි එක්සත් ජාතික පක්ෂ මහ ලේකම්  පාලිත රංගේ බණ්ඩාර මහතා පැවසීය.",
        "කැසිනෝ සහ සූදූ ව්‍යාපාරිකයින් රජයේ බදු ගෙවීම පැහැර හරිමින් ගෙන ගිය ජාවාරම මැඬලීම සඳහා කැසිනෝ සහ සූදූ ආඥා පනත  යාවත්කාලීන කිරීමට අගමැති රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතා මුදල් ඇමතිවරයා වශයෙන්  පසුගිය සඳුදා කැබිනට් පත්‍රිකාවක් ඉදිරිපත් කිරීම නිසා සූදූ සහ කැසිනෝ ව්‍යාපාරිකයින්ට මෙලෙස රිදී තිබෙන බවද   රංගේ බණ්ඩාර මහතා කීය.",
        "ඇමති ධුරයේ දිව්රුම් දී සතියක් යන්නට මත්තෙන් රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතාට මුදල් අමාත්‍ය ධුරයෙන් ඉවත් වන ලෙස පැවසීමට ධම්මික පෙරේරා මහතාට ඇති පදනම කුමක්දැයි විමසූ රංගේ බණ්ඩාර මහතා අගමැතිවරයා රටේ ප්‍රශ්නවලට විසඳුම් ලබා දෙන විට යම් යම් අයගේ යටි බලාපොරොත්තු සුන් වී කොනිත්තන්නට හදන බවද කීය.",
        "මාධ්‍ය හමුවේ විශේෂ ප්‍රකාශයක් කරමින් එජාප මහලේකම්වරයා මේ බව සඳහන් කළේය."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "එක්සත් ජාතික පක්ෂය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාලිත රංගේ බණ්ඩාර",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ධම්මික පෙරේරා",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "රංගේ බණ්ඩාර",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "පසුගිය සඳුදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "රංගේ බණ්ඩාර",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "රංගේ බණ්ඩාර",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ධම්මික පෙරේරා",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "මූල්ය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "සතියකට අඩුයි",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "එජාප ජනරාල්",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "சூதாட்ட விடுதிகளுக்கு வரி விதிப்பது ஏன் தமனிகளை பாதிக்கிறது?",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "வரி செலுத்தாத கசினோ மற்றும் சூதாட்ட வர்த்தகர்களிடம் வரி வசூலிக்க பிரதமர் ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க நடவடிக்கை எடுக்கவுள்ள நிலையில் அமைச்சர் தம்மிக்க பெரேராவிடம் வெள்ளி ஏன் என ஐக்கிய தேசியக் கட்சியின் பொதுச் செயலாளர் பாலித ரங்கே பண்டார தெரிவித்துள்ளார்.",
        "அரசாங்க வரி ஏய்ப்பு செய்து கசினோ மற்றும் சூதாட்ட வர்த்தகர்கள் மேற்கொள்ளும் மோசடிக்கு எதிராக கசினோ மற்றும் சூதாட்ட கட்டளைச் சட்டத்தை புதுப்பிப்பதற்கான அமைச்சரவை பத்திரத்தை பிரதமர் ரணில் விக்ரமசிங்க நிதியமைச்சராக கடந்த திங்கட்கிழமை சமர்ப்பித்ததாக திரு.ரங்கே பண்டார தெரிவித்தார். .",
        "ரணில் விக்ரமசிங்கவை நிதியமைச்சர் பதவியில் இருந்து விலகுமாறு கூறியதன் அடிப்படை என்ன என்று தம்மிக்க பெரேராவிடம் திரு.ரங்கே பண்டார வினவினார்.",
        "ஐக்கிய தேசியக் கட்சியின் பொதுச் செயலாளர் ஊடகங்களுக்கு வழங்கிய விசேட செவ்வியிலேயே இதனைக் குறிப்பிட்டுள்ளார்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ஐக்கிய தேசிய கட்சி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாலித ரங்கே பண்டார",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "தம்மிக்க பெரேரா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ரங்கே பண்டார",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "கடந்த திங்கட்கிழமை",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரங்கே பண்டார",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ரங்கே பண்டார",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "தம்மிக்க பெரேரா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "நிதி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஒரு வாரத்திற்கும் குறைவாக",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "UNP பொது",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}