{
  "newspaper_id": "colombo-telegraph-com",
  "url": "https://www.colombotelegraph.com/index.php/former-president-sirisena-insinuates-athuraliye-rathana-took-money-from-royal-park-murderers-parents/",
  "time_ut": 1656040497,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Former President Sirisena Insinuates Athuraliye Rathana Took Money From Royal Park Murderer’s Parents",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Former President Sirisena Insinuates Athuraliye Rathana Took Money From Royal Park Murderer’s Parents",
      "body_lines": [
        "Former President Maithripala in a startling revelation informed a television host during a Derana  talkshow recently that state intelligence officials had discovered that the parents of the infamous Royal Park convicted murderer Jude Shramantha Jayamaha had given money to an individual during the period when he had granted a Presidential pardon for the convicted murderer’s release.",
        "Insinuating this claim, former President Maithripala Sirisena said that the probable culprit who would have received the undisclosed sum, could probably be the person who was the chief negotiator and linkman, who approached him with the convicted murderer’s parents seeking the convict Jayamaha’s release.",
        "The former President and now MP Sirisena said that MP Ven. Athuraliye Rathana and the parents of the convicted murderer had met him initially seeking a Presidential pardon for the convicted murderer’s release.",
        "Former President Sirisena said that he didn’t pay much attention to the initial request.",
        "However they continued to visit him and MP Ven. Athuraliye Rathana had only several occasions requested him to exercise the powers vested in him as the President of Sri Lanka and grant them their wish through the means of a Presidential pardon.",
        "“During that period there were several rumours that I had received a large sum of money for granting this pardon. Some said I had received Rs. 50 million, some said Rs. 800 billion and some said Rs.500 billion. I can confirm that I did not receive any money,” the former President Sirisena said.",
        "“I then instructed my state intelligence officials to investigate this matter and they confirmed that the parents of the convicted murderer Jayamaha, had in fact given monies to a person during that period.”",
        "The television host then asked him “Could it be assumed that the person who was keen and who was working hard to ensure that this Presidential pardon was granted, is the person who received this money?”",
        "The former President Sirisena then replied “Yes, you could assume that the person who received this sum was the person who was keen to ensure this request was granted.”",
        "Earlier, the former President Sirisena was accused of an act of callous abuse of his office in granting a Presidential pardon to Jude Shramantha Anthony Jayamaha, breaching all procedures stipulated in the Constitution. This was after he blatantly disregarded the decision made by the panel of Judges after an intense investigation was carried out and a court case was heard in convicting Jayamaha for the now infamous ‘Royal Park Murder’.",
        "On November 11, 2019 Colombo Telegraph reported that the convicted murderer Jayamaha is a distant relative of the former President Sirisena.",
        "Jude Shramantha Anthony Jayamaha is the son of reputed businessman Preethi Jayamaha, the owner of Coronation Bar & Restaurant in Negombo and who also owns several upmarket catering services in Colombo.",
        "Kanthi Jayamaha who is the second wife of Preethi Jayamaha is the step mother of Jude Shramantha Anthony Jayamaha. Kanthi Jayamaha is related to Dudley Sirisena who is the brother of the former President Maithripala Sirisena, through her niece.",
        "The former President Sirisena justifying his decision had stated that he had taken several factors into consideration when granting this pardon.",
        "An issued release stated some of the reasons were that he was of a young age (19), when he did commit this crime and that he had pursued higher education during the time of his incarceration and that he had been rehabilitated.",
        "In 2005, Jude Shramantha Jayamaha murdered the sister of his girlfriend Yvonne Johnson at the Royal Park luxury apartment complex in 2005. He had chased her and physically brutalized her to death, whilst banging her head on the floor with the post mortem report confirming that it had fractured into 64 pieces.",
        "This case reached further attention when it came up for appeal. The Judges taking into account the violent nature of the committed act that led to the victims brutal and gruesome murder, then sentenced the convict Jayamaha to death.",
        "In an emotional open letter written to the President, Caroline Johnson, the sister of the victim wrote: “I cannot begin to understand how a father of two daughters reached the decision to release this monster?”",
        "“She fought for her life, even running from her attacker with broken ankles. I know you didn’t follow due process for this murderer’s release, but did you even take the time to look into this case at all?”",
        "“Your silence on the matter since your speech makes me fear we may never know the truth behind your decision, but you will now be attached to this case forever and for all of the wrong reasons.”"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Sirisena Insinuates",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "Royal Park Murderer’s",
          "label": "FAC"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Maithripala",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Derana",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Royal Park",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "Jude Shramantha Jayamaha",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Maithripala Sirisena",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Jayamaha",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sirisena",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Athuraliye Rathana",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sirisena",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Athuraliye Rathana",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "50 million",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "800 billion",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sirisena",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Jayamaha",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sirisena",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sirisena",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Jude Shramantha Anthony Jayamaha",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Constitution",
            "label": "LAW"
          },
          {
            "text": "Jayamaha",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "November 11, 2019",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Colombo Telegraph",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Jayamaha",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sirisena",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Jude Shramantha Anthony Jayamaha",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Preethi Jayamaha",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Coronation Bar & Restaurant",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Kanthi Jayamaha",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "second",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Preethi Jayamaha",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Jude Shramantha Anthony Jayamaha",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kanthi Jayamaha",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Dudley Sirisena",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Maithripala Sirisena",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sirisena",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "19",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "2005",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Jude Shramantha Jayamaha",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Yvonne Johnson",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Royal Park",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "2005",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "64",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Jayamaha",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Caroline Johnson",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "two",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [],
        []
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "අතුරලියේ රතන රෝයල් පාක් මිනීමරුවාගේ දෙමාපියන්ගෙන් මුදල් ගත් බව හිටපු ජනපති සිරිසේන කියයි",
      "body_lines": [
        "කුප්‍රකට රෝයල් පාක් වරදකරු වූ මිනීමරු ජූඩ් ශ්‍රමන්ත ජයමහගේ මවුපියන් ජනාධිපතිවරණ සමයේදී පුද්ගලයකුට මුදල් ලබාදී ඇති බව රාජ්‍ය බුද්ධි අංශ නිලධාරීන් විසින් අනාවරණය කරගෙන ඇතැයි හිටපු ජනාධිපති මෛත්‍රීපාල පසුගියදා දෙරණ සංවාදයකදී රූපවාහිනී නිවේදිකාවකට විස්මිත හෙළිදරව්වක් කළේය. වරදකරු වූ මිනීමරුවා නිදහස් කිරීම සඳහා සමාව.",
        "මෙම ප්‍රකාශය අවධාරනය කරමින් හිටපු ජනාධිපති මෛත්‍රීපාල සිරිසේන කියා සිටියේ හෙළි නොකළ මුදල ලැබීමට ඉඩ ඇති වැරදිකරු බොහෝ විට වැරදිකරු ජයමහ නිදහස් කරන ලෙස ඉල්ලා මිනීමරුවන්ගේ දෙමාපියන් සමඟ තමා වෙත පැමිණි ප්‍රධාන සාකච්ඡාකරු සහ සම්බන්ධකයා විය හැකි බවයි.",
        "හිටපු ජනාධිපති සහ දැන් මන්ත‍්‍රී සිරිසේන කියා සිටියේ මන්ත‍්‍රී හාමුදුරුවෝ. අතුරලියේ රතන සහ මිනීමරුවාගේ මවුපියන් ඔහුව මුණගැසී ඇත්තේ මුලින් ම ඝාතකයා නිදහස් කරන ලෙස ඉල්ලා ජනාධිපති සමාව ඉල්ලාය.",
        "හිටපු ජනාධිපති සිරිසේන ප්‍රකාශ කළේ මූලික ඉල්ලීම සම්බන්ධයෙන් තමන් වැඩි අවධානයක් යොමු නොකළ බවයි.",
        "කෙසේ වෙතත්, ඔවුන් දිගින් දිගටම උන්වහන්සේ බැහැදැකීමට පැමිණි අතර, පාර්ලිමේන්තු මන්ත්‍රී පූජ්‍ය පූජ්‍ය හිමිපාණන් වහන්සේ බැහැදුටුහ. අතුරලියේ රතන ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ ජනාධිපතිවරයා ලෙස තමාට පැවරී ඇති බලතල ක්‍රියාත්මක කර ජනාධිපති සමාවක් මාර්ගයෙන් ඔවුන්ගේ අපේක්ෂාව ඉටු කරන ලෙස ඔහුගෙන් ඉල්ලා ඇත්තේ අවස්ථා කිහිපයකදී පමණි.",
        "“ඒ කාලය තුළ මට මේ සමාව දීම සඳහා විශාල මුදලක් ලැබුණු බවට කටකතා කිහිපයක්ම පැතිර ගියා. සමහරු කිව්වා මට රු. මිලියන 50ක්, සමහරු කිව්වා රු. බිලියන 800ක්, සමහරු රුපියල් බිලියන 500ක් කිව්වා. මට කිසිම මුදලක් නොලැබුණු බව තහවුරු කරන්න පුළුවන්” යැයි හිටපු ජනාධිපති සිරිසේන මහතා පැවසීය.",
        "\"ඊට පස්සේ මම මගේ රාජ්‍ය බුද්ධි අංශ නිලධාරීන්ට මේ ගැන සොයා බලන ලෙස උපදෙස් දුන්නා. ඔවුන් තහවුරු කළා මිනීමරු ජයමහ නමැති වරදකරුගේ මව්පියන් ඇත්ත වශයෙන්ම එම කාලය තුළ පුද්ගලයෙකුට මුදල් ලබා දී ඇති බව.\"",
        "එවිට රූපවාහිනී නිවේදකයා ඔහුගෙන් ඇසුවේ “මෙම ජනාධිපති සමාව ලබා දීමට උනන්දු වූ සහ වෙහෙස මහන්සි වී වැඩ කරන පුද්ගලයා මෙම මුදල් ලබා ගත් පුද්ගලයා යැයි උපකල්පනය කළ හැකිද?”",
        "එවිට හිටපු ජනාධිපති සිරිසේන පිළිතුරු දුන්නේ, \"ඔව්, ඔබට උපකල්පනය කළ හැක්කේ මෙම මුදල ලැබුණු පුද්ගලයා මෙම ඉල්ලීම ලබා දීම සහතික කිරීමට උනන්දු වූ පුද්ගලයා බවයි.\"",
        "ආණ්ඩුක්‍රම ව්‍යවස්ථාවේ දක්වා ඇති සියලුම ක්‍රියාපටිපාටි උල්ලංඝනය කරමින් ජූඩ් ශ්‍රමන්ත ඇන්තනි ජයමහ මහතාට ජනාධිපති සමාව ලබාදීමේදී තම කාර්යාලය අයුතු ලෙස පරිහරණය කළ බවට හිටපු ජනාධිපති සිරිසේනට මීට පෙර චෝදනා එල්ල විය. ඒ, දැනට කුප්‍රකට ‘රෝයල් පාර්ක් ඝාතනය’ සම්බන්ධයෙන් ජයමහ වරදකරු කිරීමේ නඩුවක් විභාග වෙමින්, දැඩි විමර්ශනයක් සිදු කර, විනිසුරු මඩුල්ල දුන් තීන්දුව ඔහු අමු අමුවේ නොතකා හැරීමෙන් පසුවය.",
        "2019 නොවැම්බර් 11 වැනි දින කලම්බු ටෙලිග්‍රාෆ් වාර්තා කළේ වරදකරු වූ මිනීමරු ජයමහ හිටපු ජනාධිපති සිරිසේනගේ දුරස්ථ ඥාතියෙකු බවයි.",
        "ජූඩ් ශ්‍රමන්ත ඇන්තනි ජයමහ යනු මීගමුවේ කොරොනේෂන් බාර් ඇන්ඩ් රෙස්ටුරන්ට්හි හිමිකරු මෙන්ම කොළඹ ප්‍රධාන පෙළේ ආහාරපාන සේවා කිහිපයක්ද හිමි කීර්තිමත් ව්‍යාපාරික ප්‍රීති ජයමහගේ පුත්‍රයාය.",
        "ප්‍රීති ජයමහගේ දෙවැනි බිරිඳ වන කාන්ති ජයමහ ජූඩ් ශ්‍රමන්ත ඇන්තනි ජයමහගේ සුළු මවයි. කාන්ති ජයමහ හිටපු ජනාධිපති මෛත්‍රීපාල සිරිසේන මහතාගේ සොහොයුරා වන ඩඩ්ලි සිරිසේන මහතාගේ ඥාති සොහොයුරියක් වන්නේ ඇයගේ ලේලිය හරහාය.",
        "හිටපු ජනාධිපති සිරිසේන සිය තීරණය සාධාරණීකරණය කරමින් ප්‍රකාශ කර තිබුණේ මෙම සමාව ලබාදීමේදී කරුණු කිහිපයක් සැලකිල්ලට ගත් බවයි.",
        "නිකුත් කළ නිවේදනයක දැක්වෙන්නේ මෙම අපරාධය සිදු කරන විට ඔහු තරුණ වියේ (19) සිටි බවත් සිරගතව සිටින කාලයේ උසස් අධ්‍යාපනය හැදෑරීමත් පුනරුත්ථාපනය වී තිබීමත් හේතු කිහිපයක් විය.",
        "2005 වසරේ ජූඩ් ශ්‍රමන්ත ජයමහ විසින් සිය පෙම්වතිය වූ ඉවෝන් ජොන්සන්ගේ සොහොයුරිය රෝයල් පාර්ක් සුඛෝපභෝගී නිවාස සංකීර්ණයේදී ඝාතනය කර ඇත. ඔහු ඇය පසුපස හඹා ගොස් ශාරීරිකව අමානුෂික ලෙස පහරදී ඝාතනය කර ඇති අතර පශ්චාත් මරණ පරීක්ෂණ වාර්තාවෙන් ඇයගේ හිස බිමට ගසා ඝාතනය කර ඇත. කෑලි 64කට කැඩිලා තිබුණා.",
        "මෙම නඩුව අභියාචනයට කැඳවූ අවස්ථාවේදී තවදුරටත් අවධානයට ලක්විය. වින්දිතයන් ම්ලේච්ඡ හා බිහිසුණු මිනීමැරුම්වලට තුඩු දුන් එම අපරාධයේ ප්‍රචණ්ඩත්වය සැලකිල්ලට ගත් විනිසුරුවරු පසුව වරදකරු වූ ජයමහට මරණ දඬුවම නියම කළහ.",
        "වින්දිතයාගේ සහෝදරිය වන කැරොලයින් ජොන්සන් ජනාධිපතිවරයාට ලියා ඇති සංවේදී විවෘත ලිපියක මෙසේ ලිවීය: “දියණියන් දෙදෙනෙකුගේ පියෙකු මෙම යක්ෂයා නිදහස් කිරීමට තීරණය කළේ කෙසේදැයි මට තේරුම් ගත නොහැක?”",
        "“ඇය ඇගේ ජීවිතය වෙනුවෙන් සටන් කළාය, ඇගේ ප්‍රහාරකයාගෙන් බිඳුණු වළලුකර සමඟ පවා දිව ගියාය. මෙම මිනීමරුවා නිදහස් කිරීම සඳහා ඔබ නියමිත ක්‍රියා පටිපාටිය අනුගමනය නොකළ බව මම දනිමි, නමුත් මෙම නඩුව ගැන සොයා බැලීමට ඔබ කාලය ගත කළාද?",
        "\"ඔබේ කතාවේ සිට මේ කාරණය සම්බන්ධයෙන් ඔබ නිහඬව සිටීම නිසා ඔබගේ තීරණය පිටුපස ඇති සත්‍යය අප කිසිදා නොදැන සිටිය හැකි යැයි මා බියට පත් කරයි, නමුත් ඔබ දැන් මෙම නඩුවට සදහටම සහ වැරදි හේතු නිසා සම්බන්ධ වනු ඇත.\""
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "සිරිසේන අවවාද කරයි",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "රෝයල් පාක් මිනීමරුවා",
          "label": "FAC"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "මෛත්‍රීපාල",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "දෙරණ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "රාජකීය උද්යානය",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජූඩ් ශ්‍රමන්ත ජයමහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "මෛත්‍රීපාල සිරිසේන",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජයමහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "සිරිසේන",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "අතුරලියේ රතන",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "සිරිසේන",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "අතුරලියේ රතන",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "මිලියන 50 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "බිලියන 800 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "සිරිසේන",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ජයමහ",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "සිරිසේන",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "සිරිසේන",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජූඩ් ශ්‍රමන්ත ඇන්තනි ජයමහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ආණ්ඩුක්රම ව්යවස්ථාව",
            "label": "LAW"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජයමහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "නොවැම්බර් 11, 2019",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "කලම්බු ටෙලිග්‍රාෆ්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජයමහ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "සිරිසේන",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ජූඩ් ශ්‍රමන්ත ඇන්තනි ජයමහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ප්‍රීති ජයමහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "කිරීටක බාර් සහ ආපන ශාලාව",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "කාන්ති ජයමහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "දෙවැනි",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ප්‍රීති ජයමහ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජූඩ් ශ්‍රමන්ත ඇන්තනි ජයමහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "කාන්ති ජයමහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඩඩ්ලි සිරිසේන",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "මෛත්‍රීපාල සිරිසේන",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "සිරිසේන",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "19",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "2005",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජූඩ් ශ්‍රමන්ත ජයමහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉවෝන් ජොන්සන්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "රාජකීය උද්යානය",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "2005",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "64",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ජයමහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "කැරොලයින් ජොන්සන්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "දෙක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [],
        []
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "றோயல் பார்க் கொலையாளியின் பெற்றோரிடம் இருந்து பணம் பெற்றதாக அத்துரலியே ரத்தனாவை முன்னாள் ஜனாதிபதி சிறிசேன வலியுறுத்தியுள்ளார்.",
      "body_lines": [
        "பிரபல ரோயல் பார்க் குற்றவாளியான ஜூட் ஷ்ரமந்த ஜயமஹாவின் பெற்றோர் ஜனாதிபதி பதவி வழங்கிய காலப்பகுதியில் தனிநபர் ஒருவருக்கு பணம் வழங்கியதை அரச புலனாய்வு அதிகாரிகள் கண்டுபிடித்துள்ளதாக அண்மையில் தெரனா பேச்சுவார்த்தையின் போது முன்னாள் ஜனாதிபதி மைத்திரிபால ஒரு திடுக்கிடும் தகவலை வெளியிட்டார். கொலைக் குற்றவாளியின் விடுதலைக்காக மன்னிப்பு.",
        "இந்தக் கூற்றை வலியுறுத்திய முன்னாள் ஜனாதிபதி மைத்திரிபால சிறிசேன, குற்றவாளி ஜெயமஹாவை விடுதலை செய்யக் கோரி குற்றவாளியின் பெற்றோருடன் தம்மை அணுகிய முக்கியப் பேரம் பேசுபவராகவும், இணைப்பாளராகவும் இருந்த ஒருவரே, வெளிப்படுத்தப்படாத தொகையைப் பெற்றிருக்கக் கூடிய குற்றவாளியாக இருக்கலாம் என்றார்.",
        "முன்னாள் ஜனாதிபதியும் தற்போதைய பாராளுமன்ற உறுப்பினருமான சிறிசேனா, பாராளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர் வண. அத்துரலியே ரத்தின மற்றும் குற்றவாளியின் பெற்றோரும் கொலைக் குற்றவாளியின் விடுதலைக்காக ஜனாதிபதியின் பொது மன்னிப்பு கோரி அவரை முதலில் சந்தித்தனர்.",
        "முதற்கட்ட கோரிக்கைக்கு தான் அதிக கவனம் செலுத்தவில்லை என முன்னாள் அதிபர் சிறிசேனா தெரிவித்துள்ளார்.",
        "எவ்வாறாயினும் அவர்கள் தொடர்ந்து அவரையும், பாராளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர் வண. அத்துரலியே ரத்தன, இலங்கையின் ஜனாதிபதியாக தமக்கு வழங்கப்பட்டுள்ள அதிகாரங்களை பிரயோகித்து ஜனாதிபதியின் மன்னிப்பின் ஊடாக தமது விருப்பத்தை நிறைவேற்றுமாறு பல தடவைகள் கோரியிருந்தார்.",
        "“அந்த காலகட்டத்தில் இந்த மன்னிப்பு வழங்குவதற்காக நான் பெரும் தொகை பெற்றதாக பல வதந்திகள் வந்தன. சிலர் எனக்கு ரூ. 50 மில்லியன், சிலர் ரூ. 800 பில்லியன் என்றும் சிலர் 500 பில்லியன் என்றும் கூறினார்கள். நான் பணம் எதுவும் பெறவில்லை என்பதை என்னால் உறுதிப்படுத்த முடியும்” என முன்னாள் அதிபர் சிறிசேனா கூறினார்.",
        "\"பின்னர் நான் எனது மாநில புலனாய்வு அதிகாரிகளுக்கு இந்த விஷயத்தை விசாரிக்க அறிவுறுத்தினேன், மேலும் குற்றவாளி ஜெயமஹாவின் பெற்றோர் அந்த காலகட்டத்தில் ஒரு நபருக்கு பணம் கொடுத்ததை அவர்கள் உறுதிப்படுத்தினர்.\"",
        "அப்போது தொலைக்காட்சி தொகுப்பாளர் அவரிடம், \"இந்த ஜனாதிபதி மன்னிப்பு வழங்கப்படுவதை உறுதிசெய்ய ஆர்வமாக மற்றும் கடினமாக உழைத்தவர் இந்தப் பணத்தைப் பெற்றவர் என்று கருத முடியுமா?\"",
        "அதற்குப் பதிலளித்த முன்னாள் ஜனாதிபதி சிறிசேன, “ஆம், இந்தத் தொகையைப் பெற்றவர் இந்தக் கோரிக்கையை உறுதிசெய்ய ஆர்வமாக இருந்தவர் என்று நீங்கள் கருதலாம்” என்றார்.",
        "முன்னதாக, அரசியலமைப்பில் குறிப்பிடப்பட்டுள்ள அனைத்து நடைமுறைகளையும் மீறி, ஜூட் ஷ்ரமந்த அந்தோனி ஜயமஹாவுக்கு ஜனாதிபதி பொதுமன்னிப்பு வழங்கியதில் முன்னாள் ஜனாதிபதி சிறிசேன தனது பதவியை துஷ்பிரயோகம் செய்ததாக குற்றம் சாட்டப்பட்டது. இப்போது பிரபலமடைந்த ‘ராயல் பார்க் கொலைக்கு’ ஜெயமஹாவை குற்றவாளியாக்குவதற்கான நீதிமன்ற வழக்கு விசாரணைக்கு உட்படுத்தப்பட்டு, தீவிர விசாரணையின் பின்னர் நீதிபதிகள் குழு எடுத்த முடிவை அவர் அப்பட்டமாகப் புறக்கணித்த பின்னரே இது நடந்தது.",
        "2019 ஆம் ஆண்டு நவம்பர் 11 ஆம் தேதி கொழும்பு டெலிகிராப், குற்றவாளி ஜெயமஹா முன்னாள் ஜனாதிபதி சிறிசேனவின் தூரத்து உறவினர் என்று செய்தி வெளியிட்டது.",
        "ஜூட் ஷ்ரமந்த அந்தோனி ஜயமஹா, நீர்கொழும்பில் உள்ள Coronation Bar & Restaurant இன் உரிமையாளரும், கொழும்பில் பல உயர்மட்ட கேட்டரிங் சேவைகளை வைத்திருக்கும் புகழ்பெற்ற வர்த்தகர் ப்ரீத்தி ஜெயமஹாவின் மகனாவார்.",
        "ப்ரீத்தி ஜயமஹாவின் இரண்டாவது மனைவியான காந்தி ஜயமஹா ஜூட் ஷ்ரமந்த அந்தோனி ஜயமஹாவின் மாற்றாந்தாய் ஆவார். காந்தி ஜயமஹா முன்னாள் ஜனாதிபதி மைத்திரிபால சிறிசேனவின் சகோதரரான டட்லி சிறிசேனவுடன் அவரது மருமகள் ஊடாக உறவினர்.",
        "தனது தீர்மானத்தை நியாயப்படுத்திய முன்னாள் ஜனாதிபதி சிறிசேன, இந்த மன்னிப்பு வழங்கும் போது பல காரணிகளை கவனத்தில் கொண்டதாக குறிப்பிட்டிருந்தார்.",
        "அவர் இந்தக் குற்றத்தைச் செய்தபோது அவர் சிறுவயது (19) என்றும், அவர் சிறையில் இருந்த காலத்தில் உயர் கல்வியைத் தொடர்ந்தார் என்றும், அவர் புனர்வாழ்வளிக்கப்பட்டார் என்றும் சில காரணங்கள் கூறப்பட்டுள்ளன.",
        "2005 ஆம் ஆண்டில், ஜூட் ஷ்ரமந்த ஜெயமஹா தனது காதலியான இவோன் ஜான்சனின் சகோதரியை 2005 ஆம் ஆண்டு ராயல் பார்க் சொகுசு அடுக்குமாடி குடியிருப்பில் கொலை செய்தார். அவர் அவளைத் துரத்திச் சென்று உடல் ரீதியாக கொடூரமாக தாக்கி கொன்றார். 64 துண்டுகளாக உடைந்தது.",
        "இந்த வழக்கு மேல்முறையீட்டுக்கு வந்தபோது மேலும் கவனத்தை ஈர்த்தது. பாதிக்கப்பட்டவர்களை கொடூரமான மற்றும் கொடூரமான கொலைக்கு இட்டுச் சென்ற அந்தச் செயலின் வன்முறைத் தன்மையைக் கருத்தில் கொண்ட நீதிபதிகள், குற்றவாளி ஜெயமஹாவுக்கு மரண தண்டனை விதித்தனர்.",
        "பாதிக்கப்பட்டவரின் சகோதரி கரோலின் ஜான்சனுக்கு ஜனாதிபதிக்கு எழுதிய உணர்ச்சிகரமான திறந்த கடிதத்தில் எழுதினார்: \"இரண்டு மகள்களின் தந்தை எப்படி இந்த அசுரனை விடுவிக்கும் முடிவை எடுத்தார் என்பதை என்னால் புரிந்து கொள்ள முடியவில்லை?\"",
        "\"அவள் தன் உயிருக்குப் போராடினாள், கணுக்கால் உடைந்த நிலையில் தன்னைத் தாக்கியவரிடமிருந்து ஓடி வந்தாள். இந்தக் கொலையாளியின் விடுதலைக்கான சரியான நடைமுறையை நீங்கள் பின்பற்றவில்லை என்பது எனக்குத் தெரியும், ஆனால் இந்த வழக்கை விசாரிக்க நேரம் எடுத்துக் கொண்டீர்களா?",
        "\"உங்கள் பேச்சில் இருந்து இந்த விஷயத்தில் உங்கள் மௌனம் என்னை பயமுறுத்துகிறது, உங்கள் முடிவின் பின்னால் உள்ள உண்மையை நாங்கள் ஒருபோதும் அறிய முடியாது, ஆனால் நீங்கள் இப்போது இந்த வழக்கில் எப்போதும் மற்றும் தவறான காரணங்களுக்காக இணைக்கப்படுவீர்கள்.\""
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "சிறிசேன வலியுறுத்துகிறார்",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "ராயல் பார்க் கொலைகாரன்",
          "label": "FAC"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "மைத்திரிபால",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "தெரனா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ராயல் பார்க்",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜூட் ஷ்ரமந்த ஜெயமஹா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "மைத்திரிபால சிறிசேன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜெயமஹா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "சிறிசேனா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "அதுரலியே ரத்தனா",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "சிறிசேனா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "அதுரலியே ரத்தனா",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "50 மில்லியன்",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "800 பில்லியன்",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "சிறிசேனா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஜெயமஹா",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "சிறிசேனா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "சிறிசேனா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜூட் ஷ்ரமந்த அந்தோனி ஜெயமஹா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "அரசியலமைப்பு",
            "label": "LAW"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜெயமஹா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "நவம்பர் 11, 2019",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "கொழும்பு டெலிகிராப்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜெயமஹா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சிறிசேனா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஜூட் ஷ்ரமந்த அந்தோனி ஜெயமஹா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ப்ரீத்தி ஜயமஹா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "முடிசூட்டு பார் & உணவகம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "காந்தி ஜயமஹா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இரண்டாவது",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ப்ரீத்தி ஜயமஹா",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜூட் ஷ்ரமந்த அந்தோனி ஜெயமஹா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "காந்தி ஜயமஹா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "டட்லி சிறிசேனா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "மைத்திரிபால சிறிசேன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "சிறிசேனா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "19",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "2005",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜூட் ஷ்ரமந்த ஜெயமஹா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இவோன் ஜான்சன்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ராயல் பார்க்",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "2005",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "64",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஜெயமஹா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "கரோலின் ஜான்சன்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இரண்டு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [],
        []
      ]
    }
  },
  "title": "Former President Sirisena Insinuates Athuraliye Rathana Took Money From Royal Park Murderer’s Parents",
  "body_lines": [
    "Former President Maithripala in a startling revelation informed a television host during a Derana  talkshow recently that state intelligence officials had discovered that the parents of the infamous Royal Park convicted murderer Jude Shramantha Jayamaha had given money to an individual during the period when he had granted a Presidential pardon for the convicted murderer’s release.",
    "Insinuating this claim, former President Maithripala Sirisena said that the probable culprit who would have received the undisclosed sum, could probably be the person who was the chief negotiator and linkman, who approached him with the convicted murderer’s parents seeking the convict Jayamaha’s release.",
    "The former President and now MP Sirisena said that MP Ven. Athuraliye Rathana and the parents of the convicted murderer had met him initially seeking a Presidential pardon for the convicted murderer’s release.",
    "Former President Sirisena said that he didn’t pay much attention to the initial request.",
    "However they continued to visit him and MP Ven. Athuraliye Rathana had only several occasions requested him to exercise the powers vested in him as the President of Sri Lanka and grant them their wish through the means of a Presidential pardon.",
    "“During that period there were several rumours that I had received a large sum of money for granting this pardon. Some said I had received Rs. 50 million, some said Rs. 800 billion and some said Rs.500 billion. I can confirm that I did not receive any money,” the former President Sirisena said.",
    "“I then instructed my state intelligence officials to investigate this matter and they confirmed that the parents of the convicted murderer Jayamaha, had in fact given monies to a person during that period.”",
    "The television host then asked him “Could it be assumed that the person who was keen and who was working hard to ensure that this Presidential pardon was granted, is the person who received this money?”",
    "The former President Sirisena then replied “Yes, you could assume that the person who received this sum was the person who was keen to ensure this request was granted.”",
    "Earlier, the former President Sirisena was accused of an act of callous abuse of his office in granting a Presidential pardon to Jude Shramantha Anthony Jayamaha, breaching all procedures stipulated in the Constitution. This was after he blatantly disregarded the decision made by the panel of Judges after an intense investigation was carried out and a court case was heard in convicting Jayamaha for the now infamous ‘Royal Park Murder’.",
    "On November 11, 2019 Colombo Telegraph reported that the convicted murderer Jayamaha is a distant relative of the former President Sirisena.",
    "Jude Shramantha Anthony Jayamaha is the son of reputed businessman Preethi Jayamaha, the owner of Coronation Bar & Restaurant in Negombo and who also owns several upmarket catering services in Colombo.",
    "Kanthi Jayamaha who is the second wife of Preethi Jayamaha is the step mother of Jude Shramantha Anthony Jayamaha. Kanthi Jayamaha is related to Dudley Sirisena who is the brother of the former President Maithripala Sirisena, through her niece.",
    "The former President Sirisena justifying his decision had stated that he had taken several factors into consideration when granting this pardon.",
    "An issued release stated some of the reasons were that he was of a young age (19), when he did commit this crime and that he had pursued higher education during the time of his incarceration and that he had been rehabilitated.",
    "In 2005, Jude Shramantha Jayamaha murdered the sister of his girlfriend Yvonne Johnson at the Royal Park luxury apartment complex in 2005. He had chased her and physically brutalized her to death, whilst banging her head on the floor with the post mortem report confirming that it had fractured into 64 pieces.",
    "This case reached further attention when it came up for appeal. The Judges taking into account the violent nature of the committed act that led to the victims brutal and gruesome murder, then sentenced the convict Jayamaha to death.",
    "In an emotional open letter written to the President, Caroline Johnson, the sister of the victim wrote: “I cannot begin to understand how a father of two daughters reached the decision to release this monster?”",
    "“She fought for her life, even running from her attacker with broken ankles. I know you didn’t follow due process for this murderer’s release, but did you even take the time to look into this case at all?”",
    "“Your silence on the matter since your speech makes me fear we may never know the truth behind your decision, but you will now be attached to this case forever and for all of the wrong reasons.”"
  ],
  "translate": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Former President Sirisena Insinuates Athuraliye Rathana Took Money From Royal Park Murderer’s Parents",
      "body_lines": [
        "Former President Maithripala in a startling revelation informed a television host during a Derana  talkshow recently that state intelligence officials had discovered that the parents of the infamous Royal Park convicted murderer Jude Shramantha Jayamaha had given money to an individual during the period when he had granted a Presidential pardon for the convicted murderer’s release.",
        "Insinuating this claim, former President Maithripala Sirisena said that the probable culprit who would have received the undisclosed sum, could probably be the person who was the chief negotiator and linkman, who approached him with the convicted murderer’s parents seeking the convict Jayamaha’s release.",
        "The former President and now MP Sirisena said that MP Ven. Athuraliye Rathana and the parents of the convicted murderer had met him initially seeking a Presidential pardon for the convicted murderer’s release.",
        "Former President Sirisena said that he didn’t pay much attention to the initial request.",
        "However they continued to visit him and MP Ven. Athuraliye Rathana had only several occasions requested him to exercise the powers vested in him as the President of Sri Lanka and grant them their wish through the means of a Presidential pardon.",
        "“During that period there were several rumours that I had received a large sum of money for granting this pardon. Some said I had received Rs. 50 million, some said Rs. 800 billion and some said Rs.500 billion. I can confirm that I did not receive any money,” the former President Sirisena said.",
        "“I then instructed my state intelligence officials to investigate this matter and they confirmed that the parents of the convicted murderer Jayamaha, had in fact given monies to a person during that period.”",
        "The television host then asked him “Could it be assumed that the person who was keen and who was working hard to ensure that this Presidential pardon was granted, is the person who received this money?”",
        "The former President Sirisena then replied “Yes, you could assume that the person who received this sum was the person who was keen to ensure this request was granted.”",
        "Earlier, the former President Sirisena was accused of an act of callous abuse of his office in granting a Presidential pardon to Jude Shramantha Anthony Jayamaha, breaching all procedures stipulated in the Constitution. This was after he blatantly disregarded the decision made by the panel of Judges after an intense investigation was carried out and a court case was heard in convicting Jayamaha for the now infamous ‘Royal Park Murder’.",
        "On November 11, 2019 Colombo Telegraph reported that the convicted murderer Jayamaha is a distant relative of the former President Sirisena.",
        "Jude Shramantha Anthony Jayamaha is the son of reputed businessman Preethi Jayamaha, the owner of Coronation Bar & Restaurant in Negombo and who also owns several upmarket catering services in Colombo.",
        "Kanthi Jayamaha who is the second wife of Preethi Jayamaha is the step mother of Jude Shramantha Anthony Jayamaha. Kanthi Jayamaha is related to Dudley Sirisena who is the brother of the former President Maithripala Sirisena, through her niece.",
        "The former President Sirisena justifying his decision had stated that he had taken several factors into consideration when granting this pardon.",
        "An issued release stated some of the reasons were that he was of a young age (19), when he did commit this crime and that he had pursued higher education during the time of his incarceration and that he had been rehabilitated.",
        "In 2005, Jude Shramantha Jayamaha murdered the sister of his girlfriend Yvonne Johnson at the Royal Park luxury apartment complex in 2005. He had chased her and physically brutalized her to death, whilst banging her head on the floor with the post mortem report confirming that it had fractured into 64 pieces.",
        "This case reached further attention when it came up for appeal. The Judges taking into account the violent nature of the committed act that led to the victims brutal and gruesome murder, then sentenced the convict Jayamaha to death.",
        "In an emotional open letter written to the President, Caroline Johnson, the sister of the victim wrote: “I cannot begin to understand how a father of two daughters reached the decision to release this monster?”",
        "“She fought for her life, even running from her attacker with broken ankles. I know you didn’t follow due process for this murderer’s release, but did you even take the time to look into this case at all?”",
        "“Your silence on the matter since your speech makes me fear we may never know the truth behind your decision, but you will now be attached to this case forever and for all of the wrong reasons.”"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Sirisena Insinuates",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "Royal Park Murderer’s",
          "label": "FAC"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Maithripala",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Derana",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Royal Park",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "Jude Shramantha Jayamaha",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Maithripala Sirisena",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Jayamaha",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sirisena",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Athuraliye Rathana",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sirisena",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Athuraliye Rathana",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "50 million",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "800 billion",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sirisena",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Jayamaha",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sirisena",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sirisena",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Jude Shramantha Anthony Jayamaha",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Constitution",
            "label": "LAW"
          },
          {
            "text": "Jayamaha",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "November 11, 2019",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Colombo Telegraph",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Jayamaha",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sirisena",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Jude Shramantha Anthony Jayamaha",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Preethi Jayamaha",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Coronation Bar & Restaurant",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Kanthi Jayamaha",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "second",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Preethi Jayamaha",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Jude Shramantha Anthony Jayamaha",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kanthi Jayamaha",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Dudley Sirisena",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Maithripala Sirisena",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sirisena",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "19",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "2005",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Jude Shramantha Jayamaha",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Yvonne Johnson",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Royal Park",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "2005",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "64",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Jayamaha",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Caroline Johnson",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "two",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [],
        []
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "අතුරලියේ රතන රෝයල් පාක් මිනීමරුවාගේ දෙමාපියන්ගෙන් මුදල් ගත් බව හිටපු ජනපති සිරිසේන කියයි",
      "body_lines": [
        "කුප්‍රකට රෝයල් පාක් වරදකරු වූ මිනීමරු ජූඩ් ශ්‍රමන්ත ජයමහගේ මවුපියන් ජනාධිපතිවරණ සමයේදී පුද්ගලයකුට මුදල් ලබාදී ඇති බව රාජ්‍ය බුද්ධි අංශ නිලධාරීන් විසින් අනාවරණය කරගෙන ඇතැයි හිටපු ජනාධිපති මෛත්‍රීපාල පසුගියදා දෙරණ සංවාදයකදී රූපවාහිනී නිවේදිකාවකට විස්මිත හෙළිදරව්වක් කළේය. වරදකරු වූ මිනීමරුවා නිදහස් කිරීම සඳහා සමාව.",
        "මෙම ප්‍රකාශය අවධාරනය කරමින් හිටපු ජනාධිපති මෛත්‍රීපාල සිරිසේන කියා සිටියේ හෙළි නොකළ මුදල ලැබීමට ඉඩ ඇති වැරදිකරු බොහෝ විට වැරදිකරු ජයමහ නිදහස් කරන ලෙස ඉල්ලා මිනීමරුවන්ගේ දෙමාපියන් සමඟ තමා වෙත පැමිණි ප්‍රධාන සාකච්ඡාකරු සහ සම්බන්ධකයා විය හැකි බවයි.",
        "හිටපු ජනාධිපති සහ දැන් මන්ත‍්‍රී සිරිසේන කියා සිටියේ මන්ත‍්‍රී හාමුදුරුවෝ. අතුරලියේ රතන සහ මිනීමරුවාගේ මවුපියන් ඔහුව මුණගැසී ඇත්තේ මුලින් ම ඝාතකයා නිදහස් කරන ලෙස ඉල්ලා ජනාධිපති සමාව ඉල්ලාය.",
        "හිටපු ජනාධිපති සිරිසේන ප්‍රකාශ කළේ මූලික ඉල්ලීම සම්බන්ධයෙන් තමන් වැඩි අවධානයක් යොමු නොකළ බවයි.",
        "කෙසේ වෙතත්, ඔවුන් දිගින් දිගටම උන්වහන්සේ බැහැදැකීමට පැමිණි අතර, පාර්ලිමේන්තු මන්ත්‍රී පූජ්‍ය පූජ්‍ය හිමිපාණන් වහන්සේ බැහැදුටුහ. අතුරලියේ රතන ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ ජනාධිපතිවරයා ලෙස තමාට පැවරී ඇති බලතල ක්‍රියාත්මක කර ජනාධිපති සමාවක් මාර්ගයෙන් ඔවුන්ගේ අපේක්ෂාව ඉටු කරන ලෙස ඔහුගෙන් ඉල්ලා ඇත්තේ අවස්ථා කිහිපයකදී පමණි.",
        "“ඒ කාලය තුළ මට මේ සමාව දීම සඳහා විශාල මුදලක් ලැබුණු බවට කටකතා කිහිපයක්ම පැතිර ගියා. සමහරු කිව්වා මට රු. මිලියන 50ක්, සමහරු කිව්වා රු. බිලියන 800ක්, සමහරු රුපියල් බිලියන 500ක් කිව්වා. මට කිසිම මුදලක් නොලැබුණු බව තහවුරු කරන්න පුළුවන්” යැයි හිටපු ජනාධිපති සිරිසේන මහතා පැවසීය.",
        "\"ඊට පස්සේ මම මගේ රාජ්‍ය බුද්ධි අංශ නිලධාරීන්ට මේ ගැන සොයා බලන ලෙස උපදෙස් දුන්නා. ඔවුන් තහවුරු කළා මිනීමරු ජයමහ නමැති වරදකරුගේ මව්පියන් ඇත්ත වශයෙන්ම එම කාලය තුළ පුද්ගලයෙකුට මුදල් ලබා දී ඇති බව.\"",
        "එවිට රූපවාහිනී නිවේදකයා ඔහුගෙන් ඇසුවේ “මෙම ජනාධිපති සමාව ලබා දීමට උනන්දු වූ සහ වෙහෙස මහන්සි වී වැඩ කරන පුද්ගලයා මෙම මුදල් ලබා ගත් පුද්ගලයා යැයි උපකල්පනය කළ හැකිද?”",
        "එවිට හිටපු ජනාධිපති සිරිසේන පිළිතුරු දුන්නේ, \"ඔව්, ඔබට උපකල්පනය කළ හැක්කේ මෙම මුදල ලැබුණු පුද්ගලයා මෙම ඉල්ලීම ලබා දීම සහතික කිරීමට උනන්දු වූ පුද්ගලයා බවයි.\"",
