{
  "newspaper_id": "economy-next-com",
  "url": "https://economynext.com/sri-lanka-public-health-officials-launch-two-day-protest-over-fuel-shortage-96620/",
  "time_ut": 1656492960,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Sri Lanka public health officials launch two-day protest over fuel shortage",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Sri Lanka public health officials launch two-day protest over fuel shortage",
      "author": "",
      "body_lines": [
        "ECONOMYNEXT – Sri Lanka’s health sector trade unions, led by the Public Health Inspectors’ (PHI) Union, have launched a two-day strike demanding fuel and the raise of a fuel allowance granted to the PHIs, a trade union official said.",
        "Public Health Midwives, Health Entomological Officers, Diagnostic Cost Group (DCG) Recordists, Electro Cardio Gram (EEG) Recordists, Dental Therapists, Dental Technicians, and Public Health laboratories Technicians and Dispensers all joined the strike amid allegations of health sector workers not being given adequate fuel despite a promise by the government.",
        "PHI union chairman Upul Rohana said the main demands are a consistent supply of fuel and an increase in salary and allowances in par with the latest fuel price hikes.",
        "“Even if we had a consistent supply, we would not be able to buy fuel, the way prices are increasing,” Rohana told EconomyNext.",
        "Sri Lanka’s state-owned Ceylon Petroleum Corporation (CPC) and Lanka IOC, a local unit of the Indian Oil Corporation, upwardly revised prices by the same margin on Sunday June 26. Octane 92 petrol rose by 50 rupees to 470 rupees a litre, Auto Diesel by 60 rupees to 460 rupees a litre and Octane 95 petrol by 100 rupees to 550 rupees a litre, and Super Diesel 75 rupees to 520 rupees per litre.",
        "The price increase came as most of Sri Lankan fuel pumps had dried up as the government of President Gotabaya Rajapaksa failed to ensure supply due to and ongoing forex shortage.",
        "Last Friday June 24, Sri Lankan authorities had ensured that fuel would be provided to health staff from selected filling stations that day. Nine filling stations had been chosen from the capital Colombo and the Colombo district and six filling stations had been selected from adjoining Gampaha district.",
        "“We were promised fuel last Friday, but we didn’t get it. At this point. we don’t even have fuel to report to work,” said Rohana. (Colombo/Jun29/2022)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Sri Lanka",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "two-day",
          "label": "DATE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "the Public Health Inspectors",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "two-day",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Health Entomological Officers",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Diagnostic Cost Group",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Electro Cardio Gram",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Dental Technicians",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Technicians",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Upul Rohana",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Rohana",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "EconomyNext",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka’s",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ceylon Petroleum Corporation",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "CPC",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Lanka IOC",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Indian Oil Corporation",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sunday June 26",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "50",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "470",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Diesel",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "60",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "460",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "100",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "550",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Super Diesel",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lankan",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Gotabaya Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Last Friday June 24",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lankan",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "day",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Nine",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "six",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Gampaha",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "last Friday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Rohana",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Colombo/Jun29/2022",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "ඉන්ධන හිඟය සම්බන්ධයෙන් ශ්‍රී ලංකා මහජන සෞඛ්‍ය නිලධාරීන් දෙදින විරෝධතාවක් දියත් කරයි",
      "author": "",
      "body_lines": [
        "ECONOMYNEXT - මහජන සෞඛ්‍ය පරීක්ෂකවරුන්ගේ (PHI) සංගමය ප්‍රමුඛ ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ සෞඛ්‍ය අංශයේ වෘත්තීය සමිති ඉන්ධන සහ මහජන සෞඛ්‍ය පරීක්ෂකවරුන්ට ලබා දී ඇති ඉන්ධන දීමනාව වැඩි කරන ලෙස ඉල්ලා දෙදින වැඩ වර්ජනයක් දියත් කර ඇති බව වෘත්තීය සමිති නිලධාරියෙක් පැවසීය.",
        "සෞඛ්‍ය අංශයේ සේවකයන්ට ලබා නොදෙන බවට චෝදනා එල්ල වූ මහජන සෞඛ්‍ය වින්නඹු මාතාවන්, සෞඛ්‍ය කීට විද්‍යා නිලධාරීන්, රෝග විනිශ්චය පිරිවැය සමූහ (ඩීසීජී) වාර්තාකරුවන්, ඉලෙක්ට්‍රෝ කාඩියෝ ග්‍රෑම් (ඊඊජී) වාර්තාකරුවන්, දන්ත චිකිත්සකයින්, දන්ත කාර්මික ශිල්පීන් සහ මහජන සෞඛ්‍ය රසායනාගාර කාර්මික ශිල්පීන් සහ බෙදාහරින්නන් යන සියලු දෙනා වර්ජනයට එක් වූහ. රජය පොරොන්දු වී තිබියදීත් ප්‍රමාණවත් ඉන්ධන.",
        "PHI සංගමයේ සභාපති උපුල් රෝහණ පැවසුවේ ප්‍රධාන ඉල්ලීම් වන්නේ ස්ථාවර ඉන්ධන සැපයීම සහ නවතම ඉන්ධන මිල ඉහළ නැංවීමට සමගාමීව වැටුප් හා දීමනා වැඩි කිරීමයි.",
        "“අපට ස්ථාවර සැපයුමක් තිබුණත්, මිල වැඩි වන ආකාරයට අපට ඉන්ධන මිලදී ගැනීමට නොහැකි වනු ඇත,” රෝහණ EconomyNext වෙත පැවසීය.",
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ රජයට අයත් ලංකා ඛනිජ තෙල් නීතිගත සංස්ථාව (CPC) සහ ඉන්දීය තෙල් සංස්ථාවේ දේශීය ඒකකයක් වන ලංකා IOC, ජුනි 26 ඉරිදා එම සීමාවෙන්ම මිල ගණන් ඉහළ නංවා ඇත. ඔක්ටේන් 92 පෙට්‍රල් ලීටරයක් ​​රුපියල් 50 කින් ඉහළ ගොස් රුපියල් 470 ක් වී තිබේ. ඩීසල් ලීටරයක් ​​රුපියල් 60 කින් රුපියල් 460 කින් සහ ඔක්ටේන් 95 පෙට්‍රල් ලීටරයක් ​​රුපියල් 100 කින් රුපියල් 550 කින් සහ සුපර් ඩීසල් ලීටරයක් ​​රුපියල් 75 කින් රුපියල් 520 යි.",
        "ජනාධිපති ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ මහතාගේ රජය විදේශ විනිමය හිඟය සහ පවතින විදේශ විනිමය හිඟය හේතුවෙන් සැපයුම සහතික කිරීමට අපොහොසත් වීම නිසා ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ ඉන්ධන පොම්ප බොහොමයක් සිඳී ගොස් තිබීම හේතුවෙන් මෙම මිල වැඩි විය.",
        "පසුගිය ජූනි 24 සිකුරාදා තෝරාගත් පිරවුම්හල්වලින් සෞඛ්‍ය කාර්ය මණ්ඩලයට ඉන්ධන ලබා දෙන බවට ශ්‍රී ලංකා බලධාරීහු සහතික වූහ. කොළඹ අගනුවර සහ කොළඹ දිස්ත්‍රික්කයෙන් ඉන්ධන පිරවුම්හල් 9ක් තෝරාගෙන තිබූ අතර ගම්පහ දිස්ත්‍රික්කයට යාබදව ඉන්ධන පිරවුම්හල් හයක් තෝරාගෙන තිබුණි.",
        "“පසුගිය සිකුරාදා අපට ඉන්ධන ලබා දෙන බවට පොරොන්දු වූ නමුත් අපට එය ලැබුණේ නැත. මෙම මොහොතේ දී. අපිට වැඩට වාර්තා කරන්න තෙල්වත් නැහැ.” රෝහණ පැවසීය. (කොළඹ/ජුනි29/2022)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "දින දෙකක්",
          "label": "DATE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "මහජන සෞඛ්‍ය පරීක්ෂකවරුන්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "දින දෙකක්",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "සෞඛ්‍ය කීට විද්‍යා නිලධාරීන්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "රෝග විනිශ්චය පිරිවැය කණ්ඩායම",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉලෙක්ට්රෝ කාඩියෝ ග්රෑම්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "දන්ත කාර්මික ශිල්පීන්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "කාර්මික ශිල්පීන්",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "උපුල් රෝහණ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "රෝහණ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "EconomyNext",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ලංකා ඛනිජ තෙල් නීතිගත සංස්ථාව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "CPC",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ලංකා IOC",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දියානු තෙල් සංස්ථාව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජුනි 26 ඉරිදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "50",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "470",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඩීසල්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "60",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "460",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "100",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "550",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "සුපිරි ඩීසල්",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලාංකික",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "පසුගිය සිකුරාදා ජුනි 24",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලාංකික",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "දින",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "නවය",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "හය",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගම්පහ",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "පසුගිය සිකුරාදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "රෝහණ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "කොළඹ/ජුනි29/2022",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "எரிபொருள் தட்டுப்பாடு தொடர்பாக இலங்கை பொது சுகாதார அதிகாரிகள் இரண்டு நாள் போராட்டத்தை ஆரம்பித்துள்ளனர்",
      "author": "",
      "body_lines": [
        "ECONOMYNEXT - இலங்கையின் சுகாதாரத் துறை தொழிற்சங்கங்கள், பொது சுகாதார பரிசோதகர்கள் (PHI) சங்கத்தின் தலைமையில், எரிபொருள் மற்றும் PHIகளுக்கு வழங்கப்படும் எரிபொருள் கொடுப்பனவை உயர்த்தக் கோரி இரண்டு நாள் வேலைநிறுத்தத்தை ஆரம்பித்துள்ளதாக தொழிற்சங்க அதிகாரி ஒருவர் தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "பொது சுகாதார மருத்துவச்சிகள், சுகாதார பூச்சியியல் அதிகாரிகள், நோயறிதல் செலவு குழு (DCG) பதிவாளர்கள், எலக்ட்ரோ கார்டியோ கிராம் (EEG) பதிவாளர்கள், பல் சிகிச்சை நிபுணர்கள், பல் தொழில்நுட்ப வல்லுநர்கள் மற்றும் பொது சுகாதார ஆய்வகங்களின் தொழில்நுட்ப வல்லுநர்கள் மற்றும் விநியோகிப்பாளர்கள் அனைவரும் சுகாதாரத் துறை ஊழியர்களுக்கு வழங்கப்படவில்லை என்ற குற்றச்சாட்டுகளுக்கு மத்தியில் வேலைநிறுத்தத்தில் ஈடுபட்டனர். அரசாங்கம் வாக்குறுதி அளித்த போதிலும் போதுமான எரிபொருள்.",
        "PHI தொழிற்சங்கத் தலைவர் உபுல் ரோஹன கூறுகையில், நிலையான எரிபொருள் விநியோகம் மற்றும் சமீபத்திய எரிபொருள் விலை உயர்வுக்கு இணையாக சம்பளம் மற்றும் கொடுப்பனவுகளை அதிகரிப்பது முக்கிய கோரிக்கைகளாகும்.",
        "\"எங்களிடம் நிலையான விநியோகம் இருந்தாலும், எங்களால் எரிபொருளை வாங்க முடியாது, விலைகள் அதிகரித்து வருவதால்,\" ரோஹன EconomyNext இடம் கூறினார்.",
        "இலங்கையின் அரசுக்கு சொந்தமான சிலோன் பெட்ரோலியம் கூட்டுத்தாபனம் (CPC) மற்றும் இந்தியன் ஆயில் கார்ப்பரேஷனின் உள்ளூர் பிரிவான லங்கா ஐஓசி ஆகியவை ஜூன் 26 ஞாயிற்றுக்கிழமை அதே வித்தியாசத்தில் விலைகளை உயர்த்தியுள்ளன. ஒக்டேன் 92 பெட்ரோல் லிட்டருக்கு 50 ரூபாவால் 470 ரூபாயாக உயர்ந்தது, ஆட்டோ டீசல் ஒரு லீற்றர் 60 ரூபாவினால் 460 ரூபாவாகவும், ஒக்டேன் 95 பெற்றோல் ஒரு லீற்றர் 100 ரூபாவினால் 550 ரூபாவாகவும், சுப்பர் டீசல் லீற்றர் 75 ரூபா 520 ரூபாவாகவும் காணப்படுகின்றன.",
        "ஜனாதிபதி கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்சவின் அரசாங்கம் அந்நிய செலாவணி பற்றாக்குறை காரணமாக விநியோகத்தை உறுதிப்படுத்தத் தவறியதால், இலங்கையின் பெரும்பாலான எரிபொருள் பம்புகள் வறண்டு போயிருந்ததால் இந்த விலை அதிகரிப்பு ஏற்பட்டுள்ளது.",
        "கடந்த வெள்ளிக்கிழமை ஜூன் 24 அன்று, தேர்ந்தெடுக்கப்பட்ட எரிபொருள் நிரப்பு நிலையங்களில் இருந்து சுகாதார ஊழியர்களுக்கு எரிபொருள் வழங்கப்படும் என்பதை இலங்கை அதிகாரிகள் உறுதி செய்திருந்தனர். தலைநகர் கொழும்பு மற்றும் கொழும்பு மாவட்டத்தில் இருந்து ஒன்பது நிரப்பு நிலையங்களும், கம்பஹா மாவட்டத்தில் இருந்து ஆறு நிரப்பு நிலையங்களும் தெரிவு செய்யப்பட்டுள்ளன.",
        "“எங்களுக்கு கடந்த வெள்ளிக்கிழமை எரிபொருள் வாக்குறுதி அளிக்கப்பட்டது, ஆனால் எங்களுக்கு அது கிடைக்கவில்லை. இந்த கட்டத்தில். வேலைக்குச் செல்வதற்கு எங்களிடம் எரிபொருள் கூட இல்லை” என்று ரோஹன கூறினார். (கொழும்பு/ஜூன்29/2022)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "இலங்கை",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "இரண்டு நாட்கள்",
          "label": "DATE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "பொது சுகாதார ஆய்வாளர்கள்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இரண்டு நாட்கள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "சுகாதார பூச்சியியல் அதிகாரிகள்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "கண்டறியும் செலவு குழு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "எலக்ட்ரோ கார்டியோ கிராம்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "பல் தொழில்நுட்ப வல்லுநர்கள்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "தொழில்நுட்ப வல்லுநர்கள்",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "உபுல் ரோஹன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ரோஹண",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "EconomyNext",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கையின்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை பெற்றோலியக் கூட்டுத்தாபனம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "CPC",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "லங்கா ஐ.ஓ.சி",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்தியன் ஆயில் கார்ப்பரேஷன்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜூன் 26 ஞாயிறு",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "50",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "470",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "டீசல்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "60",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "460",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "100",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "550",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "சூப்பர் டீசல்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "கடந்த வெள்ளிக்கிழமை ஜூன் 24",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "நாள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஒன்பது",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆறு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "கம்பஹா",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "கடந்த வெள்ளிக்கிழமை",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரோஹண",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "கொழும்பு/ஜூன்29/2022",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}