{
  "newspaper_id": "economy-next-com",
  "url": "https://economynext.com/sri-lanka-schedules-shorter-power-cuts-for-sep-04-05-06-99385/",
  "time_ut": 1662123480,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Sri Lanka schedules shorter power cuts for Sep 04, 05, 06",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Sri Lanka schedules shorter power cuts for Sep 04, 05, 06",
      "author": "Dulya de Silva",
      "body_lines": [
        "ECONOMYNEXT – Reduced power cuts will be imposed around Sri Lanka over the weekend (September 03, 04) and on Monday (September 05), Public Utilities Commission of Sri Lankan (PUCSL) Chairman Janaka Ratnayake said.",
        "All groups A, B, C, D, E, F, G, H, I, J, K, P, Q, R, S, T, U, V and W will experience one hour of power cuts during the night time on Saturday and Sunday, and two hours on Monday.",
        "One Monday, power cuts will be one hour in the day time and one hour in the night.",
        "Sri Lanka’s power cut durations fluctuated over the past few weeks with the sudden breakdown and subsequent repair of a generator in the island’s Norochcholai coal power plant despite availability of hydroelectricity due to the unavailability of fuel.",
        "Amid fears of scarcity and petrol queues being once again spotted in several parts of the island, the state-owned Ceylon Petroleum Corporation (CPC) announced that it had adequate stocks.",
        "The CPC’s Sapugaskanda oil refinery recommenced operations on August 20, and Power & Energy Minister Kanchana Wijesekara said that the plant would be able run at full capacity for 40-days. (Colombo/Sep09/2022)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Sri Lanka",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "Sep 04",
          "label": "DATE"
        },
        {
          "text": "05",
          "label": "DATE"
        },
        {
          "text": "06",
          "label": "DATE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the weekend",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "September 03, 04",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Monday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "September 05",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Public Utilities Commission of Sri Lankan",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "PUCSL",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Janaka Ratnayake",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "F, G, H",
            "label": "PRODUCT"
          },
          {
            "text": "one hour",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "Saturday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sunday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "two hours",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "Monday",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "One",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Monday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "one hour",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "one hour",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka’s",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the past few weeks",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Norochcholai",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Ceylon Petroleum Corporation",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "CPC",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "CPC",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sapugaskanda",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "August 20",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Power & Energy",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kanchana Wijesekara",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "40-days",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "ශ්‍රී ලංකාව සැප්තැම්බර් 04, 05, 06 සඳහා කෙටි විදුලි කප්පාදුවක් සැලසුම් කරයි",
      "author": "දුල්යා ද සිල්වා",
      "body_lines": [
        "ECONOMYNEXT - සති අන්තයේ (සැප්තැම්බර් 03, 04) සහ සඳුදා (සැප්තැම්බර් 05) ශ්‍රී ලංකාව පුරා අඩු කරන ලද විදුලි කප්පාදුවක් පනවනු ලබන බව ශ්‍රී ලංකා මහජන උපයෝගිතා කොමිෂන් සභාවේ (PUCSL) සභාපති ජනක රත්නායක මහතා පැවසීය.",
        "A, B, C, D, E, F, G, H, I, J, K, P, Q, R, S, T, U, V සහ W යන සියලුම කණ්ඩායම් රාත්‍රී කාලය තුළ පැයක විදුලි කප්පාදුවක් අත්විඳිය හැකිය. සෙනසුරාදා සහ ඉරිදා, සහ සඳුදා පැය දෙකක්.",
        "සඳුදා දිනක දිවා කාලයේ පැයක් සහ රාත්‍රියේ පැයක් ලෙස විදුලිය විසන්ධි වේ.",
        "ඉන්ධන නොමැතිකම හේතුවෙන් ජල විදුලිය තිබුණද දිවයිනේ නොරොච්චෝලේ ගල් අඟුරු බලාගාරයේ ජනන යන්ත්‍රයක් හදිසියේ බිඳවැටීම සහ පසුව අලුත්වැඩියා කිරීමත් සමඟ ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ විදුලි කප්පාදු කාලසීමාවන් පසුගිය සති කිහිපය තුළ උච්චාවචනය විය.",
        "දිවයිනේ ප්‍රදේශ කිහිපයක පෙට්‍රල් හිඟය සහ පෙට්‍රල් පෝලිම් යළිත් වරක් දැකගත හැකි වීමේ බිය මධ්‍යයේ, රජයට අයත් ලංකා ඛනිජ තෙල් නීතිගත සංස්ථාව (CPC) ප්‍රමාණවත් තොග ඇති බව නිවේදනය කළේය.",
        "ඛනිජ තෙල් නීතිගත සංස්ථාවේ සපුගස්කන්ද තෙල් පිරිපහදුව අගෝස්තු 20 වැනි දින නැවත මෙහෙයුම් ආරම්භ කළ අතර, බලාගාරය දින 40ක් සඳහා පූර්ණ ධාරිතාවයෙන් පවත්වාගෙන යා හැකි බව විදුලිබල හා බලශක්ති අමාත්‍ය කංචන විජේසේකර මහතා පැවසීය. (කොළඹ/සැප්.09/2022)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "සැප් 04",
          "label": "DATE"
        },
        {
          "text": "05",
          "label": "DATE"
        },
        {
          "text": "06",
          "label": "DATE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "සති අන්තය",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "සැප්තැම්බර් 03, 04",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "සඳුදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "සැප්තැම්බර් 05",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකා මහජන උපයෝගිතා කොමිෂන් සභාව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "PUCSL",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජානක රත්නායක",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "එෆ්, ජී, එච්",
            "label": "PRODUCT"
          },
          {
            "text": "පැයක්",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "සෙනසුරාදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉරිදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "පැය දෙකක්",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "සඳුදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "එක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "සඳුදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "පැයක්",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "පැයක්",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "පසුගිය සති කිහිපය",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "නොරොච්චෝලේ",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ලංකා ඛනිජ තෙල් නීතිගත සංස්ථාව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "CPC",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "CPC",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "සපුගස්කන්ද",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "අගෝස්තු 20",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "බලය සහ බලශක්තිය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "කාංචන විජේසේකර",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "40-දින",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "செப்டம்பர் 04, 05, 06 ஆகிய தேதிகளில் குறுகிய மின்வெட்டுகளை இலங்கை திட்டமிடுகிறது",
      "author": "துல்யா டி சில்வா",
      "body_lines": [
        "பொருளாதாரம் - இலங்கை முழுவதும் வார இறுதியில் (செப்டம்பர் 03, 04) மற்றும் திங்கட்கிழமை (செப்டம்பர் 05) குறைக்கப்பட்ட மின்வெட்டு அமுல்படுத்தப்படும் என இலங்கை பொதுப் பயன்பாடுகள் ஆணைக்குழுவின் (PUCSL) தலைவர் ஜானக ரத்நாயக்க தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "A, B, C, D, E, F, G, H, I, J, K, P, Q, R, S, T, U, V மற்றும் W ஆகிய அனைத்துக் குழுக்களும் இரவு நேரத்தில் ஒரு மணி நேரம் மின்வெட்டை அனுபவிக்கும். சனி மற்றும் ஞாயிறு மற்றும் திங்கட்கிழமை இரண்டு மணி நேரம்.",
        "ஒரு திங்கட்கிழமை, பகலில் ஒரு மணி நேரமும், இரவில் ஒரு மணி நேரமும் மின்வெட்டு இருக்கும்.",
        "கடந்த சில வாரங்களாக தீவின் நொரோச்சோலை நிலக்கரி மின்நிலையத்தில் உள்ள ஜெனரேட்டரில் ஏற்பட்ட திடீர் பழுதினாலும் அதனைத் தொடர்ந்து ஏற்பட்ட பழுது காரணமாகவும் எரிபொருள் கிடைக்காத காரணத்தினால் நீர்மின்சாரம் கிடைக்கப்பெற்ற போதிலும் இலங்கையின் மின்வெட்டு காலம் ஏற்ற இறக்கமாக இருந்தது.",
        "தீவின் பல பகுதிகளில் தட்டுப்பாடு மற்றும் பெட்ரோல் வரிசைகள் மீண்டும் காணப்படுகின்றன என்ற அச்சத்தின் மத்தியில், அரசுக்கு சொந்தமான இலங்கை பெற்றோலியக் கூட்டுத்தாபனம் (CPC) தன்னிடம் போதுமான இருப்பு இருப்பதாக அறிவித்தது.",
        "CPC யின் சபுகஸ்கந்த எண்ணெய் சுத்திகரிப்பு நிலையம் ஆகஸ்ட் 20 அன்று மீண்டும் செயல்படத் தொடங்கியது, மேலும் ஆலையை 40 நாட்களுக்கு முழு கொள்ளளவிலும் இயக்க முடியும் என்று மின்சக்தி மற்றும் எரிசக்தி அமைச்சர் காஞ்சன விஜேசேகர கூறினார். (கொழும்பு/செப்09/2022)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "இலங்கை",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "செப் 04",
          "label": "DATE"
        },
        {
          "text": "05",
          "label": "DATE"
        },
        {
          "text": "06",
          "label": "DATE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "வார இறுதி",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "செப்டம்பர் 03, 04",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "திங்கட்கிழமை",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "செப்டம்பர் 05",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கையின் பொதுப் பயன்பாடுகள் ஆணைக்குழு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "PUCSL",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜனக ரத்நாயக்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "எஃப், ஜி, எச்",
            "label": "PRODUCT"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஒரு மணி நேரம்",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "சனிக்கிழமை",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஞாயிற்றுக்கிழமை",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இரண்டு மணி நேரம்",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "திங்கட்கிழமை",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஒன்று",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "திங்கட்கிழமை",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஒரு மணி நேரம்",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஒரு மணி நேரம்",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கையின்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "கடந்த சில வாரங்களாக",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "நொரோச்சோலை",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை பெற்றோலியக் கூட்டுத்தாபனம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "CPC",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "CPC",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "சபுகஸ்கந்த",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆகஸ்ட் 20",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சக்தி மற்றும் ஆற்றல்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "காஞ்சனா விஜேசேகர",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "40-நாட்கள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}