{
  "newspaper_id": "daily-ft-lk",
  "url": "https://www.ft.lk/news/Kanchana-holds-talks-with-Qatar-s-Energy-Minister/56-736828",
  "time_ut": 1656447465,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Kanchana holds talks with Qatar’s Energy Minister",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Kanchana holds talks with Qatar’s Energy Minister",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "Power and Energy Minister Kanchana Wijesekera has met with Qatar’s Minister of State for Energy Affairs and QatarEnergy President and CEO Saad Sherida Al-Kaabi yesterday.",
        "The two Ministers discussed the possibility of supplying petroleum products to Sri Lanka in a bid to overcome the energy crisis through the assistance of Qatar Energy and the Qatar Development Fund.",
        "Wijesekera said discussions centred around a possible credit line for petroleum and gas and was informed that funds have been allocated by Qatar for medical supplies and it will consider the request for a credit facility and support the IMF program",
        "On Monday night, Minister Wijesekera and Environment Minister Ahamed Nazeer left the country for Doha, Qatar to hold bilateral discussions on fuel imports among many other subjects.",
        "Separately, Education Minister Susil Premajayantha and former Sri Lankan Ambassador to Russia Saman Weerasinghe, and several officials are scheduled to leave for Moscow, Russia on Sunday to hold talks to solve Sri Lanka’s energy crisis.",
        "Minister Premajayantha has left for France via Dubai to reach Moscow",
        "The Government expects a positive response from Russia during the diplomatic visit by the Minister and officials.",
        "Given the dire straits of the economic crisis, on Monday, the Government decided to supply fuel ‘only’ to essential services till 10 July, whilst requesting all other sectors to work from home (WFH)."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Kanchana",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "Qatar",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Kanchana Wijesekera",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Qatar",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Energy Affairs",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "QatarEnergy",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Saad Sherida Al-Kaabi",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "yesterday",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "two",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Qatar Energy",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Qatar Development Fund",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Wijesekera",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Qatar",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "IMF",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Monday night",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "Wijesekera",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ahamed Nazeer",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Doha",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Qatar",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Education",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Susil Premajayantha",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lankan",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Russia",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Saman Weerasinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Moscow",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Russia",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sunday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka’s",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Premajayantha",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "France",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Dubai",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Moscow",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Government",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Russia",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Monday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "10 July",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "WFH",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "කාංචනා කටාර් බලශක්ති අමාත්‍යවරයා සමඟ සාකච්ඡා පවත්වයි",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "විදුලිබල හා බලශක්ති අමාත්‍ය කංචන විජේසේකර මහතා කටාර්හි බලශක්ති කටයුතු පිළිබඳ රාජ්‍ය අමාත්‍ය සහ කටාර් බලශක්ති සභාපති සහ ප්‍රධාන විධායක නිලධාරී Saad Sherida Al-Kaabi ඊයේ හමුවී තිබේ.",
        "කටාර් බලශක්ති සහ කටාර් සංවර්ධන අරමුදලේ සහය තුළින් බලශක්ති අර්බුදයෙන් මිදීම සඳහා ශ්‍රී ලංකාවට ඛනිජ තෙල් නිෂ්පාදන සැපයීමේ හැකියාව පිළිබඳව අමාත්‍යවරුන් දෙදෙනා සාකච්ඡා කළහ.",
        "පෙට්‍රෝලියම් සහ ගෑස් සඳහා ලබාදිය හැකි ණය මාර්ගයක් පිළිබඳ සාකච්ඡා කේන්ද්‍රගත වූ බවත් වෛද්‍ය සැපයුම් සඳහා කටාර් රාජ්‍යයෙන් මුදල් වෙන් කර ඇති බවත් ණය පහසුකම් සඳහා වන ඉල්ලීම සලකා බලා ජාත්‍යන්තර මූල්‍ය අරමුදලේ වැඩසටහනට සහාය දක්වන බවත් දන්වා ඇති බවත් විජේසේකර පැවසීය.",
        "සඳුදා රාත්‍රියේ අමාත්‍ය විජේසේකර සහ පරිසර අමාත්‍ය අහමඩ් නසීර් තවත් බොහෝ විෂයයන් අතර ඉන්ධන ආනයනය පිළිබඳ ද්විපාර්ශ්වික සාකච්ඡා පැවැත්වීමට කටාර්හි දෝහා බලා පිටත්ව ගියහ.",
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ බලශක්ති අර්බුදය විසඳීම සඳහා සාකච්ඡා කිරීම සඳහා අධ්‍යාපන අමාත්‍ය සුසිල් ප්‍රේමජයන්ත සහ රුසියාවේ හිටපු ශ්‍රී ලංකා තානාපති සමන් වීරසිංහ ඇතුළු නිලධාරීන් පිරිසක් වෙන වෙනම ඉරිදා රුසියාවේ මොස්කව් නුවර බලා පිටත්ව යාමට නියමිතයි.",
        "ප්‍රේමජයන්ත අමාත්‍යවරයා ඩුබායි හරහා ප්‍රංශය බලා පිටත්ව ගොස් ඇත්තේ මොස්කව් වෙත පැමිණීමටයි",
        "ඇමැතිවරයා ඇතුළු නිලධාරීන්ගේ රාජ්‍ය තාන්ත්‍රික සංචාරයේදී රුසියාවෙන් යහපත් ප්‍රතිචාරයක් රජය අපේක්ෂා කරයි.",
        "ආර්ථික අර්බුදයේ උග්‍ර දුෂ්කරතා සැලකිල්ලට ගෙන, සඳුදා, රජය ජූලි 10 දක්වා අත්‍යවශ්‍ය සේවා සඳහා ‘පමණක්’ ඉන්ධන සැපයීමට තීරණය කළ අතර අනෙක් සියලුම අංශවලට නිවසේ සිට වැඩ කරන ලෙස (WFH) ඉල්ලා සිටියේය."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "කාංචනා",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "කටාර්",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "කාංචන විජේසේකර",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "කටාර්",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "බලශක්ති කටයුතු",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "කටාර් බලශක්ති",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Saad Sherida Al-Kaabi",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඊයේ",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "දෙක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "කටාර් බලශක්ති",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "කටාර් සංවර්ධන අරමුදල",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "විජේසේකර",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "කටාර්",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "IMF",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "සඳුදා රෑ",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "විජේසේකර",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "අහමඩ් නසීර්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "දෝහා",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "කටාර්",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "අධ්යාපන",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "සුසිල් ප්‍රේමජයන්ත",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලාංකික",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "රුසියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "සමන් වීරසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "මොස්කව්",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "රුසියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉරිදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ප්‍රේමජයන්ත",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ප්රංශය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඩුබායි",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මොස්කව්",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ආණ්ඩුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "රුසියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "සඳුදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "10 ජූලි",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "WFH",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "கத்தாரின் எரிசக்தி அமைச்சருடன் காஞ்சனா பேச்சுவார்த்தை நடத்துகிறார்",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "மின்சக்தி மற்றும் எரிசக்தி அமைச்சர் காஞ்சனா விஜேசேகர நேற்று கத்தாரின் எரிசக்தி விவகாரங்களுக்கான இராஜாங்க அமைச்சரும் கத்தார் எரிசக்தியின் தலைவரும் பிரதம நிறைவேற்று அதிகாரியுமான சாத் ஷெரிடா அல்-காபியை சந்தித்துள்ளார்.",
        "கத்தார் எரிசக்தி மற்றும் கட்டார் அபிவிருத்தி நிதியத்தின் உதவியுடன் எரிசக்தி நெருக்கடியை சமாளிக்கும் முயற்சியில் இலங்கைக்கு பெட்ரோலிய பொருட்களை வழங்குவதற்கான சாத்தியக்கூறுகள் குறித்து இரு அமைச்சர்களும் கலந்துரையாடினர்.",
        "விஜேசேகர, பெட்ரோலியம் மற்றும் எரிவாயுக்கான சாத்தியமான கடன் வரியை மையமாகக் கொண்ட விவாதங்கள், மருத்துவப் பொருட்களுக்கு கத்தாரால் நிதி ஒதுக்கீடு செய்யப்பட்டுள்ளதாகவும், கடன் வசதிக்கான கோரிக்கையை பரிசீலித்து IMF திட்டத்திற்கு ஆதரவளிக்கும் என்றும் தெரிவிக்கப்பட்டது.",
        "திங்கட்கிழமை இரவு, அமைச்சர் விஜேசேகர மற்றும் சுற்றாடல் அமைச்சர் அஹமட் நசீர் ஆகியோர் நாட்டிலிருந்து கத்தாரின் தோஹாவிற்கு புறப்பட்டு பல விடயங்கள் மத்தியில் எரிபொருள் இறக்குமதி தொடர்பாக இருதரப்பு கலந்துரையாடல்களை நடத்தினார்கள்.",
        "கல்வி அமைச்சர் சுசில் பிரேமஜயந்த மற்றும் ரஷ்யாவுக்கான முன்னாள் இலங்கைத் தூதுவர் சமன் வீரசிங்க மற்றும் பல அதிகாரிகள் ஞாயிற்றுக்கிழமை ரஷ்யாவின் மொஸ்கோவிற்குச் சென்று இலங்கையின் எரிசக்தி நெருக்கடியைத் தீர்ப்பதற்கான பேச்சுவார்த்தைகளை நடத்த உள்ளனர்.",
        "மொஸ்கோவை சென்றடைவதற்காக அமைச்சர் பிரேமஜயந்த டுபாய் ஊடாக பிரான்ஸ் சென்றுள்ளார்",
        "அமைச்சர் மற்றும் அதிகாரிகளின் இராஜதந்திர பயணத்தின் போது ரஷ்யாவிடம் இருந்து சாதகமான பதிலை அரசாங்கம் எதிர்பார்க்கிறது.",
        "பொருளாதார நெருக்கடியின் கடுமையான நெருக்கடியைக் கருத்தில் கொண்டு, திங்கட்கிழமை, ஜூலை 10 வரை அத்தியாவசிய சேவைகளுக்கு எரிபொருளை 'மட்டும்' வழங்க அரசாங்கம் முடிவு செய்தது, அதே நேரத்தில் மற்ற அனைத்து துறைகளையும் வீட்டிலிருந்து வேலை செய்யும்படி (WFH) கோரியது."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "காஞ்சனா",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "கத்தார்",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "காஞ்சனா விஜேசேகர",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "கத்தார்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "எரிசக்தி விவகாரங்கள்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "கத்தார் எரிசக்தி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "சாத் ஷெரிடா அல்-காபி",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "நேற்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இரண்டு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "கத்தார் ஆற்றல்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "கத்தார் மேம்பாட்டு நிதி",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "விஜேசேகர",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "கத்தார்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "IMF",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "திங்கள் இரவு",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "விஜேசேகர",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "அகமது நசீர்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "தோஹா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "கத்தார்",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "கல்வி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "சுசில் பிரேமஜயந்த",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரஷ்யா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சமன் வீரசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "மாஸ்கோ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரஷ்யா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஞாயிற்றுக்கிழமை",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கையின்",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பிரேமஜயந்த",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "பிரான்ஸ்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "துபாய்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "மாஸ்கோ",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "அரசாங்கம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரஷ்யா",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "திங்கட்கிழமை",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "10 ஜூலை",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "WFH",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}