{
  "newspaper_id": "daily-mirror-lk",
  "url": "https://www.dailymirror.lk/breaking_news/No-fuel-for-people-waiting-unnecessarily-in-queues-tomorrow-Fuel-Distributors-Assn/108-241512",
  "time_ut": 1658397346,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "No fuel for people waiting unnecessarily in queues tomorrow: Fuel Distributors Assn.",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "No fuel for people waiting unnecessarily in queues tomorrow: Fuel Distributors Assn.",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "The Fuel Distributors Association (FDA) today said that they will not provide fuel for those vehicles waiting in queues if they are not entitled to the process of refuelling as per the last digit of the vehicle’s registration number on the specific day.",
        "According to FDA's Vice President Kusum Sandanayaka, more issues have arisen at filling stations as a result of the large number of people queuing for the new process.",
        "The majority of those who were present claim that they did not have enough fuel in their vehicles to leave the queues and return on the day designated by the government.",
        "\"Those people used to stay in the queues for five or six days before.\" Therefore, the association had decided to provide fuel for them for only today to reduce the number of people waiting at queues. \" Sandanayaka said. (Chaturanga Samarawickrama)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "tomorrow",
          "label": "DATE"
        },
        {
          "text": "Fuel Distributors Assn",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "The Fuel Distributors Association",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "FDA",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the specific day",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "FDA",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kusum Sandanayaka",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the day",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "five or six days",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sandanayaka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Chaturanga Samarawickrama",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "පෝලිම්වල අනවශ්‍ය ලෙස රැඳී සිටින ජනතාවට හෙට ඉන්ධන නැත: ඉන්ධන බෙදාහරින්නන් සහකාර",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "නිශ්චිත දිනයේ වාහනයේ ලියාපදිංචි අංකයේ අවසාන අංකයට අනුව ඉන්ධන පිරවීමේ ක්‍රියාවලියට හිමිකම් නොලබන්නේ නම් පෝලිම්වල රැඳී සිටින වාහන සඳහා ඉන්ධන ලබා නොදෙන බව ඉන්ධන බෙදාහරින්නන්ගේ සංගමය (FDA) අද ප්‍රකාශ කළේය.",
        "FDA හි උප සභාපති කුසුම් සන්දනායක පවසන පරිදි, නව ක්‍රියාවලිය සඳහා විශාල පිරිසක් පෝලිම්වල සිටීම හේතුවෙන් ඉන්ධන පිරවුම්හල්වල තවත් ගැටළු මතු වී තිබේ.",
        "පැමිණ සිටි බහුතරයක් දෙනා කියා සිටින්නේ රජය විසින් නියම කරන ලද දිනට පෝලිම්වලින් බැස ආපසු යාමට තම වාහනවල ඉන්ධන ප්‍රමාණවත් නොවන බවයි.",
        "\"ඒ මිනිස්සු ඉස්සර දවස් පහක් හයක් පෝලිමේ හිටියා.\" එබැවින් පෝලිම්වල රැඳී සිටීම අවම කිරීමේ අරමුණින් ඔවුන් වෙනුවෙන් අද දින පමණක් ඉන්ධන ලබාදීමට එම සංගමය තීරණය කර තිබුණා. සන්දනායක පැවසීය. (චතුරංග සමරවික්‍රම)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "හෙට",
          "label": "DATE"
        },
        {
          "text": "ඉන්ධන බෙදාහරින්නන් සහකාර",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ඉන්ධන බෙදාහරින්නන්ගේ සංගමය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "FDA",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "නිශ්චිත දිනය",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "FDA",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "කුසුම් සන්දනායක",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "දවස",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "දින පහක් හෝ හයක්",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "සන්දනායක",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "චතුරංග සමරවික්‍රම",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "வரிசையில் மக்கள் தேவையில்லாமல் காத்திருக்கும் மக்களுக்கு நாளை எரிபொருள் இல்லை: எரிபொருள் விநியோகஸ்தர்கள் உதவியாளர்.",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "குறிப்பிட்ட நாளில் வாகனத்தின் பதிவு எண்ணின் கடைசி இலக்கத்தின்படி எரிபொருள் நிரப்பும் செயல்முறைக்கு உரிமை இல்லை என்றால் வரிசையில் காத்திருக்கும் அந்த வாகனங்களுக்கு எரிபொருள் வழங்க மாட்டோம் என்று எரிபொருள் விநியோகஸ்தர்கள் சங்கம் (FDA) இன்று தெரிவித்துள்ளது.",
        "FDA இன் உப தலைவர் குசும் சந்தநாயக்க கருத்துப்படி, புதிய செயல்முறைக்கு அதிக எண்ணிக்கையிலான மக்கள் வரிசையில் நிற்பதன் விளைவாக எரிபொருள் நிரப்பு நிலையங்களில் அதிக சிக்கல்கள் எழுந்துள்ளன.",
        "அரசாங்கத்தால் நியமிக்கப்பட்ட நாளில் வரிசையை விட்டு வெளியேறுவதற்கும், திரும்புவதற்கும் போதுமான எரிபொருள் தங்களுடைய வாகனங்களில் இல்லை என்று அங்கிருந்தவர்களில் பெரும்பாலோர் கூறுகின்றனர்.",
        "\"அந்த மக்கள் முன்பு ஐந்து அல்லது ஆறு நாட்கள் வரிசையில் நிற்கிறார்கள்.\" எனவே, வரிசையில் காத்திருப்பவர்களின் எண்ணிக்கையை குறைக்கும் வகையில் இன்று மட்டும் அவர்களுக்கான எரிபொருள் வழங்க சங்கம் தீர்மானித்திருந்தது. சந்தநாயக்க தெரிவித்தார். (சதுரங்க சமரவிக்ரம)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "நாளை",
          "label": "DATE"
        },
        {
          "text": "எரிபொருள் விநியோகஸ்தர்கள் Assn",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "எரிபொருள் விநியோகஸ்தர்கள் சங்கம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "FDA",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "குறிப்பிட்ட நாள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "FDA",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "குசும் சந்தநாயக",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "தினம்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஐந்து அல்லது ஆறு நாட்கள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சந்தநாயக",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சதுரங்க சமரவிக்ரம",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}