{
  "newspaper_id": "lankadeepa-lk",
  "url": "https://www.lankadeepa.lk/latest_news/කොළඹ-නගර-සභා-‘ප්‍රජා-කුස්සිය’ට-ආහාර-භෝග-වගාව-ඇරඹේ/1-618966",
  "time_ut": 1661778821,
  "original_lang": "si",
  "original_title": "කොළඹ නගර සභා ‘ප්‍රජා කුස්සිය’ට ආහාර භෝග වගාව ඇරඹේ",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Cultivation of food crops has started for Colombo Municipal Council's 'Community Kitchen'",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "The project to grow food crops on a part of the land where the Colombo Municipal Council building is located was carried out today (29) under the leadership of the Mayor Rosy Senanayake.",
        "Vegetable plants will be planted in a part of the municipal land, and this project will be implemented in collaboration with Cargill.",
        "Mayor Mrs. Rosy Senanayake said that the Colombo Municipal Council decided to start a plantation in the municipal area as a remedy for the economic crisis and food crisis in the country.",
        "She also said that she hopes to provide vegetables needed for the 'Community Kitchen' program, which has been started with the aim of providing meals to the poor people of Colombo city, from this plantation in the future."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Colombo Municipal Council's 'Community Kitchen'",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "the Colombo Municipal Council",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "29",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Rosy Senanayake",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Cargill",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Rosy Senanayake",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Colombo Municipal Council",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the 'Community Kitchen'",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "කොළඹ නගර සභා ‘ප්‍රජා කුස්සිය’ට ආහාර භෝග වගාව ඇරඹේ",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "කොළඹ මහ නගර සභා ගොඩනැගිල්ල පිහිටි භූමියේ කොටසක ආහාර භෝග වගා කිරීමේ ව්‍යාපෘතිය නගරාධිපතිනි රෝසි සේනානායක මහත්මියගේ ප්‍රධානත්වයෙන් අද (29) සිදුකෙරිණි.",
        "නගර සභා භූමියේ කොටසක මෙලෙම එළවළු පැළ වගා කෙරෙන අතර, කාගීල්ස් ආයතනය හා එක්ව මෙම ව්‍යාපෘතිය ක්‍රියාත්මක කෙරේ.",
        "රටේ ඇති වී තිබෙන ආර්ථික අර්බුදයට හා ආහාර අර්බුදයට පිළියමක් ලෙස කොළඹ මහ නගර සභාව විසින් නගර සභා භූමියේ මෙලෙස වගාවක් ආරම්භ කිරීමට තීරණය කළ බව නගරාධිපතිනි රෝසි සේනානායක මහත්මිය පැවසුවාය.",
        "එමෙන්ම කොළඹ නගරයේ දිළිඳු ජනතාවට ආහාර වේලක් ලබාදීමේ අරමුණින් ආරම්භ කර ඇති ‘ප්‍රජා කුස්සිය’ වැඩසටහන සඳහා අවශ්‍ය එළවළු මෙම වගාබිම මගින් ඉදිරියේදී ලබාදීමට ද බලාපොරොත්තු වන බව ඇය කීවාය."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "කොළඹ මහ නගර සභාවේ 'ප්‍රජා කුස්සිය'",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "කොළඹ මහ නගර සභාව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "29",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "රෝසි සේනානායක",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "කාගිල්",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "රෝසි සේනානායක",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "කොළඹ මහ නගර සභාව",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "'ප්‍රජා කුස්සිය'",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "கொழும்பு மாநகர சபையின் 'சமூக சமையலறை'க்கான உணவுப் பயிர்கள் பயிரிடும் பணிகள் ஆரம்பமாகியுள்ளன.",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "கொழும்பு மாநகர சபை கட்டிடம் அமைந்துள்ள காணியின் ஒரு பகுதியில் உணவு பயிர்களை வளர்க்கும் வேலைத்திட்டம் மேயர் ரோசி சேனாநாயக்க தலைமையில் இன்று (29) முன்னெடுக்கப்பட்டது.",
        "மாநகராட்சி நிலத்தின் ஒரு பகுதியில் காய்கறி செடிகள் நடப்பட்டு, கார்கில் நிறுவனத்துடன் இணைந்து இத்திட்டம் செயல்படுத்தப்படும்.",
        "நாட்டில் நிலவும் பொருளாதார நெருக்கடி மற்றும் உணவு நெருக்கடிக்கு தீர்வாக மாநகரசபை பகுதியில் தோட்டமொன்றை ஆரம்பிக்க கொழும்பு மாநகர சபை தீர்மானித்ததாக மேயர் திருமதி ரோசி சேனாநாயக்க தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "கொழும்பு நகரிலுள்ள வறிய மக்களுக்கு உணவு வழங்கும் நோக்கில் ஆரம்பிக்கப்பட்டுள்ள 'சமூக சமையலறை' நிகழ்ச்சித் திட்டத்திற்குத் தேவையான மரக்கறிகளை எதிர்காலத்தில் இந்தத் தோட்டத்தில் இருந்து வழங்குவதற்கு எதிர்பார்ப்பதாகவும் அவர் கூறினார்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "கொழும்பு மாநகர சபையின் 'சமூக சமையலறை'",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "கொழும்பு மாநகர சபை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "29",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரோசி சேனாநாயக்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "கார்கில்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ரோசி சேனாநாயக்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "கொழும்பு மாநகர சபை",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "'சமூக சமையலறை'",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}