{
  "newspaper_id": "island-lk",
  "url": "http://island.lk/splice-the-mainbrace-and-navy-food/",
  "time_ut": 1655993100,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Splice the Mainbrace and Navy Food",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Splice the Mainbrace and Navy Food",
      "author": "Dilshan Nadeera",
      "body_lines": [
        "Navies are famous for excellent cooks and serving delicious food the world over. The best food is served during naval fleet exercises in overseas ports and on special days when the Navy usually serves “splice the mainbrace followed by ‘Bada Khana’ (big meal in Hindi).",
        "Braces are the lines in sailing ships that control the angle of the yards. In square rigged sailing vessels, mainbrace is the longest line in all running riggings. It was common to aim cannon fire at riggings during sea battles. If mainbrace was hit, it had to be repaired immediately. ‘Splice the mainbrace’ was performed by experienced able seaman on knots and splices under supervision of Boatswain on sailing ship’s mainbrace.",
        "This was a very tedious emergency repair until the completion of which, the sailing ship cannot change her tack (direction of sailing). It becomes much more difficult when these repairs have to be done under battle conditions. As an appreciation to his hard work, an extra ration of rum is given to the sailor concerned.",
        "The modern-day Navies have no sails and no mainbraces; but they have “splice the mainbrace ceremony “drinking a tot of rum.",
        "So, in celebration of the Navy Day, ‘splice the mainbrace’ is performed by giving our sailors extra tot of liquor (in Sri Lanka Navy – old arrack) prior to Commanding Officer and other officers sitting with sailors in the General Mess (junior sailors dining room) to have delicious ‘Bada Khana’ prepared by excellent Navy cooks.",
        "The menu for ‘Bada Khana’ is always, mouth-watering vegetable fried rice, fried chicken curry, dhal dry curry, potatoes tempered, brinjal moju, boiled egg and battered/crispy crumped sheer fish. Dessert is always Wattalappam.",
        "Our sailors love this food. They always work hard and look forward to ‘splice the mainbrace’ and ‘Bada Khanna’. Those are the traditions of the Navy.",
        "At other times, our Navy’s culinary skills are displayed when our ships sail abroad and take part in international maritime exercises. We carry our traditional food stuffs on board and participate at international food festivals.",
        "With the Navy band in attendence and our traditional dancers performing Kandyan, Sabaragamuwa, low country and Jaffna dances, we are considered cultural ambassadors of Sri Lanka.",
        "Our Navy has ships capable of performing long-distance voyages and carrying its cultural troupe and band. It is also equipped with a state-of-the-art kitchen with a bakery at the Supply and Secretariat school in Trincomalee to train cooks and stewards. For further training, they are sent to Indian and Pakistan Navy catering schools. The Navy has provided cooks and stewards both to the President’s House and Temple Trees to serve very long periods and they are capable of handling day-to-day dining and banquets held in honour of visiting Heads of State.",
        "Cooking out at sea is a difficult task. In rough sea conditions, it becomes is a nightmare with the ship or craft rolling and pitching in gale-force winds. But our cooks never keep us hungry!",
        "Anyway, only a few people can eat in such sea conditions as others fall ‘sea sick’.",
        "If you are in a small craft or FAC (Fast Attack Craft), there are no cooks. The crew members get together to prepare their meals whilst on patrol. Some seamen and marine engineering mechanics are excellent cooks. I had one such sailor, Leading Engineering Mechanic Premaratne, when I was OIC P 467 (Dovra); he rose up to Master Chief Petty Officer. He used to bring fresh vegetables from his village when he returned after leave and prepared delicious meals onboard.",
        "Where can one relish this unique ‘Navy Food’? Visit the Light House Galley restaurant at Chaithya Road, Colombo 1. Best quality food is available there at fair prices. It is becoming more and more popular among young office workers in the Fort area, especially on Friday evenings. Safe parking is available next to the Port city with Navy protection.",
        "The global South comes full circle in its search for development",
        "Leave a Reply Cancel replyYour email address will not be published. Required fields are marked *Comment Name *",
        "Save my name, email, and website in this browser for the next time I comment."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Navy",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Navy",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Bada Khana",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Hindi",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Boatswain",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "The modern-day",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka Navy",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Mess",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Bada Khana",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Navy",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Bada Khana",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Dessert",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Wattalappam",
            "label": "PRODUCT"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Bada Khanna’",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Navy",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Navy",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Navy",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kandyan",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sabaragamuwa",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Jaffna",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Navy",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Secretariat",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Indian",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Pakistan Navy",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Navy",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "House",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Temple Trees",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Heads of State",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "FAC",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Fast Attack Craft",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "one",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Leading Engineering Mechanic Premaratne",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "OIC P 467",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "one",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Navy",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Chaithya Road, Colombo 1",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "Fort",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "Friday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Port city",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Navy",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "South",
            "label": "LOC"
          }
        ],
        [],
        []
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "Mainbrace සහ Navy ආහාර බෙදන්න",
      "author": "ඩිල්ෂාන් නදීර",
      "body_lines": [
        "නාවික හමුදාව විශිෂ්ට කුක් සඳහා ප්‍රසිද්ධ වී ඇති අතර ලොව පුරා රසවත් ආහාර සපයයි. හොඳම ආහාර සපයනු ලබන්නේ විදේශීය වරායන්හි නාවික යාත්‍රා අභ්‍යාසවලදී සහ නාවික හමුදාව සාමාන්‍යයෙන් සේවය කරන විශේෂ දිනවලදී “බඩ ඛානා” (හින්දි භාෂාවෙන් විශාල ආහාර වේලක්) සමඟ ප්‍රධාන බ්‍රේස් එක බෙදන්න.",
        "වරහන් යනු යාරවල කෝණය පාලනය කරන රුවල් නැව්වල රේඛා වේ. හතරැස් සවි කළ රුවල් යාත්‍රා වල, මේන්බ්‍රේස් යනු සියලුම ධාවන රිගින් වල දිගම රේඛාව වේ. මුහුදු සටන් වලදී රිගින් වලට කාලතුවක්කු වෙඩි තැබීම සාමාන්‍ය දෙයක් විය. මේන්බ්‍රේස් එක වැදුනොත් වහා අලුත්වැඩියා කරන්න ඕන. 'Splice the mainbrace' යාත්‍රා කරන නැවේ ප්‍රධාන වරහන මත Boatswain ගේ අධීක්ෂණය යටතේ ගැට සහ splices මත පළපුරුදු දක්ෂ නාවිකයෙකු විසින් සිදු කරන ලදී.",
        "මෙය ඉතා වෙහෙසකර හදිසි අලුත්වැඩියාවක් වූ අතර, එය අවසන් වන තෙක් රුවල් නැවට ඇගේ ටැක් (යාත්‍රා කරන දිශාව) වෙනස් කළ නොහැක. මෙම අලුත්වැඩියාවන් යුධ තත්වයන් යටතේ සිදු කළ යුතු විට එය වඩාත් අපහසු වේ. ඔහුගේ වෙහෙස මහන්සි වී වැඩ කිරීම අගය කිරීමක් ලෙස, අදාළ නාවිකයාට අමතර රම් සලාකයක් ලබා දෙනු ලැබේ.",
        "නූතන නාවික හමුදාවට රුවල් සහ ප්‍රධාන වරහන් නොමැත; නමුත් ඔවුන් \"ප්‍රධාන බ්‍රේස් උත්සවයට\" රම් එකක් බොනවා.",
        "එබැවින්, නාවික හමුදා දිනය සමරමින්, 'ස්ප්ලයිස් ද මේන්බ්‍රේස්' සිදු කරනු ලබන්නේ, සාමාන්‍ය මැස්හි (කනිෂ්ඨ නාවිකයින්) නාවිකයින් සමඟ අණදෙන නිලධාරි සහ අනෙකුත් නිලධාරීන් වාඩි වීමට පෙර අපගේ නාවිකයින්ට අමතර මත්පැන් (ශ්‍රී ලංකා නාවික හමුදාවේ - පරණ අරක්කු) ලබා දීමෙනි. කෑම කාමරය) විශිෂ්ට නාවික හමුදා කෝකියන් විසින් සකස් කරන ලද රසවත් 'බඩ ඛානා' ලබා ගැනීමට.",
        "‘බඩා ඛානා’ සඳහා වන මෙනුව සෑම විටම, කටට වතුර දමන එළවලු ෆ්‍රයිඩ් රයිස්, බැදපු කුකුල් මස් කරි, පරිප්පු වියළි ව්‍යංජන, අල තෙම්පරාදු, බටු මෝජු, තැම්බූ බිත්තර සහ තැම්බූ/ක්‍රිස්පි හැපෙනසුළු මාළු. අතුරුපස හැමදාම වත්තලප්පම්.",
        "අපේ නැවියන් මෙම කෑමට කැමතියි. ඔවුන් සෑම විටම වෙහෙස මහන්සි වී වැඩ කරන අතර 'මේන්බ්‍රේස් එක බෙදීමට' සහ 'බඩා ඛන්නා' බලා සිටී. ඒවා නාවික හමුදාවේ සම්ප්‍රදායයි.",
        "වෙනත් අවස්ථාවල දී, අපගේ නැව් විදේශයන්හි යාත්‍රා කරන විට සහ ජාත්‍යන්තර සමුද්‍ර අභ්‍යාසවලට සහභාගී වන විට අපගේ නාවික හමුදාවේ සූපශාස්ත්‍ර කුසලතා ප්‍රදර්ශනය කෙරේ. අපි අපේ සාම්ප්‍රදායික ආහාර ද්‍රව්‍ය නැවේ තබාගෙන ජාත්‍යන්තර ආහාර උත්සවවලට සහභාගී වෙමු.",
        "නාවික හමුදාවේ තූර්ය වාදක කණ්ඩායම සහභාගී වීමත්, උඩරට, සබරගමුව, පහතරට සහ යාපනය නැටුම් ඉදිරිපත් කරන අපේ සම්ප්‍රදායික නර්තන ශිල්පීන් සමඟත් අපි ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ සංස්කෘතික තානාපතිවරුන් ලෙස සැලකේ.",
        "අපේ නාවික හමුදාවට දුර ගමන්වල යෙදීමට සහ එහි සංස්කෘතික කණ්ඩායම සහ තූර්ය වාදක කණ්ඩායම රැගෙන යා හැකි නැව් තිබේ. ත්‍රිකුණාමලයේ පිහිටි සැපයුම් හා ලේකම් කාර්යාලීය පාසලේ ඉවුම් පිහුම්කරුවන් සහ භාරකරුවන් පුහුණු කිරීම සඳහා බේකරියක් සමඟ නවීනතම මුළුතැන්ගෙයකින් ද එය සමන්විත වේ. වැඩිදුර පුහුණුව සඳහා ඔවුන් ඉන්දීය සහ පකිස්ථාන නාවික හමුදා ආහාරපාන පාසල් වෙත යවනු ලැබේ. නාවික හමුදාව විසින් ජනාධිපති මන්දිරයට සහ අරලියගහ මන්දිරයට ඉතා දිගු කාලයක් සේවය කිරීම සඳහා අරක්කැමියන් සහ භාරකරුවන් සපයා ඇති අතර, පැමිණෙන රාජ්‍ය නායකයින්ට උපහාර පිණිස පවත්වනු ලබන එදිනෙදා භෝජන සංග්‍රහ සහ භෝජන සංග්‍රහ හැසිරවීමට නාවික හමුදාව සමත් වේ.",
        "මුහුදේ ආහාර පිසීම දුෂ්කර කාර්යයකි. රළු මුහුදු තත්ත්‍වයේ දී, එය සුළි සුළඟින් නැව හෝ යාත්‍රාව පෙරළීම සහ තණතීරුව සමඟ බියකරු සිහිනයක් බවට පත්වේ. නමුත් අපේ කෝකියෝ කවදාවත් අපිව බඩගින්නේ තියන්නේ නැහැ!",
        "කෙසේ වෙතත්, එවැනි මුහුදු තත්වයන් තුළ ආහාර ගත හැක්කේ කිහිප දෙනෙකුට පමණි, අනෙක් අය 'මුහුදු අසනීප' වේ.",
        "ඔබ කුඩා යාත්‍රාවක හෝ FAC (Fast Attack Craft) නම්, කෝකියන් නොමැත. කාර්ය මණ්ඩල සාමාජිකයින් මුර සංචාරයේ යෙදී සිටියදී ඔවුන්ගේ ආහාර පිළියෙළ කිරීමට එක් වෙති. සමහර නාවිකයින් සහ සමුද්‍ර ඉංජිනේරු යාන්ත්‍රිකයින් විශිෂ්ට කෝකියෝ වෙති. මා OIC P 467 (Dovra) ලෙස සිටියදී මට එවැනි එක් නාවිකයෙක් සිටියේය, ප්‍රමුඛ ඉංජිනේරු කාර්මික ප්‍රේමරත්න; ඔහු මාස්ටර් ප්‍රධාන සුළු නිලධාරියා දක්වා ඉහළ ගියේය. ඔහු නිවාඩුවක් ගත කර ආපසු එන විට තම ගමෙන් නැවුම් එළවළු ගෙනැවිත් නැවෙන් රසවත් කෑම පිළියෙළ කළේය.",
        "මෙම අද්විතීය 'නාවික ආහාර' රස විඳිය හැක්කේ කොතැනින්ද? කොළඹ 1 චෛත්‍ය පාරේ ලයිට් හවුස් ගැලී අවන්හලට පිවිසෙන්න. හොඳම තත්ත්වයේ ආහාර සාධාරණ මිලට එහි ඇත. විශේෂයෙන්ම සිකුරාදා සවස් වන විට කොටුව ප්‍රදේශයේ තරුණ කාර්යාල සේවකයන් අතර එය දිනෙන් දින ජනප්‍රිය වෙමින් පවතී. නාවික හමුදාවේ ආරක්ෂාව සහිතව වරාය නගරයට යාබදව ආරක්ෂිත වාහන නැවැත්වීමේ පහසුකම් ඇත.",
        "ගෝලීය දකුණ එහි සංවර්ධනය සඳහා වූ ගවේෂණයේ සම්පූර්ණ වටයක් පැමිණේ",
        "පිළිතුරක් දෙන්න පිළිතුර අවලංගු කරන්න ඔබගේ විද්‍යුත් තැපැල් ලිපිනය ප්‍රකාශයට පත් නොකෙරේ. අවශ්‍ය ක්ෂේත්‍ර සලකුණු කර ඇත *අදහස් නම *",
        "මම ඊළඟ වතාවේ අදහස් දැක්වීම සඳහා මගේ නම, විද්‍යුත් තැපෑල සහ වෙබ් අඩවිය මෙම බ්‍රවුසරයේ සුරකින්න."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "නාවික",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "නාවික",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "බඩා ඛානා",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "හින්දි",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "බෝට්ස්වේන්",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "නූතන යුගය",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකා නාවික හමුදාව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "අවුල්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "බඩා ඛානා",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "නාවික",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "බඩා ඛානා",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "අතුරුපස",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "වත්තලප්පම්",
            "label": "PRODUCT"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "බඩා ඛන්නා'",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "නාවික",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "නාවික",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "නාවික",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "උඩරට",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "සබරගමුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "යාපනය",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "නාවික",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ලේකම් කාර්යාලය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දීය",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "පකිස්ථාන නාවික හමුදාව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "නාවික",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "නිවස",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "අරලියගහ මන්දිරය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "රාජ්ය නායකයන්",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "FAC",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "වේගවත් ප්රහාරක යාත්රාව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "එක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ප්‍රමුඛ ඉංජිනේරු කාර්මික ප්‍රේමරත්න",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ස්ථානාධිපති පී 467",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "එක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "නාවික",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "චෛත්‍ය පාර, කොළඹ 1",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "බලකොටුව",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "සිකුරාදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "වරාය නගරය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "නාවික",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "දකුණු",
            "label": "LOC"
          }
        ],
        [],
        []
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "மெயின்பிரேஸ் மற்றும் கடற்படை உணவைப் பிரிக்கவும்",
      "author": "தில்ஷான் நதீரா",
      "body_lines": [
        "கடற்படையினர் சிறந்த சமையல்காரர்களுக்கும், உலகம் முழுவதும் சுவையான உணவை வழங்குவதற்கும் பிரபலமானவர்கள். வெளிநாட்டுத் துறைமுகங்களில் கடற்படைக் கடற்படைப் பயிற்சியின் போது சிறந்த உணவு வழங்கப்படுகிறது மற்றும் கடற்படை வழக்கமாக சேவை செய்யும் சிறப்பு நாட்களில் \"படா கானா\" (இந்தி மொழியில் பெரிய உணவு) ஆகியவற்றைப் பிரிக்கவும்.",
        "பிரேஸ்கள் என்பது பாய்மரக் கப்பல்களில் உள்ள கோடுகள் ஆகும், அவை யார்டுகளின் கோணத்தைக் கட்டுப்படுத்துகின்றன. சதுர வடிவிலான பாய்மரக் கப்பல்களில், மெயின்பிரேஸ் என்பது அனைத்து இயங்கும் ரிக்கிங்கிலும் மிக நீளமான வரிசையாகும். கடல் போர்களின் போது ரிக்கிங்ஸ் மீது பீரங்கி சுடுவது வழக்கமாக இருந்தது. மெயின்பிரேஸ் தாக்கப்பட்டால், அதை உடனடியாக சரிசெய்ய வேண்டும். பாய்மரக் கப்பலின் மெயின்பிரேஸில் போட்ஸ்வைனின் மேற்பார்வையின் கீழ் முடிச்சுகள் மற்றும் ஸ்ப்லைஸ்களில் அனுபவம் வாய்ந்த கடலோடிகளால் 'ஸ்ப்லைஸ் தி மெயின்பிரேஸ்' நிகழ்த்தப்பட்டது.",
        "இது மிகவும் கடினமான அவசரகால பழுதுபார்ப்பாக இருந்தது, இது முடிவடையும் வரை, பாய்மரக் கப்பலால் அதன் போக்கை மாற்ற முடியாது (படகோட்டம் செல்லும் திசை). போர் நிலைமைகளின் கீழ் இந்த பழுதுகளைச் செய்ய வேண்டியிருக்கும் போது இது மிகவும் கடினமாகிறது. அவரது கடின உழைப்புக்கு பாராட்டு தெரிவிக்கும் வகையில், சம்பந்தப்பட்ட மாலுமிக்கு கூடுதல் ரேஷன் ரம் வழங்கப்படுகிறது.",
        "நவீன கால கடற்படைகளுக்கு பாய்மரங்களும் இல்லை, முக்கிய பிரேஸ்களும் இல்லை; ஆனால் அவர்கள் \"மெயின்பிரேஸ் விழாவை பிரித்து\" நிறைய ரம் குடித்துள்ளனர்.",
        "எனவே, கடற்படை தினத்தை கொண்டாடும் வகையில், ஜெனரல் மெஸ்ஸில் (ஜூனியர் மாலுமிகள்) மாலுமிகளுடன் கமாண்டிங் ஆபீசர் மற்றும் பிற அதிகாரிகள் அமர்வதற்கு முன்னதாக, நமது மாலுமிகளுக்கு கூடுதல் மதுபானம் (இலங்கை கடற்படையில் - பழைய அரக்கு) கொடுத்து 'ஸ்ப்லைஸ் தி மெயின்பிரேஸ்' செய்யப்படுகிறது. சாப்பாட்டு அறை) சிறந்த கடற்படை சமையல்காரர்களால் தயாரிக்கப்பட்ட சுவையான 'படா கானா'.",
        "‘படா கானா’ மெனுவில் எப்போதும், வாயில் நீர் ஊற வைக்கும் வெஜிடபிள் ஃப்ரைடு ரைஸ், வறுத்த சிக்கன் கறி, பருப்பு ட்ரை கறி, உருளைக்கிழங்கு பதப்படுத்தப்பட்ட, பிரிஞ்சி மோஜு, வேகவைத்த முட்டை மற்றும் வறுக்கப்பட்ட/மிருதுவான நொறுக்கப்பட்ட ஷீர் மீன். இனிப்பு எப்போதும் வத்தலப்பம்.",
        "எங்கள் மாலுமிகள் இந்த உணவை விரும்புகிறார்கள். அவர்கள் எப்பொழுதும் கடினமாக உழைக்கிறார்கள் மற்றும் 'மெயின்பிரேஸ்' மற்றும் 'படா கன்னா' ஆகியவற்றை எதிர்நோக்குகிறார்கள். அவை கடற்படையின் மரபுகள்.",
        "மற்ற சமயங்களில், நமது கப்பல்கள் வெளிநாடுகளுக்குச் செல்லும்போதும், சர்வதேச கடல்சார் பயிற்சிகளில் பங்கேற்கும்போதும் நமது கடற்படையின் சமையல் திறன் வெளிப்படும். நாங்கள் எங்கள் பாரம்பரிய உணவுப் பொருட்களை கப்பலில் எடுத்துச் செல்கிறோம் மற்றும் சர்வதேச உணவு திருவிழாக்களில் பங்கேற்கிறோம்.",
        "கடற்படை இசைக்குழுவினர் கலந்து கொண்டு, கண்டி, சப்ரகமுவ, கீழைநாடு மற்றும் யாழ்ப்பாண நடனங்களை எமது பாரம்பரிய நடனக் கலைஞர்கள் நிகழ்த்தியதால், நாங்கள் இலங்கையின் கலாச்சாரத் தூதுவர்களாகக் கருதப்படுகிறோம்.",
        "நமது கடற்படையில் நீண்ட தூர பயணங்களை மேற்கொள்ளும் திறன் கொண்ட கப்பல்கள் உள்ளன மற்றும் அதன் கலாச்சார குழு மற்றும் இசைக்குழுவை சுமந்து செல்கின்றன. திருகோணமலையில் உள்ள வழங்கல் மற்றும் செயலகப் பாடசாலையில் சமையல்காரர்கள் மற்றும் பணிப்பெண்களுக்கு பயிற்சியளிக்கும் வகையில் பேக்கரியுடன் கூடிய அதிநவீன சமையல் கூடத்துடன் இது பொருத்தப்பட்டுள்ளது. மேலும் பயிற்சிக்காக, அவர்கள் இந்திய மற்றும் பாகிஸ்தான் கடற்படை கேட்டரிங் பள்ளிகளுக்கு அனுப்பப்படுகிறார்கள். ஜனாதிபதி மாளிகை மற்றும் அலரிமாளிகை ஆகியவற்றிற்கு கடற்படையினர் சமையல்காரர்களையும், பணிப்பெண்களையும் மிக நீண்ட காலம் சேவையாற்றுவதற்காக வழங்கியுள்ளதுடன், அவர்கள் வருகை தரும் அரச தலைவர்களை கௌரவிக்கும் வகையில் தினசரி உணவு மற்றும் விருந்துகளை கையாளும் திறன் கொண்டவர்கள்.",
        "கடலில் சமைப்பது கடினமான பணி. கரடுமுரடான கடல் சூழ்நிலையில், இது ஒரு கனவாக மாறும், இது கப்பல் அல்லது கைவினைக் காற்றில் உருளும் மற்றும் பிட்ச் ஆகும். ஆனால், நம் சமையல்காரர்கள் நம்மைப் பசிக்க வைப்பதில்லை!",
        "எப்படியிருந்தாலும், மற்றவர்கள் 'கடல் நோய்வாய்ப்பட்டால்' இதுபோன்ற கடல் சூழ்நிலைகளில் சிலர் மட்டுமே சாப்பிட முடியும்.",
        "நீங்கள் ஒரு சிறிய கைவினை அல்லது FAC (ஃபாஸ்ட் அட்டாக் கிராஃப்ட்) இல் இருந்தால், சமையல்காரர்கள் இல்லை. ரோந்து பணியின் போது குழு உறுப்பினர்கள் ஒன்று கூடி தங்கள் உணவை தயார் செய்கிறார்கள். சில மாலுமிகள் மற்றும் கடல் பொறியியல் இயக்கவியல் சிறந்த சமையல்காரர்கள். நான் OIC P 467 (Dovra) ஆக இருந்தபோது, ​​முன்னணி பொறியியல் மெக்கானிக் பிரேமரத்ன போன்ற ஒரு மாலுமி என்னிடம் இருந்தார்; அவர் மாஸ்டர் சீஃப் குட்டி அதிகாரியாக உயர்ந்தார். அவர் விடுமுறை முடிந்து திரும்பும் போது தனது கிராமத்தில் இருந்து புதிய காய்கறிகளை கொண்டு வந்து கப்பலில் சுவையான உணவுகளை தயாரித்தார்.",
        "இந்த தனித்துவமான 'நேவி ஃபுட்'ஐ ஒருவர் எங்கே அனுபவிக்க முடியும்? கொழும்பு 1, சைத்யா வீதியில் உள்ள லைட் ஹவுஸ் கேலி உணவகத்தைப் பார்வையிடவும். சிறந்த தரமான உணவு நியாயமான விலையில் கிடைக்கும். குறிப்பாக வெள்ளிக்கிழமை மாலை வேளைகளில் கோட்டைப் பகுதியில் உள்ள இளம் அலுவலக ஊழியர்களிடையே இது மிகவும் பிரபலமாகி வருகிறது. போர்ட் சிட்டிக்கு அருகில் கடற்படை பாதுகாப்புடன் பாதுகாப்பான பார்க்கிங் உள்ளது.",
        "உலகளாவிய தெற்கு அதன் வளர்ச்சிக்கான தேடலில் முழு வட்டம் வருகிறது",
        "ஒரு பதிலை விடுங்கள் பதிலை ரத்துசெய் உங்கள் மின்னஞ்சல் முகவரி வெளியிடப்படாது. தேவையான புலங்கள் குறிக்கப்பட்டுள்ளன *கருத்து பெயர்*",
        "அடுத்த முறை நான் கருத்து தெரிவிக்க எனது பெயர், மின்னஞ்சல் மற்றும் இணையதளத்தை இந்த உலாவியில் சேமிக்கவும்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "கடற்படை",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "கடற்படை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "படா கானா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஹிந்தி",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "போட்ஸ்வைன்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "நவீன நாள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை கடற்படை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "குழப்பம்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "படா கானா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "கடற்படை",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "படா கானா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இனிப்பு",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "வத்தலப்பம்",
            "label": "PRODUCT"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "படா கண்ணா’",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "கடற்படை",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "கடற்படை",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "கடற்படை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "கண்டியன்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "சப்ரகமுவ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "யாழ்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "கடற்படை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "செயலகம்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்தியன்",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாகிஸ்தான் கடற்படை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "கடற்படை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "வீடு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "கோவில் மரங்கள்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "மாநிலத் தலைவர்கள்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "FAC",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஃபாஸ்ட் அட்டாக் கிராஃப்ட்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஒன்று",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "முன்னணி பொறியியல் மெக்கானிக் பிரேமரத்ன",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "OIC பி 467",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஒன்று",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "கடற்படை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "சைத்திய வீதி, கொழும்பு 1",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "கோட்டை",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "வெள்ளி",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "துறைமுக நகரம்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "கடற்படை",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "தெற்கு",
            "label": "LOC"
          }
        ],
        [],
        []
      ]
    }
  },
  "title": "Splice the Mainbrace and Navy Food",
  "body_lines": [
    "Navies are famous for excellent cooks and serving delicious food the world over. The best food is served during naval fleet exercises in overseas ports and on special days when the Navy usually serves “splice the mainbrace followed by ‘Bada Khana’ (big meal in Hindi).",
    "Braces are the lines in sailing ships that control the angle of the yards. In square rigged sailing vessels, mainbrace is the longest line in all running riggings. It was common to aim cannon fire at riggings during sea battles. If mainbrace was hit, it had to be repaired immediately. ‘Splice the mainbrace’ was performed by experienced able seaman on knots and splices under supervision of Boatswain on sailing ship’s mainbrace.",
    "This was a very tedious emergency repair until the completion of which, the sailing ship cannot change her tack (direction of sailing). It becomes much more difficult when these repairs have to be done under battle conditions. As an appreciation to his hard work, an extra ration of rum is given to the sailor concerned.",
    "The modern-day Navies have no sails and no mainbraces; but they have “splice the mainbrace ceremony “drinking a tot of rum.",
    "So, in celebration of the Navy Day, ‘splice the mainbrace’ is performed by giving our sailors extra tot of liquor (in Sri Lanka Navy – old arrack) prior to Commanding Officer and other officers sitting with sailors in the General Mess (junior sailors dining room) to have delicious ‘Bada Khana’ prepared by excellent Navy cooks.",
    "The menu for ‘Bada Khana’ is always, mouth-watering vegetable fried rice, fried chicken curry, dhal dry curry, potatoes tempered, brinjal moju, boiled egg and battered/crispy crumped sheer fish. Dessert is always Wattalappam.",
    "Our sailors love this food. They always work hard and look forward to ‘splice the mainbrace’ and ‘Bada Khanna’. Those are the traditions of the Navy.",
    "At other times, our Navy’s culinary skills are displayed when our ships sail abroad and take part in international maritime exercises. We carry our traditional food stuffs on board and participate at international food festivals.",
    "With the Navy band in attendence and our traditional dancers performing Kandyan, Sabaragamuwa, low country and Jaffna dances, we are considered cultural ambassadors of Sri Lanka.",
    "Our Navy has ships capable of performing long-distance voyages and carrying its cultural troupe and band. It is also equipped with a state-of-the-art kitchen with a bakery at the Supply and Secretariat school in Trincomalee to train cooks and stewards. For further training, they are sent to Indian and Pakistan Navy catering schools. The Navy has provided cooks and stewards both to the President’s House and Temple Trees to serve very long periods and they are capable of handling day-to-day dining and banquets held in honour of visiting Heads of State.",
    "Cooking out at sea is a difficult task. In rough sea conditions, it becomes is a nightmare with the ship or craft rolling and pitching in gale-force winds. But our cooks never keep us hungry!",
    "Anyway, only a few people can eat in such sea conditions as others fall ‘sea sick’.",
    "If you are in a small craft or FAC (Fast Attack Craft), there are no cooks. The crew members get together to prepare their meals whilst on patrol. Some seamen and marine engineering mechanics are excellent cooks. I had one such sailor, Leading Engineering Mechanic Premaratne, when I was OIC P 467 (Dovra); he rose up to Master Chief Petty Officer. He used to bring fresh vegetables from his village when he returned after leave and prepared delicious meals onboard.",
    "Where can one relish this unique ‘Navy Food’? Visit the Light House Galley restaurant at Chaithya Road, Colombo 1. Best quality food is available there at fair prices. It is becoming more and more popular among young office workers in the Fort area, especially on Friday evenings. Safe parking is available next to the Port city with Navy protection.",
    "The global South comes full circle in its search for development",
    "Leave a Reply Cancel replyYour email address will not be published. Required fields are marked *Comment Name *",
    "Save my name, email, and website in this browser for the next time I comment."
  ],
  "translate": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Splice the Mainbrace and Navy Food",
      "author": "Dilshan Nadeera",
      "body_lines": [
        "Navies are famous for excellent cooks and serving delicious food the world over. The best food is served during naval fleet exercises in overseas ports and on special days when the Navy usually serves “splice the mainbrace followed by ‘Bada Khana’ (big meal in Hindi).",
        "Braces are the lines in sailing ships that control the angle of the yards. In square rigged sailing vessels, mainbrace is the longest line in all running riggings. It was common to aim cannon fire at riggings during sea battles. If mainbrace was hit, it had to be repaired immediately. ‘Splice the mainbrace’ was performed by experienced able seaman on knots and splices under supervision of Boatswain on sailing ship’s mainbrace.",
        "This was a very tedious emergency repair until the completion of which, the sailing ship cannot change her tack (direction of sailing). It becomes much more difficult when these repairs have to be done under battle conditions. As an appreciation to his hard work, an extra ration of rum is given to the sailor concerned.",
        "The modern-day Navies have no sails and no mainbraces; but they have “splice the mainbrace ceremony “drinking a tot of rum.",
        "So, in celebration of the Navy Day, ‘splice the mainbrace’ is performed by giving our sailors extra tot of liquor (in Sri Lanka Navy – old arrack) prior to Commanding Officer and other officers sitting with sailors in the General Mess (junior sailors dining room) to have delicious ‘Bada Khana’ prepared by excellent Navy cooks.",
        "The menu for ‘Bada Khana’ is always, mouth-watering vegetable fried rice, fried chicken curry, dhal dry curry, potatoes tempered, brinjal moju, boiled egg and battered/crispy crumped sheer fish. Dessert is always Wattalappam.",
        "Our sailors love this food. They always work hard and look forward to ‘splice the mainbrace’ and ‘Bada Khanna’. Those are the traditions of the Navy.",
        "At other times, our Navy’s culinary skills are displayed when our ships sail abroad and take part in international maritime exercises. We carry our traditional food stuffs on board and participate at international food festivals.",
        "With the Navy band in attendence and our traditional dancers performing Kandyan, Sabaragamuwa, low country and Jaffna dances, we are considered cultural ambassadors of Sri Lanka.",
        "Our Navy has ships capable of performing long-distance voyages and carrying its cultural troupe and band. It is also equipped with a state-of-the-art kitchen with a bakery at the Supply and Secretariat school in Trincomalee to train cooks and stewards. For further training, they are sent to Indian and Pakistan Navy catering schools. The Navy has provided cooks and stewards both to the President’s House and Temple Trees to serve very long periods and they are capable of handling day-to-day dining and banquets held in honour of visiting Heads of State.",
        "Cooking out at sea is a difficult task. In rough sea conditions, it becomes is a nightmare with the ship or craft rolling and pitching in gale-force winds. But our cooks never keep us hungry!",
        "Anyway, only a few people can eat in such sea conditions as others fall ‘sea sick’.",
        "If you are in a small craft or FAC (Fast Attack Craft), there are no cooks. The crew members get together to prepare their meals whilst on patrol. Some seamen and marine engineering mechanics are excellent cooks. I had one such sailor, Leading Engineering Mechanic Premaratne, when I was OIC P 467 (Dovra); he rose up to Master Chief Petty Officer. He used to bring fresh vegetables from his village when he returned after leave and prepared delicious meals onboard.",
        "Where can one relish this unique ‘Navy Food’? Visit the Light House Galley restaurant at Chaithya Road, Colombo 1. Best quality food is available there at fair prices. It is becoming more and more popular among young office workers in the Fort area, especially on Friday evenings. Safe parking is available next to the Port city with Navy protection.",
        "The global South comes full circle in its search for development",
        "Leave a Reply Cancel replyYour email address will not be published. Required fields are marked *Comment Name *",
        "Save my name, email, and website in this browser for the next time I comment."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Navy",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Navy",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Bada Khana",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Hindi",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Boatswain",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "The modern-day",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka Navy",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Mess",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Bada Khana",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Navy",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Bada Khana",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Dessert",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Wattalappam",
            "label": "PRODUCT"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Bada Khanna’",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Navy",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Navy",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Navy",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kandyan",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sabaragamuwa",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Jaffna",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Navy",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Secretariat",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Indian",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Pakistan Navy",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Navy",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "House",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Temple Trees",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Heads of State",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "FAC",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Fast Attack Craft",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "one",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Leading Engineering Mechanic Premaratne",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "OIC P 467",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "one",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Navy",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Chaithya Road, Colombo 1",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "Fort",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "Friday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Port city",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Navy",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "South",
            "label": "LOC"
          }
        ],
        [],
        []
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "Mainbrace සහ Navy ආහාර බෙදන්න",
      "author": "ඩිල්ෂාන් නදීර",
      "body_lines": [
        "නාවික හමුදාව විශිෂ්ට කුක් සඳහා ප්‍රසිද්ධ වී ඇති අතර ලොව පුරා රසවත් ආහාර සපයයි. හොඳම ආහාර සපයනු ලබන්නේ විදේශීය වරායන්හි නාවික යාත්‍රා අභ්‍යාසවලදී සහ නාවික හමුදාව සාමාන්‍යයෙන් සේවය කරන විශේෂ දිනවලදී “බඩ ඛානා” (හින්දි භාෂාවෙන් විශාල ආහාර වේලක්) සමඟ ප්‍රධාන බ්‍රේස් එක බෙදන්න.",
        "වරහන් යනු යාරවල කෝණය පාලනය කරන රුවල් නැව්වල රේඛා වේ. හතරැස් සවි කළ රුවල් යාත්‍රා වල, මේන්බ්‍රේස් යනු සියලුම ධාවන රිගින් වල දිගම රේඛාව වේ. මුහුදු සටන් වලදී රිගින් වලට කාලතුවක්කු වෙඩි තැබීම සාමාන්‍ය දෙයක් විය. මේන්බ්‍රේස් එක වැදුනොත් වහා අලුත්වැඩියා කරන්න ඕන. 'Splice the mainbrace' යාත්‍රා කරන නැවේ ප්‍රධාන වරහන මත Boatswain ගේ අධීක්ෂණය යටතේ ගැට සහ splices මත පළපුරුදු දක්ෂ නාවිකයෙකු විසින් සිදු කරන ලදී.",
        "මෙය ඉතා වෙහෙසකර හදිසි අලුත්වැඩියාවක් වූ අතර, එය අවසන් වන තෙක් රුවල් නැවට ඇගේ ටැක් (යාත්‍රා කරන දිශාව) වෙනස් කළ නොහැක. මෙම අලුත්වැඩියාවන් යුධ තත්වයන් යටතේ සිදු කළ යුතු විට එය වඩාත් අපහසු වේ. ඔහුගේ වෙහෙස මහන්සි වී වැඩ කිරීම අගය කිරීමක් ලෙස, අදාළ නාවිකයාට අමතර රම් සලාකයක් ලබා දෙනු ලැබේ.",
        "නූතන නාවික හමුදාවට රුවල් සහ ප්‍රධාන වරහන් නොමැත; නමුත් ඔවුන් \"ප්‍රධාන බ්‍රේස් උත්සවයට\" රම් එකක් බොනවා.",
        "එබැවින්, නාවික හමුදා දිනය සමරමින්, 'ස්ප්ලයිස් ද මේන්බ්‍රේස්' සිදු කරනු ලබන්නේ, සාමාන්‍ය මැස්හි (කනිෂ්ඨ නාවිකයින්) නාවිකයින් සමඟ අණදෙන නිලධාරි සහ අනෙකුත් නිලධාරීන් වාඩි වීමට පෙර අපගේ නාවිකයින්ට අමතර මත්පැන් (ශ්‍රී ලංකා නාවික හමුදාවේ - පරණ අරක්කු) ලබා දීමෙනි. කෑම කාමරය) විශිෂ්ට නාවික හමුදා කෝකියන් විසින් සකස් කරන ලද රසවත් 'බඩ ඛානා' ලබා ගැනීමට.",
        "‘බඩා ඛානා’ සඳහා වන මෙනුව සෑම විටම, කටට වතුර දමන එළවලු ෆ්‍රයිඩ් රයිස්, බැදපු කුකුල් මස් කරි, පරිප්පු වියළි ව්‍යංජන, අල තෙම්පරාදු, බටු මෝජු, තැම්බූ බිත්තර සහ තැම්බූ/ක්‍රිස්පි හැපෙනසුළු මාළු. අතුරුපස හැමදාම වත්තලප්පම්.",
        "අපේ නැවියන් මෙම කෑමට කැමතියි. ඔවුන් සෑම විටම වෙහෙස මහන්සි වී වැඩ කරන අතර 'මේන්බ්‍රේස් එක බෙදීමට' සහ 'බඩා ඛන්නා' බලා සිටී. ඒවා නාවික හමුදාවේ සම්ප්‍රදායයි.",
        "වෙනත් අවස්ථාවල දී, අපගේ නැව් විදේශයන්හි යාත්‍රා කරන විට සහ ජාත්‍යන්තර සමුද්‍ර අභ්‍යාසවලට සහභාගී වන විට අපගේ නාවික හමුදාවේ සූපශාස්ත්‍ර කුසලතා ප්‍රදර්ශනය කෙරේ. අපි අපේ සාම්ප්‍රදායික ආහාර ද්‍රව්‍ය නැවේ තබාගෙන ජාත්‍යන්තර ආහාර උත්සවවලට සහභාගී වෙමු.",
        "නාවික හමුදාවේ තූර්ය වාදක කණ්ඩායම සහභාගී වීමත්, උඩරට, සබරගමුව, පහතරට සහ යාපනය නැටුම් ඉදිරිපත් කරන අපේ සම්ප්‍රදායික නර්තන ශිල්පීන් සමඟත් අපි ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ සංස්කෘතික තානාපතිවරුන් ලෙස සැලකේ.",
        "අපේ නාවික හමුදාවට දුර ගමන්වල යෙදීමට සහ එහි සංස්කෘතික කණ්ඩායම සහ තූර්ය වාදක කණ්ඩායම රැගෙන යා හැකි නැව් තිබේ. ත්‍රිකුණාමලයේ පිහිටි සැපයුම් හා ලේකම් කාර්යාලීය පාසලේ ඉවුම් පිහුම්කරුවන් සහ භාරකරුවන් පුහුණු කිරීම සඳහා බේකරියක් සමඟ නවීනතම මුළුතැන්ගෙයකින් ද එය සමන්විත වේ. වැඩිදුර පුහුණුව සඳහා ඔවුන් ඉන්දීය සහ පකිස්ථාන නාවික හමුදා ආහාරපාන පාසල් වෙත යවනු ලැබේ. නාවික හමුදාව විසින් ජනාධිපති මන්දිරයට සහ අරලියගහ මන්දිරයට ඉතා දිගු කාලයක් සේවය කිරීම සඳහා අරක්කැමියන් සහ භාරකරුවන් සපයා ඇති අතර, පැමිණෙන රාජ්‍ය නායකයින්ට උපහාර පිණිස පවත්වනු ලබන එදිනෙදා භෝජන සංග්‍රහ සහ භෝජන සංග්‍රහ හැසිරවීමට නාවික හමුදාව සමත් වේ.",
        "මුහුදේ ආහාර පිසීම දුෂ්කර කාර්යයකි. රළු මුහුදු තත්ත්‍වයේ දී, එය සුළි සුළඟින් නැව හෝ යාත්‍රාව පෙරළීම සහ තණතීරුව සමඟ බියකරු සිහිනයක් බවට පත්වේ. නමුත් අපේ කෝකියෝ කවදාවත් අපිව බඩගින්නේ තියන්නේ නැහැ!",
        "කෙසේ වෙතත්, එවැනි මුහුදු තත්වයන් තුළ ආහාර ගත හැක්කේ කිහිප දෙනෙකුට පමණි, අනෙක් අය 'මුහුදු අසනීප' වේ.",
        "ඔබ කුඩා යාත්‍රාවක හෝ FAC (Fast Attack Craft) නම්, කෝකියන් නොමැත. කාර්ය මණ්ඩල සාමාජිකයින් මුර සංචාරයේ යෙදී සිටියදී ඔවුන්ගේ ආහාර පිළියෙළ කිරීමට එක් වෙති. සමහර නාවිකයින් සහ සමුද්‍ර ඉංජිනේරු යාන්ත්‍රිකයින් විශිෂ්ට කෝකියෝ වෙති. මා OIC P 467 (Dovra) ලෙස සිටියදී මට එවැනි එක් නාවිකයෙක් සිටියේය, ප්‍රමුඛ ඉංජිනේරු කාර්මික ප්‍රේමරත්න; ඔහු මාස්ටර් ප්‍රධාන සුළු නිලධාරියා දක්වා ඉහළ ගියේය. ඔහු නිවාඩුවක් ගත කර ආපසු එන විට තම ගමෙන් නැවුම් එළවළු ගෙනැවිත් නැවෙන් රසවත් කෑම පිළියෙළ කළේය.",
