{
  "newspaper_id": "news-first-lk",
  "url": "https://www.newsfirst.lk/2022/07/07/long-queues-for-fuel-at-lioc-filling-stations/",
  "time_ut": 1657171200,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Long queues for fuel at LIOC filling stations",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Long queues for fuel at LIOC filling stations",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); Sri Lankans can be seen waiting in long queues for fuel, leading to the nearest Lanka IOC filling station, as the country struggles to contain a deepening economic crisis.",
        "Many tense situations have taken a place in several filling stations due to the lack of fuel.",
        "As a result, on Wednesday (6) a man from Digana climbed onto a post attached to high-voltage electricity cables to protest.",
        "Later, this man was rescued by personnel attached to the Ceylon Electricity Board and was rushed to the Theldeniya Hospital for treatment."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lankans",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "Wednesday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "6",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Digana",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the Ceylon Electricity Board",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Theldeniya Hospital",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "LIOC ඉන්ධන පිරවුම්හල්වල ඉන්ධන සඳහා දිගු පෝලිම්",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); රට ගැඹුරු වන ආර්ථික අර්බුදයක් පාලනය කිරීමට අරගල කරන විට ළඟම ඇති ලංකා IOC ඉන්ධන පිරවුම්හල වෙත යන ශ්‍රී ලාංකිකයන් ඉන්ධන සඳහා දිගු පෝලිම්වල රැඳී සිටිනු දැකිය හැකිය.",
        "ඉන්ධන නොමැතිවීම හේතුවෙන් ඉන්ධන පිරවුම්හල් කිහිපයක නොසන්සුන්කාරී තත්ත්වයන් රැසක් හටගෙන තිබෙනවා.",
        "එහි ප්‍රතිඵලයක් ලෙස බදාදා (6) දිගන ප්‍රදේශයේ පුද්ගලයකු අධි බලැති විදුලි රැහැනක සවිකර තිබූ කණුවකට නැග විරෝධය පළ කළේය.",
        "පසුව ලංකා විදුලිබල මණ්ඩලයේ නිලධාරීන් විසින් මෙම පුද්ගලයා බේරාගෙන ප්‍රතිකාර සඳහා තෙල්දෙණිය රෝහලට ඇතුළත් කර තිබේ."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලාංකිකයන්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "බදාදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "6",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "දිගන",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ලංකා විදුලිබල මණ්ඩලය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "තෙල්දෙණිය රෝහල",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "LIOC எரிபொருள் நிரப்பும் நிலையங்களில் எரிபொருளுக்கான நீண்ட வரிசைகள்",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); ஆழமடைந்து வரும் பொருளாதார நெருக்கடியை கட்டுப்படுத்துவதற்கு நாடு போராடி வரும் நிலையில், இலங்கையர்கள் எரிபொருளுக்காக நீண்ட வரிசையில் காத்திருப்பதைக் காணமுடிகிறது.",
        "எரிபொருள் பற்றாக்குறையால் பல எரிபொருள் நிரப்பு நிலையங்களில் பதற்றமான சூழல் ஏற்பட்டுள்ளது.",
        "இந்நிலையில், புதன்கிழமை (6) திகன பிரதேசத்தைச் சேர்ந்த ஒருவர் உயர் அழுத்த மின்சார கேபிள்களில் பொருத்தப்பட்டிருந்த கம்பத்தில் ஏறி ஆர்ப்பாட்டத்தில் ஈடுபட்டார்.",
        "பின்னர், இந்த நபர் இலங்கை மின்சார சபையின் பணியாளர்களால் மீட்கப்பட்டு சிகிச்சைக்காக தெல்தெனிய வைத்தியசாலைக்கு கொண்டு செல்லப்பட்டார்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கையர்கள்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "புதன்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "6",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "திகன",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை மின்சார சபை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "தெல்தெனிய வைத்தியசாலை",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}