{
  "newspaper_id": "ada-derana-lk",
  "url": "http://www.adaderana.lk/news/83240/will-assist-sri-lanka-in-line-with-imf-policies-delegation-tells-president",
  "time_ut": 1656080100,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Will assist Sri Lanka in line with IMF policies, delegation tells President",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Will assist Sri Lanka in line with IMF policies, delegation tells President",
      "author": "",
      "body_lines": [
        "The visiting delegation of the International Monetary Fund (IMF) has assured President Gotabaya Rajapaksa that they would assist Sri Lanka in this crisis situation in compliance with the IMF policies.",
        "The discussion between President Rajapaksa and the IMF delegates took place at the President’s House in Colombo this evening (June 24).",
        "The first in-person talks with the IMF delegation on Sri Lanka’s bailout request commenced in Colombo on Monday (June 20) and are going on for 10 days. Prime Minister Ranil Wickremesinghe met with the visiting IMF delegates who arrived on the island for talks on a bailout programme as Sri Lanka is battling its worst financial crisis since independence in 1948.",
        "The delegation briefed the President on the discussions held with the prime minister and the officials of the Central Bank and Finance Ministry.",
        "President Rajapaksa has meanwhile expressed gratitude to the IMF delegation for extending support to Sri Lanka for a way out of this dire situation."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Sri Lanka",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "the International Monetary Fund",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Gotabaya Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "IMF",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "this evening",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "June 24",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "first",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "IMF",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka’s",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Monday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "June 20",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "10 days",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "1948",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the Central Bank",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "IMF",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "ජාත්‍යන්තර මූල්‍ය අරමුදලේ ප්‍රතිපත්තිවලට අනුකූලව ශ්‍රී ලංකාවට සහාය දෙන බව නියෝජිත පිරිස ජනපතිට කියයි",
      "author": "",
      "body_lines": [
        "ජාත්‍යන්තර මූල්‍ය අරමුදලේ (IMF) සංචාරයක නිරත වූ ජාත්‍යන්තර මූල්‍ය අරමුදලේ (IMF) නියෝජිත පිරිස IMF ප්‍රතිපත්තිවලට අනුකූලව මෙම අර්බුදකාරී තත්ත්වයේදී ශ්‍රී ලංකාවට සහාය දෙන බවට ජනාධිපති ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ මහතාට සහතික වී තිබේ.",
        "ජනාධිපති රාජපක්ෂ මහතා සහ IMF නියෝජිතයින් අතර සාකච්ඡාව අද (ජුනි 24) සවස කොළඹ ජනාධිපති මන්දිරයේදී පැවැත්විණි.",
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ ඇපදීමේ ඉල්ලීම සම්බන්ධයෙන් ජාත්‍යන්තර මූල්‍ය අරමුදලේ නියෝජිතයන් සමඟ පළමු පුද්ගල සාකච්ඡාව සඳුදා (ජුනි 20) කොළඹදී ආරම්භ වූ අතර එය දින 10ක් පුරා පැවැත්වේ. 1948 නිදහසින් පසු ශ්‍රී ලංකාව දරුණුතම මූල්‍ය අර්බුදයකට මුහුණ දී සිටින බැවින් ඇපදීමේ වැඩසටහනක් පිළිබඳ සාකච්ඡා සඳහා දිවයිනට පැමිණි IMF නියෝජිතයින් අගමැති රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතා හමුවිය.",
        "අග්‍රාමාත්‍යවරයා සහ ශ්‍රී ලංකා මහ බැංකුවේ සහ මුදල් අමාත්‍යාංශයේ නිලධාරීන් සමඟ පැවති සාකච්ඡා පිළිබඳව නියෝජිත පිරිස ජනාධිපතිතුමා දැනුවත් කළහ.",
        "මෙම භයානක තත්ත්වයෙන් ගොඩ ඒම සඳහා ශ්‍රී ලංකාවට සහය ලබා දීම සම්බන්ධයෙන් ජාමූඅ දූත පිරිසට ජනාධිපතිතුමා කෘතඥතාව පළ කර තිබේ."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ජාත්‍යන්තර මුල්‍ය අරමුදල",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "IMF",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "අද සවස",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජූනි 24",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "පළමුවන",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "IMF",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "සඳුදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජූනි 20",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "දින 10 යි",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "1948",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "මහ බැංකුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "IMF",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "சர்வதேச நாணய நிதியத்தின் கொள்கைகளுக்கு இணங்க இலங்கைக்கு உதவுவதாக பிரதிநிதிகள் குழு ஜனாதிபதியிடம் தெரிவித்துள்ளது",
      "author": "",
      "body_lines": [
        "இலங்கைக்கு விஜயம் செய்த சர்வதேச நாணய நிதியத்தின் (IMF) பிரதிநிதிகள், சர்வதேச நாணய நிதியத்தின் கொள்கைகளுக்கு இணங்கி இந்த நெருக்கடியான சூழ்நிலையில் இலங்கைக்கு உதவுவதாக ஜனாதிபதி கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ஷவிடம் உறுதியளித்துள்ளனர்.",
        "ஜனாதிபதி ராஜபக்ஷவிற்கும் சர்வதேச நாணய நிதியத்தின் பிரதிநிதிகளுக்கும் இடையிலான கலந்துரையாடல் இன்று (ஜூன் 24) மாலை கொழும்பில் உள்ள ஜனாதிபதி மாளிகையில் நடைபெற்றது.",
        "இலங்கையின் பிணையெடுப்பு கோரிக்கை தொடர்பாக சர்வதேச நாணய நிதியத்தின் பிரதிநிதிகளுடன் முதலாவது நேரில் பேச்சுவார்த்தை திங்கட்கிழமை (ஜூன் 20) கொழும்பில் ஆரம்பமாகி 10 நாட்களாக நடைபெற்று வருகின்றது. 1948 ஆம் ஆண்டு சுதந்திரம் பெற்ற பின்னர் இலங்கை மிக மோசமான நிதி நெருக்கடியில் சிக்கித் தவிக்கும் நிலையில், பிணை எடுப்புத் திட்டம் தொடர்பான பேச்சுக்களுக்காக தீவுக்கு வருகை தந்த IMF பிரதிநிதிகளை பிரதமர் ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க சந்தித்தார்.",
        "பிரதமர் மற்றும் மத்திய வங்கி மற்றும் நிதி அமைச்சின் அதிகாரிகளுடன் இடம்பெற்ற கலந்துரையாடல்களை பிரதிநிதிகள் குழுவினர் ஜனாதிபதிக்கு விளக்கினர்.",
        "இதற்கிடையில், இந்த இக்கட்டான சூழ்நிலையில் இருந்து விடுபட இலங்கைக்கு ஆதரவை வழங்கிய சர்வதேச நாணய நிதியத்தின் பிரதிநிதிகளுக்கு ஜனாதிபதி ராஜபக்ஷ நன்றி தெரிவித்தார்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "இலங்கை",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "சர்வதேச நாணய நிதியம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ராஜபக்சே",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "IMF",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று மாலை",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜூன் 24",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "முதலில்",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "IMF",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கையின்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "திங்கட்கிழமை",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜூன் 20",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "10 நாட்கள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "1948",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "மத்திய வங்கி",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ராஜபக்சே",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "IMF",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  },
  "title": "Will assist Sri Lanka in line with IMF policies, delegation tells President",
  "body_lines": [
    "The visiting delegation of the International Monetary Fund (IMF) has assured President Gotabaya Rajapaksa that they would assist Sri Lanka in this crisis situation in compliance with the IMF policies.",
    "The discussion between President Rajapaksa and the IMF delegates took place at the President’s House in Colombo this evening (June 24).",
    "The first in-person talks with the IMF delegation on Sri Lanka’s bailout request commenced in Colombo on Monday (June 20) and are going on for 10 days. Prime Minister Ranil Wickremesinghe met with the visiting IMF delegates who arrived on the island for talks on a bailout programme as Sri Lanka is battling its worst financial crisis since independence in 1948.",
    "The delegation briefed the President on the discussions held with the prime minister and the officials of the Central Bank and Finance Ministry.",
    "President Rajapaksa has meanwhile expressed gratitude to the IMF delegation for extending support to Sri Lanka for a way out of this dire situation."
  ],
  "translate": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Will assist Sri Lanka in line with IMF policies, delegation tells President",
      "author": "",
      "body_lines": [
        "The visiting delegation of the International Monetary Fund (IMF) has assured President Gotabaya Rajapaksa that they would assist Sri Lanka in this crisis situation in compliance with the IMF policies.",
        "The discussion between President Rajapaksa and the IMF delegates took place at the President’s House in Colombo this evening (June 24).",
        "The first in-person talks with the IMF delegation on Sri Lanka’s bailout request commenced in Colombo on Monday (June 20) and are going on for 10 days. Prime Minister Ranil Wickremesinghe met with the visiting IMF delegates who arrived on the island for talks on a bailout programme as Sri Lanka is battling its worst financial crisis since independence in 1948.",
        "The delegation briefed the President on the discussions held with the prime minister and the officials of the Central Bank and Finance Ministry.",
        "President Rajapaksa has meanwhile expressed gratitude to the IMF delegation for extending support to Sri Lanka for a way out of this dire situation."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Sri Lanka",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "the International Monetary Fund",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Gotabaya Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "IMF",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "this evening",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "June 24",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "first",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "IMF",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka’s",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Monday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "June 20",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "10 days",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "1948",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the Central Bank",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "IMF",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "ජාත්‍යන්තර මූල්‍ය අරමුදලේ ප්‍රතිපත්තිවලට අනුකූලව ශ්‍රී ලංකාවට සහාය දෙන බව නියෝජිත පිරිස ජනපතිට කියයි",
      "author": "",
      "body_lines": [
        "ජාත්‍යන්තර මූල්‍ය අරමුදලේ (IMF) සංචාරයක නිරත වූ ජාත්‍යන්තර මූල්‍ය අරමුදලේ (IMF) නියෝජිත පිරිස IMF ප්‍රතිපත්තිවලට අනුකූලව මෙම අර්බුදකාරී තත්ත්වයේදී ශ්‍රී ලංකාවට සහාය දෙන බවට ජනාධිපති ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ මහතාට සහතික වී තිබේ.",
        "ජනාධිපති රාජපක්ෂ මහතා සහ IMF නියෝජිතයින් අතර සාකච්ඡාව අද (ජුනි 24) සවස කොළඹ ජනාධිපති මන්දිරයේදී පැවැත්විණි.",
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ ඇපදීමේ ඉල්ලීම සම්බන්ධයෙන් ජාත්‍යන්තර මූල්‍ය අරමුදලේ නියෝජිතයන් සමඟ පළමු පුද්ගල සාකච්ඡාව සඳුදා (ජුනි 20) කොළඹදී ආරම්භ වූ අතර එය දින 10ක් පුරා පැවැත්වේ. 1948 නිදහසින් පසු ශ්‍රී ලංකාව දරුණුතම මූල්‍ය අර්බුදයකට මුහුණ දී සිටින බැවින් ඇපදීමේ වැඩසටහනක් පිළිබඳ සාකච්ඡා සඳහා දිවයිනට පැමිණි IMF නියෝජිතයින් අගමැති රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතා හමුවිය.",
        "අග්‍රාමාත්‍යවරයා සහ ශ්‍රී ලංකා මහ බැංකුවේ සහ මුදල් අමාත්‍යාංශයේ නිලධාරීන් සමඟ පැවති සාකච්ඡා පිළිබඳව නියෝජිත පිරිස ජනාධිපතිතුමා දැනුවත් කළහ.",
        "මෙම භයානක තත්ත්වයෙන් ගොඩ ඒම සඳහා ශ්‍රී ලංකාවට සහය ලබා දීම සම්බන්ධයෙන් ජාමූඅ දූත පිරිසට ජනාධිපතිතුමා කෘතඥතාව පළ කර තිබේ."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ජාත්‍යන්තර මුල්‍ය අරමුදල",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "IMF",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "අද සවස",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජූනි 24",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "පළමුවන",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "IMF",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "සඳුදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජූනි 20",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "දින 10 යි",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "1948",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "මහ බැංකුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "IMF",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "சர்வதேச நாணய நிதியத்தின் கொள்கைகளுக்கு இணங்க இலங்கைக்கு உதவுவதாக பிரதிநிதிகள் குழு ஜனாதிபதியிடம் தெரிவித்துள்ளது",
      "author": "",
      "body_lines": [
        "இலங்கைக்கு விஜயம் செய்த சர்வதேச நாணய நிதியத்தின் (IMF) பிரதிநிதிகள், சர்வதேச நாணய நிதியத்தின் கொள்கைகளுக்கு இணங்கி இந்த நெருக்கடியான சூழ்நிலையில் இலங்கைக்கு உதவுவதாக ஜனாதிபதி கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ஷவிடம் உறுதியளித்துள்ளனர்.",
        "ஜனாதிபதி ராஜபக்ஷவிற்கும் சர்வதேச நாணய நிதியத்தின் பிரதிநிதிகளுக்கும் இடையிலான கலந்துரையாடல் இன்று (ஜூன் 24) மாலை கொழும்பில் உள்ள ஜனாதிபதி மாளிகையில் நடைபெற்றது.",
        "இலங்கையின் பிணையெடுப்பு கோரிக்கை தொடர்பாக சர்வதேச நாணய நிதியத்தின் பிரதிநிதிகளுடன் முதலாவது நேரில் பேச்சுவார்த்தை திங்கட்கிழமை (ஜூன் 20) கொழும்பில் ஆரம்பமாகி 10 நாட்களாக நடைபெற்று வருகின்றது. 1948 ஆம் ஆண்டு சுதந்திரம் பெற்ற பின்னர் இலங்கை மிக மோசமான நிதி நெருக்கடியில் சிக்கித் தவிக்கும் நிலையில், பிணை எடுப்புத் திட்டம் தொடர்பான பேச்சுக்களுக்காக தீவுக்கு வருகை தந்த IMF பிரதிநிதிகளை பிரதமர் ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க சந்தித்தார்.",
        "பிரதமர் மற்றும் மத்திய வங்கி மற்றும் நிதி அமைச்சின் அதிகாரிகளுடன் இடம்பெற்ற கலந்துரையாடல்களை பிரதிநிதிகள் குழுவினர் ஜனாதிபதிக்கு விளக்கினர்.",
        "இதற்கிடையில், இந்த இக்கட்டான சூழ்நிலையில் இருந்து விடுபட இலங்கைக்கு ஆதரவை வழங்கிய சர்வதேச நாணய நிதியத்தின் பிரதிநிதிகளுக்கு ஜனாதிபதி ராஜபக்ஷ நன்றி தெரிவித்தார்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "இலங்கை",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "சர்வதேச நாணய நிதியம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ராஜபக்சே",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "IMF",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று மாலை",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜூன் 24",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "முதலில்",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "IMF",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கையின்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "திங்கட்கிழமை",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜூன் 20",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "10 நாட்கள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "1948",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "மத்திய வங்கி",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ராஜபக்சே",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "IMF",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}