{
  "newspaper_id": "ada-lk",
  "url": "https://www.ada.lk/breaking_news/TNA-ඩලස්ට---CWC-රනිල්ට/11-395562",
  "time_ut": 1658283638,
  "original_lang": "si",
  "original_title": "TNA ඩලස්ට - CWC රනිල්ට",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "TNA to Dallas - CWC to Ranil",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "It has been decided to give the support of the Dravida National Alliance to Member of Parliament Mr. Dallas Alahapperuma in the election to be held in Parliament today for the election of a new President.",
        "This decision was taken in a discussion held yesterday between the members of that party, Mr. Sajith Premadasa and Mr. Dallas Alahapperuma.",
        "Thus, all the 10 members of parliament of the Dravida National Alliance are going to vote for Mr. Dallas Alahapperuma.",
        "Meanwhile, Mr. Jeevan Thondaman says that the Ceylon Labor Congress has decided to support the Acting Prime Minister Mr. Ranil Wickramasinghe."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Dallas",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "the Dravida National Alliance",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Dallas Alahapperuma",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "yesterday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sajith Premadasa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Dallas Alahapperuma",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "10",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Dravida National Alliance",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Dallas Alahapperuma",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Jeevan Thondaman",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Ceylon Labor Congress",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickramasinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "TNA ඩලස්ට - CWC රනිල්ට",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "අද දිනයේදී නව ජනපතිවරයෙක් තෝරා පත්කර ගැනීම වෙනුවෙන් පාර්ලිමේන්තුවේ  පැවැත්වීමට නියමිත ඡන්ද විමසීමේදී ද්‍රවිඩ ජාතික සන්ධානයේ සහාය පාර්ලිමේන්තු මන්ත්‍රී ඩලස් අලහප්පෙරුම මහතාට ලබාදීමට තීරණය කර තිබේ.",
        "ඒම පක්ෂයේ මන්ත්‍රිවරු, විපක්ෂනායක සජිත් ප්‍රේමදාස හා ඩලස් අලහප්පෙරුම යන මහත්වරු අතර ඊයේ පැවැති සාකච්ඡාවකදී මෙම තීරණය ගෙන තිබේ.",
        "මේ අනුව ද්‍රවිඩ ජාතික සන්ධානයේ පාර්ලිමේන්තු මන්ත්‍රිවරු 10 දෙනාම ඩලස් අලහප්පෙරුම මහතා වෙනුවෙන් ඡන්දය භාවිත කිරීමට නියමිතය.",
        "මේ අතර ලංකා කම්කරු කොංග්‍රසය වැඩබලන අගමැති රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතාට සහාය දැක්වීමට තිරණය කළ බව ජිවන් තොණ්ඩමන් මහතා පවසයි."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ඩලස්",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ද්‍රවිඩ ජාතික සන්ධානය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඩලස් අලහප්පෙරුම",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ඊයේ",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "සජිත් ප්‍රේමදාස",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඩලස් අලහප්පෙරුම",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "10",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ද්‍රවිඩ ජාතික සන්ධානය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඩලස් අලහප්පෙරුම",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ජීවන් තොණ්ඩමන්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ලංකා කම්කරු කොංග්‍රසය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "டலஸுக்கு தமிழ்த் தேசியக் கூட்டமைப்பு - ரணிலுக்கு இ.தொ.கா",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "புதிய ஜனாதிபதியை தெரிவுசெய்வதற்காக இன்று பாராளுமன்றத்தில் நடைபெறவுள்ள தேர்தலில் பாராளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர் டலஸ் அழகப்பெருமவிற்கு திராவிட தேசியக் கூட்டமைப்பின் ஆதரவை வழங்க தீர்மானிக்கப்பட்டுள்ளது.",
        "அக்கட்சியின் உறுப்பினர்களான திரு.சஜித் பிரேமதாச மற்றும் திரு.டலஸ் அழகப்பெரும ஆகியோருக்கிடையில் நேற்று இடம்பெற்ற கலந்துரையாடலில் இந்தத் தீர்மானம் எடுக்கப்பட்டுள்ளது.",
        "இதனால் திராவிட தேசியக் கூட்டமைப்பின் நாடாளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர்கள் 10 பேரும் திரு.டலஸ் அழகப்பெருமவுக்கு வாக்களிக்க உள்ளனர்.",
        "இதேவேளை, பதில் பிரதமர் திரு ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்கவுக்கு இலங்கை தொழிலாளர் காங்கிரஸ் ஆதரவளிக்க தீர்மானித்துள்ளதாக ஜீவன் தொண்டமான் தெரிவித்துள்ளார்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "டல்லாஸ்",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "திராவிட தேசியக் கூட்டமைப்பு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "டலஸ் அழகப்பெரும",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "நேற்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சஜித் பிரேமதாச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "டலஸ் அழகப்பெரும",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "10",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "திராவிட தேசியக் கூட்டமைப்பு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "டலஸ் அழகப்பெரும",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஜீவன் தொண்டமான்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை தொழிலாளர் காங்கிரஸ்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}