{
  "newspaper_id": "lankadeepa-lk",
  "url": "https://www.lankadeepa.lk/latest_news/බිල්-නොගෙවූ-මැති-ඇමතිවරුන්-ගැන-පරිපාලන-ලේකම්ගෙන්-කතානායකට-ලිපියක්/1-618840",
  "time_ut": 1661589708,
  "original_lang": "si",
  "original_title": "බිල් නොගෙවූ මැති ඇමතිවරුන් ගැන පරිපාලන ලේකම්ගෙන් කතානායකට ලිපියක්",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "A letter from the Administrative Secretary to the Speaker about the ministers who did not pay their bills",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "Mr. M. P. K. Mayadunne, Secretary of the Ministry of State Administration, Home Affairs, Provincial Councils and Local Government, sent a letter to the Speaker Mr. Mahinda Yapa Abeywardena asking him to intervene to collect the arrears of the ministers who defaulted on the payment of house rent, water and electricity bills. A request has been made.",
        "The letter has further informed that appropriate action will be taken through the committees of the Parliament regarding the ministers who have defaulted on the payment of water and electricity bills and house rents.",
        "Thus, the relevant sections of the Parliament will act in this regard in the future.",
        "According to the Water Supply and Drainage Board, the number of Ministers who have defaulted in paying their water bills is close to 60.",
        "The amount to be collected by the board from the said ministers is over one crore rupees.",
        "Meanwhile, it is said from the sources of the Ministry of State Administration that ten ministers have defaulted on the rent payment for the quarters used by them.",
        "These house rents should be paid by the respective ministries to which those ministers belong."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "M. P. K. Mayadunne",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Ministry of State Administration",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Home Affairs",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Provincial Councils and Local Government",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Mahinda",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Yapa Abeywardena",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the Water Supply and Drainage Board",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "60",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "the Ministry of State Administration",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ten",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "the quarters",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        []
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "බිල් නොගෙවූ මැති ඇමතිවරුන් ගැන පරිපාලන ලේකම්ගෙන් කතානායකට ලිපියක්",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "ගෙවල් කුලී ,ජල  සහ  විදුලි බිල්පත් ගෙවීම පැහැර හැර සිටින මැති ඇමැතිවරුන්ගේ  ඒ හිඟ මුදල් අය කර ගැනීම සඳහා මැදිහත්වී කටයුතු කරන්නැයි   රාජ්‍ය පරිපාලන ස්වදේශ කටයුතු පළාත් සභා හා පළාත් පාලන අමාත්‍යාංශයේ ලේකම් එම්.එම්.පී.කේ මායාදුන්නේ මහතා කතානායක මහින්ද යාපා අබේවර්ධන මහතාට  ලිපියක් යොමු කරමින් ඉල්ලීමක් කර ඇත.",
        "ජල සහ  විදුලි  බිල්පත් , ගෙවල් කුලී  ගෙවීම පැහැර හැර  සිටින මැති ඇමැතිවරුන් සම්බන්ධයෙන්  පාර්ලිමේන්තුවේ   කමිටු  මාර්ගයෙන් සුදුසු  ක්‍රියාමාර්ගයක් ගන්නා ලෙසද එම  ලිපියෙන්  වැඩිදුරටත් දැනුම්දී  ඇත.",
        "මේ අනුව පාර්ලිමේන්තුවේ අදාළ අංශ  මේ සම්බන්ධයෙන් ඉදිරියේදී ක්‍රියාත්මක වනු ඇත.",
        "ජල සම්පාදන හා ජලා පවහන  මණ්ඩලය පවසන අන්දමට  ජල බිල්පත් ගෙවීම පැහැර හැර සිටින මැති ඇමැතිවරුන්ගේ  සංඛ්‍යාව 60 කට ආසන්නය.",
        "මණ්ඩලය එම මැති ඇමැතිවරුන්ගෙන් අය     කර ගැනීමට ඇති මුදල රුපියල් කෝටියකට අධිකය.",
        "මේ අතර මැති ඇමැතිවරුන්  දස දෙනෙකු පාවිච්චි කළ නිල නිවාස වෙනුවෙන් කුලී මුදල් ගෙවීමද  පැහැර හැර ඇතැයි රාජ්‍ය පරිපාලන අමාත්‍යාංශ ආරංචි  මාර්ගවලින්  පැවසෙයි.",
        "මේ ගෙවල් කුලී  ගෙවීම් කරනු ලැබිය යුතු වන්නේ එම ඇමැතිවරුන් අයත් අදාල අමාත්‍යාංශ විසිනි."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "M. P. K. මායාදුන්නේ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "රාජ්ය පරිපාලන අමාත්යාංශය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ස්වදේශ කටයුතු",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "පළාත් සභා සහ පළාත් පාලන",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "මහින්ද",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "යාපා අබේවර්ධන",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ජල සම්පාදන හා ජලාපවහන මණ්ඩලය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "60",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "රාජ්ය පරිපාලන අමාත්යාංශය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "දස",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "නිල නිවාස",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        []
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "பணம் கட்டாத அமைச்சர்கள் குறித்து சபாநாயகருக்கு நிர்வாக செயலாளர் கடிதம்",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "அரச நிர்வாகம், உள்நாட்டலுவல்கள், மாகாண சபைகள் மற்றும் உள்ளூராட்சி அமைச்சின் செயலாளர் திரு.எம்.பி.கே.மாயாதுன்னே, சபாநாயகர் மஹிந்த யாப்பா அபேவர்தனவுக்கு கடிதம் ஒன்றை அனுப்பி வைத்துள்ளார். வீட்டு வாடகை, குடிநீர், மின் கட்டணம் செலுத்த வேண்டும் என கோரிக்கை விடுக்கப்பட்டுள்ளது.",
        "நீர், மின் கட்டணம் மற்றும் வீட்டு வாடகை செலுத்துவதில் தவறிழைத்த அமைச்சர்கள் தொடர்பில் நாடாளுமன்றக் குழுக்களின் ஊடாக உரிய நடவடிக்கை எடுக்கப்படும் என அந்தக் கடிதத்தில் மேலும் தெரிவிக்கப்பட்டுள்ளது.",
        "இதனால் எதிர்காலத்தில் இது தொடர்பில் பாராளுமன்றத்தின் சம்பந்தப்பட்ட பிரிவுகள் செயற்படும்.",
        "நீர்வழங்கல் மற்றும் வடிகாலமைப்புச் சபையின் அறிக்கையின்படி நீர் கட்டணத்தை செலுத்த தவறிய அமைச்சர்களின் எண்ணிக்கை 60ஐ நெருங்குகிறது.",
        "மேற்படி அமைச்சர்களிடம் இருந்து வாரியம் வசூலிக்க வேண்டிய தொகை ஒரு கோடி ரூபாய்க்கு மேல்.",
        "இதேவேளை, பத்து அமைச்சர்கள் தாங்கள் பயன்படுத்திய குடியிருப்புகளுக்கான வாடகையை செலுத்த தவறியுள்ளதாக அரச நிர்வாக அமைச்சு வட்டாரங்கள் தெரிவிக்கின்றன.",
        "இந்த வீட்டு வாடகையை அந்த அமைச்சர்கள் எந்த அமைச்சகங்களுக்குச் செலுத்த வேண்டும்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "எம்.பி.கே. மாயாதுன்னே",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "மாநில நிர்வாக அமைச்சகம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "உள்நாட்டு விவகாரங்கள்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "மாகாண சபைகள் மற்றும் உள்ளூராட்சி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "மஹிந்த",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "யாப்பா அபேவர்தன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "நீர் வழங்கல் மற்றும் வடிகால் வாரியம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "60",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "மாநில நிர்வாக அமைச்சகம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "பத்து",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "காலாண்டுகள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        []
      ]
    }
  }
}