{
  "newspaper_id": "ada-lk",
  "url": "https://www.ada.lk/international/පකිස්ථානය-ගංවතුර-නිසා-මරණ-1-000-ඉක්මවා-තිබේ/3-396679",
  "time_ut": 1661737427,
  "original_lang": "si",
  "original_title": "පකිස්ථානය ගංවතුර නිසා මරණ 1,000 ඉක්මවා තිබේ",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Pakistan flood death toll surpasses 1,000",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "According to the figures released by Pakistan's National Disaster Management Authority, the death toll from monsoon floods in Pakistan since June has reached 1,033.",
        "119 people have died in the last 24 hours, and more than 33 million people have been affected by heavy rains since June, which continue to lash parts of the country.",
        "More than four million people have been affected by rising water levels, the government said, as thousands evacuated Pakistan's northern regions under an order on Saturday.",
        "An official in Sindh, a province in the south-east of the country, said the floods were worse than in 2010 and could be considered one of the worst in Pakistan's history.",
        "The 2010 floods killed at least 1,700 people across Pakistan, most of them from Sindh."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Pakistan",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "1,000",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Pakistan",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "National Disaster Management Authority",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Pakistan",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "June",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "1,033",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "119",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "the last 24 hours",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "more than 33 million",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "June",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "More than four million",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "thousands",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Pakistan",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Saturday",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sindh",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "2010",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Pakistan",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "2010",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "at least 1,700",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Pakistan",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sindh",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "පකිස්ථානය ගංවතුර නිසා මරණ 1,000 ඉක්මවා තිබේ",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "පාකිස්තානයේ ජාතික ආපදා කළමනාකරණ අධිකාරිය නිකුත් කළ සංඛ්‍යාලේඛනවලට අනුව ජුනි මාසයේ සිට පාකිස්තානයේ මෝසම් ගංවතුරෙන් මියගිය සංඛ්‍යාව 1,033 දක්වා ළඟා වී තිබේ.",
        "පසුගිය පැය 24 තුළ පුද්ගලයින් 119 දෙනෙකු මිය ගොස් ඇති අතර, ජුනි මාසයේ සිට ආරම්භ වූ අධික වර්ෂාවෙන් මිලියන 33කට වැඩි පිරිසක් පීඩාවට පත් වී ඇති අතර, රටේ ප්‍රදේශවලට අඛණ්ඩව පීඩා විඳිමින් සිටිති.",
        "සෙනසුරාදා නියෝගයක් අනුව පාකිස්ථානයේ උතුරු ප්‍රදේශවලින් දහස් ගණනක් ඉවත්ව යන විට රජය ප්‍රකාශ කළේ ජල මට්ටම් ඉහළ යාමෙන් මිලියන හතරකට අධික ජනතාවක් පීඩාවට පත්ව ඇති බවයි.",
        "රටේ ගිනිකොන දිග ප්‍රදේශයේ පිහිටි පළාතක් වන සින්ද් හි නිලධාරියෙකු පෙන්වා දුන්නේ ගංවතුර 2010 දී ඇති වූවාට වඩා දරුණු වන අතර එය පාකිස්තාන ඉතිහාසයේ දරුණුතම ගංවතුරෙන් එකක් ලෙස සැලකිය හැකි බවයි.",
        "2010 ගංවතුරෙන් පාකිස්තානය පුරා අවම වශයෙන් 1,700ක් මිය ගිය අතර ඔවුන්ගෙන් වැඩි දෙනෙක් සින්ද් ප්‍රදේශයෙන් පැමිණි අය වූහ."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "පකිස්ථානය",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "1,000 කි",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "පකිස්ථානය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජාතික ආපදා කළමනාකරණ අධිකාරිය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "පකිස්ථානය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජූනි",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "1,033 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "119",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "පසුගිය පැය 24",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "මිලියන 33 කට වඩා වැඩිය",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජූනි",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "මිලියන හතරකට වැඩියි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "දහස්",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "පකිස්ථානය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "සෙනසුරාදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "සින්ද්",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "2010",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "පකිස්ථානය",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "2010",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "අවම වශයෙන් 1,700",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "පකිස්ථානය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "සින්ද්",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "பாகிஸ்தானில் வெள்ளத்தில் சிக்கி உயிரிழந்தோர் எண்ணிக்கை 1000ஐ தாண்டியுள்ளது",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "பாகிஸ்தானின் தேசிய பேரிடர் மேலாண்மை ஆணையம் வெளியிட்டுள்ள புள்ளிவிவரங்களின்படி, ஜூன் மாதம் முதல் பாகிஸ்தானில் மழை வெள்ளத்தால் உயிரிழந்தவர்களின் எண்ணிக்கை 1,033ஐ எட்டியுள்ளது.",
        "கடந்த 24 மணி நேரத்தில் 119 பேர் இறந்துள்ளனர், மேலும் 33 மில்லியனுக்கும் அதிகமான மக்கள் ஜூன் மாதத்தில் இருந்து கடுமையான மழையால் பாதிக்கப்பட்டுள்ளனர், இது நாட்டின் சில பகுதிகளில் தொடர்ந்து பெய்து வருகிறது.",
        "சனிக்கிழமையன்று உத்தரவின் பேரில் பாகிஸ்தானின் வடக்குப் பகுதிகளிலிருந்து ஆயிரக்கணக்கானோர் வெளியேறியதால், நான்கு மில்லியனுக்கும் அதிகமான மக்கள் நீர் மட்டம் உயர்வதால் பாதிக்கப்பட்டுள்ளனர் என்று அரசாங்கம் தெரிவித்துள்ளது.",
        "நாட்டின் தென்கிழக்கில் உள்ள மாகாணமான சிந்துவில் உள்ள அதிகாரி ஒருவர், வெள்ளம் 2010 ஆம் ஆண்டை விட மோசமாக இருந்தது என்றும் பாகிஸ்தானின் வரலாற்றில் இது மிக மோசமான ஒன்றாக கருதப்படலாம் என்றும் கூறினார்.",
        "2010 வெள்ளத்தில் பாகிஸ்தான் முழுவதும் குறைந்தது 1,700 பேர் கொல்லப்பட்டனர், அவர்களில் பெரும்பாலோர் சிந்துவைச் சேர்ந்தவர்கள்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "பாகிஸ்தான்",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "1,000",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "பாகிஸ்தான்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "தேசிய பேரிடர் மேலாண்மை ஆணையம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாகிஸ்தான்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜூன்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "1,033",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "119",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "கடந்த 24 மணிநேரம்",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "33 மில்லியனுக்கும் அதிகமானவை",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜூன்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "நான்கு மில்லியனுக்கும் அதிகமானவை",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆயிரக்கணக்கான",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாகிஸ்தான்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சனிக்கிழமை",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "சிந்து",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "2010",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாகிஸ்தான்",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "2010",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "குறைந்தது 1,700",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாகிஸ்தான்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சிந்து",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}