{
  "newspaper_id": "news-first-lk",
  "url": "https://www.newsfirst.lk/2022/08/28/slpp-tells-president-to-appoint-state-ministers-if-all-party-govt-is-further-delayed/",
  "time_ut": 1661663940,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "SLPP tells President to appoint State Ministers, if All-Party Govt. is further delayed",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "SLPP tells President to appoint State Ministers, if All-Party Govt. is further delayed",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st): A group of Former State Ministers representing the Sri Lanka Podujana Peramuna have requested the President to immediately appoint State Minister, if the formation of an All-Party Government is further delayed.",
        "This was announced during a recent meeting between the Former State Ministers representing the Sri Lanka Podujana Peramuna and the President.",
        "Speaking to News 1st the SLPP General Secretary Attorney-at-Law Sagara Kariyawasam said that the Former State Ministers representing the Sri Lanka Podujana Peramuna met with the President with approval from the party.",
        "Moreover, the ruling faction parliamentary group will meet on Monday (29) at 5:00 PM for a meeting with the President.",
        "SLPP tells President to appoint State Ministers, if All-Party Govt. is further delayed"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "State Ministers",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "All-Party",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "News 1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "Podujana Peramuna",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "State",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "All-Party Government",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "Podujana Peramuna",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "Podujana Peramuna",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Monday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "29",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "5:00 PM",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "State Ministers",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "All-Party",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "සර්ව පාක්ෂික ආණ්ඩුවක් නම් රාජ්‍ය අමාත්‍යවරුන් පත් කරන ලෙස ශ්‍රී ලංකා පොදුජන පෙරමුණ ජනපතිට කියයි. තව දුරටත් ප්රමාද වේ",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st) : සර්ව පාක්ෂික ආණ්ඩුවක් පිහිටුවීම තවදුරටත් ප්‍රමාද වුවහොත් වහාම රාජ්‍ය අමාත්‍යවරයා පත් කරන ලෙස ශ්‍රී ලංකා පොදුජන පෙරමුණ නියෝජනය කරන හිටපු රාජ්‍ය අමාත්‍යවරුන් පිරිසක් ජනාධිපතිවරයාගෙන් ඉල්ලීමක් කර තිබේ.",
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකා පොදුජන පෙරමුණ නියෝජනය කරන හිටපු රාජ්‍ය අමාත්‍යවරුන් සහ ජනාධිපතිවරයා අතර පසුගියදා පැවති හමුවකදී මේ බව ප්‍රකාශ කෙරුණා.",
        "News 1st වෙත අදහස් දක්වමින් ශ්‍රී ලංකා පොදුජන පෙරමුණේ මහලේකම් නීතීඥ සාගර කාරියවසම් කියා සිටියේ ශ්‍රී ලංකා පොදුජන පෙරමුණ නියෝජනය කරන හිටපු රාජ්‍ය අමාත්‍යවරුන් පක්ෂයේ අනුමැතිය ඇතිව ජනාධිපතිවරයා හමුවූ බවයි.",
        "එපමණක් නොව, ආණ්ඩු පක්ෂයේ පාර්ලිමේන්තු කණ්ඩායම සඳුදා (29) පස්වරු 5.00 ට ජනාධිපතිවරයා හමුවීම සඳහා රැස්වේ.",
        "සර්ව පාක්ෂික ආණ්ඩුවක් නම් රාජ්‍ය අමාත්‍යවරුන් පත් කරන ලෙස ශ්‍රී ලංකා පොදුජන පෙරමුණ ජනපතිට කියයි. තව දුරටත් ප්රමාද වේ"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "රාජ්‍ය ඇමැතිවරු",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "සර්ව පාක්ෂිකයි",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "News 1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "පොදුජන පෙරමුණ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "රජයේ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "සර්ව පාක්ෂික ආණ්ඩුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "පොදුජන පෙරමුණ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "පොදුජන පෙරමුණ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "සඳුදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "29",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "5:00 ප.ව",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "රාජ්‍ය ඇමැතිවරු",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "සර්ව පාක්ෂිකයි",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "சர்வகட்சி அரசாங்கம் இருந்தால், அரச அமைச்சர்களை நியமிக்குமாறு ஜனாதிபதியிடம் SLPP கூறுகிறது. மேலும் தாமதமாகிறது",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st) : சர்வகட்சி அரசாங்கம் அமைப்பது மேலும் தாமதமானால் உடனடியாக இராஜாங்க அமைச்சரை நியமிக்குமாறு ஸ்ரீலங்கா பொதுஜன பெரமுனவை பிரதிநிதித்துவப்படுத்தும் முன்னாள் இராஜாங்க அமைச்சர்கள் குழு ஜனாதிபதியிடம் கோரிக்கை விடுத்துள்ளது.",
        "ஸ்ரீலங்கா பொதுஜன பெரமுனவை பிரதிநிதித்துவப்படுத்தும் முன்னாள் இராஜாங்க அமைச்சர்களுக்கும் ஜனாதிபதிக்கும் இடையில் அண்மையில் இடம்பெற்ற சந்திப்பின் போதே இந்த விடயம் தெரிவிக்கப்பட்டுள்ளது.",
        "ஸ்ரீலங்கா பொதுஜன பெரமுனவை பிரதிநிதித்துவப்படுத்தும் முன்னாள் இராஜாங்க அமைச்சர்கள் கட்சியின் அனுமதியுடன் ஜனாதிபதியை சந்தித்ததாக ஸ்ரீலங்கா பொதுஜன பெரமுனவின் பொதுச் செயலாளர் சட்டத்தரணி சாகர காரியவசம் News 1st க்கு கருத்து தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "மேலும், ஆளும் தரப்பு நாடாளுமன்றக் குழு எதிர்வரும் திங்கட்கிழமை (29) மாலை 5 மணிக்கு ஜனாதிபதியுடனான சந்திப்பிற்காக கூடவுள்ளது.",
        "சர்வகட்சி அரசாங்கம் இருந்தால், அரச அமைச்சர்களை நியமிக்குமாறு ஜனாதிபதியிடம் SLPP கூறுகிறது. மேலும் தாமதமாகிறது"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "மாநில அமைச்சர்கள்",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "அனைத்து கட்சி",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "News 1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "பொதுஜன பெரமுன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "நிலை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "அனைத்து கட்சி அரசு",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "பொதுஜன பெரமுன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "பொதுஜன பெரமுன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "திங்கட்கிழமை",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "29",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "மாலை 5:00",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "மாநில அமைச்சர்கள்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "அனைத்து கட்சி",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}