{
  "newspaper_id": "news-first-lk",
  "url": "https://www.newsfirst.lk/2022/07/27/us-sl-relations-can-flourish-in-a-sri-lanka-that-respects-human-rights-us-ambassador/",
  "time_ut": 1658926980,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "US – SL relations can flourish in a Sri Lanka that respects Human Rights – US Ambassador",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "US – SL relations can flourish in a Sri Lanka that respects Human Rights – US Ambassador",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st): US Ambassador to Sri Lanka Julie J. Chung called on President Ranil Wickremesinghe today (27), at the President's Office.",
        "In a tweet, the Ambassador said that President Ranil Wickremesinghe takes office at a time when Sri Lanka stands at a crossroads.",
        "She said they discussed how Sri Lanka arrived at this point of economic & political crisis, and how both sides can work together to navigate toward a brighter future for all.",
        "She further tweeted \"Our countries and our people have been friends and partners for more than 70 years, relationships that will flourish in a Sri Lanka that embraces good governance, respects human rights, and listens to the aspirations of its people.\".",
        "The President's Media Division in a statement said that the discussions were centered around strengthening ties between the country and taking forward relations, and the US Ambassador had assured support for the government's future endeavors.",
        "US – SL relations can flourish in a Sri Lanka that respects Human Rights – US Ambassador",
        "Attack on Journalists: MTV Network Gives Evidence to Human Rights Commission",
        "Shots fired in Gampaha; Four criminals including Pas Podda injured"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "US",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "Sri Lanka",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "US",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "News 1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "US",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "Julie J. Chung",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "27",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "more than 70 years",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Media Division",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "US",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "US",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "US",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "Gampaha",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Four",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Pas Podda",
            "label": "PRODUCT"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "මානව හිමිකම්වලට ගරු කරන ශ්‍රී ලංකාවක් තුළ අමෙරිකා - ශ්‍රී ලංකා සබඳතා වර්ධනය විය හැකියි - ඇමෙරිකානු තානාපති",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st) : ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ ඇමෙරිකානු තානාපතිනි Julie J. Chung මහත්මිය අද (27) ජනාධිපති කාර්යාලයේදී ජනාධිපති රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතා හමුවිය.",
        "ට්විටර් පණිවුඩයක් නිකුත් කරමින් තානාපතිවරයා කියා සිටියේ ජනාධිපති රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතා බලයට පත්වන්නේ ශ්‍රී ලංකාව සන්ධිස්ථානයක සිටින අවස්ථාවක බවයි.",
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකාව මෙම ආර්ථික හා දේශපාලන අර්බුදකාරී අවස්ථාවට පැමිණි ආකාරය සහ සැමට දීප්තිමත් අනාගතයක් කරා ගමන් කිරීම සඳහා දෙපාර්ශ්වයම එක්ව කටයුතු කළ හැකි ආකාරය පිළිබඳව ඔවුන් සාකච්ඡා කළ බව ඇය පැවසුවාය.",
        "\"අපේ රටවල් සහ අපේ ජනතාව වසර 70 කට වැඩි කාලයක් මිතුරන් සහ හවුල්කරුවන් ලෙස කටයුතු කර ඇති අතර, යහපාලනය වැළඳ ගන්නා, මානව හිමිකම්වලට ගරු කරන සහ එහි ජනතාවගේ අභිලාෂයන්ට සවන් දෙන ශ්‍රී ලංකාවක සබඳතා වර්ධනය වනු ඇත\" යනුවෙන් ඇය තවදුරටත් ට්වීට් කළාය.",
        "නිවේදනයක් නිකුත් කරමින් ජනාධිපති මාධ්‍ය අංශය සඳහන් කළේ, රට අතර සබඳතා ශක්තිමත් කර ගනිමින් සබඳතා ඉදිරියට ගෙන යාම සම්බන්ධයෙන් මෙම සාකච්ඡාවේ දී අවධානය යොමු වූ අතර, රජයේ ඉදිරි වැඩකටයුතු සඳහා සහය ලබාදෙන බවට අමෙරිකානු තානාපතිවරයා සහතික වූ බවයි.",
        "මානව හිමිකම්වලට ගරු කරන ශ්‍රී ලංකාවක් තුළ අමෙරිකා - ශ්‍රී ලංකා සබඳතා වර්ධනය විය හැකියි - ඇමෙරිකානු තානාපති",
        "මාධ්‍යවේදීන්ට පහරදීම: MTV ජාලය මානව හිමිකම් කොමිසමට සාක්ෂි දෙයි",
        "ගම්පහ වෙඩි තැබීමක්; පස් පොඩ්ඩා ඇතුළු අපරාධකරුවන් හතර දෙනෙකුට තුවාල"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "එක්සත් ජනපදය",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "එක්සත් ජනපදය",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "News 1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "එක්සත් ජනපදය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජුලී ජේ චුං",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "27",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "අවුරුදු 70 කට වැඩි කාලයක්",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "මාධ්ය අංශය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "එක්සත් ජනපදය",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "එක්සත් ජනපදය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "එක්සත් ජනපදය",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "ගම්පහ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "හතර",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාස් පොඩ්ඩා",
            "label": "PRODUCT"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "மனித உரிமைகளை மதிக்கும் இலங்கையில் அமெரிக்க – இலங்கை உறவுகள் மலர முடியும் – அமெரிக்க தூதுவர்",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st): இலங்கைக்கான அமெரிக்க தூதுவர் ஜூலி ஜே.சுங் இன்று (27) ஜனாதிபதி ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்கவை ஜனாதிபதி அலுவலகத்தில் சந்தித்தார்.",
        "இலங்கை ஒரு குறுக்கு வழியில் நிற்கும் தருணத்தில் ஜனாதிபதி ரணில் விக்ரமசிங்க பதவியேற்கிறார் என தூதுவர் டுவிட்டரில் தெரிவித்துள்ளார்.",
        "பொருளாதார மற்றும் அரசியல் நெருக்கடியின் இந்த கட்டத்தில் இலங்கை எவ்வாறு வந்தது என்பது குறித்தும், அனைவருக்கும் பிரகாசமான எதிர்காலத்தை நோக்கிச் செல்வதற்கு இரு தரப்பும் எவ்வாறு இணைந்து செயல்படுவது என்பது குறித்தும் அவர்கள் கலந்துரையாடியதாக அவர் கூறினார்.",
        "அவர் மேலும் ட்வீட் செய்துள்ளார், \"எமது நாடுகளும் நமது மக்களும் 70 ஆண்டுகளுக்கும் மேலாக நண்பர்களாகவும் பங்காளிகளாகவும் உள்ளனர், நல்லாட்சியை ஏற்றுக்கொள்ளும், மனித உரிமைகளை மதிக்கும் மற்றும் அதன் மக்களின் அபிலாஷைகளுக்கு செவிசாய்க்கும் இலங்கையில் உறவுகள் வளரும்.\"",
        "நாட்டிற்கு இடையிலான உறவுகளை வலுப்படுத்துவது மற்றும் நல்லுறவை முன்னெடுத்துச் செல்வது தொடர்பில் கலந்துரையாடப்பட்டதாகவும், அரசாங்கத்தின் எதிர்கால முயற்சிகளுக்கு ஆதரவளிப்பதாக அமெரிக்கத் தூதுவர் உறுதியளித்ததாகவும் ஜனாதிபதி ஊடகப் பிரிவு விடுத்துள்ள அறிக்கையில் தெரிவிக்கப்பட்டுள்ளது.",
        "மனித உரிமைகளை மதிக்கும் இலங்கையில் அமெரிக்க – இலங்கை உறவுகள் மலர முடியும் – அமெரிக்க தூதுவர்",
        "ஊடகவியலாளர்கள் மீதான தாக்குதல்: எம்டிவி நெட்வொர்க் மனித உரிமைகள் ஆணைக்குழுவிற்கு சாட்சியமளிக்கிறது",
        "கம்பஹாவில் துப்பாக்கிச் சூடு; பாஸ் போடா உட்பட நான்கு குற்றவாளிகள் காயமடைந்தனர்"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "எங்களுக்கு",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "இலங்கை",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "எங்களுக்கு",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "News 1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "எங்களுக்கு",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜூலி ஜே. சுங்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "27",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "70 ஆண்டுகளுக்கும் மேலாக",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஊடகப் பிரிவு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "எங்களுக்கு",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "எங்களுக்கு",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "எங்களுக்கு",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "கம்பஹா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "நான்கு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாஸ் போட்டா",
            "label": "PRODUCT"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}