{
  "newspaper_id": "lankadeepa-lk",
  "url": "https://www.lankadeepa.lk/latest_news/විදුලි-බිල-ඉහළ-දැමීමට-එරෙහිව-සජබ-පාර්ලිමේන්තුව-ඉදිරිපිට-විරෝධතාවයක/1-618930",
  "time_ut": 1661753178,
  "original_lang": "si",
  "original_title": "විදුලි බිල ඉහළ දැමීමට එරෙහිව සජබ පාර්ලිමේන්තුව ඉදිරිපිට විරෝධතාවයක",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Sajaba in a protest in front of Parliament against the increase in electricity bills",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "The MPs of Samagi Jana Balawega and Samagi Jana Sanandhana engaged in a silent protest in front of Parliament today (29) against the excessive increase in electricity bills.",
        "This protest was held under the leadership of Sajith Premadasa, the leader of Samagi Janabalawega and the leader of the opposition, under the theme, Stop corruption, reduce the electricity bill - the electricity bill is sky high, the whole country is dark.",
        "Members of Parliament of Samagi Janabalaweg Lakshman Kiriella, Tissa Attanayake, Gayantha Karunathila, Mano Ganeshan, Naleen Bandara, Dilip Vedaarachchi, Mujubar Rahman, Chaminda Wijesiri, Hector Appuhami and others were present for this occasion.",
        "The opposition leader had questioned whether the people are being put in trouble by increasing the electricity bills and inviting all-party governments to share the dollars received through the Norochchole coal power plant scam.",
        "The opposition leader said that even though the people are suffering so much, the government is working to drag the country further down the cliff with such scams.",
        "Joining the occasion, the opposition leader further said that neither the party of his relatives nor the media of his relatives can see these things."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Sajaba",
          "label": "PRODUCT"
        },
        {
          "text": "Parliament",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Samagi",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Jana Balawega",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Samagi",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Jana Sanandhana",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "29",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sajith Premadasa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Samagi Janabalawega",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Parliament of Samagi Janabalaweg Lakshman Kiriella",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Tissa Attanayake",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Gayantha Karunathila",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Mano Ganeshan",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Naleen Bandara",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Dilip Vedaarachchi",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Mujubar Rahman",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Chaminda Wijesiri",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Hector Appuhami",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Norochchole",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [],
        []
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "විදුලි බිල ඉහළ දැමීමට එරෙහිව සජබ පාර්ලිමේන්තුව ඉදිරිපිට විරෝධතාවයක",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "විදුලි බිල අධික ලෙස ඉහළ දැමීමට එරෙහිව සමගි ජන බලවේගයේ සහ සමගි ජන සන්ධානයේ මන්ත්‍රීවරුන් විසින් අද(29) පාර්ලිමේන්තුව ඉදිරිපිට දී නිහඬ විරෝධතාවයක නිරතවිය.",
        "දූෂණය නවතනු විදුලි බිල අඩු කරනු - විදුලි බිල අහසට මුළු රටම අඳුරට තේමාවෙන් සමගි ජනබලවේගයේ නායක සහ විපක්ෂ නායක සජිත් ප්‍රේමදාස මහතාගේ ප්‍රධානත්වයෙන් මෙම විරෝධතාවය පැවැත්විණ.",
        "මෙම අවස්ථාව සඳහා සමගි ජනබලවේගයේ  පාර්ලිමේන්තු මන්ත්‍රීවරුන් වන ලක්ෂ්මන් කිරිඇල්ල, තිස්ස අත්තනායක, ගයන්ත කරුණාතිල, මනෝ ගනේෂන්, නලීන් බණ්ඩාර, දිලීප් වෙදආරච්චි, මුජුබර් රහුමාන්,  චමින්ද විජේසිරි, හෙක්ටර්  අප්පුහාමි යන  මහත්වරුන් ඇතුළු පිරිසක් එක්ව සිටියහ.",
        "විදුලි බිල වැඩි කොට ජනතාව කබලෙන් ලිපට දමන අතර සර්වපාක්ෂික ආණ්ඩු බිහි කරන්නට ආරාධනා කරන්නේ, නොරොච්චෝලේ ගල් අඟුරු බලාගාර මගඩිය  හරහා හිමිවන ඩොලර් බෙදාගැනීමට දැයි විපක්ෂ නායකවරයා එහිදී ප්‍රශ්න කර සිටියේය.",
        "ජනතාව මෙතරම් පීඩාවට පත්ව සිටියදීත්,මෙවැනි මගඩි වලින් තව දුරටත් මෙරට ප්‍රපාතයට ඇද වැට්ටවීමට ආණ්ඩුව කටයුතු කරමින් සිටින බවත් විපක්ෂ නායකවරයා කීවේය.",
        "උන්ගේ නෑදෑයන්ගේ පක්ෂයට හෝ උන්ගේ නෑදෑයන්ගේ මාධ්‍ය වලට මේවා නොපෙනෙන බවත් එම අවස්ථාවට එක් වෙමින්  විපක්ෂ නායකවරයා තවදුරටත් කියා සිටියේය."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "සජාබා",
          "label": "PRODUCT"
        },
        {
          "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "සමගි",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජන බලවේගය",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "සමගි",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජන සනන්දන",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "29",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "සජිත් ප්‍රේමදාස",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "සමගි ජනබලවේග",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "සමගි ජනබලවේගයේ පාර්ලිමේන්තුව ලක්ෂ්මන් කිරිඇල්ල",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "තිස්ස අත්තනායක",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගයන්ත කරුණාතිල",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "මනෝ ගනේෂන්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "නලින් බණ්ඩාර",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "දිලිප් වෙදආරච්චි",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "මුජුබර් රහ්මාන්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "චමින්ද විජේසිරි",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "හෙක්ටර් අප්පුහාමි",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "නොරොච්චෝලේ",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [],
        []
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "மின்கட்டண உயர்வை கண்டித்து சஜபா நாடாளுமன்றம் முன்பு போராட்டம் நடத்தினார்",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "மின் கட்டண உயர்வை கண்டித்து சமகி ஜன பலவேக மற்றும் சமகி ஜன சனந்தன ஆகிய கட்சிகளின் பாராளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர்கள் இன்று (29) பாராளுமன்றத்திற்கு முன்பாக மௌன போராட்டத்தில் ஈடுபட்டனர்.",
        "ஊழலை நிறுத்து, மின்சாரக் கட்டணத்தைக் குறை - மின்சாரக் கட்டணம் விண்ணை முட்டும், நாடு முழுவதும் இருள் சூழ்ந்துள்ளது என்ற தொனிப்பொருளில் சமகி ஜனபலவேகவின் தலைவரும் எதிர்க்கட்சித் தலைவருமான சஜித் பிரேமதாச தலைமையில் இந்தப் போராட்டம் நடைபெற்றது.",
        "இந்நிகழ்வில் சமகி ஜனபலவெக் நாடாளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர்களான லக்ஷ்மன் கிரியெல்ல, திஸ்ஸ அத்தநாயக்க, கயந்த கருணாதில, மனோ கணேசன், நளீன் பண்டார, திலிப் வெதஆராச்சி, முஜுபர் ரஹ்மான், சமிந்த விஜேசிறி, ஹெக்டர் அப்புஹாமி மற்றும் பலர் கலந்துகொண்டனர்.",
        "நரோச்சோலை நிலக்கரி அனல்மின் நிலைய ஊழலின் ஊடாக பெறப்பட்ட டொலர்களை அனைத்துக் கட்சி அரசாங்கங்களையும் பகிர்ந்து கொள்ள அழைப்பதன் மூலமும் மின்சாரக் கட்டணத்தை அதிகரிப்பதன் மூலமும் மக்கள் சிரமத்திற்கு உள்ளாகின்றார்களா என எதிர்க்கட்சித் தலைவர் கேள்வி எழுப்பியிருந்தார்.",
        "மக்கள் இவ்வளவு துன்பங்களை அனுபவித்தாலும் இவ்வாறான மோசடிகள் மூலம் நாட்டை மேலும் குன்றின் கீழ் இழுக்கும் நோக்கில் அரசாங்கம் செயற்படுகின்றது என எதிர்கட்சி தலைவர் தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "இதில் கலந்து கொண்டு உரையாற்றிய எதிர்க்கட்சித் தலைவர் மேலும் தெரிவிக்கையில், தமது உறவினர்களின் தரப்பினரோ அல்லது தமது உறவினர்களின் ஊடகங்களோ இவற்றைப் பார்க்க முடியாது."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "சஜபா",
          "label": "PRODUCT"
        },
        {
          "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "சமகி",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜன பலவேகா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "சமகி",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜன சனந்தனா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "29",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "சஜித் பிரேமதாச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "சமகி ஜனபாலவேகா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "சமகி ஜனபலவெக் லக்ஷ்மன் கிரியெல்லவின் பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "திஸ்ஸ அத்தநாயக்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "கயந்த கருணாதில",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "மனோ கணேசன்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "நளீன் பண்டார",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "திலீப் வேதஆராச்சி",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "முஜுபர் ரஹ்மான்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "சமிந்த விஜேசிறி",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஹெக்டர் அப்புஹாமி",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "நோரோச்சோல்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [],
        []
      ]
    }
  }
}