{
  "newspaper_id": "d-b-s-jeyaraj-com",
  "url": "https://dbsjeyaraj.com/dbsj/archives/78496",
  "time_ut": 1657392480,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Thousands of Protesters  inspired by the three-month old ‘Aragalaya’ force  President Gotabaya Rajapaksa and Prime Minister Ranil Wickremesinghe to announce their resignations.",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Thousands of Protesters  inspired by the three-month old ‘Aragalaya’ force  President Gotabaya Rajapaksa and Prime Minister Ranil Wickremesinghe to announce their resignations.",
      "author": "Administrator",
      "body_lines": [
        "Dumbfounding constitutional pundits, the largely peaceful protestors in hundreds of thousands inspired by the three-month old ‘Aragalaya’ on Saturday forced President Gotabaya Rajapaksa and Prime Minister Ranil Wickremesinghe to announce their resignations.",
        "Defying shortage of fuel and public transport, anti-Rajapaksa people countrywide took to the street on Saturday and converged at GotaGoGama at Galle Face and Fort area and broke through barricades, withstood teargas and water cannon attacks and stormed the President’s House and Presidential Secretariat calling for his and interim-Government’s resignation over the failure to resolve the worst economic crisis in the country.",
        "President Rajapaksa was not present in either of the locations and his whereabouts still remain a secret.",
        "However, the besieged Gotabaya Rajapaksa conveyed to Speaker Mahinda Yapa Abeywardena that he will step down as President on Wednesday whilst people questioned the reasons for dating his exit instead of making it immediate or in a day.",
        "However, the announcement also followed all party leaders at a late evening meeting on Saturday requesting Rajapaksa to resign immediately.",
        "Prime Minister Ranil Wickremesinghe too told the party leaders that he was willing to resign as well and make way for an all-party Government to take over.",
        "The Prime Minister’s media office quoted Wickremesinghe as saying he is taking this decision in view of the fact that countrywide fuel distribution is due to recommence this week, the World Food Program Director is due to visit the country this week and the Debt Sustainability report for the IMF is due to be finalised shortly. So as to ensure safety of the citizens, he is agreeable to this recommendation by the Opposition Party Leaders.",
        "The GotaGoGama activists on Saturday presented six urgent demands including the immediate resignation of President Gotabaya Rajapaksa, Prime Minister Ranil Wickremesinghe and all in interim Government. The activists made a statement addressing the people and media from the President’s House, which saw large crowds for the second consecutive day yesterday.",
        "The impending ouster of the President and Prime Minister and the interim-Government came as the anti-Rajapaksa people’s movement via GotaGoHome and GotaGoGama marked its three months.",
        "The ‘Aragalaya’ drew much praise as well as criticism apart from many doubting its effectiveness. Constitutional experts insisted President Rajapaksa cannot be ousted whilst he himself refused to resign stating he does not want to do so as a “failed President” and assured relief and development before his tenure ends by late 2024.",
        "Global leaders and local activists yesterday called for a swifter and smoother transition of power as political parties scrambled to reach consensus on the way forward.",
        "The Bar Association of Sri Lanka yesterday urged all parties to understand the urgency of the situation and that a prompt and smooth transition of power is necessary to ensure important decisions relating to the economy and other areas are addressed. BASL also insisted the President’s resignation must not be delayed.",
        "Several private sector associations also called for a smoother and faster transition urging all political parties to put national interest first and work together to bring immediate relief to people and ensure good governance."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Thousands",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "three-month old",
          "label": "DATE"
        },
        {
          "text": "Gotabaya Rajapaksa",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "Ranil Wickremesinghe",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "hundreds of thousands",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "three-month old",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Saturday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Gotabaya Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "anti-Rajapaksa",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Saturday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Galle Face",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "Fort",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "House",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Presidential Secretariat",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Gotabaya Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Mahinda Yapa Abeywardena",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Wednesday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "a day",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "late evening",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "Saturday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Rajapaksa",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "this week",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the World Food Program",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "this week",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Debt Sustainability",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "IMF",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Opposition Party Leaders",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Saturday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "six",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Gotabaya Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "House",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the second consecutive day",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "yesterday",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "three months",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "The ‘Aragalaya’",
            "label": "WORK_OF_ART"
          },
          {
            "text": "Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "late 2024",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "yesterday",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "The Bar Association of Sri Lanka",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "yesterday",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "first",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "මාස තුනක් පැරණි ‘අරගලයෙන්’ ආභාෂය ලැබූ දහස් සංඛ්‍යාත විරෝධතාකරුවන් ජනාධිපති ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ මහතාට සහ අගමැති රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතාට සිය ඉල්ලා අස්වීම් ප්‍රකාශ කරන ලෙස බලකරති.",
      "author": "පරිපාලක",
      "body_lines": [
        "ගොළු ව්‍යවස්ථා පණ්ඩිතයන්, සෙනසුරාදා මාස තුනක් පැරණි ‘අරගලයෙන්’ ආභාසය ලැබූ ලක්ෂ සංඛ්‍යාත සාමකාමී විරෝධතාකරුවන්, ජනාධිපති ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂට සහ අගමැති රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහට සිය ඉල්ලා අස්වීම් ප්‍රකාශයට පත් කිරීමට බල කළහ.",
        "ඉන්ධන හිඟය සහ පොදු ප්‍රවාහන හිඟය නොතකා රටපුරා සිටින රාජපක්ෂ විරෝධී ජනතාව සෙනසුරාදා පාරට බැස ගාලුමුවදොර සහ කොටුව ප්‍රදේශයේ ගෝඨගෝගමට රැස්වී බාධක බිඳගෙන කඳුළු ගෑස් සහ ජල ප්‍රහාරවලට ඔරොත්තු දෙමින් ජනාධිපති මන්දිරයට සහ ජනාධිපති ලේකම් කාර්යාලයට කඩා වැදුණහ. රටේ දරුණුතම ආර්ථික අර්බුදය විසඳීමට අපොහොසත් වීම මත ඔහුගේ සහ අන්තර්වාර ආණ්ඩුවේ ඉල්ලා අස්වීම.",
        "ජනාධිපති රාජපක්ෂ එම ස්ථාන දෙකෙහිම නොසිටි අතර ඔහු සිටින ස්ථානය තවමත් රහසක්ව පවතී.",
        "කෙසේ වෙතත්, වටලනු ලැබූ ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ මහතා බදාදා තමා ජනාධිපති ධුරයෙන් ඉල්ලා අස්වන බව කථානායක මහින්ද යාපා අබේවර්ධන මහතාට දන්වා සිටියේ, ඔහු වහාම හෝ දිනකින් ඉවත් වීම වෙනුවට දින නියම කිරීමට හේතු මොනවාදැයි ජනතාව ප්‍රශ්න කරද්දී ය.",
        "කෙසේ වෙතත්, මෙම නිවේදනය සෙනසුරාදා සවස පැවති රැස්වීමකදී සියලුම පක්ෂ නායකයින් විසින් රාජපක්ෂට වහාම ඉල්ලා අස්වන ලෙස ඉල්ලා සිටියේය.",
        "අග්‍රාමාත්‍ය රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතාද පක්ෂ නායකයින්ට ප්‍රකාශ කළේ තමන්ද ඉල්ලා අස්වී සර්ව පාක්ෂික ආණ්ඩුවක් බලයට ගෙන ඒමට ඉඩ සැලසීමට සූදානම් බවයි.",
        "රටපුරා ඉන්ධන බෙදා හැරීම මේ සතියේදී යළි ආරම්භ කිරීමට නියමිත බැවින් ලෝක ආහාර වැඩසටහන් අධ්‍යක්ෂවරයා මේ සතියේ දිවයිනට පැමිණීමට නියමිත අතර ණය තිරසාර වාර්තාව සැලකිල්ලට ගනිමින් තමන් මෙම තීරණය ගන්නා බව වික්‍රමසිංහ උපුටා දක්වමින් අග්‍රාමාත්‍ය මාධ්‍ය කාර්යාලය සඳහන් කළේය. IMF නුදුරේදීම අවසන් කිරීමට නියමිතය. එබැවින් පුරවැසියන්ගේ ආරක්ෂාව තහවුරු කිරීම සඳහා ඔහු විරුද්ධ පක්ෂ නායකයින්ගේ මෙම නිර්දේශයට එකඟ වේ.",
        "ජනාධිපති ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ, අග්‍රාමාත්‍ය රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ ඇතුළු අන්තර්වාර ආණ්ඩුවේ සියලු දෙනා වහා ඉල්ලා අස්වීම ඇතුළු හදිසි ඉල්ලීම් හයක් ගෝඨගෝගම ක්‍රියාකාරීන් විසින් සෙනසුරාදා ඉදිරිපත් කළේය. ඊයේ අඛණ්ඩව දෙවන දිනටත් විශාල ජනකායක් පැමිණි ජනාධිපති මන්දිරයේ සිට ජනතාව සහ මාධ්‍ය අමතමින් ක්‍රියාකාරීන් ප්‍රකාශයක් කළේය.",
        "ජනාධිපතිවරයාගේ සහ අගමැතිවරයාගේ සහ අන්තර්වාර ආණ්ඩුවේ එලඹීමට නියමිත බලයෙන් නෙරපීම සිදු වූයේ රාජපක්ෂ විරෝධී ජනතා ව්‍යාපාරය GotaGoHome සහ GotaGoGama හරහා එහි තෙමස සනිටුහන් කරද්දීය.",
        "‘අරගලය’ බොහෝ ප්‍රශංසාවලට මෙන්ම විවේචනයට ද ලක් වූ අතර බොහෝ දෙනා එහි සඵලතාවය ගැන සැක පහළ කළහ. \"අසාර්ථක ජනාධිපති\" ලෙස ඉල්ලා අස්වීමට අවශ්‍ය නැති බව පවසමින් ඔහුම ඉල්ලා අස්වීම ප්‍රතික්ෂේප කළ අතර, 2024 අග භාගය වන විට ඔහුගේ ධුර කාලය අවසන් වීමට පෙර සහන සහ සංවර්ධනය සහතික කරන බව ව්‍යවස්ථා විශේෂඥයෝ අවධාරණය කළහ.",
        "දේශපාලන පක්ෂ ඉදිරි මාවතේ සම්මුතියකට එළැඹීමට පොරකද්දී ගෝලීය නායකයින් සහ ප්‍රාදේශීය ක්‍රියාකාරීන් ඊයේ ඉල්ලා සිටියේ කඩිනම් සහ සුමට බල සංක්‍රමණයක් සඳහා ය.",
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකා නීතීඥ සංගමය ඊයේ සියලු පාර්ශ්වයන්ගෙන් ඉල්ලා සිටියේ මෙම තත්ත්වයෙහි හදිසි අවශ්‍යතාව අවබෝධ කර ගන්නා ලෙසත් ආර්ථිකය සහ අනෙකුත් ක්ෂේත්‍ර සම්බන්ධ වැදගත් තීරණවලට විසඳුම් ලබා දීම සහතික කිරීම සඳහා කඩිනම් සහ සුමට බල සංක්‍රමණයක් අවශ්‍ය බවයි. ජනාධිපතිවරයාගේ ඉල්ලා අස්වීම ප්‍රමාද නොකළ යුතු බව ද BASL අවධාරණය කළේය.",
        "පුද්ගලික අංශයේ සංගම් කිහිපයක් ද ජාතික අවශ්‍යතාවලට මුල් තැන දී ජනතාවට කඩිනම් සහන ගෙන ඒමට සහ යහපාලනය සහතික කිරීමට එක්ව ක්‍රියා කරන ලෙස සියලු දේශපාලන පක්ෂවලින් ඉල්ලා සිටිමින් වඩාත් සුමට හා වේගවත් සංක්‍රාන්තියක් ඉල්ලා සිටියේය."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "දහස්",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "මාස තුනක් පැරණි",
          "label": "DATE"
        },
        {
          "text": "ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "සිය දහස් ගණනක්",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "මාස තුනක් පැරණි",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "සෙනසුරාදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "රාජපක්ෂ විරෝධී",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "සෙනසුරාදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගාලු මුවදොර",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "බලකොටුව",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "නිවස",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජනාධිපති ලේකම් කාර්යාලය",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "මහින්ද යාපා අබේවර්ධන",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "බදාදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "දවසක්",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ප්රමාද සවස",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "සෙනසුරාදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "මෙම සතිය",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ලෝක ආහාර වැඩසටහන",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "මෙම සතිය",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ණය තිරසාර බව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "IMF",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "විරුද්ධ පක්ෂ නායකයින්",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "සෙනසුරාදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "හය",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "නිවස",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "අඛණ්ඩව දෙවන දිනය",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඊයේ",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "මාස තුනක්",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "‘අරගලය’",
            "label": "WORK_OF_ART"
          },
          {
            "text": "රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "2024 අග",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ඊයේ",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකා නීතිඥ සංගමය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඊයේ",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "පළමුවන",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "மூன்று மாத பழமையான ‘அரகலய’ நடவடிக்கையால் ஈர்க்கப்பட்ட ஆயிரக்கணக்கான ஆர்ப்பாட்டக்காரர்கள் ஜனாதிபதி கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ஷ மற்றும் பிரதமர் ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க ஆகியோர் பதவி விலகுவதாக அறிவித்தனர்.",
      "author": "நிர்வாகி",
      "body_lines": [
        "முட்டாள்தனமான அரசியலமைப்பு பண்டிதர்கள், சனிக்கிழமையன்று மூன்று மாத பழமையான ‘அரகலயா’ மூலம் ஈர்க்கப்பட்ட நூறாயிரக்கணக்கான அமைதியான ஆர்ப்பாட்டக்காரர்கள் ஜனாதிபதி கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ஷ மற்றும் பிரதமர் ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க ஆகியோர் தங்கள் ராஜினாமாவை அறிவிக்க கட்டாயப்படுத்தினர்.",
        "எரிபொருள் மற்றும் பொதுப் போக்குவரத்து பற்றாக்குறையை மீறி, நாடு முழுவதும் உள்ள ராஜபக்ச எதிர்ப்பு மக்கள் சனிக்கிழமை வீதியில் இறங்கி, காலி முகத்திடல் மற்றும் கோட்டை பகுதியில் உள்ள கோட்டகோகமவில் ஒன்றுகூடி, தடுப்புகளை உடைத்து, கண்ணீர்ப்புகை மற்றும் தண்ணீர் பீரங்கித் தாக்குதலைத் தாங்கிக்கொண்டு, ஜனாதிபதி மாளிகை மற்றும் ஜனாதிபதி செயலகத்தை முற்றுகையிட்டனர். நாட்டின் மிக மோசமான பொருளாதார நெருக்கடியைத் தீர்க்கத் தவறியதற்காக அவரது மற்றும் இடைக்கால அரசாங்கத்தின் ராஜினாமா.",
        "ஜனாதிபதி ராஜபக்ஷ இரண்டு இடங்களிலும் இல்லை மற்றும் அவர் இருக்கும் இடம் இன்னும் இரகசியமாகவே உள்ளது.",
        "எவ்வாறாயினும், முற்றுகையிடப்பட்ட கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ஷ, ஜனாதிபதி பதவியில் இருந்து புதன்கிழமை விலகுவதாக சபாநாயகர் மஹிந்த யாப்பா அபேவர்தனவிடம் தெரிவித்தார். அதேவேளையில், உடனடியாக அல்லது ஒரு நாளில் அவர் வெளியேறுவதற்குப் பதிலாக தேதியிட்டதற்கான காரணங்களை மக்கள் கேள்வி எழுப்பினர்.",
        "எவ்வாறாயினும், அனைத்துக் கட்சித் தலைவர்களும் சனிக்கிழமை மாலை நடைபெற்ற கூட்டத்தில் ராஜபக்சேவை உடனடியாக ராஜினாமா செய்யுமாறு கோரியதைத் தொடர்ந்து இந்த அறிவிப்பு வெளியிடப்பட்டது.",
        "பிரதமர் ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்கவும் கட்சித் தலைவர்களிடம் தாம் பதவி விலகத் தயாராக இருப்பதாகவும், சர்வகட்சி ஆட்சியைக் கைப்பற்ற வழிவகை செய்யத் தயாராக இருப்பதாகவும் தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "நாடு தழுவிய எரிபொருள் விநியோகம் இந்த வாரம் மீள ஆரம்பிக்கப்படவுள்ள நிலையில், உலக உணவுத் திட்டப் பணிப்பாளர் இந்த வாரம் நாட்டிற்கு விஜயம் செய்யவுள்ளமை மற்றும் கடன் நிலைத்தன்மை அறிக்கை என்பனவற்றை கருத்திற்கொண்டு விக்ரமசிங்க இந்த தீர்மானத்தை எடுத்ததாக பிரதமரின் ஊடக அலுவலகம் தெரிவித்துள்ளது. IMF விரைவில் இறுதி செய்யப்பட உள்ளது. குடிமக்களின் பாதுகாப்பை உறுதி செய்யும் வகையில், எதிர்க்கட்சித் தலைவர்களின் இந்த பரிந்துரையை அவர் ஏற்றுக்கொள்கிறார்.",
        "ஜனாதிபதி கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ஷ, பிரதமர் ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க மற்றும் இடைக்கால அரசாங்கத்தில் உள்ள அனைவரும் உடனடியாக பதவி விலக வேண்டும் என்பன உள்ளிட்ட 6 அவசர கோரிக்கைகளை கோட்டகோகம செயற்பாட்டாளர்கள் சனிக்கிழமை முன்வைத்தனர். தொடர்ந்து இரண்டாவது நாளாக நேற்றும் பெருந்திரளான மக்கள் திரண்டிருந்த ஜனாதிபதி மாளிகையில் இருந்து மக்கள் மற்றும் ஊடகவியலாளர்களை நோக்கி செயற்பாட்டாளர்கள் ஒரு அறிக்கையை வெளியிட்டனர்.",
        "கோட்டகோஹோம் மற்றும் கோட்டகோகம ஊடாக ராஜபக்சவுக்கு எதிரான மக்கள் இயக்கம் தனது மூன்று மாதங்களைக் குறிக்கும் வேளையில் ஜனாதிபதி மற்றும் பிரதமர் மற்றும் இடைக்கால அரசாங்கத்தின் வரவிருக்கும் வெளியேற்றம் வந்தது.",
        "'அரகலயா' பல பாராட்டுக்களையும் விமர்சனங்களையும் ஈர்த்தது, மேலும் பலர் அதன் செயல்திறனை சந்தேகிக்கின்றனர். \"தோல்வியுற்ற ஜனாதிபதியாக\" பதவி விலக விரும்பவில்லை எனக் கூறி பதவி விலக மறுத்துள்ள நிலையில், 2024 ஆம் ஆண்டின் பிற்பகுதியில் அவரது பதவிக்காலம் முடிவடைவதற்குள் நிவாரணம் மற்றும் அபிவிருத்தியை உறுதியளித்த ஜனாதிபதி ராஜபக்ஷவை பதவி நீக்கம் செய்ய முடியாது என அரசியலமைப்பு நிபுணர்கள் வலியுறுத்தியுள்ளனர்.",
        "உலகளாவிய தலைவர்கள் மற்றும் உள்ளூர் ஆர்வலர்கள் நேற்று முன்னோக்கி செல்லும் வழியில் ஒருமித்த கருத்தை எட்ட அரசியல் கட்சிகள் துடித்து வரும் நிலையில், விரைவான மற்றும் சுமூகமான அதிகார மாற்றத்திற்கு அழைப்பு விடுத்தனர்.",
        "இலங்கை சட்டத்தரணிகள் சங்கம் நேற்று அனைத்து தரப்பினரையும் நிலைமையின் அவசரத்தை புரிந்து கொள்ளுமாறும், பொருளாதாரம் மற்றும் பிற துறைகள் தொடர்பான முக்கிய தீர்மானங்களை உறுதிப்படுத்துவதற்கு விரைவான மற்றும் சுமூகமான அதிகார மாற்றம் அவசியம் என வலியுறுத்தியுள்ளது. ஜனாதிபதியின் ராஜினாமாவை தாமதப்படுத்தக்கூடாது என்றும் BASL வலியுறுத்தியுள்ளது.",
        "பல தனியார் துறை சங்கங்களும், அனைத்து அரசியல் கட்சிகளும் தேச நலனுக்கு முதலிடம் கொடுக்கவும், மக்களுக்கு உடனடி நிவாரணம் வழங்கவும், நல்லாட்சியை உறுதிப்படுத்தவும் ஒன்றிணைந்து செயல்பட வேண்டும் என்று வலியுறுத்தி, சுமூகமான மற்றும் விரைவான மாற்றத்திற்கு அழைப்பு விடுத்தன."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ஆயிரக்கணக்கில்",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "மூன்று மாத வயது",
          "label": "DATE"
        },
        {
          "text": "கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ச",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "நூறாயிரக்கணக்கான",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "மூன்று மாத வயது",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சனிக்கிழமை",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ராஜபக்ஷ எதிர்ப்பு",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "சனிக்கிழமை",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "காலி முகம்",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "கோட்டை",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "வீடு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜனாதிபதி செயலகம்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ராஜபக்சே",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "மஹிந்த யாப்பா அபேவர்தன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "புதன்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஒரு நாள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "தாமதமான மாலை",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "சனிக்கிழமை",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ராஜபக்சே",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்த வாரம்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "உலக உணவு திட்டம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்த வாரம்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "கடன் நிலைத்தன்மை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "IMF",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "எதிர்க்கட்சி தலைவர்கள்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "சனிக்கிழமை",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆறு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "வீடு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "தொடர்ந்து இரண்டாவது நாள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "நேற்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "மூன்று மாதங்கள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "‘அரகலயா’",
            "label": "WORK_OF_ART"
          },
          {
            "text": "ராஜபக்சே",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "2024 இன் பிற்பகுதியில்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "நேற்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை சட்டத்தரணிகள் சங்கம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "நேற்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "முதலில்",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}