{
  "newspaper_id": "economy-next-com",
  "url": "https://economynext.com/sri-lanka-bond-markets-inactive-ahead-of-auction-guidance-peg-weakens-97246/",
  "time_ut": 1657529340,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Sri Lanka bond markets inactive ahead of auction, guidance peg weakens",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Sri Lanka bond markets inactive ahead of auction, guidance peg weakens",
      "author": "",
      "body_lines": [
        "ECONOMYNEXT – Sri Lanka’s bonds markets were dead ahead of bond auction, while a guidance peg for interbank spot transactions weakened by one rupee to 361.35 to the US dollars.",
        "Commercial banks were offering dollars for telegraphic transfers at rates between 368.35 and 370.00 for small transactions on July 11.",
        "Banks offered to buy inward remittances at 358.50 -360.00 rupees.",
        "Bond markets were inactive after a steep rise in rates last Wednesday followed by a smaller 100 basis rate hike.",
        "“No bonds or bills quoted as at this moment,” a dealer said.",
        "“There is a bond auction and all investors are waiting for that.”",
        "On July 09, protesters in Sri Lanka gathered in Colombo, pressuring both President Gotabaya Rajapaksa and the Prime Minister Ranil Wickremesinghe to resign from their posts.",
        "President Rjapaksa has announced that, he will be resigning from the post on July 13.",
        "The political uncertainty was also weighing on the market, dealers said. A train fare hike set for Monday has been delayed. (Colombo/July11/2022)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Sri Lanka",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka’s",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "one",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "361.35",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "US",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "368.35",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "370.00",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "July 11",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "358.50",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "-360.00",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "last Wednesday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "100",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "July 09",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Colombo",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Gotabaya Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Rjapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "July 13",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Monday",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "වෙන්දේසියට පෙර ශ්‍රී ලංකා බැඳුම්කර වෙලඳපොල අක්‍රියයි, මග පෙන්වීම දුර්වල වේ",
      "author": "",
      "body_lines": [
        "ECONOMYNEXT - බැඳුම්කර වෙන්දේසියට පෙර ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ බැඳුම්කර වෙලඳපොලවල් මිය ගිය අතර අන්තර් බැංකු ස්ථාන ගනුදෙනු සඳහා මාර්ගෝපදේශක අගයක් එක්සත් ජනපද ඩොලර් වලට රුපියලකින් 361.35 දක්වා දුර්වල විය.",
        "වාණිජ බැංකු ජුලි 11 වන දින කුඩා ගනුදෙනු සඳහා 368.35 සහ 370.00 අතර මිල ගණන් යටතේ විදුලි පණිවුඩ හුවමාරු සඳහා ඩොලර් ලබා දෙන ලදී.",
        "බැංකු විසින් රුපියල් 358.50 - 360.00 ට අභ්‍යන්තර ප්‍රේෂණ මිලදී ගැනීමට ඉදිරිපත් විය.",
        "බැදුම්කර වෙලඳපොලවල් පසුගිය බදාදා පොලී අනුපාත ඉහල යාමෙන් පසුව කුඩා 100 පදනම් අනුපාත ඉහල දැමීමකින් පසුව අක්රිය විය.",
        "“මේ මොහොතේ බැඳුම්කර හෝ බිල්පත් කිසිවක් උපුටා දක්වා නැත,” අලෙවි නියෝජිතයෙක් පැවසීය.",
        "\"බැඳුම්කර වෙන්දේසියක් පවතින අතර සියලුම ආයෝජකයින් ඒ සඳහා බලා සිටී.\"",
        "ජුලි 09 වෙනිදා ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ විරෝධතාකරුවන් කොළඹට රැස්ව, ජනාධිපති ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂට සහ අගමැති රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහට තම තනතුරුවලින් ඉල්ලා අස්වන ලෙස බලපෑම් කළහ.",
        "ජුලි 13 වැනිදා තමා එම ධුරයෙන් ඉල්ලා අස්වන බව ජනාධිපති රාජපක්ෂ මහතා ප්‍රකාශ කළේය.",
        "දේශපාලන අවිනිශ්චිතතාවය ද වෙළඳපොළට බර වෙමින් පවතින බව වෙළඳුන් පවසති. සඳුදා දිනට නියම කළ දුම්රිය ගාස්තු වැඩිවීම ප්‍රමාද වී තිබේ. (කොළඹ/ජූලි11/2022)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "එක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "361.35 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "එක්සත් ජනපදය",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "368.35 කි",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "370.00 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජූලි 11",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "358.50 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "-360.00",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ගිය බදාදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "100",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "ජූලි 09",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "කොළඹ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජූලි 13",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "සඳුදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "ஏலத்திற்கு முன்னதாக இலங்கைப் பத்திரச் சந்தைகள் செயலிழந்துள்ளன, வழிகாட்டல் பெக் பலவீனமடைகிறது",
      "author": "",
      "body_lines": [
        "ECONOMYNEXT - இலங்கையின் பத்திரச் சந்தைகள் பத்திர ஏலத்திற்கு முன்னதாகவே செயலிழந்தன, அதே சமயம் வங்கிகளுக்கிடையிலான ஸ்பாட் பரிவர்த்தனைகளுக்கான வழிகாட்டுதல் பெக் ஒரு ரூபாவால் பலவீனமடைந்து அமெரிக்க டாலருக்கு 361.35 ஆக இருந்தது.",
        "வணிக வங்கிகள் ஜூலை 11 அன்று சிறிய பரிவர்த்தனைகளுக்கு 368.35 முதல் 370.00 வரையிலான கட்டணத்தில் தந்தி பரிமாற்றங்களுக்கு டாலர்களை வழங்குகின்றன.",
        "வங்கிகள் 358.50 -360.00 ரூபாய்க்கு உள்நோக்கி அனுப்பும் பணத்தை வாங்க முன்வந்தன.",
        "கடந்த புதன்கிழமை விகிதங்களில் ஒரு செங்குத்தான உயர்வைத் தொடர்ந்து சிறிய 100 அடிப்படை விகித உயர்வுக்குப் பிறகு பத்திரச் சந்தைகள் செயலற்ற நிலையில் இருந்தன.",
        "\"இந்த நேரத்தில் மேற்கோள் காட்டப்பட்ட பத்திரங்கள் அல்லது பில்கள் எதுவும் இல்லை,\" என்று ஒரு வியாபாரி கூறினார்.",
        "\"ஒரு பத்திர ஏலம் உள்ளது மற்றும் அனைத்து முதலீட்டாளர்களும் அதற்காக காத்திருக்கிறார்கள்.\"",
        "ஜூலை 09 அன்று, இலங்கையில் போராட்டக்காரர்கள் கொழும்பில் கூடி, ஜனாதிபதி கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ச மற்றும் பிரதமர் ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க ஆகியோர் தங்கள் பதவிகளை ராஜினாமா செய்யுமாறு அழுத்தம் கொடுத்தனர்.",
        "ஜூலை 13ஆம் தேதி பதவியை ராஜினாமா செய்வதாக அதிபர் ராஜபக்ச அறிவித்துள்ளார்.",
        "அரசியல் நிச்சயமற்ற தன்மையும் சந்தையை எடைபோடுவதாக விற்பனையாளர்கள் தெரிவித்தனர். திங்கள்கிழமை நிர்ணயிக்கப்பட்ட ரயில் கட்டண உயர்வு தாமதமானது. (கொழும்பு/ஜூலை11/2022)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "இலங்கை",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கையின்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஒன்று",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "361.35",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "எங்களுக்கு",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "368.35",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "370.00",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜூலை 11",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "358.50",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "-360.00",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "கடந்த புதன்கிழமை",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "100",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஜூலை 09",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "கொழும்பு",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ர்ஜபக்ச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜூலை 13",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "திங்கட்கிழமை",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}