{
  "newspaper_id": "lankadeepa-lk",
  "url": "https://www.lankadeepa.lk/latest_news/විදුලි-බිල-වැඩි-කිරීම-කළ-යුතුම-දෙයක්/1-618934",
  "time_ut": 1661754235,
  "original_lang": "si",
  "original_title": "විදුලි බිල වැඩි කිරීම කළ යුතුම දෙයක්",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Increasing the electricity bill is a must",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "Electricity and Energy Minister Kanchana Wijesekera said in Parliament today (29) that although the increase in electricity bills is difficult for the people, looking at the board's expenses, this is something that must be done.",
        "He said this during the adjournment debate regarding the government's decision to increase the electricity bill.",
        "The minister mentioned that more than 7600 crore rupees have to be paid to the Electricity Board for renewable energy projects and private power plants and the amount to be paid to the Petroleum Statutory Corporation alone is 3100 crore rupees.",
        "He also said that although the electricity bill has been increased, relief has been provided to the low income earners.",
        "Mr. Wijesekera said that some of the tasks that could be done by the Electricity Board had been assigned to other departments in the past.",
        "He said that there are serious issues regarding the salaries and allowances of the employees of the Electricity Board and the Petroleum Statutory Corporation and that these institutions give the employees a 25 percent salary increase annually without any service evaluation."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Kanchana Wijesekera",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "29",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "more than 7600",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Electricity Board",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Petroleum Statutory Corporation",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "3100",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "Wijesekera",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Electricity Board",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the Electricity Board",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Petroleum Statutory Corporation",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "25 percent",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "annually",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "විදුලි බිල වැඩි කිරීම කළ යුතුම දෙයක්",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "විදුලි බිල වැඩිවීම ජනතාවට අමාරු වුණත් මණ්ඩලයේ වියදම දෙස බැලූවිට මෙය කළ යුතුම දෙයක් බව විදුලිබල හා බලශක්ති අමාත්‍ය කංචන විජේසේකර මහතා පාර්ලිමේන්තුවේදී අද (29) පැවැසීය.",
        "ඔහු මෙසේ පැවසුවේ විදුලි බිල  වැඩි කිරීමට රජය ගෙන ඇති තීරණය සම්බන්ධයෙන් පැවැති සභාව කල්තබන අවස්ථාවේ විවාදයේදීය.",
        "පුනර්ජනනීය බලශක්ති ව්‍යාපෘති වලට සහ පෞද්ගලික බලාගාර සඳහා විදුලිබල මණ්ඩලයට රුපියල් කෝටි 7600කට වැඩි මුදලක් ගෙවීමට ඇති බවත් ඛනිජ තෙල් නීතිගත සංස්ථාවට පමණක් ගෙවීමට ඇති මුදල රුපියල් කෝටි 3100 ක් බවත්  අමාත්‍යවරයා සඳහන් කළේය.",
        "විදුලි බිල වැඩි කළත් අඩු ආදායම්ලාභී අයට සහන සලසා ඇතැයිද ඔහු කීවේය.",
        "විදුලිබල මණ්ඩලයට කළ හැකි සමහර කටයුතු  වෙනත් අංශවලට පසුගිය කාලයේදී පවරාදී තිබූ බව පැවසූ විජේසේකර මහතා  මණ්ඩලයේ මාෆියාවට විරුද්ධව කටයුතු කිරීමේදී තමා තනිවූ අවස්ථා තිබෙන බවද ප්‍රකාශ කළේය.",
        "විදුලි බල මණ්ඩලයේ සහ ඛනිජ තෙල් නීතිගත සංස්ථාවේ සේවකයන්ගේ වැටුප් සහ දීමනා සම්බන්ධයෙන් බරපතළ  ප්‍රශ්න පවතින බවත් මෙම ආයතන සේවකයන්ට සියයට  25 ක වැටුප් වර්ධකයක් වාර්ෂිකව  ලබාදෙන්නේ සේවා ඇගයීමක්  කිරීමෙන් තොරව බවත් ඔහු පැවසුවේය."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "කාංචන විජේසේකර",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "29",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "7600 ට වැඩි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "විදුලිබල මණ්ඩලය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඛනිජ තෙල් ව්‍යවස්ථාපිත සංස්ථාව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "3100",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "විජේසේකර",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "විදුලිබල මණ්ඩලය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "විදුලිබල මණ්ඩලය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඛනිජ තෙල් ව්‍යවස්ථාපිත සංස්ථාව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "සියයට 25 කි",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "වාර්ෂිකව",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "மின் கட்டணத்தை உயர்த்துவது கட்டாயம்",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "மின்சாரக் கட்டண அதிகரிப்பு மக்களுக்கு சிரமமாக இருந்தாலும் சபையின் செலவீனங்களைப் பார்க்கும் போது இது கட்டாயம் செய்யப்பட வேண்டிய ஒன்று என மின்சாரம் மற்றும் எரிசக்தி அமைச்சர் காஞ்சன விஜேசேகர இன்று (29) பாராளுமன்றத்தில் தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "மின்சாரக் கட்டணத்தை அதிகரிக்க அரசாங்கம் எடுத்த தீர்மானம் தொடர்பான சபை ஒத்திவைப்பு வேளை விவாதத்தின் போதே அவர் மேற்கண்டவாறு தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "புதுப்பிக்கத்தக்க எரிசக்தித் திட்டங்கள் மற்றும் தனியார் மின் உற்பத்தி நிலையங்களுக்காக மின்சார சபைக்கு 7600 கோடி ரூபாவுக்கும் அதிகமான தொகை செலுத்தப்பட உள்ளதாகவும், பெற்றோலிய சட்டக் கூட்டுத்தாபனத்திற்கு மட்டும் செலுத்த வேண்டிய தொகை 3100 கோடி ரூபா எனவும் அமைச்சர் குறிப்பிட்டார்.",
        "மின்சாரக் கட்டணம் அதிகரிக்கப்பட்ட போதிலும் குறைந்த வருமானம் பெறுவோருக்கு நிவாரணம் வழங்கப்பட்டுள்ளதாகவும் அவர் கூறினார்.",
        "மின்சார சபையினால் செய்யக்கூடிய சில பணிகள் கடந்த காலங்களில் வேறு திணைக்களங்களுக்கு வழங்கப்பட்டுள்ளதாக திரு.விஜேசேகர தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "மின்சார சபை மற்றும் பெற்றோலிய சட்டக் கூட்டுத்தாபன ஊழியர்களின் சம்பளம் மற்றும் கொடுப்பனவுகள் தொடர்பில் பாரிய பிரச்சினைகள் காணப்படுவதாகவும், இந்த நிறுவனங்கள் எவ்வித சேவை மதிப்பீடும் இன்றி வருடாந்தம் 25 வீத சம்பள அதிகரிப்பை ஊழியர்களுக்கு வழங்குவதாகவும் அவர் தெரிவித்தார்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "காஞ்சனா விஜேசேகர",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "29",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "7600க்கு மேல்",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "மின்சார வாரியம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "பெட்ரோலியம் சட்டப்பூர்வ நிறுவனம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "3100",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "விஜேசேகர",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "மின்சார வாரியம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "மின்சார வாரியம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "பெட்ரோலியம் சட்டப்பூர்வ நிறுவனம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "25 சதவீதம்",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆண்டுதோறும்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}