{
  "newspaper_id": "lankadeepa-lk",
  "url": "https://www.lankadeepa.lk/news/කඩකප්පල්-ක්‍රියාවක්-ගැන-පොලිස්පතිගෙන්-ආරක්ෂක-ලේකම්ට-ලිපියක්/101-615862",
  "time_ut": 1656941067,
  "original_lang": "si",
  "original_title": "කඩකප්පල් ක්‍රියාවක් ගැන පොලිස්පතිගෙන් ආරක්ෂක ලේකම්ට ලිපියක්",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "A letter from the Inspector General of Police to the Secretary of Defense about an act of vandalism",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "Tomorrow (05) or tomorrow (06) on the occasion of the 'Black Tiger Celebration', a bomb attack, some sabotage will be carried out targeting the northern, eastern or southern province. T. T. e. Inspector General of Police C. D. Mr. Wickramaratne has sent a letter to Defense Secretary retired General Kamal Gunaratne and informed.",
        "In this article, it is stated that the relevant attack will be carried out by a group of members of a foreign intelligence service.",
        "Due to this, it is also mentioned in the letter that some notice has already been given to the personnel and dignitaries working in foreign institutions in the Jaffna area not to participate in any event during these two days.",
        "In the meantime, the Inspector General of Police has reported to him that the Janata Vimukthi Peramuna and frontline parties and opposition groups are planning to target local councilors and politicians and attack them and their homes in the future to put pressure on the government and embarrass the government. This article informed.",
        "Based on information from the Anti-Terrorism and Investigation Division, the Inspector General of Police forwarded this letter to the Defense Secretary on the 27th."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "the Inspector General of Police",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "Defense",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Tomorrow",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "05",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "tomorrow",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "06",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "the 'Black Tiger Celebration'",
            "label": "EVENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "T. T. e. Inspector General of Police C. D.",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Wickramaratne",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Defense",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "General Kamal Gunaratne",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "Jaffna",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "these two days",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the Inspector General of Police",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the Inspector General of Police",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Defense",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "කඩකප්පල් ක්‍රියාවක් ගැන පොලිස්පතිගෙන් ආරක්ෂක ලේකම්ට ලිපියක්",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "‘කළු කොටි සැමරුම’ යෙදෙන හෙට (05) හෝ අනින්දා (06) උතුරු, නැගෙනහිර හෝ දකුණු පළාත ඉලක්කකරගෙන බෝම්බ ප්‍රහාරයක්, යම් කඩාකප්පල්කාරී ක්‍රියාවක් කර එය එල්. ටී. ටී. ඊ. සංවිධානය විසින් කරන ලද්දක් යැයි ඒත්තු ගැන්වීමට සුදානමක් පවතින බවට විශේෂිත තොරතුරක් ලැබී ඇතැයි පොලිස්පති සී. ඩී. වික්‍රමරත්න මහතා ආරක්ෂක ලේකම් විශ්‍රාමික ජෙනරාල් කමල් ගුණරත්න මහතාට ලිපියක් යොමු කරමින් දැනුම් දී ඇත.",
        "මෙම ලිපියෙන් තොරතුර දැනුම් දෙන ආකාරයට අදාළ ප්‍රහාරය එල්ල කරනු ලබන බවට සඳහන් වන්නේ විදේශීය ඔත්තු සේවාවක සාමාජිකයන් පිරිසක් විසිනි.",
        "මේ හේතුවෙන් දැනටමත් යාපනය ප්‍රදේශයේ විදේශීය ආයතනවල සේවය කරන පිරිස් සහ ප්‍රභූවරුන්ට මෙම දින දෙක තුළ කිසිදු උත්සවයකට සහභාගී නොවන ලෙසට යම් දැනුම් දීමක් කර ඇතැයි ද එම ලිපියේ සදහන් වෙයි.",
        "මේ අතර, ඉදිරියේදී ප්‍රාදේශීය සභා මන්ත්‍රින් ඇතුළු දේශපාලනඥයන් ඉලක්ක කර ඔවුන්ට සහ ඔවුන්ගේ නිවාසවලට ද යම් ප්‍රහාරයක් එල්ල කර ඔවුන් මගින් රජයට බලපෑම්කර රජය අපහසුතාවට පත් කිරීම සදහා ජනතා විමුක්ති පෙරමුණ සහ පෙරටුගාමී පක්ෂවලින් සහ විපක්ෂ කණ්ඩායම් මගින් සැලසුම් කර ඇති බවට තමා වෙත වාර්තා කර ඇතැයි ද පොලිස්පතිවරයා මෙම ලිපියෙන් දැනුම් දී ඇත.",
        "ත්‍රස්ත මර්දන හා විමර්ශණ කොට්ඨාසයේ තොරතුරක් මත පදනම්කරගනිමින් පොලිස්පතිවරයා විසින් ආරක්ෂක ලේකම්වරයාට මෙම ලිපිය යොමුකරනු ලැබ ඇත්තේ ඉකුත් 27 දාතමින් යුතුවය."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "පොලිස්පති",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "ආරක්ෂක",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "හෙට",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "05",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "හෙට",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "06",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "'කළු කොටි සැමරුම'",
            "label": "EVENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "ටී.ටී.ඊ. පොලිස්පති සී.ඩී.",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "වික්‍රමරත්න",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ආරක්ෂක",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජෙනරාල් කමල් ගුණරත්න",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "යාපනය",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "මේ දවස් දෙක",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "පොලිස්පති",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "පොලිස්පති",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ආරක්ෂක",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "காழ்ப்புணர்ச்சிச் செயல் குறித்து காவல் கண்காணிப்பாளரிடமிருந்து பாதுகாப்புச் செயலாளருக்குக் கடிதம்",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "நாளை (05) அல்லது நாளை (06) 'கருப்புலிகள் கொண்டாட்டம்' நிகழ்வில் வடக்கு, கிழக்கு அல்லது தென் மாகாணத்தை இலக்கு வைத்து குண்டுத் தாக்குதல், சில நாசவேலைகள் மேற்கொள்ளப்படும். டி. டி. இ. காவல் கண்காணிப்பாளர் சி. டி. விக்ரமரத்ன, பாதுகாப்புச் செயலாளர் ஓய்வுபெற்ற ஜெனரல் கமல் குணரத்னவுக்கு கடிதம் ஒன்றை அனுப்பி தெரிவித்துள்ளார்.",
        "குறித்த தாக்குதலை வெளிநாட்டு புலனாய்வுப் பிரிவைச் சேர்ந்த குழுவொன்றே மேற்கொள்ளவுள்ளதாக இந்தக் கட்டுரையில் குறிப்பிடப்பட்டுள்ளது.",
        "இதன்காரணமாக யாழ்.மாவட்டத்தில் வெளிநாட்டு நிறுவனங்களில் பணிபுரியும் அதிகாரிகள் மற்றும் உயரதிகாரிகளுக்கு இவ்விரு நாட்களிலும் எந்தவொரு நிகழ்விலும் பங்குபற்ற வேண்டாம் என ஏற்கனவே சில அறிவித்தல் விடுக்கப்பட்டுள்ளதாகவும் கடிதத்தில் குறிப்பிடப்பட்டுள்ளது.",
        "இதற்கிடையில், ஜனதா விமுக்தி பெரமுன மற்றும் முன்னணி கட்சிகள் மற்றும் எதிர்க்கட்சிகள் உள்ளுராட்சி மன்ற உறுப்பினர்கள் மற்றும் அரசியல்வாதிகளை குறிவைத்து அவர்கள் மீதும் அவர்களின் வீடுகள் மீதும் தாக்குதல் நடத்த திட்டமிட்டுள்ளதாக பொலிஸ் மா அதிபர் தமக்கு அறிவித்துள்ளார். இந்த கட்டுரை தெரிவிக்கிறது.",
        "பயங்கரவாத எதிர்ப்பு மற்றும் புலனாய்வுப் பிரிவினரின் தகவலின் அடிப்படையில், பொலிஸ் மா அதிபர் கடந்த 27ஆம் திகதி பாதுகாப்புச் செயலாளருக்கு இந்தக் கடிதத்தை அனுப்பி வைத்துள்ளார்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "இன்ஸ்பெக்டர் ஜெனரல் ஆஃப் போலீஸ்",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "பாதுகாப்பு",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "நாளை",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "05",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "நாளை",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "06",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "'கருப்புலி கொண்டாட்டம்'",
            "label": "EVENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "டி.டி. இ. காவல் கண்காணிப்பாளர் சி.டி.",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "விக்கிரமரத்ன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாதுகாப்பு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜெனரல் கமல் குணரத்ன",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "யாழ்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்த இரண்டு நாட்கள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இன்ஸ்பெக்டர் ஜெனரல் ஆஃப் போலீஸ்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இன்ஸ்பெக்டர் ஜெனரல் ஆஃப் போலீஸ்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாதுகாப்பு",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}