{
  "newspaper_id": "d-b-s-jeyaraj-com",
  "url": "https://dbsjeyaraj.com/dbsj/archives/78284",
  "time_ut": 1656445260,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Ceylon Petroleum Corporation (CPC) owes debt and payments worth nearly $ 1 billion Reveals  Ranil Wickremesinghe:Prime Minister  exposes the bankruptcy of the State-owned entity which has aggravated the on-going fuel crisis and urgent procurement.",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Ceylon Petroleum Corporation (CPC) owes debt and payments worth nearly $ 1 billion Reveals  Ranil Wickremesinghe:Prime Minister  exposes the bankruptcy of the State-owned entity which has aggravated the on-going fuel crisis and urgent procurement.",
      "author": "Administrator",
      "body_lines": [
        "Ceylon Petroleum Corporation (CPC) owes debt and payments worth nearly $ 1 billion, Prime Minister Ranil Wickremesinghe revealed yesterday exposing the bankruptcy of the State-owned entity which has aggravated the on-going fuel crisis and urgent procurement.",
        "“With accumulated debt and other pending payments, the total due is almost $ 1 billion,” Wickremesinghe told a meeting with editors of print and electronic media where he explained the current economic situation including the emergency measures being taken to address the fuel crisis.",
        "Of the CPC dues, the two State banks’ burden is nearly $ 600 million.",
        "The Prime Minister implied a major catastrophe if one analyses the debt conundrum between the two State utilities – CPC and CEB combined along with the two State banks and the national carrier SriLankan Airlines. Previously, Wickremesinghe has said that SriLankan Airlines need to be privatised as it is a burden that the State and the people can no longer bear.",
        "He said the recently passed Sri Lanka Electricity (Amendment) Bill was one of the steps to improve energy security, efficiency and renewable energy generation. The Bill allows any person to apply for a power generation license to generate electricity of over 25 MW. He also said that Sri Lanka’s potential to become a renewable energy hub is immense with Mannar and Hambantota combined capable of generating an unprecedented 15 GW with massive export potential.",
        "Advisor to the Prime Minister Sagala Ratnayake updated the editors on the current status of the fuel situation in the country. He stated that a confirmed petrol shipment was due on 22 July whilst the Government was also attempting to secure fuel shipments at an early date. However, he explained that until those were confirmed the details would not be released.",
        "Ratnayake said efforts are underway to improve the supply of diesel from 11 July onwards and furnace oil as well.",
        "In terms of LPG, he said that $ 90 million has been set aside for import of 100,000 tons (enough for four months) with funding from the World Bank ($ 70 million) and $ 20 million from Litro. A tripartite agreement including the supplier will be signed this week.",
        "Initially, 33,000 tons of LPG procured by Litro at a cost of $ 20 million will reach Sri Lanka by 6 July and ready for distribution in the city limits from 8 July onwards.",
        "Separately, at the editors meeting, Senior Economic Advisor to the Prime Minister Dr. R.H. Samaratunga, also briefed on the economic situation and how the economy has reached a precarious position."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Ceylon Petroleum Corporation",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "CPC",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "nearly $ 1 billion",
          "label": "MONEY"
        },
        {
          "text": "Ranil Wickremesinghe",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "State",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Ceylon Petroleum Corporation",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "CPC",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "nearly $ 1 billion",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "yesterday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "State",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "almost $ 1 billion",
            "label": "MONEY"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "CPC",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "two",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "State",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "nearly $ 600 million",
            "label": "MONEY"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "two",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "State",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "CPC",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "CEB",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "two",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "State",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "SriLankan Airlines",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "SriLankan Airlines",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "State",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka Electricity",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "Bill",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "25",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "MW",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka’s",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Mannar",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "15",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "GW",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sagala Ratnayake",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "22 July",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "11 July",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "LPG",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "$ 90 million",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "100,000 tons",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "four months",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the World Bank",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "$ 70 million",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "$ 20 million",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "Litro",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "this week",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "33,000 tons",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "Litro",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "$ 20 million",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "6 July",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "8 July",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "R.H. Samaratunga",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "ලංකා ඛනිජ තෙල් නීතිගත සංස්ථාව (CPC) ඩොලර් බිලියනයකට ආසන්න ණය සහ ගෙවීම් රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ හෙළි කරයි: පවතින ඉන්ධන අර්බුදය සහ හදිසි ප්‍රසම්පාදනය උග්‍ර කර ඇති රජය සතු ආයතනයේ බංකොලොත්භාවය අගමැති හෙළි කරයි.",
      "author": "පරිපාලක",
      "body_lines": [
        "ලංකා ඛනිජ තෙල් නීතිගත සංස්ථාව (CPC) ඩොලර් බිලියනයකට ආසන්න ණය සහ ගෙවීම් ගෙවිය යුතු බව අග්‍රාමාත්‍ය රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතා ඊයේ අනාවරණය කළේ පවතින ඉන්ධන අර්බුදය සහ හදිසි ප්‍රසම්පාදනය උග්‍ර කර ඇති රාජ්‍ය ආයතනයේ බංකොලොත්භාවය හෙළිදරව් කරමිනි.",
        "“සමුච්චිත ණය සහ අනෙකුත් නොගෙවන ගෙවීම් සමඟ, ගෙවිය යුතු මුළු මුදල ඩොලර් බිලියනයකට ආසන්නයි,” වික්‍රමසිංහ මුද්‍රිත හා විද්‍යුත් මාධ්‍ය කතුවරුන් සමඟ පැවති රැස්වීමකදී ඉන්ධන අර්බුදය විසඳීමට ගෙන ඇති හදිසි පියවර ඇතුළු වත්මන් ආර්ථික තත්ත්වය පැහැදිලි කළේය.",
        "CPC හිඟ මුදලින් රාජ්‍ය බැංකු දෙකේ බර ඩොලර් මිලියන 600කට ආසන්නය.",
        "CPC සහ CEB යන රාජ්‍ය උපයෝගිතා දෙක අතර රාජ්‍ය බැංකු දෙක සහ ජාතික ගුවන් සේවය වන ශ්‍රීලංකන් ගුවන් සේවය සමඟ ඒකාබද්ධව ඇති ණය ප්‍රහේලිකාව විග්‍රහ කළහොත් විශාල ව්‍යසනයක් බව අග්‍රාමාත්‍යවරයා ඇඟවුම් කළේය. ශ්‍රී ලංකන් ගුවන් සේවය තවදුරටත් රජයට සහ ජනතාවට දරාගත නොහැකි බරක් බැවින් එය පෞද්ගලීකරණය කළ යුතු බව වික්‍රමසිංහ මීට පෙර ප්‍රකාශ කළේය.",
        "මෑතකදී සම්මත වූ ශ්‍රී ලංකා විදුලිබල (සංශෝධන) පනත් කෙටුම්පත බලශක්ති සුරක්ෂිතතාව, කාර්යක්ෂමතාව සහ පුනර්ජනනීය බලශක්ති උත්පාදනය වැඩිදියුණු කිරීමේ එක් පියවරක් බව ඔහු පැවසීය. මෙගාවොට් 25 ට වැඩි විදුලිය නිපදවීම සඳහා ඕනෑම පුද්ගලයෙකුට විදුලිබල උත්පාදන බලපත්‍රයක් සඳහා ඉල්ලුම් කිරීමට මෙම පනත් කෙටුම්පත මඟින් ඉඩ ලබා දේ. මන්නාරම සහ හම්බන්තොට ඒකාබද්ධව පුනර්ජනනීය බලශක්ති කේන්ද්‍රස්ථානයක් බවට පත්වීමට ශ්‍රී ලංකාවට ඇති හැකියාව අතිමහත් බවත්, දැවැන්ත අපනයන විභවයක් සහිත පෙර නොවූ විරූ ලෙස ගිගාවොට් 15ක් ජනනය කළ හැකි බවත් ඔහු පැවසීය.",
        "අග්‍රාමාත්‍ය උපදේශක සාගල රත්නායක මහතා රටේ ඉන්ධන තත්ත්වය පිළිබඳ වත්මන් තත්ත්වය පිළිබඳව කතුවරුන් වෙත යාවත්කාලීන කරන ලදී. තහවුරු කළ පෙට්‍රල් නැව්ගත කිරීමක් ජුලි 22 වන දිනට නියමිතව ඇති බවත්, ඉන්ධන තොග කඩිනමින් ලබා ගැනීමට රජය උත්සාහ කරමින් සිටින බවත් ඔහු ප්‍රකාශ කළේය. කෙසේ වෙතත්, ඒවා තහවුරු වන තුරු තොරතුරු ප්‍රකාශ නොකරන බව ඔහු පැහැදිලි කළේය.",
        "රත්නායක මහතා පැවසුවේ ජූලි 11 වැනිදා සිට ඩීසල් සැපයුම වැඩි දියුණු කිරීමට සහ උදුන තෙල් ද වැඩිදියුණු කිරීමට උත්සාහ දරන බවයි.",
        "LPG සම්බන්ධයෙන් ගත් කල, ලෝක බැංකුවේ (ඩොලර් මිලියන 70) අරමුදල් සහ ලිට්‍රෝ වෙතින් ඩොලර් මිලියන 20 ක් ටොන් 100,000 (මාස හතරකට ප්‍රමාණවත්) ආනයනය සඳහා ඩොලර් මිලියන 90 ක් වෙන් කර ඇති බව ඔහු පැවසීය. සැපයුම්කරු ඇතුළු ත්‍රෛපාර්ශ්වික ගිවිසුමක් මේ සතියේ අත්සන් කරනවා.",
        "මුලදී, ඩොලර් මිලියන 20 ක වියදමින් ලිට්‍රෝ සමාගම විසින් ලබා ගන්නා ලද LPG ටොන් 33,000 ක් ජූලි 6 වැනිදා වන විට ශ්‍රී ලංකාවට ළඟා වන අතර ජූලි 8 වැනිදා සිට නගර සීමාවේ බෙදා හැරීමට සූදානම් වේ.",
        "වෙනමම, කර්තෘ රැස්වීමේදී, අග්‍රාමාත්‍ය ජ්‍යෙෂ්ඨ ආර්ථික උපදේශක ආචාර්ය ආර්."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ලංකා ඛනිජ තෙල් නීතිගත සංස්ථාව",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "CPC",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "ඩොලර් බිලියන 1 කට ආසන්න",
          "label": "MONEY"
        },
        {
          "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "රජයේ",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ලංකා ඛනිජ තෙල් නීතිගත සංස්ථාව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "CPC",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඩොලර් බිලියන 1 කට ආසන්න",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඊයේ",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "රජයේ",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ආසන්න වශයෙන් ඩොලර් බිලියන 1",
            "label": "MONEY"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "CPC",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "දෙක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "රජයේ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඩොලර් මිලියන 600 කට ආසන්න",
            "label": "MONEY"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "දෙක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "රජයේ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "CPC",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ලංවිම",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "දෙක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "රජයේ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකන් ගුවන් සේවය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකන් ගුවන් සේවය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "රජයේ",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකා විදුලිය",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "බිල්පත්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "25",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "මෙ.වො",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මන්නාරම",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "15",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "GW",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "සාගල රත්නායක",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "22 ජූලි",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ජූලි 11",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "එල්.පී.ජී",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඩොලර් මිලියන 90 කි",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "ටොන් 100,000 කි",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "සිව් මාස",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ලෝක බැංකුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඩොලර් මිලියන 70 කි",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඩොලර් මිලියන 20 කි",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "ලිට්රෝ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "මෙම සතිය",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ටොන් 33,000 කි",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "ලිට්රෝ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඩොලර් මිලියන 20 කි",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "6 ජූලි",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "8 ජූලි",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ආර්.එච් සමරතුංග",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "இலங்கை பெற்றோலியக் கூட்டுத்தாபனம் (CPC) கிட்டத்தட்ட 1 பில்லியன் டொலர் பெறுமதியான கடன் மற்றும் கொடுப்பனவுகளை செலுத்த வேண்டியுள்ளது.",
      "author": "நிர்வாகி",
      "body_lines": [
        "இலங்கை பெற்றோலியக் கூட்டுத்தாபனம் (CPC) கிட்டத்தட்ட 1 பில்லியன் டொலர் பெறுமதியான கடன் மற்றும் கொடுப்பனவுகளை செலுத்த வேண்டியுள்ளது என பிரதமர் ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க நேற்று அம்பலப்படுத்தினார்.",
        "\"திரட்டப்பட்ட கடன் மற்றும் நிலுவையில் உள்ள பிற கொடுப்பனவுகளுடன், மொத்த நிலுவைத் தொகை கிட்டத்தட்ட $1 பில்லியன் ஆகும்,\" என்று விக்கிரமசிங்க அச்சு மற்றும் இலத்திரனியல் ஊடகங்களின் ஆசிரியர்களுடனான சந்திப்பில் கூறினார், அங்கு எரிபொருள் நெருக்கடியை எதிர்கொள்ள எடுக்கப்படும் அவசர நடவடிக்கைகள் உட்பட தற்போதைய பொருளாதார நிலைமையை விளக்கினார்.",
        "CPC நிலுவைத் தொகையில், இரண்டு ஸ்டேட் வங்கிகளின் சுமை கிட்டத்தட்ட $600 மில்லியன் ஆகும்.",
        "CPC மற்றும் CEB ஆகிய இரண்டு அரச வங்கிகள் மற்றும் தேசிய விமான நிறுவனமான ஸ்ரீலங்கன் ஏர்லைன்ஸுடன் இணைந்து இரண்டு மாநில பயன்பாட்டு நிறுவனங்களுக்கிடையில் உள்ள கடன் குழப்பத்தை ஒருவர் பகுப்பாய்வு செய்தால், பிரதமர் ஒரு பெரிய பேரழிவை சுட்டிக்காட்டினார். ஸ்ரீலங்கன் ஏர்லைன்ஸ் நிறுவனத்தை தனியார் மயமாக்குவது அரசும் மக்களும் இனியும் தாங்க முடியாத சுமையாக இருப்பதாக விக்கிரமசிங்க முன்னர் தெரிவித்திருந்தார்.",
        "அண்மையில் நிறைவேற்றப்பட்ட இலங்கை மின்சாரம் (திருத்தம்) சட்டமூலம் எரிசக்தி பாதுகாப்பு, செயல்திறன் மற்றும் புதுப்பிக்கத்தக்க ஆற்றல் உற்பத்தியை மேம்படுத்துவதற்கான நடவடிக்கைகளில் ஒன்றாகும் என்றார். 25 மெகாவாட்டிற்கு மேல் மின்சாரம் உற்பத்தி செய்ய எந்தவொரு நபரும் மின் உற்பத்தி உரிமத்திற்கு விண்ணப்பிக்க இந்த மசோதா அனுமதிக்கிறது. மன்னார் மற்றும் அம்பாந்தோட்டை இணைந்து பாரிய ஏற்றுமதி ஆற்றலுடன் முன்னோடியில்லாத வகையில் 15 GW உற்பத்தி செய்யும் திறன் கொண்ட இலங்கையின் புதுப்பிக்கத்தக்க எரிசக்தி மையமாக மாறுவதற்கான சாத்தியம் அபரிமிதமானது என்றும் அவர் கூறினார்.",
        "பிரதமரின் ஆலோசகர் சாகல ரத்நாயக்க, நாட்டின் எரிபொருள் நிலைமையின் தற்போதைய நிலை குறித்து ஆசிரியர்களுக்கு அறிவித்தார். ஜூலை 22 ஆம் தேதி உறுதிப்படுத்தப்பட்ட பெட்ரோல் ஏற்றுமதி செய்யப்பட உள்ளது என்றும், அதே நேரத்தில் எரிபொருள் ஏற்றுமதியை முன்கூட்டியே பாதுகாக்க அரசாங்கம் முயற்சித்து வருவதாகவும் அவர் கூறினார். எனினும், அவை உறுதிப்படுத்தப்படும் வரை விவரங்கள் வெளியிடப்படாது என்று அவர் விளக்கினார்.",
        "ரத்நாயக்க, ஜூலை 11 முதல் டீசல் விநியோகத்தை மேம்படுத்துவதற்கான முயற்சிகள் மேற்கொள்ளப்பட்டு வருவதாகவும், மேலும் உலை எண்ணெய் விநியோகத்தை மேம்படுத்தவும் முயற்சிகள் மேற்கொள்ளப்பட்டு வருவதாகவும் தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "எல்பிஜியைப் பொறுத்தவரை, உலக வங்கியின் ($ 70 மில்லியன்) நிதியுதவியுடன் 100,000 டன்கள் (நான்கு மாதங்களுக்குப் போதுமானது) இறக்குமதி செய்ய 90 மில்லியன் டாலர்கள் மற்றும் லிட்ரோவிலிருந்து 20 மில்லியன் டாலர்கள் ஒதுக்கப்பட்டுள்ளதாக அவர் கூறினார். சப்ளையர் உள்ளிட்ட முத்தரப்பு ஒப்பந்தம் இந்த வாரம் கையெழுத்தாகும்.",
        "ஆரம்பத்தில், லிட்ரோவினால் 20 மில்லியன் டொலர்கள் செலவில் கொள்வனவு செய்யப்பட்ட 33,000 தொன் எல்பிஜி ஜூலை 6 ஆம் திகதி இலங்கையை வந்தடையும் மற்றும் ஜூலை 8 ஆம் திகதி முதல் நகர எல்லைகளில் விநியோகிக்கத் தயாராக உள்ளது.",
        "தனித்தனியாக, ஆசிரியர் கூட்டத்தில், பிரதமரின் சிரேஷ்ட பொருளாதார ஆலோசகர் கலாநிதி ஆர்.எச்.சமரதுங்க, பொருளாதார நிலைமை மற்றும் பொருளாதாரம் எவ்வாறு ஆபத்தான நிலையை அடைந்துள்ளது என்பது குறித்தும் விளக்கினார்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "இலங்கை பெற்றோலியக் கூட்டுத்தாபனம்",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "CPC",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "கிட்டத்தட்ட $ 1 பில்லியன்",
          "label": "MONEY"
        },
        {
          "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "நிலை",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை பெற்றோலியக் கூட்டுத்தாபனம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "CPC",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "கிட்டத்தட்ட $ 1 பில்லியன்",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "நேற்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "நிலை",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "கிட்டத்தட்ட $1 பில்லியன்",
            "label": "MONEY"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "CPC",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இரண்டு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "நிலை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "கிட்டத்தட்ட $600 மில்லியன்",
            "label": "MONEY"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இரண்டு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "நிலை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "CPC",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "CEB",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இரண்டு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "நிலை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஸ்ரீலங்கன் ஏர்லைன்ஸ்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஸ்ரீலங்கன் ஏர்லைன்ஸ்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "நிலை",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை மின்சாரம்",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "ர சி து",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "25",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "மெகாவாட்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கையின்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "மன்னார்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "15",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜி.டபிள்யூ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "சாகல ரத்நாயக்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "22 ஜூலை",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "11 ஜூலை",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "எல்.பி.ஜி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "$ 90 மில்லியன்",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "100,000 டன்",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "நான்கு மாதங்கள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "உலக வங்கி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "$ 70 மில்லியன்",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "$ 20 மில்லியன்",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "லிட்ரோ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்த வாரம்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "33,000 டன்",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "லிட்ரோ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "$ 20 மில்லியன்",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "6 ஜூலை",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "8 ஜூலை",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஆர்.எச் சமரதுங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}