{
  "newspaper_id": "lankadeepa-lk",
  "url": "https://www.lankadeepa.lk/news/වෑන්---ත්‍රිරෝද-ගැටී-දෙකක්-මරුට:අයෙක්-රෝහලට/101-618652",
  "time_ut": 1661304937,
  "original_lang": "si",
  "original_title": "වෑන් - ත්‍රිරෝද ගැටී දෙකක් මරුට:අයෙක් රෝහලට",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Van - three-wheeler collision, two dead: one in hospital",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "According to Dodangoda Police, two people have died and another person has been seriously injured in a head-on collision between a van and a three-wheeler in Malabada area of ​​Dodangoda.",
        "The police said that the three-wheeler was going towards Kalutara from Matugama after getting fuel from Yadola petrol station, and the van was going towards Matugama from Kalutara.",
        "The police said that the two people who were traveling behind the three-wheeler died in the accident and they were residents of Sapugahawatta area in Dodangoda.",
        "It is also said that the condition of the three-wheeler driver who has been taken to the hospital is quite serious."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "three",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "two",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "one",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Dodangoda Police",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "two",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "three",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Malabada",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "​​Dodangoda",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "three",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kalutara",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Matugama",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Yadola",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Matugama",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kalutara",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "two",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "three",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Dodangoda",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "three",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "වෑන් - ත්‍රිරෝද ගැටී දෙකක් මරුට:අයෙක් රෝහලට",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "දොඩංගොඩ මලබඩ ප්‍රදේශයේ දී වෑන් රථයක් සහ ත්‍රීරෝද රථයක් මුහුණට මුහුණ ගැටී සිදුවූ රිය අනතුරකින් පුද්ගලයන් දෙදෙනකු මියගොස් තවත් පුද්ගලයකු බරපතළ තුවාල ලබා රෝහල් ගතකර ඇතැයි දොඩංගොඩ පොලිසිය පවසයි.",
        "ත්‍රීරෝද රථය යටදොල ඉන්ධන පිරවුම්හලෙන් ඉන්ධන ලබාගෙන මතුගම දෙස සිට කළුතර දෙසට යමින් සිට ඇති අතර , වැන් රථය කළුතර දෙස සිට මතුගම දෙසට යමින් සිටියදී මෙම අනතුර සිදුව ඇතැයි පොලිසිය කීය.",
        "අනතුරෙන් මියගොස් ඇත්තේ ත්‍රීරෝද රථයේ පසුපස ගමන්ගත් දෙදෙනා බවත් ඔවුන් දොඩංගොඩ සපුගහවත්ත ප්‍රදේශයේ පදිංචි කරුවන් බවත් පොලිසිය කීය.",
        "රෝහල් ගතකර ඇති ත්‍රීරෝද රථ රියදුරුගේ තත්ත්වයද තරමක් බරපතළ බවද සදහන් වේ."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "තුන්",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "දෙක",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "එක",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "දොඩංගොඩ පොලිසිය",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "දෙක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "තුන්",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "මලබඩ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "දොඩන්ගොඩ",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "තුන්",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "කළුතර",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "මතුගම",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "යදොල",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "මතුගම",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "කළුතර",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "දෙක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "තුන්",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "දොඩන්ගොඩ",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "තුන්",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "வேனும் முச்சக்கரவண்டியும் மோதி இருவர் பலி: ஒருவர் வைத்தியசாலையில்",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "தொடங்கொட, மலபட பகுதியில் வான் ஒன்றும் முச்சக்கரவண்டியும் நேருக்கு நேர் மோதியதில் இருவர் உயிரிழந்துள்ளதுடன் மேலும் ஒருவர் படுகாயமடைந்துள்ளதாக தொடங்கொட பொலிஸார் தெரிவித்தனர்.",
        "முச்சக்கரவண்டி யதோல எரிபொருள் நிரப்பு நிலையத்தில் இருந்து எரிபொருளை பெற்றுக்கொண்டு மத்துகமவிலிருந்து களுத்துறை நோக்கி சென்று கொண்டிருந்ததாகவும், வேன் களுத்துறையில் இருந்து மத்துகம நோக்கி சென்று கொண்டிருந்ததாகவும் பொலிஸார் தெரிவித்தனர்.",
        "முச்சக்கரவண்டியின் பின்னால் பயணித்த இருவர் விபத்தில் உயிரிழந்துள்ளதுடன், அவர்கள் தொடங்கொட சபுகஹவத்த பிரதேசத்தை சேர்ந்தவர்கள் எனவும் பொலிஸார் தெரிவித்தனர்.",
        "வைத்தியசாலையில் அனுமதிக்கப்பட்ட முச்சக்கரவண்டி சாரதியின் நிலைமை கவலைக்கிடமாக உள்ளதாகவும் தெரிவிக்கப்படுகின்றது."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "மூன்று",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "இரண்டு",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "ஒன்று",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "தொடங்கொட பொலிஸ்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இரண்டு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "மூன்று",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "மலபாடா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "தொடங்கொடா",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "மூன்று",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "களுத்துறை",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "மத்துகம",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "யதோலா",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "மத்துகம",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "களுத்துறை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இரண்டு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "மூன்று",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "தொடங்கொட",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "மூன்று",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}