{
  "newspaper_id": "lankadeepa-lk",
  "url": "https://www.lankadeepa.lk/latest_news/ගම්පහ-අධිකරණය-ඉදිරිපිට-වෙඩි-තැබීමක්/1-617120",
  "time_ut": 1658908362,
  "original_lang": "si",
  "original_title": "ගම්පහ අධිකරණය ඉදිරිපිට වෙඩි තැබීමක්",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "A shooting in front of the Gampaha court",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "According to hospital sources, a shooting took place in front of the Gampaha court today (27) and four injured people have been admitted to the Gampaha District General Hospital.",
        "This shooting was done by someone or a group of people who came in a vehicle and a group of people who came with him for a hearing.",
        "Responding to a query that the four injured in the incident are currently receiving treatment in the intensive care unit of the Gampaha hospital, the hospital director, Dr. Saman Pathirana, said."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Gampaha",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Gampaha",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "27",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "four",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Gampaha District General Hospital",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "four",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Gampaha",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Saman Pathirana",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "ගම්පහ අධිකරණය ඉදිරිපිට වෙඩි තැබීමක්",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "ගම්පහ අධිකරණය ඉදිරිපිටදී අද (27) දහවල් වෙඩි තැබීමක් සිදුව ඇති අතර මෙහිදී තුවාල ලැබූ පුද්ගලයින් සිව් දෙනෙකු ගම්පහ දිස්ත්‍රික් මහ රෝහලට ඇතුලත් කොට ඇති බව රෝහල් ආරංචි මාර්ග සඳහන් කරයි.",
        "නඩු විභාගයක් සදහා පැමිණි පස් පොඩ්ඩා නමැත්තා සහ ඔහු සමග පැමිණි පිරිසකට , වාහනයකින් පැමිණ ඇති යමෙකු හෝ පිරිසක් විසින් මෙම වෙඩි තැබීම සිදු කොට ඇත.",
        "සිද්ධියෙන් තුවාල ලැබූ සිව්දෙනා මේ වන විට ගම්පහ රෝහලෙහි දැඩි සත්කාර ඒකකයේ  ප්‍රතිකාර ලබන බව කළ විමසුමකට පිළිතුරු දෙමින් රෝහල් අධ්‍යක්ෂ විශේෂඥ වෛද්‍ය සමන් පතිරණ මහතා පැවසීය."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ගම්පහ",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ගම්පහ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "27",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "හතර",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගම්පහ දිස්ත්‍රික් මහ රෝහල",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "හතර",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගම්පහ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "සමන් පතිරණ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "கம்பஹா நீதிமன்றத்திற்கு முன்பாக துப்பாக்கிச் சூடு",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "கம்பஹா நீதிமன்றத்திற்கு முன்பாக இன்று (27) துப்பாக்கிச் சூடு இடம்பெற்றதாகவும், காயமடைந்த நால்வர் கம்பஹா மாவட்ட பொது வைத்தியசாலையில் அனுமதிக்கப்பட்டுள்ளதாகவும் வைத்தியசாலை வட்டாரங்கள் தெரிவிக்கின்றன.",
        "இந்த துப்பாக்கிச் சூடு யாரோ அல்லது வாகனத்தில் வந்த சிலரோ, அவருடன் விசாரணைக்காக வந்த ஒரு குழுவினரோ நடத்தியுள்ளனர்.",
        "சம்பவத்தில் காயமடைந்த நால்வரும் தற்போது கம்பஹா வைத்தியசாலையின் அதிதீவிர சிகிச்சைப் பிரிவில் சிகிச்சை பெற்று வருவதாக வைத்தியசாலை பணிப்பாளர் வைத்தியர் சமன் பத்திரன தெரிவித்துள்ளார்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "கம்பஹா",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "கம்பஹா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "27",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "நான்கு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "கம்பஹா மாவட்ட பொது வைத்தியசாலை",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "நான்கு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "கம்பஹா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சமன் பத்திரன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}