{
  "newspaper_id": "news-first-lk",
  "url": "https://www.newsfirst.lk/2022/07/26/sri-lanka-aragalaya-activist-arrested-aboard-flight-to-dubai/",
  "time_ut": 1658847960,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Sri Lanka: Aragalaya activist arrested aboard flight to Dubai",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Sri Lanka: Aragalaya activist arrested aboard flight to Dubai",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st);  The Criminal Investigations Department carried out an inflight arrest of an Aragalaya Activist today.",
        "The CID arrested an Aragalaya Activist identified as ‘Danish Ali’ while he was attempting to travel to Dubai.",
        "Social Media footage showed the infight arrest, and Police said he was connected to the incident where activists stormed into the Sri Lanka Rupavahini Corporation recently.",
        "CID arrested an individual named ‘Danish Ali’ when attempting to travel to Dubai. He was arrested inside a flight, and was connected to storming into the Sri Lanka Rupavahini Corporation – Police#lka #SriLanka #SLnews #News1st #ProtestLK #SriLankaProtest #CID #Arrest #Inflight pic.twitter.com/28RYL6FPTI",
        "Five COVID deaths for Monday (25), over 100 cases today (26)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Sri Lanka",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "Dubai",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "News 1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "The Criminal Investigations Department",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Aragalaya Activist",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "CID",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Aragalaya Activist",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Dubai",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Social Media",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Sri Lanka Rupavahini Corporation",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "CID",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Dubai",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Sri Lanka Rupavahini Corporation",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "SriLanka",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "#ProtestLK #SriLankaProtest #CID",
            "label": "MONEY"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Five",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Monday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "25",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "over 100",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "26",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "ශ්‍රී ලංකාව: අරගලයා ක්‍රියාකාරිකයෙකු ඩුබායි වෙත ගුවන් යානයකදී අත්අඩංගුවට ගෙන ඇත",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); අපරාධ පරීක්ෂණ දෙපාර්තමේන්තුව විසින් අරගලය ක්‍රියාකාරිකයෙකු ගුවන් යානයකින් අත්අඩංගුවට ගැනීමක් අද සිදු කළා.",
        "ඩුබායි බලා යාමට තැත් කිරීමේදී අරගලය ක්‍රියාකාරිකයෙකු වන ඩනිෂ් අලි නමැති අයෙකු අපරාධ පරීක්ෂණ දෙපාර්තමේන්තුව විසින් අත්අඩංගුවට ගෙන තිබේ.",
        "සමාජ මාධ්‍ය දර්ශනවල දර්ශන තලය මගින් අත්අඩංගුවට ගෙන ඇති අතර, පසුගියදා ශ්‍රී ලංකා රූපවාහිනී සංස්ථාවට ක්‍රියාකාරීන් කඩා වැදීමේ සිද්ධියට මොහු සම්බන්ධ බව පොලිසිය පවසයි.",
        "ඩුබායි බලා යාමට තැත් කිරීමේදී අපරාධ පරීක්ෂණ දෙපාර්තමේන්තුව විසින් ‘ඩැනිෂ් අලි’ නමැති පුද්ගලයෙකු අත්අඩංගුවට ගෙන ඇත. ඔහු ගුවන් යානයක් තුළදී අත්අඩංගුවට ගෙන ඇති අතර, ශ්‍රී ලංකා රූපවාහිනී සංස්ථාවට කඩා වැදීමට සම්බන්ධ අයෙකි - පොලිස්#lka #SriLanka #SLnews #News1st #ProtestLK #SriLankaProtest #CID #Arrest #Inflight pic.twitter.com/28RYL6FPTI",
        "සඳුදා (25) කොවිඩ් මරණ පහක්, අද (26) රෝගීන් 100 ඉක්මවයි."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "ඩුබායි",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "News 1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "අපරාධ පරීක්ෂණ දෙපාර්තමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "අරගලය ක්‍රියාකාරිකයෙක්",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "CID",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "අරගලය ක්‍රියාකාරිකයෙක්",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඩුබායි",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "සමාජ මාධ්ය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකා රූපවාහිනී සංස්ථාව",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "CID",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඩුබායි",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකා රූපවාහිනී සංස්ථාව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "#ProtestLK #SriLankaProtest #CID",
            "label": "MONEY"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "පහ",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "සඳුදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "25",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "100 ට වැඩි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "26",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "இலங்கை: துபாய் செல்லும் விமானத்தில் அரகலயா ஆர்வலர் கைது செய்யப்பட்டார்",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); குற்றப் புலனாய்வுத் திணைக்களம் இன்று அரகலய செயற்பாட்டாளர் ஒருவரை உள்நாட்டில் கைது செய்துள்ளது.",
        "‘டானிஷ் அலி’ என அடையாளம் காணப்பட்ட அரகலயா செயற்பாட்டாளர் ஒருவரை டுபாய் செல்ல முற்பட்ட போது குற்றப் புலனாய்வுப் பிரிவினர் கைது செய்துள்ளனர்.",
        "சமூக ஊடகக் காட்சிகள் உட்கட்சி கைது செய்யப்பட்டதைக் காட்டுகின்றன, மேலும் சமீபத்தில் இலங்கை ரூபவாஹினி கூட்டுத்தாபனத்திற்குள் ஆர்வலர்கள் நுழைந்த சம்பவத்துடன் அவருக்கு தொடர்பு இருப்பதாக பொலிஸார் தெரிவித்தனர்.",
        "துபாய் செல்ல முயன்றபோது ‘டானிஷ் அலி’ என்ற நபரை CID கைது செய்தது. அவர் ஒரு விமானத்திற்குள் கைது செய்யப்பட்டார், மேலும் அவர் இலங்கை ரூபவாஹினி கூட்டுத்தாபனத்திற்குள் நுழைந்ததுடன் தொடர்புடையவர் - பொலிஸ்#lka #SriLanka #SLnews #News1st #ProtestLK #SriLankaProtest #CID #Arrest #Inflight pic.twitter.com/28RYL6FPTI",
        "திங்கட்கிழமை (25) ஐந்து கோவிட் இறப்புகள், இன்று (26) 100 க்கும் மேற்பட்ட வழக்குகள்"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "இலங்கை",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "துபாய்",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "News 1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "குற்றப் புலனாய்வுத் திணைக்களம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "அரகலய செயற்பாட்டாளர்",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "சி.ஐ.டி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "அரகலய செயற்பாட்டாளர்",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "துபாய்",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "சமூக ஊடகம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை ரூபவாஹினி கூட்டுத்தாபனம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "சி.ஐ.டி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "துபாய்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை ரூபவாஹினி கூட்டுத்தாபனம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "#ProtestLK #SriLankaProtest #CID",
            "label": "MONEY"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஐந்து",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "திங்கட்கிழமை",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "25",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "100க்கு மேல்",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "26",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}