{
  "newspaper_id": "tamil-mirror-lk",
  "url": "https://www.tamilmirror.lk/செய்திகள்/கண்டிக்காது-மத்திய-அரசு-வேடிக்கையே-பார்க்கிறது/175-299800",
  "time_ut": 1657050700,
  "original_lang": "ta",
  "original_title": "கண்டிக்காது மத்திய அரசு வேடிக்கையே பார்க்கிறது",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "The central government is just having fun",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "The general secretary of Renaissance Dravidian Development Association (MDMU) Vaiko, who has issued a strong condemnation regarding the arrest of Indian fishermen from Rameswaram by the Sri Lankan Navy, has said that it is an injustice to the fishermen of Tamil Nadu that the central government is making fun of Sri Lanka without condemning it.",
        "\"The case filed in the Madras High Court seeking the release of 68 fishermen from Tamil Nadu imprisoned in Sri Lanka was heard in the last week of March in a bench comprising Chief Justice Munishwarnath Bhandari and Justice Bharata Chakraborty.",
        "The judges then said that the ongoing arrest of Tamil Nadu fishermen and confiscation of their boats by the Sri Lankan Navy has become an ongoing story.",
        "In this situation, they ordered the Indian Ministry of External Affairs to take steps to release the 68 Tamil Nadu fishermen who were arrested by the Sri Lankan Navy.",
        "Even after this, the Sri Lankan Navy continued to arrest Indian fishermen, 12 fishermen each on April 2nd and July 1st, and arrested 24 people. He pointed out that 5 fishermen were arrested on July 4.",
        "The Madhya Bharatiya Janata Party (BJP) government putting pressure on the Sri Lankan government and making fun of it without condemning it is an injustice done to the fishermen of Tamil Nadu. When will the Sri Lankan government's atrocity of arresting Tamil Nadu fishermen entering Indian waters and imprisoning them in Sri Lankan jails come to an end?\" Vaiko asked."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Renaissance Dravidian Development Association",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Indian",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Sri Lankan Navy",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Tamil Nadu",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the Madras High Court",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "68",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Tamil Nadu",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the last week of March",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Munishwarnath Bhandari",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Bharata Chakraborty",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Tamil Nadu",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Sri Lankan Navy",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the Indian Ministry of External Affairs",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "68",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Tamil Nadu",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Sri Lankan Navy",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the Sri Lankan Navy",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Indian",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "12",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "April 2nd and July 1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "24",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "5",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "July 4",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "The Madhya Bharatiya Janata Party",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "BJP",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lankan",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Tamil Nadu",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lankan",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Tamil Nadu",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Indian",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lankan",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "මධ්‍යම ආණ්ඩුව නිකන් ආතල් ගන්නවා",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකා නාවික හමුදාව විසින් රාමේෂ්වරම් ප්‍රදේශයේදී ඉන්දීය ධීවරයින් අත්අඩංගුවට ගැනීම සම්බන්ධයෙන් දැඩි හෙළා දකින පුනරුද ද්‍රවිඩ සංවර්ධන සංගමයේ (MDMU) ප්‍රධාන ලේකම් වයිකෝ පවසන්නේ එය තමිල්නාඩු ධීවරයින්ට මධ්‍යම රජයෙන් අසාධාරණයක් බවයි. එය හෙළා නොදකිමින් ශ්‍රී ලංකාවට විහිළු කරයි.",
        "“ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ සිරගත කර සිටින තමිල්නාඩුවේ ධීවරයින් 68 දෙනෙකු නිදහස් කරන ලෙස ඉල්ලා මදුරාසි මහාධිකරණයේ ගොනු කර ඇති නඩුව මාර්තු අවසන් සතියේ අගවිනිසුරු මුනිෂ්වර්නාත් භණ්ඩාරි සහ විනිසුරු භාරත චක්‍රබෝර්ති යන විනිසුරු මඩුල්ලක් හමුවේ විභාග විය.",
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකා නාවික හමුදාව විසින් තමිල්නාඩු ධීවරයන් දිගින් දිගටම අත්අඩංගුවට ගැනීම සහ ඔවුන්ගේ බෝට්ටු රාජසන්තක කිරීම දිගින් දිගටම කතාවක් බවට පත්ව ඇති බව විනිසුරුවරු එහිදී ප්‍රකාශ කළහ.",
        "මෙම තත්ත්වය තුළ ශ්‍රී ලංකා නාවික හමුදාව විසින් අත්අඩංගුවට ගෙන සිටින තමිල්නාඩු ධීවරයින් 68 දෙනා නිදහස් කිරීමට පියවර ගන්නා ලෙස ඔවුන් ඉන්දීය විදේශ කටයුතු අමාත්‍යාංශයට නියෝග කළා.",
        "ඉන් පසුවද ශ්‍රී ලංකා නාවික හමුදාව විසින් ඉන්දීය ධීවරයින් 12 බැගින් අප්‍රේල් 2 සහ ජුලි 01 යන දෙදින තුළ දිගින් දිගටම අත්අඩංගුවට ගෙන 24 දෙනෙකු අත්අඩංගුවට ගෙන ඇත. ජුලි 4 වැනිදා ධීවරයින් 5 දෙනෙකු අත්අඩංගුවට ගත් බවයි ඔහු පෙන්වා දුන්නේ.",
        "මධ්‍ය භාරතීය ජනතා පක්‍ෂය (BJP) රජය ශ්‍රී ලංකා රජයට බලපෑම් කරමින් එය හෙළා නොදකිමින් විහිළු තහළු කිරීම තමිල්නාඩු ධීවරයන්ට කරන අසාධාරණයකි. ඉන්දීය මුහුදු සීමාවට ඇතුළු වන තමිල්නාඩු ධීවරයන් අත්අඩංගුවට ගෙන ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ සිරගෙවල්වල සිරකර තැබීමේ ශ්‍රී ලංකා ආණ්ඩුවේ සාහසික ක්‍රියා කවදා අවසන් වේද?” වයිකෝ ප්‍රශ්න කළේය."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "පුනරුද ද්‍රවිඩ සංවර්ධන සංගමය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දීය",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකා නාවික හමුදාව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "තමිල්නාඩුව",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "මදුරාසි මහාධිකරණය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "68",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "තමිල්නාඩුව",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මාර්තු අවසාන සතියේ",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මුනිෂ්වර්නාත් භණ්ඩාරි",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "භාරත චක්‍රබෝර්ති",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "තමිල්නාඩුව",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකා නාවික හමුදාව",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දීය විදේශ කටයුතු අමාත්‍යාංශය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "68",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "තමිල්නාඩුව",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකා නාවික හමුදාව",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකා නාවික හමුදාව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දීය",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "12",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "අප්රේල් 2 සහ ජූලි 1",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "24",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "5",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජූලි 4",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "මධ්‍ය භාරතීය ජනතා පක්ෂය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "බී.ජේ.පී",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලාංකික",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "තමිල්නාඩුව",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලාංකික",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "තමිල්නාඩුව",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දීය",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලාංකික",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "கண்டிக்காது மத்திய அரசு வேடிக்கையே பார்க்கிறது",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "ராமேஸ்வரத்தைச் சேர்ந்த இந்திய மீனவர்களை இலங்கை கடற்படை கைது செய்தது தொடர்பாக கடுமையான கண்டனத்தை வெளியிட்டுள்ள மறுமலர்ச்சி திராவிட ​முன்​​னேற்ற கழகத்தின் (ம.தி.மு.க)  பொதுச் செயலாளர் வைகோ, இலங்கைக்கு கண்டனம் தெரிவிக்காமல் மத்திய அரசு வேடிக்கை பார்ப்பது தமிழக மீனவர்களுக்கு இழைக்கப்படும் அநீதியாகுமென தெரிவித்துள்ளார்.",
        "\"இலங்கை சிறையில் அடைக்கப்பட்டுள்ள தமிழக மீனவர்கள் 68 பேரை விடுவிக்க தேவையான நடவடிக்கை எடுக்கக் கோரி, சென்னை உயர் நீதிமன்றத்தில் தாக்கல் செய்யப்பட்ட வழக்கு, தலைமை நீதிபதி முனிஷ்வர்நாத் பண்டாரி மற்றும் நீதிபதி பரத சக்கரவர்த்தி ஆகியோரைக் கொண்ட அமர்வில், கடந்த மார்ச் கடைசி வாரம் விசாரணைக்கு வந்தது.",
        "இலங்கைக் கடற்படையினரால் தமிழக மீனவர்கள் தொடர்ந்து கைது செய்யப்படுவதும், அவர்களின் படகுகள் பறிமுதல் செய்யப்படுவதும் தொடர்கதை ஆகி வருகிறது என நீதிபதிகள் அப்போது தெரிவித்தனர்.",
        "இந்த நிலையில், இலங்கைக் கடற்படையினரால் கைது செய்யப்பட்ட 68 தமிழக மீனவர்களை விடுவிக்க நடவடிக்கை எடுக்க வேண்டும் என இந்திய வெளியுறவு அமைச்சகத்துக்கு உத்தரவிட்டனர்.",
        "இதன் பின்னரும் இந்திய மீனவர்களை கைது செய்யும் நடவடிக்கைகளை இலங்கை கடற்படையினர் முன்னெடுத்தனர், தலா 12 மீனவர்களென ஏப்ரல் 2, ஜூலை 1 ஆம் திகதிகளில், 24 பேரை கைது செய்தனர்.  ஜூலை 4 ஆம் திகதி 5 மீனவர்களை கைது செய்தனர் என சுட்டிக்காட்டிள்ளார்.",
        "மத்திய பாரதிய ஜனதா கட்சி ( பா.ஜ.க) அரசு, இலங்கை அரசுக்கு உரிய முறையில் அழுத்தம் கொடுத்து, கண்டனம் தெரிவிக்காமல் வேடிக்கை பார்ப்பது தமிழக மீனவர்களுக்கு இழைக்கப்படும் அநீதியாகும். தமிழக மீனவர்களை இந்திய கடல் எல்லைக்குள் நுழைந்து கைது செய்து, இலங்கை சிறையில் அடைக்கும் இலங்கை அரசின் அட்டூழியத்திற்கு முற்றுப்புள்ளி வைக்கப் போவது எப்போது?\" என்றும் வைகோ கேள்வியெழுப்பியுள்ளார்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "மறுமலர்ச்சி திராவிட முன்னேற்றக் கழகம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்தியன்",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை கடற்படை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "தமிழ்நாடு",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "சென்னை உயர் நீதிமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "68",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "தமிழ்நாடு",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "மார்ச் கடைசி வாரம்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "முனிஷ்வர்நாத் பண்டாரி",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "பரத சக்ரவர்த்தி",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "தமிழ்நாடு",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை கடற்படை",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இந்திய வெளியுறவு அமைச்சகம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "68",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "தமிழ்நாடு",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை கடற்படை",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை கடற்படை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்தியன்",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "12",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஏப்ரல் 2 மற்றும் ஜூலை 1",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "24",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "5",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜூலை 4",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "மத்திய பாரதிய ஜனதா கட்சி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "பா.ஜ.க",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "தமிழ்நாடு",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "தமிழ்நாடு",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்தியன்",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}