{
  "newspaper_id": "ada-derana-lk",
  "url": "http://www.adaderana.lk/news/84410/navy-seizes-kerala-cannabis-worth-over-rs-27-million-in-jaffna",
  "time_ut": 1660921380,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Navy seizes Kerala cannabis worth over Rs. 27 million in Jaffna",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Navy seizes Kerala cannabis worth over Rs. 27 million in Jaffna",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "A foot patrol conducted by Sri Lanka navy personnel in the beach area of Saukkadi, Madagal in Jaffna has led to the seizure of about 93kg and 200g (wet weight) of Kerala cannabis this morning (19).",
        "The seizure was made by SLNS Agbo in the Northern Naval Command after searching a shrimp-weir off Saukkadi, during a foot patrol conducted in the beach area this morning.",
        "The recovered Kerala cannabis was found stuffed in 40 packages, and weighed about 93kg and 200g (wet weight) in total.",
        "It is believed that smugglers might have left behind the consignment in the shrimp-weir, being unable to bring it ashore, due to naval operations in the area.",
        "Meanwhile, the street value of the seized consignment of Kerala cannabis is believed to be over Rs. 27 million.",
        "The stock has been kept in the naval custody, until onward investigation into the incident gets underway, the SLN said."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Navy",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "Kerala",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "27 million",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "Jaffna",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Saukkadi",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Jaffna",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "about 93kg",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kerala",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "this morning",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "19",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "SLNS Agbo",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Northern Naval Command",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "Saukkadi",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "this morning",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Kerala",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "40",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "about 93kg",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "Kerala",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "27 million",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "SLN",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "රුපියල් කෝටියකට අධික වටිනාකමකින් යුත් කේරළ ගංජා තොගයක් නාවික හමුදා භාරයට යාපනයේ මිලියන 27යි",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකා නාවික හමුදාවේ නිලධාරීන් විසින් යාපනයේ සවුක්කාඩි, මාඩගල් වෙරළ තීරයේ අද (19) උදෑසන සිදුකළ පා මුර සංචාරයකදී කේරළ ගංජා කිලෝග්‍රෑම් 93 යි ග්‍රෑම් 200 ක් පමණ (තෙත් බර) අත්අඩංගුවට ගෙන ඇත.",
        "උතුරු නාවික විධානයට අයත් ශ්‍රී ලංකා නාවික නෞකා අග්බෝ නෞකාව විසින් සෞක්කාඩි ප්‍රදේශයට ඔබ්බෙන් වූ ඉස්සන් වැල්ලක් සෝදිසි කිරීමෙන් අනතුරුව අද පෙරවරුවේ මුහුදු වෙරළ ප්‍රදේශයේ සිදුකළ පාද මුර සංචාරයකදී මෙම අත්අඩංගුවට ගැනීම සිදු කර ඇත.",
        "සොයා ගන්නා ලද කේරළ ගංජා තොගය ඇසුරුම් 40ක පුරවා තිබූ අතර, එහි මුළු බර කිලෝග්‍රෑම් 93 යි ග්‍රෑම් 200 (තෙත් බර) පමණ වේ.",
        "ප්‍රදේශයේ නාවික හමුදා මෙහෙයුම් හේතුවෙන් ජාවාරම්කරුවන් විසින් මෙම ඉස්සන් තොගය ගොඩබිමට ගෙන ඒමට නොහැකිව මෙම ඉස්සන් තොගයේ දමා යන්නට ඇති බවටයි විශ්වාස කෙරෙන්නේ.",
        "මේ අතර, අත්අඩංගුවට ගත් කේරළ ගංජා තොගයේ වීදි වටිනාකම රුපියල් කෝටියකට අධික බව විශ්වාස කෙරේ. මිලියන 27 කි.",
        "සිද්ධිය සම්බන්ධයෙන් ඉදිරි විමර්ශන කටයුතු ආරම්භ කරන තුරු තොගය නාවික හමුදා භාරයේ තබා ඇති බව ශ්‍රී ලංකා නාවික හමුදාව පවසයි."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "නාවික",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "කේරල",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "මිලියන 27 කි",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "යාපනය",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "සෞක්කාඩි",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "යාපනය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "93kg පමණ",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "කේරල",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මේ උදෑසන",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "19",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකා නාවික නෞකා අග්බෝ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "උතුරු නාවික විධානය",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "සෞක්කාඩි",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මේ උදෑසන",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "කේරල",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "40",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "93kg පමණ",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "කේරල",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මිලියන 27 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "SLN",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "ஒரு கோடி ரூபாய்க்கு மேல் பெறுமதியான கேரள கஞ்சாவை கடற்படையினர் கைப்பற்றியுள்ளனர். யாழ்ப்பாணத்தில் 27 மில்லியன்",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "யாழ்ப்பாணம் சௌக்கடி, மடகல் கடற்கரைப் பகுதியில் இலங்கை கடற்படையினர் மேற்கொண்ட கால் ரோந்து நடவடிக்கையின் போது சுமார் 93 கிலோ 200 கிராம் (ஈரமான எடை) கேரள கஞ்சா இன்று (19) காலை கைப்பற்றப்பட்டுள்ளது.",
        "வடக்கு கடற்படை கட்டளையில் உள்ள எஸ்.எல்.என்.எஸ் அக்போ மூலம் இன்று காலை கடற்கரை பகுதியில் மேற்கொள்ளப்பட்ட கால் ரோந்து நடவடிக்கையின் போது சவுக்கடி பகுதியில் உள்ள இறால்களை தேடிய பின்னர் இந்த கைப்பற்றப்பட்டது.",
        "மீட்கப்பட்ட கேரள கஞ்சா 40 பொதிகளில் அடைக்கப்பட்டு, மொத்தம் 93 கிலோ 200 கிராம் (ஈரமான எடை) எடை கொண்டது.",
        "அப்பகுதியில் கடற்படை நடவடிக்கைகள் காரணமாக, கடத்தல்காரர்கள் இறால்-மரத்தில் சரக்குகளை கரைக்கு கொண்டு வர முடியாமல் விட்டுச் சென்றிருக்கலாம் என்று நம்பப்படுகிறது.",
        "இதேவேளை, கைப்பற்றப்பட்ட கேரள கஞ்சாப் பொதியின் பெறுமதி ஒரு இலட்சம் ரூபாவிற்கும் அதிகம் என நம்பப்படுகிறது. 27 மில்லியன்.",
        "சம்பவம் தொடர்பிலான விசாரணைகள் ஆரம்பிக்கப்படும் வரை, கடற்படைக் காவலில் வைக்கப்பட்டுள்ளதாக, SLN தெரிவித்துள்ளது."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "கடற்படை",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "கேரளா",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "27 மில்லியன்",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "யாழ்",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சவுக்கடி",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "யாழ்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சுமார் 93 கிலோ",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "கேரளா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று காலை",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "19",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "எஸ்எல்என்எஸ் அக்போ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "வடக்கு கடற்படை கட்டளை",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "சவுக்கடி",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று காலை",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "கேரளா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "40",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "சுமார் 93 கிலோ",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "கேரளா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "27 மில்லியன்",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "எஸ்.எல்.என்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}