{
  "newspaper_id": "ada-derana-lk",
  "url": "http://www.adaderana.lk/news/83745/rambukkana-shooting-court-to-decide-on-issuing-interim-order-on-cops-involved",
  "time_ut": 1658236680,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Rambukkana shooting: Court to decide on issuing interim order on cops involved",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Rambukkana shooting: Court to decide on issuing interim order on cops involved",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "The Court of Appeal ordered today (19) that the decision on whether it will issue or not an interim order suspending the order given by the Kegalle Magistrate’s Court regarding the police officers involved in Rambukkana shooting incident will be announced on August 30.",
        "Kegalle Magistrate’s Court had recently ordered the four police officers including the former Senior Superintendent of Police (SSP) in charge of Kegalle, K. B. Keerthirathna to be arrested and remanded in custody, over the said incident.",
        "The order was passed by the Appeals Court bench consisting of Judges Sobitha Rajakaruna and Dhammika Ganepola, after considering the writ petitions submitted by the police officers in question.",
        "The bench has also directed the concerned parties to file any written submissions related to these petitions, before 05th of August.",
        "When these petitions were considered today, Additional Solicitor General Vikum de Abrew, who appeared for the Attorney General, presented submissions before the court and urged the court to reject this request.",
        "On 19th April a group of protestors gathered near a filling station in Rambukkana in the Kegalle District had continued to protest for two days, demanding fuel to be supplied at old prices. As a tense situation had ensued, the police had fired tear gas and later, as the situation escalated, they had used firearms to disperse the crowd resulting in the death of one person death and injuries to several protestors."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Rambukkana",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "19",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Kegalle Magistrate’s Court",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Rambukkana",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "August 30",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Kegalle Magistrate’s Court",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "four",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Senior Superintendent of Police",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kegalle",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "K. B. Keerthirathna",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the Appeals Court",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sobitha Rajakaruna",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Dhammika Ganepola",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "August",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Additional Solicitor",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Vikum de Abrew",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "19th April",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Rambukkana",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Kegalle District",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "two days",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "one",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "රඹුක්කන වෙඩි තැබීමට සම්බන්ධ පොලිස් නිලධාරීන්ට අතුරු නියෝගයක් නිකුත් කිරීම ගැන අධිකරණය තීරණය කරයි",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "රඹුක්කන වෙඩි තැබීමේ සිද්ධියට සම්බන්ධ පොලිස් නිලධාරීන් සම්බන්ධයෙන් කෑගල්ල මහේස්ත්‍රාත් අධිකරණය ලබාදුන් නියෝගය අත්හිටුවමින් අතුරු නියෝගයක් නිකුත් කරනවාද නැද්ද යන්න පිළිබඳ තීන්දුව අගෝස්තු 30 වැනිදා ප්‍රකාශයට පත් කරන ලෙස අභියාචනාධිකරණය අද (19) නියෝග කළේය.",
        "මෙම සිද්ධිය සම්බන්ධයෙන් කෑගල්ල ප්‍රදේශය භාර හිටපු ජ්‍යෙෂ්ඨ පොලිස් අධිකාරී කේ.බී.කීර්තිරත්න ඇතුළු පොලිස් නිලධාරීන් සිව්දෙනා අත්අඩංගුවට ගෙන රක්ෂිත බන්ධනාගාරගත කරන ලෙස කෑගල්ල මහේස්ත්‍රාත් අධිකරණය පසුගියදා නියෝග කළේය.",
        "සෝභිත රාජකරුණා සහ ධම්මික ගනේපොල යන විනිසුරුවරුන්ගෙන් සමන්විත අභියාචනාධිකරණ විනිසුරු මඩුල්ල විසින් මෙම නියෝගය ලබා දුන්නේ අදාළ පොලිස් නිලධාරීන් විසින් ඉදිරිපත් කර තිබූ රිට් පෙත්සම් සලකා බැලීමෙන් අනතුරුවය.",
        "මෙම පෙත්සම්වලට අදාළ ලිඛිත දේශන ඇත්නම් අගෝස්තු 05 වැනිදාට පෙර ගොනු කරන ලෙස ද විනිසුරු මඩුල්ල අදාළ පාර්ශවයන්ට නියෝග කර ඇත.",
        "මෙම පෙත්සම් අද සලකා බැලූ අවස්ථාවේදී නීතිපතිවරයා වෙනුවෙන් පෙනී සිටි අතිරේක සොලිසිටර් ජනරාල් විකුම් ද ආබෲ මහතා අධිකරණය හමුවේ කරුණු ඉදිරිපත් කරමින් මෙම ඉල්ලීම ප්‍රතික්ෂේප කරන ලෙස අධිකරණයෙන් ඉල්ලා සිටියේය.",
        "පසුගිය අප්‍රේල් 19 වනදා කෑගල්ල දිස්ත්‍රික්කයේ රඹුක්කන ප්‍රදේශයේ ඉන්ධන පිරවුම්හලක් අසලට රැස්වූ විරෝධතාකරුවන් පිරිසක් පැරණි මිලටම ඉන්ධන ලබාදෙන ලෙස ඉල්ලමින් දින දෙකක් පුරාවට විරෝධතාවයේ නිරත වුණා. එහිදී ඇති වූ නොසන්සුන්කාරී තත්ත්වයක් හේතුවෙන් පොලිසිය කඳුළු ගෑස් ප්‍රහාරයක් එල්ල කර ඇති අතර පසුව තත්ත්වය උත්සන්න වීමත් සමඟ ගිනි අවි භාවිත කරමින් රැස්ව සිටි පිරිස විසුරුවා හැරීමට කටයුතු කළ අතර එහිදී එක් අයෙකු මිය ගොස් විරෝධතාකරුවන් කිහිප දෙනෙකුට තුවාල සිදු විය."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "රඹුක්කන",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "19",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "කෑගල්ල මහේස්ත්‍රාත් අධිකරණය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "රඹුක්කන",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "අගෝස්තු 30",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "කෑගල්ල මහේස්ත්‍රාත් අධිකරණය",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "හතර",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජ්‍යෙෂ්ඨ පොලිස් අධිකාරි",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "කෑගල්ල",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "K. B. කීර්තිරත්න",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "අභියාචනාධිකරණය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "සෝභිත රාජකරුණා",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ධම්මික ගනේපොල",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "අගෝස්තු",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "අතිරේක සොලිසිටර්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "විකුම් ද ආබෲ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "අප්රේල් 19",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "රඹුක්කන",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "කෑගල්ල දිස්ත්‍රික්කය",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "දින දෙකක්",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "එක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "ரம்புக்கன துப்பாக்கிச் சூடு: சம்பந்தப்பட்ட பொலிஸாருக்கு இடைக்கால உத்தரவு பிறப்பிப்பது குறித்து நீதிமன்றம் தீர்மானிக்கவுள்ளது",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "ரம்புக்கனை துப்பாக்கிச் சூட்டுச் சம்பவத்துடன் தொடர்புடைய பொலிஸ் உத்தியோகத்தர்கள் தொடர்பில் கேகாலை நீதவான் நீதிமன்றம் வழங்கிய உத்தரவை இடைநிறுத்தி இடைக்கால உத்தரவைப் பிறப்பிப்பதா இல்லையா என்பது குறித்த தீர்மானத்தை ஆகஸ்ட் 30 ஆம் திகதி அறிவிக்கப்படும் என மேன்முறையீட்டு நீதிமன்றம் இன்று (19) உத்தரவிட்டுள்ளது.",
        "இந்த சம்பவம் தொடர்பில் கேகாலைக்கு பொறுப்பான முன்னாள் சிரேஷ்ட பொலிஸ் அத்தியட்சகர் கே.பி.கீர்த்திரத்ன உள்ளிட்ட நான்கு பொலிஸ் அதிகாரிகளை கைது செய்து விளக்கமறியலில் வைக்குமாறு கேகாலை நீதவான் நீதிமன்றம் அண்மையில் உத்தரவிட்டிருந்தது.",
        "குறித்த பொலிஸ் உத்தியோகத்தர்களால் சமர்ப்பிக்கப்பட்ட ரிட் மனுக்களை பரிசீலித்த மேன்முறையீட்டு நீதிமன்ற நீதிபதிகளான சோபித ராஜகருணா மற்றும் தம்மிக்க கணேபொல ஆகியோர் அடங்கிய அமர்வு இந்த உத்தரவை பிறப்பித்துள்ளது.",
        "இந்த மனுக்கள் தொடர்பான எழுத்துப்பூர்வ சமர்ப்பிப்புகளை ஆகஸ்ட் 05 ஆம் தேதிக்கு முன்னர் தாக்கல் செய்யுமாறு சம்பந்தப்பட்ட தரப்பினருக்கு பெஞ்ச் உத்தரவிட்டுள்ளது.",
        "இந்த மனுக்கள் இன்று பரிசீலனைக்கு எடுத்துக் கொள்ளப்பட்ட போது, ​​சட்டமா அதிபர் சார்பில் ஆஜரான மேலதிக சொலிசிட்டர் ஜெனரல் விக்கும் டி அப்ரூ நீதிமன்றத்தில் சமர்ப்பணங்களை முன்வைத்து இந்தக் கோரிக்கையை நிராகரிக்குமாறு நீதிமன்றத்தை வலியுறுத்தினார்.",
        "ஏப்பிரல் 19 ஆம் திகதி கேகாலை மாவட்டத்தில் ரம்புக்கனையில் உள்ள எரிபொருள் நிரப்பு நிலையத்திற்கு அருகில் ஒன்று கூடிய ஆர்ப்பாட்டக்காரர்கள் பழைய விலைக்கே எரிபொருளை வழங்குமாறு கோரி இரண்டு நாட்களாக தொடர்ந்து போராட்டத்தில் ஈடுபட்டனர். பதட்டமான சூழ்நிலை ஏற்பட்டதால், போலீசார் கண்ணீர் புகை குண்டுகளை வீசினர், பின்னர், நிலைமை அதிகரித்ததால், கூட்டத்தைக் கலைக்க துப்பாக்கிப் பிரயோகம் மேற்கொண்டனர், இதன் விளைவாக ஒருவர் இறந்தார் மற்றும் பல போராட்டக்காரர்கள் காயமடைந்தனர்"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ரம்புக்கன",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "19",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "கேகாலை நீதவான் நீதிமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரம்புக்கன",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆகஸ்ட் 30",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "கேகாலை நீதவான் நீதிமன்றம்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "நான்கு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "மூத்த காவல் கண்காணிப்பாளர்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "கேகாலை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "கே.பி. கீர்த்திரத்னா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "மேல்முறையீட்டு நீதிமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "சோபித ராஜகருணா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "தம்மிக்க கணேபொல",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஆகஸ்ட்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "கூடுதல் வழக்கறிஞர்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "விக்கும் டி அப்ரூ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஏப்ரல் 19",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரம்புக்கன",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "கேகாலை மாவட்டம்",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "இரண்டு நாட்கள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஒன்று",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}