{
  "newspaper_id": "economy-next-com",
  "url": "https://economynext.com/sri-lanka-to-sell-down-20-pct-state-banks-shares-to-workers-depositors-99190/",
  "time_ut": 1661850000,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Sri Lanka to sell down 20-pct state banks shares to workers, depositors",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Sri Lanka to sell down 20-pct state banks shares to workers, depositors",
      "author": "",
      "body_lines": [
        "ECONOMYNEXT – Sri Lanka will give 20 percent of stock in state banks to workers and depositors, President Ranil Wickremesinghe said presenting a revised budget to parliament.",
        "Sri Lanka’s banks are facing higher bad loans and market to market losses on bonds holdings in 2022 after interest rates rose sharply after the collapse of a soft-peg.",
        "There has been concern that rupee bonds may also be re-structured which may further hurt banks.",
        "Selling down stock in state-banks are opposed by some trade unions.",
        "Sri Lanka’s government is no longer in the position to use tax money to support state enterprises, President Wickremesinghe said."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Sri Lanka",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "20",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "20 percent",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka’s",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "2022",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවෙන් සියයට 20ක රාජ්‍ය බැංකු කොටස් කම්කරුවන්ට, තැන්පත්කරුවන්ට විකිණීමට",
      "author": "",
      "body_lines": [
        "ECONOMYNEXT - ශ්‍රී ලංකාව රාජ්‍ය බැංකුවල ඇති කොටස්වලින් සියයට 20ක් කම්කරුවන්ට සහ තැන්පත්කරුවන්ට ලබා දෙන බව ජනාධිපති රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතා පාර්ලිමේන්තුවට සංශෝධිත අයවැයක් ඉදිරිපත් කරමින් පැවසීය.",
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ බැංකු, 2022 දී සොෆ්ට්-පෙග් බිඳවැටීමෙන් පසු පොලී අනුපාත තියුනු ලෙස ඉහළ යාමෙන් පසු, 2022 දී බැඳුම්කර හිමිකම මත ඉහළ බොල් ණය සහ වෙලඳපොලේ වෙළඳපල පාඩු වලට මුහුණ දෙයි.",
        "බැංකුවලට තවදුරටත් හානියක් විය හැකි රුපියලේ බැඳුම්කර ද ප්‍රතිව්‍යුහගත විය හැකි බවට කනස්සල්ලක් පවතී.",
        "රාජ්‍ය බැංකුවල කොටස් තොග විකිණීමට සමහර වෘත්තීය සමිති විරුද්ධයි.",
        "රාජ්‍ය ව්‍යවසායන් සඳහා බදු මුදල් යෙදවීමට ශ්‍රී ලංකා රජයට තවදුරටත් හැකියාවක් නොමැති බව ජනාධිපති වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතා පැවසීය."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "20",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "සියයට 20 කි",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "2022",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "இலங்கை அரசு வங்கிகளின் 20 சதவீத பங்குகளை தொழிலாளர்கள், வைப்பாளர்களுக்கு விற்க உள்ளது",
      "author": "",
      "body_lines": [
        "பொருளாதாரம் - இலங்கை அரச வங்கிகளில் உள்ள 20 சதவீத பங்குகளை தொழிலாளர்கள் மற்றும் வைப்பாளர்களுக்கு வழங்கும் என்று ஜனாதிபதி ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க பாராளுமன்றத்தில் திருத்தப்பட்ட வரவு செலவுத் திட்டத்தை சமர்ப்பித்து தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "இலங்கையின் வங்கிகள் 2022 ஆம் ஆண்டில் வட்டி விகிதங்கள் ஒரு சாஃப்ட்-பெக் சரிவுக்குப் பிறகு கடுமையாக உயர்ந்ததை அடுத்து, அதிக மோசமான கடன்கள் மற்றும் சந்தைக்கு சந்தை இழப்புகளை பத்திரப் பத்திரங்களின் மீது எதிர்கொள்கின்றன.",
        "ரூபாய் பத்திரங்களும் மறுகட்டமைக்கப்படலாம், இது வங்கிகளை மேலும் பாதிக்கலாம் என்ற கவலை உள்ளது.",
        "அரசு வங்கிகளில் பங்குகளை விற்பதை சில தொழிற்சங்கங்கள் எதிர்க்கின்றன.",
        "அரச நிறுவனங்களுக்கு ஆதரவாக வரிப் பணத்தைப் பயன்படுத்தும் நிலையில் இலங்கை அரசாங்கம் இனி இல்லை என ஜனாதிபதி விக்கிரமசிங்க தெரிவித்துள்ளார்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "இலங்கை",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "20",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "20 சதவீதம்",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கையின்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "2022",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}