{
  "newspaper_id": "daily-mirror-lk",
  "url": "https://www.dailymirror.lk/top_story/Basil-fights-back-to-save-his-political-future-as-RW-pushes-for-21A-today/155-237802",
  "time_ut": 1653613036,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Basil fights back to save his political future as RW pushes for 21A today",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Basil fights back to save his political future as RW pushes for 21A today",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "* The committee that drafted the amendment will also be present at the meeting today",
        "In a move to push for the 21st amendment to be accepted by the party leaders today, Prime Minister Ranil Wickremesinghe will lobby for it at the party leaders' meeting at 3.30 pm today in order to reduce the powers of the President and also remove dual citizens from holding a parliamentary seat, which in turn will end Basil Rajapaksa's political career in Sri Lanka.",
        "The party leaders who have already been given a draft of the 21st amendment for them to study can raise any proposals or objections on the clauses today so that a final draft can be prepared and submitted at the next cabinet meeting.",
        "The committee that has drafted the 21st amendment will also be present at the meeting today afternoon to note the changes that will be proposed by the party leaders and incorporate them in the final draft.",
        "The Daily Mirror learns that while SLPP Leader Mahinda Rajapaksa may not attend the meeting, he will send a representative to be present.",
        "However, despite Mahinda Rajapaksa being the SLPP Leader, it is learnt that Basil Rajapaksa is the man now calling the shots among the majority in the party and is lobbying against the 21A so that he can save his political career in Sri Lanka. The SLPP is specifically trying to leave out clauses such as the abolition of the dual citizenship as well as the reduction of the President's powers on Basil's insistence and is aiming not to pass it when it is presented before the Parliament.",
        "Other party leaders have already consented to the 21A but may propose some changes. However, all other leaders are of the view that the President's powers must be reduced as a way of further strengthening the Parliament as well as discontinuing dual citizens from holding future parliamentary seats.",
        "Senior UNP sources have also requested law enforcement authorities to probe as to who carried out a protest outside the Prime Minister's Office yesterday, as the Gota Go Gama protesters had said it was not their protesters. UNP Seniors suspect and alleged that the SLPP was now trying to create protests against the Prime Minister in a way to pressure him against presenting the 21A.",
        "If the 21A is approved by the party leaders today, even with the changes they propose, it will be presented to the cabinet again. Once approved by the cabinet of ministers, it will then be presented to Parliament for a vote.",
        "Prime Minister Wickremesinghe is already in discussions with all party leaders to keep the two clauses on reducing the President's powers and the dual citizenship clause in order to minimise the Rajapaksas representation in the government. (JAMILA HUSAIN)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "RW",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "21A",
          "label": "DATE"
        },
        {
          "text": "today",
          "label": "DATE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "21st",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "3.30 pm",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Basil Rajapaksa's",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "21st",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "21st",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "afternoon",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "The Daily Mirror",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Mahinda Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Mahinda Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Basil Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Basil",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "UNP",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "yesterday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Gama",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "UNP Seniors",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "21A.",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "two",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Rajapaksas",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "RW අද 21A සඳහා තල්ලු කරද්දී බැසිල් තම දේශපාලන අනාගතය බේරා ගැනීමට සටන් කරයි",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "* සංශෝධන කෙටුම්පත් කළ කමිටුවත් අද රැස්වීමට එනවා",
        "21 වන ව්‍යවස්ථා සංශෝධනය අද පක්ෂ නායකයින් විසින් පිළිගන්නා ලෙසට බලකිරීමේ අරමුණින් අද පස්වරු 3.30 ට පැවැත්වෙන පක්ෂ නායක රැස්වීමේදී ඒ සඳහා බලපෑම් කිරීමට අග්‍රාමාත්‍ය රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතා තීරණය කර ඇත්තේ ජනාධිපතිවරයාගේ බලතල අඩු කිරීමට සහ ද්විත්ව පුරවැසියන් ඉවත් කිරීමටයි. පාර්ලිමේන්තු මන්ත්‍රී ධුරයක් දැරීමෙන් බැසිල් රාජපක්ෂගේ ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ දේශපාලන ජීවිතය අවසන් වනු ඇත.",
        "21 වැනි ව්‍යවස්ථා සංශෝධනයේ කෙටුම්පත අධ්‍යයනය කිරීම සඳහා දැනටමත් ලබා දී ඇති පක්ෂ නායකයින්ට අද දිනයේදී එම වගන්ති පිළිබඳ යෝජනා හෝ විරෝධතා ඉදිරිපත් කළ හැකි අතර එමඟින් අවසන් කෙටුම්පතක් සකස් කර මීළඟ කැබිනට් රැස්වීමට ඉදිරිපත් කළ හැකිය.",
        "පක්ෂ නායකයින් විසින් යෝජනා කරන වෙනස්කම් සටහන් කර අවසන් කෙටුම්පතට ඇතුළත් කිරීම සඳහා 21 වන සංශෝධනය කෙටුම්පත් කර ඇති කමිටුව ද අද පස්වරුවේ රැස්වීමට පැමිණෙනු ඇති.",
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකා පොදුජන පෙරමුණේ නායක මහින්ද රාජපක්ෂ මහතා රැස්වීමට නොපැමිණීමට ඉඩ ඇති අතර, ඔහු එහි නියෝජිතයෙකු එවීමට නියමිත බව ඩේලි මිරර් වෙත වාර්තා වේ.",
        "කෙසේ වෙතත්, ශ්‍රී ලංකා පොදුජන පෙරමුණේ නායකයා ලෙස මහින්ද රාජපක්ෂ සිටියද, දැන් පක්ෂයේ බහුතරය අතරට වෙඩි තබන පුද්ගලයා බැසිල් රාජපක්ෂ බවත්, ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ දේශපාලන ජීවිතය බේරා ගැනීමට 21A ට එරෙහිව බලපෑම් කරමින් සිටින බවත් දැනගන්නට ඇත. ද්විත්ව පුරවැසිභාවය අහෝසි කිරීම මෙන්ම ජනාධිපති බලතල කප්පාදු කිරීම වැනි වගන්ති බැසිල්ගේ බලකිරීම මත අත්හැරීමට ශ්‍රී ලංකා පොදුජන පෙරමුණ විශේෂයෙන් උත්සාහ කරන අතර එය පාර්ලිමේන්තුවට ඉදිරිපත් කරන විට එය සම්මත නොකිරීමට උත්සාහ කරයි.",
        "අනෙකුත් පක්ෂ නායකයින් දැනටමත් 21A සඳහා කැමැත්ත පළ කර ඇති නමුත් සමහර වෙනස්කම් යෝජනා කළ හැකිය. කෙසේ වෙතත්, පාර්ලිමේන්තුව තවදුරටත් ශක්තිමත් කිරීමට මෙන්ම ද්විත්ව පුරවැසියන්ට අනාගත පාර්ලිමේන්තු මන්ත්‍රී ධුර දැරීම අත්හිටුවීමේ මාර්ගයක් ලෙස ජනාධිපතිවරයාගේ බලතල අඩු කළ යුතු බව අනෙකුත් සියලුම නායකයින්ගේ අදහසයි.",
        "ඊයේ අග්‍රාමාත්‍ය කාර්යාලය ඉදිරිපිට විරෝධතාවයක් සිදුකළේ කවුරුන්ද යන්න පිළිබඳව සොයා බලන ලෙස එක්සත් ජාතික පක්ෂයේ ජ්‍යෙෂ්ඨ ආරංචි මාර්ග ද ඉල්ලා ඇත්තේ ගෝඨා ගෝ ගම විරෝධතාකරුවන් එය තම විරෝධතාකරුවන් නොවන බවයි. 21A ඉදිරිපත් කිරීමට එරෙහිව අගමැතිවරයාට බලපෑම් කිරීම සඳහා ශ්‍රී ලංකා පොදුජන පෙරමුණ දැන් ඔහුට එරෙහිව විරෝධතා ඇති කිරීමට උත්සාහ කරන බවට එජාප ජ්‍යෙෂ්ඨයින් සැක කරන අතර චෝදනා කරයි.",
        "අද පක්‍ෂ නායකයන් විසින් 21ඒ අනුමත කළහොත් ඔවුන් යෝජනා කරන වෙනස්කම් සමඟ වුවද එය නැවත කැබිනට් මණ්ඩලයට ඉදිරිපත් කරනු ඇත. අමාත්‍ය මණ්ඩලයේ අනුමැතියෙන් පසු එය ඡන්ද විමසීමක් සඳහා පාර්ලිමේන්තුවට ඉදිරිපත් කිරීමට නියමිතයි.",
        "ආණ්ඩුව තුළ රාජපක්ෂවරුන්ගේ නියෝජනය අවම කිරීම සඳහා ජනාධිපති බලතල අඩු කිරීමේ වගන්ති දෙක සහ ද්විත්ව පුරවැසිභාවය පිළිබඳ වගන්ති දෙක දිගටම තබා ගැනීමට අගමැති වික්‍රමසිංහ මේ වන විටත් සියලු පක්ෂ නායකයන් සමඟ සාකච්ඡා කරමින් සිටී. (ජමිලා හුසේන්)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "RW",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "21A",
          "label": "DATE"
        },
        {
          "text": "අද",
          "label": "DATE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "21 වැනි",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "3.30 ප.ව",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "බැසිල් රාජපක්ෂගේ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "21 වැනි",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "21 වැනි",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "දහවල්",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ඩේලි මිරර්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "මහින්ද රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "මහින්ද රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "බැසිල් රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "බැසිල්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "එජාප",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඊයේ",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගම",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "එජාප ජ්‍යෙෂ්ඨයෝ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "21A.",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "දෙක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "රාජපක්ෂලා",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "RW இன்று 21A க்கு தள்ளும் போது பசில் தனது அரசியல் எதிர்காலத்தை காப்பாற்ற போராடுகிறார்",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "* திருத்தத்தை உருவாக்கிய குழுவும் இன்று கூட்டத்தில் பங்கேற்கும்",
        "இன்று பிற்பகல் 3.30 மணிக்கு இடம்பெறவுள்ள கட்சித் தலைவர்கள் கூட்டத்தில் 21ஆவது திருத்தச் சட்டத்தை கட்சித் தலைவர்கள் ஏற்றுக்கொள்வதற்கு அழுத்தம் கொடுக்கும் வகையில் பிரதமர் ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க, ஜனாதிபதியின் அதிகாரங்களைக் குறைப்பதற்கும் இரட்டைக் குடியுரிமையை நீக்குவதற்கும் முயற்சி மேற்கொள்ளவுள்ளார். இலங்கையில் பசில் ராஜபக்சேவின் அரசியல் வாழ்க்கையை முடிவுக்கு கொண்டு வரும் நாடாளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர் பதவியை பிடிப்பதில் இருந்து.",
        "ஏற்கனவே 21வது திருத்தச் சட்ட வரைவை ஆய்வு செய்வதற்காகக் கொடுக்கப்பட்டுள்ள கட்சித் தலைவர்கள், ஷரத்துகள் மீது ஏதேனும் முன்மொழிவுகள் அல்லது ஆட்சேபனைகளை முன்வைத்தால், அடுத்த அமைச்சரவைக் கூட்டத்தில் இறுதி வரைவு தயாரிக்கப்பட்டு சமர்ப்பிக்கப்படும்.",
        "21வது திருத்தச் சட்டத்தை வரைந்துள்ள குழுவும் இன்று பிற்பகல் கூடும் கூட்டத்தில் கட்சித் தலைவர்களால் முன்மொழியப்படும் மாற்றங்களை அவதானித்து இறுதி வரைவில் இணைத்துக் கொள்ளவுள்ளது.",
        "ஸ்ரீலங்கா பொதுஜன பெரமுனவின் தலைவர் மகிந்த ராஜபக்ச கூட்டத்தில் கலந்து கொள்ளாத நிலையில், அவர் ஒரு பிரதிநிதியை பிரசன்னமாக அனுப்புவார் என டெய்லி மிரர் செய்தி வெளியிட்டுள்ளது.",
        "எவ்வாறாயினும், மகிந்த ராஜபக்ச ஸ்ரீலங்கா பொதுஜன பெரமுனவின் தலைவராக இருந்த போதிலும், பசில் ராஜபக்ச தற்போது கட்சியில் உள்ள பெரும்பான்மையினருக்கு அழைப்பு விடுப்பதாகவும், இலங்கையில் தனது அரசியல் வாழ்க்கையை காப்பாற்றுவதற்காக 21A க்கு எதிராக பிரச்சாரம் செய்வதாகவும் அறியப்படுகிறது. SLPP குறிப்பாக இரட்டைக் குடியுரிமையை ரத்து செய்தல் மற்றும் பசிலின் வலியுறுத்தலின் பேரில் ஜனாதிபதியின் அதிகாரங்களைக் குறைத்தல் போன்ற சரத்துக்களை விட்டுவிட முயல்வதுடன் அது பாராளுமன்றத்தில் முன்வைக்கப்படும் போது அதனை நிறைவேற்றாமல் இருப்பதை நோக்கமாகக் கொண்டுள்ளது.",
        "மற்ற கட்சித் தலைவர்கள் ஏற்கனவே 21A க்கு ஒப்புதல் அளித்துள்ளனர், ஆனால் சில மாற்றங்களை முன்மொழியலாம். எவ்வாறாயினும், பாராளுமன்றத்தை மேலும் பலப்படுத்தும் ஒரு வழியாக ஜனாதிபதியின் அதிகாரங்கள் குறைக்கப்பட வேண்டும் என்பதுடன் இரட்டைக் குடியுரிமை பெற்றவர்கள் எதிர்கால நாடாளுமன்ற ஆசனங்களை வகிப்பதில் இருந்து நிறுத்தப்பட வேண்டும் என்று மற்ற அனைத்துத் தலைவர்களும் கருதுகின்றனர்.",
        "கோட்டா கோ கம எதிர்ப்பாளர்கள் தெரிவித்ததையடுத்து, நேற்று பிரதமர் அலுவலகத்திற்கு வெளியே போராட்டம் நடத்தியவர்கள் யார் என்பது குறித்து விசாரணை நடத்துமாறு ஐக்கிய தேசியக் கட்சியின் மூத்த வட்டாரங்கள் சட்ட அமலாக்க அதிகாரிகளிடம் கோரிக்கை விடுத்துள்ளன. 21A ஐ முன்வைப்பதற்கு எதிராக அவருக்கு அழுத்தம் கொடுக்கும் வகையில் ஸ்ரீலங்கா பொதுஜன பெரமுன தற்போது பிரதமருக்கு எதிராக எதிர்ப்புக்களை உருவாக்க முயற்சிப்பதாக ஐக்கிய தேசியக் கட்சியின் சிரேஷ்டர்கள் சந்தேகிக்கின்றனர்.",
        "இன்று கட்சித் தலைவர்களால் 21A க்கு அங்கீகாரம் கிடைத்தால், அவர்கள் முன்வைக்கும் மாற்றங்களுடன் கூட, அது மீண்டும் அமைச்சரவையில் முன்வைக்கப்படும். அமைச்சரவையின் அங்கீகாரம் கிடைத்ததும், அது வாக்கெடுப்புக்கு நாடாளுமன்றத்தில் சமர்ப்பிக்கப்படும்.",
        "அரசாங்கத்தில் ராஜபக்சக்களின் பிரதிநிதித்துவத்தை குறைக்கும் வகையில் ஜனாதிபதியின் அதிகாரங்களைக் குறைப்பது மற்றும் இரட்டைக் குடியுரிமைச் சட்டப்பிரிவு ஆகிய இரு சரத்துக்களை வைத்து பிரதமர் விக்ரமசிங்க ஏற்கனவே அனைத்துக் கட்சித் தலைவர்களுடன் கலந்துரையாடி வருகிறார். (ஜமிலா ஹுசைன்)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "RW",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "21A",
          "label": "DATE"
        },
        {
          "text": "இன்று",
          "label": "DATE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "21 ஆம் தேதி",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "மாலை 3.30 மணி",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "பசில் ராஜபக்சவின்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "21 ஆம் தேதி",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "21 ஆம் தேதி",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "பிற்பகல்",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "டெய்லி மிரர்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "மஹிந்த ராஜபக்ஷ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "மஹிந்த ராஜபக்ஷ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "பசில் ராஜபக்ச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "துளசி",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஐ.தே.க",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "நேற்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "காமா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "UNP மூத்தவர்கள்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "21A.",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இரண்டு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ராஜபக்சேக்கள்",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}