{
  "newspaper_id": "lankadeepa-lk",
  "url": "https://www.lankadeepa.lk/news/අගමැති-දිනේෂ්--වැඩ-අරඹයි/101-616987",
  "time_ut": 1658729663,
  "original_lang": "si",
  "original_title": "අගමැති දිනේෂ්  වැඩ අරඹයි",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Prime Minister Dinesh starts work",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "Prime Minister Dinesh Gunawardena assumed office at the prime minister's office this morning (25).",
        "Mr. Dinesh Gunawardena was recently appointed as the Prime Minister of the new government by Mr. Ranil Wickramasinghe. He took the oath of office on the 22nd before the President.",
        "Mr. Dinesh Gunawardena served as the Minister of Local Government Home Affairs and Provincial Councils and also as the Leader of the Parliament before becoming the Prime Minister.",
        "Mr. Gunawardena, who is an accomplished politician, is the son of Mr. Philip Gunawardena, a well-known left-wing leader in this country."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Dinesh",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Dinesh Gunawardena",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "this morning",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "25",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Dinesh Gunawardena",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickramasinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the 22nd",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Dinesh Gunawardena",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Provincial Councils",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Gunawardena",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Philip Gunawardena",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "අගමැති දිනේෂ්  වැඩ අරඹයි",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "අග්‍රාමාත්‍ය දිනේෂ් ගුණවර්ධන මහතා අග්‍රාමාත්‍ය කාර්යාලයේදී සිය ධුරයේ සුබ මොහොතින් අද (25) පෙරවරුවේ වැඩ බාර ගත්තේය.",
        "ජනාධිපති රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතා විසින් නව ආණ්ඩුවේ  අග්‍රාමාත්‍ය ධූරයට දිනේෂ් ගුණවර්ධන මහතා පසුගියදා පත් කරනු ලැබීය. ඔහු   ඉකුත් 22 වැනිදා  ජනාධිපතිවරයා ඉදිරියේ එම තනතුරේ දිවුරුම් දුන්නේය.",
        "දිනේෂ් ගුණවර්ධන මහතා අග්‍රාමාත්‍ය ධූරයට පත්වීමට පෙර පළාත් පාලන ස්වදේශ කටයුතු හා පළාත් සභා  අමාත්‍යවරයා ලෙස ද පාර්ලිමේන්තුවේ සභානායකවරයා ලෙසද කටයුතු කළේය.",
        "කෘතහස්ත දේශපාලනඥයකු වන  ගුණවර්ධන මහතා මෙරට ප්‍රසිද්ධ වාමාංශික නායකයකුවූ පිලිප් ගුණවර්ධන මහතාගේ පුත්‍රයාය."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "දිනේෂ්",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "දිනේෂ් ගුණවර්ධන",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "මේ උදෑසන",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "25",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "දිනේෂ් ගුණවර්ධන",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "22 වැනි",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "දිනේෂ් ගුණවර්ධන",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "පළාත් සභා",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ගුණවර්ධන ය",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "පිලිප් ගුණවර්ධන",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "பிரதமர் தினேஷ் பணிகளை தொடங்கி வைத்தார்",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "பிரதமர் தினேஷ் குணவர்தன இன்று (25) காலை பிரதமர் அலுவலகத்தில் பதவியேற்றார்.",
        "திரு.ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்கவினால் புதிய அரசாங்கத்தின் பிரதமராக திரு.தினேஷ் குணவர்தன அண்மையில் நியமிக்கப்பட்டார். கடந்த 22ஆம் திகதி ஜனாதிபதி முன்னிலையில் பதவிப் பிரமாணம் செய்துகொண்டார்.",
        "திரு.தினேஷ் குணவர்தன உள்ளூராட்சி உள்நாட்டலுவல்கள் மற்றும் மாகாண சபைகள் அமைச்சராகவும், பிரதமராவதற்கு முன்னர் பாராளுமன்றத்தின் தலைவராகவும் பணியாற்றினார்.",
        "ஒரு சிறந்த அரசியல்வாதியான திரு.குணவர்தன, இந்நாட்டில் நன்கு அறியப்பட்ட இடதுசாரித் தலைவரான திரு.பிலிப் குணவர்தனவின் மகனாவார்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "தினேஷ்",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "தினேஷ் குணவர்தன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று காலை",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "25",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "தினேஷ் குணவர்தன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "22வது",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "தினேஷ் குணவர்தன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "மாகாண சபைகள்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "குணவர்தன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "பிலிப் குணவர்தன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}