{
  "newspaper_id": "virakesari-lk",
  "url": "http://www.virakesari.lk/article/131967",
  "time_ut": 1658403288,
  "original_lang": "ta",
  "original_title": "‘நோ-டீல் கம’ போராட்டக்களத்தை அகற்ற தீர்மானம்",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Resolution to eliminate the 'No-Deal Kama' protest",
      "author": "T Yuwaraj",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO - Anti-government protesters have decided to remove the 'No-Deal Gama' protest site set up in front of the Prime Minister's official residence, Alarimalika, in the Kollupitiya area.",
        "After the appointment of Ranil Wickremesinghe as Prime Minister in May 2022, the 'No-Deal Coma' protest was formed by anti-government protesters.",
        "Ranil Wickremesinghe was appointed Prime Minister by former President Gotabaya Rajapaksa after former Prime Minister Mahinda Rajapaksa resigned as Prime Minister following the May 09 violence.",
        "In this case, after Ranil Wickremesinghe was sworn in as the Prime Minister, the anti-government protesters set up a 'No-Deal Kama' protest site in front of the Alari House.",
        "It is noteworthy that as Ranil Wickremesinghe has been sworn in today as the 8th executive president of Sri Lanka, the protestors have decided to remove the protest site from that area."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Kollupitiya",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "May 2022",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Gotabaya Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Mahinda Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "May 09",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Alari House",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "8th",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "‘නෝ ඩීල් කම’ විරෝධය නැති කිරීමට යෝජනාවක්",
      "author": "ටී යුවරාජ්",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO - කොල්ලුපිටිය ප්‍රදේශයේ අග්‍රාමාත්‍ය නිල නිවස වන ඇලරිමලිකා ඉදිරිපිට පිහිටුවා ඇති ‘නෝ ඩීල් ගම’ විරෝධතා ස්ථානය ඉවත් කිරීමට ආණ්ඩු විරෝධී විරෝධතාකරුවන් තීරණය කර තිබේ.",
        "2022 මැයි මාසයේදී රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතා අග්‍රාමාත්‍ය ධුරයට පත්වීමෙන් පසු ‘නෝ ඩීල් කෝමා’ විරෝධතාව ගොඩනැගුනේ ආණ්ඩු විරෝධී උද්ඝෝෂකයන් විසිනි.",
        "මැයි 09 ප්‍රචණ්ඩත්වය හේතුවෙන් හිටපු අගමැති මහින්ද රාජපක්ෂ මහතා අගමැති ධූරයෙන් ඉල්ලා අස්වීමෙන් පසු හිටපු ජනාධිපති ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ මහතා විසින් රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතා අග්‍රාමාත්‍යවරයා ලෙස පත් කරන ලදී.",
        "මෙම නඩුවේදී රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතා අග්‍රාමාත්‍යවරයා ලෙස දිවුරුම් දීමෙන් පසු ආණ්ඩු විරෝධී උද්ඝෝෂකයින් විසින් අලරි නිවස ඉදිරිපිට 'නෝ ඩීල් කම' විරෝධතා භූමියක් පිහිටුවා ගත්හ.",
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ 8 වැනි විධායක ජනාධිපතිවරයා ලෙස රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතා අද දිවුරුම් දී ඇති බැවින් විරෝධතාවයේ නිරත වූ ස්ථානය එම ප්‍රදේශයෙන් ඉවත් කිරීමට විරෝධතාකරුවන් තීරණය කර තිබීම විශේෂත්වයකි."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "කොල්ලුපිටිය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "2022 මැයි",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "මහින්ද රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "මැයි 09",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ආලාරි මන්දිරය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "8 වැනි",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "‘நோ-டீல் கம’ போராட்டக்களத்தை அகற்ற தீர்மானம்",
      "author": "T Yuwaraj",
      "body_lines": [
        "கொழும்பு - கொள்ளுப்பிட்டி பகுதியில் உள்ள பிரதமரின் உத்தியோகபூர்வ இல்லமான அலரிமாளிகைக்கு முன்னால் அமைக்கப்பட்டுள்ள 'நோ-டீல் கம’ போராட்டக்களத்தை அகற்ற அரசாங்க எதிர்ப்பு போராட்டக்காரர்கள் தீர்மானித்துள்ளனர்.",
        "2022 ஆம் ஆண்டு மே மாதம் ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க பிரதமராக நியமிக்கப்பட்டதை அடுத்து, அரச எதிர்ப்பு போராட்டக்காரர்களால் ‘நோ-டீல் கம’ போராட்டக்களம் அமைக்கப்பட்டது.",
        "மே 09 ஏற்பட்ட வன்முறையின் பின்னர் முன்னாள் பிரதமர் மஹிந்த ராஜபக்ஷ பிரதமர் பதவியை ராஜினாமா செய்ததையடுத்து முன்னாள் ஜனாதிபதி கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ஷவினால் ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க பிரதமராக நியமிக்கப்பட்டார்.",
        "இந்நிலையில், ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க பிரதமராக பதவியேற்றதையடுத்து அரச எதிர்ப்பு ஆர்ப்பாட்டக்காரர்கள் அலரி மாளிகைக்கு முன்னால் ‘நோ-டீல் கம’ போராட்டக்களத்தை அமைத்தனர்.",
        "இதையடுத்து இலங்கையின் 8 ஆவது நிறைவேற்று அதிகாரம் கொண்ட ஜனாதிபதியாக ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க இன்று பதவிப்பிரமாணம் செய்துள்ள நிலையில், குறித்த பகுதியில் இருந்த போராட்டக்களத்தை அங்கிருந்து அகற்ற போராட்டக்காரர்கள் தீர்மானித்துள்ளமை குறிப்பிடத்தக்கது."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "கொள்ளுப்பிட்டி",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "மே 2022",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "மஹிந்த ராஜபக்ஷ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "மே 09",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "அலரி மாளிகை",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "8வது",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}