{
  "newspaper_id": "lankadeepa-lk",
  "url": "https://www.lankadeepa.lk/latest_news/ජී-එම්-ඕ-ඒ-අනතුරු-අඟවයි/1-616242",
  "time_ut": 1657531455,
  "original_lang": "si",
  "original_title": "ජී.එම්.ඕ.ඒ අනතුරු අඟවයි",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "GMOA warns",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "The Ministry of Health has informed the Government Medical Officers' Association to take necessary measures from now on as there is a possibility of spreading the Omacron 2.75 variant of Corona in Sri Lanka which is currently spreading across India.",
        "Dr. Haritha Aluthge, editor of the Government Medical Officers' Association, says that the Ministerial Technology Advisory Committee has been informed to gather immediately and take the necessary measures as there is a situation where the people will not be able to pay attention to the disease if it spreads in the country's economic crisis.",
        "Dr. Aluthge also mentioned that although this variety has not been reported from Sri Lanka, early preparation is important.",
        "The Ministry of Health has also been informed to encourage the people who have not received all three vaccines to get vaccinated."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "The Ministry of Health",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Government Medical Officers' Association",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Omacron",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Corona",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "India",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Haritha Aluthge",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Government Medical Officers' Association",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Ministerial Technology Advisory Committee",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Aluthge",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "The Ministry of Health",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "three",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "ජී.එම්.ඕ.ඒ අනතුරු අඟවයි",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "දැනට ඉන්දියාව පුරා පැතිරෙමින් පවතින ඔමක්‍රෝන් 2.75 කොරෝනා ප්‍රභේදය ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ ව්‍යාප්තවීමට ඉඩකඩ ඇති නිසා දැන් සිටම අවශ්‍ය පියවර ගන්නැයි රජයේ වෛද්‍ය නිලධාරින්ගේ සංගමය සෞඛ්‍ය අමාත්‍යංශයෙන් දැනුම් දි ඇත.",
        "රටේ පවතින ආර්ථික අර්බුදය අස්සේ මෙම රෝගය ව්‍යාප්ත වුවහොත් ජනතාවට ඒ සම්බන්ධයෙන් අවධානයක් දැක්වීමට නොහැකි තත්ත්වයක් පවතින බැවින්  අමාත්‍යංශ තාක්ෂණ උපදේශක කමිටුව වහාම රැස්කර අවශ්‍ය පියවර ගන්නා ලෙසට දැනුම් දී ඇතැයි රජයේ වෛද්‍ය නිලදාරින්ගේ සංගමයේ සංස්කාරක වෛද්‍ය හරිත අලුත්ගේ මහතා පවසයි.",
        "මෙම ප්‍රභේදය දැනට ලංකාවෙන් වාර්තා වී නැතත් කල් ඇතිව සූදානම වැදගත් බව ද වෛද්‍ය අලුත්ගේ මහතා සඳහන් කළේය.",
        "මේ වන විට එන්නත් තුනම ලබාගෙන නැති ජනතාව එන්නත් ලබාගැනීමට පොළඹවන ලෙස ද සෞඛ්‍ය අමාත්‍යංශයට දන්වා ඇත."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "සෞඛ්‍ය අමාත්‍යාංශය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "රජයේ වෛද්‍ය නිලධාරීන්ගේ සංගමය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඔමැක්රොන්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "කොරෝනා",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "හරිත අලුත්ගේ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "රජයේ වෛද්‍ය නිලධාරීන්ගේ සංගමය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "අමාත්‍ය තාක්ෂණ උපදේශක කමිටුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "අලුත්ගේ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "සෞඛ්‍ය අමාත්‍යාංශය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "තුන්",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "GMOA எச்சரிக்கிறது",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "தற்போது இந்தியா முழுவதும் பரவி வரும் ஒமக்ரோன் 2.75 வகை கொரோனா வைரஸ் இலங்கையிலும் பரவுவதற்கான சாத்தியக்கூறுகள் இருப்பதால், இனிமேலாவது தேவையான நடவடிக்கைகளை எடுக்குமாறு சுகாதார அமைச்சு அரசாங்க மருத்துவ அதிகாரிகள் சங்கத்திற்கு அறிவித்துள்ளது.",
        "இந்நோய் தொடர்பில் மக்கள் கவனம் செலுத்த முடியாத நிலை ஏற்பட்டுள்ளதால், அமைச்சர் தொழிநுட்ப ஆலோசனைக் குழுவை உடனடியாகக் கூடி தேவையான நடவடிக்கைகளை மேற்கொள்ளுமாறு அறிவிக்கப்பட்டுள்ளதாக அரச வைத்திய அதிகாரிகள் சங்கத்தின் ஆசிரியர் டொக்டர் ஹரித அலுத்கே தெரிவித்துள்ளார். நாட்டில் ஏற்பட்டுள்ள பொருளாதார நெருக்கடி காரணமாக பரவினால்.",
        "இந்த வகை இலங்கையில் இருந்து பதிவாகவில்லை என்றாலும், முன்கூட்டியே தயார் செய்வது முக்கியம் என்றும் டாக்டர் அலுத்கே குறிப்பிட்டார்.",
        "மூன்று தடுப்பூசிகளையும் பெற்றுக் கொள்ளாதவர்களை தடுப்பூசிகளைப் போட்டுக்கொள்ள ஊக்குவிக்குமாறு சுகாதார அமைச்சுக்கு அறிவிக்கப்பட்டுள்ளது."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "சுகாதார அமைச்சு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "அரசாங்க மருத்துவ அதிகாரிகள் சங்கம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஓமக்ரான்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "கொரோனா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்தியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஹரிதா அலுத்கே",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "அரசாங்க மருத்துவ அதிகாரிகள் சங்கம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "மந்திரி தொழில்நுட்ப ஆலோசனைக் குழு",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "அலுத்கே",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "சுகாதார அமைச்சு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "மூன்று",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}