{
  "newspaper_id": "daily-ft-lk",
  "url": "https://www.ft.lk/news/Cardinal-says-SL-will-not-achieve-true-freedom-till-supremacy-of-law-maintained/56-738686",
  "time_ut": 1660507964,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Cardinal says SL will not achieve true freedom till supremacy of law maintained",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Cardinal says SL will not achieve true freedom till supremacy of law maintained",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "Archbishop of Colombo Cardinal Malcolm Ranjith yesterday pointed out that Sri Lanka will not achieve its true freedom till the supremacy of the law is maintained.",
        "“The legal system is bent according to the will of the political leaders over and over again during the past 74 years. Till this system is changed, Sri Lanka will never be free. The slavery to politicians will continue, till the day that the legal system is completely independent of persons in power,” Cardinal said during an event held at the St. Anthony’s Church in Kochchikade, yesterday.",
        "Last week, Pope Francis granted € 100,000, as an aid to the victims of the 2019 Easter Sunday attacks. The financial aid was disbursed among the affected families at the St. Sebastian’s Church in Katuwapitiya and St. Anthony’s Church in Kochchikade yesterday.",
        "“Sri Lanka will not achieve its true freedom, till political leaders themselves, obey the rule of law,” he added.",
        "The Cardinal also stressed that justice does not prevail in Sri Lanka in most instances, and people have lost faith in the judicial system.",
        "“Despite the concerns and appeals made by Pope Francis for justice for the victims of the 2019 Easter Sunday attacks, our authorities have not taken any action against the culprits,” he claimed.",
        "He went on to blame generations of politicians for influencing the law, to obtain personal benefits, whilst dragging the country down the drain in the process.",
        "The Cardinal also stressed that all of Sri Lanka’s political leaders have contributed to destroying the independence of the judiciary, after coming to power.",
        "“Sri Lanka is not truly independent even after 74 years if the Police continue to be influenced by politicians and connected persons,” he pointed out."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Malcolm Ranjith",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "yesterday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the past 74 years",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the day",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the St. Anthony’s Church",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kochchikade",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "yesterday",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Last week",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Pope Francis",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "100,000",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "2019",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sunday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the St. Sebastian’s Church in Katuwapitiya and St. Anthony’s Church",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kochchikade",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "yesterday",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "LOC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Francis",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "2019",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sunday",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "74 years",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "නීතියේ ආධිපත්‍යය රැකෙන තුරු ශ්‍රී ලංකාවට සැබෑ නිදහසක් නොලැබෙන බව කාදිනල්තුමා පවසයි",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "නීතියේ උත්තරීතර භාවය රැකෙන තුරු ශ්‍රී ලංකාවට සැබෑ නිදහස හිමි නොවන බව කොළඹ අගරදගුරු කාදිනල් මැල්කම් රංජිත් හිමිපාණන් ඊයේ පෙන්වා දුන්නා.",
        "“පසුගිය වසර 74 තුළ දේශපාලන නායකයින්ගේ කැමැත්තට අනුව නීති පද්ධතිය නැවත නැවතත් නැවී තිබෙනවා. මේ ක්‍රමය වෙනස් කරන තුරු ශ්‍රී ලංකාවට කිසිදා නිදහසක් නැත. නීති පද්ධතිය බලයේ සිටින පුද්ගලයන්ගෙන් සම්පූර්ණයෙන්ම ස්වාධීන වන දිනය දක්වා දේශපාලනඥයන්ගේ වහල්භාවය දිගටම පවතිනු ඇත, ”කාදිනල්තුමා ඊයේ කොච්චිකඩේ ශාන්ත අන්තෝනි දේවස්ථානයේ පැවති උත්සවයකදී පැවසීය.",
        "2019 පාස්කු ඉරිදා ප්‍රහාරයෙන් විපතට පත් වූවන්ට ආධාර වශයෙන් පසුගිය සතියේ ෆ්‍රැන්සිස් පාප් වහන්සේ යුරෝ 100,000ක් ප්‍රදානය කළහ. ඊයේ කටුවාපිටිය ශාන්ත සෙබස්තියන් දේවස්ථානයේදී සහ කොච්චිකඩේ ශාන්ත අන්තෝනි දේවස්ථානයේදී විපතට පත් පවුල් වෙත මුල්‍ය ආධාර ලබාදීම සිදුකෙරුණා.",
        "\"දේශපාලන නායකයන් විසින්ම නීතියේ ආධිපත්‍යයට අවනත වන තුරු ශ්‍රී ලංකාව එහි සැබෑ නිදහස අත්කර නොගනු ඇත,\" ඔහු වැඩිදුරටත් පැවසීය.",
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකාව තුළ බොහෝ අවස්ථාවලදී යුක්තිය ඉටු නොවන බවත්, අධිකරණ පද්ධතිය කෙරෙහි ජනතාවගේ විශ්වාසය නැති වී ඇති බවත් කාදිනල්තුමා අවධාරණය කළේය.",
        "\"2019 පාස්කු ඉරිදා ප්‍රහාරයේ වින්දිතයින්ට යුක්තිය පසිඳලීම සඳහා ෆ්‍රැන්සිස් පාප් වහන්සේ විසින් කනස්සල්ල සහ ආයාචනා කළද, අපගේ බලධාරීන් වැරදිකරුවන්ට එරෙහිව කිසිදු ක්‍රියාමාර්ගයක් ගෙන නොමැත,\" ඔහු කියා සිටියේය.",
        "එම ක්‍රියාවලියේ දී රට කාණුවට ඇද දමන අතරම, නීතියට බලපෑම් කිරීම, පුද්ගලික ප්‍රතිලාභ ලබා ගැනීම සම්බන්ධයෙන් ඔහු දේශපාලනඥයන්ගේ පරම්පරාවන්ට දොස් පැවරීය.",
        "බලයට පත්වීමෙන් පසු ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ සියලුම දේශපාලන නායකයින් අධිකරණයේ ස්වාධීනත්වය විනාශ කිරීමට දායක වී ඇති බව ද කාදිනල් හිමිපාණෝ අවධාරණය කළහ.",
        "“පොලිසියට දේශපාලනඥයින්ගේ සහ සම්බන්ධිත පුද්ගලයන්ගේ බලපෑම් දිගටම පවතින්නේ නම් වසර 74කට පසුවත් ශ්‍රී ලංකාව සැබවින්ම ස්වාධීන නොවේ,” ඔහු පෙන්වා දුන්නේය."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "මැල්කම් රංජිත්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඊයේ",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "පසුගිය වසර 74 තුළ",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "දවස",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශාන්ත අන්තෝනි දේවස්ථානය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "කොච්චිකඩේ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඊයේ",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ගිය සතිය",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ෆ්රැන්සිස් පාප් වහන්සේ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "100,000 කි",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "2019",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉරිදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "කටුවාපිටිය ශාන්ත සෙබස්තියන් දේවස්ථානය සහ ශාන්ත අන්තෝනි දේවස්ථානය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "කොච්චිකඩේ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඊයේ",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "LOC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ෆ්රැන්සිස්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "2019",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉරිදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "අවුරුදු 74 යි",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "சட்டத்தின் மேலாதிக்கம் பேணப்படும் வரை இலங்கை உண்மையான சுதந்திரத்தை அடையாது என்று கார்டினல் கூறுகிறார்",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "சட்டத்தின் மேலாதிக்கம் நிலைநாட்டப்படும் வரை இலங்கை உண்மையான சுதந்திரத்தை அடையாது என கொழும்பு பேராயர் கர்தினால் மல்கம் ரஞ்சித் நேற்று சுட்டிக்காட்டினார்.",
        "கடந்த 74 ஆண்டுகளில் அரசியல் தலைவர்களின் விருப்பத்திற்கேற்ப சட்ட அமைப்பு வளைந்துள்ளது. இந்த முறை மாற்றப்படும் வரை இலங்கைக்கு சுதந்திரம் கிடைக்காது. அதிகாரத்தில் இருப்பவர்களிடமிருந்து சட்ட அமைப்பு முற்றிலும் சுதந்திரமாக இருக்கும் நாள் வரை அரசியல்வாதிகளின் அடிமைத்தனம் தொடரும்” என கொச்சிக்கடை புனித அந்தோனியார் தேவாலயத்தில் நேற்று நடைபெற்ற நிகழ்வொன்றில் கர்தினால் கூறினார்.",
        "கடந்த வாரம், போப் பிரான்சிஸ் 2019 ஈஸ்டர் ஞாயிறு தாக்குதலில் பாதிக்கப்பட்டவர்களுக்கு உதவியாக 100,000 யூரோக்களை வழங்கினார். கட்டுவாப்பிட்டி புனித செபஸ்தியார் தேவாலயம் மற்றும் கொச்சிக்கடை புனித அந்தோனியார் தேவாலயத்தில் பாதிக்கப்பட்ட குடும்பங்களுக்கு நிதியுதவி நேற்று வழங்கப்பட்டது.",
        "\"அரசியல் தலைவர்கள் தாங்களாகவே சட்டத்தின் ஆட்சிக்குக் கீழ்ப்படியும் வரை இலங்கை அதன் உண்மையான சுதந்திரத்தை அடையாது\" என்று அவர் மேலும் கூறினார்.",
        "பெரும்பாலான சந்தர்ப்பங்களில் இலங்கையில் நீதி நிலைநாட்டப்படுவதில்லை என்றும், நீதித்துறையின் மீது மக்கள் நம்பிக்கை இழந்துவிட்டனர் என்றும் கர்தினால் வலியுறுத்தினார்.",
        "\"2019 ஈஸ்டர் ஞாயிறு தாக்குதலில் பாதிக்கப்பட்டவர்களுக்கு நீதி கோரி போப் பிரான்சிஸ் கவலைகள் மற்றும் முறையீடுகள் செய்த போதிலும், எங்கள் அதிகாரிகள் குற்றவாளிகளுக்கு எதிராக எந்த நடவடிக்கையும் எடுக்கவில்லை,\" என்று அவர் கூறினார்.",
        "சட்டத்தின் மீது செல்வாக்கு செலுத்துவதற்கும், தனிப்பட்ட நன்மைகளைப் பெறுவதற்கும், அதே நேரத்தில் நாட்டை சாக்கடையில் இழுப்பதற்காகவும் அவர் தலைமுறை தலைமுறையாக அரசியல்வாதிகளை குற்றம் சாட்டினார்.",
        "இலங்கையின் அனைத்து அரசியல் தலைவர்களும் ஆட்சிக்கு வந்த பின்னர், நீதித்துறையின் சுதந்திரத்தை அழிப்பதில் பங்களிப்பு செய்துள்ளதாகவும் கர்தினால் வலியுறுத்தினார்.",
        "அரசியல்வாதிகள் மற்றும் தொடர்புடைய நபர்களால் பொலிசார் தொடர்ந்து செல்வாக்குச் செலுத்தினால், 74 ஆண்டுகளுக்குப் பிறகும் இலங்கை உண்மையிலேயே சுதந்திரமாக இல்லை,\" என்று அவர் சுட்டிக்காட்டினார்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "மால்கம் ரஞ்சித்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "நேற்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "கடந்த 74 ஆண்டுகளாக",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "தினம்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "புனித அந்தோணி தேவாலயம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "கொச்சிக்கடை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "நேற்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "கடந்த வாரம்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "போப் பிரான்சிஸ்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "100,000",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "2019",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஞாயிற்றுக்கிழமை",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "கட்டுவாப்பிட்டியில் உள்ள புனித செபஸ்டியன் தேவாலயம் மற்றும் புனித அந்தோனியார் தேவாலயம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "கொச்சிக்கடை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "நேற்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "LOC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பிரான்சிஸ்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "2019",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஞாயிற்றுக்கிழமை",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "74 ஆண்டுகள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}