{
  "newspaper_id": "daily-mirror-lk",
  "url": "https://www.dailymirror.lk/breaking_news/India-should-be-alert-about-unruly-behavior-of-lumpen-elements-in-SL-Swamy/108-241002",
  "time_ut": 1657710931,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "India should be alert about unruly behavior of lumpen elements in SL-Swamy",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "India should be alert about unruly behavior of lumpen elements in SL-Swamy",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "Indian ruling party politician Subramanian Swamy says India should be alert about unruly behavior of lumpen elements in Sri Lanka.",
        "He tweeted ,”After getting information that the unruly crowds roaming around Colombo are being guided by SL version of Naxals, Jehadis, anti- socials etc ., India has to be concerned about Sri Lanka’s degeneration caused by lumpen elements, and its future impact on India.”"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "India",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "SL-Swamy",
          "label": "WORK_OF_ART"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Indian",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Subramanian Swamy",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "India",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Colombo",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Jehadis",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "India",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "India",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "SL-Swamy හි ලුම්පන් මූලද්‍රව්‍යවල නොහික්මුණු හැසිරීම් පිළිබඳව ඉන්දියාව අවදියෙන් සිටිය යුතුය",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ ලුම්පන් කොටස්වල නොහික්මුණු හැසිරීම් පිළිබඳව ඉන්දියාව අවධානයෙන් සිටිය යුතු බව ඉන්දීය පාලක පක්ෂ දේශපාලනඥයා වන සුබ්‍රමනියන් ස්වාමි පවසයි.",
        "ඔහු ට්විටර් පණිවුඩයක් නිකුත් කරමින් කියා සිටියේ, “කොළඹ අවට සැරිසරන නොහික්මුණු ජනකාය නක්සල්, ජෙහාඩි, සමාජ විරෝධී වැනි ශ්‍රී ලංකා අනුවාදයෙන් මෙහෙයවන බවට තොරතුරු ලැබීමෙන් පසු, ඉන්දියාවට ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ ලූම්පන් මූලද්‍රව්‍ය නිසා ඇති වන පරිහානිය සහ එහි අනාගත බලපෑම ගැන සැලකිලිමත් විය යුතුය. ඉන්දියාව.\""
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ඉන්දියාව",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "SL-ස්වාමි",
          "label": "WORK_OF_ART"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දීය",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "සුබ්‍රමනියන් ස්වාමි",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "කොළඹ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජෙහාඩිස්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "எஸ்.எல்.-சுவாமியின் லும்பன் கூறுகளின் கட்டுக்கடங்காத நடத்தை குறித்து இந்தியா எச்சரிக்கையாக இருக்க வேண்டும்",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "இந்திய ஆளும் கட்சி அரசியல்வாதியான சுப்பிரமணியன் சுவாமி, இலங்கையில் லம்பன் கூறுகளின் கட்டுக்கடங்காத நடத்தை குறித்து இந்தியா எச்சரிக்கையாக இருக்க வேண்டும் என்று கூறுகிறார்.",
        "அவர் தனது ட்விட்டர் பதிவில், ”கொழும்பில் சுற்றித்திரியும் கட்டுக்கடங்காத கூட்டம் நக்சல்கள், ஜெஹாதிகள், சமூகவிரோதிகள் போன்றவற்றின் SL பதிப்பால் வழிநடத்தப்படுகிறது என்ற தகவல் கிடைத்ததும், இலங்கையின் சீரழிவு மற்றும் அதன் எதிர்கால தாக்கம் குறித்து இந்தியா கவலைப்பட வேண்டும். இந்தியா.”"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "இந்தியா",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "எஸ்.எல்-சுவாமி",
          "label": "WORK_OF_ART"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "இந்தியன்",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "சுப்பிரமணியன் சுவாமி",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்தியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "கொழும்பு",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜெஹாதிகள்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்தியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்தியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}