{
  "newspaper_id": "virakesari-lk",
  "url": "http://www.virakesari.lk/article/131360",
  "time_ut": 1657695570,
  "original_lang": "ta",
  "original_title": "இன்றைய வானிலை !",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Today's weather!",
      "author": "Digital Desk 5",
      "body_lines": [
        "The Department of Meteorology has said that it will rain several times in Sabaragamuwa province and Nuwara Eliya, Kandy, Galle and Matara districts.",
        "The western slopes of Central Highlands and North, North Central and North Western Provinces and Trincomalee and Ambandottai districts may experience gusty winds of up to 50 kmph from time to time.",
        "There will be light rain over coastal areas from Puttalam through Colombo and Galle to Matara.",
        "Wind will blow from South-West direction with wind speed of 30-40 kmph. The wind speed may increase to 50-60 kmph over the coastal areas from Puttalam to Trincomalee via Gangesanthurai and Mannar and from Matara to Pottuvil via Ambandottai.",
        "The sea surface from Puttalam to Trincomalee via Kangesanthurai and Mannar and from Matara to Pottuvil via Hambantota will be rough from time to time. Other sea surfaces around the island are expected to be somewhat rough from time to time."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Today",
          "label": "DATE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "The Department of Meteorology",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sabaragamuwa province",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Nuwara Eliya",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kandy",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Galle",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Matara",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Central Highlands",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "North Central",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "Trincomalee",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ambandottai",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "up to 50 kmph",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Puttalam",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Colombo",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Galle",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Matara",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "South-West",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "30-40 kmph",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "50-60 kmph",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "Puttalam",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Trincomalee",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Gangesanthurai and Mannar",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Matara",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Puttalam",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Trincomalee",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Matara",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "අද කාලගුණය!",
      "author": "ඩිජිටල් මේසය 5",
      "body_lines": [
        "සබරගමුව පළාතේත් නුවරඑළිය, මහනුවර, ගාල්ල සහ මාතර දිස්ත්‍රික්කවලත් විටින් විට වැසි ඇති විය හැකි බව කාලගුණ විද්‍යා දෙපාර්තමේන්තුව පවසයි.",
        "මධ්‍යම කඳුකරයේ බටහිර බෑවුම් ප්‍රදේශවල සහ උතුර, උතුරු මැද සහ වයඹ පළාත්වලත් ත්‍රිකුණාමලය සහ අම්බන්තොට්ටෙයි දිස්ත්‍රික්කවලත් විටින් විට හමන පැ.කි.මී.50 දක්වා තද සුළං ඇති විය හැක.",
        "පුත්තලම සිට කොළඹ සහ ගාල්ල හරහා මාතර දක්වා වෙරළබඩ ප්‍රදේශවල සිහින් වැසි ඇති වේ.",
        "සුළඟේ වේගය පැ.කි.මී. 30-40 දක්වාත් සමඟ නිරිත දෙසින් සුළඟ හමයි. පුත්තලම සිට ගංගේසන්තුරය සහ මන්නාරම හරහා ත්‍රිකුණාමලය දක්වා සහ මාතර සිට අඹන්තොට හරහා පොතුවිල් දක්වා වෙරළබඩ ප්‍රදේශවල සුළගේ වේගය පැ.කි.මී.50-60 දක්වා වැඩි විය හැක.",
        "පුත්තලම සිට කාංගේසන්තුරේ සහ මන්නාරම හරහා ත්‍රිකුණාමලය දක්වා සහ මාතර සිට හම්බන්තොට හරහා පොතුවිල් දක්වා වන මුහුදු පෘෂ්ඨය විටින් විට රළු වේ. දිවයින වටා වන අනෙකුත් මුහුදු පෘෂ්ඨයන් විටින් විට තරමක් රළු විය හැක."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "අද",
          "label": "DATE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "කාලගුණ විද්‍යා දෙපාර්තමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "සබරගමුව පළාත",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "නුවරඑළිය",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "මහනුවර",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගාල්ල",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මාතර",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "මධ්‍යම කඳුකරය",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "උතුරු මැද",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "ත්රිකුණාමලය",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "අම්බන්ඩොට්ටයි",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "50 kmph දක්වා",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "පුත්තලම",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "කොළඹ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගාල්ල",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මාතර",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "නිරිත-බටහිර",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "30-40 kmph",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "50-60 kmph",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "පුත්තලම",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ත්රිකුණාමලය",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගංගේසන්තුරේ සහ මන්නාරම",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "මාතර",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "පුත්තලම",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ත්රිකුණාමලය",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "මාතර",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "இன்றைய வானிலை !",
      "author": "Digital Desk 5",
      "body_lines": [
        "சப்ரகமுவ மாகாணத்திலும் நுவரெலியா, கண்டி, காலி மற்றும் மாத்தறை மாவட்டங்களிலும் பல தடவைகள் மழை பெய்யும் என வளிமண்டலவியல் திணைக்களம் தெரிவித்துள்ளது.",
        "மத்திய மலைநாட்டின் மேற்கு சரிவுகளிலும் வடக்கு, வடமத்திய மற்றும் வடமேற்கு மாகாணங்களிலும் திருகோணமலை மற்றும் அம்பாந்தோட்டை மாவட்டங்களிலும் அவ்வப்போது மணித்தியாலத்துக்கு 50 கிலோமீற்றர் வேகத்தில் பலத்த காற்று வீசக்கூடும்.",
        "புத்தளத்திலிருந்து கொழும்பு மற்றும் காலி ஊடாக மாத்தறை வரையான கடற்கரைக்கு அப்பாற்பட்ட கடற்பரப்புகளில் சிறிதளவு மழை பெய்யும்.",
        "காற்று தென்மேற்கு திசையில் வீசும், காற்றின் வேகம் மணிக்கு 30-40 கி.மீ. புத்தளத்திலிருந்து காங்கேசன்துறை மற்றும் மன்னார் ஊடாக திருகோணமலை வரையிலும் மாத்தறையிலிருந்து அம்பாந்தோட்டை ஊடாக பொத்துவில் வரையான கடற்பரப்புகளிலும் காற்றின் வேகமானது மணித்தியாலத்துக்கு 50-60 கிலோ மீற்றர் வரை அதிகரித்து வீசக்கூடும்.",
        "புத்தளத்திலிருந்து காங்கேசன்துறை மற்றும் மன்னார் ஊடாக திருகோணமலை வரையிலும் மாத்தறையிலிருந்து ஹம்பாந்தோட்டை ஊடாக பொத்துவில் வரையான கடற்பரப்புகளும் அவ்வப்போது கொந்தளிப்பாக காணப்படும். தீவைச் சுற்றியுள்ள ஏனைய கடற்பரப்புகள் அவ்வப்போது ஓரளவு கொந்தளிப்பாகக் காணப்படும் என எதிர்பார்க்கப்படுகிறது."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "இன்று",
          "label": "DATE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "வளிமண்டலவியல் திணைக்களம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "சப்ரகமுவ மாகாணம்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "நுவரெலியா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "கண்டி",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "காலி",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "மாத்தறை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "மத்திய மலைநாடு",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "வட மத்திய",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "திருகோணமலை",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "அம்பந்தோட்டை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "மணிக்கு 50 கி.மீ",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "புத்தளம்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "கொழும்பு",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "காலி",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "மாத்தறை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "தென்மேற்கு",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "மணிக்கு 30-40 கி.மீ",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "மணிக்கு 50-60 கி.மீ",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "புத்தளம்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "திருகோணமலை",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "கங்கேசன்துறை மற்றும் மன்னார்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "மாத்தறை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "புத்தளம்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "திருகோணமலை",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "மாத்தறை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}