{
  "newspaper_id": "ada-lk",
  "url": "https://www.ada.lk/international/නාසා-සඳ-රොකට්ටුව-යළි-දියත්-කිරීමේ-උත්සාහයක/3-396848",
  "time_ut": 1662182761,
  "original_lang": "si",
  "original_title": "නාසා සඳ රොකට්ටුව යළි දියත් කිරීමේ උත්සාහයක",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "NASA is trying to relaunch the moon rocket",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "Ground crews at the Kennedy Space Center in Florida, USA, are nearing the second attempt to send NASA's next-generation giant moon rocket on its maiden test flight.",
        "The final full day of preparations for the launch has begun, five days after technical problems thwarted an initial attempt.",
        "Mission managers prepare to lift off the Space Launch System (SLS) rocket and its Orion space capsule Saturday afternoon to kick off NASA's Moon-to-Mars Artemis program, the successor to the Apollo lunar missions.",
        "Investigations on Thursday night revealed that technicians had fixed a leaking fuel line. That contributed to NASA's decision to halt Monday's initial launch mission, the space station's deputy program manager, Jeremy Parsons, told reporters.",
        "Two other major problems with the rocket, a faulty engine temperature sensor and some cracks in the insulating foam, have been largely resolved, Artemis mission manager Mike Sarafin told reporters.",
        "Accordingly, Melody Lovin, a launch weather officer for the US Space Force at Cape Canaveral, said the launch is expected to take place on Saturday at 2:17 p.m."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "NASA",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "the Kennedy Space Center",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "Florida",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "USA",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "second",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "NASA",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "five days",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the Space Launch System",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Orion",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Saturday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "afternoon",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "NASA",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Moon",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Mars Artemis",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Apollo",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Thursday night",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "NASA",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Monday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Jeremy Parsons",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Two",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Artemis",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Mike Sarafin",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Melody Lovin",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the US Space Force at",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Cape Canaveral",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Saturday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "2:17 p.m.",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "නාසා සඳ රොකට්ටුව යළි දියත් කිරීමේ උත්සාහයක",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "ඇමෙරිකාවේ, ෆ්ලොරිඩාවේ කෙනඩි අභ්‍යවකාශ මධ්‍යස්ථානයේ භූමි කණ්ඩායම් නාසා ඊළඟ පරම්පරාවේ යෝධ සඳ රොකට්ටුව සිය මංගල පරීක්ෂණ පියාසැරිය සඳහා යැවීමේ දෙවැනි උත්සාහයට ආසන්නයට පැමිණ සිටී.",
        "දියත් කිරීමේ අවසාන පූර්ණ දින සූදානම් කිරීම් ආරම්භ කර ඇති අතර, ඒ තාක්ෂණික ගැටළු මූලික උත්සාහයක් අසාර්ථක වීමෙන් දින පහකට පසුවය.",
        "ඇපලෝ චන්ද්‍ර මෙහෙයුම්වල අනුප්‍රාප්තිකයා වන නාසා හි සඳ-අඟහරු ආටෙමිස් වැඩසටහන ආරම්භ කිරීම සඳහා දූත මණ්ඩල කළමනාකරුවන් සෙනසුරාදා දහවල් අභ්‍යවකාශ දියත් කිරීමේ පද්ධතිය (SLS) රොකට්ටුව සහ එහි ඔරියන් අභ්‍යවකාශ කැප්සියුලය ඔසවා තැබීමට සූදානම් වෙයි.",
        "බ්‍රහස්පතින්දා රාත්‍රියේ සිදු කරන ලද පරීක්ෂණවලින් පෙනී ගියේ කාර්මික ශිල්පීන් කාන්දු වන ඉන්ධන මාර්ගයක් සවි කර ඇති බවය. එය සඳුදා ආරම්භක දියත් කිරීමේ මෙහෙයුම නැවැත්වීමට නාසා හි තීරණයට දායක වූ බව අභ්‍යවකාශ මධ්‍යස්ථානයේ නියෝජ්‍ය වැඩසටහන් කළමනාකරු ජෙරමි පාර්සන්ස් වාර්තාකරුවන්ට පැවසීය.",
        "රොකට්ටුවේ ඇති තවත් ප්‍රධාන ගැටළු දෙකක් වන දෝෂ සහිත එන්ජින් උෂ්ණත්ව සංවේදකයක් සහ පරිවාරක පෙනවල සමහර ඉරිතැලීම් බොහෝ දුරට විසඳා ඇති බව ආටෙමිස් මෙහෙවර කළමනාකරු මයික් සරෆින් වාර්තාකරුවන්ට පැවසීය.",
        "ඒ අනුව,කේප් කැනවෙරල් හි එක්සත් ජනපද අභ්‍යවකාශ බලකායේ දියත් කිරීමේ කාලගුණ නිලධාරියෙකු වන මෙලඩි ලොවින් පැවසුවේ සෙනසුරාදා පස්වරු 2:17 ට දියත් කිරීමට අපේක්ෂා කරන බවයි."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "නාසා",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "කෙනඩි අභ්‍යවකාශ මධ්‍යස්ථානය",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "ෆ්ලොරිඩාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඇඑජ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "දෙවැනි",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "නාසා",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "දින පහක්",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "අභ්යවකාශ දියත් කිරීමේ පද්ධතිය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඔරියන්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "සෙනසුරාදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "දහවල්",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "නාසා",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "සඳ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "අඟහරු ආටෙමිස්",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඇපලෝ",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "බ්රහස්පතින්දා රාත්රිය",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "නාසා",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "සඳුදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජෙරමි පාර්සන්ස්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "දෙක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ආටෙමිස්",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Mike Sarafin",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "මෙලඩි ලොවින්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "එක්සත් ජනපද අභ්‍යවකාශ බලකාය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "කේප් කැනවරල්",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "සෙනසුරාදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "2:17 ප.ව.",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "சந்திரன் ராக்கெட்டை மீண்டும் விண்ணில் செலுத்த நாசா முயற்சித்து வருகிறது",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "அமெரிக்காவின் புளோரிடாவில் உள்ள கென்னடி விண்வெளி மையத்தில் உள்ள தரைக் குழுவினர், நாசாவின் அடுத்த தலைமுறை ராட்சத நிலவு ராக்கெட்டை அதன் முதல் சோதனை விமானத்தில் அனுப்பும் இரண்டாவது முயற்சியை நெருங்கியுள்ளனர்.",
        "தொடக்க முயற்சியை தொழில்நுட்பக் கோளாறுகள் முறியடித்த ஐந்து நாட்களுக்குப் பிறகு, ஏவுதலுக்கான இறுதி நாள் முழுவதுமான தயாரிப்புகள் தொடங்கியுள்ளன.",
        "அப்பல்லோ சந்திரப் பயணங்களின் வாரிசான நாசாவின் சந்திரன்-செவ்வாய் ஆர்ட்டெமிஸ் திட்டத்தைத் தொடங்குவதற்காக விண்வெளி ஏவுதள அமைப்பு (SLS) ராக்கெட்டையும் அதன் ஓரியன் ஸ்பேஸ் கேப்சூலையும் சனிக்கிழமை பிற்பகலில் உயர்த்துவதற்கு மிஷன் மேலாளர்கள் தயாராகிறார்கள்.",
        "வியாழன் இரவு விசாரணையில் தொழில்நுட்ப வல்லுநர்கள் கசிவு எரிபொருள் பாதையை சரிசெய்தது தெரியவந்தது. திங்கட்கிழமை ஆரம்ப ஏவுகணை பணியை நிறுத்த நாசாவின் முடிவிற்கு இது பங்களித்தது என்று விண்வெளி நிலையத்தின் துணை நிரல் மேலாளர் ஜெர்மி பார்சன்ஸ் செய்தியாளர்களிடம் கூறினார்.",
        "ராக்கெட்டில் உள்ள மற்ற இரண்டு முக்கிய பிரச்சனைகள், ஒரு தவறான இயந்திர வெப்பநிலை சென்சார் மற்றும் இன்சுலேடிங் நுரையில் சில விரிசல்கள் ஆகியவை பெரும்பாலும் தீர்க்கப்பட்டுள்ளன, ஆர்ட்டெமிஸ் மிஷன் மேலாளர் மைக் சரஃபின் செய்தியாளர்களிடம் கூறினார்.",
        "அதன்படி, கேப் கனாவரலில் உள்ள அமெரிக்க விண்வெளிப் படையின் ஏவுகணை வானிலை அதிகாரி மெலடி லோவின், சனிக்கிழமை பிற்பகல் 2:17 மணிக்கு ஏவப்படும் என எதிர்பார்க்கப்படுகிறது."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "நாசா",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "கென்னடி விண்வெளி மையம்",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "புளோரிடா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "அமெரிக்கா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இரண்டாவது",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "நாசா",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஐந்து நாட்கள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "விண்வெளி ஏவுதல் அமைப்பு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஓரியன்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "சனிக்கிழமை",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "பிற்பகல்",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "நாசா",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "நிலா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "செவ்வாய் ஆர்ட்டெமிஸ்",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "அப்பல்லோ",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "வியாழன் இரவு",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "நாசா",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "திங்கட்கிழமை",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜெர்மி பார்சன்ஸ்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இரண்டு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆர்ட்டெமிஸ்",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Mike Sarafin",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "மெலடி லோவின்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "அமெரிக்க விண்வெளிப் படையில்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "கேப் கனாவெரல்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சனிக்கிழமை",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "பிற்பகல் 2:17",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}