{
  "newspaper_id": "lankadeepa-lk",
  "url": "https://www.lankadeepa.lk/latest_news/මාතර-ගෝඨා-ගෝගමට-ප්‍රහාරයක්/1-616942",
  "time_ut": 1658654493,
  "original_lang": "si",
  "original_title": "මාතර ගෝඨා ගෝගමට ප්‍රහාරයක්",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "An attack on Gota Gogama, Matara",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "The organizers say that some group attacked Matara Gotagogama last night.",
        "A group of about six people who arrived in a luxury jeep showed a knife and scared a young man away and caused damage to the premises.",
        "Banners and cutouts drawn and exhibited by the struggling youth were also cut and damaged.",
        "It is not yet known who did this.",
        "However, the attack took place at a time when the organizers had decided to evacuate the Matara Gotagogama premises yesterday (24).",
        "On the 16th of last April, Mr. Sarath Vemalasuriya, a retired medical officer, started Matara Gotagogama near the Matara main bus stand and yesterday (24) was supposed to complete 100 days."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Gota Gogama",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "Matara",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Matara Gotagogama",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "last night",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "about six",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "premises",
            "label": "LOC"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "Matara",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Gotagogama",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "yesterday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "24",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the 16th of last April",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sarath Vemalasuriya",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Matara Gotagogama",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Matara",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "yesterday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "24",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "100 days",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "මාතර ගෝඨා ගෝගමට ප්‍රහාරයක්",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "මාතර ගෝඨාගෝගමට ඊයේ රාත්‍රි කාලයේ කිසියම් පිරිසක් ප්‍රහාරයක් එල්ල කර ඇති බව එහි සංවිධායකයෝ පවසති.",
        "සුබෝපභෝගී ජීප් රථයකින් පැමිණි හය දෙනෙකුගෙන් පමණ සමන්විත පිරිසක් පිහි පෙන්වා එහි සිටි තරුණයෙකු බිය ගන්වා පලවා හැර එම පරිශ්‍රයට අලාභ හානි සිදු කර තිබේ.",
        "අරගලයේ නිරත තරුණ තරුණියන් විසින් ඇද තිබු චිත්‍ර හා ප්‍රදර්ශනය කර තිබු බැනර් හා කටවුට් ද කපා දමා හානී සිදු කර තිබුණි.",
        "මෙය කවුරුන් විසින් සිදු කලේද යන්න මේ වන තෙක් අනාවරණය වී නොමැත.",
        "කෙසේ වෙත මාතර ගෝඨාගෝගම පරිශ්‍රය ඊයේ (24) ඉවත් කර ගැනීමට එහි සංවිධායකයින් තීරණය කර තිබු අවස්ථාවක මෙම ප්‍රහාරය එල්ල වී තිබේ.",
        "ඉකුත් අප්‍රේල් මස 16 වැනි දින විශ්‍රාමික වෛද්‍ය නිලධාරී සරත් වීමලසූරිය මහතා මාතර ගෝඨාගෝගම මාතර ප්‍රධාන බස් නැවතුම් පොල අසල ආරම්භ කල අතර ඊට ඊයේ (24) දින 100 ක් සම්පූර්ණ වීමට නියමිතව තිබුණි."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ගෝඨා ගොගම",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "මාතර",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Matara Gotagogama",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "අවසන් රාත්රිය",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "හයක් පමණ",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "පරිශ්රය",
            "label": "LOC"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "මාතර",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගෝඨගෝගම",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඊයේ",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "24",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "පසුගිය අප්‍රේල් 16 වැනිදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "සරත් වේමලසූරිය",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Matara Gotagogama",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "මාතර",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඊයේ",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "24",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "දින 100 යි",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "மாத்தறை கோட்டா கோகம மீது தாக்குதல்",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "மாத்தறை கோட்டகோகம மீது நேற்றிரவு சிலர் தாக்குதல் நடத்தியதாக ஏற்பாட்டாளர்கள் தெரிவித்துள்ளனர்.",
        "சொகுசு ஜீப்பில் வந்த சுமார் 6 பேர் கொண்ட கும்பல் கத்தியைக் காட்டி இளைஞர் ஒருவரை பயமுறுத்தி அந்த வளாகத்தை சேதப்படுத்தியுள்ளது.",
        "போராட்டத்தில் ஈடுபட்ட இளைஞர்கள் வரைந்து காட்சிப்படுத்திய பேனர்கள், கட்அவுட்டுகளும் வெட்டி சேதப்படுத்தப்பட்டன.",
        "இதை செய்தது யார் என்று இதுவரை தெரியவில்லை.",
        "எவ்வாறாயினும், மாத்தறை கோட்டகோகம வளாகத்தை நேற்று (24) காலி செய்ய ஏற்பாட்டாளர்கள் தீர்மானித்திருந்த நிலையிலேயே இந்த தாக்குதல் இடம்பெற்றுள்ளது.",
        "கடந்த ஏப்ரல் மாதம் 16 ஆம் திகதி ஓய்வுபெற்ற வைத்திய அதிகாரி திரு.சரத் வெமலசூரிய மாத்தறை பிரதான பஸ் நிலையத்திற்கு அருகில் மாத்தறை கோட்டகோகமவை ஆரம்பித்து நேற்றுடன் (24) 100 நாட்களை பூர்த்தி செய்யவிருந்தது."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "கோத ோகம",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "மாத்தறை",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Matara Gotagogama",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "நேற்று இரவு",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "சுமார் ஆறு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "வளாகம்",
            "label": "LOC"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "மாத்தறை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "கோடகோகம",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "நேற்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "24",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "கடந்த ஏப்ரல் 16ஆம் தேதி",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சரத் ​​வெமலசூரிய",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Matara Gotagogama",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "மாத்தறை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "நேற்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "24",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "100 நாட்கள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}