{
  "newspaper_id": "news-first-lk",
  "url": "https://www.newsfirst.lk/2022/07/01/no-ntmi-service-on-friday-saturday/",
  "time_ut": 1656665220,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "NO NTMI service on Friday & Saturday",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "NO NTMI service on Friday & Saturday",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); The National Transport Medical Institute says that from today (1) & tomorrow (2) there will be no service every Friday and Saturday.",
        "The NTMI said in a statement that the decision was taken due to the crisis in the country.",
        "The National Transport Medical Institute further informed the public that they can make an appointment for any day except for Friday & Saturday by calling 225 from any mobile number, and 1225 from any fixed land number.",
        "Meanwhile, the issuance of revenue licenses for registered vehicles in the Western Province will be restricted to three days from next Monday until further notice.",
        "Accordingly, the service will only be available on Mondays, Wednesdays, and Thursdays.",
        "The Chief Secretary of the Western Province J.M.C Jayanthi Wijetunga said that these steps were taken due to the current fuel crisis.",
        "It has also been decided not to impose any fine for vehicle revenue licenses in the Western Province which expire from June 29th.",
        "The Chief Secretary of the Western Province further informed that vehicle revenue licenses can be obtained for vehicles registered in the Western Province through the online system."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Friday & Saturday",
          "label": "DATE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "The National Transport Medical Institute",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "tomorrow",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "2",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "every Friday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Saturday",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "NTMI",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "The National Transport Medical Institute",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Friday & Saturday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "225",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "1225",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the Western Province",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "three days",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "next Monday",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Mondays, Wednesdays",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the Western Province",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Jayanthi Wijetunga",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the Western Province",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "June 29th",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Western Province",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "සිකුරාදා සහ සෙනසුරාදා NTMI සේවාවක් නොමැත",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); අද (1) සහ හෙට (2) සිට සෑම සිකුරාදා සහ සෙනසුරාදා දිනකම සේවාවක් නොමැති බව ජාතික ප්‍රවාහන වෛද්‍ය ආයතනය පවසයි.",
        "රට තුළ පවතින අර්බුදකාරී තත්ත්වය හේතුවෙන් මෙම තීරණය ගත් බව නිවේදනයක් නිකුත් කරමින් NTMI පවසයි.",
        "සිකුරාදා සහ සෙනසුරාදා දින හැර ඕනෑම දිනක ඕනෑම ජංගම දුරකථන අංකයකින් 225 ට සහ ඕනෑම ස්ථාවර ඉඩම් අංකයකින් 1225 ට ඇමතීමෙන් වේලාවක් වෙන් කර ගත හැකි බව ජාතික ප්‍රවාහන වෛද්‍ය ආයතනය වැඩිදුරටත් ජනතාවට දන්වා සිටියේය.",
        "මේ අතර බස්නාහිර පළාතේ ලියාපදිංචි වාහන සඳහා ආදායම් බලපත්‍ර නිකුත් කිරීම නැවත දැනුම් දෙන තුරු ලබන සඳුදා සිට දින තුනකට සීමා කෙරේ.",
        "ඒ අනුව සඳුදා, බදාදා සහ බ්‍රහස්පතින්දා දිනවල පමණක් මෙම සේවාව ක්‍රියාත්මක වේ.",
        "පවතින ඉන්ධන අර්බුදය හේතුවෙන් මෙම පියවර ගත් බවයි බස්නාහිර පළාත් ප්‍රධාන ලේකම් ජේ.එම්.සී ජයන්ති විජේතුංග කියා සිටියේ.",
        "ජූනි 29 වැනිදායින් අවසන් වන බස්නාහිර පළාතේ වාහන ආදායම් බලපත්‍ර සඳහා කිසිදු දඩ මුදලක් අය නොකිරීමට ද තීරණය කර ඇත.",
        "බස්නාහිර පළාතේ ලියාපදිංචි වාහන සඳහා ඔන්ලයින් ක්‍රමය හරහා වාහන ආදායම් බලපත්‍ර ලබා ගත හැකි බව බස්නාහිර පළාත් ප්‍රධාන ලේකම්වරයා වැඩිදුරටත් දන්වා සිටියේය."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "සිකුරාදා සෙනසුරාදා",
          "label": "DATE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ජාතික ප්‍රවාහන වෛද්‍ය ආයතනය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "හෙට",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "2",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "සෑම සිකුරාදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "සෙනසුරාදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "NTMI",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ජාතික ප්‍රවාහන වෛද්‍ය ආයතනය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "සිකුරාදා සෙනසුරාදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "225",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "1225",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "බස්නාහිර පළාත",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "දවස් තුනක්",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ලබන සඳුදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "සඳුදා, බදාදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "බස්නාහිර පළාත",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජයන්ති විජේතුංග",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "බස්නාහිර පළාත",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජුනි 29",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "බස්නාහිර පළාත",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "வெள்ளி மற்றும் சனிக்கிழமைகளில் NTMI சேவை இல்லை",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); இன்று (1) மற்றும் நாளை (2) முதல் வெள்ளி மற்றும் சனிக்கிழமைகளில் சேவை இருக்காது என தேசிய போக்குவரத்து மருத்துவ நிறுவனம் தெரிவித்துள்ளது.",
        "நாட்டில் நிலவும் நெருக்கடி காரணமாக இந்த முடிவு எடுக்கப்பட்டுள்ளதாக என்டிஎம்ஐ அறிக்கையில் தெரிவிக்கப்பட்டுள்ளது.",
        "225 என்ற எண்ணில் இருந்தும், 1225 என்ற எண்ணில் இருந்தும் 225 என்ற எண்ணிலும், வெள்ளி மற்றும் சனி தவிர மற்ற எந்த நாளிலும் சந்திப்பை மேற்கொள்ளலாம் என தேசிய போக்குவரத்து மருத்துவ நிறுவனம் பொதுமக்களுக்கு மேலும் தெரிவித்துள்ளது.",
        "இதேவேளை, மேல் மாகாணத்தில் பதிவு செய்யப்பட்ட வாகனங்களுக்கான வருமான அனுமதிப்பத்திரம் வழங்குவது எதிர்வரும் திங்கட்கிழமை முதல் மறு அறிவித்தல் வரை மூன்று நாட்களுக்கு மட்டுப்படுத்தப்படவுள்ளது.",
        "அதன்படி, திங்கள், புதன் மற்றும் வியாழன் ஆகிய கிழமைகளில் மட்டுமே இந்த சேவை கிடைக்கும்.",
        "தற்போது நிலவும் எரிபொருள் நெருக்கடி காரணமாக இந்த நடவடிக்கை எடுக்கப்பட்டுள்ளதாக மேல் மாகாண பிரதம செயலாளர் ஜே.எம்.சி ஜயந்தி விஜேதுங்க தெரிவித்துள்ளார்.",
        "மேல் மாகாணத்தில் ஜூன் 29ஆம் திகதியுடன் காலாவதியாகும் வாகன வருமான அனுமதிப்பத்திரங்களுக்கு அபராதம் விதிக்கப்படுவதில்லை எனவும் தீர்மானிக்கப்பட்டுள்ளது.",
        "மேல்மாகாணத்தில் பதிவு செய்யப்பட்ட வாகனங்களுக்கான வாகன வருமான அனுமதிப்பத்திரத்தை இணையத்தளத்தின் ஊடாக பெற்றுக்கொள்ள முடியும் என மேல்மாகாண பிரதம செயலாளர் மேலும் தெரிவித்தார்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "வெள்ளிக்கிழமை சனிக்கிழமை",
          "label": "DATE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "தேசிய போக்குவரத்து மருத்துவ நிறுவனம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "நாளை",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "2",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஒவ்வொரு வெள்ளிக்கிழமை",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சனிக்கிழமை",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "என்.டி.எம்.ஐ",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "தேசிய போக்குவரத்து மருத்துவ நிறுவனம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "வெள்ளிக்கிழமை சனிக்கிழமை",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "225",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "1225",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "மேல் மாகாணம்",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "மூன்று நாட்கள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "அடுத்த திங்கள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "திங்கள், புதன்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "மேல் மாகாணம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜெயந்தி விஜேதுங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "மேல் மாகாணம்",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜூன் 29",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "மேல் மாகாணம்",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}