{
  "newspaper_id": "news-first-lk",
  "url": "https://www.newsfirst.lk/2022/09/02/dr-gayashan-nawananda-petitions-against-decision-to-oust-him/",
  "time_ut": 1662123720,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Dr. Gayashan Nawananda petitions against decision to oust him",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Dr. Gayashan Nawananda petitions against decision to oust him",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st);  Moneragala District Parliamentarian Dr. Gayashan Nawananda filed a petition with the Supreme Court of Sri Lanka seeking an order to invalidate the decision taken by the Sri Lanka Podujana Peramuna to expel him from his Parliamentary Seat on the instructions of the General Secretary of the Democratic Left Front, Vasudeva Nanayakkara.",
        "The Secretary of the Democratic Left Front Vasudeva Nanayakkara, General Secretary of the Sri Lanka Podujana Peramuna Attorney-at-Law Sagara Kariyawasam, among others were named as respondents in the case.",
        "The petitioner states that he decided to support the Government, and thereafter the Secretary of the Democratic Left Front, Vasudeva Nanayakkara alleging that he breached party discipline, had requested the General Secretary of the SLPP to take action to invalidate his seat in Parliament.",
        "The petition states that the Sri Lanka Podujana Peramuna has taken measures to expel the MP from his parliamentary seat.",
        "Dr. Gayashan Nawananda states the respondents did not actively conduct a just and fair investigation before reaching such a decision, and therefore it is a violation of natural justice.",
        "Chinese Fertilizer: Auditor General recommends to recover losses; prosecute those responsible",
        "Money printing fueling inflation; CBSL autonomy paramount – IMF Mission Chief"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Gayashan Nawananda",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "News 1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Gayashan Nawananda",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Supreme Court of Sri Lanka",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "Podujana Peramuna",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliamentary Seat",
            "label": "WORK_OF_ART"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Democratic Left Front",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Vasudeva Nanayakkara",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the Democratic Left Front Vasudeva Nanayakkara",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "Podujana Peramuna",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sagara Kariyawasam",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the Democratic Left Front",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Vasudeva Nanayakkara",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "Podujana Peramuna",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Gayashan Nawananda",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Chinese",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        []
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "තමන් නෙරපා හැරීමට ගත් තීරණයට එරෙහිව වෛද්‍ය ගයාෂාන් නවානන්ද පෙත්සමක්",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); ප්‍රජාතන්ත්‍රවාදී වාමාංශික පෙරමුණේ ප්‍රධාන ලේකම්වරයාගේ උපදෙස් පරිදි තමන්ව පාර්ලිමේන්තු මන්ත්‍රී ධුරයෙන් නෙරපීමට ශ්‍රී ලංකා පොදුජන පෙරමුණ ගත් තීරණය බලරහිත කරන ලෙස ඉල්ලා මොණරාගල දිස්ත්‍රික් පාර්ලිමේන්තු මන්ත්‍රී ආචාර්ය ගයාෂාන් නවානන්ද ශ්‍රේෂ්ඨාධිකරණයට පෙත්සමක් ගොනු කළා. , වාසුදේව නානායක්කාර.",
        "මෙම නඩුවේ වගඋත්තරකරුවන් ලෙස ප්‍රජාතන්ත්‍රවාදී වාමාංශික පෙරමුණේ ලේකම් වාසුදේව නානායක්කාර, ශ්‍රී ලංකා පොදුජන පෙරමුණේ ප්‍රධාන ලේකම් නීතීඥ සාගර කාරියවසම් ඇතුළු පිරිසක් නම් කර තිබේ.",
        "තමන් රජයට සහය දැක්වීමට තීරණය කළ බවත්, ඉන් අනතුරුව තමන් පක්ෂ විනය කඩ කළ බවට චෝදනා කරමින් ප්‍රජාතන්ත්‍රවාදී වාමාංශික පෙරමුණේ ලේකම් වාසුදේව නානායක්කාර ශ්‍රී ලංකා පොදුජන පෙරමුණේ මහලේකම්වරයාගෙන් ඉල්ලා සිටියේ තමාගේ පාර්ලිමේන්තු මන්ත්‍රී ධුරය අවලංගු කිරීමට කටයුතු කරන ලෙසයි.",
        "මන්ත්‍රීවරයා පාර්ලිමේන්තු මන්ත්‍රී ධුරයෙන් නෙරපීමට ශ්‍රී ලංකා පොදුජන පෙරමුණ කටයුතු කර ඇති බව පෙත්සමේ සඳහන් වේ.",
        "වෛද්‍ය ගයාෂාන් නවානන්ද පවසන්නේ වගඋත්තරකරුවන් එවැනි තීරණයකට පැමිණීමට පෙර සාධාරණ හා සාධාරණ පරීක්ෂණයක් සක්‍රීයව සිදු නොකළ බවත් එබැවින් එය ස්වභාවික යුක්තිය උල්ලංඝනය කිරීමක් බවත්ය.",
        "චීන පොහොර: පාඩු අයකර ගැනීමට විගණකාධිපති නිර්දේශ කරයි; වගකිව යුත්තන්ට නඩු පවරන්න",
        "මුදල් මුද්‍රණය උද්ධමනය වැඩි කරයි; CBSL ස්වයං පාලනය අතිමහත් - IMF දූත මණ්ඩල ප්‍රධානියා"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ගයාෂාන් නවානන්ද",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "News 1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගයාෂාන් නවානන්ද",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ ශ්‍රේෂ්ඨාධිකරණය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "පොදුජන පෙරමුණ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තු ආසනය",
            "label": "WORK_OF_ART"
          },
          {
            "text": "ප්‍රජාතන්ත්‍රවාදී වාම පෙරමුණ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "වාසුදේව නානායක්කාර",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ප්‍රජාතන්ත්‍රවාදී වාමාංශික පෙරමුණ වාසුදේව නානායක්කාර",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "පොදුජන පෙරමුණ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "සාගර කාරියවසම්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ප්‍රජාතන්ත්‍රවාදී වාම පෙරමුණ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "වාසුදේව නානායක්කාර",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "පොදුජන පෙරමුණ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ගයාෂාන් නවානන්ද",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "චීන",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        []
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "டொக்டர் கயாஷான் நாவானந்தா தம்மை பதவி நீக்கம் செய்வதற்கான தீர்மானத்திற்கு எதிராக மனுத்தாக்கல் செய்தார்",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); ஜனநாயக இடதுசாரி முன்னணியின் பொதுச் செயலாளரின் பணிப்புரையின் பேரில் தம்மை நாடாளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர் பதவியிலிருந்து நீக்குவதற்கு ஸ்ரீலங்கா பொதுஜன பெரமுன எடுத்த தீர்மானத்தை செல்லுபடியற்றதாக்குமாறு கோரி மொனராகலை மாவட்ட நாடாளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர் கலாநிதி கயாஷான் நாவானந்தா உச்ச நீதிமன்றத்தில் மனு தாக்கல் செய்துள்ளார். , வாசுதேவ நாணயக்கார.",
        "இந்த வழக்கில் ஜனநாயக இடதுசாரி முன்னணியின் செயலாளர் வாசுதேவ நாணயக்கார, ஸ்ரீலங்கா பொதுஜன பெரமுனவின் பொதுச் செயலாளர் சட்டத்தரணி சாகர காரியவசம் உள்ளிட்டோர் பிரதிவாதிகளாக குறிப்பிடப்பட்டுள்ளனர்.",
        "அரசாங்கத்திற்கு ஆதரவளிக்க தாம் தீர்மானித்ததாகவும், அதன் பின்னர் ஜனநாயக இடதுசாரி முன்னணியின் செயலாளர் வாசுதேவ நாணயக்கார, கட்சியின் ஒழுக்கத்தை மீறியதாக குற்றம் சுமத்தியுள்ள மனுதாரர், தனது நாடாளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர் பதவியை செல்லாததாக்க நடவடிக்கை எடுக்குமாறு ஸ்ரீலங்கா பொதுஜன பெரமுனவின் பொதுச் செயலாளரிடம் கோரிக்கை விடுத்துள்ளார்.",
        "ஸ்ரீலங்கா பொதுஜன பெரமுன பாராளுமன்ற உறுப்பினரை அவரது பாராளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர் பதவியில் இருந்து வெளியேற்ற நடவடிக்கை எடுத்துள்ளதாக மனுவில் குறிப்பிடப்பட்டுள்ளது.",
        "கலாநிதி கயாஷான் நவானந்தா, அத்தகைய முடிவை எடுப்பதற்கு முன், பதிலளித்தவர்கள் ஒரு நியாயமான மற்றும் நியாயமான விசாரணையை தீவிரமாக நடத்தவில்லை, எனவே இது இயற்கை நீதியை மீறுவதாகும்.",
        "சீன உரம்: ஆடிட்டர் ஜெனரல் இழப்புகளை மீட்டெடுக்க பரிந்துரைக்கிறார்; பொறுப்பானவர்கள் மீது வழக்குத் தொடரவும்",
        "பணம் அச்சிடுதல் பணவீக்கத்தைத் தூண்டுகிறது; CBSL தன்னாட்சி மிக முக்கியமானது - IMF மிஷன் தலைவர்"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "கயாஷான் நவானந்தா",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "News 1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "கயாஷான் நவானந்தா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கையின் உச்ச நீதிமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "பொதுஜன பெரமுன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்ற இருக்கை",
            "label": "WORK_OF_ART"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜனநாயக இடது முன்னணி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "வாசுதேவ நாணயக்கார",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஜனநாயக இடதுசாரி முன்னணி வாசுதேவ நாணயக்கார",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "பொதுஜன பெரமுன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "சாகர காரியவசம்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஜனநாயக இடது முன்னணி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "வாசுதேவ நாணயக்கார",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "பொதுஜன பெரமுன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "கயாஷான் நவானந்தா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "சீன",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        []
      ]
    }
  }
}