{
  "newspaper_id": "virakesari-lk",
  "url": "http://www.virakesari.lk/article/131746",
  "time_ut": 1658199456,
  "original_lang": "ta",
  "original_title": "பாராளுமன்றம் கூடுகிறது ! இடைக்கால ஜனாதிபதி தெரிவிற்கான வேட்புமனு தாக்கல் இன்று : நாளை இரகசிய வாக்கெடுப்பு",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Parliament meets! Filing of nominations for Interim Presidential election today: Secret ballot tomorrow",
      "author": "",
      "body_lines": [
        "The parliamentary session will be held on Tuesday amid the turmoil in Sri Lankan politics following the resignation of former President Gotabaya Rajapaksa.",
        "Also, the secret ballot to elect the President tomorrow, Wednesday, will be held under the leadership of Parliamentary Secretary General Dammika Dasanayake.",
        "It is a special feature in Sri Lanka's political history that tomorrow will be the day when a President will be elected for the second time through the Parliament.",
        "The parliamentary session will begin today at 10 am under the chairmanship of Speaker Mahinda Yappa Abeywardhana.",
        "In contrast to the usual situation, security has been strengthened in the parliamentary circuit today.",
        "As per article 40 of the constitution following the vacancy of the presidency, the nomination petition will be held today to elect a new president through the parliament.",
        "While the member contesting for the presidential election will officially announce his decision to the Parliamentary Secretary General today, the other person will have to confirm it.",
        "It is mandatory for the candidates who are ready to contest for the presidential election to socialize the assembly today.",
        "Opposition Leader Sajith Premadasa, Acting President Ranil Wickramasinghe, former Minister Dalus Alagaperuma and People's Liberation Front President Anurakumara Dissanayake will contest for the vacant presidency.",
        "Former President Maithripala Sirisena has mentioned that the running of more than one candidate during the interim presidential election will pollute the Parliament among the people, and therefore the Freedom Party will not support anyone during this time.",
        "After the assassination of the then President Ranasinghe Premadasa on May 1993, the acting President T. P. Wijatunga was elected as the interim President without a vote in the Parliament.",
        "But as more than one candidate has entered the field, it is noteworthy that according to the constitution, the new president will be chosen tomorrow through a secret ballot in the parliament."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Parliament",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "today",
          "label": "DATE"
        },
        {
          "text": "tomorrow",
          "label": "DATE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Tuesday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lankan",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "Gotabaya Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "tomorrow, Wednesday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Dammika Dasanayake",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka's",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the day",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "second",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "10 am",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "Mahinda Yappa Abeywardhana",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "article 40",
            "label": "LAW"
          },
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sajith Premadasa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickramasinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Dalus Alagaperuma",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "People's Liberation Front",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Anurakumara Dissanayake",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Maithripala Sirisena",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "more than one",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Freedom Party",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Ranasinghe Premadasa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "May 1993",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "T. P. Wijatunga",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "more than one",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "tomorrow",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව රැස්වෙයි! අන්තර්වාර ජනපතිවරණය සඳහා නාමයෝජනා භාරදීම අද: රහස් ඡන්දය හෙට",
      "author": "",
      "body_lines": [
        "හිටපු ජනාධිපති ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ මහතා ඉල්ලා අස්වීමත් සමඟ ශ්‍රී ලංකා දේශපාලනයේ ඇති වූ කැළඹිලි මධ්‍යයේ පාර්ලිමේන්තු සැසිවාරය ලබන අඟහරුවාදා පැවැත්වේ.",
        "එමෙන්ම හෙට බදාදා ජනාධිපතිවරයා තෝරා ගැනීමේ රහස් ඡන්දය පාර්ලිමේන්තු මහලේකම් දම්මික දසනායක මහතාගේ ප්‍රධානත්වයෙන් පැවැත්වෙයි.",
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකා දේශපාලන ඉතිහාසයේ පාර්ලිමේන්තුව හරහා දෙවැනි වරටත් ජනාධිපතිවරයකු පත්වන දිනය හෙට වීම විශේෂත්වයකි.",
        "කථානායක මහින්ද යාප්පා අබේවර්ධන මහතාගේ ප්‍රධානත්වයෙන් පාර්ලිමේන්තු සැසිවාරය අද පෙරවරු 10.00ට ආරම්භ වීමට නියමිතයි.",
        "සාමාන්‍ය තත්ත්වයට වඩා වෙනස්ව අද පාර්ලිමේන්තු පරිශ‍්‍රයේ ආරක්ෂාව තර කර තිබෙනවා.",
        "ආණ්ඩුක්‍රම ව්‍යවස්ථාවේ 40 වැනි වගන්තියට අනුව ජනාධිපති ධුරය පුරප්පාඩු වීමත් සමඟ පාර්ලිමේන්තුව හරහා නව ජනාධිපතිවරයකු තෝරා පත් කර ගැනීම සඳහා නාමයෝජනා පෙත්සම අද පැවැත්වේ.",
        "ජනාධිපතිවරණයට තරග කරන මන්ත්‍රීවරයා සිය තීරණය අද පාර්ලිමේන්තු මහලේකම්වරයාට නිල වශයෙන් ප්‍රකාශ කරන අතර අනෙක් පුද්ගලයාට එය තහවුරු කිරීමට සිදුවේ.",
        "ජනාධිපතිවරණයට ඉදිරිපත්වීමට සූදානම් අපේක්ෂකයින් අද සභාව සමාජගත කිරීම අනිවාර්යයි.",
        "පුරප්පාඩු වූ ජනාධිපති ධූරය සඳහා විපක්ෂ නායක සජිත් ප්‍රේමදාස, වැඩබලන ජනාධිපති රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ, හිටපු අමාත්‍ය ඩලස් අලගපෙරුම සහ මහජන විමුක්ති පෙරමුණේ සභාපති අනුරකුමාර දිසානායක යන මහත්වරුන් තරඟ වදිනු ඇති.",
        "අන්තර්වාර ජනාධිපතිවරණයේදී එක් අපේක්ෂකයෙකුට වඩා ඉදිරිපත් වීම ජනතාව අතර පාර්ලිමේන්තුව අපිරිසිදු කරන බවත්, එබැවින් නිදහස් පක්ෂය මේ කාලය තුළ කිසිවකුට සහය නොදෙන බවත් හිටපු ජනාධිපති මෛත්‍රීපාල සිරිසේන මහතා පවසයි.",
        "1993 මැයි මාසයේදී එවකට ජනාධිපති රණසිංහ ප්‍රේමදාස මහතා ඝාතනය කිරීමෙන් පසු වැඩබලන ජනාධිපති ටී.පී.විජතුංග මහතා පාර්ලිමේන්තුවේ ඡන්දයකින් තොරව අන්තර්වාර ජනාධිපතිවරයා ලෙස තේරී පත් විය.",
        "එහෙත් එක් අපේක්ෂකයෙකුට වඩා තරග බිමට පැමිණ ඇති බැවින් ආණ්ඩුක්‍රම ව්‍යවස්ථාව අනුව හෙට දිනයේ පාර්ලිමේන්තුවේ රහස් ඡන්දයකින් නව ජනාධිපතිවරයා තෝරා ගැනීම විශේෂත්වයකි."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "අද",
          "label": "DATE"
        },
        {
          "text": "හෙට",
          "label": "DATE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "අඟහරුවාදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලාංකික",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "හෙට, බදාදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "දම්මික දසනායක",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "දවස",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "දෙවැනි",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "පෙරවරු 10",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "මහින්ද යාප්පා අබේවර්ධන",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "40 වැනි වගන්තිය",
            "label": "LAW"
          },
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "සජිත් ප්‍රේමදාස",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "දලස් අලගපෙරුම",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "මහජන විමුක්ති පෙරමුණ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "අනුරකුමාර දිසානායක",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "මෛත්‍රීපාල සිරිසේන",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "එකකට වඩා",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "නිදහස් පක්ෂය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "රණසිංහ ප්‍රේමදාස",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "1993 මැයි",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ටී.පී.විජතුංග",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "එකකට වඩා",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "හෙට",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "பாராளுமன்றம் கூடுகிறது ! இடைக்கால ஜனாதிபதி தெரிவிற்கான வேட்புமனு தாக்கல் இன்று : நாளை இரகசிய வாக்கெடுப்பு",
      "author": "",
      "body_lines": [
        "முன்னாள் ஜனாதிபதி கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ஷவின் பதவி விலகலையடுத்து இலங்கை அரசியலில் ஏற்பட்டுள்ள பரபரப்புக்களுக்கு மத்தியில் இன்று செவ்வாய்கிழமை பாராளுமன்ற அமர்வு இடம்பெறவுள்ளது.",
        "அத்தோடு நாளை புதன்கிழமை ஜனாதிபதியை தெரிவு செய்வதற்கான இரகசிய வாக்கெடுப்பு  பாராளுமன்ற செயலாளர் நாயகம் தம்மிக தசநாயக்கவின் தலைமையில் இடம்பெறவுள்ளது.",
        "இலங்கை அரசியல் வரலாற்றில் பாராளுமன்றத்தின் ஊடாக இரண்டாவது முறையாக ஜனாதிபதியொருவரை தெரிவு செய்யும் நாளாக நாளைய நாள் பதிவாகவுள்ளமை விசேட அம்சமாகும்.",
        "சபாநாயகர் மஹிந்த யாப்பா அபேவர்தன தலைமையில் இன்று காலை 10 மணிக்கு பாராளுமன்ற அமர்வு ஆரம்பமாகும்.",
        "இந்நிலையில் வழமைக்கு மாறாக இன்றை தினம் பாராளுமன்ற சுற்று வட்டாரத்தில் பாதுகாப்பு பலப்படுத்தப்பட்டுள்ளது.",
        "ஜனாதிபதி பதவி வெற்றிடமாகியதை தொடர்ந்து அரசியலமைப்பின் 40 ஆவது உறுப்புரையின் பிரகாரம் பாராளுமன்றத்தின் ஊடாக புதிய ஜனாதிபதியை தெரிவு செய்யும் வகையில் வேட்பு மனுத்தாக்கல் இன்று இடம்பெறவுள்ளது.",
        "ஜனாதிபதி தெரிவிற்காக போட்டியிடும் உறுப்பினர் தனது தீர்மானத்தை பாராளுமன்ற செயலாளர் நாயகத்திற்கு இன்றைய தினம் உத்தியோகப்பூர்வமாக அறிவிக்கும் அதே வேளை , பிறிதொருவர் அதனை உறுதிப்படுத்த வேண்டும்.",
        "ஜனாதிபதி தெரிவிற்காக போட்டியிட தயாராகவுள்ள வேட்பாளர்கள் இன்றைய தினம் சபைக்கு சமூகமளிக்க வேண்டியது கட்டாயமாகும்.",
        "எதிர்க்கட்சி தலைவர் சஜித் பிரேமதாஸ, பதில் ஜனாதிபதி ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க, முன்னாள் அமைச்சர் டலஸ் அழகபெரும மற்றும் மக்கள் விடுதலை முன்னணியின் தலைவர் அனுரகுமார திஸாநாயக்க ஆகியோர் வெற்றிடமாகியுள்ள ஜனாதிபதிக்கு போட்டியிடவுள்ளனர்.",
        "இடைக்கால ஜனாதிபதி தெரிவின் போது ஒன்றுக்கு மேற்பட்ட வேட்பாளர்கள் போட்டியிடுவதானது , மக்கள் மத்தியில் பாராளுமன்றத்தை மலினப்படுத்தும் என்றும் , எனவே இதன் போது சுதந்திர கட்சி எவருக்கும் ஆதரவு வழங்காது என்றும் முன்னாள் ஜனாதிபதி மைத்திரிபால சிறிசேன குறிப்பிட்டுள்ளார்.",
        "1993 மே தினத்தன்று அப்போதைய ஜனாதிபதி ரணசிங்க பிரேமதாச கொல்லப்பட்டதையடுத்து , பதில் ஜனாதிபதியான டி.பி.விஜதுங்க , பாராளுமன்றத்தில் வாக்கெடுப்பில்லாமல் இடைக்கால ஜனாதிபதியாகவும் தெரிவு செய்யப்பட்டார்.",
        "ஆனால் தற்போது ஒன்றுக்கும் மேற்பட்ட வேட்பாளர்கள் களமிறங்கியுள்ளமையால் அரசியலமைப்பின் படி நாளை பாராளுமன்றில் இரகசிய வாக்கெடுப்பின் ஊடாக புதிய ஜனாதிபதி தெரிவு செய்யப்படவுள்ளமை குறிப்பிடத்தக்கது."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "இன்று",
          "label": "DATE"
        },
        {
          "text": "நாளை",
          "label": "DATE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "செவ்வாய்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "நாளை, புதன்கிழமை",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "தம்மிக்க தசநாயக்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கையின்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "தினம்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இரண்டாவது",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "காலை 10 மணி",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "மஹிந்த யாப்பா அபேவர்தன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "கட்டுரை 40",
            "label": "LAW"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "சஜித் பிரேமதாச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "டலஸ் அழகப்பெரும",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "மக்கள் விடுதலை முன்னணி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "அனுரகுமார திஸாநாயக்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "மைத்திரிபால சிறிசேன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஒன்றுக்கு மேற்பட்ட",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "சுதந்திரக் கட்சி",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ரணசிங்க பிரேமதாச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "மே 1993",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "டி.பி.விஜதுங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஒன்றுக்கு மேற்பட்ட",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "நாளை",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}