{
  "newspaper_id": "ada-derana-lk",
  "url": "http://www.adaderana.lk/news/83446/senior-army-officer-involved-in-yakgahapitiya-incident-relieved-of-duties",
  "time_ut": 1657022100,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Senior army officer involved in Yakgahapitiya incident relieved of duties",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Senior army officer involved in Yakgahapitiya incident relieved of duties",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "Commander of the Army, Lieutenant General Vikum Liyanage has relieved the officer involved in the incident at Yakgahapitiya Petrol Station of all his duties with immediate effect until the 5-member Court of Inquiry’s recommendations are received.",
        "A parallel military investigation of the Sri Lanka Army Corps of Military Police (SLACMP) with regard to the incident is also underway recording statements, the Sri Lanka Army said today.",
        "The Security Force Headquarters - West on Monday (4) appointed a five-member Court of Inquiry, headed by a Brigade Commander to investigate into the issue, related to the Senior Officer’s conduct and to make its recommendations.",
        "A video recorded using a mobile phone, showing an army officer kicking a person on the chest at a fuel station, had been widely circulated on social media recently prompting the internal investigation."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Yakgahapitiya",
          "label": "NORP"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Army",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Vikum Liyanage",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Yakgahapitiya Petrol Station",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "5",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Court of Inquiry’s",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the Sri Lanka Army Corps of Military Police",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Sri Lanka Army",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Monday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "4",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "five",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Court of Inquiry",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        []
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "යක්ගහපිටිය සිද්ධියට සම්බන්ධ ජ්‍යෙෂ්ඨ හමුදා නිලධාරියා රාජකාරියෙන් නිදහස්",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "යක්ගහපිටිය ඉන්ධන පිරවුම්හලේ සිද්ධියට සම්බන්ධ නිලධාරියා පංච පුද්ගල විමර්ශන අධිකරණයේ නිර්දේශ ලැබෙන තුරු වහාම ක්‍රියාත්මක වන පරිදි යුද හමුදාපති ලුතිනන් ජෙනරාල් විකුම් ලියනගේ ඔහුගේ සියලු රාජකාරිවලින් නිදහස් කර තිබේ.",
        "සිද්ධිය සම්බන්ධයෙන් ශ්‍රී ලංකා යුධ හමුදා පොලිස් බලකායේ (SLACMP) සමාන්තර හමුදා පරීක්ෂණයක් ද ප්‍රකාශ සටහන් කර ගනිමින් පවතින බව ශ්‍රී ලංකා යුධ හමුදාව අද ප්‍රකාශ කළේය.",
        "ජ්‍යෙෂ්ඨ නිලධාරියාගේ ක්‍රියාකලාපය සම්බන්ධයෙන් විමර්ශනය කර එහි නිර්දේශ ඉදිරිපත් කිරීම සඳහා බලසේනාධිපතිවරයෙකුගේ ප්‍රධානත්වයෙන් යුත් පංච පුද්ගල විමර්ශන අධිකරණයක් බටහිර ආරක්ෂක සේනා මූලස්ථානය විසින් සඳුදා (4) පත් කරන ලදී.",
        "ඉන්ධන පිරවුම්හලකදී හමුදා නිළධාරියෙකු පුද්ගලයෙකුගේ පපුවට පයින් පහර දෙන අයුරු දැක්වෙන වීඩියෝවක් ජංගම දුරකථනයකින් පටිගත කෙරුණු වීඩියෝවක් පසුගියදා සමාජ මාධ්‍ය ඔස්සේ පුළුල් ලෙස ප්‍රචාරය වී තිබුණේ අභ්‍යන්තර පරීක්ෂණයක් ආරම්භ කරමිනි."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "යක්ගහපිටිය",
          "label": "NORP"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "හමුදා",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "විකුම් ලියනගේ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "යක්ගහපිටිය ඉන්ධන පිරවුම්හල",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "5",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "විමර්ශන අධිකරණයේ",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "හමුදා පොලිසියේ ශ්‍රී ලංකා යුද හමුදා බලකාය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකා යුද හමුදාව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "සඳුදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "4",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "පහ",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "විමර්ශන අධිකරණය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        []
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "யக்கஹாபிட்டிய சம்பவத்துடன் தொடர்புடைய சிரேஷ்ட இராணுவ அதிகாரி பணியிலிருந்து விடுவிக்கப்பட்டுள்ளார்",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "யக்கஹாபிட்டிய பெற்றோல் நிலையத்தில் இடம்பெற்ற சம்பவத்துடன் தொடர்புடைய அதிகாரியை உடனடியாக அமுலுக்கு வரும் வகையில் 5 பேர் கொண்ட விசாரணை நீதிமன்றத்தின் பரிந்துரைகள் பெற்றுக்கொள்ளப்படும் வரை இராணுவத் தளபதி லெப்டினன்ட் ஜெனரல் விகும் லியனகே அனைத்து கடமைகளிலிருந்தும் விடுவித்துள்ளார்.",
        "இச்சம்பவம் தொடர்பாக சிறிலங்கா இராணுவப் படைப் பிரிவு இராணுவப் பொலிஸாரின் (SLACMP) சமாந்தரமான இராணுவ விசாரணையும் வாக்குமூலங்களைப் பதிவுசெய்து வருவதாக இலங்கை இராணுவம் இன்று தெரிவித்துள்ளது.",
        "பாதுகாப்புப் படைத் தலைமையகம் - மேற்கு திங்கட்கிழமை (4) மூத்த அதிகாரியின் நடத்தை தொடர்பான பிரச்சினையை ஆராய்வதற்கும் அதன் பரிந்துரைகளை வழங்குவதற்கும் பிரிகேட் கமாண்டர் தலைமையில் ஐந்து பேர் கொண்ட விசாரணை நீதிமன்றத்தை நியமித்தது.",
        "கையடக்கத் தொலைபேசி மூலம் பதிவுசெய்யப்பட்ட காணொளி, எரிபொருள் நிரப்பு நிலையத்தில் இராணுவ அதிகாரி ஒருவர் ஒருவரை மார்பில் உதைப்பதைக் காட்டும் காணொளி ஒன்று சமூக ஊடகங்களில் அண்மையில் பரவலாகப் பரப்பப்பட்டு உள்ளக விசாரணையைத் தூண்டியது."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "யக்கஹாபிட்டிய",
          "label": "NORP"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "இராணுவம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "விக்கும் லியனகே",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "யக்கஹாபிட்டிய பெற்றோல் நிலையம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "5",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "விசாரணை நீதிமன்றத்தின்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இராணுவ காவல்துறையின் இலங்கை இராணுவப் படை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை இராணுவம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "திங்கட்கிழமை",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "4",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஐந்து",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "விசாரணை நீதிமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        []
      ]
    }
  }
}