{
  "newspaper_id": "economy-next-com",
  "url": "https://economynext.com/top-un-officials-asks-sri-lanka-president-to-not-to-sign-detention-orders-on-iusf-convenor-98844/",
  "time_ut": 1661094480,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Top UN officials asks Sri Lanka president to not to sign detention orders on IUSF convenor",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Top UN officials asks Sri Lanka president to not to sign detention orders on IUSF convenor",
      "author": "",
      "body_lines": [
        "ECONOMYNEXT – UN Special Rapporteur on Human Rights Defenders Mary Lawlorbhas requested Sri Lanka President Ranil Wickremesinghe to not to sign the detention orders of Inter University Students Federation convener Wasnatha Mudalige and two others protestors.",
        "“I’m deeply concerned that Human Rights Defenders Wasantha Mudalige, Hashan Jeevantha & Galwewa Siridamma Himi have been arrested under the #SriLanka’s Prevention of Terrorism Act. I call on President Ranil not to sign their detention order, doing so would be a dark day for 🇱🇰,”Lawlor tweeted on Sunday August 21.",
        "Mudalige and the others were arrested on Thursday August 18 after a protest in Colombo and were subsequently detained for 72 hours for police questioning.",
        "Police said in a statement on Sunday that investigations were under way to see whether the suspects were involved in anti-state activity.",
        "Opposition lawnkers, civil society groups and activists have condemned the arrests. (Colombo/Aug21/2022)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "UN",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "Sri Lanka",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "IUSF",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Mary Lawlorbhas",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Inter University Students Federation",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Wasnatha Mudalige",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "two",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Wasantha Mudalige",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Hashan Jeevantha &",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Siridamma Himi",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "SriLanka",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ranil",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Lawlor",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sunday August 21",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Mudalige",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Thursday August 18",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Colombo",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "72 hours",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sunday",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Colombo/Aug21/2022",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "අන්තර් විශ්වවිද්‍යාල ශිෂ්‍ය බල මණ්ඩලයේ කැඳවුම්කරු රඳවා තබා ගැනීමේ නියෝගවලට අත්සන් නොකරන ලෙස එක්සත් ජාතීන්ගේ ඉහළ පෙළේ නිලධාරීන් ශ්‍රී ලංකා ජනාධිපතිවරයාගෙන් ඉල්ලා සිටියි",
      "author": "",
      "body_lines": [
        "ECONOMYNEXT – අන්තර් විශ්වවිද්‍යාල ශිෂ්‍ය බලමණ්ඩලයේ කැඳවුම්කරු වාසනාත මුදලිගේ සහ තවත් විරෝධතාකරුවන් දෙදෙනෙකුගේ රැඳවුම් නියෝගවලට අත්සන් නොකරන ලෙස මානව හිමිකම් ආරක්ෂකයින් පිළිබඳ එක්සත් ජාතීන්ගේ විශේෂ වාර්තාකරු මේරි ලෝලෝර්බාස් ශ්‍රී ලංකා ජනාධිපති රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහගෙන් ඉල්ලා සිටියාය.",
        "“ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ ත්‍රස්තවාදය වැලැක්වීමේ පනත යටතේ මානව හිමිකම් ආරක්ෂකයින් වන වසන්ත මුදලිගේ, හෂාන් ජීවන්ත සහ ගල්වැව සිරිදම්ම හිමි අත්අඩංගුවට ගැනීම ගැන මම දැඩි කනස්සල්ලට පත්ව සිටිමි. ඔවුන්ගේ රැඳවුම් නියෝගයට අත්සන් නොකරන ලෙස මම ජනාධිපති රනිල්ගෙන් ඉල්ලා සිටිමි, එසේ කිරීම 🇱🇰 සඳහා අඳුරු දිනයක් වනු ඇත, ”ලෝලර් අගෝස්තු 21 ඉරිදා ට්වීට් කළේය.",
        "මුදලිගේ ඇතුළු පිරිස අගෝස්තු 18 බ්‍රහස්පතින්දා කොළඹ පැවති විරෝධතාවයකින් පසු අත්අඩංගුවට ගත් අතර පසුව පොලිස් ප්‍රශ්න කිරීම් සඳහා පැය 72 ක් රඳවාගෙන සිටියහ.",
        "පොලිසිය ඉරිදා නිවේදනයක් නිකුත් කරමින් කියා සිටියේ සැකකරුවන් රාජ්‍ය විරෝධී ක්‍රියාවලට සම්බන්ධ දැයි සොයා බැලීම සඳහා පරීක්ෂණ පවත්වන බවයි.",
        "විපක්‍ෂයේ නීතිඥයින්, සිවිල් සමාජ කණ්ඩායම් සහ ක්‍රියාකාරීන් මෙම අත්අඩංගුවට ගැනීම හෙළා දැක ඇත. (කොළඹ/අගෝස්තු 21/2022)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "එ.ජා",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "අවිශිබම",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "මේරි ලෝලෝර්බාස්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "අන්තර් විශ්වවිද්‍යාල ශිෂ්‍ය බල මණ්ඩලය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "වස්නාථ මුදලිගේ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "දෙක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "වසන්ත මුදලිගේ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "හෂාන් ජීවන්ත සහ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "සිරිදම්ම හිමි",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "රනිල්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ලෝලර්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "අගෝස්තු 21 ඉරිදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "මුදලිගේ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "අගෝස්තු 18 බ්‍රහස්පතින්දා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "කොළඹ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "පැය 72 යි",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ඉරිදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "කොළඹ/අගෝස්තු 21/2022",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "IUSF அழைப்பாளர் மீதான தடுப்புக்காவல் உத்தரவில் கையெழுத்திட வேண்டாம் என ஐ.நாவின் உயர்மட்ட அதிகாரிகள் இலங்கை ஜனாதிபதியிடம் கோரிக்கை விடுத்துள்ளனர்",
      "author": "",
      "body_lines": [
        "ECONOMYNEXT – பல்கலைக்கழகங்களுக்கு இடையிலான மாணவர் சம்மேளனத்தின் அழைப்பாளர் வஸ்நாத முதலிகே மற்றும் இரண்டு ஆர்ப்பாட்டக்காரர்களின் தடுப்புக் காவலில் கையொப்பமிட வேண்டாம் என இலங்கை ஜனாதிபதி ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்கவிடம் மனித உரிமைகள் பாதுகாப்பாளர்களுக்கான ஐ.நாவின் விசேட அறிக்கையாளர் மேரி லோலோர்பாஸ் கோரிக்கை விடுத்துள்ளார்.",
        "“மனித உரிமைப் பாதுகாவலர்களான வசந்த முதலிகே, ஹஷன் ஜீவந்த மற்றும் கல்வெவ சிறிதம்மா ஹிமி ஆகியோர் #இலங்கையின் பயங்கரவாதத் தடைச் சட்டத்தின் கீழ் கைது செய்யப்பட்டுள்ளதையிட்டு நான் ஆழ்ந்த கவலையடைகிறேன். அவர்களின் தடுப்புக் காவலில் கையெழுத்திட வேண்டாம் என்று நான் ஜனாதிபதி ரணிலைக் கேட்டுக்கொள்கிறேன், அவ்வாறு செய்வது 🇱🇰 க்கு ஒரு இருண்ட நாளாக இருக்கும், ”லாலர் ஆகஸ்ட் 21 ஞாயிற்றுக்கிழமை ட்வீட் செய்தார்.",
        "முதலிகே மற்றும் மற்றவர்கள் கொழும்பில் நடந்த போராட்டத்தின் பின்னர் ஆகஸ்ட் 18 வியாழன் அன்று கைது செய்யப்பட்டனர், பின்னர் 72 மணிநேரம் போலீஸ் விசாரணைக்காக தடுத்து வைக்கப்பட்டனர்.",
        "சந்தேகநபர்கள் அரச விரோத நடவடிக்கையில் ஈடுபட்டார்களா என்பது குறித்து விசாரணைகள் இடம்பெற்று வருவதாக பொலிஸார் ஞாயிற்றுக்கிழமை விடுத்துள்ள அறிக்கையில் தெரிவித்துள்ளனர்.",
        "இந்த கைது நடவடிக்கைக்கு எதிர்க்கட்சியினர், சிவில் சமூக அமைப்புகள் மற்றும் ஆர்வலர்கள் கண்டனம் தெரிவித்துள்ளனர். (கொழும்பு/ஆகஸ்ட்21/2022)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ஐ.நா",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "இலங்கை",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "IUSF",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "மேரி லாலோர்பாஸ்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "பல்கலைக்கழகங்களுக்கு இடையிலான மாணவர் கூட்டமைப்பு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "வஸ்நாத முதலிகே",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இரண்டு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "வசந்த முதலிகே",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஹஷன் ஜீவந்த &",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "சிரிதாம்மா ஹிமி",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரணில்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "சட்டத்தரணி",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆகஸ்ட் 21 ஞாயிறு",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "முதலிகே",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆகஸ்ட் 18 வியாழன்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "கொழும்பு",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "72 மணிநேரம்",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஞாயிற்றுக்கிழமை",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "கொழும்பு/ஆகஸ்ட்21/2022",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}