{
  "newspaper_id": "economy-next-com",
  "url": "https://economynext.com/slight-increase-in-covid-19-cases-in-sri-lanka-who-report-indicates-22-pct-hike-97591/",
  "time_ut": 1658145540,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Slight increase in COVID-19 cases in Sri Lanka; WHO report indicates 22 pct hike",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Slight increase in COVID-19 cases in Sri Lanka; WHO report indicates 22 pct hike",
      "author": "Neshella Perera",
      "body_lines": [
        "ECONOMYNEXT – Sri Lanka is seeing a slight increase in the average number of COVID-19 cases being reported, according to government health officials, while a World Health Organisation (WHO) report showed a 22 percent increase since June.",
        "“There is no significant increase, up till the recent past the average cases reported were around ten but there has been an increase in the average from 15 to 20 cases per day,” Deputy Director-General of Public Health Services Dr Hemantha Herath said on Monday July 18.",
        "However, due to this minor increment, health officials are monitoring and taking precautionary measures to prevent the formation of new COVID-19 clusters in Sri Lanka.",
        "As per the Epidemiology Unit at the Ministry of Health, cases since July 11 are an accumulative 158 while the moving average per day is 22 cases.",
        "The number of inward and home based and waiting to be admitted cases have increased in the past week has increased to a total of 411. Recoveries for this week has been a constant of three per day.",
        "Sri Lanka’s total confirmed COVID-19 infections have now reached 664,414.",
        "As per the WHO’s weekly global report, “the South-East Asia Region has been reporting an increasing trend in cases since early June, with over 164 000 new cases reported, a 5% increase as compared to the previous week.”",
        "Four out of 10 countries for which data were available showed increases in the number of new cases at 20% or greater, with some of the greatest proportional increases observed in Nepal (516 vs 268 new cases; +93%) and Sri Lanka (106 vs 87 new cases; +22%), the report said.",
        "Meanwhile, Sri Lanka has also seen an increase in influenza which is considered normal for this time of the year, said Dr  Herath, due to weather and seasonal conditions. Dengue, too, is spreading in Sri Lanka and mild dengue patients are categorised as influenza patients due to the symptoms observed.",
        "The BA.5 is a sub variant of the highly contagious omicron variant of SARS-CoV-2, the virus that causes COVID-19 has yet to be identified in Sri Lanka, according to Dr Herath. The strain, which originated in South Africa in February, is currently the dominant variant in the US.",
        "The new variant is reported to be highly transmissible and vaccines are said to have a comparatively lower response rate to it, though severe disease has been found to be lower when vaccinated.",
        "Sri Lanka is now offering the fourth dose of the COVID-19 vaccine, which can be obtained at the nearest Medical Officer of Health (MOH) vaccination centre. The vaccine is recommended for everyone over the age of 20 and is highly recommended for citizens above the age of 60 and those above 20 with comorbidities.",
        "The newly emerged variant has been classified as the “worst version of the virus we’ve seen”, by Eric Topol, a cardiologist and professor of molecular medicine at Scripps Research. (Colombo/Jul18/2022"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Sri Lanka",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "WHO",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "22",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "World Health Organisation",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "22 percent",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "June",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ten",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "15 to 20",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "General of",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Monday July 18",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the Epidemiology Unit",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Ministry of Health",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "July 11",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "158",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "22",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the past week",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "411",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "this week",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "three per day",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "664,414",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "WHO",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "weekly",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "South",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "early June",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "5%",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "the previous week",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Four",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "10",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "20%",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "Nepal",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "516",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "268",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "106",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "87",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the year",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Dr  Herath",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Dr Herath",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "South Africa",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "February",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "US",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "fourth",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Medical Officer of Health",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the age of 20",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "20",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Eric Topol",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Scripps Research",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ COVID-19 රෝගීන්ගේ සුළු වැඩිවීමක්; ලෝක සෞඛ්‍ය සංවිධානයේ වාර්තාව පෙන්වා දෙන්නේ සියයට 22ක වැඩිවීමක්",
      "author": "නෙෂෙල්ලා පෙරේරා",
      "body_lines": [
        "ECONOMYNEXT - රජයේ සෞඛ්‍ය නිලධාරීන්ට අනුව ශ්‍රී ලංකාව වාර්තා වන සාමාන්‍ය COVID-19 රෝගීන් සංඛ්‍යාවේ සුළු වැඩිවීමක් දකින අතර ලෝක සෞඛ්‍ය සංවිධානයේ (WHO) වාර්තාවක් ජුනි මාසයේ සිට සියයට 22 ක වැඩිවීමක් පෙන්නුම් කරයි.",
        "\"පසුගිය කාලය දක්වාම වාර්තා වූ සාමාන්‍ය රෝගීන් සංඛ්‍යාව දහයක් පමණ වූ නමුත් සැලකිය යුතු වැඩි වීමක් සිදුවී නොමැති නමුත් දිනකට රෝගීන් 15 සිට 20 දක්වා සාමාන්‍ය වැඩිවීමක් දක්නට ලැබේ\" යනුවෙන් මහජන සෞඛ්‍ය සේවා නියෝජ්‍ය අධ්‍යක්ෂ ජනරාල් වෛද්‍ය හේමන්ත හේරත් මහතා පැවසීය. ජූලි 18 සඳුදා.",
        "කෙසේ වෙතත්, මෙම සුළු වර්ධක හේතුවෙන්, සෞඛ්‍ය නිලධාරීන් විසින් ශ්‍රී ලංකාව තුළ නව COVID-19 පොකුරු ඇතිවීම වැලැක්වීම සඳහා අධීක්ෂණය සහ පූර්වාරක්ෂාව ගනිමින් සිටී.",
        "සෞඛ්‍ය අමාත්‍යාංශයේ වසංගත රෝග විද්‍යා අංශයට අනුව, ජූලි 11 සිට රෝගීන් 158 සමුච්චිත වන අතර දිනකට චලනය වන සාමාන්‍යය රෝගීන් 22 කි.",
        "පසුගිය සතිය තුළ ඇතුළත සහ නිවෙස් පදනම් කරගත් සහ ඇතුළත් කිරීමට බලා සිටින රෝගීන් සංඛ්‍යාව මුළු 411 දක්වා වැඩි වී ඇත. මෙම සතිය සඳහා ප්‍රතිසාධනය දිනකට තුන බැගින් වේ.",
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවෙන් තහවුරු වූ මුළු COVID-19 ආසාදන මේ වන විට 664,414 දක්වා ඉහළ ගොස් තිබේ.",
        "ලෝක සෞඛ්‍ය සංවිධානයේ සතිපතා ගෝලීය වාර්තාවට අනුව, \"අග්නිදිග ආසියා කලාපය ජුනි මස මුල සිට වැඩිවන ප්‍රවණතාවක් වාර්තා කරයි, නව රෝගීන් 164 000 කට වඩා වාර්තා වී ඇත, පෙර සතියට සාපේක්ෂව 5% ක වැඩිවීමකි.\"",
        "දත්ත ලබා ගත හැකි රටවල් 10 න් හතරක් නේපාලයේ (516 එදිරිව නව අවස්ථා 268; +93%) සහ ශ්‍රී ලංකාව (106) හි විශාලතම සමානුපාතික වැඩිවීම් සමඟින් 20% හෝ ඊට වැඩි නව රෝගීන් සංඛ්‍යාවේ වැඩි වීමක් පෙන්නුම් කරයි. එදිරිව නව අවස්ථා 87; + 22%), වාර්තාව පවසයි.",
        "මේ අතර, වසරේ මෙම කාලය සඳහා සාමාන්‍ය යැයි සැලකෙන ඉන්ෆ්ලුවෙන්සා රෝගයේ වැඩිවීමක් ශ්‍රී ලංකාව ද දැක ඇති බව කාලගුණය සහ සෘතුමය තත්ත්වයන් හේතුවෙන් වෛද්‍ය හේරත් මහතා පැවසීය. ශ්‍රී ලංකාව තුළද ඩෙංගු රෝගය ව්‍යාප්ත වෙමින් පවතින අතර මෘදු ඩෙංගු රෝගීන් ඉන්ෆ්ලුවෙන්සා රෝගීන් ලෙස වර්ගීකරණය කර ඇත්තේ එහි දක්නට ලැබෙන රෝග ලක්ෂණ අනුවයි.",
        "BA.5 යනු SARS-CoV-2 හි අධික ලෙස බෝවන Omicron ප්‍රභේදයේ උප ප්‍රභේදයකි, COVID-19 ඇති කරන වෛරසය ශ්‍රී ලංකාව තුළ තවමත් හඳුනාගෙන නොමැති බව වෛද්‍ය හේරත් පවසයි. පෙබරවාරි මාසයේදී දකුණු අප්‍රිකාවේ ආරම්භ වූ වික්‍රියාව දැනට එක්සත් ජනපදයේ ප්‍රමුඛ ප්‍රභේදයයි.",
        "නව ප්‍රභේදය අධික ලෙස සම්ප්‍රේෂණය වන බව වාර්තා වන අතර එන්නත් කරන විට දරුණු රෝග අඩු බව සොයාගෙන ඇතත්, එන්නත් වලට සාපේක්ෂව අඩු ප්‍රතිචාර අනුපාතයක් ඇති බව කියනු ලැබේ.",
        "ළඟම ඇති සෞඛ්‍ය වෛද්‍ය නිලධාරී (MOH) එන්නත් මධ්‍යස්ථානයෙන් ලබා ගත හැකි COVID-19 එන්නතෙහි සිව්වන මාත්‍රාව ශ්‍රී ලංකාව දැන් පිරිනමයි. මෙම එන්නත වයස අවුරුදු 20 ට වැඩි සෑම කෙනෙකුටම නිර්දේශ කර ඇති අතර වයස අවුරුදු 60 ට වැඩි පුරවැසියන් සහ 20 ට වැඩි සහසම්බන්ධතා ඇති අය සඳහා ඉතා ඉහළින් නිර්දේශ කෙරේ.",
        "Scripps Research හි හෘද රෝග විශේෂඥ සහ අණුක වෛද්‍ය විද්‍යාව පිළිබඳ මහාචාර්ය එරික් ටොපෝල් විසින් අලුතින් මතු වූ ප්‍රභේදය “අපි දැක ඇති වෛරසයේ නරකම අනුවාදය” ලෙස වර්ගීකරණය කර ඇත. (කොළඹ/ජූලි18/2022"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "කවුද",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "22",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ලෝක සෞඛ්ය සංවිධානය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "සියයට 22 කි",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජූනි",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "දස",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "15 සිට 20 දක්වා",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජෙනරාල්ගේ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජූලි 18 සඳුදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "වසංගත රෝග ඒකකය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "සෞඛ්ය අමාත්යාංශය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජූලි 11",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "158",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "22",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "පසුගිය සතියේ",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "411",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "මෙම සතිය",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "දිනකට තුනක්",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "664,414 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "කවුද",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "සතිපතා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "දකුණු",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජූනි මස මුල",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "5%",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "පෙර සතියේ",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "හතර",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "10",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "20%",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "නේපාලය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "516",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "268",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "106",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "87",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "වසර",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ආචාර්ය හේරත්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ආචාර්ය හේරත්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "දකුණු අප්රිකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "පෙබරවාරි",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "එක්සත් ජනපදය",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "හතරවන",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "සෞඛ්‍ය වෛද්‍ය නිලධාරී",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "වයස අවුරුදු 20 යි",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "20",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "එරික් ටොපෝල්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Scripps පර්යේෂණ",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "இலங்கையில் கோவிட்-19 நோயாளிகள் சிறிதளவு அதிகரிப்பு; WHO அறிக்கை 22 சதவீதம் உயர்வைக் குறிக்கிறது",
      "author": "நெஷெல்லா பெரேரா",
      "body_lines": [
        "ECONOMYNEXT - அரசாங்க சுகாதார அதிகாரிகளின் கூற்றுப்படி, இலங்கையில் கோவிட்-19 வழக்குகளின் சராசரி எண்ணிக்கையில் சிறிதளவு அதிகரிப்பு காணப்படுகிறது, அதே நேரத்தில் உலக சுகாதார அமைப்பின் (WHO) அறிக்கை ஜூன் மாதத்திலிருந்து 22 சதவீத அதிகரிப்பைக் காட்டுகிறது.",
        "\"கணிசமான அதிகரிப்பு எதுவும் இல்லை, கடந்த காலம் வரை சராசரியாக பத்து வழக்குகள் பதிவாகியுள்ளன, ஆனால் ஒரு நாளைக்கு சராசரியாக 15 முதல் 20 வழக்குகள் வரை அதிகரித்துள்ளன\" என்று பொது சுகாதார சேவைகளின் பிரதிப் பணிப்பாளர் நாயகம் டாக்டர் ஹேமந்த ஹேரத் தெரிவித்தார். ஜூலை 18 திங்கட்கிழமை.",
        "எவ்வாறாயினும், இந்த சிறிய அதிகரிப்பு காரணமாக, இலங்கையில் புதிய COVID-19 குழுக்கள் உருவாக்கப்படுவதைத் தடுக்க சுகாதார அதிகாரிகள் கண்காணித்து முன்னெச்சரிக்கை நடவடிக்கைகளை மேற்கொண்டு வருகின்றனர்.",
        "சுகாதார அமைச்சின் தொற்றுநோயியல் பிரிவின்படி, ஜூலை 11 முதல், ஒரு நாளுக்கு சராசரியாக 22 வழக்குகள் ஒரே நேரத்தில் 158 ஆக உள்ளது.",
        "கடந்த வாரத்தில் உள்நோயாளிகள் மற்றும் வீடுகள் சார்ந்த மற்றும் அனுமதிக்கப்படக் காத்திருக்கும் வழக்குகளின் எண்ணிக்கை மொத்தம் 411 ஆக அதிகரித்துள்ளது. இந்த வாரத்திற்கான மீட்புகள் ஒரு நாளைக்கு மூன்று என்ற நிலையாக உள்ளது.",
        "இலங்கையின் மொத்த உறுதிப்படுத்தப்பட்ட COVID-19 தொற்றுகள் இப்போது 664,414 ஐ எட்டியுள்ளன.",
        "WHO இன் வாராந்திர உலகளாவிய அறிக்கையின்படி, \"தென்-கிழக்கு ஆசிய பிராந்தியத்தில் ஜூன் தொடக்கத்தில் இருந்து வழக்குகள் அதிகரித்து வருகின்றன, 164 000 க்கும் மேற்பட்ட புதிய வழக்குகள் பதிவாகியுள்ளன, முந்தைய வாரத்துடன் ஒப்பிடும்போது 5% அதிகரிப்பு.\"",
        "நேபாளம் (516 vs 268 புதிய வழக்குகள்; +93%) மற்றும் இலங்கை (106) ஆகியவற்றில் சில மிகப் பெரிய விகிதாசார அதிகரிப்புடன், தரவுகள் கிடைத்த 10 நாடுகளில் நான்கு புதிய வழக்குகளின் எண்ணிக்கையில் 20% அல்லது அதற்கும் அதிகமாக அதிகரித்துள்ளன. எதிராக 87 புதிய வழக்குகள்; +22%), அறிக்கை கூறியது.",
        "இதற்கிடையில், காலநிலை மற்றும் பருவகால நிலைமைகள் காரணமாக, ஆண்டின் இந்த நேரத்தில் சாதாரணமாகக் கருதப்படும் இன்ஃப்ளூயன்ஸாவின் அதிகரிப்பு இலங்கையிலும் காணப்படுகிறது என்று டாக்டர் ஹேரத் கூறினார். டெங்கு, இலங்கையிலும் பரவி வருகின்றது மற்றும் மிதமான டெங்கு நோயாளர்கள் காணப்பட்ட அறிகுறிகளின் காரணமாக இன்புளுவன்சா நோயாளிகளாக வகைப்படுத்தப்பட்டுள்ளனர்.",
        "BA.5 என்பது SARS-CoV-2 இன் மிகவும் தொற்றக்கூடிய ஓமிக்ரான் மாறுபாட்டின் துணை வகையாகும், இது COVID-19 ஐ ஏற்படுத்தும் வைரஸ் இலங்கையில் இன்னும் அடையாளம் காணப்படவில்லை என்று டாக்டர் ஹேரத் கூறுகிறார். பிப்ரவரியில் தென்னாப்பிரிக்காவில் தோன்றிய திரிபு, தற்போது அமெரிக்காவில் ஆதிக்கம் செலுத்தும் மாறுபாடு ஆகும்.",
        "புதிய மாறுபாடு மிகவும் பரவக்கூடியது மற்றும் தடுப்பூசிகள் ஒப்பீட்டளவில் குறைவான பதில் விகிதத்தைக் கொண்டிருப்பதாகக் கூறப்படுகிறது, இருப்பினும் தடுப்பூசி போடும்போது கடுமையான நோய் குறைவாக இருப்பதாகக் கண்டறியப்பட்டது.",
        "இலங்கை இப்போது கோவிட்-19 தடுப்பூசியின் நான்காவது டோஸை வழங்குகிறது, அதை அருகிலுள்ள சுகாதார மருத்துவ அதிகாரி (MOH) தடுப்பூசி மையத்தில் பெறலாம். தடுப்பூசி 20 வயதுக்கு மேற்பட்ட அனைவருக்கும் பரிந்துரைக்கப்படுகிறது, மேலும் 60 வயதுக்கு மேற்பட்ட குடிமக்கள் மற்றும் 20 வயதுக்கு மேல் உள்ளவர்களுக்கு பரிந்துரைக்கப்படுகிறது.",
        "புதிதாக தோன்றிய மாறுபாடு, \"நாம் பார்த்த வைரஸின் மோசமான பதிப்பு\" என வகைப்படுத்தப்பட்டுள்ளது, எரிக் டோபோல், இருதயநோய் நிபுணரும் ஸ்க்ரிப்ஸ் ஆராய்ச்சியில் மூலக்கூறு மருத்துவப் பேராசிரியருமான. (கொழும்பு/ஜூலை18/2022"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "இலங்கை",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "WHO",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "22",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "உலக சுகாதார நிறுவனம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "22 சதவீதம்",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜூன்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பத்து",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "15 முதல் 20 வரை",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "பொது",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜூலை 18 திங்கட்கிழமை",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "தொற்றுநோயியல் பிரிவு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "சுகாதார அமைச்சகம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜூலை 11",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "158",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "22",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "கடந்த வாரம்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "411",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்த வாரம்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஒரு நாளைக்கு மூன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "664,414",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "WHO",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "வாரந்தோறும்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "தெற்கு",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜூன் தொடக்கத்தில்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "5%",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "முந்தைய வாரம்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "நான்கு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "10",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "20%",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "நேபாளம்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "516",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "268",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "106",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "87",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆண்டு",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "டாக்டர் ஹேரத்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "டாக்டர் ஹேரத்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "தென்னாப்பிரிக்கா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "பிப்ரவரி",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "எங்களுக்கு",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "நான்காவது",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "சுகாதார வைத்திய அதிகாரி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "20 வயது",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "20",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "எரிக் டோபோல்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஸ்கிரிப்ஸ் ஆராய்ச்சி",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}