{
  "newspaper_id": "virakesari-lk",
  "url": "http://www.virakesari.lk/article/132177",
  "time_ut": 1658669653,
  "original_lang": "ta",
  "original_title": "கோத்தபாய ராஜபக்சவை கைதுசெய்யவேண்டும் - சிங்கப்பூர் சட்டமா அதிபர் திணைக்களத்திடம் சர்வதேச அமைப்பு மனு",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Gotabaya Rajapaksa should be arrested - International organization petitions Singapore Attorney General's Department",
      "author": "Rajeeban",
      "body_lines": [
        "The International Truth and Justice Project has filed a petition with the Singapore Attorney General's Department seeking the arrest of former Sri Lankan President Gotabaya Rajapaksa.",
        "According to Truth and Justice International, an international organization documenting human rights abuses, Gotabaya Rajapaksa committed massive human rights violations while serving as Sri Lanka's defense secretary in 2009.",
        "The South Africa-based organization has said that investigations can be conducted in Singapore based on international jurisprudence regarding alleged human rights violations."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Gotabaya Rajapaksa",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "Singapore",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "General's",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "Department",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "The International Truth",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Justice Project",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Singapore",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lankan",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Gotabaya Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Truth",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Justice International",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Gotabaya Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka's",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "2009",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "South Africa",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Singapore",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ අත්අඩංගුවට ගත යුතුයි - ජාත්‍යන්තර සංවිධානය සිංගප්පූරු නීතිපති දෙපාර්තමේන්තුවට පෙත්සමක්",
      "author": "රජීබන්",
      "body_lines": [
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ හිටපු ජනාධිපති ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ අත්අඩංගුවට ගන්නා ලෙස ඉල්ලා ජාත්‍යන්තර සත්‍යය සහ යුක්තිය ව්‍යාපෘතිය සිංගප්පූරු නීතිපති දෙපාර්තමේන්තුවට පෙත්සමක් ගොනු කර තිබේ.",
        "මානව හිමිකම් උල්ලංඝනය කිරීම් ලේඛනගත කරන ජාත්‍යන්තර සංවිධානයක් වන Truth and Justice International වෙත අනුව, ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ මහතා 2009 වසරේ ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ ආරක්ෂක ලේකම්වරයා ලෙස කටයුතු කරමින් සිටියදී දැවැන්ත මානව හිමිකම් කඩකිරීම් සිදු කර ඇත.",
        "සිංගප්පූරුවේදී සිදුවී ඇතැයි කියන මානව හිමිකම් කඩකිරීම් සම්බන්ධයෙන් ජාත්‍යන්තර නීති විද්‍යාව පදනම් කරගෙන පරීක්ෂණ පැවැත්විය හැකි බව දකුණු අප්‍රිකාව පදනම් කරගත් එම සංවිධානය පවසා තිබේ."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "සිංගප්පූරුව",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "ජෙනරාල්ගේ",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "ෙදපාර්තෙම්න්තුෙව්",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ජාත්‍යන්තර සත්‍යය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "යුක්තිය ව්යාපෘතිය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "සිංගප්පූරුව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලාංකික",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "සත්යය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජස්ටිස් ඉන්ටර්නැෂනල්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "2009",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "දකුණු අප්රිකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "සිංගප්පූරුව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "கோத்தபாய ராஜபக்சவை கைதுசெய்யவேண்டும் - சிங்கப்பூர் சட்டமா அதிபர் திணைக்களத்திடம் சர்வதேச அமைப்பு மனு",
      "author": "Rajeeban",
      "body_lines": [
        "இலங்கையின் முன்னாள் ஜனாதிபதி கோத்தபாய ராஜபக்சவை கைதுசெய்யவேண்டும் என கோரும் மனுவொன்றை சர்வதேச உண்மை மற்றும் நீதிக்கான திட்டம் சிங்கப்பூர் சட்டமா அதிபர் திணைக்களத்தில் தாக்கல் செய்துள்ளது",
        "2009 இல் கோத்தபாய ராஜபக்ச  இலங்கையின் பாதுகாப்பு செயலாளராக பணியாற்றியவேளை பாரிய மனித உரிமை மீறல்களில் ஈடுபட்டார் என மனித உரிமை மீறல்களை ஆவணப்படுத்தும் சர்வதேச அமைப்பான உண்மை மற்றும் நீதிக்கான சர்வதேச  தெரிவித்துள்ளது.",
        "இடம்பெற்றதாக குற்றம்சாட்டப்படும் மனித உரிமை மீறல்கள்  குறித்து சர்வதேச நியாயாதிக்கத்தின் அடிப்படையில் சிங்கப்பூரில் விசாரணைகளை மேற்கொள்ள முடியும் என தென்னாபிரிக்காவை தளமாக கொண்ட அமைப்பு தெரிவித்துள்ளது."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ச",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "சிங்கப்பூர்",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "ஜெனரலின்",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "துறை",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "சர்வதேச உண்மை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "நீதி திட்டம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "சிங்கப்பூர்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "உண்மை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "நீதி சர்வதேசம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கையின்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "2009",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "தென்னாப்பிரிக்கா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சிங்கப்பூர்",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}