{
  "newspaper_id": "virakesari-lk",
  "url": "http://www.virakesari.lk/article/132120",
  "time_ut": 1658642844,
  "original_lang": "ta",
  "original_title": "கறுப்பு ஜூலையின் 39 ஆவது ஆண்டு நினைவேந்தல் அனுஷ்டிப்பு",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "39th Anniversary of Black July Commemoration",
      "author": "Vishnu",
      "body_lines": [
        "The 39th anniversary of the Black July riots against the Tamil people was observed on the 23rd. In the early hours of July 23, 1983, ethnic riots against the Tamil people were unleashed across the country after a landmine attack on the army in Tirunelveli.",
        "During this, thousands of Tamil people from Colombo and other areas were looted and destroyed their properties and were driven northwards as refugees.",
        "Thus commemoration events were conducted in various places on the occasion of the 39th anniversary of Black July when the genocide against Tamils ​​was unleashed.",
        "In this case, advance has been made in Tamil Tesiya Kotalampapu Aluvaikit in Vadamaratsi-Matthadi area. This event is organized by the North Maratshi branch of the Tamil National Federation.",
        "Under the leadership of Member of Parliament MA Sumanthran, members of Provincial Council Municipal Council, Prakadasa Sabha members and members of Vadamaratsi branch took part and lit candles. Meanwhile, the Black July commemoration event was held at the University of Jaffna. In this event, students of Jaffna University paid respects to the memorial, lit lamps and sprinkled flowers.",
        "Also, another event was held at Navalar Mani Mandapam. With the participation of Ananthi Sasitharan and others, an agreement has been reached regarding the formation of a coalition against the destruction of Tamils."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Black July Commemoration",
          "label": "EVENT"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "39th",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Black July",
            "label": "EVENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "Tamil",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the 23rd",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the early hours of July 23, 1983",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "Tamil",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Tirunelveli",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "thousands",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Colombo",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "39th",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Black July",
            "label": "EVENT"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Kotalampapu Aluvaikit",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Vadamaratsi-Matthadi",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "North Maratshi",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Tamil National Federation",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Parliament MA Sumanthran",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Provincial Council Municipal Council",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Prakadasa Sabha",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Vadamaratsi",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Black July",
            "label": "EVENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "the University of Jaffna",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Jaffna University",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Mani Mandapam",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ananthi Sasitharan",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Tamils",
            "label": "LOC"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "කළු ජූලි සැමරුමේ 39 වැනි සංවත්සරය",
      "author": "විෂ්ණු",
      "body_lines": [
        "දෙමළ ජනතාවට එරෙහි කළු ජූලි කෝලාහලයේ 39 වැනි සංවත්සරය පසුගිය 23 වැනිදාට යෙදී තිබුණි. 1983 ජූලි 23 වැනිදා අලුයම තිරුනෙල්වේලිහිදී හමුදාවට බිම් බෝම්බ ප්‍රහාරයක් එල්ල කිරීමෙන් පසු දෙමළ ජනතාවට එරෙහිව වාර්ගික කෝලාහල රට පුරා මුදා හැරිණි.",
        "මේ කාලය තුළ කොළඹ ඇතුළු ප්‍රදේශවලින් දහස් ගණන් දෙමළ ජනයා කොල්ලකා ඔවුන්ගේ දේපළ විනාශ කර උතුරට සරණාගතයන් ලෙස පලවා හරින ලදී.",
        "දෙමළ ජනතාවට එරෙහි ජන සංහාරය මුදාහරින ලද කළු ජූලියේ 39 වැනි සංවත්සරය නිමිත්තෙන් විවිධ ස්ථානවල සමරු උත්සව පැවැත්විණි.",
        "මෙහිදී වඩමරට්සි-මත්තාඩි ප්‍රදේශයේ දෙමළ තේසිය කොතලම්පාපු අලුවයිකිට් ප්‍රදේශයේ අත්තිකාරම් ලබාදී ඇත. මෙම උත්සවය දෙමළ ජාතික සම්මේලනයේ උතුරු මරාට්ෂි ශාඛාව විසින් සංවිධානය කරනු ලැබේ.",
        "පාර්ලිමේන්තු මන්ත්‍රී එම් ඒ සුමන්ත‍්‍රන් මහතාගේ ප්‍රධානත්වයෙන් පළාත් සභා මහ නගර සභා මන්ත්‍රීවරුන්, ප්‍රකාශක සභා මන්ත්‍රීවරුන් සහ වඩමරට්සි ශාඛාවේ මන්ත්‍රීවරුන් සහභාගී වී ඉටිපන්දම් දල්වන ලදී. මේ අතර කළු ජූලිය සැමරුම් උත්සවය යාපනය විශ්වවිද්‍යාලයේ දී පැවැත්වුණා. මෙහිදී යාපනය විශ්ව විද්‍යාලයේ සිසුන් ස්මාරකයට ගෞරව දැක්වීම, පහන් දල්වා මල් ඉසිනු ලැබීය.",
        "එමෙන්ම නාවලර් මනි මණ්ඩපයේදී තවත් උත්සවයක් පැවැත්විණි. අනන්ති සසිදරන් ඇතුළු පිරිසකගේ සහභාගිත්වයෙන් දෙමළ විනාශයට එරෙහිව සන්ධානයක් පිහිටුවීම සම්බන්ධයෙන් එකඟතාවකට පැමිණ තිබේ."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "කළු ජූලි සැමරුම",
          "label": "EVENT"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "39 වැනි",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "කළු ජූලිය",
            "label": "EVENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "දෙමළ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "23 වැනි",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "1983 ජුලි 23 වෙනිදා පාන්දර",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "දෙමළ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "තිරුනෙල්වේලි",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "දහස්",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "කොළඹ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "39 වැනි",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "කළු ජූලිය",
            "label": "EVENT"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "කොතලම්පපු අලුවයිකිත්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "වඩමාරට්සි-මත්තාඩි",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "උතුරු මරාට්ෂි",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "දෙමළ ජාතික සම්මේලනය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව එම් ඒ සුමන්ත‍්‍රන්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "පළාත් සභා මහ නගර සභාව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ප්‍රකාදාස සභාව",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "වඩමාරට්සි",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "කළු ජූලිය",
            "label": "EVENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "යාපනය විශ්වවිද්‍යාලය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "යාපනය විශ්වවිද්‍යාලය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "මනි මණ්ඩපය",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "අනන්ති සසිදරන්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "දෙමළ අය",
            "label": "LOC"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "கறுப்பு ஜூலையின் 39 ஆவது ஆண்டு நினைவேந்தல் அனுஷ்டிப்பு",
      "author": "Vishnu",
      "body_lines": [
        "தமிழ் மக்களுக்கு எதிராக நிகழ்த்தப்பட்ட கறுப்பு ஜூலை இனக்கலவரங்களின் 39ஆவது நினைவு நாள் 23 ஆம் திகதி அனுஷ்டிக்கப்பட்டது. 1983ஆம் ஆண்டு , ஜூலை 23 ஆம் திகதி அதிகாலை திருநெல்வேலியில் இராணுவத்தினர் மீது நடத்தப்பட்ட கண்ணி வெடித்தாக்குதலை அடுத்து, நாடு முழுவதும் தமிழ் மக்களுக்கு எதிரான இனக்கலவரம் கட்டவிழ்த்து விடப்பட்டது.",
        "இதன்போது கொழும்பிலும், ஏனைய பகுதிகளிலும் இருந்து ஆயிரக்கணக்கான தமிழ் மக்களின் சொத்துக்கள் சூறையாடப்பட்டும், அழிக்கப்பட்டும், வடக்கு நோக்கி அகதிகளாக விரட்டியடிக்கப்பட்டனர்.",
        "இவ்வாறு, தமிழருக்கு எதிரான இனஅழிப்பு கட்டவிழ்த்து விடப்பட்ட கறுப்பு ஜூலையின் 39ஆவது நினைவு தினத்தினை முன்னிட்டு பல்வேறு, இடங்களிலும் நினைவேந்தல் நிகழ்வுகள் முன்னெடுக்கப்பட்டன.",
        "இந்நிலையில், வடமராட்சி - மடத்தடி பகுதியில் உள்ள தமிழ்த்தேசியக் கூட்டலமப்பு அலுவைக்தில் முன் வனடுக்கப்பட்டுள்ளது. தமிழ்த் தேசியக் கூட்டலைப்பின் வடமராட்சி கிளையின் ஏற்பாட்டில் இந்தநிகழ்வு இடம்வபற்றுள்ளது.",
        "பாராளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர் எம்.ஏ.சுமந்திரன் தலைமையில் மாகாணசபை நகரசபை, பிரகதச சபை உறுப்பினர்கள் மற்றும் வடமராட்சி கிளையின் உறுப்பினர்கள் பங்ககற்று, மெழுகுவர்த்த ஏந்தி அச்சலி செலுத்தனர். இதேவேளை,  கறுப்பு ஜூலை நினைவேந்தல் நிகழ்வு யாழ்.பல்கலைக்கழகத்தில் இடம்பெற்றது. இந்நிகழ்வில் யாழ்.பல்கலைக்கழக மாணவர்களால் நினைவுத்தூபிக்கு அகவணக்கம் செலுத்தி, தீபம் ஏற்றி மலர்கள் தூவி அஞ்சலி செலுத்தப்பட்டிருந்தது.",
        "அத்துடன், பிறிதொரு நிகழ்வு நாவலர் மணிமண்டபத்தில் நடைபெற்றது. இதில் அனந்தி சசிதரன் உள்ளிட்டவர்கள் பங்கேற்றதுடன் தமிழின அழிப்புக்கு எதிரான கூட்டமைப்பொன்றை உருவாக்குவது தொடர்பில் இணக்கப்பாடு எட்டப்பட்டுள்ளது."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "கருப்பு ஜூலை நினைவேந்தல்",
          "label": "EVENT"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "39வது",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "கருப்பு ஜூலை",
            "label": "EVENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "தமிழ்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "23 ஆம் தேதி",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜூலை 23, 1983 அதிகாலை",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "தமிழ்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "திருநெல்வேலி",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஆயிரக்கணக்கான",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "கொழும்பு",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "39வது",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "கருப்பு ஜூலை",
            "label": "EVENT"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "கொத்தலம்பாப்பு அலுவைகிட்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "வடமராட்சி-மத்தடி",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "வட மராட்டி",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "தமிழ் தேசிய கூட்டமைப்பு",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்ற எம்.ஏ.சுமந்திரன்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "மாகாண சபை மாநகர சபை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "பிரகதாச சபை",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "வடமராட்சி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "கருப்பு ஜூலை",
            "label": "EVENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "யாழ்ப்பாணப் பல்கலைக்கழகம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "யாழ்ப்பாணப் பல்கலைக்கழகம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "மணி மண்டபம்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "அனந்தி சசிதரன்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "தமிழர்கள்",
            "label": "LOC"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}