{
  "newspaper_id": "ada-derana-lk",
  "url": "http://www.adaderana.lk/news/83732/sajith-withdraws-candidacy-sjb-to-support-dullas-for-presidency",
  "time_ut": 1658205480,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Sajith withdraws candidacy; SJB to support Dullas for Presidency",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Sajith withdraws candidacy; SJB to support Dullas for Presidency",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "The Samagi Jana Balawegaya (SJB) has decided to support SLPP parliamentarian Dullas Alahapperuma’s candidacy for the Presidency.",
        "Opposition Leader and SJB leader, Sajith Premadasa says he withdraws his candidacy for the position of President and that their alliance and opposition partners will work towards ensuring victory to MP Alahapperuma.",
        "“For the greater good of my country that I love and the people I cherish I hereby withdraw my candidacy for the position of President.”",
        "“SJB and our alliance and our opposition partners will work hard towards making Dullas Alahapperuma",
        "Earlier today, the Leader of the Opposition had tweeted saying, “On my way to Parliament to take a crucial step. I want the people of Sri Lanka to know that I will take the correct decision at the appropriate time to protect my motherland’s national interest and the rights of all my fellow Sri Lankan people.”"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "SJB",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "Dullas",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Samagi",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Jana Balawegaya",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "SJB",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Dullas Alahapperuma",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "SJB",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sajith Premadasa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "SJB",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Dullas Alahapperuma",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Earlier today",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Opposition",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lankan",
            "label": "LOC"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "සජිත් අපේක්ෂකත්වය ඉල්ලා අස්කර ගනී; SJB ඩලස්ට ජනාධිපතිවරණයට සහය දෙනවා",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "සමගි ජන බලවේගය (SJB) ශ්‍රී ලංකා පොදුජන පෙරමුණේ පාර්ලිමේන්තු මන්ත්‍රී ඩලස් අලහප්පෙරුම මහතාගේ ජනාධිපති අපේක්ෂකත්වයට සහය දැක්වීමට තීරණය කර තිබේ.",
        "විපක්ෂ නායක සහ SJB නායක සජිත් ප්‍රේමදාස මහතා පවසන්නේ තමා ජනාධිපති අපේක්ෂකත්වය ඉල්ලා අස්කර ගන්නා බවත්, අලහප්පෙරුම මන්ත්‍රීවරයාගේ ජයග්‍රහණය තහවුරු කිරීම සඳහා තම සන්ධානය සහ විපක්ෂ හවුල්කරුවන් කටයුතු කරන බවත්ය.",
        "\"මා ආදරය කරන මගේ රටේ සහ මා ආදරය කරන මිනිසුන්ගේ යහපත වෙනුවෙන් මම මගේ ජනාධිපති අපේක්ෂකත්වය මෙයින් ඉවත් කරමි.\"",
        "“ඩලස් අලහප්පෙරුම හදන්න SJB සහ අපේ සන්ධානය සහ අපේ විපක්ෂ හවුල්කරුවන් මහන්සි වෙනවා",
        "අද උදෑසන විපක්ෂ නායකවරයා ට්විටර් පණිවුඩයක් නිකුත් කරමින් කියා සිටියේ, “මම තීරණාත්මක පියවරක් ගැනීමට පාර්ලිමේන්තුවට යන ගමනේදී. මගේ මාතෘභූමියේ ජාතික අවශ්‍යතා සහ මගේ සියලු ශ්‍රී ලාංකික ජනතාවගේ අයිතිවාසිකම් ආරක්ෂා කිරීම සඳහා සුදුසු අවස්ථාවේදී මම නිවැරදි තීරණයක් ගන්නා බව ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ ජනතාව දැන ගැනීමට මට අවශ්‍යය."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "එස්.ජේ.බී",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "ඩලස්",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "සමගි",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජන බලවේගය",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "එස්.ජේ.බී",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඩලස් අලහප්පෙරුම",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "එස්.ජේ.බී",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "සජිත් ප්‍රේමදාස",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "එස්.ජේ.බී",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඩලස් අලහප්පෙරුම",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "අද කලින්",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "විපක්ෂ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලාංකික",
            "label": "LOC"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "சஜித் வேட்புமனு வாபஸ்; ஜனாதிபதி பதவிக்கு டல்லாஸை ஆதரிக்க SJB",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "ஸ்ரீலங்கா பொதுஜன பெரமுனவின் நாடாளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர் டலஸ் அழகப்பெருமவின் ஜனாதிபதி வேட்புமனுவை ஆதரிக்க சமகி ஜன பலவேகய (SJB) தீர்மானித்துள்ளது.",
        "ஜனாதிபதி பதவிக்கான வேட்புமனுவை தாம் வாபஸ் பெறுவதாகவும், தமது கூட்டணி மற்றும் எதிர்க்கட்சி பங்காளிகள் எம்.பி. அழகப்பெருமவின் வெற்றியை உறுதிப்படுத்தும் வகையில் செயற்படுவார்கள் எனவும் எதிர்க்கட்சித் தலைவரும் SJB தலைவருமான சஜித் பிரேமதாச தெரிவித்துள்ளார்.",
        "\"நான் நேசிக்கும் எனது நாட்டிற்கும், நான் நேசிக்கும் மக்களின் நலனுக்காகவும் ஜனாதிபதி பதவிக்கான எனது வேட்புமனுவை இதன் மூலம் திரும்பப் பெறுகிறேன்.\"",
        "டலஸ் அழகப்பெருமவை உருவாக்குவதற்கு எஸ்.ஜே.பியும் எமது கூட்டணியும் எமது எதிர்க்கட்சி பங்காளிகளும் கடுமையாக உழைக்கவுள்ளனர்",
        "இன்று முன்னதாக, எதிர்க்கட்சித் தலைவர் ட்வீட் செய்திருந்தார், “நான் ஒரு முக்கியமான நடவடிக்கை எடுக்க நாடாளுமன்றத்திற்குச் செல்கிறேன். எனது தாய்நாட்டின் தேசிய நலனையும் எனது சக இலங்கை மக்களின் உரிமைகளையும் பாதுகாப்பதற்கு நான் சரியான நேரத்தில் சரியான முடிவை எடுப்பேன் என்பதை இலங்கை மக்கள் அறிந்து கொள்ள வேண்டும் என்று நான் விரும்புகிறேன்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "எஸ்.ஜே.பி",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "டல்லாஸ்",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "சமகி",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜன பலவேகயா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "எஸ்.ஜே.பி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "டலஸ் அழகப்பெரும",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "எஸ்.ஜே.பி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "சஜித் பிரேமதாச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "எஸ்.ஜே.பி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "டலஸ் அழகப்பெரும",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "முன்னதாக இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "எதிர்ப்பு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "LOC"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}