{
  "newspaper_id": "ada-derana-lk",
  "url": "http://www.adaderana.lk/news/84675/landslide-warnings-for-8-districts-red-alert-for-kalutara-ratnapura",
  "time_ut": 1661967540,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Landslide warnings for 8 districts; ‘Red’ alert for Kalutara, Ratnapura",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Landslide warnings for 8 districts; ‘Red’ alert for Kalutara, Ratnapura",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "The National Building Research Organization today (Aug 31) issued landslide warnings for eight districts – Colombo, Galle, Kalutara, Kandy, Kegalle, Matale, Nuwara-Eliya and Ratnapura.",
        "Level 3 (Red) warning is effective in Kalutara and Ratnapura districts for a period of 24 hours until 5.30 am tomorrow (Sep 01).",
        "Since the rainfall within the past 24 hours has exceeded 150 mm, people living in the aforementioned areas have been urged to evacuate to safe locations to avoid the risk of landslides, slope failures, rock falls, cutting failures and ground subsidence if the showery condition persists.",
        "Meanwhile, Level 2 (Amber) warning for possible landslides was issued for the following areas:",
        "Level 1 (Yellow) warning is effective for the following areas:",
        "• Kegalle District – Yatiyantota, Dehiowita, Ruwanwella, Deraniyagala and Bulathkohupitiya"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "8",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "Kalutara",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "Ratnapura",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "The National Building Research Organization",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Galle",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kalutara, Kandy",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kegalle",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Matale",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ratnapura",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "3",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kalutara",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ratnapura",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "24 hours",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "5.30 am",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "tomorrow",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sep 01",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the past 24 hours",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "150",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "2",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "1",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Yatiyantota",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Dehiowita",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ruwanwella",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Deraniyagala",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Bulathkohupitiya",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "දිස්ත්‍රික්ක 8කට නායයෑම් අනතුරු ඇඟවීම්; කළුතර, රත්නපුරයට ‘රතු’ නිවේදනයක්",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "ජාතික ගොඩනැගිලි පර්යේෂණ සංවිධානය අද (අගෝස්තු 31) කොළඹ, ගාල්ල, කළුතර, මහනුවර, කෑගල්ල, මාතලේ, නුවරඑළිය සහ රත්නපුර යන දිස්ත්‍රික්ක 8 සඳහා නායයෑම් අනතුරු ඇඟවීම් නිකුත් කළේය.",
        "3 මට්ටමේ (රතු) අනතුරු ඇඟවීම හෙට (සැප් 01) අලුයම 5.30 දක්වා පැය 24ක කාලයක් කළුතර සහ රත්නපුර දිස්ත්‍රික්කවල ක්‍රියාත්මක වේ.",
        "ගත වූ පැය 24 තුළ වර්ෂාපතනය මිලිමීටර් 150 ඉක්ම වූ බැවින්, වර්ෂා තත්ත්වය තවදුරටත් පැවතියහොත් නායයෑම්, බෑවුම් කඩා වැටීම්, ගල් පෙරළීම්, කැපුම් කඩා වැටීම් සහ පොළව ගිලා බැසීමේ අවදානම වළක්වා ගැනීම සඳහා ඉහත ප්‍රදේශවල ජීවත් වන ජනතාව ආරක්ෂිත ස්ථාන කරා ඉවත් වන ලෙස ඉල්ලා සිටියි. .",
        "මේ අතර, පහත සඳහන් ප්‍රදේශ සඳහා නාය යාම් පිළිබඳ 2 මට්ටමේ (ඇම්බර්) අනතුරු ඇඟවීම් නිකුත් කරන ලදී.",
        "1 මට්ටමේ (කහ) අනතුරු ඇඟවීම පහත ප්‍රදේශ සඳහා ක්‍රියාත්මක වේ:",
        "• කෑගල්ල දිස්ත්‍රික්කය - යටියන්තොට, දෙහිඕවිට, රුවන්වැල්ල, දැරණියගල සහ බුලත්කොහුපිටිය"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "8",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "කළුතර",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "රත්නපුරය",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ජාතික ගොඩනැගිලි පර්යේෂණ සංවිධානය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගාල්ල",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "කළුතර, මහනුවර",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "කෑගල්ල",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මාතලේ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "රත්නපුරය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "3",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "කළුතර",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "රත්නපුරය",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "පැය 24",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "5.30 පෙ.ව",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "හෙට",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "සැප් 01",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "පසුගිය පැය 24 තුළ",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "150",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "2",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "1",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "යටියන්තොට",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "දෙහිඕවිට",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "රුවන්වැල්ල",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "දැරණියගල",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "බුලත්කොහුපිටිය",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "8 மாவட்டங்களுக்கு மண்சரிவு எச்சரிக்கை; களுத்துறை, இரத்தினபுரிக்கு ‘ரெட்’ அலர்ட்",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "கொழும்பு, காலி, களுத்துறை, கண்டி, கேகாலை, மாத்தளை, நுவரெலியா மற்றும் இரத்தினபுரி ஆகிய எட்டு மாவட்டங்களுக்கு தேசிய கட்டிட ஆராய்ச்சி நிறுவனம் இன்று (ஆகஸ்ட் 31) மண்சரிவு எச்சரிக்கையை விடுத்துள்ளது.",
        "களுத்துறை மற்றும் இரத்தினபுரி மாவட்டங்களில் 3ஆம் நிலை (சிவப்பு) எச்சரிக்கை நாளை (செப். 01) அதிகாலை 5.30 மணி வரை 24 மணித்தியாலங்களுக்கு அமுலில் இருக்கும்.",
        "கடந்த 24 மணித்தியாலங்களில் 150 மில்லி மீற்றர் மழைவீழ்ச்சி பதிவாகியுள்ளதால், நிலச்சரிவு, சரிவுகள், பாறை சரிவுகள், வெட்டுக்கள் மற்றும் மண் சரிவு போன்ற அபாயங்களைத் தவிர்ப்பதற்காக மேற்குறிப்பிட்ட பகுதிகளில் வசிக்கும் மக்கள் பாதுகாப்பான இடங்களுக்கு செல்லுமாறு அறிவுறுத்தப்பட்டுள்ளனர். .",
        "இதற்கிடையில், பின்வரும் பகுதிகளுக்கு நிலச்சரிவு ஏற்படுவதற்கான நிலை 2 (ஆம்பர்) எச்சரிக்கை விடுக்கப்பட்டது:",
        "நிலை 1 (மஞ்சள்) எச்சரிக்கை பின்வரும் பகுதிகளுக்கு பயனுள்ளதாக இருக்கும்:",
        "• கேகாலை மாவட்டம் – யட்டியந்தோட்டை, தெஹியோவிட்ட, ருவன்வெல்ல, தெரணியகல மற்றும் புலத்கொஹுபிட்டிய"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "8",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "களுத்துறை",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "இரத்தினபுரி",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "தேசிய கட்டிட ஆராய்ச்சி நிறுவனம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "காலி",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "களுத்துறை, கண்டி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "கேகாலை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "மாத்தளை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இரத்தினபுரி",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "3",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "களுத்துறை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இரத்தினபுரி",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "24 மணி நேரம்",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "காலை 5.30 மணி",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "நாளை",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "செப் 01",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "கடந்த 24 மணிநேரம்",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "150",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "2",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "1",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "யட்டியந்தோட்டை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "தெஹியோவிட்ட",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ருவன்வெல்ல",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "தெரணியகல",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "புலத்கொஹுபிட்டிய",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}