{
  "newspaper_id": "b-b-c-com-sinhala",
  "url": "https://www.bbc.com/sinhala/sri-lanka-62202964",
  "time_ut": 1658177198,
  "original_lang": "si",
  "original_title": "සජිත්-ඩලස් බෙදී තරග කරන්නේ නම්,රනිල් ජනපති වන බව ස්ථිරයි!",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "If Sajith-Dallas competes separately, it is certain that Ranil will be the President!",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "Currently, it has been announced that opposition leader Sajith Premadasa, Sri Lanka Podujana Peramuna member former minister Dallas Alahaperuma and National People's Force leader Anura Kumara Dissanayake will be contesting for the presidential election on July 20.",
        "Although the current Prime Minister, Acting President Ranil Wickremesinghe has not announced that he will contest the contest, it can be assumed that he will enter this battle as well.",
        "At the moment, everyone is expecting who will be the President for the remaining term of the resigned President Gotabhaya Rajapaksa.",
        "Sri Lanka Podujana Peramuna's candidate Ajith Rajapaksa, who obtained 109 votes in the secret ballot held in Parliament on May 17, for the election of the Deputy Speaker, got the position. Rohini Kaviratne, who was proposed by the opposition, won 78 votes. The number of rejected votes is 23.",
        "Prior to this, Ranjith Siyambalapitiya got 148 votes and Imtiaz Bakir Marker got 65 votes in the secret poll held on May 5th to elect a deputy. Three votes were rejected. On that day, eight Members of Parliament did not attend the voting to elect the Deputy Speaker.",
        "Thus it appears that Sri Lanka Podujana Peramuna has between 109 and 148 votes. But this time two candidates are competing from Sri Lanka Podujana Peramuna. They are former Minister Dallas Alahaperuma and Acting President and Prime Minister Ranil Wickremesinghe.",
        "A seasoned politician, Ranil Wickramasinghe was able to enter the Parliament this time as the only National List member of the United National Party. But Ranil Wickramasinghe continued to receive the support of the Sri Lanka Podujana Peramuna after the appointment of Ranil Wickramasinghe to the position left vacant by the resignation of Prime Minister Mahinda Rajapaksa to manage those problems due to the economic and political instability of the country.",
        "So far, a part of the Sri Lanka Podujana Peramuna has appeared to support Ranil Wickramasinghe, while another part will support Dallas Alahaperuma, political commentators say.",
        "Here, political commentators say that Ranil Wickremesinghe may get the support of some people of the Samagi Jana Balavega this time, just as he got the support of Harin Fernando and Manusha Nanayakkara of the Samagi Jana Balavega when he became the Prime Minister.",
        "If Sajith-Dallas is divided and competes, it is certain that Ranil will be the President.",
        "\"Many people say that if Sajith leaves and the Sajjab-led opposition shares the post of President and Prime Minister with Dulles, they will win the day. If Sajith is not President, he can solve the country's problems by 'making a national government' which the country hopes for. Otherwise, the opposition will put Sajith forward. ``If you don't have a head, you can show the drama ``Kanda Fight'','' political commentator and former governor Ranjith Keerthy Tennakoon told the BBC Sinhala Service.",
        "\"Dallas - Even if Sajith unites, Ranil Wickremesinghe cannot be defeated by the cold room experts of the opposition. Their argument is that 1/3 of the Tamil and Muslim members of the joint opposition will vote for Ranil and not for Dallas in a secret ballot.\"",
        "\"If both Sajith and Dallas contest, Ranil Wickremesinghe will be the top President,\" said Ranjith Keerthy Thennakone.",
        "\"Even though Ranil talked about driving, either the opposition has no real need for it! Otherwise, there is no possibility! There is no plan or program!\"",
        "Ranjith Keerthi Tennakoon says that Ranil Wickramasinghe will start this election campaign with the support of 73 votes, i.e. MPs whose house was burnt down.",
        "Political commentators say that if Sajith Premadasa and Dallas Alahaperuma come together, there is a possibility of defeating Ranil Wickremesinghe and if not, Ranil Wickremesinghe has a great possibility of becoming the President.",
        "But if Sajith Premadasa does not accept his nomination, there is a possibility of another candidate from Samagi Janbalawega being presented, according to political commentators.",
        "Rajith Keerthi Tennakoon says that the support of the Dravida National Alliance will be divided between Ranil Wickramasinghe and Dallas Alahaperuma.",
        "\"The two main anti-Ranil characters are MA Sumandhiran and R Shanakyan with Dallas.\"",
        "Meanwhile, political commentators say that the Sri Lanka Freedom Party and the Sri Lanka Muslim Congress have also split.",
        "The 6 Upland Tamil MPs in the opposition will also be divided between Ranil Wickramasinghe and Dallas Alahaperuma.",
        "\"Digambaram and Udayakumar of Nuwara Eliya in Sajith's 62 team are extremely close to Ranil than Dallas. Aravinda Kumar of Badulla is already with Ranil,\" said Ranjith Keerthy Thennakone.",
        "\"Mano, Velukumar and Radhakrishnan will stand with whatever decision Sajith makes. That is because they want parliaments from Colombo and Kandy to come in the next general election.\"",
        "\"It looks like the Thondamans will stay with the Sri Lankan Party. Digambaram - Thondaman will definitely go to two camps.\"",
        "\"Rishad Badurdeen, Ishaq Rahman, Taufiq, Faisal Qasim and Haris who broke away from Rauf Hakeem are now in the joint opposition. These four votes are not sure for Dallas.\"",
        "\"On the other hand, Rahman, Taufiq, Faisal and Harris don't have the same aura that Rauf Hakeem has with Ranil. Nor does the Vimal-Gammanpila camp have the same comfort as Ranil.\"",
        "\"Rishad Badurdeen was put in jail because of the pressure of Ratana Thero and Vimal's party. Will Rishad and the party forget the past when the secret police put a water bottle on his head and sleep on a piece of cardboard? The relationship between Ranil and Rishad is 20 years.\" Ranjith Keerthy Tennakoon added."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Sajith",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "Dallas",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "Ranil",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Sajith Premadasa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Podujana Peramuna",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Dallas Alahaperuma",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "National People's Force",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Anura Kumara Dissanayake",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "July 20",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Gotabhaya Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Podujana Peramuna's",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ajith Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "109",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "May 17",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Rohini Kaviratne",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "78",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "23",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Ranjith Siyambalapitiya",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "148",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Imtiaz Bakir Marker",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "65",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "May 5th",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Three",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "that day",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "eight",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Podujana Peramuna",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "between 109 and 148",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "two",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "Podujana Peramuna",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Dallas Alahaperuma",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickramasinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "National List",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the United National Party",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickramasinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "Podujana Peramuna",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickramasinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Mahinda Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "Podujana Peramuna",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickramasinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Dallas Alahaperuma",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Jana Balavega",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Harin Fernando",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Manusha Nanayakkara",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Jana Balavega",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sajith",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ranil",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sajith",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sajjab",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Dulles",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the day",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sajith",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sajith",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ranjith Keerthy",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the BBC Sinhala Service",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Dallas - Even",
            "label": "WORK_OF_ART"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sajith",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "1/3",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Tamil",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Muslim",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ranil",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Dallas",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sajith",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Dallas",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ranjith Keerthy Thennakone",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Ranil",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Ranjith Keerthi",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickramasinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "73",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Dallas",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Samagi",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the Dravida National Alliance",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickramasinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Dallas Alahaperuma",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "two",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "anti-Ranil",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Dallas",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the Sri Lanka Freedom Party",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Sri Lanka Muslim Congress",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "6",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickramasinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Dallas Alahaperuma",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Digambaram and Udayakumar of Nuwara Eliya",
            "label": "WORK_OF_ART"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sajith",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "62",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ranil",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Dallas",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Aravinda",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Badulla",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ranil",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ranjith Keerthy Thennakone",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Mano",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Velukumar",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Radhakrishnan",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sajith",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Colombo",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kandy",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Thondamans",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Sri Lankan Party",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "two",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Ishaq Rahman",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Taufiq",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Faisal Qasim",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Haris",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Rauf Hakeem",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "four",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Dallas",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Rahman",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Taufiq",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Faisal",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Harris",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Rauf Hakeem",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ranil",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ranil",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Ratana Thero",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Vimal",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Will Rishad",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ranil",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Rishad",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "20 years",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ranjith Keerthy Tennakoon",
            "label": "WORK_OF_ART"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "සජිත්-ඩලස් බෙදී තරග කරන්නේ නම්,රනිල් ජනපති වන බව ස්ථිරයි!",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "මේ වන විට ජූලි 20 වැනිදා පාර්ලිමේන්තුවේ පැවැත්වෙන ජනපති තේරීමේ තරගයට  විපක්ෂ නායක සජිත් ප්‍රේමදාස, ශ්‍රී ලංකා පොදුජන පෙරමුණු මන්ත්‍රී හිටපු අමාත්‍ය ඩලස් අලහපෙරුම සහ  ජාතික ජන බලවේගයේ නායක අනුර කුමාර දිසානායක  ඉදිරිපත් වන බවට ප්‍රකාශයට පත් කර ඇත.",
        "වර්තමාන අගමැති, වැඩබලන ජනපති රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ මේ වන තෙක් තමන් එම තරගයට ඉදිරිපත් වන බව ප්‍රකාශකර නැතත් ඔහුත් මෙම සටනට පිවිසේයැයි උපකල්පනය කල හැක.",
        "මේ වන විට සියලුදෙනා බලාපොරොත්තු වන්නේ ඉල්ලා අස්වූ ජනපති ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂගේ ධුරයේ ඉතිරි කාලවකවානුව සඳහා කවුරුන් ජනපති වේදැයි යන්නයි.",
        "නියෝජ්‍ය කතානායක තේරීම සඳහා  පසුගිය මැයි 17 දා පාර්ලිමේන්තුවේදී කළ රහස් ඡන්දය විමසීමේදී ඡන්ද 109ක් ලබාගත් ශ්‍රී ලංකා පොදුජන පෙරමුණේ අපේක්ෂක අජිත් රාජපක්ෂ එම ධූරයට පත්විය. එහිදී විපක්ෂය ඒ සඳහා යෝජනා කළ රෝහිණි කවිරත්නට ඡන්ද 78ක් හිමි වූවාය. ප්‍රතික්ෂේප වූ ඡන්ද සංඛ්‍යාව 23කි.",
        "මෙයට පෙර මැයි මස 05 වැනිදා පැවැත්වූ නියෝජ්‍යකතානයක තෝරා පත්කරගැනීමට පැවැත්වූ රහස් ඡන්ද විමසීමෙන් රංජිත් සියඹලාපිටිය ඡන්ද 148ක් ලබාගත් අතර, ඉමිතියාස් බාකීර් මාකර්ට හිමිවූයේ ඡන්ද 65කි. ඡන්ද තුනක් ප්‍රතික්ෂේප විය. එදින පාර්ලිමේන්තු මන්ත්‍රීවරුන් අටදෙනෙක් නියෝජ්‍ය කතානායකවරයා තෝරා පත් කර ගැනීමේ ඡන්ද විමසීමට පැමිණ සිටියේ නැත.",
        "මේ අනුව පෙනීයන්නේ ශ්‍රී ලංකා පොදුජන පෙරමුණට ඡන්ද 109ත් 148ත් අතර ප්‍රමාණයක් ඇති බවයි. එහෙත් මෙවර ශ්‍රී ලංකා පොදුජන පෙරමුණෙන් අපේක්ෂකයින් දෙදෙනකු තරග වදියි. ඒ හිටපු අමාත්‍ය ඩලස් අලහපෙරුම හා වැඩබලන ජනපති, අග්‍රාමාත්‍ය රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහයි.",
        "පරිනත දේශපාලනඥයකු වූ රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහට මෙවර පාර්ලිමෙතුවට පිවිසීමට හැකි වුයේ එක්සත් ජාතික පක්ෂයට හිමිවූ එකම ජාතික ලැයිස්තු මන්ත්‍රී ධුරයෙනි. එහෙත් රටේ පැනනැගුනු ආර්ථික හා දේශපාලන අස්ථාවරභාවය හේතුවෙන් එම ගැටළු කළමණාකරණය  කිරීමට අගමැති මහින්ද රාජපක්ෂගේ ඉල්ලා අස්වීමෙන් පුරප්පාඩු වූ එම ධුරයට රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ පත්කිරීමෙන් පසු ශ්‍රී ලංකා පොදුජන පෙරමුණේ සහාය දිගටම රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහට හිමි විය.",
        "මේ වන විට ශ්‍රී ලංකා පොදුජන පෙරමුණේ කොටසක් රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහට සහාය දක්වන බවට පෙනීගොස් ඇති අතර තවත් කොටසක් ඩලස් අලහපෙරුම සහාය දෙනු ඇතැයි දේශපාලන විචාරකයෝ පවසති.",
        "මෙහිදී දේශපාලන විචාරකයින් පවසන්නේ රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ අග්‍රාමාත්‍ය තනතුරට පත්වීමත් සමඟ  සමගි ජන බලවේගයේ හරීන් ප්‍රනාන්දු හා මනුෂ නානායක්කාරගේ සහාය  ලබගත්තාක් මෙන් මෙවරද  සමගි ජන බලවේගයේ යම් පිරිසකගේ සහාය ඔහුට හිමිවිය හැකි බවයි.",
        "සජිත් - ඩලස් බෙදී තරග කරන්නේ නම්, රනිල් ජනපති වන බව ස්ථිර ය.",
        "\"සජිත් ඉවත් වී, සජබ ප්‍රමුඛ විපක්ෂය ඩලස් සමඟ ජනපති අගමැති තනතුරු බෙදාගන්නේ නම්, ඔවුන් උඩින්ම දින දිනන්නේ යැයි බොහෝ දෙනා කියති. සජිත්ට ජනපති නැතිනම් අගමැති ලෙස රටම බලාපොරොත්තු වන 'ජාතික ආණ්ඩුවක් හදා' රටේ ප්‍රශ්න විසඳිය හැකිය. නැතිනම් විපක්ෂයට සජිත් ඉදිරියට දමා, 'ඔළුව නැතත් කඳ ෆයිට්' නාට්‍යය පෙන්විය හැකිය,\"යනුවෙන් දේශපාලන විචාරක හා හිටපු ආණ්ඩුකාර රංජිත් කීර්ති තෙන්නකෝන් බීබීසී සිංහල සේවයට පැවසීය.",
        "\"ඩලස් - සජිත් එක් වූවත් රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ පරාජය කළ නොහැකි බව විපක්ෂයේ සීත කාමර විශේෂඥයින්ගේ මතය වී ඇත. ඔවුන්ගේ තර්කය ඒකාබද්ධ විපක්ෂයේ 1/3ක් වන දෙමළ,මුස්ලිම් මන්ත්‍රීවරුන් රහස් ඡන්දයක දී රනිල් ට මිස ඩලස් ට ඡන්දය දෙන්නේ නැත' යන්නය.\"",
        "\"සජිත් - ඩලස් දෙදෙනාම තරග කරන්නේ නම්, රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ උඩින්ම ජනපති වනු ඇත,\" යනුවෙන්  රංජිත් කීර්ති තෙන්නකෝන් පැවසීය.",
        "\"රනිල් එළවන්නට කතා කළාට, එක්කෝ විපක්ෂයට එයට සැබෑ අවශ්‍යතාවයක් නැත!  නැතිනම්, හැකියාවක් නැත! සැලසුමක් හෝ වැඩ පිළිවෙලක් නම් ඇත්තේම නැත!\"",
        "රංජිත් කීර්ති තෙන්නකෝන් පවසන්නේ රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ මෙම ඡන්ද සටන පටන්ගන්නේ ඡන්ද 73ක් එනම් තම නිවස ගිනිගත් මන්ත්‍රීවරුන්ගේ සහාය අතැතිව බවයි.",
        "දේශපාලන විචාරකයින් පවසන්නේ සජිත් ප්‍රේමදාස සහ ඩලස්  අලහපෙරුම එක්වුවහොත් රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ පරාජය කිරීමේ හැකියාවක් ඇති බවත් එසේ නොවන්නේ නම් රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහට ජනපති වීමට විශාල හැකියාවක් ඇති බවයි.",
        "එහෙත් සජිත් ප්‍රේමදාස තම නාමයෝජනා බාරනොදෙන්නේනම් සමගි ජනබලවේගයෙන් වෙනත් අපේක්ෂකයකු ඉදිරිපත්වීමේ හැකියාවක් ද ඇති බව දේශපාලන විචාරක මතයයි.",
        "මෙහිදී ද්‍රවිඩ ජාතික සන්ධානයේ සහාය රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ හා ඩලස් අලහපෙරුම අතර බෙදෙනු ඇතැයි රජිත් කීර්ති තෙන්නකෝන් පවසයි.",
        "\"රනිල් විරෝධී ප්‍රධානම චරිත දෙක එම් ඒ සුමන්දිරන් හා ආර් ශානක්‍යන් ඩලස් සමඟ රැදෙයි.\"",
        "මේ අතර ශ්‍රී ලංකා නිදහස් පක්ෂය සහ ශ්‍රී ලංකා මුස්ලිම් කොංග්‍රසයද බෙදී ඇති බවට දේශපාලන විචාරකයෝ පවසති.",
        "විපක්ෂයේ උඩරට දෙමළ මන්ත්‍රීවරුන් 6 දෙනා ද රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ හා ඩලස් අලහපෙරුම අතර බෙදී යනු ඇත.",
        "\"සජිත්ගේ 62 කණ්ඩායමේ සිටින නුවරඑළියේ දිගම්බරම් සහ උදයකුමාර් ඩලස් ට වඩා රනිල්ට අතිශයින්ම සමීපය. බදුල්ලේ අරවින්ද කුමාර දැනටමත් රනිල් සමඟ ය,\" රංජිත් කීර්ති තෙන්නකෝන් පැවසීය.",
        "\"මනෝ, වේලුකුමාර් සහ රාධක්‍රිෂ්ණන් සජිත් ගේ කුමන තීරණයක් සමඟ හෝ රැදෙනු ඇත. ඒ ඊළඟ මහා මැතිවරණයේදී  කොළඹ සහ මහනුවරින් පාර්ලිමේන්තු එන්නට අවශ්‍ය නිසාය.\"",
        "\"තොන්ඩමන් ලා නවතින්නේ ශ්‍රීලනිප සමඟ බව බැලූ බැල්මට පෙනේ.  දිගම්බරම් - තොන්ඩමන් අනිවාර්යයෙන්ම කඳවුරු දෙකකට යනු ඇත.\"",
        "\"රිෂාඩ් බදුර්දීන්, රවුෆ් හකීම් ගෙන් කැඩී ගිය ඉෂාක් රහමන්, තවුෆීක්, ෆයිසාල් කාසිම් සහ හාරිස් දැන් ඒකාබද්ධ විපක්ෂයේ ය. මේ ඡන්ද හතර ඩලස් ට ස්ථිර නැත.\"",
        "\"අනෙක් අතට, රවුෆ් හකීම්ට රනිල් සමඟ  ඇති කුමන හෝ ආරෝවක් රහමන්, තවුෆික්, ෆයිසාල් හා හාරිස් ට රනිල් සමඟ නැත.  රනිල් තරම් සුවපහසුවක් විමල්-ගම්මන්පිල කඳවුරෙන් ලැබෙන්නේ ද නැත.\"",
        "\"රිෂාඩ් බදුර්දීන් හිරේ දැම්මේ රතන හිමි හා විමල් ගේ පක්ෂයේ  පීඩනය නිසාය. රහස් පොලීසියේ වතුර බෝතලයක් හිසට තබා, කාඩ්බෝඩ් කැබැල්ලක නිදාගන්න මග පෑදු අතීතය රිෂාඩ් සහ පක්ෂය අමතක කරයි ද?  රනිල් හා රිෂාඩ් අතර සම්බන්ධය වසර 20 කි.\" රංජිත් කීර්ති තෙන්නකෝන් වැඩිදුරටත් සඳහන් කළේය."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "සජිත්",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "ඩලස්",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "රනිල්",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "සජිත් ප්‍රේමදාස",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "පොදුජන පෙරමුණ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඩලස් අලහපෙරුම",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජාතික ජනතා බලවේගය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "අනුර කුමාර දිසානායක",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජූලි 20",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "පොදුජන පෙරමුණේ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "අජිත් රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "109",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "මැයි 17",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "රෝහිණී කවිරත්න",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "78",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "23",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "රංජිත් සියඹලාපිටිය",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "148",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉමිටියාස් බාකීර් මාකර්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "65",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "මැයි 5 වැනිදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "තුන්",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "එදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "අට",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "පොදුජන පෙරමුණ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "109 සහ 148 අතර",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "දෙක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "පොදුජන පෙරමුණ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඩලස් අලහපෙරුම",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජාතික ලැයිස්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "එක්සත් ජාතික පක්ෂය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "පොදුජන පෙරමුණ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "මහින්ද රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "පොදුජන පෙරමුණ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඩලස් අලහපෙරුම",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජන බලවේගය",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "හරීන් ප්‍රනාන්දු",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "මනූෂ නානායක්කාර",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජන බලවේගය",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "සජිත්",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "රනිල්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "සජිත්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "සජ්ජාබ්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඩලස්",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "දවස",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "සජිත්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "සජිත්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "රංජිත් කීර්ති",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "බීබීසී සිංහල සේවය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ඩලස් - පවා",
            "label": "WORK_OF_ART"
          },
          {
            "text": "සජිත්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "1/3",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "දෙමළ",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "මුස්ලිම්",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "රනිල්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඩලස්",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "සජිත්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඩලස්",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "රංජිත් කීර්ති තෙන්නකෝන්",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "රනිල්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "රංජිත් කීර්ති",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "73",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ඩලස්",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "සමගි",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ද්‍රවිඩ ජාතික සන්ධානය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඩලස් අලහපෙරුම",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "දෙක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "රනිල් විරෝධී",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඩලස්",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකා නිදහස් පක්ෂය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකා මුස්ලිම් කොංග්‍රසය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "6",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඩලස් අලහපෙරුම",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "දිගම්බරම් සහ නුවරඑළියේ උදයකුමාර්",
            "label": "WORK_OF_ART"
          },
          {
            "text": "සජිත්",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "62",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "රනිල්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඩලස්",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "අරවින්ද",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "බදුල්ල",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "රනිල්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "රංජිත් කීර්ති තෙන්නකෝන්",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "මනෝ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "වේලුකුමාර් ය",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "රාධක්‍රිෂ්ණන්",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "සජිත්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "කොළඹ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "මහනුවර",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "තොණ්ඩමන්ලා",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකා පක්ෂය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "දෙක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Ishaq Rahman",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "තවුෆික්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ෆයිසාල් කාසිම්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "හරිස්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "රවුෆ් හකීම්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "හතර",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඩලස්",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "රහ්මාන්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "තවුෆික්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ෆයිසාල්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "හැරිස්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "රවුෆ් හකීම්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "රනිල්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "රනිල්",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "රතන හාමුදුරුවෝ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "විමල්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "විල් රිෂාඩ්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "රනිල්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "රිෂාඩ්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "20 වසර",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "රංජිත් කීර්ති තෙන්නකෝන්",
            "label": "WORK_OF_ART"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "சஜித்-டலஸ் தனித்து போட்டியிட்டால் ரணில் ஜனாதிபதியாவது உறுதி!",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "எதிர்வரும் ஜூலை 20ஆம் திகதி நடைபெறவுள்ள ஜனாதிபதித் தேர்தலில் எதிர்க்கட்சித் தலைவர் சஜித் பிரேமதாச, ஸ்ரீலங்கா பொதுஜன பெரமுனவின் முன்னாள் அமைச்சர் டலஸ் அழகப்பெரும, தேசிய மக்கள் சக்தியின் தலைவர் அனுரகுமார திஸாநாயக்க ஆகியோர் போட்டியிடவுள்ளதாக தற்போது அறிவிக்கப்பட்டுள்ளது.",
        "தற்போதைய பிரதமரும், பதில் ஜனாதிபதியுமான ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க போட்டியிடப்போவதாக அறிவிக்காவிட்டாலும், இந்தப் போரிலும் களமிறங்குவார் என்றே கருத முடியும்.",
        "தற்போது ராஜினாமா செய்த ஜனாதிபதி கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ஷவின் எஞ்சிய காலத்துக்கு ஜனாதிபதி யார் என்பதை அனைவரும் எதிர்பார்த்துள்ளனர்.",
        "பிரதி சபாநாயகர் தெரிவுக்கான பாராளுமன்றத்தில் கடந்த மே மாதம் 17ஆம் திகதி நடைபெற்ற இரகசிய வாக்கெடுப்பில் 109 வாக்குகளைப் பெற்று ஸ்ரீலங்கா பொதுஜன பெரமுனவின் வேட்பாளர் அஜித் ராஜபக்ச பதவியைப் பெற்றார். எதிரணியால் முன்மொழியப்பட்ட ரோகினி கவிரத்ன 78 வாக்குகளைப் பெற்றார். நிராகரிக்கப்பட்ட வாக்குகளின் எண்ணிக்கை 23 ஆகும்.",
        "இதற்கு முன்னதாக கடந்த மே மாதம் 5ஆம் திகதி பிரதியமைச்சரை தெரிவுசெய்வதற்காக நடத்தப்பட்ட இரகசிய வாக்கெடுப்பில் ரஞ்சித் சியம்பலாபிட்டிய 148 வாக்குகளையும் இம்தியாஸ் பாக்கீர் மார்க்கர் 65 வாக்குகளையும் பெற்றனர். மூன்று வாக்குகள் நிராகரிக்கப்பட்டன. அன்றைய தினம் பிரதி சபாநாயகரை தெரிவு செய்வதற்கான வாக்கெடுப்பில் எட்டு பாராளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர்கள் கலந்து கொள்ளவில்லை.",
        "இதன்படி ஸ்ரீலங்கா பொதுஜன பெரமுன 109 முதல் 148 வரையிலான வாக்குகளைப் பெற்றுள்ளதாகத் தெரிகிறது. ஆனால் இம்முறை ஸ்ரீலங்கா பொதுஜன பெரமுன சார்பில் இரண்டு வேட்பாளர்கள் போட்டியிடுகின்றனர். அவர்கள் முன்னாள் அமைச்சர் டலஸ் அழகப்பெரும மற்றும் பதில் ஜனாதிபதியும் பிரதமருமான ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க ஆவார்கள்.",
        "ஒரு அனுபவமிக்க அரசியல்வாதியான ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க ஐக்கிய தேசியக் கட்சியின் ஒரே தேசியப்பட்டியல் உறுப்பினராக இம்முறை பாராளுமன்றம் செல்ல முடிந்தது. ஆனால், நாட்டின் பொருளாதார மற்றும் அரசியல் ஸ்திரமின்மை காரணமாக அந்த பிரச்சினைகளை நிர்வகிப்பதற்காக பிரதமர் மஹிந்த ராஜபக்ஷவின் இராஜினாமாவால் வெற்றிடமாக இருந்த பதவிக்கு ரணில் விக்ரமசிங்க நியமிக்கப்பட்டதன் பின்னர் ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க ஸ்ரீலங்கா பொதுஜன பெரமுனவின் ஆதரவை தொடர்ந்து பெற்று வந்தார்.",
        "இதுவரை ஸ்ரீலங்கா பொதுஜன பெரமுனவின் ஒரு பகுதியினர் ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்கவிற்கு ஆதரவளிப்பதாகவும், மற்றொரு பகுதியினர் டலஸ் அழகப்பெருமவிற்கு ஆதரவளிப்பதாகவும் அரசியல் விமர்சகர்கள் தெரிவிக்கின்றனர்.",
        "இங்கு ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க பிரதமராக பதவியேற்ற போது ஹரீன் பெர்னாண்டோ மற்றும் சமகி ஜன பலவேகவின் மனுஷ நாணயக்கார ஆகியோரின் ஆதரவைப் பெற்றதைப் போன்று இம்முறையும் ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்கவுக்கு சமகி ஜன பலவேகவின் சிலரின் ஆதரவு கிடைக்கலாம் என அரசியல் விமர்சகர்கள் தெரிவிக்கின்றனர்.",
        "சஜித்-டலஸ் பிரிந்து போட்டியிட்டால் ரணில் ஜனாதிபதி என்பது உறுதி.",
        "\"சஜித் வெளியேறி சஜாப் தலைமையிலான எதிர்க்கட்சிகள் ஜனாதிபதி மற்றும் பிரதமர் பதவியை டல்லஸுடன் பகிர்ந்து கொண்டால் அன்றைய தினம் வெற்றியடைவார்கள் என பலர் கூறுகின்றனர். சஜித் ஜனாதிபதியாகவில்லை என்றால் 'தேசிய அரசாங்கத்தை உருவாக்கி' நாட்டின் பிரச்சினைகளை தீர்க்க முடியும். நாடு எதிர்பார்க்கும் ஒன்று.இல்லையெனில் எதிர்க்கட்சிகள் சஜித்தை முன்னிறுத்துவார்கள்.உங்களுக்கு தலை இல்லையென்றால் கந்த சண்டை நாடகத்தை காட்டலாம் என அரசியல் விமர்சகரும் முன்னாள் ஆளுநருமான ரஞ்சித் கீர்த்தி தென்னகோன் தெரிவித்துள்ளார். பிபிசி சிங்கள சேவை.",
        "“டலஸ் – சஜித் இணைந்தாலும் ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்கவை எதிர்கட்சியின் குளிர்சாதன நிபுணர்களால் தோற்கடிக்க முடியாது, கூட்டு எதிரணியின் 1/3 தமிழ், முஸ்லிம் உறுப்பினர்கள் இரகசியமாக டலசுக்கு வாக்களிக்காமல் ரணிலுக்கு வாக்களிப்பார்கள் என்பதே அவர்களின் வாதம். வாக்குச்சீட்டு.\"",
        "சஜித் மற்றும் டலஸ் இருவரும் போட்டியிட்டால் ரணில் விக்ரமசிங்கே அதிபராக இருப்பார் என ரஞ்சித் கீர்த்தி தென்னகோன் தெரிவித்துள்ளார்.",
        "\"ரணில் ஓட்டுப் பற்றிப் பேசினாலும், ஒன்று எதிர்க்கட்சிகளுக்கு உண்மையான தேவை இல்லை! இல்லையேல் சாத்தியம் இல்லை! திட்டமும் இல்லை, வேலைத்திட்டமும் இல்லை!\"",
        "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க இந்த தேர்தல் பிரச்சாரத்தை 73 வாக்குகள் அதாவது வீடு எரிக்கப்பட்ட பாராளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர்களின் ஆதரவுடன் ஆரம்பிக்கவுள்ளதாக ரஞ்சித் கீர்த்தி தென்னகோன் தெரிவித்துள்ளார்.",
        "சஜித் பிரேமதாசவும், டலஸ் அழகப்பெருமவும் ஒன்றிணைந்தால் ரணில் விக்ரமசிங்கவை தோற்கடிக்க வாய்ப்பு இருப்பதாகவும், இல்லை என்றால் ரணில் விக்ரமசிங்க ஜனாதிபதியாக வருவதற்கான வாய்ப்புகள் அதிகம் எனவும் அரசியல் விமர்சகர்கள் தெரிவிக்கின்றனர்.",
        "ஆனால் சஜித் பிரேமதாச தனது வேட்புமனுவை ஏற்கவில்லை என்றால், சமகி ஜன்பலவேகவின் மற்றொரு வேட்பாளர் முன்வைக்கப்பட வாய்ப்பு இருப்பதாக அரசியல் விமர்சகர்கள் தெரிவிக்கின்றனர்.",
        "திராவிடத் தேசியக் கூட்டமைப்பின் ஆதரவு ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்கவுக்கும் டலஸ் அழகப்பெருமவுக்கும் இடையில் பிரிக்கப்படும் என ரஜித் கீர்த்தி தென்னகோன் தெரிவித்துள்ளார்.",
        "\"ரணிலுக்கு எதிரான இரண்டு முக்கிய கதாபாத்திரங்கள் எம்.ஏ.சுமந்திரன் மற்றும் டலஸுடன் ஆர். ஷனாக்யன்.\"",
        "இதேவேளை, ஸ்ரீலங்கா சுதந்திரக் கட்சி மற்றும் ஸ்ரீலங்கா முஸ்லிம் காங்கிரஸ் ஆகிய கட்சிகளும் பிளவுபட்டுள்ளதாக அரசியல் விமர்சகர்கள் தெரிவிக்கின்றனர்.",
        "எதிர்க்கட்சியில் உள்ள 6 மலையக தமிழ் எம்.பி.க்களும் ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க மற்றும் டலஸ் அழகப்பெரும ஆகியோருக்கு இடையில் பிளவுபடுவார்கள்.",
        "சஜித்தின் 62 அணியில் உள்ள நுவரெலியாவைச் சேர்ந்த திகாம்பரம் மற்றும் உதயகுமார் ஆகியோர் டலஸை விட ரணிலுக்கு மிகவும் நெருக்கமானவர்கள். பதுளையின் அரவிந்த குமார் ஏற்கனவே ரணிலுடன் இருக்கிறார் என ரஞ்சித் கீர்த்தி தென்னகோன் தெரிவித்துள்ளார்.",
        "\"சஜித் எந்த முடிவு எடுத்தாலும் மனோவும், வேலுகுமாரும், ராதாகிருஷ்ணனும் துணை நிற்பார்கள். அடுத்த பொதுத் தேர்தலில் கொழும்பிலிருந்தும் கண்டியிலிருந்தும் நாடாளுமன்றங்கள் வர வேண்டும் என்பதே அவர்களின் விருப்பம்.\"",
        "\"தொண்டமான்கள் இலங்கைக் கட்சியுடன்தான் இருப்பார்கள் போலிருக்கிறது. திகாம்பரம் - தொண்டமான் இரண்டு முகாம்களுக்கு நிச்சயம் செல்வார்.\"",
        "\"ரவூப் ஹக்கீமிடம் இருந்து பிரிந்து சென்ற ரிஷாத் பதுர்தீன், இஷாக் ரஹ்மான், தௌபீக், பைசல் காசிம், ஹரீஸ் ஆகியோர் தற்போது கூட்டு எதிரணியில் உள்ளனர். இந்த நான்கு வாக்குகளும் டலஸுக்கு நிச்சயம் இல்லை.\"",
        "\"மறுபுறம் ரவூப் ஹக்கீமுக்கு ரணிலிடம் இருக்கும் அரவணைப்பு ரஹ்மான், தௌபீக், பைசல், ஹாரிஸ் ஆகியோருக்கு இல்லை. ரணிலுக்கு இருக்கும் ஆறுதல் விமல்-கம்மன்பில முகாமுக்கும் இல்லை.\"",
        "“ரதன தேரர் மற்றும் விமல் தரப்பு அழுத்தம் காரணமாக ரிஷாத் பதுர்தீன் சிறையில் அடைக்கப்பட்டார். இரகசியப் பொலிஸார் தண்ணீர் போத்தலைத் தலையில் வைத்து அட்டைத் துண்டில் உறங்கிய கடந்த காலத்தை ரிஷாத் கட்சியும் மறக்குமா? ரணிலுக்கும் இடையிலான உறவு ரிஷாத்துக்கு 20 வயது. ரஞ்சித் கீர்த்தி தென்னகோன் மேலும் தெரிவித்தார்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "சஜித்",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "டல்லாஸ்",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "ரணில்",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "சஜித் பிரேமதாச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "பொதுஜன பெரமுன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "டலஸ் அழகபெரும",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "தேசிய மக்கள் படை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "அனுரகுமார திஸாநாயக்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜூலை 20",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "கோத்தபாய ராஜபக்ச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பொதுஜன பெரமுனவின்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "அஜித் ராஜபக்ச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "109",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "மே 17",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரோகினி கவிரத்ன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "78",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "23",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ரஞ்சித் சியம்பலாபிட்டிய",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "148",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "இம்தியாஸ் பக்கீர் மார்க்கர்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "65",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "மே 5ம் தேதி",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "மூன்று",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "அந்த நாள்",
