{
  "newspaper_id": "ada-derana-lk",
  "url": "http://www.adaderana.lk/news/83568/pope-tells-leaders-of-sri-lanka-not-to-ignore-needs-of-the-people",
  "time_ut": 1657479720,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Pope tells leaders of Sri Lanka not to ignore needs of the people",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Pope tells leaders of Sri Lanka not to ignore needs of the people",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "I unite myself to the sorrow of the people of Sri Lanka who continue to suffer the effects of political and economic instability. Together with the country's Bishops, I renew my appeal for peace and I implore those who have authority not to ignore the cry of the poor.— Pope Francis (@Pontifex) July 10, 2022",
        "VATICAN CITY, July 10 (Reuters) - Pope Francis on Sunday told the leaders of Sri Lanka “not to ignore the cry of the poor and the needs of the people,” and appealed for peace in the Asian country.",
        "Frustration with the economic crisis boiled over on Saturday in Sri Lanka, when a huge crowd of protesters stormed the presidential palace and forced the president to agree to resign.",
        "Speaking from St. Peter’s square for his Sunday Angelus message, the Pope expressed solidarity with the people of Sri Lanka who he said “continue to suffer from political and economic instability”.",
        "“Together with the bishops of the country, I renew my appeal for peace,” the Pope said.",
        "In his message Francis also mentioned Libya, urging “constructive dialogue and national reconciliation” in the northern African country and saying the international community can help in this effort."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Pope",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "Sri Lanka",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Bishops",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Pope Francis",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "July 10, 2022",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "VATICAN CITY",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "July 10",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Reuters",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Francis",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sunday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Asian",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Saturday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "St. Peter’s",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sunday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "Francis",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Libya",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "African",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "ජනතාවගේ අවශ්‍යතා නොසලකා හරින්න එපා යැයි පාප් වහන්සේ ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ නායකයින්ට පවසයි",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "දේශපාලන හා ආර්ථික අස්ථාවරත්වයේ ප්‍රතිවිපාක අඛණ්ඩව විඳිමින් සිටින ශ්‍රී ලාංකීය ජනතාවගේ ශෝකය වෙනුවෙන් මම එක් වෙමි. රටේ බිෂොප්වරුන් සමඟ එක්ව, මම සාමය සඳහා මගේ ආයාචනය අලුත් කරන අතර දුප්පතුන්ගේ කෑගැසීම නොසලකා නොහරින ලෙස මම බලය ඇති අයගෙන් අයැද සිටිමි.— ෆ්‍රැන්සිස් පාප් වහන්සේ (@Pontifex) 2022 ජූලි 10",
        "වතිකානුව, ජූලි 10 (රොයිටර්) - ෆ්‍රැන්සිස් පාප් වහන්සේ ඉරිදා ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ නායකයින්ට “දුප්පතුන්ගේ කෑගැසීම සහ ජනතාවගේ අවශ්‍යතා නොසලකා නොහරින ලෙස” පැවසූ අතර ආසියානු රට තුළ සාමය සඳහා ආයාචනා කළහ.",
        "සෙනසුරාදා ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ ආර්ථික අර්බුදය පිළිබඳ කලකිරීම උතුරා ගිය අතර, විරෝධතාකරුවන් විශාල පිරිසක් ජනාධිපති මන්දිරයට කඩා වැදී ජනාධිපතිවරයාට ඉල්ලා අස්වීමට එකඟ වන ලෙස බල කළහ.",
        "සිය ඉරිදා ඇන්ජලස් පණිවිඩය සඳහා ශාන්ත පීතර චතුරශ්‍රයේ සිට අදහස් දක්වමින් පාප් වහන්සේ “දේශපාලන හා ආර්ථික අස්ථාවරත්වයෙන් දිගටම පීඩා විඳින්න” යැයි පැවසූ ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ ජනතාවට සහයෝගීතාව පළ කළහ.",
        "\"රටේ රදගුරුවරුන් සමඟ එක්ව, මම සාමය සඳහා මගේ ආයාචනය අලුත් කරමි,\" පාප් වහන්සේ පැවසීය.",
        "ෆ්‍රැන්සිස් සිය පණිවිඩයේ ලිබියාව ගැන ද සඳහන් කරමින්, උතුරු අප්‍රිකානු රට තුළ “නිර්මාණාත්මක සංවාදයක් සහ ජාතික ප්‍රතිසන්ධානයක්” ඉල්ලා සිටින අතර ජාත්‍යන්තර ප්‍රජාවට මෙම ප්‍රයත්නයට උදව් කළ හැකි බව පැවසීය."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "පාප් වහන්සේ",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "බිෂොප්වරු",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ෆ්රැන්සිස් පාප් වහන්සේ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජූලි 10, 2022",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "වතිකානු නගරය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජූලි 10",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "රොයිටර්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ෆ්රැන්සිස්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉරිදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ආසියානු",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "සෙනසුරාදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශාන්ත පීතර",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉරිදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "ෆ්රැන්සිස්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ලිබියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "අප්රිකානු",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "மக்களின் தேவைகளைப் புறக்கணிக்க வேண்டாம் என்று இலங்கைத் தலைவர்களுக்கு பாப்பரசர் கூறுகிறார்",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "அரசியல் மற்றும் பொருளாதார ஸ்திரமின்மையால் தொடர்ந்தும் பாதிக்கப்பட்டு வரும் இலங்கை மக்களின் துக்கத்தில் என்னை இணைத்துக் கொள்கிறேன். நாட்டின் ஆயர்களுடன் சேர்ந்து, அமைதிக்கான எனது வேண்டுகோளை நான் புதுப்பிக்கிறேன், மேலும் ஏழைகளின் அழுகையைப் புறக்கணிக்க வேண்டாம் என்று அதிகாரம் உள்ளவர்களைக் கேட்டுக்கொள்கிறேன்.— போப் பிரான்சிஸ் (@Pontifex) ஜூலை 10, 2022",
        "வத்திக்கான் சிட்டி, ஜூலை 10 (ராய்ட்டர்ஸ்) - \"ஏழைகளின் அழுகையையும் மக்களின் தேவைகளையும் புறக்கணிக்காதீர்கள்\" என்று இலங்கைத் தலைவர்களிடம் ஞாயிற்றுக்கிழமை தெரிவித்த போப் பிரான்சிஸ், ஆசிய நாட்டில் அமைதிக்காக வேண்டுகோள் விடுத்தார்.",
        "இலங்கையில் சனிக்கிழமையன்று பொருளாதார நெருக்கடியின் விரக்தி கொதித்தது, ஆர்ப்பாட்டக்காரர்களின் பெரும் கூட்டம் ஜனாதிபதி மாளிகையை முற்றுகையிட்டு, ஜனாதிபதியை ராஜினாமா செய்ய ஒப்புக்கொள்ளும்படி கட்டாயப்படுத்தியது.",
        "புனித பீட்டர் சதுக்கத்தில் இருந்து தனது ஞாயிறு ஏஞ்சலஸ் செய்திக்காக உரையாற்றிய பாப்பரசர், \"அரசியல் மற்றும் பொருளாதார ஸ்திரமின்மையால் தொடர்ந்து பாதிக்கப்படுங்கள்\" என்று கூறிய இலங்கை மக்களுக்கு ஒருமைப்பாட்டை தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "\"நாட்டின் ஆயர்களுடன் சேர்ந்து, அமைதிக்கான எனது வேண்டுகோளை நான் புதுப்பிக்கிறேன்\" என்று போப் கூறினார்.",
        "பிரான்சிஸ் தனது செய்தியில் லிபியாவையும் குறிப்பிட்டு, வட ஆபிரிக்க நாட்டில் \"ஆக்கபூர்வமான உரையாடல் மற்றும் தேசிய நல்லிணக்கத்தை\" வலியுறுத்தினார் மற்றும் இந்த முயற்சியில் சர்வதேச சமூகம் உதவ முடியும் என்று கூறினார்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "போப்",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "இலங்கை",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆயர்கள்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "போப் பிரான்சிஸ்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜூலை 10, 2022",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "வாடிகன் நகரம்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜூலை 10",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ராய்ட்டர்ஸ்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "பிரான்சிஸ்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஞாயிற்றுக்கிழமை",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆசிய",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "சனிக்கிழமை",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "செயின்ட் பீட்டர்ஸ்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஞாயிற்றுக்கிழமை",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "பிரான்சிஸ்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "லிபியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆப்பிரிக்க",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}