{
  "newspaper_id": "virakesari-lk",
  "url": "http://www.virakesari.lk/article/132328",
  "time_ut": 1658899278,
  "original_lang": "ta",
  "original_title": "தமிழகத்திற்கு மேலும் 6 பேர் அகதிகளாக சென்றுள்ளனர்",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "6 more people have gone to Tamil Nadu as refugees",
      "author": "T. Saranya",
      "body_lines": [
        "06 people from Jaffna and Kilinochchi district have gone to Tamil Nadu by sea and claimed refugee status.",
        "06 people including 5 people belonging to the same family living in Kilinochchi and one from Jaffna were taken away early on Wednesday morning at a place called Kampipad near Dhanushkodi in Tamil Nadu.",
        "The Coast Guard got information about it and rescued them, detained them at Mandapam Police Station and are conducting investigations.",
        "During investigations, they said that they had given the boat for 1 lakh 50 thousand rupees.",
        "Meanwhile, due to the severe economic downturn in Sri Lanka, the price of essential commodities such as rice, pulses and wheat has increased. Similarly, the prices of diesel and petrol have also increased significantly.",
        "One has to stand in line for 4 days to buy 2 liters of kerosene, continuous power cuts, shortage of medicine in government hospitals.",
        "Also, a bag of cement is being sold at 3,500 rupees, so the construction industry has been affected and they have no way to live because they cannot go to wage work.",
        "It is noteworthy that 129 Sri Lankan Tamils ​​have gone to Tamil Nadu as refugees from Sri Lanka since March 22nd till date due to economic crisis."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "6",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "Tamil Nadu",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "06",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Jaffna",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kilinochchi",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Tamil Nadu",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "06",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "5",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kilinochchi",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Jaffna",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Wednesday morning",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kampipad",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Dhanushkodi",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Tamil Nadu",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "The Coast Guard",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Mandapam Police Station",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "50 thousand",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "4 days",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "2",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "3,500",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "129",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lankan",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "Tamil Nadu",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "March 22nd",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "තවත් පුද්ගලයින් 6 දෙනෙකු සරණාගතයින් ලෙස තමිල්නාඩුවට ගොස් තිබෙනවා",
      "author": "T. Saranya",
      "body_lines": [
        "යාපනය සහ කිලිනොච්චි දිස්ත්‍රික්කවල පුද්ගලයන් 06 දෙනෙකු මුහුදු මාර්ගයෙන් තමිල්නාඩුවට ගොස් සරණාගත තත්ත්වය ඉල්ලා ඇත.",
        "කිලිනොච්චියේ පදිංචි එකම පවුලේ 5 දෙනෙකු සහ යාපනයේ එක් අයෙකු ඇතුළු පුද්ගලයින් 06 දෙනෙකු තමිල්නාඩුවේ ධනුෂ්කොඩි අසල කැම්පිපාඩ් නම් ස්ථානයේදී බදාදා අලුයම රැගෙන ගොස් තිබෙනවා.",
        "වෙරළාරක්ෂක දෙපාර්තමේන්තුවට ඒ පිළිබඳ තොරතුරක් ලැබී ඔවුන් බේරාගෙන මණ්ඩපම් පොලිස් ස්ථානයේ රඳවා පරීක්ෂණ පවත්වයි.",
        "පරීක්‍ෂණවලදී ඔවුන් පැවසුවේ බෝට්ටුව රුපියල් එක්‌ලක්ෂ පනස්‌දහසකට ලබාදුන් බවයි.",
        "මේ අතර ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ පවතින දැඩි ආර්ථික පසුබෑම හේතුවෙන් සහල්, පරිප්පු, තිරිඟු වැනි අත්‍යවශ්‍ය භාණ්ඩවල මිල ඉහළ ගොස් තිබේ. එසේම ඩීසල් සහ පෙට්‍රල් මිලද විශාල ලෙස ඉහළ ගොස් තිබේ.",
        "භූමිතෙල් ලීටර් 2ක් ගන්න එකාට දවස් 4ක් පෝලිමේ ඉන්න වෙනවා, එක දිගට විදුලිය කප්පාදුව, රජයේ රෝහල්වල බෙහෙත් හිඟය.",
        "එමෙන්ම සිමෙන්ති කොට්ටයක් රුපියල් 3500ට අලෙවි කරන නිසා ඉදිකිරීම් ක්ෂේත්‍රයට බලපෑම් එල්ල වී ඇති අතර කුලී වැඩට යාමට නොහැකිව ජීවත්වීමට මාර්ගයක් නොමැතිව සිටිනවා.",
        "ආර්ථික අර්බුදය හේතුවෙන් මාර්තු 22 වැනිදා සිට මේ දක්වා ශ්‍රී ලාංකික දෙමළ ජාතිකයන් 129 දෙනෙකු ශ්‍රී ලංකාවෙන් සරණාගතයින් ලෙස තමිල්නාඩුවට ගොස් ඇති බව සඳහන්."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "6",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "තමිල්නාඩුව",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "06",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "යාපනය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "කිලිනොච්චි",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "තමිල්නාඩුව",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "06",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "5",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "කිලිනොච්චි",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "යාපනය",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "බදාදා උදෑසන",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "කැම්පිපාඩ්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ධනුෂ්කොඩි",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "තමිල්නාඩුව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "වෙරළාරක්ෂක බලකාය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "මණ්ඩපම් පොලිස් ස්ථානය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "50 දහසක්",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "දින 4 යි",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "2",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "3,500 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "129",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලාංකික",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "තමිල්නාඩුව",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මාර්තු 22 වැනිදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "தமிழகத்திற்கு மேலும் 6 பேர் அகதிகளாக சென்றுள்ளனர்",
      "author": "T. Saranya",
      "body_lines": [
        "யாழ்ப்பாணம் மற்றும் கிளிநொச்சி மாவட்டத்தை சேர்ந்த 06 பேர் கடல் வழியாக தமிழகத்திற்கு சென்று அகதி அந்தஸ்து கோரியுள்ளனர்.",
        "தமிழகம் தனுஷ்கோடிக்கு அருகில் உள்ள கம்பிப்பாடு எனும் இடத்தில் புதன்கிழமை அதிகாலை கிளிநொச்சியில் வசித்து வந்த ஒரே குடும்பத்தை சேர்ந்த 5 பேரும், யாழ்ப்பாணத்தை சேர்ந்த ஒருவருமாக 06பேர் கொண்டு சென்று விடப்பட்டுள்ளனர்.",
        "அது தொடர்பில் தகவல் அறிந்த கடலோர காவல் படை அவர்களை மீட்டு, மண்டபம் காவல் நிலையத்தில் தடுத்து வைத்து விசாரணைகளை முன்னெடுத்து வருகின்றனர்.",
        "விசாரணைகளின் போது, தாம் படகு ஒரு இலட்சத்து 50 ஆயிரம் ரூபாய் கொடுத்து வந்ததாக தெரிவித்தனர்.",
        "அதேவேளை இலங்கையில் ஏற்பட்டுள்ள கடுமையான பொருளாதார வீழ்ச்சியின் காரணமாக அத்தியவாசிய பொருட்களான அரிசி, பருப்பு, கோதுமை விலை அதிகரித்தள்ளது. அதே போல் டீசல் மற்றம் பெற்றோல் விலையும் வெகுவாக உயர்ந்துள்ளது.",
        "2 லிட்டர் மண்ணெய் வாங்க 4 நாட்கள் வரிசையில் நிற்கவேண்டியுள்ளது, தொடர் மின்வெட்டு, அரசு வைத்தியசாலைகளில் மருந்து தட்டுபாடு உள்ளது.",
        "மேலும் ஒரு மூட்டை  சீமெந்து  3,500 ரூபாய்க்கு விற்பனை செய்யப்படுவதால் கட்டுமான தொழில் பாதிக்கப்பட்டு கூலி வேலைக்கு செல்ல முடியாததால் வாழ வழியின்றி வந்ததாக தெரிவித்துள்ளனர்.",
        "பொருளாதார நெருக்கடியை காரணம் காட்டி, கடந்த மார்ச் மாதம் 22 ஆம் திகதி முதல் இன்று வரை இலங்கையில் இருந்து 129 இலங்கை தமிழர்கள் அகதிகளாக தமிழகம் சென்றுள்ளமை குறிப்பிடத்தக்கது."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "6",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "தமிழ்நாடு",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "06",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "யாழ்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "கிளிநொச்சி",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "தமிழ்நாடு",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "06",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "5",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "கிளிநொச்சி",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "யாழ்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "புதன்கிழமை காலை",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "கம்பிபாட்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "தனுஷ்கோடி",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "தமிழ்நாடு",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "கடலோர காவல்படை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "மண்டபம் காவல் நிலையம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "50 ஆயிரம்",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "4 நாட்கள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "2",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "3,500",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "129",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "தமிழ்நாடு",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "மார்ச் 22",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}