{
  "newspaper_id": "lankadeepa-lk",
  "url": "https://www.lankadeepa.lk/latest_news/රෑ-බතත්-ජනපති-මැදුරේ-සැකසේ/1-616133",
  "time_ut": 1657371915,
  "original_lang": "si",
  "original_title": "රෑ බතත් ජනපති මැදුරේ සැකසේ",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "At night, rice is prepared in the presidential palace",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "Photographs are being shared on the Internet showing that the fighters who took over Fort President House are preparing to cook rice at night after playing water sports in the swimming pool of the President House.",
        "The activists who entered the presidential palace were also seen walking in the rooms and sitting in comfortable seats making tea and drinking.",
        "Some people climbed onto the roof of the President's House and waved national flags and cheered.",
        "The security guards guarding the Presidential Palace were also seen leaving the buses this afternoon. Later, the activists also held a press conference at the President's House. They asked the people not to damage any public property."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "night",
          "label": "TIME"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Fort",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "House",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "night",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "House",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "House",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the Presidential Palace",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "this afternoon",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "House",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "රෑ බතත් ජනපති මැදුරේ සැකසේ",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "කොටුව ජනාධිපති මන්දිරය අත්පත් කරගත් අරගලකරුවන් ජනාධිපති මන්දිරයේ පිහිනුම් තටාකයේ පිහිනා ජල ක්‍රීඩා කිරීමෙන් අනතුරුව දැන් රෑ බත උයන්නට සූදානම් වන අයුරු අන්තර්ජලයේ  ඡායාරූප හුවමාරු වෙයි.",
        "ජනාධිපති මන්දිරයට ඇතුළු වූ අරගල කරුවන් එහි කාමර වල ද ඇවිදිමින් සුව පහසු ආසන වල අසුන් ගනිමින් තේ හදාගෙන බොමින් සිටින අයුරු දැකගත හැකි විය.",
        "ඇතැම්හු ජනාධිපති මන්දිරයේ වහලයට නැඟ ජාතික කොඩි වනමින් ප්‍රීති ඝෝෂා කළහ.",
        "ජනාධිපති මන්දිරයේ රැකවල්ලා සිටි ආරක්ෂක භටයන් ද අද පස්වරුවේ බස් රථ වලින් ඉවත්ව යන අයුරු දැකගත හැකි විය. අනතුරුව අරගල කරුවෝ ජනාධිපති මන්දිරයේ දී මාධ්‍ය හමුවක් ද පැවැත්වූහ. එහිදී ඔවුන් ජනතාවගෙන් ඉල්ලා සිටියේ ජනතා දේපොළ කිසිවකට හානි නොකරන ලෙසයි."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "රෑ",
          "label": "TIME"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "බලකොටුව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "නිවස",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "රෑ",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "නිවස",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "නිවස",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ජනාධිපති මන්දිරය",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "අද පස්වරුවේ",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "නිවස",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "இரவு ஜனாதிபதி மாளிகையில் சாதம் தயாரிக்கப்படுகிறது",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "கோட்டை ஜனாதிபதி மாளிகையை கைப்பற்றிய போராளிகள் ஜனாதிபதி மாளிகையின் நீச்சல் தடாகத்தில் நீர் விளையாட்டு விளையாடி இரவு சோறு சமைக்க தயாராகி வருவதாக இணையத்தில் புகைப்படங்கள் பகிரப்பட்டு வருகின்றன.",
        "ஜனாதிபதி மாளிகைக்குள் நுழைந்த ஆர்வலர்கள் அறைகளில் நடந்து சென்று வசதியான இருக்கைகளில் அமர்ந்து தேநீர் அருந்திக் கொண்டிருந்தனர்.",
        "சிலர் ஜனாதிபதி மாளிகையின் மேற்கூரையில் ஏறி தேசிய கொடிகளை அசைத்து ஆரவாரம் செய்தனர்.",
        "இன்று பிற்பகல் ஜனாதிபதி மாளிகையில் பாதுகாப்பு பணியில் ஈடுபட்டிருந்த பாதுகாவலர்களும் பஸ்களை விட்டு வெளியேறினர். பின்னர், ஜனாதிபதி மாளிகையில் செயற்பாட்டாளர்கள் செய்தியாளர் சந்திப்பையும் நடத்தினர். பொதுச் சொத்துக்களுக்கு சேதம் விளைவிக்க வேண்டாம் என மக்களை கேட்டுக் கொண்டனர்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "இரவு",
          "label": "TIME"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "கோட்டை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "வீடு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இரவு",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "வீடு",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "வீடு",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஜனாதிபதி மாளிகை",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று மதியம்",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "வீடு",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}