{
  "newspaper_id": "ada-lk",
  "url": "https://www.ada.lk/breaking_news/ශ්‍රී-ලාංකිකයන්ට-ජපානයේ-කෘෂිකර්මාන්තයේ-දොරත්-ඇරෙයි/11-395717",
  "time_ut": 1658732952,
  "original_lang": "si",
  "original_title": "ශ්‍රී ලාංකිකයන්ට ජපානයේ කෘෂිකර්මාන්තයේ දොරත් ඇරෙයි",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "The door of agriculture in Japan is also open to Sri Lankans",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "The Foreign Employment Bureau of Sri Lanka states that the Japanese government has agreed to provide employment opportunities to Sri Lankan workers in the agriculture sector in addition to the jobs in the nursing and food and beverage services sectors that Japan has provided to Sri Lanka under the Special Skilled Employment Program.",
        "Accordingly, more Sri Lankan workers have been given the opportunity to be directed to jobs in the agricultural sector under the employment program with special skills.",
        "With the intervention of the Embassy of Sri Lanka in Japan and other institutions, approval has been obtained for employment opportunities in this agricultural sector, and the Embassy has played a special role in this.",
        "Jobs in the agricultural sector require professional qualifications in addition to Japanese language proficiency, and qualified individuals over the age of 17 can apply, the bureau notes.",
        "Examinations related to Merit Test 2022 July 29 and 31, August 2,3,5,7-10,19,21,23-26 and 28, September 1,2,4,6,7,9 and 11, October 11- 13, 16, 18-20 and 23 and November 8-10, 13, 15 and 16 will be conducted through computer.",
        "This exam will be held at the Australia College of Business and Technology located at Lester James Peiris Mawatha Mawatha, Colombo Five.",
        "A maximum of 150 candidates can appear for the exam per month and the exam fee is 3500 Japanese Yen or 6300.00 Sri Lanka Rupees.",
        "The information required to enter this examination can be obtained by visiting the Japanese Job Portal (SSW Japan) on the website of the Sri Lanka Foreign Employment Bureau www.slbfe.lk."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Japan",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "Sri Lankans",
          "label": "NORP"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "The Foreign Employment Bureau of Sri Lanka",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Japanese",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lankan",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Japan",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Special Skilled Employment Program",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lankan",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the Embassy of Sri Lanka",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Japan",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Embassy",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Japanese",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "the age of 17",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Merit Test",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "July 29 and 31, August 2,3,5,7-10,19,21,23-26 and 28, September 1,2,4,6,7,9 and 11, October 11- 13",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "16",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "18-20",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "November 8-10,",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "13",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "15",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the Australia College of Business and Technology",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "James Peiris Mawatha Mawatha",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Colombo Five",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "150",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Japanese",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Yen",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "6300.00",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka Rupees",
            "label": "LOC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Japanese",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "SSW Japan",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Sri Lanka Foreign Employment Bureau www.slbfe.lk",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "ශ්‍රී ලාංකිකයන්ට ජපානයේ කෘෂිකර්මාන්තයේ දොරත් ඇරෙයි",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "විශේෂ නිපුණතා සහිත රැකියා වැඩසටහන යටතේ ජපානය මෙතෙක් ශ්‍රි ලංකාව වෙත ලබා දුන් සාත්තු සේවා හා ආහාර පාන සේවා ක්ෂේත්‍රයේ රැකියාවලට අමතරව කෘෂිකර්ම ක්ෂේත්‍රයේ රැකියා අවස්ථාවන් ශ්‍රී ලාංකික ශ්‍රමිකයන්ට ලබාදීමට ජපන් රජය එකඟතාවය පළ කර ඇති බව ශ්‍රී ලංකා විදේශ සේවා නියුක්ති කාර්යාංශය සඳහන් කරයි.",
        "ඒ අනුව ශ්‍රී ලාංකික ශ්‍රමිකයන් වැඩි පිරිසක් විශේෂ නිපුණතා සහිත රැකියා වැඩසටහන යටතේ කෘෂිකර්මාන්ත ක්ෂේත්‍රයේ රැකියා සඳහා යොමු කිරීමට අවස්ථාව ලැබී තිබේ.",
        "ජපානයේ ශ්‍රී ලංකා තානාපති කාර්යාලය හා අනෙකුත් ආයතනවල මැදිහත්වීම මත මෙම කෘෂි ක්ෂේත්‍රයේ රැකියා අවස්ථාවන් සඳහා අනුමැතිය ලබාගෙන ඇති අතර, තානාපති කාර්යාලය මෙහිදී සුවිශේෂි කාර්යභාරයක් සිදුකර ඇත.",
        "කෘෂිකර්මාන්ත ක්ෂේත්‍රයේ රැකියා සඳහා ජපන් භාෂා ප්‍රවීණතාවයට අමතරව වෘත්තීය සුදුසුකම්ද අවශ්‍ය වන අතර වයස අවුරුදු 17 ට වැඩි සුදුසුකම් ලත් අයට මේ සඳහා අයදුම් කළ හැකි බව කාර්යාංශය සඳහන් කරයි.",
        "කුසලතා පරීක්ෂණයට අදාළ විභාග 2022 ජූලි මස 29 හා 31,  අගෝස්තු 2,3,5,7-10,19,21,23-26 හා 28,    සැප්තැම්බර් 1,2,4,6,7,9 හා 11, ඔක්තෝම්බර් 11-13,16,18-20 හා 23 සහ නොවැම්බර් මස 8-10,13, 15 හා 16 යන දින වලදී පරිගණක ආශ්‍රයෙන් පැවැත්වේ.",
        "පරිගණක ආශ්‍රයෙන් මෙම විභාගය පැවැත්වෙන්නේ කොළඹ පහ ලෙස්ටර් ජේම්ස් පීරිස් මාවත මාවතේ පිහිටි Australia college of business and technology ආයතනයේදීය.",
        "එක් මසකට උපරිම අයදුම්කරුවන් 150ට විභාගයට පෙනී සිටිය හැකි අතර විභාග ගාස්තු ජපන් යෙන් 3500 ක් හෙවත් ශ්‍රී ලංකා රුපියල් 6300.00 ක් පමණ වේ.",
        "මෙම විභාගයට ප්‍රවේශ වීම සඳහා අවශ්‍ය තොරතුරු ශ්‍රී ලංකා විදේශ සේවා නියුක්ති කාර්යාංශයේ www.slbfe.lk වෙබ් අඩවියේ ජපන් රැකියා ද්වාරය (SSW Japan) වෙත පිවිසීමෙන් ලබාගත හැකිය."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ජපානය",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "ශ්‍රී ලාංකිකයන්",
          "label": "NORP"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකා විදේශ සේවා නියුක්ති කාර්යාංශය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජපන්",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලාංකික",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජපානය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "විශේෂ නිපුණතා රැකියා වැඩසටහන",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලාංකික",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකා තානාපති කාර්යාලය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජපානය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "තානාපති කාර්යාලය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ජපන්",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "වයස අවුරුදු 17",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "කුසලතා පරීක්ෂණය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජූලි 29 සහ 31, අගෝස්තු 2,3,5,7-10,19,21,23-26 සහ 28, සැප්තැම්බර් 1,2,4,6,7,9 සහ 11, ඔක්තෝබර් 11-13",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "16",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "18-20",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "නොවැම්බර් 8-10,",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "13",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "15",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ඕස්ට්‍රේලියානු ව්‍යාපාර හා තාක්ෂණ විද්‍යාලය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජේම්ස් පීරිස් මාවත මාවත",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "කොළඹ පහ",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "150",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජපන්",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "යෙන්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "6300.00 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකා රුපියල්",
            "label": "LOC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ජපන්",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "SSW ජපානය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකා විදේශ සේවා නියුක්ති කාර්යාංශය www.slbfe.lk",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "ஜப்பானில் விவசாயத்தின் கதவு இலங்கையர்களுக்கும் திறக்கப்பட்டுள்ளது",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "விசேட சட்டத்தின் கீழ் ஜப்பான் இலங்கைக்கு வழங்கிய தாதிய மற்றும் உணவு மற்றும் பான சேவைத் துறைகளின் தொழில்களுக்கு மேலதிகமாக விவசாயத் துறையில் இலங்கை தொழிலாளர்களுக்கு தொழில் வாய்ப்புகளை வழங்க ஜப்பான் அரசாங்கம் இணக்கம் தெரிவித்துள்ளதாக இலங்கை வெளிநாட்டு வேலைவாய்ப்பு பணியகம் தெரிவித்துள்ளது. திறமையான வேலைவாய்ப்பு திட்டம்.",
        "இதன்படி, விசேட திறன்களுடன் கூடிய வேலைவாய்ப்புத் திட்டத்தின் கீழ் அதிகளவான இலங்கைத் தொழிலாளர்களுக்கு விவசாயத் துறையில் பணிகளுக்கு அனுப்புவதற்கான வாய்ப்பு வழங்கப்பட்டுள்ளது.",
        "ஜப்பானில் உள்ள இலங்கைத் தூதரகம் மற்றும் ஏனைய நிறுவனங்களின் தலையீட்டினால் இவ் விவசாயத் துறையில் தொழில் வாய்ப்புக்களுக்கான அங்கீகாரம் கிடைத்துள்ளதுடன், தூதரகமும் இதில் சிறப்பான பங்களிப்பை ஆற்றியுள்ளது.",
        "விவசாயத் துறையில் உள்ள வேலைகளுக்கு ஜப்பானிய மொழித் தேர்ச்சியுடன் கூடுதலாக தொழில்முறைத் தகுதிகள் தேவை, மேலும் 17 வயதுக்கு மேற்பட்ட தகுதியுள்ள நபர்கள் விண்ணப்பிக்கலாம் என்று பணியகம் குறிப்பிடுகிறது.",
        "தகுதித் தேர்வு தொடர்பான தேர்வுகள் 2022 ஜூலை 29 மற்றும் 31, ஆகஸ்ட் 2,3,5,7-10,19,21,23-26 மற்றும் 28, செப்டம்பர் 1,2,4,6,7,9 மற்றும் 11, அக்டோபர் 11- 13, 16, 18-20 மற்றும் 23 மற்றும் நவம்பர் 8-10, 13, 15 மற்றும் 16 ஆகிய தேதிகளில் கணினி மூலம் நடத்தப்படும்.",
        "இந்தப் பரீட்சை கொழும்பு ஐந்தில் லெஸ்டர் ஜேம்ஸ் பீரிஸ் மாவத்தையில் அமைந்துள்ள அவுஸ்திரேலியா வர்த்தக மற்றும் தொழில்நுட்பக் கல்லூரியில் நடைபெறவுள்ளது.",
        "மாதாந்தம் அதிகபட்சமாக 150 பரீட்சார்த்திகள் பரீட்சைக்குத் தோற்ற முடியும் மற்றும் பரீட்சை கட்டணம் 3500 ஜப்பானிய யென் அல்லது 6300.00 இலங்கை ரூபாயாகும்.",
        "இந்தப் பரீட்சையில் நுழைவதற்குத் தேவையான தகவல்களை இலங்கை வெளிநாட்டு வேலைவாய்ப்புப் பணியகத்தின் www.slbfe.lk என்ற இணையத்தளத்தில் உள்ள ஜப்பானிய வேலை இணையத்தளத்திற்கு (SSW Japan) சென்று பெற்றுக்கொள்ளலாம்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ஜப்பான்",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "இலங்கையர்கள்",
          "label": "NORP"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கையின் வெளிநாட்டு வேலைவாய்ப்பு பணியகம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜப்பானியர்",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜப்பான்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சிறப்புத் திறன் வேலைவாய்ப்புத் திட்டம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை தூதரகம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜப்பான்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "தூதரகம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஜப்பானியர்",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "17 வயது",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "மெரிட் டெஸ்ட்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜூலை 29 மற்றும் 31, ஆகஸ்ட் 2,3,5,7-10,19,21,23-26 மற்றும் 28, செப்டம்பர் 1,2,4,6,7,9 மற்றும் 11, அக்டோபர் 11- 13",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "16",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "18-20",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "நவம்பர் 8-10,",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "13",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "15",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஆஸ்திரேலியா வணிகம் மற்றும் தொழில்நுட்பக் கல்லூரி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜேம்ஸ் பீரிஸ் மாவத்தை மாவத்தை",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "கொழும்பு ஐந்து",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "150",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜப்பானியர்",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "யென்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "6300.00",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை ரூபாய்",
            "label": "LOC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஜப்பானியர்",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "SSW ஜப்பான்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை வெளிநாட்டு வேலைவாய்ப்பு பணியகம் www.slbfe.lk",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}