{
  "newspaper_id": "daily-mirror-lk",
  "url": "https://www.dailymirror.lk/latest_news/New-Cabinet-appointment-to-be-delayed-by-week/342-243266",
  "time_ut": 1660785304,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "New Cabinet appointment to be delayed by week",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "New Cabinet appointment to be delayed by week",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "The appointment of the new Cabinet will be delayed for another one week due to closed door discussions being underway with the parties on the formation of it , Daily Mirror learns .",
        "Opposition Leader Sajith Premadasa is adamant that his Samagi Jana Balawegaya",
        "(SJB) should not team up with the government. However , some of its MPs insist on the need to take up Cabinet responsibilities.",
        "According to informed sources, these MPs want to hold ministerial responsibilities instead of heading parliamentary committees proposed to be set up as an initiative by President Ranil Wickremesinghe to strengthen the Legislature.",
        "Sri Lanka Freedom Party( SLFP) is likely to join the government as a party .",
        "The Tamil Progressive Alliance ( TPA), an ally of the SJB, has decided to delay its decision to join the government .",
        "Its presidium met recently and decided to withhold taking any decision at this moment. (Kelum Bandara)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "week",
          "label": "DATE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Cabinet",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "another one week",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Daily Mirror",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sajith Premadasa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Samagi",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "SJB",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Cabinet",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Legislature",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka Freedom Party",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "The Tamil Progressive Alliance",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "SJB",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Kelum Bandara",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "නව කැබිනට් පත්‍රිකාව සතියකින් ප්‍රමාද වෙයි",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "නව අමාත්‍ය මණ්ඩලය පිහිටුවීම සම්බන්ධයෙන් පක්ෂ සමඟ සංවෘත සාකච්ජා පැවැත්වෙන බැවින් එය පත් කිරීම තවත් සතියකින් ප්‍රමාද වනු ඇතැයි ඩේලි මිරර් වෙත වාර්තා වේ.",
        "විපක්ෂ නායක සජිත් ප්‍රේමදාස මහතා තම සමගි ජන බලවේගය බව ස්ථිරයි",
        "(SJB) රජය සමඟ එකතු නොවිය යුතුය. කෙසේ වෙතත්, එහි ඇතැම් මන්ත්‍රීවරු කැබිනට් වගකීම් භාරගැනීමේ අවශ්‍යතාව අවධාරණය කරති.",
        "ව්‍යවස්ථාදායකය ශක්තිමත් කිරීම සඳහා ජනාධිපති රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතාගේ මූලිකත්වයෙන් පිහිටුවීමට යෝජිත පාර්ලිමේන්තු කමිටු ප්‍රධානියා වෙනුවට අමාත්‍ය ධුර දැරීමට මෙම මන්ත්‍රීවරුන්ට අවශ්‍යව ඇතැයි තතුදත් ආරංචි මාර්ග සඳහන් කරයි.",
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකා නිදහස් පක්ෂය (ශ්‍රීලනිප) පක්ෂයක් ලෙස ආණ්ඩුවට එක්වීමට බොහෝ දුරට ඉඩ තිබේ.",
        "SJB හි හවුල්කරුවෙකු වන දෙමළ ප්‍රගතිශීලී සන්ධානය (TPA) රජයට එක්වීමට ගත් තීරණය ප්‍රමාද කිරීමට තීරණය කර ඇත.",
        "එහි සභාපතිවරයා පසුගියදා රැස්වූ අතර මේ මොහොතේ කිසිදු තීරණයක් ගැනීම වළක්වා ගැනීමට තීරණය කළේය. (කැළුම් බණ්ඩාර)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "සතිය",
          "label": "DATE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "මණ්ඩල",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "තවත් සතියක්",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඩේලි මිරර්",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "සජිත් ප්‍රේමදාස",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "සමගි",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "එස්.ජේ.බී",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "මණ්ඩල",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ව්යවස්ථාදායකය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකා නිදහස් පක්ෂය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "දෙමළ ප්‍රගතිශීලී සන්ධානය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "එස්.ජේ.බී",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "කැළුම් බණ්ඩාර",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "புதிய அமைச்சரவை நியமனம் ஒருவாரம் தாமதமாகும்",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "புதிய அமைச்சரவையை அமைப்பது தொடர்பாக கட்சிகளுடன் மூடிமறைக்கப்பட்ட விவாதங்கள் நடைபெற்று வருவதால், புதிய அமைச்சரவை நியமனம் இன்னும் ஒரு வாரத்திற்கு தாமதமாகும் என டெய்லி மிரர் செய்தி வெளியிட்டுள்ளது.",
        "எதிர்க்கட்சித் தலைவர் சஜித் பிரேமதாச தனது சமகி ஜன பலவேகய என்பதில் உறுதியாக உள்ளார்",
        "(SJB) அரசாங்கத்துடன் அணிசேர்க்கக் கூடாது. இருப்பினும், அதன் எம்.பி.க்கள் சிலர் அமைச்சரவைப் பொறுப்புகளை ஏற்க வேண்டியதன் அவசியத்தை வலியுறுத்துகின்றனர்.",
        "நாடாளுமன்றத்தை வலுப்படுத்தும் வகையில் ஜனாதிபதி ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்கவினால் அமைக்கப்படவுள்ள பாராளுமன்ற குழுக்களுக்கு தலைமை தாங்குவதற்கு பதிலாக அமைச்சுப் பொறுப்புகளை வகிக்கவே இந்த எம்.பிக்கள் விரும்புவதாக தகவலறிந்த வட்டாரங்கள் தெரிவிக்கின்றன.",
        "ஸ்ரீலங்கா சுதந்திரக் கட்சி (SLFP) ஒரு கட்சியாக அரசாங்கத்தில் இணையும் வாய்ப்புகள் அதிகம்.",
        "SJB இன் கூட்டாளியான தமிழ் முற்போக்குக் கூட்டணி, அரசாங்கத்துடன் இணைவதற்கான தனது முடிவை தாமதப்படுத்தத் தீர்மானித்துள்ளது.",
        "அதன் பிரீசிடியம் சமீபத்தில் கூடி, இந்த நேரத்தில் எந்த முடிவையும் எடுப்பதை நிறுத்த முடிவு செய்தது. (கெலும் பண்டார)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "வாரம்",
          "label": "DATE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "மந்திரி சபை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "மற்றொரு ஒரு வாரம்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "டெய்லி மிரர்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "சஜித் பிரேமதாச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "சமகி",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "எஸ்.ஜே.பி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "மந்திரி சபை",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "சட்டமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஸ்ரீலங்கா சுதந்திரக் கட்சி",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "தமிழ் முற்போக்குக் கூட்டணி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "எஸ்.ஜே.பி",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "கெலும் பண்டார",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}