{
  "newspaper_id": "daily-mirror-lk",
  "url": "https://www.dailymirror.lk/breaking_news/Opp-parties-Govt-factions-make-fresh-bid-for-all-party-government/108-240447",
  "time_ut": 1657077402,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Opp. parties, Govt factions make fresh bid for all party government",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Opp. parties, Govt factions make fresh bid for all party government",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "In a fresh bid for the formation of an all party government, the parties in the opposition, bar the JVP-led National Peoples’ Power, and some factions of the ruling side met in the parliamentary complex yesterday to discuss the way forward, but the event was marred by differences of opinion, Daily Mirror learns.",
        "In addition to the main opposition Samagi Jana Balawegaya (SJB), the parties such as the Sri Lanka Freedom Party (SLFP), the Independent Group of ruling Sri Lanka Podujana Peramuna (SLPP), the Tamil National Alliance (TNA), Sri Lanka Muslim Congress (SLMC), the Tamil Progressive Alliance (TPA) and the Ceylon Workers Congress (CWC) attended the meeting.",
        "Also, the representatives of the 11-party alliance (the parties that remained aligned with the ruling SLPP) participated in the discussion.",
        "They put forth their views but could not reach any finality on the structure of the government to be formed by them.",
        "SJB leader Sajith Premadasa is reported to have said that there are no short term fixes to the current problems. He insisted on collective efforts to find long term and long lasting solutions.",
        "MP Vasudeva Nanayakkara who represented the 11-party alliance said the required number for an all party government could be mustered easily. He asked for initiatives to establish such a government as a result. SJB MP Kumara Welgama said it would be difficult to operate an all party government under current President Gotabaya Rajapaksa.",
        "TNA MP M.A. Sumanthiran stressed the need to resolve what he called ‘the Tamil national question’ to boost confidence in the government internationally for support to revive the economy. He said there would be an avalanche of investments from the Tamil Diaspora once the national question was resolved.",
        "TPP leader Mano Ganeshan, in his remarks to the meeting, said a common governing mechanism had to be evolved to run the country during this trying time.",
        "The JVP has been invited for the meeting but none of its representatives has turned up.(Kelum Bandara)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Opp",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "Govt",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "JVP",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "National Peoples’ Power",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "yesterday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Daily Mirror",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Samagi Jana Balawegaya",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Sri Lanka Freedom Party",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "SLFP",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Independent Group",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Podujana Peramuna",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Tamil National Alliance",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka Muslim Congress",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Tamil Progressive Alliance",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Ceylon Workers Congress",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "CWC",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "11",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "SJB",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sajith Premadasa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Vasudeva Nanayakkara",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "11",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kumara Welgama",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Gotabaya Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "M.A. Sumanthiran",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Tamil",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Tamil Diaspora",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "TPP",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Mano Ganeshan",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "up.(Kelum Bandara",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "විරුද්ධ පක්ෂ, රජයේ කන්ඩායම් සර්ව පාක්ෂික ආන්ඩුව සඳහා අලුත් ලංසුවක් ඉදිරිපත් කරයි",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "සර්ව පාක්ෂික ආණ්ඩුවක් පිහිටුවීමේ නව උත්සාහයක් ලෙස විපක්ෂයේ පක්ෂ, ජනතා විමුක්ති පෙරමුණ ප්‍රමුඛ ජාතික ජන බලවේගයට බාධා කරන අතර, ඉදිරි මග පිළිබඳව සාකච්ඡා කිරීමට ආණ්ඩු පක්ෂයේ ඇතැම් කණ්ඩායම් ඊයේ පාර්ලිමේන්තු සංකීර්ණයේදී රැස්වූ නමුත්, මතභේද හේතුවෙන් මෙම සිදුවීම විනාශ වූ බව ඩේලි මිරර් වෙත වාර්තා වේ.",
        "ප්‍රධාන විපක්ෂය වන සමගි ජන බලවේගයට (SJB) අමතරව ශ්‍රී ලංකා නිදහස් පක්ෂය (SLFP), පාලක ශ්‍රී ලංකා පොදුජන පෙරමුණේ (SLPP), දෙමළ ජාතික සන්ධානය (TNA), ශ්‍රී ලංකා මුස්ලිම් වැනි පක්ෂ කොංග්‍රසය (SLMC), දෙමළ ප්‍රගතිශීලී සන්ධානය (TPA) සහ ලංකා කම්කරු කොංග්‍රසය (CWC) රැස්වීමට සහභාගි විය.",
        "එසේම, පක්ෂ 11 සන්ධානයේ (පාලක ශ්‍රී ලංකා පොදුජන පෙරමුණ සමඟ දිගටම සන්ධානගතව සිටි පක්ෂ) නියෝජිතයින් මෙම සාකච්ඡාවට සහභාගී විය.",
        "ඔවුන් තම අදහස් ඉදිරිපත් කළ නමුත් ඔවුන් විසින් පිහිටුවන ආණ්ඩුවේ ව්‍යුහය පිළිබඳ අවසන් නිගමනයකට එළඹීමට නොහැකි විය.",
        "පවතින ගැටලුවලට කෙටිකාලීන විසඳුම් නොමැති බව SJB නායක සජිත් ප්‍රේමදාස මහතා ප්‍රකාශ කර ඇතැයි වාර්තා වේ. දිගුකාලීන හා දිගුකාලීන විසඳුම් සෙවීම සඳහා සාමූහික උත්සාහයන් සඳහා ඔහු අවධාරනය කළේය.",
        "පක්ෂ 11 ක සන්ධානය නියෝජනය කළ පාර්ලිමේන්තු මන්ත්‍රී වාසුදේව නානායක්කාර පැවසුවේ සර්ව පාක්ෂික ආණ්ඩුවක් සඳහා අවශ්‍ය සංඛ්‍යාව පහසුවෙන් රැස් කළ හැකි බවයි. එහි ප්‍රතිඵලයක් ලෙස එවැනි රජයක් පිහිටුවීමට පියවර ගන්නා ලෙස ඔහු ඉල්ලා සිටියේය. වත්මන් ජනාධිපති ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ මහතා යටතේ සර්ව පාක්ෂික ආණ්ඩුවක් ක්‍රියාත්මක කිරීම දුෂ්කර බව SJB පාර්ලිමේන්තු මන්ත්‍රී කුමාර වෙල්ගම මහතා පැවසීය.",
        "දෙමළ ජාතික සන්ධානයේ පාර්ලිමේන්තු මන්ත්‍රී එම්.ඒ.සුමන්තිරන් මහතා ආර්ථිකය පුනර්ජීවනය කිරීමට සහාය වීම සඳහා ජාත්‍යන්තර වශයෙන් රජය කෙරෙහි විශ්වාසය ඉහළ නැංවීම සඳහා ‘දෙමළ ජාතික ප්‍රශ්නය’ ලෙස හැඳින්වූ දෙය විසඳිය යුතු බව අවධාරණය කළේය. ජාතික ප්‍රශ්නය විසඳූ පසු දෙමළ ඩයස්පෝරාවෙන් ආයෝජන විශාල වශයෙන් කඩා වැටෙනු ඇතැයි ඔහු පැවසීය.",
        "ටීපීපී නායක මනෝ ගනේෂන් රැස්වීමට අදහස් දක්වමින් කියා සිටියේ මෙම දුෂ්කර කාලය තුළ රට පාලනය කිරීම සඳහා පොදු පාලන යාන්ත්‍රණයක් සකස් කළ යුතු බවයි.",
        "මෙම රැස්වීම සඳහා ජනතා විමුක්ති පෙරමුණට ආරාධනා කර ඇතත් එහි කිසිදු නියෝජිතයෙකු පැමිණ නැත.(කැළුම් බණ්ඩාර)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "විරුද්ධ",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "රජය",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ජ.වි.පෙ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජාතික ජනතා බලය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඊයේ",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඩේලි මිරර්",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "සමගි ජන බලවේගය",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකා නිදහස් පක්ෂය",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රීලනිප",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ස්වාධීන කණ්ඩායම",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "පොදුජන පෙරමුණ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "දෙමළ ජාතික සන්ධානය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකා මුස්ලිම් කොංග්‍රසය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "දෙමළ ප්‍රගතිශීලී සන්ධානය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ලංකා කම්කරු කොංග්‍රසය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "සීඩබ්ලිව්සී",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "11",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "එස්.ජේ.බී",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "සජිත් ප්‍රේමදාස",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "වාසුදේව නානායක්කාර",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "11",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "කුමාර වෙල්ගම",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "එම්.ඒ.සුමන්තිරන්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "දෙමළ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "දෙමළ ඩයස්පෝරාව",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "TPP",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "මනෝ ගනේෂන්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "දක්වා.(කැලුම් බණ්ඩාර",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "எதிர் கட்சிகள், அரசாங்கப் பிரிவுகள் அனைத்துக் கட்சி அரசாங்கத்திற்கான புதிய முயற்சியை மேற்கொள்கின்றன",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "சர்வகட்சி அரசாங்கத்தை அமைப்பதற்கான புதிய முயற்சியில், எதிர்க்கட்சியில் உள்ள கட்சிகள், ஜே.வி.பி தலைமையிலான தேசிய மக்கள் சக்தியைத் தடை செய்ததோடு, ஆளும் தரப்பின் சில தரப்பினரும் நேற்று நாடாளுமன்ற வளாகத்தில் கூடி முன்னோக்கிச் செல்வது குறித்து ஆலோசித்தனர். இந்த நிகழ்வு கருத்து வேறுபாடுகளால் சிதைக்கப்பட்டது என்று டெய்லி மிரர் அறியிறது.",
        "பிரதான எதிர்க்கட்சியான சமகி ஜன பலவேகய (SJB) தவிர, ஸ்ரீலங்கா சுதந்திரக் கட்சி (SLFP), ஆளும் ஸ்ரீலங்கா பொதுஜன பெரமுன (SLPP), தமிழ்த் தேசியக் கூட்டமைப்பு (TNA), ஸ்ரீலங்கா முஸ்லிம் போன்ற கட்சிகள். காங்கிரஸ் (SLMC), தமிழ் முற்போக்குக் கூட்டணி (TPA) மற்றும் இலங்கை தொழிலாளர் காங்கிரஸ் (CWC) ஆகியன இந்தக் கூட்டத்தில் கலந்து கொண்டன.",
        "மேலும், 11 கட்சிகள் கொண்ட கூட்டணியின் (ஆளும் SLPP யுடன் தொடர்ந்து இணைந்த கட்சிகள்) பிரதிநிதிகள் விவாதத்தில் பங்கேற்றனர்.",
        "அவர்கள் தங்கள் கருத்துக்களை முன்வைத்தனர், ஆனால் அவர்களால் உருவாக்கப்படும் அரசாங்கத்தின் கட்டமைப்பில் எந்த இறுதி முடிவையும் எட்ட முடியவில்லை.",
        "தற்போதைய பிரச்சினைகளுக்கு குறுகிய கால தீர்வுகள் எதுவும் இல்லை என SJB தலைவர் சஜித் பிரேமதாச தெரிவித்துள்ளார். நீண்ட கால மற்றும் நீடித்த தீர்வுகளைக் கண்டறிய கூட்டு முயற்சிகளை அவர் வலியுறுத்தினார்.",
        "11 கட்சிகளை கொண்ட கூட்டணியை பிரதிநிதித்துவப்படுத்திய பாராளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர் வாசுதேவ நாணயக்கார, அனைத்து கட்சி அரசாங்கத்திற்கு தேவையான எண்ணிக்கையை இலகுவாக திரட்ட முடியும் என்றார். அதன் விளைவாக அத்தகைய அரசாங்கத்தை நிறுவுவதற்கான முயற்சிகளை அவர் கேட்டார். தற்போதைய ஜனாதிபதி கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ஷவின் கீழ் சர்வகட்சி அரசாங்கத்தை நடத்துவது கடினம் என SJB பாராளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர் குமார வெல்கம தெரிவித்துள்ளார்.",
        "பொருளாதாரத்தை புத்துயிர் பெறுவதற்கு ஆதரவளிப்பதற்காக சர்வதேச ரீதியில் அரசாங்கத்தின் மீதான நம்பிக்கையை அதிகரிப்பதற்காக ‘தமிழ் தேசியப் பிரச்சினை’ என்று அவர் கூறியதைத் தீர்க்க வேண்டியதன் அவசியத்தை தமிழ்த் தேசியக் கூட்டமைப்பின் பாராளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர் எம்.ஏ.சுமந்திரன் வலியுறுத்தினார். தேசியப் பிரச்சினைக்கு தீர்வு கிடைத்தவுடன் புலம்பெயர் தமிழ் மக்களிடம் இருந்து முதலீடுகள் பனிச்சரிவு ஏற்படும் என்றார்.",
        "இக்கூட்டத்தில் கருத்து தெரிவித்த TPP தலைவர் மனோ கணேசன், இந்த இக்கட்டான நேரத்தில் நாட்டை நடத்துவதற்கு பொதுவான ஆட்சிப் பொறிமுறையை உருவாக்க வேண்டும் என்றார்.",
        "கூட்டத்திற்கு ஜே.வி.பி.க்கு அழைப்பு விடுக்கப்பட்டுள்ளது ஆனால் அதன் பிரதிநிதிகள் யாரும் வரவில்லை.(கெலும் பண்டார)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "எதிர்",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "அரசு",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ஜே.வி.பி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "தேசிய மக்கள் சக்தி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "நேற்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "டெய்லி மிரர்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "சமகி ஜன பலவேகயா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஸ்ரீலங்கா சுதந்திரக் கட்சி",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஸ்ரீ.ல.சு.க",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "சுயாதீன குழு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "பொதுஜன பெரமுன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "தமிழ் தேசிய கூட்டமைப்பு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஸ்ரீலங்கா முஸ்லிம் காங்கிரஸ்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "தமிழ் முற்போக்கு கூட்டணி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை தொழிலாளர் காங்கிரஸ்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "CWC",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "11",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "எஸ்.ஜே.பி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "சஜித் பிரேமதாச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "வாசுதேவ நாணயக்கார",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "11",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "குமார வெல்கம",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "எம்.ஏ.சுமந்திரன்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "தமிழ்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "புலம்பெயர் தமிழ் மக்கள்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "TPP",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "மனோ கணேசன்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "வரை.(கெலும் பண்டார",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}