{
  "newspaper_id": "news-first-lk",
  "url": "https://www.newsfirst.lk/2022/09/04/imf-chief-pleased-by-imf-staff-level-agreement/",
  "time_ut": 1662273060,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "IMF Chief pleased by IMF staff level agreement",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "IMF Chief pleased by IMF staff level agreement",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); IMF Chief Kristalina Georgieva has stated that she is pleased that IMF staff and Sri Lankan government officials have reached a staff-level agreement to support the country’s economic policies.",
        "The Sri Lankan Government and the IMF reached an agreement for a 48-month Extended Fund Facility of  US$ 2.9 billion recently.",
        "\"This is an important step forward for Sri Lanka,\" she stated."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "News 1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "IMF",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kristalina Georgieva",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lankan",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "The Sri Lankan Government",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "48-month",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "US$ 2.9 billion",
            "label": "MONEY"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "ජාත්‍යන්තර මූල්‍ය අරමුදලේ මාණ්ඩලික මට්ටමේ ගිවිසුමෙන් IMF ප්‍රධානියා සතුටු විය",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); ජාත්‍යන්තර මූල්‍ය අරමුදලේ ප්‍රධානී ක්‍රිස්ටලිනා ජෝර්ජිවා ප්‍රකාශ කර ඇත්තේ IMF කාර්ය මණ්ඩලය සහ ශ්‍රී ලංකා රජයේ නිලධාරීන් රටේ ආර්ථික ප්‍රතිපත්තිවලට සහාය වීම සඳහා කාර්ය මණ්ඩල මට්ටමේ එකඟතාවකට පැමිණීම පිළිබඳව තමන් සතුටු වන බවයි.",
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකා රජය සහ ජාත්‍යන්තර මූල්‍ය අරමුදල විසින් මාස 48ක විස්තීරණ අරමුදල් පහසුකම සඳහා  ඇ.ඩොලර් බිලියන 2.9ක ගිවිසුමකට පසුගියදා එළඹුණි.",
        "“මෙය ශ්‍රී ලංකාවට වැදගත් ඉදිරි පියවරක්,” ඇය ප්‍රකාශ කළාය."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "News 1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "IMF",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ක්රිස්ටලිනා ජෝර්ජිවා",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලාංකික",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකා රජය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "48-මාස",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඇමෙරිකානු ඩොලර් බිලියන 2.9 කි",
            "label": "MONEY"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "IMF பணியாளர் நிலை ஒப்பந்தத்தால் IMF தலைவர் மகிழ்ச்சி அடைந்தார்",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); சர்வதேச நாணய நிதியத்தின் தலைவர் கிறிஸ்டலினா ஜோர்ஜீவா, நாட்டின் பொருளாதாரக் கொள்கைகளுக்கு ஆதரவளிப்பதற்காக சர்வதேச நாணய நிதியத்தின் ஊழியர்களும் இலங்கை அரசாங்க அதிகாரிகளும் ஊழியர் மட்ட உடன்பாட்டை எட்டியதில் மகிழ்ச்சியடைவதாக தெரிவித்துள்ளார்.",
        "இலங்கை அரசாங்கமும் சர்வதேச நாணய நிதியமும்  அமெரிக்க $2.9 பில்லியன் 48 மாத விரிவாக்கப்பட்ட நிதி வசதிக்கான உடன்படிக்கையை அண்மையில் எட்டியுள்ளன.",
        "\"இது இலங்கைக்கு ஒரு முக்கியமான முன்னேற்றம்\" என்று அவர் கூறினார்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "News 1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "IMF",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "கிறிஸ்டலினா ஜார்ஜீவா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை அரசு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "48-மாதம்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "அமெரிக்க டாலர் 2.9 பில்லியன்",
            "label": "MONEY"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}