{
  "newspaper_id": "ada-derana-lk",
  "url": "http://www.adaderana.lk/news/83950/new-public-school-bus-service-operative-from-aug",
  "time_ut": 1659090720,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "New public school bus service operative from Aug",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "New public school bus service operative from Aug",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "The new public bus transport service for school children, introduced in view of the ongoing fuel crisis, will be in operation from the 01st of August, the National Transport Commission (NTC) says.",
        "Addressing a media briefing this morning, NTC Director-General Dr. Nilan Miranda said the school children using this transport service will be charged the usual bus fare.",
        "At least 40 buses will be up and running in the Western Province from August 01, Dr. Miranda said further, adding that at its initial level, these buses will provide services to transport students to leading schools in several areas including Colombo, Gampaha, Kalutara, Horana, Homagama and Maharagama.",
        "Parents can obtain details about this school bus service by contacting the NTC’s 24-hour hotline 1955 and its official website (www.ntc.gov.lk)."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "the 01st of August",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the National Transport Commission",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "NTC",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "this morning",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "NTC",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Nilan Miranda",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "At least 40",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Western Province",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "August 01",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Miranda",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Colombo",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Gampaha",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kalutara",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Horana",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Homagama",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Maharagama",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "NTC",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "24-hour",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "නව රජයේ පාසල් බස් සේවාව අගෝස්තු මස සිට ක්‍රියාත්මක වේ",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "පවතින ඉන්ධන අර්බුදය හමුවේ පාසල් සිසුන් සඳහා හඳුන්වා දුන් නව පොදු බස් ප්‍රවාහන සේවාව අගෝස්තු 01 වැනිදා සිට ක්‍රියාත්මක වන බව ජාතික ගමනාගමන කොමිෂන් සභාව පවසයි.",
        "අද පෙරවරුවේ පැවති මාධ්‍ය හමුවකට එක්වෙමින් NTC අධ්‍යක්ෂ ජනරාල් වෛද්‍ය නිලාන් මිරැන්ඩා පැවසුවේ මෙම ප්‍රවාහන සේවය භාවිතා කරන පාසල් සිසුන්ගෙන් සාමාන්‍ය බස් ගාස්තුව අය කරන බවයි.",
        "අගෝස්තු 01 වැනිදා සිට බස්නාහිර පළාතේ අවම වශයෙන් බස්රථ 40ක් ධාවනයට යොදවන බවත්, එහි මූලික මට්ටමේදී කොළඹ, ගම්පහ, කළුතර ඇතුළු ප්‍රදේශ කිහිපයක ප්‍රධාන පෙළේ පාසල්වලට සිසුන් ප්‍රවාහනය කිරීම සඳහා මෙම බස් රථ සේවා සපයන බවත් වෛද්‍ය මිරැන්ඩා වැඩිදුරටත් පැවසීය. , හොරණ, හෝමාගම සහ මහරගම.",
        "NTC හි පැය 24 පුරා ක්‍රියාත්මක වන 1955 ක්ෂණික ඇමතුම් අංකය සහ එහි නිල වෙබ් අඩවිය (www.ntc.gov.lk) ඇමතීමෙන් දෙමාපියන්ට මෙම පාසල් බස් සේවාව පිළිබඳ විස්තර ලබා ගත හැක."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "අගෝස්තු 01 වෙනිදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජාතික ගමනාගමන කොමිෂන් සභාව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "NTC",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "මේ උදෑසන",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "NTC",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "නිලාන් මිරැන්ඩා",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "අවම වශයෙන් 40",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "බස්නාහිර පළාත",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "අගෝස්තු 01",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මිරැන්ඩා",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "කොළඹ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගම්පහ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "කළුතර",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "හොරණ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Homagama",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "මහරගම",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "NTC",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "පැය 24",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "புதிய அரசுப் பள்ளி பேருந்து சேவை ஆகஸ்ட் முதல் இயக்கப்படுகிறது",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "தற்போது நிலவும் எரிபொருள் நெருக்கடியை கருத்தில் கொண்டு அறிமுகப்படுத்தப்பட்ட பாடசாலை மாணவர்களுக்கான புதிய பொது பஸ் போக்குவரத்து சேவை எதிர்வரும் ஆகஸ்ட் மாதம் 01 ஆம் திகதி முதல் அமுல்படுத்தப்படும் என தேசிய போக்குவரத்து ஆணைக்குழு (NTC) தெரிவித்துள்ளது.",
        "இன்று காலை ஊடகவியலாளர் சந்திப்பில் உரையாற்றிய NTC பணிப்பாளர் நாயகம் கலாநிதி நிலான் மிராண்டா, இந்த போக்குவரத்து சேவையை பயன்படுத்தும் பாடசாலை மாணவர்களிடம் வழமையான பஸ் கட்டணம் அறவிடப்படும் என தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "ஆகஸ்ட் 01 முதல் மேல் மாகாணத்தில் குறைந்தது 40 பேரூந்துகள் இயங்கும் என்றும், அதன் ஆரம்ப மட்டத்தில், கொழும்பு, கம்பஹா, களுத்துறை உள்ளிட்ட பல பகுதிகளில் உள்ள முன்னணி பாடசாலைகளுக்கு மாணவர்களை ஏற்றிச் செல்வதற்கான சேவைகளை இந்தப் பேருந்துகள் வழங்கும் என்றும் டாக்டர் மிராண்டா மேலும் தெரிவித்தார். , ஹொரண, ஹோமாகம மற்றும் மஹரகம.",
        "NTC இன் 24 மணி நேர ஹாட்லைன் 1955 மற்றும் அதன் அதிகாரப்பூர்வ இணையதளம் (www.ntc.gov.lk) ஆகியவற்றைத் தொடர்புகொள்வதன் மூலம் பெற்றோர்கள் இந்தப் பள்ளி பேருந்து சேவையைப் பற்றிய விவரங்களைப் பெறலாம்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ஆகஸ்ட் 01 ஆம் தேதி",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "தேசிய போக்குவரத்து ஆணையம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "என்.டி.சி",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இன்று காலை",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "என்.டி.சி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "நிலன் மிராண்டா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "குறைந்தது 40",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "மேல் மாகாணம்",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆகஸ்ட் 01",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "மிராண்டா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "கொழும்பு",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "கம்பஹா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "களுத்துறை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஹொரணை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Homagama",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "மஹரகம",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "என்.டி.சி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "24-மணிநேரம்",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}