{
  "newspaper_id": "lankadeepa-lk",
  "url": "https://www.lankadeepa.lk/latest_news/මුහුදුබඩ-දුම්රිය-මාර්ගයේ-ගමන-අවදානමේ/1-615481",
  "time_ut": 1656320312,
  "original_lang": "si",
  "original_title": "මුහුදුබඩ දුම්රිය මාර්ගයේ ගමන අවදානමේ",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Coastal rail travel at risk",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "The Railway Department has revealed that 76 tracks on the Moratuwa-Panadura-Wadduwa coastal railway line from Colombo to Matara are dilapidated.",
        "As a result, speed limits have been imposed on the same line and the dollar problem has affected repairs to the dilapidated track, railway sources said.",
        "We inquired about this from the Chief Engineer (Roads and Industries) of the Railway Department, HMKW Bandara, who said that due to the derailment of a considerable number of tracks in the region from Colombo to Wadduwa, the speed limit is 20 to 30 km per hour. That restrictions have been imposed.",
        "Accordingly, the dilapidated condition of the Colombo-Matara dual carriageway, which is considered to be the upper line of the Colombo-Payagala dual carriageway, will be seen at 31 points and the lower road from the Matara to Colombo will be dilapidated at 25 points, he said.",
        "He also said that the railway line from Payagala to Matara as a single track was in a dilapidated condition at ten places.",
        "He said that the main reason for the decay was the proximity of the coastal railway line to the sea."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Coastal",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "The Railway Department",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "76",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Moratuwa-Panadura-Wadduwa",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "Matara",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "the Railway Department",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "HMKW Bandara",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Wadduwa",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "20 to 30 km per hour",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the Colombo-Matara",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "31",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Matara to Colombo",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "25",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Payagala",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Matara",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ten",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        []
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "මුහුදුබඩ දුම්රිය මාර්ගයේ ගමන අවදානමේ",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "කොළඹ සිට මාතර දක්වා දිවෙන මොරටුව,පානදුර වාද්දුව මුහුදු බඩ දුම්රිය මාර්ගයේ ස්ථාන 76 රේල් පීලි දිරාපත්ව අබලන් තත්ත්වයට පත්ව ඇතැයි දුම්රිය දෙපාර්තමේන්තු අනාවරණය කරගෙන ඇත.",
        "මේ හේතුවෙන්එ ම මාර්ගයේ වේග සීමා පන්වා ඇති බවත් අබලන් වූ මාර්ගය අලුත්වැඩියා කිරීම්ට ඩොලර් ගැටලුව බලපෑම් එල්ල කොට ඇති බවත් දුම්රිය ආරංචිමාර්ග පවසයි.",
        "මේ පිළිබඳව දුම්රිය දෙපාර්තමේන්තු ප්‍රධාන ඉංජිනේරු (මාර්ග හා කර්මාන්ත) එච්.එම්.කේ.ඩබ්ලිව් බණ්ඩාර මහතාගෙන් අප විමසා සිටි අතර ඒ මහතා පැවසූයේ මේ වන විට කොළඹ සිට වාද්දුව දක්වා කලාපයේ සැලකිය යුතු ප්‍රමාණයක පීලි දීරා පත්වීම නිසා පැයට කිලෝ මීටර් විස්ස, තිහ වශයෙන් වේග සීමා පනවා ඇති බවයි.",
        "ඒ අනුව කොළඹ සිට පයාගල දක්වා දිවෙන ද්විත්ව දුම්රිය මගෙහි උඩු මාර්ගය ලෙස සැලකෙන කොළඹ සිට මාතර දක්වා දිවෙන මගෙහි ස්ථාන තිස් එකකද පහල මාර්ගය ලෙස සැලකෙන මාතර සිට කොළඹට දිවෙන මගෙහි ස්ථාන විසි පහකද මෙම අබලන් තත්වයට දක්නට ලැබෙන බව ඔහු පැවසීය.",
        "එමෙන්ම පයාගල සිට තනි මාර්ගයක් ලෙස මාතර දක්වා දිවෙන මාර්ගයේද ස්ථාන දහයක රේල් පීලි අබලන් තත්ත්වයට පත්ව ඇති බව ඔහු පැවසීය",
        "එම දිරාපත් වීමට ප්‍රධාන හේතුව මුහුදුබඩ දුම්රිය මාර්ගය මුහුදට ඉතා ආසන්නයෙන් පිහිටීම යැයි ඒ මහතා පැවැසීය."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "වෙරළබඩ",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "දුම්රිය දෙපාර්තමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "76",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "මොරටුව - පානදුර - වාද්දුව",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "මාතර",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "දුම්රිය දෙපාර්තමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "එච්.එම්.කේ.ඩබ්. බණ්ඩාර",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "වාද්දුව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "පැයට කිලෝමීටර 20 සිට 30 දක්වා",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "කොළඹ-මාතර",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "31",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "මාතර සිට කොළඹ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "25",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "පයාගල",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මාතර",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "දස",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        []
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "கடலோர ரயில் போக்குவரத்து ஆபத்தில் உள்ளது",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "கொழும்பில் இருந்து மாத்தறை வரையிலான மொரட்டுவை - பாணந்துறை - வாத்துவ கரையோர ரயில் பாதையில் 76 தண்டவாளங்கள் பழுதடைந்துள்ளதாக ரயில்வே திணைக்களம் தெரிவித்துள்ளது.",
        "இதனால், அதே வழித்தடத்தில் வேகத்தடை விதிக்கப்பட்டு, டாலர் பிரச்னையால், பழுதடைந்த தண்டவாளத்தை சீரமைக்கும் பணியில் பாதிப்பு ஏற்பட்டுள்ளதாக, ரயில்வே வட்டாரங்கள் தெரிவிக்கின்றன.",
        "இது குறித்து புகையிரத திணைக்களத்தின் பிரதம பொறியியலாளர் (சாலைகள் மற்றும் கைத்தொழில்கள்) எச்.எம்.கே.டபிள்யூ பண்டாரவிடம் வினவியபோது, ​​கொழும்பில் இருந்து வாதுவ வரையான பகுதியில் கணிசமான எண்ணிக்கையிலான தண்டவாளங்கள் தடம் புரண்டதன் காரணமாக 20 முதல் 30 கி.மீ. ஒரு மணி நேரத்திற்கு என்று கட்டுப்பாடுகள் விதிக்கப்பட்டுள்ளன.",
        "இதன்படி, கொழும்பு - பயாகலை இரட்டைப் பாதையின் மேல் பாதையாகக் கருதப்படும் கொழும்பு - மாத்தறை இரட்டைப் பாதையின் பாழடைந்த நிலை 31 புள்ளிகளிலும், மாத்தறையில் இருந்து கொழும்பு வரையிலான கீழ் வீதி 25 புள்ளிகளிலும் பாழடைந்துள்ளது. , அவன் சொன்னான்.",
        "மேலும், பயாகல முதல் மாத்தறை வரையான புகையிரதப் பாதை ஒற்றைப் பாதையாகப் பத்து இடங்களில் பாழடைந்த நிலையில் காணப்படுவதாகவும் அவர் கூறினார்.",
        "கடலோர ரயில் பாதை கடலுக்கு அருகாமையில் உள்ளதே பழுதடைந்ததற்கு முக்கிய காரணம் என்றார்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "கடற்கரை",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ரயில்வே துறை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "76",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "மொரட்டுவ - பாணந்துறை - வாதுவ",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "மாத்தறை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "ரயில்வே துறை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "HMKW பண்டார",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "வாதுவ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "மணிக்கு 20 முதல் 30 கி.மீ",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "கொழும்பு-மாத்தறை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "31",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "மாத்தறை முதல் கொழும்பு வரை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "25",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பயாகலா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "மாத்தறை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "பத்து",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        []
      ]
    }
  }
}