{
  "newspaper_id": "lankadeepa-lk",
  "url": "https://www.lankadeepa.lk/latest_news/පොල්ගහවෙල-රිය-අනතුරකින්-එස්-ටී-එෆ්--8-ක්-ඇගලුම්-සේවිකාවෝ-7-ක්-රෝහලේ/1-617473",
  "time_ut": 1659443165,
  "original_lang": "si",
  "original_title": "පොල්ගහවෙල රිය අනතුරකින් එස්.ටී.එෆ්. 8 ක් ඇගලුම් සේවිකාවෝ 7 ක් රෝහලේ",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Polgahawela STF in a car accident. 8 maids and 7 in the hospital",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "Dewalegama Police say that 8 officers and 7 maids belonging to the Police Special Task Force were injured in a car accident on the Rambukkana-Polgahawela main road near the Narangbedda Police Special Task Force camp this morning (2nd).",
        "Dewalegama police said that eight persons including a sergeant working in Narangbedda camp and 7 officers working in Kurunegala camp are undergoing treatment in Kurunegala General Hospital and the maids of Agalum Institute are undergoing treatment in Kegalle General Hospital.",
        "The case related to the incident of damaging the Mawanella Buddha statues was held at the Sabaragamuwa Provincial Kegalle High Court yesterday. A group of officers belonging to the Kurunegala Police Special Task Force camp has arrived at the Rambukkana Narangbedda camp early in the morning to search the court premises where the case is taking place. A group of officers from Narangbedda camp had left at 6.00 am to provide security to the Kegalle High Court and then the Kurunegala group had traveled to Kegalle from Narangbedda at 7.00 am in a cab belonging to Narangbedda camp.",
        "The police said that a bus which was transporting a garment firm from Rambukkana to Polgahawela for official work came at a high speed and collided with the cab when it was about 500 meters towards Hirivadunna.",
        "Later, all the 8 Special Task Force officers in the cab got injured and were admitted to the Kurunegala General Hospital.",
        "7 maids of the bus have been admitted to Kegalle General Hospital with minor injuries and the driver of the bus is also undergoing treatment at Kegalle General Hospital."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Polgahawela",
          "label": "NORP"
        },
        {
          "text": "8",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "7",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "8",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "7",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Police Special Task Force",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Narangbedda Police Special Task Force",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "this morning",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "2nd",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Dewalegama",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "eight",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Narangbedda",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "7",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kurunegala",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kurunegala General Hospital",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "Agalum Institute",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kegalle General Hospital",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the Sabaragamuwa Provincial Kegalle High Court",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "yesterday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Kurunegala Police Special Task Force",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "early in the morning",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "Narangbedda",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "6.00 am",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kurunegala",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kegalle",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Narangbedda",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Narangbedda",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Rambukkana",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Polgahawela",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "about 500 meters",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "Hirivadunna",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "8",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Kurunegala General Hospital",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "7",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kegalle General Hospital",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kegalle General Hospital",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "පොල්ගහවෙල රිය අනතුරකින් එස්.ටී.එෆ්. 8 ක් ඇගලුම් සේවිකාවෝ 7 ක් රෝහලේ",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "රඹුක්කන පොල්ගහවෙල ප්‍රධාන මාර්ගයේ නාරංබැද්ද පොලිස් විශේෂ කාර්ය බළකා කදවුර ආසන්නයේ දී සිදු වු රිය අනතුරකින් පොලිස් විශේෂ කාර්ය බළකායට අයත් නිලධාරින් 8 දෙනෙකු හා ඇගලුම් සේවිකාවන් 7 දෙනෙකු අද (2) වැනිදා පෙරවරුවේ තුවාල ලබා රෝහල් ගත කර ඇතැයි දේවාලේගම පොලිසිය කියයි.",
        "මෙලෙස කුරුණෑගල මහ රෝහලේ නේවාසිකව ප්‍රතිකාර ලබමින් සිටින්නේ නාරංබැද්ද කදවුරේ සේවය කරන සාජන්වරයෙකු හා කුරුණෑගල කදවුරේ සේවය කරන නිලධාරින් 7 කු ඇතුළු 8 දෙනෙකු බවත් ඇගලුම් ආයතනයේ සේවිකාවන් කෑගල්ල මහ රෝහලේ නේවාසිකව ප්රමතිකාර ලබන බවත් දේවාලේගම පොලිසිය පැවසීය.",
        "ඊයේ 02 වැනිදා මාවනැල්ල බුදු පිළිමවලට හානි කිරීමේ සිද්ධිය සම්බන්ධයෙන් නඩුව සබරගමුව පළාත් බද කෑගල්ල මහධිකරණයේ පැවැත්විණ. එම නඩුව පැවැවෙන අධිකරණ භූමිය සෝදිසි කිරීම සදහා  කුරුණෑගල පොලිස් විශේෂ කාර්ය බළකා කදවුරට අයත් නිලධාරින් කණ්ඩායමක් රඹුක්කන නාරංබැද්ද කදවුරට අලුයම පැමිණ තිබේ. නාරංබැද්ද කදවුරේ නිලධාරින් කණ්ඩායමක් අලුයම 6.00 ට කෑගල්ල මහධිකරණයට ආරක්ෂාව සපයා දීම සදහා පිටත්ව ගොස් ඇති අතර පසුව කුරුණෑගල පිරිස පෙරවරු 7.00 ට නාරංබැද්දේ සිට නාරංබැද්ද කදවුරට අයත් කැබ් රථයකින් නිලධාරින් 8 න් සමන්විත  කණ්ඩායමක් කෑගල්ල බලා ගමන් කර තිබුණි.",
        "ගමන් ආරම්භ කර මීටර් 500 ක් පමණ හිරිවඩුන්න දෙසට ගමන් කරමින් සිටින අවස්ථාවේ දී රඹුක්කන සිට පොල්ගහවෙල දක්වා ඇගළුම් ආයතනයක රාජකාරී කටයුතු සදහා ප්‍රවාහන කරමින් තිබුණු බස් රථයක් අධික වේගයෙන් පැමිණ කැබ් රථයේ ගැටී ඇති බවත් පොලිසිය පැවසීය.",
        "පසුව කැබ් රථයේ සිටි විශේෂ කාර්ය බළකායට අයත් නිලධාරින් 8 දෙනාම තුවාල ලබා කුරුණෑගල මහ රෝහලට ඇතුළත් කෙරිණ.",
        "බස් රථයේ ඇගළුම් සේවිකාවන් 7 දෙනෙකු සුළු තුවාල ලබා කෑගල්ල මහ රෝහලට ඇතුළත් කර ඇති අතර බස් රථයේ රියදුරුවරයා ද කෑගල්ල මහ රෝහලේ නේවාසිකව ප්‍රතිකාර ලබයි."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "පොල්ගහවෙල",
          "label": "NORP"
        },
        {
          "text": "8",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "7",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "8",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "7",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "පොලිස් විශේෂ කාර්ය බලකාය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "නාරංබැද්ද පොලිස් විශේෂ කාර්ය බලකාය",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "මේ උදෑසන",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "2 වැනි",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "දේවාලේගම",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "අට",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "නාරංබැද්ද",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "7",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "කුරුණෑගල",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "කුරුණෑගල මහ රෝහල",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "Agalum ආයතනය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "කෑගල්ල මහ රෝහල",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "සබරගමුව පළාත් කෑගල්ල මහාධිකරණය",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඊයේ",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "කුරුණෑගල පොලිස් විශේෂ කාර්ය බලකාය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "උදේ පාන්දර",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "නාරංබැද්ද",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "6.00 පෙ.ව",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "කුරුණෑගල",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "කෑගල්ල",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "නාරංබැද්ද",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "නාරංබැද්ද",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "රඹුක්කන",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "පොල්ගහවෙල",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මීටර් 500 ක් පමණ",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "හිරිවඩුන්න",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "8",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "කුරුණෑගල මහ රෝහල",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "7",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "කෑගල්ල මහ රෝහල",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "කෑගල්ල මහ රෝහල",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "கார் விபத்தில் பொல்கஹவெல STF. மருத்துவமனையில் 8 பணிப்பெண்கள் மற்றும் 7 பேர்",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "ரம்புக்கன - பொல்கஹவெல பிரதான வீதியில் நாரங்கபெத்த பொலிஸ் விசேட அதிரடிப்படை முகாமுக்கு அருகில் இன்று (2ம் திகதி) காலை இடம்பெற்ற வாகன விபத்தில் பொலிஸ் விசேட அதிரடிப்படையைச் சேர்ந்த 8 அதிகாரிகள் மற்றும் 7 பணிப்பெண்கள் காயமடைந்துள்ளதாக தெவலேகம பொலிஸார் தெரிவிக்கின்றனர்.",
        "நாரங்கபெத்த முகாமில் கடமையாற்றும் சார்ஜன்ட் ஒருவரும் குருநாகல் முகாமில் கடமையாற்றும் 7 உத்தியோகத்தர்களும் உட்பட 8 பேர் குருநாகல் பொது வைத்தியசாலையிலும் அகலும் நிறுவனத்தின் பணிப்பெண்கள் கேகாலை பொது வைத்தியசாலையிலும் சிகிச்சை பெற்று வருவதாக தெவலேகம பொலிஸார் தெரிவித்தனர்.",
        "மாவனல்லை புத்தர் சிலைகளை சேதப்படுத்திய சம்பவம் தொடர்பான வழக்கு நேற்று சப்ரகமுவ மாகாண கேகாலை மேல் நீதிமன்றில் நடைபெற்றது. வழக்கு நடைபெற்று வரும் நீதிமன்ற வளாகத்தை சோதனையிடுவதற்காக குருநாகல் பொலிஸ் விசேட அதிரடிப்படை முகாமைச் சேர்ந்த அதிகாரிகள் குழுவொன்று அதிகாலை ரம்புக்கன நாரங்கபெத்த முகாமுக்கு வந்துள்ளது. கேகாலை மேல் நீதிமன்றத்திற்கு பாதுகாப்பு வழங்குவதற்காக நாரங்கபெத்த முகாமில் இருந்து அதிகாரிகள் குழுவொன்று காலை 6.00 மணியளவில் புறப்பட்டுச் சென்றதுடன், குருநாகல் குழுவினர் நாரங்கபெத்த முகாமுக்குச் சொந்தமான கெப் வண்டியில் 7.00 மணியளவில் நாரங்கபெத்தவிலிருந்து கேகாலை நோக்கி பயணித்துள்ளனர்.",
        "உத்தியோகபூர்வ வேலைக்காக ரம்புக்கனையிலிருந்து பொல்கஹவெல நோக்கி ஆடை நிறுவனமொன்றை ஏற்றிச் சென்ற பேருந்து ஒன்று ஹிரிவடுன்ன நோக்கி சுமார் 500 மீற்றர் தூரத்தில் சென்ற போது அதிவேகமாக வந்து கெப் வண்டியுடன் மோதியதாக பொலிஸார் தெரிவித்தனர்.",
        "பின்னர், கெப் வண்டியில் இருந்த 8 விசேட அதிரடிப்படை அதிகாரிகளும் காயமடைந்து குருநாகல் பொது வைத்தியசாலையில் அனுமதிக்கப்பட்டுள்ளனர்.",
        "பேருந்தின் பணிப்பெண்கள் 7 பேர் சிறு காயங்களுடன் கேகாலை பொது வைத்தியசாலையில் அனுமதிக்கப்பட்டுள்ளதுடன், பேருந்தின் சாரதியும் கேகாலை பொது வைத்தியசாலையில் சிகிச்சை பெற்று வருகின்றார்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "பொல்கஹவெல",
          "label": "NORP"
        },
        {
          "text": "8",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "7",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "8",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "7",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "பொலிஸ் விசேட அதிரடிப்படை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "நாரங்கபெட்டா காவல்துறையின் சிறப்பு அதிரடிப்படை",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று காலை",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "2வது",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "தெவலேகம",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "எட்டு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "நாரங்கபெத்தா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "7",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "குருநாகல்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "குருநாகல் பொது வைத்தியசாலை",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "அகலும் நிறுவனம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "கேகாலை பொது வைத்தியசாலை",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "சப்ரகமுவ மாகாண கேகாலை மேல் நீதிமன்றம்",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "நேற்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "குருநாகல் பொலிஸ் விசேட அதிரடிப்படை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "அதிகாலையில்",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "நாரங்கபெத்தா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "காலை 6.00 மணி",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "குருநாகல்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "கேகாலை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "நாரங்கபெத்தா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "நாரங்கபெத்தா",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ரம்புக்கன",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "பொல்கஹவெல",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சுமார் 500 மீட்டர்",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஹிரிவடுன்னா",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "8",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "குருநாகல் பொது வைத்தியசாலை",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "7",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "கேகாலை பொது வைத்தியசாலை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "கேகாலை பொது வைத்தியசாலை",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}