{
  "newspaper_id": "ada-derana-lk",
  "url": "http://www.adaderana.lk/news/84509/seven-arrested-over-torching-of-presidents-residence-remanded-further",
  "time_ut": 1661334960,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Seven arrested over torching of President’s residence remanded further",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Seven arrested over torching of President’s residence remanded further",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "Colombo Fort Magistrate Thilina Gamage has ordered the seven suspects, who are in custody in connection with the torching of President Ranil Wickremesinghe’s private residence, to be further remanded further until September 07.",
        "The magistrate issued the order after considering the objections with regard to granting bail to the suspects, presented by Additional Solicitor General Haripriya Jayasundara who appeared on behalf of the prosecution.",
        "During a protest staged outside President Ranil Wickremesinghe’s private residence on 09th July, a group of people had stormed the premises and later set fire to the establishment which was replete with a rare collection of books and old Buddha statues, most of which Wickremesinghe had inherited."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Seven",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "seven",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "September 07",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Additional Solicitor",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Haripriya Jayasundara",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "09th July",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Buddha",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "ජනපති නිවසට ගිනි තැබීමේ සිද්ධිය සම්බන්ධයෙන් අත්අඩංගුවට ගත් 7ක් යළි රිමාන්ඩ්",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "ජනාධිපති රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතාගේ පෞද්ගලික නිවසට ගිනි තැබීමේ සිද්ධිය සම්බන්ධයෙන් අත්අඩංගුවේ පසුවන සැකකරුවන් හත් දෙනා සැප්තැම්බර් 07 වැනිදා දක්වා තවදුරටත් රිමාන්ඩ් කරන ලෙස කොළඹ කොටුව මහේස්ත්‍රාත් තිළිණ ගමගේ මහතා නියෝග කළේය.",
        "සැකකරුවන්ට ඇප ලබාදීමට අදාළව පැමිණිල්ල වෙනුවෙන් පෙනී සිටි අතිරේක සොලිසිටර් ජනරාල් හරිප්‍රියා ජයසුන්දර මහත්මිය ඉදිරිපත් කළ විරෝධතා සලකා බැලීමෙන් අනතුරුවයි මහේස්ත්‍රාත්වරයා මෙම නියෝගය නිකුත් කළේ.",
        "ජුලි 09 වැනි දින ජනාධිපති රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතාගේ පෞද්ගලික නිවස ඉදිරිපිට පැවති විරෝධතාවයක් අතරතුර කිසියම් පිරිසක් එම පරිශ්‍රයට කඩා වැදී වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතාට උරුම වූ දුර්ලභ පොත්පත් සහ පැරණි බුද්ධ ප්‍රතිමා වලින් පිරී තිබූ ආයතනයට පසුව ගිනි තබා ඇත."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "හත",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "හත",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "සැප්තැම්බර් 07",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "අතිරේක සොලිසිටර්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "හරිප්‍රියා ජයසුන්දර",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජූලි 09",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "බුද්ධ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "ஜனாதிபதியின் இல்லத்திற்கு தீ வைத்த குற்றச்சாட்டில் கைது செய்யப்பட்ட 7 பேர் மீண்டும் விளக்கமறியலில் வைக்கப்பட்டுள்ளனர்",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "ஜனாதிபதி ரணில் விக்ரமசிங்கவின் தனிப்பட்ட இல்லத்திற்கு தீ வைத்த சம்பவம் தொடர்பில் விளக்கமறியலில் வைக்கப்பட்டுள்ள சந்தேகநபர்கள் 7 பேரையும் எதிர்வரும் செப்டெம்பர் 07ஆம் திகதி வரை விளக்கமறியலில் வைக்குமாறு கொழும்பு கோட்டை நீதவான் திலின கமகே உத்தரவிட்டுள்ளார்.",
        "சந்தேகநபர்களுக்கு பிணை வழங்குவது தொடர்பிலான ஆட்சேபனைகளை சட்டத்தரணி சார்பில் ஆஜரான மேலதிக சொலிசிட்டர் ஜெனரல் ஹரிபிரியா ஜயசுந்தர பரிசீலித்தபோதே நீதவான் இந்த உத்தரவை பிறப்பித்துள்ளார்.",
        "ஜூலை 09 ஆம் திகதி ஜனாதிபதி ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்கவின் தனிப்பட்ட இல்லத்திற்கு வெளியே நடத்தப்பட்ட ஆர்ப்பாட்டத்தின் போது, ​​ஒரு குழுவினர் வளாகத்திற்குள் நுழைந்து, பின்னர் விக்ரமசிங்க மரபுரிமையாக பெற்ற அரிய புத்தகங்கள் மற்றும் பழைய புத்தர் சிலைகள் நிறைந்த நிறுவனத்திற்கு தீ வைத்தனர்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ஏழு",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ஏழு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "செப்டம்பர் 07",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "கூடுதல் வழக்கறிஞர்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஹரிப்ரியா ஜெயசுந்தரா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜூலை 09",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "புத்தர்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}