{
  "newspaper_id": "daily-ft-lk",
  "url": "https://www.ft.lk/business/Kirklees-Estate-amongst-record-books-at-Colombo-tea-auctions/34-738030",
  "time_ut": 1659037023,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Kirklees Estate amongst record books at Colombo tea auctions",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Kirklees Estate amongst record books at Colombo tea auctions",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "At the recently concluded Colombo Tea Auction of 27 July, Kirklees Estate established an all-time record price of Rs. 1550/- for a BOPF grade, in the Uda Pussellawa category. This line of tea was purchased by M/s. Adam Expo.",
        "Kirklees Estate is renowned for its high-quality BOP, BOPF and Dust-1 grades, which are highly sought-after teas by buyers at the Colombo Tea Auctions.",
        "Kirklees is situated at an elevation of 1400 meters above mean sea level in the Uda Pussellawa Planting District.  The total extent is 232 hectares with an annual production of 600,000 kgs. of made Tea. Kirklees Estate comes under the stewardship of the Superintendent Chaminda Jayaratne. Eastern Brokers Lrd., are the brokers associated in selling and marketing of Kirklees Estate Teas.",
        "Kirklees Estate comes under the management of Kegalle Plantation and owned by the Richard Peiris Group of Companies."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Kirklees Estate",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Colombo Tea Auction",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "27 July",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kirklees Estate",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "1550/-",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Uda Pussellawa",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Adam Expo",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Kirklees Estate",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "BOP",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Dust-1",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Colombo Tea Auctions",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Kirklees",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "1400 meters",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Uda Pussellawa Planting District",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "232 hectares",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "600,000",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Tea",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Eastern Brokers Lrd",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kirklees Estate Teas",
            "label": "FAC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Kirklees Estate",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kegalle Plantation",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Richard Peiris Group of Companies",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "කොළඹ තේ වෙන්දේසියේ වාර්තා පොත් අතර කර්ක්ලීස් වත්ත",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "පසුගිය ජුලි 27 වැනිදා අවසන් වූ කොළඹ තේ වෙන්දේසියේදී කර්ක්ලීස් වතුයාය සර්වකාලීන වාර්තාගත මිල රු. 1550/- BOPF ශ්‍රේණියක් සඳහා, උඩ පුස්සැල්ලාව කාණ්ඩයේ. මෙම තේ මාර්ගය M/s විසින් මිලදී ගන්නා ලදී. ඇඩම් එක්ස්පෝ.",
        "කර්ක්ලීස් වතුයාය එහි උසස් තත්ත්වයේ BOP, BOPF සහ Dust-1 ශ්‍රේණි සඳහා ප්‍රසිද්ධියක් උසුලන අතර, ඒවා කොළඹ තේ වෙන්දේසියේදී ගැනුම්කරුවන් විසින් ඉහළ ඉල්ලුමක් ඇති තේ වේ.",
        "කර්ක්ලීස් පිහිටා ඇත්තේ උඩ පුස්සැල්ලාව වැවිලි දිස්ත්‍රික්කයේ මධ්‍ය මුහුදු මට්ටමේ සිට මීටර් 1400 ක උන්නතාංශයක ය. මුළු භූමි ප්‍රමාණය හෙක්ටයාර 232 ක් වන අතර වාර්ෂික නිෂ්පාදනය කිලෝග්‍රෑම් 600,000 කි. සාදන ලද තේ වලින්. කර්ක්ලීස් වතුයාය අධිකාරී චමින්ද ජයරත්නගේ භාරකාරත්වය යටතේ පවතී. East Brokers Lrd., Kirklees Estate Teas විකිණීම සහ අලෙවි කිරීම සම්බන්ධ තැරැව්කරුවන් වේ.",
        "කර්ක්ලීස් වත්ත කෑගල්ල වැවිලි සමාගමේ කළමනාකාරීත්වය යටතේ පවතින අතර රිචඩ් පීරිස් සමාගම් සමූහයට අයත් වේ."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "කිර්ක්ලීස් වත්ත",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "කොළඹ තේ වෙන්දේසිය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජූලි 27",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "කිර්ක්ලීස් වත්ත",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "1550/-",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "උඩ පුස්සැල්ලාව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඇඩම් එක්ස්පෝ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "කිර්ක්ලීස් වත්ත",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "BOP",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "දූවිලි-1",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "කොළඹ තේ වෙන්දේසි",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "කිර්ක්ලීස්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "මීටර් 1400",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "උඩ පුස්සැල්ලාව වැවිලි දිස්ත්‍රික්කය",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "හෙක්ටයාර 232 කි",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "600,000 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "තේ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "නැගෙනහිර තැරැව්කරුවන් Lrd",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "කිර්ක්ලීස් වතු තේ",
            "label": "FAC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "කිර්ක්ලීස් වත්ත",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "කෑගල්ල වැවිලි",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "රිචඩ් පීරිස් සමාගම් සමූහය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "கொழும்பு தேயிலை ஏலத்தில் கிர்க்லீஸ் தோட்டம் சாதனை புத்தகங்களில் ஒன்றாகும்",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "ஜுலை 27ஆம் திகதி அண்மையில் நிறைவடைந்த கொழும்பு தேயிலை ஏலத்தில், கிர்க்லீஸ் தோட்டத்தின் அனைத்து கால சாதனை விலையான ரூ. உடா புஸ்ஸல்லாவ பிரிவில் BOPF தரத்திற்கு 1550/-. இந்த தேயிலையை M/s வாங்கினார். ஆடம் எக்ஸ்போ.",
        "Kirklees Estate அதன் உயர்தர BOP, BOPF மற்றும் Dust-1 தரங்களுக்குப் புகழ்பெற்றது, இவை கொழும்பு தேயிலை ஏலத்தில் வாங்குபவர்களால் அதிகம் விரும்பப்படும் தேயிலைகளாகும்.",
        "கிர்க்லீஸ், உடா புஸ்ஸல்லாவ நாற்று மாவட்டத்தில் சராசரி கடல் மட்டத்திலிருந்து 1400 மீற்றர் உயரத்தில் அமைந்துள்ளது. மொத்த பரப்பளவு 232 ஹெக்டேர், ஆண்டு உற்பத்தி 600,000 கிலோ. தயாரிக்கப்பட்ட தேநீர். கிர்க்லீஸ் தோட்டம் அத்தியட்சகர் சமிந்த ஜயரத்னவின் கட்டுப்பாட்டின் கீழ் வருகிறது. கிழக்கு தரகர்கள் Lrd., கிர்க்லீஸ் எஸ்டேட் டீஸ் விற்பனை மற்றும் சந்தைப்படுத்தல் தொடர்பான தரகர்கள்.",
        "கிர்க்லீஸ் தோட்டம் கேகாலை தோட்ட நிர்வாகத்தின் கீழ் உள்ளது மற்றும் ரிச்சர்ட் பீரிஸ் குழும நிறுவனங்களுக்கு சொந்தமானது."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "கிர்க்லீஸ் எஸ்டேட்",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "கொழும்பு தேயிலை ஏலம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "27 ஜூலை",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "கிர்க்லீஸ் எஸ்டேட்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "1550/-",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "உடா புஸ்ஸல்லாவ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆடம் எக்ஸ்போ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "கிர்க்லீஸ் எஸ்டேட்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "BOP",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "தூசி-1",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "கொழும்பு தேயிலை ஏலம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "கிர்க்லீஸ்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "1400 மீட்டர்",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "உடா புஸ்ஸல்லாவ நடவு மாவட்டம்",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "232 ஹெக்டேர்",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "600,000",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "தேநீர்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "கிழக்கு தரகர்கள் Lrd",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "கிர்க்லீஸ் எஸ்டேட் டீஸ்",
            "label": "FAC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "கிர்க்லீஸ் எஸ்டேட்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "கேகாலை தோட்டம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரிச்சர்ட் பீரிஸ் குழும நிறுவனங்கள்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}