{
  "newspaper_id": "news-first-lk",
  "url": "https://www.newsfirst.lk/2022/07/25/president-putin-congratulates-ranil-w-on-election-to-office-of-president/",
  "time_ut": 1658744220,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "President Putin congratulates Ranil W on election to office of President",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "President Putin congratulates Ranil W on election to office of President",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st): Russian President Vladimir Putin has congratulated President  Ranil Wickremesinghe’s election to the office of the Presidency.",
        "In a letter addressed to President Wickremesinghe, the Russian President had also expressed his hopes to further strengthen relations between the two nations.",
        "“I am counting on your activities as Head of State to foster further development of the constructive bilateral cooperation in various spheres for the benefits of our peoples and in the interest of strengthening the regional stability and security,” Russian President Vladimir Putin further said in the letter",
        "Travel ban against six activists including Rev. Fr. Jeewantha, & IUSF Chief",
        "President Putin congratulates Ranil W on election to office of President",
        "Fuel Pass: Implementation from 26th July; Only QR based service from 1st August",
        "Three men nabbed while trying to sell loot from President’s Office"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Putin",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "Ranil W",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "News 1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Russian",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Vladimir Putin",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickremesinghe’s",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Russian",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "two",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Russian",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Vladimir Putin",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "six",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Fr",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Jeewantha, & IUSF",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Putin",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ranil W",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "26th July",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "August",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Three",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "ජනාධිපති ධූරයට තේරී පත් වූ රනිල් ඩබ්ලිව්",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st): ජනාධිපති  රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතා ජනාධිපති කාර්යාලයට තේරී පත්වීම සම්බන්ධයෙන් රුසියානු ජනාධිපති ව්ලැඩිමීර් පුටින් මහතා සුබපැතුම් පළ කර තිබේ.",
        "ජනාධිපති වික්‍රමසිංහ වෙත ලිපියක් යොමු කරමින් රුසියානු ජනාධිපතිවරයා ද දෙරට අතර සබඳතා තවදුරටත් ශක්තිමත් කර ගැනීමට බලාපොරොත්තු වන බව සඳහන් කර තිබේ.",
        "“අපේ ජනතාවගේ ප්‍රතිලාභ සහ කලාපීය ස්ථාවරත්වය සහ ආරක්ෂාව ශක්තිමත් කිරීමේ අවශ්‍යතාවය සඳහා විවිධ ක්ෂේත්‍රවල නිර්මාණාත්මක ද්විපාර්ශ්වික සහයෝගීතාව තවදුරටත් වර්ධනය කිරීම සඳහා රාජ්‍ය නායකයා ලෙස ඔබගේ ක්‍රියාකාරකම් කෙරෙහි මම විශ්වාසය තබමි,” රුසියානු ජනාධිපති ව්ලැඩිමීර් පුටින් වැඩිදුරටත් පැවසීය. ලිපියක්",
        "ගරු පියතුමා ඇතුළු ක්‍රියාකාරීන් හය දෙනෙකුට විදෙස් ගමන් තහනමක් ජීවන්ත සහ අවිශිබම ප්‍රධානී",
        "ජනාධිපති ධූරයට තේරී පත් වූ රනිල් ඩබ්ලිව්",
        "ඉන්ධන අවසරපත්ර: ජූලි 26 සිට ක්රියාත්මක කිරීම; අගෝස්තු 1 සිට QR පදනම් කරගත් සේවාවක් පමණි",
        "ජනාධිපති කාර්යාලයෙන් කොල්ලකෑමට ගිය තිදෙනෙකු මාට්ටු"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "පුටින්",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "රනිල් ඩබ්ලිව්",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "News 1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "රුසියානු",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ව්ලැඩිමීර් පුටින්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහගේ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "රුසියානු",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "දෙක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "රුසියානු",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ව්ලැඩිමීර් පුටින්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "හය",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශා",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජීවන්ත, සහ අවිශිබම",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "පුටින්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "රනිල් ඩබ්ලිව්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ජූලි 26",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "1 වැනි",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "අගෝස්තු",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "තුන්",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "ஜனாதிபதி பதவிக்கு தெரிவு செய்யப்பட்ட ரணில் வுக்கு ஜனாதிபதி புடின் வாழ்த்து தெரிவித்துள்ளார்",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st): ஜனாதிபதி  ரணில் விக்ரமசிங்கே ஜனாதிபதி பதவிக்கு தெரிவு செய்யப்பட்டதற்கு ரஷ்ய ஜனாதிபதி விளாடிமிர் புடின் வாழ்த்து தெரிவித்துள்ளார்.",
        "ஜனாதிபதி விக்கிரமசிங்கவிற்கு அனுப்பிய கடிதத்தில், இரு நாடுகளுக்கும் இடையிலான உறவுகளை மேலும் வலுப்படுத்துவதற்கு ரஷ்ய ஜனாதிபதி நம்பிக்கை வெளியிட்டுள்ளார்.",
        "\"எங்கள் மக்களின் நலன்களுக்காகவும், பிராந்திய ஸ்திரத்தன்மை மற்றும் பாதுகாப்பை வலுப்படுத்தும் நலனுக்காகவும் பல்வேறு துறைகளில் ஆக்கபூர்வமான இருதரப்பு ஒத்துழைப்பை மேலும் மேம்படுத்துவதற்கு, அரச தலைவர் என்ற முறையில் உங்களது செயல்பாடுகளை நான் எதிர்பார்க்கிறேன்\" என்று ரஷ்ய அதிபர் விளாடிமிர் புடின் மேலும் கூறினார். கடிதம்",
        "Rev. Fr உட்பட ஆறு ஆர்வலர்களுக்கு எதிராக பயணத் தடை. ஜீவந்த மற்றும் IUSF தலைவர்",
        "ஜனாதிபதி பதவிக்கு தெரிவு செய்யப்பட்ட ரணில் வுக்கு ஜனாதிபதி புடின் வாழ்த்து தெரிவித்துள்ளார்",
        "எரிபொருள் அனுமதிச் சீட்டு: ஜூலை 26 முதல் அமலாக்கம்; ஆகஸ்ட் 1 முதல் QR அடிப்படையிலான சேவை மட்டுமே",
        "ஜனாதிபதி அலுவலகத்தில் கொள்ளையடிக்க முயன்ற மூவர் கைது செய்யப்பட்டுள்ளனர்"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "புடின்",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "ரணில் டபிள்யூ",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "News 1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரஷ்யன்",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "விளாடிமிர் புடின்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்கவின்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரஷ்யன்",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "இரண்டு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ரஷ்யன்",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "விளாடிமிர் புடின்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஆறு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Fr",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜீவந்த, & IUSF",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "புடின்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரணில் டபிள்யூ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஜூலை 26",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "1வது",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆகஸ்ட்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "மூன்று",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}