{
  "newspaper_id": "daily-mirror-lk",
  "url": "https://www.dailymirror.lk/breaking_news/Search-for-wild-elephant-continues-after-crashing-with-Anthony-s-cab/108-240310",
  "time_ut": 1656926103,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Search for wild elephant continues after crashing with Anthony ’s cab",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Search for wild elephant continues after crashing with Anthony ’s cab",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "The Department of Wildlife Conservation had today deployed two teams to track down the wild elephant involved in the accident at Moragoda in Thalawa in which veteran artiste Jackson Anthony and two others were seriously injured.",
        "A senior official of the Wildlife Conservation Department in Anuradhapura said that the jumbo had fallen twice on the double cab in the impact and that it would have sustained serious injuries.",
        "He said the two teams comprising officers from Thalawa and Anuradhapura Wildlife Conservation offices were now looking for it in Ulukkulama and Weerawewa areas.",
        "Meanwhile Wildlife Veterinary Surgeon in Anuradhapura Zone Dr. Chandana Jayasinghe said the picture appearing in social media as the wild elephant involved in the accident was false and that the wildlife conservators had not been able to trace it by today afternoon. He said the dearth of fuel for the departmental vehicles was an obstacle to the search. (Dayaratne Embogama and B.G.Chaturanga)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Anthony",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "The Department of Wildlife Conservation",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "two",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Thalawa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Jackson Anthony",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "two",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the Wildlife Conservation Department",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "two",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Thalawa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ulukkulama",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Chandana Jayasinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "afternoon",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "Dayaratne Embogama",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "ඇන්තනීගේ කැබ් රථයේ ගැටීමෙන් පසු වන අලි සෙවීම දිගටම කරගෙන යයි",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "ප්‍රවීණ කලාකරු ජැක්සන් ඇන්තනී ඇතුළු දෙදෙනකුට බරපතළ තුවාල සිදු කළ තලාව මොරගොඩ ප්‍රදේශයේ සිදු වූ රිය අනතුරකින් වන අලියා සෙවීමට වනජීවී සංරක්ෂණ දෙපාර්තමේන්තුව අද කණ්ඩායම් දෙකක් යොදවා තිබිණි.",
        "අනුරාධපුර වනජීවී සංරක්ෂණ දෙපාර්තමේන්තුවේ ජ්‍යෙෂ්ඨ නිලධාරියෙකු සඳහන් කළේ මෙම ගැටීමෙන් ජම්බෝ රථය ඩබල් කැබ් රථය මතට දෙවරක් වැටී ඇති අතර බරපතල තුවාල සිදුවන්නට ඇති බවයි.",
        "තලාව සහ අනුරාධපුර වනජීවී සංරක්ෂණ කාර්යාලවල නිලධාරීන්ගෙන් සමන්විත කණ්ඩායම් දෙක මේ වන විට උළුක්කුලම සහ වීරවැව ප්‍රදේශවල එය සොයමින් සිටින බව ඔහු පැවසීය.",
        "මේ අතර අනුරාධපුර කලාපයේ වනජීවී පශු වෛද්‍ය චන්දන ජයසිංහ කියා සිටියේ අනතුරට ලක්වූ වන අලියා ලෙස සමාජ මාධ්‍යවල පළවන පින්තූරය අසත්‍ය බවත් අද පස්වරුව වන විටත් වනජීවී සංරක්ෂණ නිලධාරීන්ට සොයා ගැනීමට නොහැකි වූ බවයි. දෙපාර්තමේන්තු වාහන සඳහා ඉන්ධන හිඟවීම සෝදිසි කිරීමට බාධාවක් බව ඔහු පැවසීය. (දයාරත්න එම්බෝගම සහ බී.ජී. චතුරංග)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ඇන්තනි",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "වනජීවී සංරක්ෂණ දෙපාර්තමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "දෙක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "තලාව",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජැක්සන් ඇන්තනි",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "දෙක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "වනජීවී සංරක්ෂණ දෙපාර්තමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "දෙක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "තලාව",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "උළුක්කුලම",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "චන්දන ජයසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "දහවල්",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "දයාරත්න ඇම්බෝගම",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "அந்தோணி வண்டி மீது மோதிய காட்டு யானையை தேடும் பணி தொடர்கிறது",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "தலாவ மொரகொடவில் இடம்பெற்ற விபத்தில் சிரேஷ்ட கலைஞர் ஜேக்சன் அந்தோனி மற்றும் இருவர் படுகாயமடைந்த காட்டு யானையை கண்டுபிடிப்பதற்காக வனஜீவராசிகள் பாதுகாப்பு திணைக்களம் இன்று இரண்டு குழுக்களை நியமித்துள்ளது.",
        "அநுராதபுரத்தில் உள்ள வனஜீவராசிகள் பாதுகாப்பு திணைக்களத்தின் உயர் அதிகாரி ஒருவர், இந்த தாக்கத்தில் இரட்டை வண்டியின் மீது ஜம்போ இரண்டு முறை விழுந்ததாகவும், அது பலத்த காயங்களுக்கு ஆளாகியிருக்கும் என்றும் கூறினார்.",
        "தலாவ மற்றும் அநுராதபுரம் வனஜீவராசிகள் பாதுகாப்பு அலுவலக அதிகாரிகளை உள்ளடக்கிய இரண்டு குழுக்கள் தற்போது உலுக்குளம மற்றும் வீரவெவ பிரதேசங்களில் தேடுவதாக அவர் கூறினார்.",
        "இதேவேளை, காட்டு யானை விபத்துக்குள்ளானதாக சமூக ஊடகங்களில் வெளியான படம் பொய்யானது எனவும், இன்று பிற்பகல் வரை வனவிலங்கு காப்பாளர்களால் அதனை கண்டுபிடிக்க முடியவில்லை எனவும் அனுராதபுரம் வலய வனவிலங்கு கால்நடை வைத்திய நிபுணர் டொக்டர் சந்தன ஜயசிங்க தெரிவித்துள்ளார். துறைசார்ந்த வாகனங்களுக்கு எரிபொருள் பற்றாக்குறையே தேடுதலுக்கு தடையாக உள்ளது என்றார். (தயாரத்ன எம்போகம மற்றும் பி.ஜி.சதுரங்க)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "அந்தோணி",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "வனவிலங்கு பாதுகாப்பு திணைக்களம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இரண்டு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "தலைவா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜாக்சன் ஆண்டனி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இரண்டு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "வனவிலங்கு பாதுகாப்பு துறை",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இரண்டு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "தலைவா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "உளுக்குளம",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "சந்தன ஜயசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "பிற்பகல்",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "தயாரத்ன எம்போகம",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}