{
  "newspaper_id": "news-first-lk",
  "url": "https://www.newsfirst.lk/2022/07/01/pucsl-in-talks-with-lioc-for-fuel/",
  "time_ut": 1656670560,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "PUCSL in talks with LIOC for Fuel",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "PUCSL in talks with LIOC for Fuel",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); The Public Utilities Commission of Sri Lanka (PUCSL) has commenced discussions with Lanka IOC to provide diesel for the Ceylon Electricity Board (CEB) for the next 55 days.",
        "The Chairman of the Public Utilities Commission of Sri Lanka Janaka Ratnayake said that he discusses the matters with the Managing Director of Lanka IOC Manoj Gupta.",
        "The PUCSL said that diesel power plants had generated about 13 GW hours of total power generation on Wednesday (29)."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "The Public Utilities Commission",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Ceylon Electricity Board",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "CEB",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the next 55 days",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the Public Utilities Commission",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Janaka Ratnayake",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "PUCSL",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "GW hours",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Wednesday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "29",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "PUCSL ඉන්ධන සඳහා LIOC සමඟ සාකච්ඡා කරයි",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); ඉදිරි දින 55 සඳහා ලංකා විදුලිබල මණ්ඩලයට (CEB) ඩීසල් සැපයීම සඳහා ශ්‍රී ලංකා මහජන උපයෝගිතා කොමිෂන් සභාව (PUCSL) Lanka IOC සමඟ සාකච්ඡා ආරම්භ කර ඇත.",
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකා මහජන උපයෝගිතා කොමිෂන් සභාවේ සභාපති ජානක රත්නායක මහතා පැවසුවේ, ලංකා IOC හි කළමනාකාර අධ්‍යක්ෂ මනෝජ් ගුප්තා මහතා සමඟ මේ පිළිබඳව සාකච්ඡා කරන බවයි.",
        "ඩීසල් බලාගාර මගින් බදාදා (29) මුළු විදුලි ජනනයෙන් ගිගාවොට් පැය 13ක් පමණ ජනනය කර ඇති බව මහජන උපයෝගිතා කොමිසම පවසයි."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "මහජන උපයෝගිතා කොමිෂන් සභාව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ලංකා විදුලිබල මණ්ඩලය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ලංවිම",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉදිරි දින 55",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "මහජන උපයෝගිතා කොමිෂන් සභාව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජානක රත්නායක",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "PUCSL",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "GW පැය",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "බදාදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "29",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "PUCSL எரிபொருளுக்காக LIOC உடன் பேச்சுவார்த்தை நடத்துகிறது",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); இலங்கை மின்சார சபைக்கு (CEB) டீசலை அடுத்த 55 நாட்களுக்கு வழங்குவது தொடர்பாக இலங்கை பொதுப் பயன்பாடுகள் ஆணைக்குழு (PUCSL) லங்கா IOC உடன் கலந்துரையாடலை ஆரம்பித்துள்ளது.",
        "லங்கா ஐஓசியின் முகாமைத்துவப் பணிப்பாளர் மனோஜ் குப்தாவுடன் இது தொடர்பில் கலந்துரையாடுவதாக இலங்கை பொதுப் பயன்பாடுகள் ஆணைக்குழுவின் தலைவர் ஜானக ரத்நாயக்க தெரிவித்துள்ளார்.",
        "புதன்கிழமை (29) டீசல் மின் உற்பத்தி நிலையங்கள் மொத்த மின் உற்பத்தியில் சுமார் 13 GW மணிநேரத்தை உற்பத்தி செய்துள்ளதாக PUCSL தெரிவித்துள்ளது."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "பொது பயன்பாட்டு ஆணையம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை மின்சார சபை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "CEB",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "அடுத்த 55 நாட்கள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பொது பயன்பாட்டு ஆணையம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜனக ரத்நாயக்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "PUCSL",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "GW மணிநேரம்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "புதன்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "29",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}