{
  "newspaper_id": "lankadeepa-lk",
  "url": "https://www.lankadeepa.lk/latest_news/අර්බුදයට-හේතුව--රජය-ජනතාව-රැවටීමයි/1-616006",
  "time_ut": 1657190828,
  "original_lang": "si",
  "original_title": "අර්බුදයට හේතුව  රජය ජනතාව රැවටීමයි",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "The reason for the crisis is that the government is deceiving the people",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "Opposition leader Mr. Sajith Premadasa said in Colombo today (7) that the current government has deceived the people in every field and due to such deception, the country is currently facing a huge crisis.",
        "The leader of the opposition mentioned that the people including himself have never deceived the people as an opposition and even from the opposition they have done a lot of work for the people under the 'Husma' program.",
        "He said this in a discussion held with various parties at the opposition leader's office that Samagi Janabalawega is a party with a social democratic program.",
        "The leader of the opposition said that the government had even deceived the farmers and that due to shortage of fertilizers, the harvest of Maas season has decreased by 50 percent.",
        "A group of party representatives, including Janasetha Peramuna party leader Battaramulale Selarathana Thera, were present for this."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Sajith",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "7",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Husma",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Samagi Janabalawega",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Maas",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "50 percent",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Janasetha Peramuna",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Battaramulale Selarathana Thera",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "අර්බුදයට හේතුව  රජය ජනතාව රැවටීමයි",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "වර්තමාන රජය සෑම ක්ෂේත්‍රයකින්ම ජනතාව රවටා ඇති බවත් එසේ රැවටීමෙන් වර්තමානයේ රට දැවැන්ත අර්බුධයකට මුහුණ පා ඇති බවත් විපක්ෂ නායක සජිත් ප්‍රේමදාස මහතා කොළඹදී අද(7) පැවසීය.",
        "විපක්ෂයක් ලෙස තමන් ඇතුලු පිරිස කිසිදා ජනතාව රවටා නැති අතර ‘හුස්ම‘ වැඩසටහන යටතේ විපක්ෂයේ සිට පවා ජනතාව වෙනුවෙන් විශාල වැඩකොටසක් සිදු කර ඇති බවත් විපක්ෂනායකවරයා සඳහන් කළේය.",
        "සමගි ජනබලවේගය  කියන දේ කරන සමාජ ප්‍රජාතනත්‍රවාදී වැඩපිළිවෙළක් සහිත පක්ෂයක් බවත් විවිධ පක්ෂ සමග විපක්ෂ නායක කාර්යාලයේදී පැවැති සාකච්ඡාවකදී ඔහු මේ බව පැවසීය.",
        "රජය ගොවීන් පවා රැවටූ බවත්  මේ වන විට පොහොර හිගය නිසා මාස් කන්නයේ අස්වැන්න සියයට 50කින් අඩු වූ බවත් විපක්ෂනායකවරයා පැවසීය.",
        "ජනසෙත පෙරමුණේ පකෂ නායක බත්තරමුලලේ සීලරතන හිමි ඇතුලු පක්ෂ නියෝජිතයින් පිරිසක් මේ සඳහා එක්ව සිටියහ."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "සජිත්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "7",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "හුස්මා",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "සමගි ජනබලවේග",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "මාස්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "සියයට 50 කි",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ජනසෙත පෙරමුණ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "බත්තරමුලේ සේලරතන හිමි",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "அரசாங்கம் மக்களை ஏமாற்றுவதே நெருக்கடிக்குக் காரணம்",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "தற்போதைய அரசாங்கம் சகல துறைகளிலும் மக்களை ஏமாற்றி வருவதாகவும், இவ்வாறான ஏமாற்றுகளால் நாடு தற்போது பாரிய நெருக்கடியை எதிர்நோக்கியுள்ளதாகவும் எதிர்க்கட்சித் தலைவர் திரு.சஜித் பிரேமதாச இன்று (7) கொழும்பில் தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "தாம் உட்பட மக்கள் எதிர்க்கட்சி என்ற ரீதியில் மக்களை ஒருபோதும் ஏமாற்றவில்லை எனவும், எதிர்க்கட்சியாக இருந்தும் ஹஸ்மா திட்டத்தின் கீழ் மக்களுக்கு பல பணிகளை செய்துள்ளதாகவும் எதிர்க்கட்சித் தலைவர் குறிப்பிட்டுள்ளார்.",
        "சமகி ஜனபலவேக சமூக ஜனநாயக வேலைத்திட்டம் கொண்ட கட்சி என எதிர்க்கட்சித் தலைவர் அலுவலகத்தில் பல்வேறு தரப்பினருடன் இடம்பெற்ற கலந்துரையாடலில் அவர் இதனைத் தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "அரசாங்கம் விவசாயிகளைக் கூட ஏமாற்றிவிட்டதாகவும், உரத் தட்டுப்பாட்டினால் மாஸ் பருவத்தின் அறுவடை 50 வீதத்தால் குறைந்துள்ளதாகவும் எதிர்க்கட்சித் தலைவர் தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "இதற்கு ஜனசெத பெரமுன கட்சியின் தலைவர் பத்தரமுலே செளரதன தேரர் உட்பட கட்சி பிரதிநிதிகள் குழுவொன்று பிரசன்னமாகியிருந்தது."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "சஜித்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "7",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஹஸ்மா",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "சமகி ஜனபாலவேகா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "மாஸ்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "50 சதவீதம்",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஜனசேத பெரமுன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "பத்தரமுலே செளரதன தேரர்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}