{
  "newspaper_id": "island-lk",
  "url": "http://island.lk/ceat-adopts-new-model-to-honour-top-dealers-of-2020-21/",
  "time_ut": 1659100020,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "CEAT adopts new model to honour top dealers of 2020-21",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "CEAT adopts new model to honour top dealers of 2020-21",
      "author": "Thilina Walpola",
      "body_lines": [
        "CEAT Kelani Holdings has honoured 99 leading tyre dealers in Sri Lanka by presenting them with award trophies, cash prizes and certificates at their doorsteps, adapting to the challenges of the times to continue its tradition of recognising those who contributed to the Company’s growth.Substituting the usual gala awards weekend at a five-star hotel with visits to the top performing tyre dealers of 2020-21, CEAT has presented a total of 14 trophies, 85 certificates and 85 cash cheques to reward overall excellence as well as top sales performances under four product categories – Radial tyres, Truck tyres, Light Truck tyres and Three-wheeler tyres.",
        "The trophies were presented to the Top 10 dealers who generated the highest sales revenue for the brand, and to the Gold award winning dealers in each product category.CEAT also presented cash cheques to the highest performing dealers in lieu of the customary overseas trips they usually enjoy according to their respective loyalty ratings of Platinum, Gold and Silver.",
        "“The circumstances we are in are not conducive for the conduct of a conventional dealer awards night, but we felt strongly that it is important to acknowledge our loyal dealers, who are also facing many challenges,” CEAT Kelani Managing Director Ravi Dadlani said. “We look forward to interacting with them and their families once again whenever the situation permits the hosting of an awards event.”",
        "The theme chosen for the unusual dealer awards initiative was ‘Striving for unity to conquer’ highlighting the importance of working together to overcome the challenges confronting businesses in Sri Lanka.",
        "CEAT’s top 10 dealers of 2020-21 were the Dealer of the Year U&H Wheel Service of Colombo 2, Sumith Marketing – Ambalangoda, Nanda Tyre House – Vavuniya, Sumidag Tyre Co – Kurunegala, Paramount Tyre Traders – Colombo 14, Sripali Tyre House – Anuradhapura, Supiri Tyre House – Kandy, Crown Tyres – Colombo 14, Tyre Link – Walasmulla and Asanka Tyre House – Madampe.",
        "The manufacturer of half of the Sri Lanka’s pneumatic tyre requirements, CEAT Kelani Holdings is considered one of the most successful India – Sri Lanka joint ventures. The joint venture’s cumulative investment in Sri Lanka to date exceeds Rs 8 billion, and another Rs 3.2 billion has been committed in 2022 for expansion of volumes, technology upgrades and new product development. The company’s manufacturing operations in Sri Lanka encompass tyres in the radial (passenger cars, vans and SUVs), commercial (nylon and radial), motorcycle, three-wheeler and agricultural vehicle segments.",
        "Founder Chairman, Nippon Donation Foundation, hoping to invest in multiple projects in Sri Lanka",
        "‘Sri Lanka missing out on billions of dollars in oil and gas Foreign Direct Investment’",
        "Leave a Reply Cancel replyYour email address will not be published. Required fields are marked *Comment Name *",
        "Save my name, email, and website in this browser for the next time I comment."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "CEAT",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "2020-21",
          "label": "DATE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "CEAT Kelani Holdings",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "99",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Company",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "weekend",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "five",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "2020-21",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "CEAT",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "14",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "85",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "85",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "four",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Truck",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Light Truck",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Three",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "10",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "CEAT",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Platinum, Gold and Silver",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "night",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ravi Dadlani",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "CEAT",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "10",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "2020-21",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Dealer of",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sumith Marketing",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sumidag Tyre Co",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kurunegala",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "14",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Tyre House",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Anuradhapura",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kandy",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "14",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "half",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "CEAT Kelani Holdings",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "India",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Rs 8 billion",
            "label": "LAW"
          },
          {
            "text": "2022",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "three",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Nippon Donation Foundation",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "billions of dollars",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "Foreign Direct Investment’",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [],
        []
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "2020-21 වසරේ ප්‍රමුඛ පෙළේ අලෙවිකරුවන්ට ගෞරව දැක්වීම සඳහා සියැට් නව මාදිලිය අනුගමනය කරයි",
      "author": "තිළිණ වල්පොල",
      "body_lines": [
        "සියැට් කැලණි හෝල්ඩිංග්ස් සමාගම ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ ප්‍රමුඛ පෙළේ ටයර් අලෙවිකරුවන් 99 දෙනෙකුට සම්මාන කුසලාන, මුදල් ත්‍යාග සහ සහතික පත්‍ර ඔවුන්ගේ දොරකඩින් ප්‍රදානය කරමින්, සමාගමේ වර්ධනයට දායක වූවන් පිළිගැනීමේ සම්ප්‍රදාය අඛණ්ඩව ඉදිරියට ගෙන යාම සඳහා යුගයේ අභියෝගවලට අනුගත වෙමින් ගෞරවාදරයට පත් කර ඇත. සාමාන්‍ය ගාලා සම්මාන සති අන්තයේ තරු පහේ හෝටලයකදී 2020-21 වසරේ ඉහළම ක්‍රියාකාරී ටයර් අලෙවි නියෝජිතයන් හමුවීමට, සියැට් විසින් සමස්ත විශිෂ්ටත්වයට මෙන්ම හතරක් යටතේ ඉහළම විකුණුම් කාර්ය සාධනය වෙනුවෙන් කුසලාන 14ක්, සහතික 85ක් සහ මුදල් චෙක්පත් 85ක් පිරිනමා ඇත. නිෂ්පාදන කාණ්ඩ - රේඩියල් ටයර්, ට්‍රක් ටයර්, සැහැල්ලු ට්‍රක් ටයර් සහ ත්‍රිරෝද රථ ටයර්.",
        "සන්නාමය සඳහා ඉහළම විකුණුම් ආදායමක් උපයාගත් හොඳම අලෙවි නියෝජිතයන් 10 දෙනාට සහ එක් එක් නිෂ්පාදන කාණ්ඩයේ රන් සම්මානලාභී අලෙවි නියෝජිතයන් වෙත කුසලාන පිරිනැමිණි. සියැට් සාමාන්‍ය විදේශ සංචාර වෙනුවට ඉහළම කාර්යසාධනයක් ඇති අලෙවි නියෝජිතයන් වෙත මුදල් චෙක්පත් ප්‍රදානය කරන ලදී. ප්ලැටිනම්, රන් සහ රිදී යන ඔවුන්ගේ ලැදියා ශ්‍රේණිගත කිරීම් අනුව භුක්ති විඳින්න.",
        "\"අප සිටින තත්ත්වය සාම්ප්‍රදායික අලෙවි නියෝජිත සම්මාන රාත්‍රියක් පැවැත්වීම සඳහා හිතකර නොවන නමුත් අභියෝග රැසකට මුහුණ දී සිටින අපගේ විශ්වාසවන්ත අලෙවිකරුවන් පිළිගැනීම වැදගත් බව අපට දැඩි ලෙස හැඟුණා\" යැයි සියැට් කැලණි කළමනාකාර අධ්‍යක්ෂ රවී ඩඩ්ලානි මහතා පැවසීය. \"සම්මාන උළෙලක් පැවැත්වීම සඳහා තත්වය ඉඩ දෙන සෑම විටම ඔවුන් සහ ඔවුන්ගේ පවුල් සමඟ නැවත වරක් අන්තර් ක්‍රියා කිරීමට අපි බලාපොරොත්තු වෙමු.\"",
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ ව්‍යාපාර මුහුණ දෙන අභියෝග ජය ගැනීම සඳහා එක්ව ක්‍රියා කිරීමේ වැදගත්කම හුවා දක්වමින් අසාමාන්‍ය අලෙවි නියෝජිත සම්මාන ප්‍රදානෝත්සවය සඳහා තේමා කර ඇත්තේ ‘ජය ගැනීමට එකමුතුකම සඳහා වෙහෙසීම’ යන්නයි.",
        "සියැට් හි 2020-21 වසරේ හොඳම අලෙවි නියෝජිතයින් 10 දෙනා වූයේ කොළඹ 2 වසරේ U&H රෝද සේවාවේ අලෙවි නියෝජිතයා, සුමිත් අලෙවිකරණය - අම්බලන්ගොඩ, නන්දා ටයර් හවුස් - වවුනියාව, සුමිදාග් ටයර් සමාගම - කුරුණෑගල, පැරමවුන්ට් ටයර් ට්‍රේඩර්ස් - කොළඹ 14, ශ්‍රීපාලිපුර ටයර් හවුස් - අනුරාධපුර ටයර් හවුස් ය. , සුපිරි ටයර් හවුස් - මහනුවර, ක්‍රවුන් ටයර් - කොළඹ 14, ටයර් ලින්ක් - වලස්මුල්ල සහ අසංක ටයර් හවුස් - මාදම්පේ.",
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ වායුමය ටයර් අවශ්‍යතාවයෙන් අඩක් නිෂ්පාදකයා වන සියැට් කැලණි හෝල්ඩිංග්ස් වඩාත් සාර්ථක ඉන්දීය - ශ්‍රී ලංකා හවුල් ව්‍යාපාරයක් ලෙස සැලකේ. මේ දක්වා ශ්‍රී ලංකාව තුළ ඒකාබද්ධ ව්‍යාපාරයේ සමුච්චිත ආයෝජනය රුපියල් බිලියන 8 ඉක්මවන අතර, පරිමාව පුළුල් කිරීම, තාක්‍ෂණික වැඩිදියුණු කිරීම් සහ නව නිෂ්පාදන සංවර්ධනය සඳහා තවත් රුපියල් බිලියන 3.2 ක් 2022 දී කැප කර ඇත. සමාගමේ ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ නිෂ්පාදන මෙහෙයුම් රේඩියල් (මගී මෝටර් රථ, වෑන් සහ SUV), වාණිජ (නයිලෝන් සහ රේඩියල්), යතුරුපැදි, ත්‍රිරෝද රථ සහ කෘෂිකාර්මික වාහන යන අංශවල ටයර් ඇතුළත් වේ.",
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ විවිධ ව්‍යාපෘති සඳහා ආයෝජනය කිරීමට බලාපොරොත්තු වන Nippon Donation Foundation හි නිර්මාතෘ සභාපති",
        "‘ශ‍්‍රී ලංකාවට ඩොලර් බිලියන ගණනක තෙල් හා ගෑස් විදේශ සෘජු ආයෝජන මග හැරී යයි’",
        "පිළිතුරක් දෙන්න පිළිතුර අවලංගු කරන්න ඔබගේ විද්‍යුත් තැපැල් ලිපිනය ප්‍රකාශයට පත් නොකෙරේ. අවශ්‍ය ක්ෂේත්‍ර සලකුණු කර ඇත *අදහස් නම *",
        "මම ඊළඟ වතාවේ අදහස් දැක්වීම සඳහා මගේ නම, විද්‍යුත් තැපෑල සහ වෙබ් අඩවිය මෙම බ්‍රවුසරයේ සුරකින්න."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "සියැට්",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "2020-21",
          "label": "DATE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "සියැට් කැලණි හෝල්ඩින්ග්ස්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "99",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "සමාගම",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "සති අන්තය",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "පහ",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "2020-21",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "සියැට්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "14",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "85",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "85",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "හතර",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ට්රක් රථය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "සැහැල්ලු ට්රක් රථය",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "තුන්",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "10",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "සියැට්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ප්ලැටිනම්, රන් සහ රිදී",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "රෑ",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "රවී ඩඩ්ලානි",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "සියැට්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "10",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "2020-21",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "බෙදාහරින්නා",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "සුමිත් මාර්කටින්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "සුමිදාග් ටයර් සමාගම",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "කුරුණෑගල",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "14",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ටයර් හවුස්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "අනුරාධපුර",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මහනුවර",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "14",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "අඩක්",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "සියැට් කැලණි හෝල්ඩින්ග්ස්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "රුපියල් බිලියන 8යි",
            "label": "LAW"
          },
          {
            "text": "2022",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "තුන්",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "නිපොන් පරිත්‍යාග පදනම",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ඩොලර් බිලියන ගණනක්",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "සෘජු විදේශ ආයෝජන'",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [],
        []
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "2020-21 ஆம் ஆண்டின் சிறந்த டீலர்களை கௌரவிக்க சியட் புதிய மாடலை ஏற்றுக்கொள்கிறது",
      "author": "திலின வல்பொல",
      "body_lines": [
        "CEAT Kelani Holdings இலங்கையின் முன்னணி டயர் டீலர்கள் 99 பேருக்கு அவர்களின் வீட்டு வாசலில் விருதுக் கோப்பைகள், ரொக்கப் பரிசுகள் மற்றும் சான்றிதழ்களை வழங்கி கௌரவித்துள்ளது, காலத்தின் சவால்களுக்கு ஏற்ப, நிறுவனத்தின் வளர்ச்சிக்கு பங்களித்தவர்களை அங்கீகரிக்கும் பாரம்பரியத்தைத் தொடர்கிறது. வழக்கமான காலா விருதுகள் வார இறுதியில் ஐந்து நட்சத்திர ஹோட்டலில் 2020-21 இல் சிறந்த செயல்திறன் கொண்ட டயர் டீலர்களை பார்வையிட்டது, CEAT மொத்தம் 14 கோப்பைகள், 85 சான்றிதழ்கள் மற்றும் 85 ரொக்க காசோலைகளை வழங்கியுள்ளது. தயாரிப்பு வகைகள் - ரேடியல் டயர்கள், டிரக் டயர்கள், இலகுரக டிரக் டயர்கள் மற்றும் முச்சக்கர வண்டி டயர்கள்.",
        "பிராண்டிற்கு அதிக விற்பனை வருவாயை ஈட்டிய முதல் 10 டீலர்களுக்கும், ஒவ்வொரு தயாரிப்பு வகையிலும் தங்க விருது பெற்ற டீலர்களுக்கும் கோப்பைகள் வழங்கப்பட்டன. CEAT வழக்கமான வெளிநாட்டு பயணங்களுக்கு பதிலாக அதிக செயல்திறன் கொண்ட டீலர்களுக்கு பண காசோலைகளை வழங்கியது. பிளாட்டினம், தங்கம் மற்றும் வெள்ளியின் அந்தந்த விசுவாச மதிப்பீடுகளின்படி அனுபவிக்கவும்.",
        "\"வழக்கமான டீலர் விருதுகள் இரவை நடத்துவதற்கு நாங்கள் இருக்கும் சூழ்நிலைகள் சாதகமாக இல்லை, ஆனால் பல சவால்களை எதிர்கொண்டிருக்கும் எங்கள் விசுவாசமான டீலர்களை அங்கீகரிப்பது முக்கியம் என்பதை நாங்கள் உறுதியாக உணர்ந்தோம்\" என்று CEAT களனியின் முகாமைத்துவப் பணிப்பாளர் ரவி தத்லானி தெரிவித்தார். \"விருது வழங்கும் நிகழ்வை நடத்துவதற்கு சூழ்நிலை அனுமதிக்கும் போதெல்லாம் அவர்களுடனும் அவர்களது குடும்பங்களுடனும் மீண்டும் ஒருமுறை தொடர்புகொள்வதை நாங்கள் எதிர்நோக்குகிறோம்.\"",
        "இலங்கையில் வணிகங்கள் எதிர்கொள்ளும் சவால்களை வெற்றிகொள்வதற்கு ஒன்றிணைந்து செயற்படுவதன் முக்கியத்துவத்தை எடுத்துக்காட்டும் வகையில் ‘ஒற்றுமையை வெற்றிகொள்ள முயற்சித்தல்’ என்பது அசாதாரணமான டீலர் விருதுகள் முன்முயற்சிக்காக தெரிவுசெய்யப்பட்டது.",
        "CEAT இன் 2020-21 ஆம் ஆண்டின் சிறந்த 10 டீலர்கள், கொழும்பு 2, சுமித் மார்க்கெட்டிங் - அம்பலாங்கொட, நந்தா டயர் ஹவுஸ் - வவுனியா, சுமிடாக் டயர் கோ - குருநாகல், பாரமவுன்ட் டயர் டிரேடர்ஸ் - கொழும்பு 14, ஸ்ரீபாலி டயர் ஹவுஸ் - அனுராதபுர டயர் ஹவுஸ். , சுப்பிரி டயர் ஹவுஸ் – கண்டி, கிரவுன் டயர்ஸ் – கொழும்பு 14, டயர் லிங்க் – வலஸ்முல்ல மற்றும் அசங்க டயர் ஹவுஸ் – மாதம்பே.",
        "இலங்கையின் நியூமேடிக் டயர் தேவைகளில் பாதியை உற்பத்தி செய்யும் சியெட் களனி ஹோல்டிங்ஸ் மிகவும் வெற்றிகரமான இந்தியா - இலங்கை கூட்டு முயற்சிகளில் ஒன்றாக கருதப்படுகிறது. இலங்கையில் இன்றுவரை கூட்டு முயற்சியின் மொத்த முதலீடு 8 பில்லியன் ரூபாவைத் தாண்டியுள்ளது, மேலும் 2022 ஆம் ஆண்டில் தொகுதிகளின் விரிவாக்கம், தொழில்நுட்ப மேம்பாடு மற்றும் புதிய தயாரிப்பு மேம்பாட்டிற்காக மேலும் 3.2 பில்லியன் ரூபாய்கள் வழங்கப்பட்டுள்ளன. இலங்கையில் நிறுவனத்தின் உற்பத்தி நடவடிக்கைகள் ரேடியல் (பயணிகள் கார்கள், வேன்கள் மற்றும் SUVகள்), வர்த்தக (நைலான் மற்றும் ரேடியல்), மோட்டார் சைக்கிள், முச்சக்கர வண்டி மற்றும் விவசாய வாகனப் பிரிவுகளில் டயர்களை உள்ளடக்கியது.",
        "நிப்பான் நன்கொடை அறக்கட்டளையின் ஸ்தாபகத் தலைவர், இலங்கையில் பல திட்டங்களில் முதலீடு செய்ய எதிர்பார்க்கிறார்",
        "‘எண்ணெய் மற்றும் எரிவாயுவில் வெளிநாட்டு நேரடி முதலீட்டில் பில்லியன் கணக்கான டொலர்களை இலங்கை இழக்கிறது’",
        "ஒரு பதிலை விடுங்கள் பதிலை ரத்துசெய் உங்கள் மின்னஞ்சல் முகவரி வெளியிடப்படாது. தேவையான புலங்கள் குறிக்கப்பட்டுள்ளன *கருத்து பெயர் *",
        "அடுத்த முறை நான் கருத்து தெரிவிக்க, எனது பெயர், மின்னஞ்சல் மற்றும் இணையதளத்தை இந்த உலாவியில் சேமிக்கவும்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "சியட்",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "2020-21",
          "label": "DATE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "சியெட் களனி ஹோல்டிங்ஸ்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "99",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "நிறுவனம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "வார இறுதி",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஐந்து",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "2020-21",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சியட்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "14",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "85",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "85",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "நான்கு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "டிரக்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலகுரக டிரக்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "மூன்று",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "10",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "சியட்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "பிளாட்டினம், தங்கம் மற்றும் வெள்ளி",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இரவு",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரவி தத்லானி",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "சியட்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "10",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "2020-21",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "என்ற வியாபாரி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "சுமித் மார்க்கெட்டிங்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "சுமிடாக் டயர் கோ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "குருநாகல்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "14",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "டயர் ஹவுஸ்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "அனுராதபுரம்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "கண்டி",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "14",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பாதி",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சியெட் களனி ஹோல்டிங்ஸ்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்தியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரூ 8 பில்லியன்",
            "label": "LAW"
          },
          {
            "text": "2022",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "மூன்று",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "நிப்பான் நன்கொடை அறக்கட்டளை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பில்லியன் டாலர்கள்",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "அந்நிய நேரடி முதலீடு'",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [],
        []
      ]
    }
  }
}