{
  "newspaper_id": "lankadeepa-lk",
  "url": "https://www.lankadeepa.lk/latest_news/සජබ-ජාතික-ලැයිස්තුවේ-පළමු-පුරප්පාඩුවට-රංජන්ට/1-618806",
  "time_ut": 1661513453,
  "original_lang": "si",
  "original_title": "සජබ ජාතික ලැයිස්තුවේ පළමු පුරප්පාඩුවට රංජන්ට",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Ranjan for the first vacancy in the Sahab national list",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "Opposition leader Sajith Premadasa said in Colombo today (26) that former Member of Parliament Mr. Ranjan Ramanayake will be appointed for the first vacancy in the national list of Samagi Jana Balavega.",
        "The opposition leader also mentioned that Mr. Ranjan Ramanayake will be invited to act as the head of the country's corruption prevention program.",
        "Mr. Ranjan Ramanayake is entitled to partial freedom and should be given full freedom to engage in politics full time, he said this while attending a joint press conference with former Minister of State Ranjan Ramanayake who was pardoned by the President at the office of the opposition leader in Marx Fernando Mawatha, Colombo.",
        "The opposition leader also said that he is extremely happy about the freedom that Mr. Ranjan Ramanayake, who was a people's leader who fought against fraud and corruption, got."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Ranjan",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "first",
          "label": "ORDINAL"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Sajith Premadasa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Colombo",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "26",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ranjan Ramanayake",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "first",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Samagi",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Jana Balavega",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Ranjan Ramanayake",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Ranjan Ramanayake",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "State",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ranjan Ramanayake",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Marx Fernando Mawatha",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Colombo",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Ranjan Ramanayake",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "සජබ ජාතික ලැයිස්තුවේ පළමු පුරප්පාඩුවට රංජන්ට",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "සමගි ජන බලවේගයේ ජාතික ලැයිස්තුවේ ඇති වන පළමු පුරප්පාඩුව සඳහා හිටපු පාර්ලිමේන්තු මන්ත්‍රී රන්ජන් රාමනායක මහතා පත්කිරීමට කටයුතු කරන බව විපක්ෂ නායක සජිත් ප්‍රේමදාස මහතා කොළඹදී අද (26)පැවසීය.",
        "රටේ දූෂණ වංචා වැළැක්වීමේ වැඩපිළිවෙළේ ප්‍රධානියා ලෙස කටයුතු කරන්නැයි රන්ජන් රාමනායක මහතාට ආරාධනා කරන බවත් විපක්ෂ නායකවරයා සඳහන් කළේය.",
        "රන්ජන් රාමනායක මහතාට හිමිව ඇත්තේ අර්ධ නිදහසක් බවත් පූර්ණ කාලීනව දේශපාලනයේ නිරත වීම සඳහා ඔහුට පූර්ණ නිදහස ලබාදීමට කටයුතු කළ යුතු බවත් ජනාධිපති සමාව ලැබූ හිටපු රාජ්‍ය අමාත්‍ය රංජන් රාමනායක මහතා සමඟ කොළඹ මාක්ස් ප්‍රනාන්දු මාවතේ විපක්ෂ නායක කාර්යාලයේදී ඒකාබද්ධ මාධ්‍ය හමුවකට එක්වෙමින් ඔහු මේ බව පැවසීය.",
        "වංචාවට දූෂණයට එරෙහිව සටන් වැදුණු ජනතා නායකයෙකු වූ රන්ජන් රාමනායක මහතාට හිමි වූ නිදහස සම්බන්ධයෙන් තමන් අතිශයින් සතුටට පත්වන බවත් විපක්ෂ නායකවරයා එහිදී කීවේය."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "රන්ජන්",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "පළමුවන",
          "label": "ORDINAL"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "සජිත් ප්‍රේමදාස",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "කොළඹ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "26",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "රන්ජන් රාමනායක",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "පළමුවන",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "සමගි",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජන බලවේගය",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "රන්ජන් රාමනායක",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "රන්ජන් රාමනායක",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "රජයේ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "රන්ජන් රාමනායක",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "මාක්ස් ප්‍රනාන්දු මාවත",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "කොළඹ",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "රන්ජන් රාමනායක",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "சஹாப் தேசிய பட்டியலில் முதல் வெற்றிடத்திற்கு ரஞ்சன்",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "சமகி ஜன பலவேகவின் தேசியப்பட்டியலின் முதலாவது வெற்றிடத்திற்கு முன்னாள் நாடாளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர் திரு.ரஞ்சன் ராமநாயக்க நியமிக்கப்படுவார் என எதிர்க்கட்சித் தலைவர் சஜித் பிரேமதாச இன்று (26) கொழும்பில் தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "நாட்டின் ஊழல் தடுப்பு வேலைத்திட்டத்தின் தலைவராக செயற்படுவதற்கு திரு.ரஞ்சன் ராமநாயக்கவுக்கு அழைப்பு விடுக்கப்படும் எனவும் எதிர்க்கட்சித் தலைவர் குறிப்பிட்டுள்ளார்.",
        "திரு ரஞ்சன் ராமநாயக்கவுக்கு பகுதி சுதந்திரம் உண்டு, முழு நேர அரசியலில் ஈடுபட முழு சுதந்திரம் வழங்கப்பட வேண்டும் என ஜனாதிபதியினால் மன்னிக்கப்பட்ட முன்னாள் இராஜாங்க அமைச்சர் ரஞ்சன் ராமநாயக்கவுடன் இணைந்து ஊடகவியலாளர் சந்திப்பில் கலந்து கொண்ட போதே அவர் மேற்கண்டவாறு தெரிவித்தார். கொழும்பு மார்க்ஸ் பெர்னாண்டோ மாவத்தையில் உள்ள எதிர்க்கட்சித் தலைவர் அலுவலகம்.",
        "மோசடிக்கும் ஊழலுக்கும் எதிராகப் போராடிய மக்கள் தலைவரான திரு.ரஞ்சன் ராமநாயக்கவுக்குக் கிடைத்த சுதந்திரம் குறித்து தாம் மிகவும் மகிழ்ச்சியடைவதாகவும் எதிர்க்கட்சித் தலைவர் தெரிவித்தார்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ரஞ்சன்",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "முதலில்",
          "label": "ORDINAL"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "சஜித் பிரேமதாச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "கொழும்பு",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "26",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரஞ்சன் ராமநாயக்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "முதலில்",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "சமகி",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜன பலவேகா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ரஞ்சன் ராமநாயக்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ரஞ்சன் ராமநாயக்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "நிலை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரஞ்சன் ராமநாயக்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "மார்க்ஸ் பெர்னாண்டோ மாவத்தை",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "கொழும்பு",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ரஞ்சன் ராமநாயக்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}