{
  "newspaper_id": "daily-mirror-lk",
  "url": "https://www.dailymirror.lk/breaking_news/Man-killed-two-injured-in-broad-daylight-shooting-in-Rathgama/108-242114",
  "time_ut": 1659260314,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Man killed, two injured in broad daylight shooting in Rathgama",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Man killed, two injured in broad daylight shooting in Rathgama",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "One person was killed and two others were injured during a shooting by two men on a motorcycle at Gammaddegoda in Rathgama this afternoon.",
        "Police said the gunmen had used a T-56 weapon to carry out the shooting.",
        "Three people were injured in the shooting and admitted to Karapitiya Hospital where one person died while being admitted to the hospital.",
        "The deceased was identified as a 45-year-old resident of Rathgama.",
        "Two persons aged 47 and 29 who were injured in this shooting are currently receiving treatment at Karapitiya Hospital and Rathgama Police are conducting further investigations.(DSB)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "two",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "Rathgama",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "One",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "two",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "two",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Gammaddegoda",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Rathgama",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "this afternoon",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "Three",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Karapitiya Hospital",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "one",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "45-year-old",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Rathgama",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Two",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "47 and 29",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Karapitiya Hospital",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Rathgama Police",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "රත්ගමදී මහ දවල් වෙඩි තැබීමකින් පුද්ගලයෙක් මරුට, දෙදෙනෙකුට තුවාල",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "අද දහවල් රත්ගම ගම්මැද්දෙගොඩදී යතුරුපැදියකින් පැමිණි පුද්ගලයින් දෙදෙනෙකු සිදුකළ වෙඩි තැබීමකින් එක් පුද්ගලයෙකු මියගොස් තවත් දෙදෙනෙකු තුවාල ලබා තිබෙනවා.",
        "වෙඩි තැබීම සඳහා තුවක්කුකරුවන් ටී 56 ගිනි අවියක් භාවිත කර ඇති බව පොලිසිය පවසයි.",
        "වෙඩි තැබීමෙන් පුද්ගලයින් තිදෙනෙකු තුවාල ලබා කරාපිටිය රෝහලට ඇතුළත් කර ඇති අතර එහිදී එක් අයෙකු රෝහල් ගතකරමින් සිටියදී ජීවිතක්ෂයට පත්වුණා.",
        "මියගොස් ඇත්තේ රත්ගම ප්‍රදේශයේ පදිංචි 45 හැවිරිදි පුද්ගලයෙකි.",
        "මෙම වෙඩි තැබීමෙන් තුවාල ලැබූ 47 සහ 29 හැවිරිදි පුද්ගලයින් දෙදෙනෙකු මේ වන විට කරාපිටිය රෝහලේ ප්‍රතිකාර ලබන අතර රත්ගම පොලීසිය වැඩිදුර විමර්ශන සිදු කරයි.(DSB)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "දෙක",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "රත්ගම",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "එක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "දෙක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "දෙක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගම්මැද්දෙගොඩ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "රත්ගම",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "අද පස්වරුවේ",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "තුන්",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "කරාපිටිය රෝහල",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "එක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "45 හැවිරිදිය",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "රත්ගම",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "දෙක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "47 සහ 29",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "කරාපිටිය රෝහල",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "රත්ගම පොලිසිය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "ரத்கமவில் பட்டப்பகலில் இடம்பெற்ற துப்பாக்கிச் சூட்டில் ஒருவர் பலி, இருவர் காயமடைந்துள்ளனர்",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "இன்று பிற்பகல் ரத்கம, கம்மத்தேகொடவில் மோட்டார் சைக்கிளில் வந்த இருவர் மேற்கொண்ட துப்பாக்கிச் சூட்டில் ஒருவர் உயிரிழந்துள்ளதுடன் மேலும் இருவர் காயமடைந்துள்ளனர்.",
        "துப்பாக்கிதாரிகள் T-56 ஆயுதத்தை பயன்படுத்தி துப்பாக்கிச்சூடு நடத்தியதாக பொலிஸார் தெரிவித்தனர்.",
        "துப்பாக்கிச் சூட்டில் மூவர் காயமடைந்து கராப்பிட்டிய வைத்தியசாலையில் அனுமதிக்கப்பட்ட நிலையில் வைத்தியசாலையில் அனுமதிக்கப்பட்ட நிலையில் ஒருவர் உயிரிழந்துள்ளார்.",
        "உயிரிழந்தவர் ரத்கம பகுதியைச் சேர்ந்த 45 வயதுடையவர் என அடையாளம் காணப்பட்டுள்ளார்.",
        "இந்த துப்பாக்கிச் சூட்டில் காயமடைந்த 47 மற்றும் 29 வயதுடைய இருவர் தற்போது கராப்பிட்டிய வைத்தியசாலையில் சிகிச்சை பெற்று வருவதுடன், ரத்கம பொலிஸார் மேலதிக விசாரணைகளை மேற்கொண்டு வருகின்றனர்.(DSB)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "இரண்டு",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "ரத்கம",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ஒன்று",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "இரண்டு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "இரண்டு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "கம்மத்தேகொட",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரத்கம",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று மதியம்",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "மூன்று",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "கராபிட்டிய வைத்தியசாலை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஒன்று",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "45 வயது",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரத்கம",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இரண்டு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "47 மற்றும் 29",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "கராபிட்டிய வைத்தியசாலை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரத்கம பொலிஸ்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}