{
  "newspaper_id": "lankadeepa-lk",
  "url": "https://www.lankadeepa.lk/news/පොහොට්ටුවේ-නිල-සහාය-රනිල්ට/101-616483",
  "time_ut": 1657897235,
  "original_lang": "si",
  "original_title": "පොහොට්ටුවේ නිල සහාය රනිල්ට",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Pohottuva's official support to Ranil",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "The General Secretary of Sri Lanka Podujana Peramuna, Member of Parliament Mr. Aegina Sagara Kariyawasam says in a statement that Sri Lanka Podujana Peramuna will support Acting President Ranil Wickramasinghe during the election of the President to be held on the 20th in Parliament.",
        "Mr. Kariyawasam has further said that with the decision that a member of Parliament of the Sri Lanka Podujana Peramuna will run for the presidency, Mr. Ranil Wickramasinghe has decided to support Mr. Wickramasinghe as he thinks that Mr. Wickramasinghe is the most suitable person for the presidency at this time. The announcement is given below."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Pohottuva",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Podujana Peramuna",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Aegina Sagara Kariyawasam",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Podujana Peramuna",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickramasinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the 20th",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Kariyawasam",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament of the Sri Lanka",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Podujana Peramuna",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickramasinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Wickramasinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Wickramasinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "පොහොට්ටුවේ නිල සහාය රනිල්ට",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "පාර්ලිමේන්තුවේදී ලබන 20 වැනිදා පැවැත්වීමට නියමිත ජනාධිපතිවරයා තේරාගැනීමේ අවස්ථාවේදී ශ්‍රී ලංකා පොදුජන පෙරමුණ වැඩබලන ජනාධිපති රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතාට සහයෝගය දක්වන බව ශ්‍රී ලංකා පොදුජන පෙරමුණේ ප්‍රධාන ලේකම්, පාර්ලිමේන්තු මන්ත්‍රී නීතිඥා සාගර කාරියවසම් මහතා නිවේදනයක් නිකුත් කරමින් පවසයි.",
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකා පොදුජන පෙරමුණේ පාර්ලිමේන්තු මන්ත්‍රීවරයකු ජනාධිපති ධූරයට තරග කරන්නේ යැයි තීරණය කිරීමත් සමඟ රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතා මේ අවස්ථාවේදී ජනාධිපති ධූරයට වඩාත් සුදුසු පුද්ගලයා වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතා යැයි හැගෙන හෙයින් සහාය දැක්වීමට තීරණය කළ බවත් කාරියවසම් මහතා වැඩි දුරටත් පවසා තිබේ. එම නිවේදනය පහත දැක්වේ."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "පොහොට්ටුව",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "පොදුජන පෙරමුණ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඒජින සාගර කාරියවසම්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "පොදුජන පෙරමුණ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "20 වැනි",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "කාරියවසම්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකා පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "පොදුජන පෙරමුණ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "ரணிலுக்கு பொஹொட்டுவாவின் உத்தியோகபூர்வ ஆதரவு",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "எதிர்வரும் 20ஆம் திகதி பாராளுமன்றத்தில் நடைபெறவுள்ள ஜனாதிபதித் தேர்தலின் போது, ​​பதில் ஜனாதிபதி ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்கவிற்கு ஸ்ரீலங்கா பொதுஜன பெரமுன ஆதரவளிக்கும் என ஸ்ரீலங்கா பொதுஜன பெரமுனவின் பொதுச் செயலாளரும், நாடாளுமன்ற உறுப்பினருமான திரு.ஏஜினா சாகர காரியவசம் அறிக்கையொன்றில் தெரிவித்துள்ளார்.",
        "ஶ்ரீலங்கா பொதுஜன பெரமுனவின் நாடாளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர் ஒருவர் ஜனாதிபதி தேர்தலில் போட்டியிடுவார் என்ற தீர்மானத்துடன், ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க மிகவும் பொருத்தமானவர் என கருதி அவருக்கு ஆதரவளிக்க தீர்மானித்துள்ளதாக திரு காரியவசம் மேலும் தெரிவித்துள்ளார். இந்த நேரத்தில் ஜனாதிபதி பதவிக்கு. அறிவிப்பு கீழே கொடுக்கப்பட்டுள்ளது."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "பொஹொட்டுவா",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "பொதுஜன பெரமுன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஏஜின சாகர காரியவசம்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "பொதுஜன பெரமுன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "20 ஆம் தேதி",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "காரியவசம்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "பொதுஜன பெரமுன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "விக்கிரமாதித்தன்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "விக்கிரமாதித்தன்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}