{
  "newspaper_id": "ada-derana-lk",
  "url": "http://www.adaderana.lk/news/83235/leave-of-agri-ministry-employees-cancelled-from-july-06",
  "time_ut": 1656062940,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Leave of Agri. Ministry employees cancelled from July 06",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Leave of Agri. Ministry employees cancelled from July 06",
      "body_lines": [
        "Leave of the staff members of all departments under the purview of the Agriculture Ministry will be cancelled effective from July 06.",
        "According to the Agriculture Ministry, the decision was taken to facilitate efficient distribution of urea fertilizer arriving in Sri Lanka from India.",
        "The decision was reached upon the instructions of the Agriculture Ministry.",
        "Earlier this month, Sri Lanka today inked a Line of Credit (LOC) agreement with the Export-Import (EXIM) Bank of India for the purchase of 65,000 metric tonnes of urea fertilizer required for the Yala Season.",
        "In response to an urgent request from the Sri Lankan government, the Indian government decided to extend an LOC of USD 55 million to Sri Lanka for the procurement of urea fertiliser."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "July 06",
          "label": "DATE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "the Agriculture Ministry",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "July 06",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the Agriculture Ministry",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "India",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the Agriculture Ministry",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Earlier this month",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "LOC",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Export-Import",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Bank of India",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "65,000 metric tonnes",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Yala Season",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lankan",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Indian",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "LOC",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "USD 55 million",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "කෘෂිකාර්මික නිවාඩු. ජුලි 06 සිට අමාත්‍යාංශ සේවකයන් අවලංගුයි",
      "body_lines": [
        "කෘෂිකර්ම අමාත්‍යාංශයේ විෂය පථයට අයත් සියලුම දෙපාර්තමේන්තු වල කාර්ය මණ්ඩල සාමාජිකයින්ගේ නිවාඩු ජූලි 06 සිට ක්‍රියාත්මක වේ.",
        "ඉන්දියාවේ සිට ශ්‍රී ලංකාවට පැමිණෙන යූරියා පොහොර කාර්යක්ෂමව බෙදා හැරීමට පහසුකම් සැලසීමේ අරමුණින් මෙම තීරණය ගෙන ඇති බව කෘෂිකර්ම අමාත්‍යාංශය පවසයි.",
        "කෘෂිකර්ම අමාත්‍යාංශයේ උපදෙස් මත මෙම තීරණයට එළැඹ ඇත.",
        "යල කන්නය සඳහා අවශ්‍ය යූරියා පොහොර මෙට්‍රික් ටොන් 65,000ක් මිලදී ගැනීම සඳහා ශ්‍රී ලංකාව මේ මස මුලදී, ඉන්දීය අපනයන-ආනයන (EXIM) බැංකුව සමඟ ණය රේඛාව (LOC) ගිවිසුමකට අත්සන් තැබීය.",
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකා රජයෙන් කළ හදිසි ඉල්ලීමකට ප්‍රතිචාර වශයෙන් යූරියා පොහොර ප්‍රසම්පාදනය සඳහා ශ්‍රී ලංකාවට ඇමෙරිකානු ඩොලර් මිලියන 55ක LOC මුදලක් ලබාදීමට ඉන්දීය රජය තීරණය කළේය."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ජූලි 06",
          "label": "DATE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "කෘෂිකර්ම අමාත්‍යාංශය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජූලි 06",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "කෘෂිකර්ම අමාත්‍යාංශය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "කෘෂිකර්ම අමාත්‍යාංශය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "මේ මාසේ මුල",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "LOC",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "අපනයන-ආනයන",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දියානු බැංකුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "මෙට්‍රික් ටොන් 65,000 කි",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "යල කන්නය",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලාංකික",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දීය",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "LOC",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඩොලර් මිලියන 55 කි",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "அக்ரிக்கு விடுப்பு. ஜூலை 06 முதல் அமைச்சக ஊழியர்கள் ரத்து",
      "body_lines": [
        "விவசாய அமைச்சின் கீழ் உள்ள அனைத்து துறைகளின் ஊழியர்களின் விடுமுறை ஜூலை 06 முதல் ரத்து செய்யப்படுகிறது.",
        "இந்தியாவில் இருந்து இலங்கைக்கு வரும் யூரியா உரத்தை வினைத்திறனாக விநியோகிக்க வசதியாக இந்த முடிவு எடுக்கப்பட்டுள்ளதாக விவசாய அமைச்சு தெரிவித்துள்ளது.",
        "விவசாய அமைச்சின் அறிவுறுத்தலின் பேரில் இந்த முடிவு எட்டப்பட்டுள்ளது.",
        "இம்மாதத் தொடக்கத்தில், யாலா பருவத்திற்குத் தேவையான 65,000 மெற்றிக் தொன் யூரியா உரத்தை கொள்வனவு செய்வதற்கு இலங்கை ஏற்றுமதி இறக்குமதி (EXIM) வங்கியுடன் கடன் வரி (LOC) உடன்படிக்கையில் இன்று கையெழுத்திட்டது.",
        "இலங்கை அரசாங்கத்தின் அவசர கோரிக்கைக்கு இணங்க, யூரியா உரம் கொள்வனவு செய்வதற்கு 55 மில்லியன் அமெரிக்க டொலர்களை இலங்கைக்கு வழங்க இந்திய அரசாங்கம் தீர்மானித்துள்ளது."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ஜூலை 06",
          "label": "DATE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "விவசாய அமைச்சகம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜூலை 06",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "விவசாய அமைச்சகம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்தியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "விவசாய அமைச்சகம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இந்த மாத தொடக்கத்தில்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "LOC",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஏற்றுமதி-இறக்குமதி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "பேங்க் ஆஃப் இந்தியா",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "65,000 மெட்ரிக் டன்",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "யாலா பருவம்",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்தியன்",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "LOC",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "55 மில்லியன் அமெரிக்க டாலர்கள்",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  },
  "title": "Leave of Agri. Ministry employees cancelled from July 06",
  "body_lines": [
    "Leave of the staff members of all departments under the purview of the Agriculture Ministry will be cancelled effective from July 06.",
    "According to the Agriculture Ministry, the decision was taken to facilitate efficient distribution of urea fertilizer arriving in Sri Lanka from India.",
    "The decision was reached upon the instructions of the Agriculture Ministry.",
    "Earlier this month, Sri Lanka today inked a Line of Credit (LOC) agreement with the Export-Import (EXIM) Bank of India for the purchase of 65,000 metric tonnes of urea fertilizer required for the Yala Season.",
    "In response to an urgent request from the Sri Lankan government, the Indian government decided to extend an LOC of USD 55 million to Sri Lanka for the procurement of urea fertiliser."
  ],
  "translate": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Leave of Agri. Ministry employees cancelled from July 06",
      "body_lines": [
        "Leave of the staff members of all departments under the purview of the Agriculture Ministry will be cancelled effective from July 06.",
        "According to the Agriculture Ministry, the decision was taken to facilitate efficient distribution of urea fertilizer arriving in Sri Lanka from India.",
        "The decision was reached upon the instructions of the Agriculture Ministry.",
        "Earlier this month, Sri Lanka today inked a Line of Credit (LOC) agreement with the Export-Import (EXIM) Bank of India for the purchase of 65,000 metric tonnes of urea fertilizer required for the Yala Season.",
        "In response to an urgent request from the Sri Lankan government, the Indian government decided to extend an LOC of USD 55 million to Sri Lanka for the procurement of urea fertiliser."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "July 06",
          "label": "DATE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "the Agriculture Ministry",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "July 06",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the Agriculture Ministry",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "India",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the Agriculture Ministry",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Earlier this month",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "LOC",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Export-Import",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Bank of India",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "65,000 metric tonnes",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Yala Season",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lankan",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Indian",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "LOC",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "USD 55 million",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "කෘෂිකාර්මික නිවාඩු. ජුලි 06 සිට අමාත්‍යාංශ සේවකයන් අවලංගුයි",
      "body_lines": [
        "කෘෂිකර්ම අමාත්‍යාංශයේ විෂය පථයට අයත් සියලුම දෙපාර්තමේන්තු වල කාර්ය මණ්ඩල සාමාජිකයින්ගේ නිවාඩු ජූලි 06 සිට ක්‍රියාත්මක වේ.",
        "ඉන්දියාවේ සිට ශ්‍රී ලංකාවට පැමිණෙන යූරියා පොහොර කාර්යක්ෂමව බෙදා හැරීමට පහසුකම් සැලසීමේ අරමුණින් මෙම තීරණය ගෙන ඇති බව කෘෂිකර්ම අමාත්‍යාංශය පවසයි.",
        "කෘෂිකර්ම අමාත්‍යාංශයේ උපදෙස් මත මෙම තීරණයට එළැඹ ඇත.",
        "යල කන්නය සඳහා අවශ්‍ය යූරියා පොහොර මෙට්‍රික් ටොන් 65,000ක් මිලදී ගැනීම සඳහා ශ්‍රී ලංකාව මේ මස මුලදී, ඉන්දීය අපනයන-ආනයන (EXIM) බැංකුව සමඟ ණය රේඛාව (LOC) ගිවිසුමකට අත්සන් තැබීය.",
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකා රජයෙන් කළ හදිසි ඉල්ලීමකට ප්‍රතිචාර වශයෙන් යූරියා පොහොර ප්‍රසම්පාදනය සඳහා ශ්‍රී ලංකාවට ඇමෙරිකානු ඩොලර් මිලියන 55ක LOC මුදලක් ලබාදීමට ඉන්දීය රජය තීරණය කළේය."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ජූලි 06",
          "label": "DATE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "කෘෂිකර්ම අමාත්‍යාංශය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජූලි 06",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "කෘෂිකර්ම අමාත්‍යාංශය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "කෘෂිකර්ම අමාත්‍යාංශය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "මේ මාසේ මුල",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "LOC",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "අපනයන-ආනයන",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දියානු බැංකුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "මෙට්‍රික් ටොන් 65,000 කි",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "යල කන්නය",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලාංකික",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දීය",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "LOC",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඩොලර් මිලියන 55 කි",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "அக்ரிக்கு விடுப்பு. ஜூலை 06 முதல் அமைச்சக ஊழியர்கள் ரத்து",
      "body_lines": [
        "விவசாய அமைச்சின் கீழ் உள்ள அனைத்து துறைகளின் ஊழியர்களின் விடுமுறை ஜூலை 06 முதல் ரத்து செய்யப்படுகிறது.",
        "இந்தியாவில் இருந்து இலங்கைக்கு வரும் யூரியா உரத்தை வினைத்திறனாக விநியோகிக்க வசதியாக இந்த முடிவு எடுக்கப்பட்டுள்ளதாக விவசாய அமைச்சு தெரிவித்துள்ளது.",
        "விவசாய அமைச்சின் அறிவுறுத்தலின் பேரில் இந்த முடிவு எட்டப்பட்டுள்ளது.",
        "இம்மாதத் தொடக்கத்தில், யாலா பருவத்திற்குத் தேவையான 65,000 மெற்றிக் தொன் யூரியா உரத்தை கொள்வனவு செய்வதற்கு இலங்கை ஏற்றுமதி இறக்குமதி (EXIM) வங்கியுடன் கடன் வரி (LOC) உடன்படிக்கையில் இன்று கையெழுத்திட்டது.",
        "இலங்கை அரசாங்கத்தின் அவசர கோரிக்கைக்கு இணங்க, யூரியா உரம் கொள்வனவு செய்வதற்கு 55 மில்லியன் அமெரிக்க டொலர்களை இலங்கைக்கு வழங்க இந்திய அரசாங்கம் தீர்மானித்துள்ளது."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ஜூலை 06",
          "label": "DATE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "விவசாய அமைச்சகம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜூலை 06",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "விவசாய அமைச்சகம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்தியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "விவசாய அமைச்சகம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இந்த மாத தொடக்கத்தில்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "LOC",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஏற்றுமதி-இறக்குமதி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "பேங்க் ஆஃப் இந்தியா",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "65,000 மெட்ரிக் டன்",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "யாலா பருவம்",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்தியன்",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "LOC",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "55 மில்லியன் அமெரிக்க டாலர்கள்",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}