{
  "newspaper_id": "news-first-lk",
  "url": "https://www.newsfirst.lk/2022/07/15/imf-wants-stability-in-sri-lanka-to-resume-talks/",
  "time_ut": 1657855140,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "IMF wants stability in Sri Lanka to resume talks",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "IMF wants stability in Sri Lanka to resume talks",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); The International Monetary Fund says that it is deeply concerned about the ongoing crisis, it’s impact on the Sri Lankan people, and particularly the poor and the vulnerable groups in Sri Lanka.",
        "“We hope for a resolution of the current situation that would allow for our resumption of a dialogue on an IMF supported program,” said Gerry Rice, the Director of the Communications Department of the IMF.",
        "“The high-level discussions with the authorities that we would need to begin discussions on a program, we hope again, that these would be able to resume as soon as possible. So, you know, looking to do all we can in just an extraordinary difficult situation,” he added,",
        "Sri Lanka’s public debt is assessed as unsustainable and as is the case with every IMF program, not just the case of Sri Lanka, for approval by the Board, he noted.",
        "“And we are not at that stage, but for approval by the Board, a program would require adequate assurances on debt sustainability. So, that’s what I have on this, you know, situation that’s of great concern in Sri Lanka,” said Rice.",
        "Sri Lanka President’s resignation received, official announcement on Friday (15)",
        "Dayasiri requests CJ to consider that President fled the country"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Sri Lanka",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "News 1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "The International Monetary Fund",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lankan",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "IMF",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Gerry Rice",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Communications Department",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka’s",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Board",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Board",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Rice",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Friday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "15",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        []
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "සාකච්ඡා නැවත ආරම්භ කිරීම සඳහා ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ ස්ථාවරත්වය IMF ට අවශ්‍යයි",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); ජාත්‍යන්තර මූල්‍ය අරමුදල පවසන්නේ පවතින අර්බුදය, එය ශ්‍රී ලාංකික ජනතාවට සහ විශේෂයෙන්ම ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ දිළිඳු සහ අවදානමට ලක්විය හැකි කණ්ඩායම්වලට ඇති කරන බලපෑම පිළිබඳව දැඩි කනස්සල්ලෙන් පසුවන බවයි.",
        "IMF හි සන්නිවේදන දෙපාර්තමේන්තුවේ අධ්‍යක්ෂ ජෙරී රයිස් පැවසුවේ “ජාමූඅ සහාය දක්වන වැඩසටහනක් පිළිබඳ සංවාදයක් නැවත ආරම්භ කිරීමට ඉඩ සලසන වත්මන් තත්ත්වය පිළිබඳ විසඳුමක් සඳහා අපි බලාපොරොත්තු වෙමු.",
        "“වැඩසටහනක් පිළිබඳ සාකච්ඡා ආරම්භ කිරීමට අවශ්‍ය බව බලධාරීන් සමඟ ඉහළ මට්ටමේ සාකච්ඡා, අපි නැවත බලාපොරොත්තු වෙනවා, මේවා හැකි ඉක්මනින් නැවත ආරම්භ කිරීමට හැකි වනු ඇතැයි. ඉතින්, ඔබ දන්නවා, අසාමාන්‍ය දුෂ්කර තත්වයක් තුළ අපට කළ හැකි සෑම දෙයක්ම කිරීමට බලාපොරොත්තු වෙනවා, ”ඔහු වැඩිදුරටත් පැවසීය.",
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ රාජ්‍ය ණය තිරසාර නොවන ලෙස තක්සේරු කර ඇති අතර, ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ පමණක් නොව, සෑම ජාත්‍යන්තර මූල්‍ය අරමුදලේ වැඩසටහනකදීම සිදු වන පරිදි, මණ්ඩලයේ අනුමැතිය සඳහා ඔහු සඳහන් කළේය.",
        "“අපි එම අදියරේ නොසිටිමු, නමුත් මණ්ඩලයේ අනුමැතිය සඳහා, වැඩසටහනකට ණය තිරසාරභාවය පිළිබඳ ප්‍රමාණවත් සහතිකයක් අවශ්‍ය වේ. ඉතින්, මේ සම්බන්ධයෙන් මට ඇත්තේ එයයි, ඔබ දන්නවා, ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ විශාල කනස්සල්ලට කරුණක්, ”රයිස් පැවසීය.",
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකා ජනාධිපතිවරයාගේ ඉල්ලා අස්වීම සිකුරාදා (15) නිල නිවේදනය ලැබී ඇත.",
        "ජනපති රටින් පැන ගිය බව සලකන්නැයි දයාසිරි අගවිනිසුරුවරයාගෙන් ඉල්ලා සිටී"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "News 1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජාත්‍යන්තර මුල්‍ය අරමුදල",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලාංකික",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "IMF",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගෙරි රයිස්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "සන්නිවේදන දෙපාර්තමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මණ්ඩලය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "මණ්ඩලය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "සහල්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "සිකුරාදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "15",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        []
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "பேச்சுவார்த்தைகளை மீண்டும் தொடங்க இலங்கையில் ஸ்திரத்தன்மையை IMF விரும்புகிறது",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); இலங்கையில் நிலவும் நெருக்கடி, அது இலங்கை மக்கள் மற்றும் குறிப்பாக ஏழைகள் மற்றும் பாதிக்கப்படக்கூடிய குழுக்களின் மீதான தாக்கம் குறித்து ஆழ்ந்த கவலை கொண்டுள்ளதாக சர்வதேச நாணய நிதியம் தெரிவித்துள்ளது.",
        "IMF இன் தகவல் தொடர்புத் துறையின் இயக்குநர் ஜெர்ரி ரைஸ் கூறுகையில், \"தற்போதைய சூழ்நிலையில் தீர்வு கிடைக்கும் என்று நாங்கள் நம்புகிறோம்.",
        "\"ஒரு திட்டத்தில் விவாதங்களைத் தொடங்க வேண்டும் என்று அதிகாரிகளுடனான உயர்மட்ட விவாதங்கள், அவை கூடிய விரைவில் மீண்டும் தொடங்கும் என்று மீண்டும் நம்புகிறோம். எனவே, உங்களுக்குத் தெரியும், ஒரு அசாதாரண கடினமான சூழ்நிலையில் எங்களால் முடிந்த அனைத்தையும் செய்ய விரும்புகிறோம், ”என்று அவர் மேலும் கூறினார்.",
        "இலங்கையின் பொதுக் கடன் தாங்க முடியாதது என மதிப்பிடப்பட்டுள்ளது, மேலும் ஒவ்வொரு சர்வதேச நாணய நிதியத்தின் திட்டத்திலும் உள்ளது போல், இலங்கையின் விஷயத்தில் மட்டுமல்ல, வாரியத்தின் ஒப்புதலுக்காக, அவர் குறிப்பிட்டார்.",
        "\"மேலும் நாங்கள் அந்த நிலையில் இல்லை, ஆனால் வாரியத்தின் ஒப்புதலுக்கு, ஒரு திட்டத்திற்கு கடன் நிலைத்தன்மை குறித்த போதுமான உத்தரவாதங்கள் தேவைப்படும். எனவே, இது குறித்து எனக்கு என்ன இருக்கிறது, உங்களுக்குத் தெரியும், இது இலங்கையில் மிகவும் கவலைக்குரியது, ”என்று ரைஸ் கூறினார்.",
        "சிறிலங்கா அதிபரின் இராஜினாமா, வெள்ளிக்கிழமை (15) உத்தியோகபூர்வ அறிவிப்பு கிடைத்தது.",
        "ஜனாதிபதி நாட்டை விட்டு வெளியேறியதை கருத்தில் கொள்ளுமாறு தயாசிறி தலைமை நீதிபதியிடம் கோரிக்கை விடுத்துள்ளார்"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "இலங்கை",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "News 1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சர்வதேச நாணய நிதியம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "IMF",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜெர்ரி ரைஸ்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "தகவல் தொடர்பு துறை",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கையின்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "பலகை",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பலகை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "அரிசி",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "வெள்ளி",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "15",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        []
      ]
    }
  }
}