{
  "newspaper_id": "economy-next-com",
  "url": "https://economynext.com/a-second-sri-lankan-police-officer-shoots-himself-in-under-a-month-96699/",
  "time_ut": 1656575700,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "A second Sri Lankan police officer shoots himself in under a month",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "A second Sri Lankan police officer shoots himself in under a month",
      "author": "Neshella Perera",
      "body_lines": [
        "ECONOMYNEXT – A sub inspector (SI) attached to Sri Lanka’s police paramilitary unit the Special Task Force (STF) has shot himself dead using his service weapon in the western town of Kadawatha, the second such incident in June.",
        "The incident occurred Thursday June 30 morning, and police suspect the SI took his own life over a personal matter relating to a private dispute.",
        "The body is being held in the Colombo North Teaching Hospital in Ragama, police said.",
        "Statements are currently being taken from STF personnel at the camp in question.",
        "This is the second incident less than a month where a Sri Lankan police officer died by suicide using their own service weapon.",
        "On June 17 a sergeant attached to the Tangalle police station, in Sri Lanka’s deep south, shot himself with his service weapon outside the Tangalle Deputy Inspector General (DIG)’s office. (Colombo/Jun30/2022)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "second",
          "label": "ORDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "Sri Lankan",
          "label": "NORP"
        },
        {
          "text": "under a month",
          "label": "DATE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka’s",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Special Task Force",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "STF",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kadawatha",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "second",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "June",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Thursday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "June 30",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the Colombo North Teaching Hospital",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ragama",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "STF",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "second",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "less than a month",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lankan",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "June 17",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Tangalle",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka’s",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Tangalle",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "DIG",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Colombo/Jun30/2022",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "දෙවන ශ්‍රී ලාංකික පොලිස් නිලධාරියෙක් මාසයකට අඩු කාලයකදී වෙඩි තබාගෙන සියදිවි නසා ගනී",
      "author": "නෙෂෙල්ලා පෙරේරා",
      "body_lines": [
        "ඉකොනොමිනෙක්ස්ට් - විශේෂ කාර්ය බළකායේ (එස්ටීඑෆ්) ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ පොලිස් පැරාමිලිටරි ඒකකයට අනුයුක්තව සේවය කළ උප පොලිස් පරීක්ෂකවරයකු (එස්අයි) තම සේවා ආයුධයෙන් වෙඩි තබාගෙන සියදිවි හානිකරගෙන ඇත්තේ බටහිර කඩවත නගරයේ දී ය.",
        "ජුනි 30 බ්‍රහස්පතින්දා අලුයම මෙම සිදුවීම සිදුවී ඇති අතර, පෞද්ගලික ආරවුලක් සම්බන්ධ පෞද්ගලික කරුණක් මත එස්අයි සියදිවි නසා ගන්නට ඇතැයි පොලිසිය සැක කරයි.",
        "මෘත ශරීරය රාගම උතුර කොළඹ ශික්ෂණ රෝහලේ තැන්පත් කර ඇති බව පොලිසිය පවසයි.",
        "අදාළ කඳවුරේ සිටින විශේෂ කාර්ය බළකායේ නිලධාරීන්ගෙන් මේ වන විට ප්‍රකාශ සටහන් කර ගනිමින් තිබේ.",
        "මාසයකට අඩු කාලයකදී ශ්‍රී ලාංකික පොලිස් නිලධාරියෙකු තමන්ගේම සේවා අවියක් භාවිතා කර සියදිවි නසාගත් දෙවන සිදුවීම මෙයයි.",
        "ජූනි 17 වැනිදා, ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ ගැඹුරු දකුණේ, තංගල්ල පොලිස් ස්ථානයට අනුයුක්තව සේවය කළ සැරයන්වරයකු, තංගල්ල නියෝජ්‍ය පොලිස්පති (ඩී.අයි.ජී.) කාර්යාලය ඉදිරිපිටදී සිය සේවා ආයුධයෙන් වෙඩි තබාගෙන සියදිවි හානිකර ගත්තේය. (කොළඹ/ජුනි30/2022)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "දෙවැනි",
          "label": "ORDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "ශ්‍රී ලාංකික",
          "label": "NORP"
        },
        {
          "text": "මාසයක් යටතේ",
          "label": "DATE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "විශේෂ කාර්ය බලකාය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "එස්.ටී.එෆ්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "කඩවත",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "දෙවැනි",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජූනි",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "බ්රහස්පතින්දා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජූනි 30",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "උතුරු කොළඹ ශික්ෂණ රෝහල",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "රාගම",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "එස්.ටී.එෆ්",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "දෙවැනි",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "මාසයකට අඩු",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලාංකික",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ජූනි 17",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "තංගල්ල",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "තංගල්ල",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඩී.අයි.ජී",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "කොළඹ/ජුනි30/2022",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "ஒரு மாதத்திற்குள் இரண்டாவது இலங்கை பொலிஸ் அதிகாரி தன்னைத்தானே சுட்டுக் கொண்டார்",
      "author": "நெஷெல்லா பெரேரா",
      "body_lines": [
        "எகனாமினெக்ஸ்ட் - இலங்கையின் பொலிஸ் துணை இராணுவப் பிரிவின் (STF) துணைப் பரிசோதகர் (SI) ஒருவர், கடவத்தை மேற்கு நகரத்தில் தனது சேவை ஆயுதத்தைப் பயன்படுத்தி தன்னைத்தானே சுட்டுக் கொண்டு தற்கொலை செய்து கொண்டார், இது ஜூன் மாதத்தில் நடந்த இரண்டாவது சம்பவம்.",
        "இச்சம்பவம் ஜூன் 30 வியாழன் காலை நடந்தது, தனிப்பட்ட தகராறு தொடர்பான தனிப்பட்ட விஷயத்திற்காக எஸ்ஐ தனது உயிரை மாய்த்துக் கொண்டதாக போலீசார் சந்தேகிக்கின்றனர்.",
        "சடலம் ராகமவில் உள்ள கொழும்பு வடக்கு போதனா வைத்தியசாலையில் வைக்கப்பட்டுள்ளதாக பொலிஸார் தெரிவித்தனர்.",
        "குறித்த முகாமில் உள்ள STF பணியாளர்களிடம் தற்போது வாக்குமூலம் எடுக்கப்பட்டு வருகிறது.",
        "ஒரு மாதத்திற்குள் இலங்கை பொலிஸ் உத்தியோகத்தர் ஒருவர் தமது சேவை ஆயுதத்தை பயன்படுத்தி தற்கொலை செய்துகொண்ட இரண்டாவது சம்பவம் இதுவாகும்.",
        "ஜூன் 17 அன்று, இலங்கையின் ஆழமான தெற்கில் உள்ள தங்காலை பொலிஸ் நிலையத்தில் கடமையாற்றும் சார்ஜென்ட் ஒருவர் தங்காலை பிரதிப் பொலிஸ் பரிசோதகர் (டிஐஜி) அலுவலகத்திற்கு வெளியே தனது சேவை ஆயுதத்தால் தன்னைத்தானே சுட்டுக் கொண்டார். (கொழும்பு/ஜூன்30/2022)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "இரண்டாவது",
          "label": "ORDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "இலங்கை",
          "label": "NORP"
        },
        {
          "text": "ஒரு மாதத்திற்குள்",
          "label": "DATE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கையின்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சிறப்பு அதிரடிப்படை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "எஸ்.டி.எஃப்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "கடவத்த",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இரண்டாவது",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜூன்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "வியாழன்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜூன் 30",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "கொழும்பு வடக்கு போதனா வைத்தியசாலை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ராகம",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "எஸ்.டி.எஃப்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இரண்டாவது",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஒரு மாதத்திற்கும் குறைவாக",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஜூன் 17",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "தங்கல்லை",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கையின்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "தங்கல்லை",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "டி.ஐ.ஜி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "கொழும்பு/ஜூன்30/2022",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}