{
  "newspaper_id": "ada-lk",
  "url": "https://www.ada.lk/breaking_news/දේශපාලනයෙන්-තොරව-සහාය-දෙනවානම්-මාස-6න්-රට-සාමාන්‍ය-තත්ත්වයට/11-396878",
  "time_ut": 1662292666,
  "original_lang": "si",
  "original_title": "දේශපාලනයෙන් තොරව සහාය දෙනවානම් මාස 6න් රට සාමාන්‍ය තත්ත්වයට",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "If supported without politics, the country will be back to normal in 6 months",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "Former state minister Mr. Anuradha Jayaratne said that if the leader who took charge of the country to overcome the economic crisis of the country is supported without party color politics, the country's economy will be balanced within a short period of six months.",
        "The former state minister said that after participating as the chief guest in the softball cricket tournament held by the Nawalapitiya Police on (04) on the occasion of the 156th Police Day.",
        "Mr. Anuradha Jayaratne, the former Minister of State, who commented further, said that Mr. Gotabhaya Rajapaksa, who held the position of President of the country for a short period of two years, is a leader with a wealth of experience.",
        "Mr. Anuradha Jayaratne claims that in order to get those experiences from Mr. Gotabhaya Rajapaksa, he should be involved in active politics and give those experiences to the next generation.",
        "Mr. Anuradha Jayaratne further said that due to the increase in the price of fuel, the price of many essential food items has increased and has severely affected the people of the entire country, and it is only a short-term problem."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "6 months",
          "label": "DATE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Anuradha Jayaratne",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "six months",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the Nawalapitiya Police",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Anuradha Jayaratne",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "State",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Gotabhaya Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "two years",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Anuradha Jayaratne",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Gotabhaya Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Anuradha Jayaratne",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "දේශපාලනයෙන් තොරව සහාය දෙනවානම් මාස 6න් රට සාමාන්‍ය තත්ත්වයට",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "රටේ පවතින ආර්ථික අර්බුධය ජය ගැනිමට රට භාරගත් නායකයාට පක්ෂ පාට භේද දේශපාලනයෙන් තොරව සහයෝගය දක්වන්නේ නම් මාස හයක් වැනි කෙටි කාලයක් තුල රටේ ආර්ථිකය සමාන්‍ය තත්ත්වයට පත් වන බව හිටපු රාජ්‍ය අමාත්‍ය අනුරාධ ජයරත්න මහතා පැවසිය.",
        "156 වෙනි පොලිස් දිනය නිමිතෙන් නාවලපිටිය පොලිසිය විසින් (04) දින නාවලපිටිය ජයතිලක ක්‍රිඩාංගණයේ පැවති සැහැල්ලු පන්දු ක්‍රිකට් තරගාවලියට ප්‍රධාන ආරාධිතයා වශයෙන් සහභාගි විමෙන් අනතුරුව මාධ්‍ය හමුවේ හිටපු රාජ්‍ය අමාත්‍යවරයා ඒ බැව් පැවසිය.",
        "මෙහිදි වැඩිදුරටත් අදහස් දැක් වු හිටපු රාජ්‍ය අමාත්‍ය අනුරාධ ජයරත්න මහතා කියා සිටියේ වසර දෙකක කෙටි කාලයක් රටේ ජනාධිපති ධුරය දැරු ගෝඨාභය රජපක්ෂ මහතා අත්දැකිම් බහුල නායකයෙකු බවයි.",
        "ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ මහතාගෙන් එම අත්දැකිම් ලබාගැනිමට එතුමා සක්‍රිය දේශපාලනයට එක් කර ගනිමින් එම අත්දැකිම් ඊලග තරුණ පරපුරට ලබාදිය යුතු බවයි අනුරාධ ජයරත්න මහතා කියා සිටින්නේ.",
        "ඉන්ධන මිල ඉහල යාම හමුවේ අතවශ්‍ය ආහාර ද්‍රව්‍ය රැසකම මිල ඉහල ගොස් තිබිම සමස්ත රටේ ජනතාවටම දැඩි ලෙස බලපැම් ඇති කර ඇති බවත්, එය කෙටි කාලින ගැටළුවක් පමණක් බවයි අනුරාධ ජයරත්න මහතා වැඩිදුරටත් කියා සිටියේ."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "මාස 6 යි",
          "label": "DATE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "අනුරාධ ජයරත්න",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "මාස හයක්",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "නාවලපිටිය පොලිසිය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "අනුරාධ ජයරත්න",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "රජයේ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "අවුරුදු දෙකක්",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "අනුරාධ ජයරත්න",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "අනුරාධ ජයරත්න",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "அரசியல் இல்லாமல் ஆதரித்தால் 6 மாதத்தில் நாடு இயல்பு நிலைக்குத் திரும்பும்",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "நாட்டின் பொருளாதார நெருக்கடியை போக்க நாட்டைப் பொறுப்பேற்ற தலைவருக்கு கட்சி நிற அரசியலின்றி ஆதரவளித்தால் ஆறுமாத காலத்துக்குள் நாட்டின் பொருளாதாரம் சீராகும் என முன்னாள் இராஜாங்க அமைச்சர் திரு அனுராத ஜயரத்ன தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "156வது பொலிஸ் தினத்தை முன்னிட்டு நாவலப்பிட்டி பொலிஸாரால் (04) நடாத்தப்பட்ட மென்பந்து கிரிக்கட் சுற்றுப்போட்டியில் பிரதம அதிதியாக கலந்து கொண்ட பின்னர் முன்னாள் இராஜாங்க அமைச்சர் இவ்வாறு தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "மேலும் கருத்து தெரிவித்த முன்னாள் இராஜாங்க அமைச்சர் திரு.அனுராத ஜயரத்ன, நாட்டின் ஜனாதிபதியாக இரண்டு வருடங்கள் என்ற குறுகிய காலமே பதவி வகித்த திரு.கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ஷ அனுபவச் செல்வம் கொண்ட தலைவர்.",
        "திரு.கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ஷவிடம் இருந்து அந்த அனுபவங்களைப் பெறுவதற்கு தான் தீவிர அரசியலில் ஈடுபட்டு அடுத்த தலைமுறைக்கு அந்த அனுபவங்களை வழங்க வேண்டும் என திரு.அனுராத ஜயரத்ன கூறுகிறார்.",
        "எரிபொருள் விலையேற்றம் காரணமாக பல அத்தியாவசிய உணவுப் பொருட்களின் விலைகள் அதிகரித்து முழு நாட்டு மக்களையும் கடுமையாகப் பாதித்துள்ளதுடன், இது குறுகிய காலப் பிரச்சினையே எனவும் திரு அனுராத ஜயரத்ன மேலும் தெரிவித்தார்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "6 மாதங்கள்",
          "label": "DATE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "அனுராதா ஜயரத்ன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆறு மாதங்கள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "நாவலப்பிட்டி பொலிஸ்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "அனுராதா ஜயரத்ன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "நிலை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "கோத்தபாய ராஜபக்ச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இரண்டு ஆண்டுகளுக்கு",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "அனுராதா ஜயரத்ன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "கோத்தபாய ராஜபக்ச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "அனுராதா ஜயரத்ன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}