{
  "newspaper_id": "daily-mirror-lk",
  "url": "https://www.dailymirror.lk/latest_news/Allegations-against-Nimal-Siripala-committee-submits-report/342-242116",
  "time_ut": 1659274528,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Allegations against Nimal Siripala: committee submits report",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Allegations against Nimal Siripala: committee submits report",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "The report of the three-member committee, which was appointed by President Ranil Wickremesinghe to conduct an Investigation into the bribery allegation against former minister Nimal Siripala de Silva, was handed over to Secretary to the President Saman Ekanayake today.",
        "The President's Media Division said the report was handed over by Retired High Court Judge and President's Counsel Kusala Sarojini Weerawardena at the Presidential Secretariat today.",
        "The President appointed the Committee headed by Retired High Court Judge and President's Counsel Kusala Sarojini Weerawardena, Retired Senior DIGs of Police S. M. Wickremasinghe, a Retired Special Grade Officer of Sri Lanka Administrative Service S.M.G.K. Perera on July 22 and asked them to submit the investigation report to him before July 31."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Nimal Siripala",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "three",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Nimal Siripala de Silva",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Saman Ekanayake",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Media Division",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Counsel Kusala Sarojini Weerawardena",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Presidential Secretariat",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Committee",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Counsel Kusala Sarojini Weerawardena, Retired Senior DIGs of",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "S. M. Wickremasinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka Administrative Service",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "July 22",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "July 31",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "නිමල් සිරිපාලට චෝදනා: කමිටුව වාර්තාවක්",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "හිටපු අමාත්‍ය නිමල් සිරිපාල ද සිල්වාට එරෙහි අල්ලස් චෝදනාව සම්බන්ධයෙන් විමර්ශනයක් සිදුකිරීමට ජනාධිපති රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතා විසින් පත්කළ ත්‍රිපුද්ගල කමිටු වාර්තාව අද ජනාධිපති ලේකම් සමන් ඒකනායක මහතා වෙත භාර දෙනු ලැබුවා.",
        "ජනාධිපති මාධ්‍ය අංශය පැවසුවේ, විශ්‍රාමලත් මහාධිකරණ විනිසුරු සහ ජනාධිපති නීතීඥ කුසලා සරෝජනී වීරවර්ධන මහත්මිය විසින් අදාළ වාර්තාව අද ජනාධිපති කාර්යාලයේදී භාරදුන් බව ය.",
        "විශ්‍රාමලත් මහාධිකරණ විනිසුරු සහ ජනාධිපති නීතීඥ කුසලා සරෝජනී වීරවර්ධන, විශ්‍රාමික පොලිස් ජ්‍යෙෂ්ඨ නියෝජ්‍ය පොලිස්පති එස්. පෙරේරා ජුලි 22 වැනිදා ඔවුන්ගෙන් ඉල්ලා සිටියේ විමර්ශන වාර්තාව ජූලි 31 වැනිදාට පෙර තමාට ලබාදෙන ලෙසය."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "නිමල් සිරිපාල",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "තුන්",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "නිමල් සිරිපාල ද සිල්වා",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "සමන් ඒකනායක",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "මාධ්ය අංශය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "නීතීඥ කුසලා සරෝජිනී වීරවර්ධන",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජනාධිපති ලේකම් කාර්යාලය",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "කමිටුවක්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "නීතීඥ කුසලා සරෝජිනී වීරවර්ධන, විශ්‍රාමික ජ්‍යෙෂ්ඨ නියෝජ්‍ය පොලිස්පතිවරුන්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "එස් එම් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකා පරිපාලන සේවය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජූලි 22",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජූලි 31",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "நிமல் சிறிபாலவுக்கு எதிரான குற்றச்சாட்டுகள்: குழு அறிக்கை சமர்ப்பித்தது",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "முன்னாள் அமைச்சர் நிமல் சிறிபால டி சில்வாவுக்கு எதிரான இலஞ்ச ஊழல் குற்றச்சாட்டு தொடர்பில் விசாரணைகளை மேற்கொள்வதற்காக ஜனாதிபதி ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்கவினால் நியமிக்கப்பட்ட மூவரடங்கிய குழுவின் அறிக்கை ஜனாதிபதியின் செயலாளர் சமன் ஏக்கநாயக்கவிடம் இன்று கையளிக்கப்பட்டது.",
        "ஓய்வுபெற்ற மேல் நீதிமன்ற நீதிபதியும் ஜனாதிபதி சட்டத்தரணியுமான குசலா சரோஜினி வீரவர்தனவினால் இந்த அறிக்கை இன்று ஜனாதிபதி செயலகத்தில் கையளிக்கப்பட்டதாக ஜனாதிபதி ஊடகப் பிரிவு தெரிவித்துள்ளது.",
        "ஓய்வுபெற்ற மேல் நீதிமன்ற நீதிபதியும் ஜனாதிபதி சட்டத்தரணியுமான குசலா சரோஜினி வீரவர்தன, ஓய்வுபெற்ற சிரேஷ்ட பொலிஸ் மா அதிபர் எஸ்.எம்.விக்ரமசிங்க, இலங்கை நிர்வாக சேவையின் ஓய்வுபெற்ற விசேட தர அதிகாரி எஸ்.எம்.ஜி.கே ஆகியோர் தலைமையிலான குழுவை ஜனாதிபதி நியமித்தார். பெரேரா ஜூலை 22 அன்று, விசாரணை அறிக்கையை ஜூலை 31 க்கு முன் தன்னிடம் சமர்ப்பிக்கும்படி கேட்டுக் கொண்டார்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "நிமல் சிறிபால",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "மூன்று",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "நிமல் சிறிபால டி சில்வா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "சமன் ஏக்கநாயக்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஊடகப் பிரிவு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "சட்டத்தரணி குசலா சரோஜினி வீரவர்தன",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜனாதிபதி செயலகம்",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "குழு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "சட்டத்தரணி குசலா சரோஜினி வீரவர்தன, ஓய்வுபெற்ற சிரேஷ்ட பிரதி பொலிஸ் மா அதிபர்கள்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "எஸ்.எம். விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை நிர்வாக சேவை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜூலை 22",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜூலை 31",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}