{
  "newspaper_id": "ada-derana-lk",
  "url": "http://www.adaderana.lk/news/83240/imf-delegation-assures-support-for-sri-lanka-",
  "time_ut": 1656080100,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "IMF delegation assures support for Sri Lanka",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "IMF delegation assures support for Sri Lanka",
      "author": "",
      "body_lines": [
        "The visiting delegation of the International Monetary Fund (IMF) has assured President Gotabaya Rajapaksa that they would assist Sri Lanka in this crisis situation in compliance with the IMF’s policies.",
        "The meeting between the IMF delegation and the Head of State took place at the President’s House in Colombo this evening (June 24)."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Sri Lanka",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "the International Monetary Fund",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Gotabaya Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "IMF",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "IMF",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "this evening",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "June 24",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "ජාත්‍යන්තර මූල්‍ය අරමුදලේ නියෝජිතයින් ශ්‍රී ලංකාවට සහාය දෙන බවට සහතික වෙයි",
      "author": "",
      "body_lines": [
        "ජාත්‍යන්තර මූල්‍ය අරමුදලේ ප්‍රතිපත්තිවලට අනුකූලව මෙම අර්බුදකාරී තත්ත්වය තුළ ශ්‍රී ලංකාවට සහය වන බවට ජාත්‍යන්තර මූල්‍ය අරමුදලේ (IMF) සංචාරයක නිරත වූ නියෝජිත පිරිස ජනාධිපති ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ මහතාට සහතික වී තිබේ.",
        "ජාත්‍යන්තර මූල්‍ය අරමුදලේ නියෝජිත පිරිස සහ රාජ්‍ය නායකයා අතර හමුව අද (ජුනි 24) සවස කොළඹ ජනාධිපති මන්දිරයේදී පැවැත්විණි."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ජාත්‍යන්තර මුල්‍ය අරමුදල",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "IMF",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "IMF",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "අද සවස",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජූනි 24",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "சர்வதேச நாணய நிதியத்தின் பிரதிநிதிகள் இலங்கைக்கு ஆதரவளிப்பதாக உறுதியளித்துள்ளனர்",
      "author": "",
      "body_lines": [
        "இந்த நெருக்கடியான சூழ்நிலையில் இலங்கைக்கு சர்வதேச நாணய நிதியத்தின் கொள்கைகளுக்கு இணங்க உதவுவதாக சர்வதேச நாணய நிதியத்தின் (IMF) பிரதிநிதிகள் ஜனாதிபதி கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ஷவிடம் உறுதியளித்துள்ளனர்.",
        "சர்வதேச நாணய நிதியத்தின் பிரதிநிதிகளுக்கும் அரச தலைவருக்கும் இடையிலான சந்திப்பு கொழும்பில் உள்ள ஜனாதிபதி மாளிகையில் இன்று (ஜூன் 24) மாலை இடம்பெற்றது."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "இலங்கை",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "சர்வதேச நாணய நிதியம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "IMF",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "IMF",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று மாலை",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜூன் 24",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  },
  "title": "IMF delegation assures support for Sri Lanka",
  "body_lines": [
    "The visiting delegation of the International Monetary Fund (IMF) has assured President Gotabaya Rajapaksa that they would assist Sri Lanka in this crisis situation in compliance with the IMF’s policies.",
    "The meeting between the IMF delegation and the Head of State took place at the President’s House in Colombo this evening (June 24)."
  ],
  "translate": {
    "en": {
      "title": "IMF delegation assures support for Sri Lanka",
      "author": "",
      "body_lines": [
        "The visiting delegation of the International Monetary Fund (IMF) has assured President Gotabaya Rajapaksa that they would assist Sri Lanka in this crisis situation in compliance with the IMF’s policies.",
        "The meeting between the IMF delegation and the Head of State took place at the President’s House in Colombo this evening (June 24)."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Sri Lanka",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "the International Monetary Fund",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Gotabaya Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "IMF",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "IMF",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "this evening",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "June 24",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "ජාත්‍යන්තර මූල්‍ය අරමුදලේ නියෝජිතයින් ශ්‍රී ලංකාවට සහාය දෙන බවට සහතික වෙයි",
      "author": "",
      "body_lines": [
        "ජාත්‍යන්තර මූල්‍ය අරමුදලේ ප්‍රතිපත්තිවලට අනුකූලව මෙම අර්බුදකාරී තත්ත්වය තුළ ශ්‍රී ලංකාවට සහය වන බවට ජාත්‍යන්තර මූල්‍ය අරමුදලේ (IMF) සංචාරයක නිරත වූ නියෝජිත පිරිස ජනාධිපති ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ මහතාට සහතික වී තිබේ.",
        "ජාත්‍යන්තර මූල්‍ය අරමුදලේ නියෝජිත පිරිස සහ රාජ්‍ය නායකයා අතර හමුව අද (ජුනි 24) සවස කොළඹ ජනාධිපති මන්දිරයේදී පැවැත්විණි."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ජාත්‍යන්තර මුල්‍ය අරමුදල",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "IMF",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "IMF",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "අද සවස",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජූනි 24",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "சர்வதேச நாணய நிதியத்தின் பிரதிநிதிகள் இலங்கைக்கு ஆதரவளிப்பதாக உறுதியளித்துள்ளனர்",
      "author": "",
      "body_lines": [
        "இந்த நெருக்கடியான சூழ்நிலையில் இலங்கைக்கு சர்வதேச நாணய நிதியத்தின் கொள்கைகளுக்கு இணங்க உதவுவதாக சர்வதேச நாணய நிதியத்தின் (IMF) பிரதிநிதிகள் ஜனாதிபதி கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ஷவிடம் உறுதியளித்துள்ளனர்.",
        "சர்வதேச நாணய நிதியத்தின் பிரதிநிதிகளுக்கும் அரச தலைவருக்கும் இடையிலான சந்திப்பு கொழும்பில் உள்ள ஜனாதிபதி மாளிகையில் இன்று (ஜூன் 24) மாலை இடம்பெற்றது."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "இலங்கை",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "சர்வதேச நாணய நிதியம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "IMF",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "IMF",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று மாலை",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜூன் 24",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}