{
  "newspaper_id": "daily-ft-lk",
  "url": "https://www.ft.lk/news/SL-Bangladesh-commit-to-boost-ties/56-736661",
  "time_ut": 1656096533,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "SL, Bangladesh commit to boost ties",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "SL, Bangladesh commit to boost ties",
      "author": "",
      "body_lines": [
        "Sri Lanka and Bangladesh this week recognised that time is right to further strengthen economic cooperation between the two countries.",
        "Bangladesh High Commissioner to Sri Lanka Tareq Ariful Islam said such a course will lead to progress in a number of areas, including apparel, agriculture, health and investment.",
        "The High Commissioner made these remarks when he called on President Gotabaya Rajapaksa on Thursday.",
        "This year 2022 marks the 50th anniversary of diplomatic relations between the two countries. During this period, both States were able to work very closely and amicably. President Rajapaksa also appreciated Bangladesh’s support in the current economic crisis.",
        "The High Commissioner pointed out that there is an opportunity for both countries to strengthen cooperation in the fields of trade, tourism and education and expressed confidence that Sri Lanka will be able to overcome the current situation expeditiously."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Bangladesh",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Bangladesh",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "this week",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "two",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Islam",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Gotabaya Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Thursday",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "This year",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "50th",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "two",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Bangladesh",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "ශ්‍රී ලංකාව සහ බංග්ලාදේශය සබඳතා ඉහළ නැංවීමට කැපවී සිටිති",
      "author": "",
      "body_lines": [
        "දෙරට අතර ආර්ථික සහයෝගීතාව තවදුරටත් ශක්තිමත් කිරීමට කාලය එළඹ ඇති බව ශ්‍රී ලංකාව සහ බංග්ලාදේශය මේ සතියේ පිළිගත්තේය.",
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ බංග්ලාදේශ මහ කොමසාරිස් Tareq Ariful Islam පැවසුවේ එවැනි පාඨමාලාවක් ඇඟලුම්, කෘෂිකර්මය, සෞඛ්‍ය සහ ආයෝජන ඇතුළු ක්ෂේත්‍ර ගණනාවක ප්‍රගතියට හේතු වනු ඇති බවයි.",
        "මහ කොමසාරිස්වරයා මෙම අදහස් පළ කළේ බ්‍රහස්පතින්දා ජනාධිපති ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ මහතා හමුවූ අවස්ථාවේදීය.",
        "මෙම වසර 2022 දෙරට අතර රාජ්‍ය තාන්ත්‍රික සබඳතාවලට වසර 50ක් සපිරේ. මෙම කාල සීමාව තුළ රාජ්‍යයන් දෙකටම ඉතා සමීපව සහ සුහදව කටයුතු කිරීමට හැකි විය. වත්මන් ආර්ථික අර්බුදයේදී බංග්ලාදේශයේ සහයෝගය ද ජනාධිපතිතුමා අගය කළේය.",
        "වෙළෙඳ, සංචාරක සහ අධ්‍යාපන ක්ෂේත්‍රවල සහයෝගිතාව ශක්තිමත් කර ගැනීමට දෙරටටම අවස්ථාවක් පවතින බව පෙන්වා දුන් මහ කොමසාරිස්වරයා වත්මන් තත්ත්වය කඩිනමින් ජය ගැනීමට ශ්‍රී ලංකාවට හැකි වනු ඇතැයි විශ්වාසය පළ කළේය."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "බංග්ලාදේශය",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "බංග්ලාදේශය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මෙම සතිය",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "දෙක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉස්ලාම්",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "බ්රහස්පතින්දා",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "මේ වසරේ",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "50 වැනි",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "දෙක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "බංග්ලාදේශය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "இலங்கை, பங்களாதேஷ் உறவுகளை மேம்படுத்த உறுதிபூண்டுள்ளன",
      "author": "",
      "body_lines": [
        "இரு நாடுகளுக்கும் இடையிலான பொருளாதார ஒத்துழைப்பை மேலும் வலுப்படுத்துவதற்கான நேரம் சரியானது என்பதை இலங்கை மற்றும் பங்களாதேஷ் இந்த வாரம் அங்கீகரித்துள்ளன.",
        "இலங்கைக்கான பங்களாதேஷ் உயர்ஸ்தானிகர் தாரீக் அரிஃபுல் இஸ்லாம் கூறுகையில், ஆடை, விவசாயம், சுகாதாரம் மற்றும் முதலீடு உள்ளிட்ட பல துறைகளில் இத்தகைய பாடநெறி முன்னேற்றத்திற்கு வழிவகுக்கும்.",
        "ஜனாதிபதி கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ஷவை நேற்று வியாழக்கிழமை சந்தித்தபோதே உயர்ஸ்தானிகர் இதனைத் தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "இந்த ஆண்டு 2022 இரு நாடுகளுக்கும் இடையிலான இராஜதந்திர உறவுகளின் 50 வது ஆண்டு நிறைவைக் குறிக்கிறது. இந்த காலகட்டத்தில், இரு மாநிலங்களும் மிகவும் நெருக்கமாகவும் இணக்கமாகவும் செயல்பட முடிந்தது. தற்போதைய பொருளாதார நெருக்கடியில் பங்களாதேஷின் ஆதரவையும் ஜனாதிபதி ராஜபக்ஷ பாராட்டினார்.",
        "வர்த்தகம், சுற்றுலா மற்றும் கல்வி ஆகிய துறைகளில் இரு நாடுகளுக்கும் ஒத்துழைப்பை வலுப்படுத்துவதற்கான சந்தர்ப்பம் காணப்படுவதாக சுட்டிக்காட்டிய உயர்ஸ்தானிகர், தற்போதைய நிலைமையை இலங்கையால் விரைவாக வெற்றிகொள்ள முடியும் என நம்பிக்கை தெரிவித்தார்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "பங்களாதேஷ்",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "பங்களாதேஷ்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்த வாரம்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இரண்டு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இஸ்லாம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "வியாழன்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இந்த வருடம்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "50வது",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "இரண்டு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ராஜபக்சே",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "பங்களாதேஷ்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  },
  "title": "SL, Bangladesh commit to boost ties",
  "body_lines": [
    "Sri Lanka and Bangladesh this week recognised that time is right to further strengthen economic cooperation between the two countries.",
    "Bangladesh High Commissioner to Sri Lanka Tareq Ariful Islam said such a course will lead to progress in a number of areas, including apparel, agriculture, health and investment.",
    "The High Commissioner made these remarks when he called on President Gotabaya Rajapaksa on Thursday.",
    "This year 2022 marks the 50th anniversary of diplomatic relations between the two countries. During this period, both States were able to work very closely and amicably. President Rajapaksa also appreciated Bangladesh’s support in the current economic crisis.",
    "The High Commissioner pointed out that there is an opportunity for both countries to strengthen cooperation in the fields of trade, tourism and education and expressed confidence that Sri Lanka will be able to overcome the current situation expeditiously."
  ],
  "translate": {
    "en": {
      "title": "SL, Bangladesh commit to boost ties",
      "author": "",
      "body_lines": [
        "Sri Lanka and Bangladesh this week recognised that time is right to further strengthen economic cooperation between the two countries.",
        "Bangladesh High Commissioner to Sri Lanka Tareq Ariful Islam said such a course will lead to progress in a number of areas, including apparel, agriculture, health and investment.",
        "The High Commissioner made these remarks when he called on President Gotabaya Rajapaksa on Thursday.",
        "This year 2022 marks the 50th anniversary of diplomatic relations between the two countries. During this period, both States were able to work very closely and amicably. President Rajapaksa also appreciated Bangladesh’s support in the current economic crisis.",
        "The High Commissioner pointed out that there is an opportunity for both countries to strengthen cooperation in the fields of trade, tourism and education and expressed confidence that Sri Lanka will be able to overcome the current situation expeditiously."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Bangladesh",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Bangladesh",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "this week",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "two",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Islam",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Gotabaya Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Thursday",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "This year",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "50th",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "two",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Bangladesh",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "ශ්‍රී ලංකාව සහ බංග්ලාදේශය සබඳතා ඉහළ නැංවීමට කැපවී සිටිති",
      "author": "",
      "body_lines": [
        "දෙරට අතර ආර්ථික සහයෝගීතාව තවදුරටත් ශක්තිමත් කිරීමට කාලය එළඹ ඇති බව ශ්‍රී ලංකාව සහ බංග්ලාදේශය මේ සතියේ පිළිගත්තේය.",
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ බංග්ලාදේශ මහ කොමසාරිස් Tareq Ariful Islam පැවසුවේ එවැනි පාඨමාලාවක් ඇඟලුම්, කෘෂිකර්මය, සෞඛ්‍ය සහ ආයෝජන ඇතුළු ක්ෂේත්‍ර ගණනාවක ප්‍රගතියට හේතු වනු ඇති බවයි.",
        "මහ කොමසාරිස්වරයා මෙම අදහස් පළ කළේ බ්‍රහස්පතින්දා ජනාධිපති ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ මහතා හමුවූ අවස්ථාවේදීය.",
        "මෙම වසර 2022 දෙරට අතර රාජ්‍ය තාන්ත්‍රික සබඳතාවලට වසර 50ක් සපිරේ. මෙම කාල සීමාව තුළ රාජ්‍යයන් දෙකටම ඉතා සමීපව සහ සුහදව කටයුතු කිරීමට හැකි විය. වත්මන් ආර්ථික අර්බුදයේදී බංග්ලාදේශයේ සහයෝගය ද ජනාධිපතිතුමා අගය කළේය.",
        "වෙළෙඳ, සංචාරක සහ අධ්‍යාපන ක්ෂේත්‍රවල සහයෝගිතාව ශක්තිමත් කර ගැනීමට දෙරටටම අවස්ථාවක් පවතින බව පෙන්වා දුන් මහ කොමසාරිස්වරයා වත්මන් තත්ත්වය කඩිනමින් ජය ගැනීමට ශ්‍රී ලංකාවට හැකි වනු ඇතැයි විශ්වාසය පළ කළේය."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "බංග්ලාදේශය",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "බංග්ලාදේශය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මෙම සතිය",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "දෙක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉස්ලාම්",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "බ්රහස්පතින්දා",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "මේ වසරේ",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "50 වැනි",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "දෙක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "බංග්ලාදේශය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "இலங்கை, பங்களாதேஷ் உறவுகளை மேம்படுத்த உறுதிபூண்டுள்ளன",
      "author": "",
      "body_lines": [
        "இரு நாடுகளுக்கும் இடையிலான பொருளாதார ஒத்துழைப்பை மேலும் வலுப்படுத்துவதற்கான நேரம் சரியானது என்பதை இலங்கை மற்றும் பங்களாதேஷ் இந்த வாரம் அங்கீகரித்துள்ளன.",
        "இலங்கைக்கான பங்களாதேஷ் உயர்ஸ்தானிகர் தாரீக் அரிஃபுல் இஸ்லாம் கூறுகையில், ஆடை, விவசாயம், சுகாதாரம் மற்றும் முதலீடு உள்ளிட்ட பல துறைகளில் இத்தகைய பாடநெறி முன்னேற்றத்திற்கு வழிவகுக்கும்.",
        "ஜனாதிபதி கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ஷவை நேற்று வியாழக்கிழமை சந்தித்தபோதே உயர்ஸ்தானிகர் இதனைத் தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "இந்த ஆண்டு 2022 இரு நாடுகளுக்கும் இடையிலான இராஜதந்திர உறவுகளின் 50 வது ஆண்டு நிறைவைக் குறிக்கிறது. இந்த காலகட்டத்தில், இரு மாநிலங்களும் மிகவும் நெருக்கமாகவும் இணக்கமாகவும் செயல்பட முடிந்தது. தற்போதைய பொருளாதார நெருக்கடியில் பங்களாதேஷின் ஆதரவையும் ஜனாதிபதி ராஜபக்ஷ பாராட்டினார்.",
        "வர்த்தகம், சுற்றுலா மற்றும் கல்வி ஆகிய துறைகளில் இரு நாடுகளுக்கும் ஒத்துழைப்பை வலுப்படுத்துவதற்கான சந்தர்ப்பம் காணப்படுவதாக சுட்டிக்காட்டிய உயர்ஸ்தானிகர், தற்போதைய நிலைமையை இலங்கையால் விரைவாக வெற்றிகொள்ள முடியும் என நம்பிக்கை தெரிவித்தார்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "பங்களாதேஷ்",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "பங்களாதேஷ்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்த வாரம்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இரண்டு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இஸ்லாம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "வியாழன்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இந்த வருடம்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "50வது",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "இரண்டு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ராஜபக்சே",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "பங்களாதேஷ்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}