{
  "newspaper_id": "news-first-lk",
  "url": "https://www.newsfirst.lk/2022/09/02/slfp-to-make-key-amendments-to-the-party-constitution/",
  "time_ut": 1662106680,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "SLFP to make key amendments to the party constitution",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "SLFP to make key amendments to the party constitution",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); The Central Committee of the Sri Lanka Freedom Party (SLFP) has agreed on amending its party constitution to empower the Central Committee and the Party Leadership to take action against party members who act in a manner that is harming the policies and discipline of the party.",
        "The SLFP Central Committee met under the leadership of Party Leader Maithripala Sirisena, at the Party Headquarters on Thursday (1).",
        "However, Nimal Siripala de Silva, Mahinda Amaraweera, Chamara Sampath Dissanayke, Duminda Dissanayake, Lasantha Alagiyawanna and Jagath Pushpakumara objected to the proposal.",
        "Weak Regulators Framework root cause for loan issue – Verite’"
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "News 1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "The Central Committee of the Sri Lanka Freedom Party",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Central Committee",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Party Leadership",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Party",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Maithripala Sirisena",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Party Headquarters",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "Thursday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "1",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Nimal Siripala de Silva",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Mahinda Amaraweera",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Chamara Sampath Dissanayke",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Duminda Dissanayake",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Lasantha Alagiyawanna",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Weak Regulators Framework",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "පක්ෂ ව්‍යවස්ථාවේ ප්‍රධාන සංශෝධන කිරීමට ශ්‍රීලනිප",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); ශ්‍රී ලංකා නිදහස් පක්ෂයේ ප්‍රතිපත්ති හා විනයට හානි වන අයුරින් ක්‍රියා කරන පාක්ෂිකයන්ට එරෙහිව ක්‍රියා කිරීමට මධ්‍යම කාරක සභාවට සහ පක්ෂ නායකත්වයට බලය පැවරෙන පරිදි පක්ෂ ව්‍යවස්ථාව සංශෝධනය කිරීමට ශ්‍රී ලංකා නිදහස් පක්ෂයේ මධ්‍යම කාරක සභාව එකඟ වී තිබේ.",
        "ශ්‍රීලනිප මධ්‍යම කාරක සභාව පක්ෂ නායක මෛත්‍රීපාල සිරිසේන මහතාගේ ප්‍රධානත්වයෙන් බ්‍රහස්පතින්දා (1) පක්ෂ මූලස්ථානයේදී රැස්විය.",
        "කෙසේ වෙතත් නිමල් සිරිපාල ද සිල්වා, මහින්ද අමරවීර, චාමර සම්පත් දිසානායක, දුමින්ද දිසානායක, ලසන්ත අලගියවන්න, ජගත් පුෂ්පකුමාර යන මහත්වරු එම යෝජනාවට විරෝධය පළ කළහ.",
        "දුර්වල නියාමක රාමුව ණය ප්‍රශ්නයට මූලික හේතුව - Verite'"
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "News 1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකා නිදහස් පක්ෂයේ මධ්‍යම කාරක සභාව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "මධ්යම කාරක සභාව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "පක්ෂ නායකත්වය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "පක්ෂය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "මෛත්‍රීපාල සිරිසේන",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "පක්ෂ මූලස්ථානය",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "බ්රහස්පතින්දා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "1",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "නිමල් සිරිපාල ද සිල්වා",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "මහින්ද අමරවීර",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "චාමර සම්පත් දිසානායක",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "දුමින්ද දිසානායක",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ලසන්ත අලගියවන්න",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "දුර්වල නියාමක රාමුව",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "கட்சியின் அரசியலமைப்பில் முக்கிய திருத்தங்களை மேற்கொள்ள ஸ்ரீ.ல.சு.க",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); கட்சியின் கொள்கைகளுக்கும் ஒழுக்கத்துக்கும் ஊறு விளைவிக்கும் வகையில் செயற்படும் கட்சி உறுப்பினர்களுக்கு எதிராக நடவடிக்கை எடுப்பதற்கு மத்திய குழு மற்றும் கட்சித் தலைமைக்கு அதிகாரம் அளிக்கும் வகையில் கட்சியின் அரசியலமைப்பை திருத்துவதற்கு ஸ்ரீலங்கா சுதந்திரக் கட்சியின் மத்திய குழு இணக்கம் தெரிவித்துள்ளது.",
        "ஸ்ரீலங்கா சுதந்திரக் கட்சியின் மத்தியக் குழுக் கூட்டம் கட்சியின் தலைவர் மைத்திரிபால சிறிசேன தலைமையில் வியாழக்கிழமை (1) கட்சித் தலைமையகத்தில் நடைபெற்றது.",
        "எனினும் நிமல் சிறிபால டி சில்வா, மஹிந்த அமரவீர, சாமர சம்பத் திஸாநாயக்க, துமிந்த திஸாநாயக்க, லசந்த அழகியவன்ன மற்றும் ஜகத் புஷ்பகுமார ஆகியோர் இந்த பிரேரணைக்கு எதிர்ப்பு தெரிவித்தனர்.",
        "பலவீனமான கட்டுப்பாட்டாளர்கள் கட்டமைப்பு கடன் பிரச்சினைக்கான மூல காரணம் - சரிபார்க்கவும்"
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "News 1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஸ்ரீலங்கா சுதந்திரக் கட்சியின் மத்திய குழு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "மத்திய குழு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "கட்சி தலைமை",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பார்ட்டி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "மைத்திரிபால சிறிசேன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "கட்சியின் தலைமையகம்",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "வியாழன்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "1",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "நிமல் சிறிபால டி சில்வா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "மஹிந்த அமரவீர",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "சாமர சம்பத் திசாநாயக்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "துமிந்த திசாநாயக்க",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "லசந்த அழகியவன்ன",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பலவீனமான கட்டுப்பாட்டாளர்கள் கட்டமைப்பு",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}