{
  "newspaper_id": "news-first-lk",
  "url": "https://www.newsfirst.lk/2022/07/22/general-kamal-gunaratne-retd-reappointed-as-the-secretary-of-defence/",
  "time_ut": 1658474460,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "General Kamal Gunaratne (Retd) reappointed as the Secretary of Defence",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "General Kamal Gunaratne (Retd) reappointed as the Secretary of Defence",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); General G.D.H. Kamal Gunaratne (Retd) has been reappointed as the Secretary of Defence by President Ranil Wickremesinghe with effect from today (22).",
        "Being a decorated soldier, he commanded his troops during the Humanitarian Operation of the final phase of the Eelam War IV, which completely annihilated the 30-years of terrorism on May 19.",
        "General Gunaratne (Retd) has been awarded with several Gallantry Awards, Distinguished Service Medals, Campaign Medals and Service Medals for his acts of bravery and exceptional acts of valour in the battlefield. He is the recipient of the following medals.",
        "General Kamal Gunaratne (Retd) reappointed as the Secretary of Defence"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Kamal Gunaratne",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "Defence",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "News 1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "G.D.H. Kamal",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "22",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the Humanitarian Operation",
            "label": "EVENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Eelam War IV",
            "label": "EVENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "30-years",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "May 19",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Gallantry Awards",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Campaign Medals and Service Medals",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Kamal Gunaratne",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Defence",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "ජෙනරාල් කමල් ගුණරත්න (විශ්‍රාමික) ආරක්‍ෂක ලේකම්වරයා ලෙස නැවත පත් කෙරේ",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); ජෙනරාල් ජී.ඩී.එච්. අද (22) සිට ක්‍රියාත්මක වන පරිදි ජනාධිපති රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතා විසින් ආරක්ෂක ලේකම්වරයා ලෙස කමල් ගුණරත්න (විශ්‍රාමික) යළි පත් කර තිබේ.",
        "සරසන ලද සොල්දාදුවෙකු වූ ඔහු, මැයි 19 වන දින 30 වසරක ත්‍රස්තවාදය මුළුමනින්ම සමූලඝාතනය කළ IV ඊළාම් යුද්ධයේ අවසන් අදියරේ මානුෂීය මෙහෙයුමේදී තම හමුදාවන්ට අණ දුන්නේය.",
        "ජෙනරාල් ගුණරත්න (විශ්‍රාමික) යුධ පිටියේ ඔහුගේ නිර්භීත ක්‍රියාවන් සහ සුවිශේෂී වීර ක්‍රියාවන් වෙනුවෙන් වීර සම්මාන, විශිෂ්ට සේවා පදක්කම්, ප්‍රචාරක පදක්කම් සහ සේවා පදක්කම් කිහිපයක් පිරිනමා ඇත. ඔහු පහත පදක්කම්ලාභියා වේ.",
        "ජෙනරාල් කමල් ගුණරත්න (විශ්‍රාමික) ආරක්‍ෂක ලේකම්වරයා ලෙස නැවත පත් කෙරේ"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "කමල් ගුණරත්න",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "ආරක්ෂක",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "News 1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජී.ඩී.එච්. කමල්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "22",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "මානුෂීය මෙහෙයුම",
            "label": "EVENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "IV ඊළාම් යුද්ධය",
            "label": "EVENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "අවුරුදු 30ක්",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මැයි 19",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Gallantry Awards",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ප්‍රචාරක පදක්කම් සහ සේවා පදක්කම්",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "කමල් ගුණරත්න",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ආරක්ෂක",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "ஜெனரல் கமல் குணரத்ன (ஓய்வு) பாதுகாப்புச் செயலாளராக மீண்டும் நியமிக்கப்பட்டார்",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); ஜெனரல் ஜி.டி.எச். கமல் குணரத்ன (ஓய்வு) இன்று (22) முதல் அமுலுக்கு வரும் வகையில் ஜனாதிபதி ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்கவினால் மீண்டும் பாதுகாப்புச் செயலாளராக நியமிக்கப்பட்டுள்ளார்.",
        "ஒரு அலங்கரிக்கப்பட்ட சிப்பாயாக இருந்த அவர், மே 19 அன்று 30 ஆண்டுகால பயங்கரவாதத்தை முற்றிலுமாக அழித்த ஈழப் போரின் இறுதிக் கட்டத்தின் மனிதாபிமான நடவடிக்கையின் போது தனது படைகளுக்கு கட்டளையிட்டார்.",
        "ஜெனரல் குணரத்ன (ஓய்வு) போர்க்களத்தில் அவரது துணிச்சல் மற்றும் விதிவிலக்கான வீரச் செயல்களுக்காக பல திறமை விருதுகள், சிறப்புமிக்க சேவை பதக்கங்கள், பிரச்சார பதக்கங்கள் மற்றும் சேவை பதக்கங்கள் ஆகியவற்றைப் பெற்றுள்ளார். அவர் பின்வரும் பதக்கங்களைப் பெற்றவர்.",
        "ஜெனரல் கமல் குணரத்ன (ஓய்வு) பாதுகாப்புச் செயலாளராக மீண்டும் நியமிக்கப்பட்டார்"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "கமல் குணரத்ன",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "பாதுகாப்பு",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "News 1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜி.டி.எச். கமல்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "22",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "மனிதாபிமான நடவடிக்கை",
            "label": "EVENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஈழப் போர் IV",
            "label": "EVENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "30-ஆண்டுகள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "மே 19",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "கேலண்ட்ரி விருதுகள்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "பிரச்சார பதக்கங்கள் மற்றும் சேவை பதக்கங்கள்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "கமல் குணரத்ன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாதுகாப்பு",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}