{
  "newspaper_id": "lankadeepa-lk",
  "url": "https://www.lankadeepa.lk/latest_news/ධනංජය-ඇතුළු-ක්‍රීඩකයන්-කීපදෙනකුට-‘කොවිඩ්’/1-615965",
  "time_ut": 1657114649,
  "original_lang": "si",
  "original_title": "ධනංජය ඇතුළු ක්‍රීඩකයන් කීපදෙනකුට ‘කොවිඩ්’",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Several players including Dhananjaya have 'Covid'",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "A senior official of Sri Lanka Cricket said that several players, including Dhananjaya de Silva, who were scheduled to participate in the second and final Test match against Australia starting tomorrow (8), have been confirmed to be infected with 'Covid'.",
        "In place of those players, hard bowlers Prabhat Jayasuriya and Lakshan Sandakan have been called to the squad.",
        "Angelo Mathews, who was previously infected with 'Covid', is currently in the squad and Praveen Jayawickrama was found to be infected earlier."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Dhananjaya",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka Cricket",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Dhananjaya de Silva",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "second",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Australia",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "tomorrow",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "8)",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Jayasuriya",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Lakshan Sandakan",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Angelo Mathews",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Praveen Jayawickrama",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "ධනංජය ඇතුළු ක්‍රීඩකයන් කීපදෙනකුට ‘කොවිඩ්’",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "ඕස්ටේලියාවට එරෙහිව අනිද්දා (8) ආරම්භ වන දෙවැනි සහ අවසන් ටෙස්ට් තරගයට සහභාගි වීමට නියමිතව සිටි ධනංජය ද සිල්වා ඇතුළු ක්‍රීඩකයන් කීපදෙනක්ට ‘කොවිඩ්’ ආසාදිත බවට තහවුරු වී ඇති බව ශ්‍රී ලංකා ක්‍රිකට් ආයතනයේ උසස් නිලධාරියෙක් පැවසීය.",
        "එම ක්‍රීඩකයන් වෙනුවට දඝ පන්දු යවන්නන් වන ප්‍රභාත් ජයසූරිය සහ ලක්‍ෂාන් සඳකැන් සංචිතයට කැඳවා තිබේ.",
        "මීට පෙර ‘කොවිඩ්’ ආසාදිත වූ ඇන්ජලෝ මැතිව්ස් මේ වන විට සංචිතයට පැමිණ සිටින අතර ප්‍රවීන් ජයවික්‍රම මීට පෙර ආසාදිත බවට හදුනාගත්තේය."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ධනංජය",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකා ක්‍රිකට්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ධනංජය ද සිල්වා",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "දෙවැනි",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඕස්ට්රේලියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "හෙට",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "8)",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ජයසූරිය",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ලක්ෂාන් සඳකැන්",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ඇන්ජලෝ මැතිව්ස්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ප්‍රවීන් ජයවික්‍රම",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "தனஞ்சய உட்பட பல வீரர்களுக்கு 'கோவிட்'",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "அவுஸ்திரேலியாவுக்கு எதிராக நாளை (8) ஆரம்பமாகவுள்ள இரண்டாவதும் இறுதியுமான டெஸ்ட் போட்டியில் பங்கேற்கவிருந்த தனஞ்சய டி சில்வா உட்பட பல வீரர்களுக்கு ‘கொவிட்’ தொற்று இருப்பது உறுதி செய்யப்பட்டுள்ளதாக இலங்கை கிரிக்கெட்டின் சிரேஷ்ட அதிகாரி ஒருவர் தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "அந்த வீரர்களுக்குப் பதிலாக கடினப் பந்துவீச்சாளர்களான பிரபாத் ஜயசூரிய மற்றும் லக்ஷான் சந்தகன் ஆகியோர் அணிக்கு அழைக்கப்பட்டுள்ளனர்.",
        "முன்னதாக 'கோவிட்' நோயால் பாதிக்கப்பட்ட ஏஞ்சலோ மேத்யூஸ் தற்போது அணியில் உள்ளார், மேலும் பிரவீன் ஜெயவிக்ரம ஏற்கனவே பாதிக்கப்பட்டிருப்பது கண்டறியப்பட்டது."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "தனஞ்சய",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை கிரிக்கெட்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "தனஞ்சய டி சில்வா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இரண்டாவது",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆஸ்திரேலியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "நாளை",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "8)",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஜெயசூர்யா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "லக்ஷன் சண்டகன்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஏஞ்சலோ மேத்யூஸ்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "பிரவீன் ஜெயவிக்ரம",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}