{
  "newspaper_id": "ada-lk",
  "url": "https://www.ada.lk/breaking_news/ආරුක්කු-නවයේ-පාලමේ-බඹර-ඇවිස්සිමෙන්-සංචාරකයින්ට-බාධා/11-396504",
  "time_ut": 1661149784,
  "original_lang": "si",
  "original_title": "ආරුක්කු නවයේ පාලමේ බඹර ඇවිස්සිමෙන් සංචාරකයින්ට බාධා",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Tourists are disturbed by wasps on the nine-arch bridge",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "Residents say that local and foreign tourists are often attacked by the wasps on the pillars of the Ella Demodara nine-arch bridge on the Udara railway line.",
        "It is said that the wasps that have been stuck on the stone pillars of the nine-arch bridge for a long time sting the tourists who are watching Siri on the bridge because the animals scatter due to the attacks of hawks and the shock caused by the train.",
        "Local and foreign tourists who are often attacked by wasps are admitted to Demodara, Ella, Bandarawela and Badulla hospitals for treatment and the local residents have informed the relevant authorities several times but they say that no remedy has been received so far."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "nine",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Udara",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "nine",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Siri",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Ella",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Bandarawela",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Badulla",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "ආරුක්කු නවයේ පාලමේ බඹර ඇවිස්සිමෙන් සංචාරකයින්ට බාධා",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "උඩරට දුම්රිය මාර්ගයේ ඇල්ල දෙමෝදර ආරුක්කු නවයේ පාළමේ කුළුණු මත තිබෙන බඹර ඇවිස්සිමෙන් නිතර දේශීය විදේශිය සංචාරකයින් සතුන්ගේ ප්‍රහාර වලට ලක්වෙන බව ප්‍රදේශවාසීන් පවසයි.",
        "ආරුක්කු නවයේ පාලමේ  ගල් කුළුණු මත දීර්ග කාලයක් තිස්සේ බැද තිබෙන බඹර උකුසු ප්‍රහාරවලට හා දුම්රිය ගමන් කිරීමේදි ඇතිවන කම්පනයට විසීරී යන සතුන් පාලම මත සිරි නරඹමින් සිටින සංචාරකයින්ට දෂ්ඨ කරන බව කියයි,",
        "නිතර බඹර ප්‍රහාර වලට ලක්වන දේශිය විදේශීය සංචාරකයින් ප්‍රතිකාර සදහා දෙමෝදර,ඇල්ල,බණ්ඩාරවෙළ හ බදුල්ල රෝහල් සදහා ඇතුලත් කරන අතර අදාල බළධාරීන්ට කිහිපවරක්ම ප්‍රදේශවාසීන් දැනුම් දුන්නත් මෙතෙක් පිළියම් ලැබී නැති බව පවසති."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "නවය",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "උදාර",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "නවය",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "සිරි",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ඇල්ල",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "බණ්ඩාරවෙල",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "බදුල්ල",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "ஒன்பது வளைவுகள் கொண்ட பாலத்தில் குளவிகள் கொட்டுவதால் சுற்றுலா பயணிகள் சிரமப்படுகின்றனர்",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "உதர புகையிரத பாதையில் உள்ள எல்ல தெமோதர ஒன்பது வளைவு பாலத்தின் தூண்களில் உள்ள குளவிகளால் அடிக்கடி உள்ளூர் மற்றும் வெளிநாட்டு சுற்றுலா பயணிகள் தாக்கப்படுவதாக பிரதேசவாசிகள் தெரிவிக்கின்றனர்.",
        "பருந்துகளின் தாக்குதலால் விலங்குகள் சிதறியதால், ஒன்பது வளைவு பாலத்தின் கல் தூண்களில் நீண்ட நாட்களாக ஒட்டிய குளவிகள் பாலத்தில் சிரியை பார்க்கும் சுற்றுலா பயணிகளை கொட்டுவதாக கூறப்படுகிறது. தொடர்வண்டி.",
        "அடிக்கடி குளவி தாக்குதலுக்கு உள்ளாகும் உள்ளூர் மற்றும் வெளிநாட்டு சுற்றுலாப் பயணிகள் தெமோதர, எல்ல, பண்டாரவளை, பதுளை ஆகிய வைத்தியசாலைகளில் சிகிச்சைக்காக அனுமதிக்கப்பட்டு வருவதாகவும் பிரதேசவாசிகள் சம்பந்தப்பட்ட அதிகாரிகளுக்கு பலமுறை தெரிவித்தும் இதுவரை எவ்வித தீர்வும் கிடைக்கவில்லை என அவர்கள் தெரிவிக்கின்றனர்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ஒன்பது",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "உதாரா",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஒன்பது",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "சிரி",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "எல்லா",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "பண்டாரவளை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "பதுளை",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}