{
  "newspaper_id": "daily-mirror-lk",
  "url": "https://www.dailymirror.lk/business-news/Tourist-arrivals-in-July-cross-28-000-mark/273-241644",
  "time_ut": 1658516691,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Tourist arrivals in July cross 28,000 mark",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Tourist arrivals in July cross 28,000 mark",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "UK, India and Germany emerge as largest tourist traffic generators for Sri Lanka for July thus far",
        "India, UK and Russian Federation rank as top three markets for Jan. 01-Jul. 19 period",
        "Tourist arrivals likely to decrease in coming weeks as govt. reimposed state of emergency",
        "Sri Lanka welcomed 28,733 tourists for the first 19 days of July, bringing the total number of international visitors entering the country for the year starting January 01 to 440,110.",
        "Data from the Sri Lanka Tourism Development Authority (SLTDA) show a reduced but steady flow of tourists into the country, which indicates that despite the ongoing political and economic turmoil in the country, interest in destination Sri Lanka still remains.",
        "The country-wise breakdown of the key contributors to the country’s tourist traffic for July shows that the UK ranks as the largest source market for Sri Lanka tourism. For the first 19 days of July, the UK accounted for 4,714 of the total arrivals.",
        "Ranking as the second largest contributor to tourist traffic is India, which brought in 3,375 tourists; Germany emerged as the third largest source market, accounting for 2,322 international visitors.",
        "Other notable markets for the month of July include Canada, France, Switzerland and Australia.",
        "The cumulative analysis of the total arrivals for the year ending on July 19 shows that India tops the list as the largest contributor to the tourist traffic of destination Sri Lanka, with 72,136 visitors arriving from that country. The UK ranks second with 54,336 visitors and the Russian Federation ranks third with 47,412 visitors. However, with newly-elected President Ranil Wickremesinghe reimposing a state of emergency in the country, the number of arrivals to the country is likely to further reduce, the reason being, travel and tour companies are unable to promote a destination that is in a state of emergency."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "July",
          "label": "DATE"
        },
        {
          "text": "28,000",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "UK",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "India",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Germany",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "July",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "India",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "UK",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Russian Federation",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "three",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Jan. 01-Jul. 19",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "coming weeks",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "28,733",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "the first 19 days of July",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the year",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "January 01",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "440,110",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the Sri Lanka Tourism Development Authority",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "July",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "UK",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the first 19 days of July",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "UK",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "4,714",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "second",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "India",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "3,375",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Germany",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "third",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "2,322",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the month of July",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Canada",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "France",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Switzerland",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Australia",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the year ending on July 19",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "India",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "72,136",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "UK",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "second",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "54,336",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "third",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "47,412",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "ජූලි මාසයේ සංචාරක පැමිණීම් 28,000 සීමාව ඉක්මවයි",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "එක්සත් රාජධානිය, ඉන්දියාව සහ ජර්මනිය මෙතෙක් ජූලි මාසය සඳහා ශ්‍රී ලංකාව සඳහා විශාලතම සංචාරක ගමනාගමන උත්පාදකයින් බවට පත්වේ",
        "ඉන්දියාව, එක්සත් රාජධානිය සහ රුසියානු සමූහාණ්ඩුව ජනවාරි 01-ජූලි සඳහා ඉහළම වෙළඳපල තුන ලෙස ශ්‍රේණිගත කරයි. 19 කාල සීමාව",
        "රජයක් ලෙස ඉදිරි සති කිහිපය තුළ සංචාරක පැමිණීම් අඩුවීමට ඉඩ ඇත. හදිසි නීතිය යළි පැනවීය",
        "ජූලි මස පළමු දින 19 තුළ ශ්‍රී ලංකාව සංචාරකයින් 28,733ක් පිළිගෙන ඇති අතර, ජනවාරි 01 වැනිදායින් ආරම්භ වන වසර සඳහා ශ්‍රී ලංකාවට ඇතුළු වූ මුළු ජාත්‍යන්තර අමුත්තන් සංඛ්‍යාව 440,110 දක්වා ගෙන එයි.",
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකා සංචාරක සංවර්ධන අධිකාරියේ (SLTDA) දත්තවලට අනුව රට තුළට සංචාරකයන් පැමිණීම අඩු වූ නමුත් ස්ථාවර ප්‍රවාහයක් පෙන්නුම් කරයි, එයින් ඇඟවෙන්නේ රට තුළ පවතින දේශපාලන හා ආර්ථික කැලඹිලි තිබියදීත්, ගමනාන්තය ශ්‍රී ලංකාව කෙරෙහි උනන්දුවක් තවමත් පවතින බවයි.",
        "ජූලි මාසය සඳහා රටේ සංචාරක ගමනාගමනය සඳහා ප්‍රධාන දායකයින්ගේ රට අනුව බිඳවැටීමෙන් පෙන්නුම් කරන්නේ එක්සත් රාජධානිය ශ්‍රී ලංකා සංචාරක කර්මාන්තය සඳහා විශාලතම මූලාශ්‍ර වෙළඳපොළ ලෙස ශ්‍රේණිගත කරන බවයි. ජූලි මාසයේ පළමු දින 19 සඳහා, එක්සත් රාජධානියේ මුළු පැමිණීම් වලින් 4,714 ක් විය.",
        "සංචාරක ගමනාගමනය සඳහා දෙවන විශාලතම දායකයා ලෙස ශ්‍රේණිගත කිරීම සංචාරකයින් 3,375 ගෙන ආ ඉන්දියාව; ජාත්‍යන්තර අමුත්තන් 2,322 ක් සඳහා ජර්මනිය තුන්වන විශාලතම මූලාශ්‍ර වෙළඳපොළ ලෙස ඉස්මතු විය.",
        "කැනඩාව, ප්‍රංශය, ස්විට්සර්ලන්තය සහ ඕස්ට්‍රේලියාව ජූලි මාසය සඳහා අනෙකුත් කැපී පෙනෙන වෙලඳපොලවල් වේ.",
        "ජුලි 19 න් අවසන් වන වසර සඳහා වූ සමස්ත පැමිණීමේ සමුච්චිත විශ්ලේෂණයෙන් පෙනී යන්නේ ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ සංචාරක ගමනාගමනය සඳහා විශාලතම දායකත්වය සපයන්නා ලෙස ඉන්දියාව ලැයිස්තුවේ ඉහළින්ම සිටින බවත්, එම රටෙන් පැමිණෙන අමුත්තන් 72,136 ක් බවත්ය. නරඹන්නන් 54,336 ක් සමඟ එක්සත් රාජධානිය දෙවන ස්ථානයේ සිටින අතර රුසියානු සමූහාණ්ඩුව අමුත්තන් 47,412 ක් සමඟ තුන්වන ස්ථානයේ සිටී. කෙසේ වෙතත්, අලුතින් තේරී පත් වූ ජනාධිපති රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතා රට තුළ යළි හදිසි නීතිය පැනවීමත් සමඟ මෙරටට පැමිණෙන සංඛ්‍යාව තවදුරටත් අඩුවීමට ඉඩ ඇති අතර, සංචාරක සහ සංචාරක සමාගම්වලට ගමනාන්තයක් ප්‍රවර්ධනය කිරීමට නොහැකි වීම ඊට හේතුවයි. හදිසි"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ජුලි",
          "label": "DATE"
        },
        {
          "text": "28,000 කි",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "එක්සත් රාජධානිය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජර්මනිය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජුලි",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "එක්සත් රාජධානිය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "රුසියානු සමූහාණ්ඩුව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "තුන්",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජනවාරි 01-ජූලි. 19",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ඉදිරි සති",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "28,733 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජූලි පළමු දින 19",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "වසර",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජනවාරි 01",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "440,110 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකා සංචාරක සංවර්ධන අධිකාරිය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ජුලි",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "එක්සත් රාජධානිය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජූලි පළමු දින 19",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "එක්සත් රාජධානිය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "4,714 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "දෙවැනි",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "3,375 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජර්මනිය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "තෙවන",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "2,322 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ජූලි මාසය",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "කැනඩාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ප්රංශය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ස්විට්සර්ලන්තය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඕස්ට්රේලියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ජූලි 19 න් අවසන් වන වසර",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "72,136 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "එක්සත් රාජධානිය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "දෙවැනි",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "54,336 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "තෙවන",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "47,412 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "ஜூலை மாதத்தில் சுற்றுலாப் பயணிகளின் வருகை 28,000ஐத் தாண்டியுள்ளது",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "இதுவரை ஜூலை மாதத்திற்கான இலங்கைக்கான மிகப்பெரிய சுற்றுலாப் போக்குவரத்து உற்பத்தியாளர்களாக இங்கிலாந்து, இந்தியா மற்றும் ஜேர்மனி ஆகிய நாடுகள் உருவாகியுள்ளன",
        "இந்தியா, இங்கிலாந்து மற்றும் ரஷ்ய கூட்டமைப்பு ஆகியவை ஜனவரி 01-ஜூலைக்கான முதல் மூன்று சந்தைகளாக தரவரிசையில் உள்ளன. 19 காலம்",
        "வரும் வாரங்களில் சுற்றுலா பயணிகளின் வருகை குறைய வாய்ப்புள்ளது. அவசர நிலை மீண்டும் அமல்படுத்தப்பட்டது",
        "இலங்கை ஜூலை முதல் 19 நாட்களுக்கு 28,733 சுற்றுலாப் பயணிகளை வரவேற்றது, ஜனவரி 01 ஆம் தேதி முதல் நாட்டிற்குள் நுழைந்த மொத்த சர்வதேச பார்வையாளர்களின் எண்ணிக்கையை 440,110 ஆகக் கொண்டு வந்தது.",
        "இலங்கை சுற்றுலா அபிவிருத்தி அதிகார சபையின் (SLTDA) தரவுகள் நாட்டிற்குள் சுற்றுலாப் பயணிகளின் வருகை குறைந்த ஆனால் நிலையானதாக இருப்பதைக் காட்டுகின்றது, இது நாட்டில் அரசியல் மற்றும் பொருளாதாரக் குழப்பங்கள் நிலவி வருகின்ற போதிலும், இலக்கு இலங்கையின் மீதான ஆர்வம் இன்னும் தொடர்வதைக் குறிக்கிறது.",
        "ஜூலை மாதத்திற்கான நாட்டின் சுற்றுலாப் போக்குவரத்திற்கு முக்கிய பங்களிப்பாளர்களின் நாடு வாரியான முறிவு, இலங்கை சுற்றுலாவின் மிகப்பெரிய ஆதார சந்தையாக இங்கிலாந்து தரவரிசையில் இருப்பதைக் காட்டுகிறது. ஜூலை முதல் 19 நாட்களில், மொத்த வருகையில் 4,714 பேர் இங்கிலாந்துக்கு வந்துள்ளனர்.",
        "3,375 சுற்றுலாப் பயணிகளைக் கொண்டு வந்த இந்தியா, சுற்றுலாப் போக்குவரத்தில் இரண்டாவது பெரிய பங்களிப்பாளராக உள்ளது; 2,322 சர்வதேச பார்வையாளர்களைக் கொண்டு ஜெர்மனி மூன்றாவது பெரிய மூலச் சந்தையாக உருவெடுத்தது.",
        "ஜூலை மாதத்திற்கான மற்ற குறிப்பிடத்தக்க சந்தைகளில் கனடா, பிரான்ஸ், சுவிட்சர்லாந்து மற்றும் ஆஸ்திரேலியா ஆகியவை அடங்கும்.",
        "ஜூலை 19 ஆம் தேதியுடன் முடிவடைந்த ஆண்டிற்கான மொத்த வருகைகளின் ஒட்டுமொத்த பகுப்பாய்வு, இலங்கையின் சுற்றுலாப் போக்குவரத்தில் மிகப்பெரிய பங்களிப்பாளராக பட்டியலில் இந்தியா முதலிடத்தில் உள்ளது என்பதைக் காட்டுகிறது, அந்த நாட்டிலிருந்து 72,136 பார்வையாளர்கள் வந்துள்ளனர். இங்கிலாந்து 54,336 பார்வையாளர்களுடன் இரண்டாவது இடத்தில் உள்ளது மற்றும் ரஷ்ய கூட்டமைப்பு 47,412 பார்வையாளர்களுடன் மூன்றாவது இடத்தில் உள்ளது. எவ்வாறாயினும், புதிதாகத் தேர்ந்தெடுக்கப்பட்ட ஜனாதிபதி ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க நாட்டில் மீண்டும் அவசரகாலச் சட்டத்தை அமுல்படுத்தியிருப்பதால், நாட்டிற்கு வருபவர்களின் எண்ணிக்கை மேலும் குறைய வாய்ப்புள்ளது, காரணம், பயண மற்றும் சுற்றுலா நிறுவனங்களுக்கு ஒரு மாநிலத்தில் உள்ள இலக்கை மேம்படுத்த முடியவில்லை. அவசரநிலை."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ஜூலை",
          "label": "DATE"
        },
        {
          "text": "28,000",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "யுகே",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்தியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜெர்மனி",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜூலை",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இந்தியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "யுகே",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இரஷ்ய கூட்டமைப்பு",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "மூன்று",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜனவரி 01-ஜூலை. 19",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "வரும் வாரங்கள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "28,733",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜூலை முதல் 19 நாட்கள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆண்டு",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜனவரி 01",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "440,110",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை சுற்றுலா அபிவிருத்தி அதிகாரசபை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஜூலை",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "யுகே",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜூலை முதல் 19 நாட்கள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "யுகே",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "4,714",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இரண்டாவது",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்தியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "3,375",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜெர்மனி",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "மூன்றாவது",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "2,322",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஜூலை மாதம்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "கனடா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "பிரான்ஸ்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சுவிட்சர்லாந்து",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆஸ்திரேலியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஜூலை 19 இல் முடிவடையும் ஆண்டு",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்தியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "72,136",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "யுகே",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இரண்டாவது",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "54,336",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "மூன்றாவது",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "47,412",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}