{
  "newspaper_id": "economy-next-com",
  "url": "https://economynext.com/sri-lanka-stock-index-gains-over-1-6-pct-in-mid-day-96399/",
  "time_ut": 1656053040,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Sri Lanka stock index gains over 1.6 pct in mid-day",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Sri Lanka stock index gains over 1.6 pct in mid-day",
      "body_lines": [
        "ECONOMYNEXT – Sri Lanka’s key stock index moved up over 1.6 percent on Friday (24), pushed up by the market heavyweight Expolanka shares, Colombo Stock Exchange data showed.",
        "The main index All Share Price Index gained 1-61 percent or 121.38 points to 7,677.47 as of 1200 hours.",
        "An analyst said the market was kept up mainly by Expolanka shares following its 8.19 rupee dividend for the year ending March 2023.",
        "Top gainers were Expolanka, LOLC and Hayleys Plc. (Colombo/June 24/2022)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Sri Lanka",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "1.6",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "mid-day",
          "label": "DATE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "over 1.6 percent",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "Friday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "24",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Expolanka",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Colombo Stock Exchange",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "1-61 percent",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "121.38",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "7,677.47",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "1200 hours",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Expolanka",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "8.19",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "the year ending March 2023",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Expolanka",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "LOLC",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Hayleys Plc",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Colombo/June 24/2022",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "ශ්‍රී ලංකා කොටස් දර්ශක මධ්‍යම දිනය තුළ සියයට 1.6 කින් ඉහළ ගියේය",
      "body_lines": [
        "ECONOMYNEXT - ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ ප්‍රධාන කොටස් දර්ශකය සිකුරාදා (24) සියයට 1.6 කින් ඉහළ ගිය අතර, වෙළෙඳපොළ හෙවිවේට් එක්ස්පෝලංකා කොටස් මගින් ඉහළ ගිය බව කොළඹ කොටස් වෙළෙඳපොළ දත්ත පෙන්වා දෙයි.",
        "ප්‍රධාන දර්ශකය වන සියලුම කොටස් මිල දර්ශකය පැය 1200 වන විට සියයට 1-61 කින් හෙවත් ඒකක 121.38 කින් 7,677.47 කින් ඉහළ ගියේය.",
        "විශ්ලේෂකයෙකු පැවසුවේ 2023 මාර්තු අවසන් වන වසර සඳහා එහි රුපියල් 8.19 ලාභාංශයෙන් පසුව එක්ස්පෝලංකා කොටස් ප්‍රධාන වශයෙන් වෙළඳපල ඉහළ නංවා ගත් බවයි.",
        "ඉහළම ලාභීන් වූයේ එක්ස්පෝලංකා, එල්ඕඑල්සී සහ හේලීස් පීඑල්සී ය. (කොළඹ/ජුනි 24/2022)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "1.6",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "මැද භාගයේ",
          "label": "DATE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "සියයට 1.6 ට වැඩි",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "සිකුරාදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "24",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "එක්ස්පෝලංකා",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "කොළඹ කොටස් වෙළෙඳපොළ",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "සියයට 1-61",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "121.38 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "7,677.47 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "පැය 1200 යි",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "එක්ස්පෝලංකා",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "8.19",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "2023 මාර්තු අවසන් වන වසර",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "එක්ස්පෝලංකා",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "LOLC",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "හේලීස් පීඑල්සී",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "කොළඹ/ජුනි 24/2022",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "இலங்கை பங்குச் சுட்டெண் 1.6 சதவீதத்திற்கு மேல் நண்பகலில் ஏற்றம் பெற்றது",
      "body_lines": [
        "ECONOMYNEXT - இலங்கையின் முக்கிய பங்குச் சுட்டெண் வெள்ளியன்று (24) 1.6 சதவீதத்திற்கும் மேலாக உயர்ந்தது, சந்தையின் ஹெவிவெயிட் எக்ஸ்போலங்கா பங்குகளால் உயர்ந்தது என்று கொழும்பு பங்குச் சந்தை தரவுகள் தெரிவிக்கின்றன.",
        "1200 மணி நேர நிலவரப்படி முக்கிய குறியீடு அனைத்து பங்கு விலைக் குறியீடு 1-61 சதவீதம் அல்லது 121.38 புள்ளிகள் அதிகரித்து 7,677.47 ஆக இருந்தது.",
        "மார்ச் 2023 இல் முடிவடைந்த ஆண்டிற்கான 8.19 ரூபாய் ஈவுத்தொகையைத் தொடர்ந்து எக்ஸ்போலங்கா பங்குகளால் சந்தை முக்கியமாக பராமரிக்கப்பட்டது என்று ஒரு ஆய்வாளர் கூறினார்.",
        "Expolanka, LOLC மற்றும் Hayleys Plc ஆகியவை அதிக லாபம் ஈட்டியுள்ளன. (கொழும்பு/ஜூன் 24/2022)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "இலங்கை",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "1.6",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "மத்தியானம்",
          "label": "DATE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "1.6 சதவீதத்திற்கும் மேல்",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "வெள்ளி",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "24",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "எக்ஸ்போலங்கா",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "கொழும்பு பங்குச் சந்தை",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "1-61 சதவீதம்",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "121.38",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "7,677.47",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "1200 மணிநேரம்",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "எக்ஸ்போலங்கா",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "8.19",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "மார்ச் 2023 இல் முடிவடையும் ஆண்டு",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "எக்ஸ்போலங்கா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "LOLC",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஹேலிஸ் பி.எல்.சி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "கொழும்பு/ஜூன் 24/2022",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  },
  "title": "Sri Lanka stock index gains over 1.6 pct in mid-day",
  "body_lines": [
    "ECONOMYNEXT – Sri Lanka’s key stock index moved up over 1.6 percent on Friday (24), pushed up by the market heavyweight Expolanka shares, Colombo Stock Exchange data showed.",
    "The main index All Share Price Index gained 1-61 percent or 121.38 points to 7,677.47 as of 1200 hours.",
    "An analyst said the market was kept up mainly by Expolanka shares following its 8.19 rupee dividend for the year ending March 2023.",
    "Top gainers were Expolanka, LOLC and Hayleys Plc. (Colombo/June 24/2022)"
  ],
  "translate": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Sri Lanka stock index gains over 1.6 pct in mid-day",
      "body_lines": [
        "ECONOMYNEXT – Sri Lanka’s key stock index moved up over 1.6 percent on Friday (24), pushed up by the market heavyweight Expolanka shares, Colombo Stock Exchange data showed.",
        "The main index All Share Price Index gained 1-61 percent or 121.38 points to 7,677.47 as of 1200 hours.",
        "An analyst said the market was kept up mainly by Expolanka shares following its 8.19 rupee dividend for the year ending March 2023.",
        "Top gainers were Expolanka, LOLC and Hayleys Plc. (Colombo/June 24/2022)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Sri Lanka",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "1.6",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "mid-day",
          "label": "DATE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "over 1.6 percent",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "Friday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "24",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Expolanka",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Colombo Stock Exchange",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "1-61 percent",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "121.38",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "7,677.47",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "1200 hours",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Expolanka",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "8.19",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "the year ending March 2023",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Expolanka",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "LOLC",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Hayleys Plc",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Colombo/June 24/2022",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "ශ්‍රී ලංකා කොටස් දර්ශක මධ්‍යම දිනය තුළ සියයට 1.6 කින් ඉහළ ගියේය",
      "body_lines": [
        "ECONOMYNEXT - ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ ප්‍රධාන කොටස් දර්ශකය සිකුරාදා (24) සියයට 1.6 කින් ඉහළ ගිය අතර, වෙළෙඳපොළ හෙවිවේට් එක්ස්පෝලංකා කොටස් මගින් ඉහළ ගිය බව කොළඹ කොටස් වෙළෙඳපොළ දත්ත පෙන්වා දෙයි.",
        "ප්‍රධාන දර්ශකය වන සියලුම කොටස් මිල දර්ශකය පැය 1200 වන විට සියයට 1-61 කින් හෙවත් ඒකක 121.38 කින් 7,677.47 කින් ඉහළ ගියේය.",
        "විශ්ලේෂකයෙකු පැවසුවේ 2023 මාර්තු අවසන් වන වසර සඳහා එහි රුපියල් 8.19 ලාභාංශයෙන් පසුව එක්ස්පෝලංකා කොටස් ප්‍රධාන වශයෙන් වෙළඳපල ඉහළ නංවා ගත් බවයි.",
        "ඉහළම ලාභීන් වූයේ එක්ස්පෝලංකා, එල්ඕඑල්සී සහ හේලීස් පීඑල්සී ය. (කොළඹ/ජුනි 24/2022)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "1.6",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "මැද භාගයේ",
          "label": "DATE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "සියයට 1.6 ට වැඩි",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "සිකුරාදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "24",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "එක්ස්පෝලංකා",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "කොළඹ කොටස් වෙළෙඳපොළ",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "සියයට 1-61",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "121.38 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "7,677.47 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "පැය 1200 යි",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "එක්ස්පෝලංකා",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "8.19",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "2023 මාර්තු අවසන් වන වසර",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "එක්ස්පෝලංකා",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "LOLC",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "හේලීස් පීඑල්සී",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "කොළඹ/ජුනි 24/2022",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "இலங்கை பங்குச் சுட்டெண் 1.6 சதவீதத்திற்கு மேல் நண்பகலில் ஏற்றம் பெற்றது",
      "body_lines": [
        "ECONOMYNEXT - இலங்கையின் முக்கிய பங்குச் சுட்டெண் வெள்ளியன்று (24) 1.6 சதவீதத்திற்கும் மேலாக உயர்ந்தது, சந்தையின் ஹெவிவெயிட் எக்ஸ்போலங்கா பங்குகளால் உயர்ந்தது என்று கொழும்பு பங்குச் சந்தை தரவுகள் தெரிவிக்கின்றன.",
        "1200 மணி நேர நிலவரப்படி முக்கிய குறியீடு அனைத்து பங்கு விலைக் குறியீடு 1-61 சதவீதம் அல்லது 121.38 புள்ளிகள் அதிகரித்து 7,677.47 ஆக இருந்தது.",
        "மார்ச் 2023 இல் முடிவடைந்த ஆண்டிற்கான 8.19 ரூபாய் ஈவுத்தொகையைத் தொடர்ந்து எக்ஸ்போலங்கா பங்குகளால் சந்தை முக்கியமாக பராமரிக்கப்பட்டது என்று ஒரு ஆய்வாளர் கூறினார்.",
        "Expolanka, LOLC மற்றும் Hayleys Plc ஆகியவை அதிக லாபம் ஈட்டியுள்ளன. (கொழும்பு/ஜூன் 24/2022)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "இலங்கை",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "1.6",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "மத்தியானம்",
          "label": "DATE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "1.6 சதவீதத்திற்கும் மேல்",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "வெள்ளி",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "24",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "எக்ஸ்போலங்கா",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "கொழும்பு பங்குச் சந்தை",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "1-61 சதவீதம்",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "121.38",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "7,677.47",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "1200 மணிநேரம்",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "எக்ஸ்போலங்கா",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "8.19",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "மார்ச் 2023 இல் முடிவடையும் ஆண்டு",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "எக்ஸ்போலங்கா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "LOLC",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஹேலிஸ் பி.எல்.சி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "கொழும்பு/ஜூன் 24/2022",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}