{
  "newspaper_id": "daily-ft-lk",
  "url": "https://www.ft.lk/news/Deutsche-Bank-donates-Rs-16-5-m-to-provide-relief-to-Sri-Lankan-citizens/56-739248",
  "time_ut": 1661810319,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Deutsche Bank donates Rs. 16.5 m to provide relief to Sri Lankan citizens",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Deutsche Bank donates Rs. 16.5 m to provide relief to Sri Lankan citizens",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "In response to Sri Lanka’s economic and humanitarian crisis, Deutsche Bank has donated 40,000 euros (approximately Rs. 14.6 million) to provide medicines, storage equipment and 1,000 packets of food to the most vulnerable citizens of the country.",
        "The Bank’s staff also rallied their support to raise an additional 7,453 euros (Rs. 1.9 million) for this cause. Staff also participated in yoga sessions on World Meditation Day on 20 May, to raise awareness about the situation in Sri Lanka.",
        "The bulk of the funds went to the purchasing of medication to support local hospitals. Deutsche Bank worked with the Red Cross Society, who assisted the Sri Lanka Ministry of Health with the distribution to hospitals. Medicines were provided to District General Hospital in Vavuniya, the National Hospital of Sri Lanka and Lady Ridgeway Hospital for Children, both in Colombo. The Bank also provided the Red Cross Society with tentage and equipment to store medicines.",
        "In addition to the above, Deutsche Bank also supported feeding programs, providing rice to 150 families in need, as well as seeds and paddy grains to 1,350 farmer families to help with their agriculture sustainability.",
        "“As a committed partner to the country for close to 42 years, we have been involved in Sri Lanka’s development and partnered with various social causes over the years. So, it was only natural for the bank and its employees to stand behind the citizens of our country in their time of need,” Deutsche Bank Sri Lanka Chief Country Officer Vikas Arora said.",
        "Over the years, Deutsche Bank’s Corporate Social Responsibility program has actively engaged in addressing most relevant concerns of the local community in Sri Lanka. Supported by active staff volunteers, the program works in the areas of education, community development and women’s empowerment.",
        "Deutsche Bank provides commercial and investment banking, retail banking, transaction banking and asset and wealth management products and services to corporations, governments, institutional investors, small- and medium-sized businesses, and private individuals. Deutsche Bank is Germany’s leading bank, with a strong position in Europe and a significant presence in the Americas and Asia Pacific.",
        "Deutsche Bank has been operating in Sri Lanka since 1980, providing cash management, FX, trade finance, trust and securities services with strong support and capabilities of superior technology on the Autobahn app"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Deutsche Bank",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "16.5",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "Sri Lankan",
          "label": "NORP"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka’s",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Deutsche Bank",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "40,000",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Rs",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "14.6 million",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "1,000",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Bank",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "an additional 7,453",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "1.9 million",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "World Meditation Day",
            "label": "EVENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "20 May",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Deutsche Bank",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Red Cross Society",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Sri Lanka Ministry of Health",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "District General Hospital",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Vavuniya",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the National Hospital of Sri Lanka",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Lady Ridgeway Hospital for Children",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "Colombo",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Bank",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Red Cross Society",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Deutsche Bank",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "150",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "1,350",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "close to 42 years",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka’s",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the years",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Deutsche Bank Sri Lanka",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Vikas Arora",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the years",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Deutsche Bank’s Corporate Social Responsibility",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Deutsche Bank",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Deutsche Bank",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Germany",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Europe",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "Americas",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "Asia Pacific",
            "label": "LOC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Deutsche Bank",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "1980",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "FX",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Autobahn",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "ඩොයිෂ් බැංකුව රු. ශ්‍රී ලාංකික පුරවැසියන්ට සහන සැලසීම සඳහා මීටර් 16.5 කි",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ ආර්ථික හා මානුෂීය අර්බුදයට ප්‍රතිචාර වශයෙන්, ඩොයිෂ් බැංකුව රටේ වඩාත් අවදානමට ලක්විය හැකි පුරවැසියන් සඳහා ඖෂධ, ගබඩා උපකරණ සහ ආහාර පැකට් 1,000 ක් ලබා දීම සඳහා යුරෝ 40,000 (ආසන්න වශයෙන් රුපියල් මිලියන 14.6) පරිත්‍යාග කර ඇත.",
        "මේ සඳහා අමතර යුරෝ 7,453ක් (රු. මිලියන 1.9) රැස් කිරීමට බැංකුවේ කාර්ය මණ්ඩලය ද ඔවුන්ගේ සහයෝගය ලබා ගත්හ. ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ තත්ත්වය පිළිබඳව දැනුවත් කිරීම සඳහා කාර්ය මණ්ඩලය මැයි 20 වන දින ලෝක භාවනා දිනයේදී යෝග සැසි සඳහා සහභාගී විය.",
        "අරමුදල්වලින් වැඩි ප්‍රමාණයක් ගියේ ප්‍රාදේශීය රෝහල්වලට ආධාර කිරීම සඳහා ඖෂධ මිලදී ගැනීම සඳහා ය. ඩොයිෂ් බැංකුව ශ්‍රී ලංකා සෞඛ්‍ය අමාත්‍යාංශයට රෝහල්වලට බෙදා හැරීමට සහය වූ රතු කුරුස සමාජය සමඟ එක්ව කටයුතු කළේය. වව්නියාවේ දිස්ත්‍රික් මහ රෝහලට, ශ්‍රී ලංකා ජාතික රෝහලට සහ කොළඹ රිජ්වේ ආර්යා ළමා රෝහලට ඖෂධ ලබා දෙන ලදී. බැංකුව විසින් රතු කුරුස සමාජයට කූඩාරම් සහ ඖෂධ ගබඩා කිරීම සඳහා උපකරණ ද ලබා දී ඇත.",
        "ඉහත කරුණු වලට අමතරව, ඩොයිෂ් බැංකුව විසින් පෝෂණ වැඩසටහන්, අවශ්‍යතා ඇති පවුල් 150 කට සහල් ලබා දීම, මෙන්ම ගොවි පවුල් 1,350 කට බීජ සහ වී ධාන්‍ය ලබා දීම සඳහා ඔවුන්ගේ කෘෂිකාර්මික තිරසාරභාවය සඳහා සහාය විය.",
        "“වසර 42 කට ආසන්න කාලයක් රට වෙනුවෙන් කැපවී සිටින හවුල්කරුවෙකු ලෙස, අපි වසර ගණනාවක් පුරා ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ සංවර්ධනයට සම්බන්ධ වී විවිධ සමාජ අරමුණු සමඟ හවුල් වී සිටිමු. ඉතින්, බැංකුව සහ එහි සේවකයන් අපේ රටේ පුරවැසියන්ට අවශ්‍ය අවස්ථාවලදී ඔවුන් පිටුපසින් සිටීම ස්වභාවික දෙයක් පමණයි,” ඩොයිෂ් බැංකුවේ ශ්‍රී ලංකා ප්‍රධාන රටේ නිලධාරි විකාස් අරෝරා පැවසීය.",
        "වසර ගණනාවක් පුරා, ඩොයිෂ් බැංකුවේ ආයතනික සමාජ වගකීම් වැඩසටහන ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ ප්‍රාදේශීය ප්‍රජාවගේ වඩාත් අදාළ ගැටළු විසඳීම සඳහා ක්‍රියාකාරීව නිරත වී ඇත. ක්‍රියාකාරී කාර්ය මණ්ඩල ස්වේච්ඡා සේවකයන්ගේ සහාය ඇතිව, මෙම වැඩසටහන අධ්‍යාපනය, ප්‍රජා සංවර්ධනය සහ කාන්තා සවිබල ගැන්වීම යන ක්ෂේත්‍රවල ක්‍රියා කරයි.",
        "ඩොයිෂ් බැංකුව වාණිජ සහ ආයෝජන බැංකුකරණය, සිල්ලර බැංකුකරණය, ගනුදෙනු බැංකුකරණය සහ වත්කම් සහ ධනය කළමනාකරණ නිෂ්පාදන සහ සේවාවන් සංස්ථා, රජයන්, ආයතනික ආයෝජකයින්, කුඩා හා මධ්‍යම ප්‍රමාණයේ ව්‍යාපාර සහ පුද්ගලික පුද්ගලයින්ට සපයයි. ඩොයිෂ් බැංකුව ජර්මනියේ ප්‍රමුඛ බැංකුව වන අතර යුරෝපයේ ශක්තිමත් ස්ථානයක් සහ ඇමරිකාවේ සහ ආසියා පැසිෆික් කලාපයේ සැලකිය යුතු පැවැත්මක් ඇත.",
        "ඩොයිෂ් බැංකුව 1980 වසරේ සිට ශ්‍රී ලංකාව තුළ ක්‍රියාත්මක වන අතර, Autobahn යෙදුම මත ශක්තිමත් සහය සහ උසස් තාක්ෂණයේ හැකියාවන් සමඟ මුදල් කළමනාකරණය, FX, වෙළඳ මූල්‍ය, විශ්වාසය සහ සුරැකුම්පත් සේවා සපයයි."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ඩොයිෂ් බැංකුව",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "16.5",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "ශ්‍රී ලාංකික",
          "label": "NORP"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඩොයිෂ් බැංකුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "40,000 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "රුපියල්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "මිලියන 14.6 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "1,000 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "බැංකුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "අතිරේක 7,453",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "මිලියන 1.9 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ලෝක භාවනා දිනය",
            "label": "EVENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "20 මැයි",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ඩොයිෂ් බැංකුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "රතු කුරුස සමාජය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකා සෞඛ්‍ය අමාත්‍යාංශය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "දිස්ත්රික් මහ රෝහල",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "වවුනියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ ජාතික රෝහල",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ළමුන් සඳහා රිජ්වේ ආර්යා රෝහල",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "කොළඹ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "බැංකුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "රතු කුරුස සමාජය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ඩොයිෂ් බැංකුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "150",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "1,350 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "අවුරුදු 42කට කිට්ටුයි",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "වසර",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඩොයිෂ් බැංකුව ශ්‍රී ලංකා",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "විකාස් අරෝරා",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "වසර",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඩොයිෂ් බැංකුවේ ආයතනික සමාජ වගකීම",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ඩොයිෂ් බැංකුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඩොයිෂ් බැංකුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජර්මනිය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "යුරෝපය",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඇමරිකාව",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "ආසියා පැසිෆික්",
            "label": "LOC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ඩොයිෂ් බැංකුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "1980",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "FX",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඔටෝබාන්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "டாய்ச் வங்கி ரூ. இலங்கை பிரஜைகளுக்கு நிவாரணம் வழங்க 16.5 மீ",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "இலங்கையின் பொருளாதார மற்றும் மனிதாபிமான நெருக்கடிக்கு பதிலளிக்கும் வகையில், நாட்டின் மிகவும் பாதிக்கப்படக்கூடிய குடிமக்களுக்கு மருந்துகள், சேமிப்பு உபகரணங்கள் மற்றும் 1,000 உணவுப் பொதிகளை வழங்குவதற்காக Deutsche Bank 40,000 யூரோக்களை (சுமார் ரூ. 14.6 மில்லியன்) நன்கொடையாக வழங்கியுள்ளது.",
        "இந்த காரணத்திற்காக கூடுதலாக 7,453 யூரோக்கள் (ரூ. 1.9 மில்லியன்) திரட்ட வங்கியின் ஊழியர்களும் தங்கள் ஆதரவைத் திரட்டினர். இலங்கையின் நிலைமை குறித்து விழிப்புணர்வை ஏற்படுத்த மே 20 அன்று உலக தியான தினத்தில் யோகா அமர்வுகளில் ஊழியர்கள் பங்கேற்றனர்.",
        "நிதியின் பெரும்பகுதி உள்ளூர் மருத்துவமனைகளை ஆதரிப்பதற்காக மருந்துகளை வாங்குவதற்குச் சென்றது. Deutsche Bank செஞ்சிலுவைச் சங்கத்துடன் இணைந்து பணியாற்றியது, இது மருத்துவமனைகளுக்கு விநியோகம் செய்வதில் இலங்கை சுகாதார அமைச்சுக்கு உதவி செய்தது. வவுனியாவிலுள்ள மாவட்ட பொது வைத்தியசாலை, இலங்கையின் தேசிய வைத்தியசாலை மற்றும் கொழும்பிலுள்ள லேடி ரிட்ஜ்வே சிறுவர்களுக்கான வைத்தியசாலை ஆகிய இரண்டுக்கும் மருந்துகள் வழங்கப்பட்டன. செஞ்சிலுவைச் சங்கத்திற்கு மருந்துகளை சேமித்து வைப்பதற்கான கூடாரம் மற்றும் உபகரணங்களையும் வங்கி வழங்கியது.",
        "மேற்கூறியவற்றைத் தவிர, Deutsche Bank உணவுத் திட்டங்களுக்கு ஆதரவளித்தது, தேவைப்படும் 150 குடும்பங்களுக்கு அரிசி, அத்துடன் 1,350 விவசாயக் குடும்பங்களுக்கு விதைகள் மற்றும் நெல் தானியங்களை வழங்கி அவர்களின் விவசாய நிலைத்தன்மைக்கு உதவியது.",
        "“கடந்த 42 வருடங்களாக நாட்டிற்கு அர்ப்பணிப்புள்ள பங்காளியாக நாம் இலங்கையின் அபிவிருத்தியில் ஈடுபட்டு வருவதோடு, பல வருடங்களாக பல்வேறு சமூகக் காரணங்களுடனும் இணைந்து செயற்பட்டு வருகின்றோம். எனவே, வங்கியும் அதன் ஊழியர்களும் நமது நாட்டின் குடிமக்களின் தேவைப்படும் நேரத்தில் அவர்களுக்குப் பின்னால் நிற்பது இயற்கையானது” என்று Deutsche Bank Sri Lanka இன் தலைமை நாட்டு அதிகாரி விகாஸ் அரோரா கூறினார்.",
        "பல ஆண்டுகளாக, Deutsche Bank இன் நிறுவன சமூகப் பொறுப்புத் திட்டம், இலங்கையில் உள்ள உள்ளூர் சமூகத்தின் மிகவும் பொருத்தமான கவலைகளை நிவர்த்தி செய்வதில் தீவிரமாக ஈடுபட்டுள்ளது. சுறுசுறுப்பான பணியாளர் தன்னார்வலர்களின் ஆதரவுடன், கல்வி, சமூக மேம்பாடு மற்றும் பெண்கள் அதிகாரமளித்தல் ஆகிய துறைகளில் இத்திட்டம் செயல்படுகிறது.",
        "Deutsche Bank வணிக மற்றும் முதலீட்டு வங்கி, சில்லறை வங்கி, பரிவர்த்தனை வங்கி மற்றும் சொத்து மற்றும் செல்வ மேலாண்மை பொருட்கள் மற்றும் சேவைகளை பெருநிறுவனங்கள், அரசாங்கங்கள், நிறுவன முதலீட்டாளர்கள், சிறு மற்றும் நடுத்தர வணிகங்கள் மற்றும் தனியார் தனிநபர்களுக்கு வழங்குகிறது. Deutsche Bank ஜேர்மனியின் முன்னணி வங்கியாகும், ஐரோப்பாவில் வலுவான நிலை மற்றும் அமெரிக்கா மற்றும் ஆசிய பசிபிக் நாடுகளில் குறிப்பிடத்தக்க இருப்பு உள்ளது.",
        "Deutsche Bank 1980 ஆம் ஆண்டு முதல் இலங்கையில் இயங்கி வருகிறது, பண மேலாண்மை, FX, வர்த்தக நிதி, நம்பிக்கை மற்றும் பாதுகாப்பு சேவைகளை Autobahn செயலியில் சிறந்த தொழில்நுட்பத்தின் வலுவான ஆதரவு மற்றும் திறன்களுடன் வழங்குகிறது."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Deutsche Bank",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "16.5",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "இலங்கை",
          "label": "NORP"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கையின்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Deutsche Bank",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "40,000",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரூ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "14.6 மில்லியன்",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "1,000",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "வங்கி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "கூடுதலாக 7,453",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "1.9 மில்லியன்",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "உலக தியான தினம்",
            "label": "EVENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "20 மே",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Deutsche Bank",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "செஞ்சிலுவை சங்கம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை சுகாதார அமைச்சு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "மாவட்ட பொது மருத்துவமனை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "வவுனியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கையின் தேசிய மருத்துவமனை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "குழந்தைகளுக்கான லேடி ரிட்ஜ்வே மருத்துவமனை",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "கொழும்பு",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "வங்கி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "செஞ்சிலுவை சங்கம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Deutsche Bank",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "150",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "1,350",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "அருகில் 42 ஆண்டுகள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கையின்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆண்டுகள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Deutsche Bank Sri Lanka",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "விகாஸ் அரோரா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஆண்டுகள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Deutsche Bank இன் நிறுவன சமூகப் பொறுப்பு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Deutsche Bank",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Deutsche Bank",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜெர்மனி",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஐரோப்பா",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "அமெரிக்கா",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆசிய பசிபிக்",
            "label": "LOC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Deutsche Bank",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "1980",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "FX",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆட்டோபான்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}