{
  "newspaper_id": "virakesari-lk",
  "url": "http://www.virakesari.lk/article/132157",
  "time_ut": 1658662500,
  "original_lang": "ta",
  "original_title": "கறுப்பு ஜூலையின் 39 ஆவது ஆண்டு நினைவு தினம் :  கனேடிய பிரதமர் ஜஸ்ரின் ட்ரூடோ விசேட  அறிக்கை",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "39th Anniversary of Black July: Special Statement by Canadian Prime Minister Justin Trudeau",
      "author": "T Yuwaraj",
      "body_lines": [
        "Canadian Prime Minister Justin Trudeau said in a statement issued yesterday on the occasion of the 39th anniversary of Black July that we remember those who lost their lives, lost their property and were displaced in the brutal Black July violence against Tamils ​​in Sri Lanka.",
        "The massacre of Tamils ​​in Colombo followed decades of unrest and tension across the country.",
        "These deadly events, known as Black July, triggered an armed conflict that lasted 26 years. It caused the death of tens of thousands of people. Houses and commercial establishments owned by Tamils ​​were destroyed.",
        "In the months following the Black July violence, the Canadian government implemented a special response to the violence in Sri Lanka. It helped more than 1,800 Tamils ​​immigrate to Canada. I had the privilege of meeting many Tamil Canadians who survived the Black July atrocities.",
        "I was moved by their painful experiences of loss, displacement and regression.",
        "Canada is now home to one of the world's largest diaspora Tamils. We thank Tamil Canadians for contributing so much to making Canada the strong, vibrant and multicultural country it is today.",
        "Canada stands ready to help the people of Sri Lanka affected by the current economic and political crisis. Canada strongly encourages the Government of Sri Lanka and the new President, Ranil Wickremesinghe, recently elected by the Sri Lankan Parliament, to resolve this crisis and undertake the necessary reforms, promote democracy and human rights and uphold the rule of law.",
        "Canada also reiterates the need to ensure that protesters' rights and freedom of the press are protected during these difficult times.",
        "Our thoughts are with all the victims and their families and friends during Black July and the conflict that followed. We are committed to working together to build a better future for all."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Canadian",
          "label": "NORP"
        },
        {
          "text": "Justin Trudeau",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Canadian",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Justin Trudeau",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "yesterday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "39th",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Black July",
            "label": "EVENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "Black July",
            "label": "EVENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "Tamils ​​in Sri Lanka",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Tamils ​​in Colombo",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "decades",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Black July",
            "label": "EVENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "26 years",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "tens of thousands",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the months",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Black July",
            "label": "EVENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "Canadian",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "more than 1,800",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Canada",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Tamil Canadians",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Black July",
            "label": "EVENT"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "Canada",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Tamil Canadians",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Canada",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Canada",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Canada",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Government of Sri Lanka",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Sri Lankan Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Canada",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Black July",
            "label": "EVENT"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "කළු ජූලියේ 39 වැනි සංවත්සරය: කැනේඩියානු අගමැති ජස්ටින් ටෘඩෝගේ විශේෂ ප්‍රකාශය",
      "author": "ටී යුවරාජ්",
      "body_lines": [
        "කැනේඩියානු අගමැති ජස්ටින් ටෘඩෝ ඊයේ කළු ජූලියේ 39 වැනි සංවත්සරය නිමිත්තෙන් නිකුත් කළ නිවේදනයක සඳහන් කළේ ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ දෙමළ ජනතාවට එරෙහි කළු ජූලියේ ම්ලේච්ඡ ප්‍රචණ්ඩත්වය හේතුවෙන් ජීවිත, දේපළ අහිමි වූ සහ අවතැන් වූවන් අප සිහිපත් කරන බවයි.",
        "කොළඹ දෙමළ සංහාරය දශක ගනනාවක් තිස්සේ රට පුරා නොසන්සුන්තාවයෙන් හා ආතතියෙන් පසුවය.",
        "කළු ජූලිය ලෙස හැඳින්වෙන මෙම මාරාන්තික සිදුවීම් වසර 26 ක් පැවති සන්නද්ධ ගැටුමකට තුඩු දුන්නේය. එය දස දහස් ගණනකගේ මරණයට හේතු විය. ද්‍රවිඩ ජනතාවට අයත් නිවාස සහ වාණිජ ආයතන විනාශ විය.",
        "කළු ජූලියේ ප්‍රචණ්ඩත්වයෙන් පසු මාස ​​කිහිපය තුළ කැනේඩියානු රජය ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ ප්‍රචණ්ඩත්වයට විශේෂ ප්‍රතිචාරයක් ක්‍රියාත්මක කළේය. එය දෙමළ ජාතිකයින් 1,800 කට වැඩි පිරිසකට කැනඩාවට සංක්‍රමණය වීමට උපකාර විය. කළු ජූලියේ ම්ලේච්ඡ ක්‍රියාවලින් දිවි ගලවා ගත් බොහෝ දෙමළ කැනේඩියානුවන් හමුවීමේ භාග්‍ය ​​මට හිමි විය.",
        "ඔවුන්ගේ අහිමිවීම්, අවතැන්වීම් සහ පසුබෑම පිළිබඳ වේදනාකාරී අත්දැකීම් මා සසල කළේය.",
        "කැනඩාව දැන් ලොව විශාලතම ඩයස්පෝරා දෙමළ ජනතාවගෙන් කෙනෙකි. කැනඩාව අද පවතින ශක්තිමත්, ජවසම්පන්න සහ බහු සංස්කෘතික රට බවට පත් කිරීමට මෙතරම් දායකත්වයක් ලබා දීම ගැන අපි දෙමළ කැනේඩියානුවන්ට ස්තූතිවන්ත වෙමු.",
        "වත්මන් ආර්ථික හා දේශපාලන අර්බුදයෙන් විපතට පත් ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ ජනතාවට උපකාර කිරීමට කැනඩාව සූදානම්. මෙම අර්බුදය විසඳීමට සහ අවශ්‍ය ප්‍රතිසංස්කරණ සිදු කිරීමට, ප්‍රජාතන්ත්‍රවාදය සහ මානව හිමිකම් ප්‍රවර්ධනය කිරීමට සහ නීතියේ ආධිපත්‍යය තහවුරු කිරීමට කැනඩාව ශ්‍රී ලංකා රජයට සහ ශ්‍රී ලංකා පාර්ලිමේන්තුව විසින් මෑතකදී තේරී පත් වූ නව ජනාධිපති රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතාට දැඩි ලෙස දිරිගන්වයි.",
        "මෙම තීරණාත්මක කාලවලදී විරෝධතාකරුවන්ගේ අයිතිවාසිකම් සහ මාධ්‍ය නිදහස ආරක්ෂා කිරීම සහතික කිරීමේ අවශ්‍යතාවය ද කැනඩාව නැවත අවධාරණය කරයි.",
        "අපගේ සිතුවිලි කළු ජූලිය සහ ඉන් පසුව ඇති වූ ගැටුමේදී වින්දිතයන් සහ ඔවුන්ගේ පවුල් සහ මිතුරන් සමඟයි. සැමට යහපත් අනාගතයක් ගොඩනැගීම සඳහා එක්ව කටයුතු කිරීමට අපි කැපවී සිටිමු."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "කැනේඩියානු",
          "label": "NORP"
        },
        {
          "text": "ජස්ටින් ටෲඩෝ",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "කැනේඩියානු",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජස්ටින් ටෲඩෝ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඊයේ",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "39 වැනි",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "කළු ජූලිය",
            "label": "EVENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "කළු ජූලිය",
            "label": "EVENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ දෙමළ ජනතාව",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "කොළඹ දෙමළ ජනතාව",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "දශක",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "කළු ජූලිය",
            "label": "EVENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "අවුරුදු 26 යි",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "දස දහස් ගණනක්",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "මාස",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "කළු ජූලිය",
            "label": "EVENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "කැනේඩියානු",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "1,800 ට වඩා වැඩිය",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "කැනඩාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "දෙමළ කැනේඩියානුවන්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "කළු ජූලිය",
            "label": "EVENT"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "කැනඩාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "දෙමළ කැනේඩියානුවන්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "කැනඩාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "කැනඩාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "කැනඩාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකා රජය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකා පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "කැනඩාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "කළු ජූලිය",
            "label": "EVENT"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "கறுப்பு ஜூலையின் 39 ஆவது ஆண்டு நினைவு தினம் :  கனேடிய பிரதமர் ஜஸ்ரின் ட்ரூடோ விசேட  அறிக்கை",
      "author": "T Yuwaraj",
      "body_lines": [
        "இலங்கையில் தமிழர்களுக்கு எதிராக இடம்பெற்ற கறுப்பு ஜூலை கொடூரமான வன்முறைகளில் தங்கள் உயிர்கள், உடமைகளை இழந்த மற்றும் இடம்பெயர்ந்தவர்களை நினைவு கூருகிறோம் என கறுப்பு ஜூலை 39-ஆவது ஆண்டு நினைவு தினத்தையொட்டி கனேடிய பிரதமர் ஜஸ்ரின் ட்ரூடோ நேற்று வெளியிட்டுள்ள அறிக்கையில் தெரிவிக்கப்பட்டுள்ளது.",
        "நாடு முழுவதும் பல தசாப்தங்களாக நீடித்த அமைதியின்மை மற்றும் பதற்றங்களைத் தொடர்ந்து, கொழும்பில் தமிழர் படுகொலைகள் இடம்பெற்றன.",
        "கறுப்பு ஜூலை என்று அழைக்கப்படும் இந்த கொடிய நிகழ்வுகள் 26 ஆண்டுகள் நீடித்த ஆயுத மோதலைத் தூண்டியது. இது பல்லாயிரக்கணக்கான மக்கள் உயிரிழக்கக் காரணமானது. தமிழர்களுக்கு சொந்தமான வீடுகள் மற்றும் வணிக நிறுவனங்கள் அழிக்கப்பட்டன.",
        "கருப்பு ஜூலை வன்முறைகளைத் தொடர்ந்து வந்த மாதங்களில் இலங்கையில் நடந்த வன்முறைகளுக்கு பதிலளிக்க கனடா அரசாங்கம் ஒரு சிறப்பு நடவடிக்கையை செயற்படுத்தியது. இது 1,800 க்கும் மேற்பட்ட தமிழர்கள் கனடாவில் குடியேற உதவியது. கறுப்பு ஜூலை கொடூரங்களில் இருந்து தப்பிய பல தமிழ் கனேடிய மக்களை சந்திக்கும் பாக்கியம் எனக்கு கிடைத்தது.",
        "அவர்களின் இழப்பு, இடப்பெயர்வு மற்றும் பின்னடைவு போன்ற வேதனையான அனுபவங்களால் நெகிழ்ந்து போனேன்.",
        "கனடா இப்போது உலகின் மிகப்பெரிய புலம்பெயர்ந்த தமிழர்களின் புகலிடங்களில் ஒன்றாக உள்ளது. கனடாவை இன்று வலுவான, துடிப்பான மற்றும் பல்கலாசார நாடாக மாற்றுவதற்கு பெருமளவில் பங்களித்ததற்காக தமிழ் கனேடியர்களுக்கு நாங்கள் நன்றி கூறுகிறோம்.",
        "தற்போதைய பொருளாதார மற்றும் அரசியல் நெருக்கடியால் பாதிக்கப்பட்டுள்ள இலங்கை மக்களுக்கு உதவ கனடா தயாராக உள்ளது. இந்த நெருக்கடியைத் தீர்ப்பதற்கும் தேவையான சீர்திருத்தங்களை மேற்கொள்வதற்கும், ஜனநாயகம் மற்றும் மனித உரிமைகளை மேம்படுத்துவதற்கும் சட்டத்தின் ஆட்சியை பேணுவதற்கும் இலங்கை அரசாங்கத்தையும் இலங்கை நாடாளுமன்றத்தால் அண்மையில் தெரிவு செய்யப்பட்ட புதிய ஜனாதிபதி ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்கவையும் கனடா வலுவாக ஊக்குவிக்கிறது.",
        "இந்த இக்கட்டான காலங்களில் போராட்டக்காரர்களின் உரிமைகள் மற்றும் பத்திரிகை சுதந்திரம் பாதுகாக்கப்படுவதை உறுதி செய்ய வேண்டியதன் அவசியத்தையும் கனடா மீண்டும் வலியுறுத்துகிறது.",
        "கறுப்பு ஜூலை மற்றும் அதைத் தொடர்ந்து ஏற்பட்ட மோதலின் போது பாதிக்கப்பட்டவர்கள் மற்றும் அவர்களின் குடும்பத்தினர், நண்பர்கள் அனைவருடனும் எங்கள் எண்ணங்கள் உள்ளன. அனைவருக்கும் சிறந்த எதிர்காலத்தைக் கட்டியெழுப்புவதற்கு நாங்கள் ஒன்றிணைந்து செயல்பட உறுதி பூண்டுள்ளோம் என்றுள்ளது."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "கனடியன்",
          "label": "NORP"
        },
        {
          "text": "ஜஸ்டின் ட்ரூடோ",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "கனடியன்",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜஸ்டின் ட்ரூடோ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "நேற்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "39வது",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "கருப்பு ஜூலை",
            "label": "EVENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "கருப்பு ஜூலை",
            "label": "EVENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கையில் உள்ள தமிழர்கள்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "கொழும்பில் உள்ள தமிழர்கள்",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "பத்தாண்டுகள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "கருப்பு ஜூலை",
            "label": "EVENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "26 ஆண்டுகள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "பல்லாயிரக்கணக்கானவர்கள்",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "மாதங்கள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "கருப்பு ஜூலை",
            "label": "EVENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "கனடியன்",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "1,800க்கு மேல்",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "கனடா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "தமிழ் கனடியர்கள்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "கருப்பு ஜூலை",
            "label": "EVENT"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "கனடா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "தமிழ் கனடியர்கள்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "கனடா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "கனடா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "கனடா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை அரசாங்கம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "கனடா",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "கருப்பு ஜூலை",
            "label": "EVENT"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}