{
  "newspaper_id": "virakesari-lk",
  "url": "http://www.virakesari.lk/article/130837",
  "time_ut": 1657013521,
  "original_lang": "ta",
  "original_title": "இந்திய மீனவர்களுக்கு விளக்கமறியல்",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Detention of Indian fishermen",
      "author": "T Yuwaraj",
      "body_lines": [
        "The Local Police Magistrate Court has ordered that the 5 Tamil Nadu fishermen who were arrested on charges of fishing across the border be remanded till the 19th.",
        "The five fishermen from Pudukottai district's Jagadapattinam area, who left for fishing from Kodiakkarai area in a boat, were arrested by the navy yesterday, Monday, while they were engaged in catching fish across the border at Karainagar beach, Jaffna.",
        "The arrested fishermen were produced in the District Magistrate's Court today, Tuesday, through the Department of Marine and Hydrological Resources, and the judge ordered them to be remanded until the 19th.",
        "On the other hand, the 12 Tamil Nadu fishermen who were arrested for the crime of fishing across the border last Sunday have been ordered to be remanded till the next 08th.",
        "It is noteworthy that 17 Tamil Nadu fishermen have been arrested under the crime of crossing the border in two days."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Indian",
          "label": "NORP"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "The Local Police Magistrate Court",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "5",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Tamil Nadu",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "five",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Jagadapattinam",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kodiakkarai",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "yesterday, Monday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Karainagar",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Jaffna",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the District Magistrate's Court",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "today, Tuesday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Department of Marine and Hydrological Resources",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the 19th",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "12",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Tamil Nadu",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "last Sunday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the next 08th",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "17",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Tamil Nadu",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "two days",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "ඉන්දීය ධීවරයින් රඳවා තබා ගැනීම",
      "author": "ටී යුවරාජ්",
      "body_lines": [
        "දේශ සීමාව හරහා මසුන් ඇල්ලීමේ චෝදනාව මත අත්අඩංගුවට ගත් තමිල්නාඩු ධීවරයින් 5 දෙනා ලබන 19 වනදා දක්වා රක්ෂිත බන්ධනාගාර ගත කිරීමට ප්‍රාදේශීය පොලිස් මහේස්ත්‍රාත් අධිකරණය නියෝග කර තිබෙනවා.",
        "කොඩියක්කරෙයි ප්‍රදේශයේ සිට බෝට්ටුවකින් ධීවර කටයුතු සඳහා පිටත්ව ගිය පුදුකෝට්ටෙයි දිස්ත්‍රික්කයේ ජගදපට්ටිනම් ප්‍රදේශයේ ධීවරයින් පස්දෙනා ඊයේ සඳුදා යාපනයේ කරෙයිනගර් වෙරළ තීරයේ මායිම හරහා මසුන් ඇල්ලීමේ නිරතව සිටියදී නාවික හමුදාව විසින් අත්අඩංගුවට ගෙන ඇත.",
        "අත්අඩංගුවට ගත් ධීවරයින් අද අඟහරුවාදා සමුද්‍ර හා ජලවිද්‍යා දෙපාර්තමේන්තුව හරහා දිසා මහේස්ත්‍රාත් අධිකරණයට ඉදිරිපත් කළ අතර එහිදී විනිසුරුවරයා ඔවුන් ලබන 19 වැනිදා දක්වා රක්ෂිත බන්ධනාගාර ගත කිරීමට නියෝග කළේය.",
        "අනෙක් අතට දේශසීමා හරහා ධීවර කටයුතුවල නිරත වීමේ වරදට පසුගිය ඉරිදා අත්අඩංගුවට ගත් තමිල්නාඩු ධීවරයින් 12 දෙනා ලබන 08 වැනිදා දක්වා රක්ෂිත බන්ධනාගාර ගත කිරීමට නියෝග කර තිබෙනවා.",
        "දින දෙකක් තුළ දේශසීමා තරණය කිරීමේ අපරාධය යටතේ තමිල්නාඩු ධීවරයින් 17 දෙනෙකු අත්අඩංගුවට ගෙන තිබීම විශේෂත්වයක්."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ඉන්දීය",
          "label": "NORP"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ප්‍රාදේශීය පොලිස් මහේස්ත්‍රාත් අධිකරණය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "5",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "තමිල්නාඩුව",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "පහ",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජගදපට්ටිනම්",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kodiakkarai",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඊයේ, සඳුදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "කරෙයිනගර්",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "යාපනය",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "දිස්ත්‍රික් මහේස්ත්‍රාත් අධිකරණය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "අද, අඟහරුවාදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "සමුද්‍ර හා ජල විද්‍යා සම්පත් දෙපාර්තමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "19 වැනි",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "12",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "තමිල්නාඩුව",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "පසුගිය ඉරිදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මීළඟ 08 වැනිදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "17",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "තමිල්නාඩුව",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "දින දෙකක්",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "இந்திய மீனவர்களுக்கு விளக்கமறியல்",
      "author": "T Yuwaraj",
      "body_lines": [
        "எல்லை தாண்டி மீன் பிடித்த குற்றச்சாட்டில் கைது செய்யப்பட்ட 5 தமிழக மீனவர்களையும் எதிர்வரும் 19ஆம் திகதி வரையில் விளக்கமறியலில் வைக்குமாறு ஊர்காவற்துறை நீதவான் நீதிமன்றம் உத்தரவிட்டுள்ளது.",
        "புதுக்கோட்டை மாவட்டம் ஜெகதாப்பட்டினம் பகுதியை சேர்ந்த ஐந்து மீனவர்களும் விசைப்படகொன்றில் கோடியாக்கரை பகுதியில் இருந்து மீன் பிடிக்க புறப்பட்டவர்கள் எல்லை தாண்டி யாழ்ப்பாணம் காரைநகர் கடற்பரப்பில் மீன் பிடியில் ஈடுபட்டு இருந்த வேளை கடற்படையினரால் நேற்றைய தினம் திங்கட்கிழமை கைது செய்யப்பட்டுள்ளனர்.",
        "கைது செய்யப்பட்ட மீனவர்கள் இன்றைய தினம் செவ்வாய்க்கிழமை கடற்தொழில் நீரியல் வளத்துறையினர் ஊடாக ஊர்காவற்துறை நீதவான் நீதிமன்றில் முற்படுத்தப்பட்டதை தொடர்ந்து அவர்களை எதிர்வரும் 19ஆம் திகதி வரையில் விளக்க மறியலில் வைக்க நீதவான் உத்தரவிட்டார்.",
        "அதேவேளை கடந்த ஞாயிற்றுக்கிழமை எல்லை தாண்டி மீன் பிடியில் ஈடுபட்ட குற்றத்தில் கைது செய்யப்பட்ட 12 தமிழக மீனவர்களை பருத்தித்துறை நீதவான் எதிர்வரும் 08ஆம் திகதி வரையில் விளக்கமறியலில் வைக்குமாறு உத்தரவிட்டுள்ளார்.",
        "இரு தினங்களில் எல்லை தாண்டிய குற்றத்தின் கீழ் 17 தமிழக மீனவர்கள் கைது செய்யப்பட்டுள்ளமை குறிப்பிடத்தக்கது."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "இந்தியன்",
          "label": "NORP"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "உள்ளூர் போலீஸ் மாஜிஸ்திரேட் நீதிமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "5",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "தமிழ்நாடு",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஐந்து",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜகதாபட்டினம்",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kodiakkarai",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "நேற்று, திங்கட்கிழமை",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "காரைநகர்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "யாழ்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "மாவட்ட மாஜிஸ்திரேட் நீதிமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று, செவ்வாய்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "கடல் மற்றும் நீரியல் வளங்கள் துறை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "19 ஆம் தேதி",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "12",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "தமிழ்நாடு",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "கடந்த ஞாயிறு",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "அடுத்த 08 ஆம் திகதி",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "17",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "தமிழ்நாடு",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இரண்டு நாட்கள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}