{
  "newspaper_id": "news-first-lk",
  "url": "https://www.newsfirst.lk/2022/07/27/motorcycle-gunmen-kill-two-men-in-ambalangoda-police-say-murders-likely-linked-to-tuesdays-26-shooting/",
  "time_ut": 1658938260,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Motorcycle gunmen kill two men in Ambalangoda; Police say murders likely linked to Tuesday’s (26) shooting",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Motorcycle gunmen kill two men in Ambalangoda; Police say murders likely linked to Tuesday’s (26) shooting",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); Two people were gunned donw by an unknown gunan on a motorbike in the Galagoda area in Ambalangoda.",
        "Sri Lanka Police said one person died on the spot, and the other died upon admission to the Balapitiya Hospital.",
        "The deceased were identified as a 49-year-old man and a 44-year-old man from Galagoda.",
        "Police suspect that this shooting may be linked to the shooting in Urawatte, Ambalangoda yesterday (26) that killed one man.",
        "Motorcycle gunmen kill two men in Ambalangoda; Police say murders likely linked to Tuesday’s (26) shooting",
        "Chinese Ambassador meets Ali Sabry to discuss current situation in Sri Lanka",
        "IMF says Sri Lanka needs to talk with China about debt restructuring",
        "US – SL relations can flourish in a Sri Lanka that respects Human Rights – US Ambassador",
        "Attack on Journalists: MTV Network Gives Evidence to Human Rights Commission"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "two",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "Tuesday",
          "label": "DATE"
        },
        {
          "text": "26",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "News 1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Two",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ambalangoda",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka Police",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "one",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Balapitiya Hospital",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "49-year-old",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "44-year-old",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Urawatte",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "yesterday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "26",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "one",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "two",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Tuesday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "26",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Chinese",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ali Sabry",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "IMF",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "China",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "US",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "US",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        []
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "අම්බලන්ගොඩදී යතුරුපැදි තුවක්කුකරුවන් දෙදෙනෙකු මරුට; අඟහරුවාදා (26) සිදුවූ වෙඩි තැබීමට ඝාතන සම්බන්ධ විය හැකි බව පොලිසිය කියයි",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); අම්බලන්ගොඩ, ගලගොඩ ප්‍රදේශයේදී යතුරුපැදියකින් පැමිණි නාඳුනන ගුනෙකු විසින් පුද්ගලයින් දෙදෙනෙකුට වෙඩි තබා තිබේ.",
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකා පොලිසිය පැවසුවේ එක් අයෙකු එම ස්ථානයේදීම මිය ගිය අතර අනෙක් පුද්ගලයා බලපිටිය රෝහලට ඇතුළත් කිරීමේදී මියගොස් ඇති බවයි.",
        "මියගොස් ඇත්තේ ගලගොඩ ප්‍රදේශයේ පදිංචි 49 හැවිරිදි පුද්ගලයෙක් සහ 44 හැවිරිදි පුද්ගලයෙක්.",
        "මෙම වෙඩි තැබීම ඊයේ (26) අම්බලන්ගොඩ ඌරවත්ත ප්‍රදේශයේ සිදු වූ වෙඩි තැබීමකින් එක් අයෙකුට මරු කැඳවූ සිද්ධියට සම්බන්ධ වන්නට ඇතැයි පොලිසිය සැක කරයි.",
        "අම්බලන්ගොඩදී යතුරුපැදි තුවක්කුකරුවන් දෙදෙනෙකු මරුට; අඟහරුවාදා (26) සිදුවූ වෙඩි තැබීමට ඝාතන සම්බන්ධ විය හැකි බව පොලිසිය කියයි",
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ වත්මන් තත්ත්වය පිළිබඳව සාකච්ඡා කිරීමට චීන තානාපති අලි සබ්රි හමුවෙයි",
        "ණය ප්‍රතිව්‍යුහගත කිරීම සම්බන්ධයෙන් ශ්‍රී ලංකාව චීනය සමඟ කතා කළ යුතු බව IMF පවසයි",
        "මානව හිමිකම්වලට ගරු කරන ශ්‍රී ලංකාවක් තුළ අමෙරිකා - ශ්‍රී ලංකා සබඳතා වර්ධනය විය හැකියි - ඇමෙරිකානු තානාපති",
        "මාධ්‍යවේදීන්ට පහරදීම: MTV ජාලය මානව හිමිකම් කොමිසමට සාක්ෂි දෙයි"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "දෙක",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "අඟහරුවාදා",
          "label": "DATE"
        },
        {
          "text": "26",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "News 1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "දෙක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "අම්බලන්ගොඩ",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකා පොලිසිය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "එක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "බලපිටිය රෝහල",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "49 හැවිරිදිය",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "44 හැවිරිදිය",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Urawatte",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඊයේ",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "26",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "එක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "දෙක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "අඟහරුවාදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "26",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "චීන",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "අලි සබ්රි",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "IMF",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "චීනය",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "එක්සත් ජනපදය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "එක්සත් ජනපදය",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        []
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "அம்பலாங்கொடையில் மோட்டார் சைக்கிள் துப்பாக்கிதாரிகள் இருவர் பலி; செவ்வாய்க்கிழமை (26) இடம்பெற்ற துப்பாக்கிச் சூட்டுச் சம்பவத்துடன் கொலைகள் தொடர்புடையதாக இருக்கலாம் என பொலிஸார் தெரிவித்துள்ளனர்",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); அம்பலாங்கொடை, கலகொட பிரதேசத்தில் மோட்டார் சைக்கிளில் வந்த இனந்தெரியாத நபர் ஒருவரால் இருவர் துப்பாக்கிச் சூட்டுக்கு இலக்காகியுள்ளனர்.",
        "ஒருவர் சம்பவ இடத்திலேயே உயிரிழந்ததாகவும், மற்றையவர் பலப்பிட்டிய வைத்தியசாலையில் அனுமதிக்கப்பட்ட பின்னர் உயிரிழந்துள்ளதாகவும் இலங்கை பொலிஸார் தெரிவித்தனர்.",
        "உயிரிழந்தவர்கள் கலகொட பிரதேசத்தைச் சேர்ந்த 49 வயதுடையவர் மற்றும் 44 வயதுடையவர் என அடையாளம் காணப்பட்டுள்ளனர்.",
        "அம்பலாங்கொட, உரவத்தையில் நேற்று (26) ஒருவர் கொல்லப்பட்ட துப்பாக்கிச் சூட்டுச் சம்பவத்துடன் இந்த துப்பாக்கிச் சூட்டுச் சம்பவமும் தொடர்புடையதாக இருக்கலாம் என பொலிஸார் சந்தேகிக்கின்றனர்.",
        "அம்பலாங்கொடையில் மோட்டார் சைக்கிள் துப்பாக்கிதாரிகள் இருவர் பலி; செவ்வாய்க்கிழமை (26) இடம்பெற்ற துப்பாக்கிச் சூட்டுச் சம்பவத்துடன் கொலைகள் தொடர்புடையதாக இருக்கலாம் என பொலிஸார் தெரிவித்துள்ளனர்",
        "இலங்கையின் தற்போதைய நிலைமை குறித்து ஆராய்வதற்காக சீனத் தூதுவர் அலி சப்ரியை சந்தித்தார்",
        "கடன் மறுசீரமைப்பு குறித்து இலங்கை சீனாவுடன் பேச வேண்டும் என சர்வதேச நாணய நிதியம் தெரிவித்துள்ளது",
        "மனித உரிமைகளை மதிக்கும் இலங்கையில் அமெரிக்க – இலங்கை உறவுகள் மலர முடியும் – அமெரிக்க தூதுவர்",
        "ஊடகவியலாளர்கள் மீதான தாக்குதல்: எம்டிவி நெட்வொர்க் மனித உரிமைகள் ஆணைக்குழுவிற்கு சாட்சியமளிக்கிறது"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "இரண்டு",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "செவ்வாய்",
          "label": "DATE"
        },
        {
          "text": "26",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "News 1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இரண்டு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "அம்பலாங்கொட",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை காவல்துறை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஒன்று",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "பலபிட்டிய வைத்தியசாலை",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "49 வயது",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "44 வயது",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Urawatte",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "நேற்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "26",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஒன்று",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இரண்டு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "செவ்வாய்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "26",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "சீன",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "அலி சப்ரி",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "IMF",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சீனா",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "எங்களுக்கு",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "எங்களுக்கு",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        []
      ]
    }
  }
}