{
  "newspaper_id": "colombo-telegraph-com",
  "url": "https://www.colombotelegraph.com/index.php/rti-act-used-on-tear-gas-and-litro-gas-by-aragalaya-protestors/",
  "time_ut": 1662249600,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "RTI Act Used On Tear Gas And Litro Gas By ‘Aragalaya’ Protestors!",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "RTI Act Used On Tear Gas And Litro Gas By ‘Aragalaya’ Protestors!",
      "author": "COLOMBO TELEGRAPH",
      "body_lines": [
        "The Sri Lanka Police Department, on Thursday September 1st 2022, agreed to provide information to a group of Sri Lanka’s leading ‘Aragalaya’ protestors on the quantity of tear gas brought to Sri Lanka during January 1st 2020 – January 1st 2022 and money expended for that purpose, all documentation, tender documents, procurement committee reports etc.",
        "This was during a hearing before the Right to Information Commission where the Police Department had told the protestors that they had dispensed with the relevant documents as they were more than five years old.",
        "Commissioners Kishali Pinto-Jayawardena and Jagath Liyana Arachchi questioned the police at length as to why the Department had given contradictory and different explanations to refuse the information in the three information requests filed by the Centre for Society and Religion.",
        "It was pointed out that the excuse of not having documentation or of destroying documentation cannot be done lightly as the internal circulars of the Department of the Police themselves prohibit this and further, that Section 7 (3) of the RTI Act prohibits destroying new records created from the year, 2017, for 12 years from that year.",
        "Commissioners referred to a previous Order  of 28th July 2022 issued by Chairman and Commissioners of the RTI Commission, Upaly Abeyratne, Kishali Pinto-Jayawardena and Jagath Liyana Arachchi in which the Department of the Police had admitted that there was no legal grounds under the RTI Act to refuse the information in relation to another information request.",
        "Journalists and activists who had suffered health repercussions as a result of what they alleged were expired tear gas used on them, had also asked for details of safety checks on the tear gas brought to Sri Lanka which had been refused by the police on the basis of national security. The Commission called upon the Inspector General of Police to strictly justify their denial to give the information based on national security. The appeal is ongoing.",
        "Thursday’s hearing followed an Order handed down by the RTI Commission on Monday August 29th  where information was directed to be released in a different ‘gas’ matter. This was in response to a citizen, WKS Karunaratne asking for details of salaries of top management of LITRO Gas together with the amount of loans taken by them. He had filed an appeal to the Commission against the refusal of LITRO Gas to give the information, stating that, the salaries and allowances of LIRO’s employees have been ‘immensely increased’, violating government policies imposed to protect the public money which attracts the public interest.",
        "Mr Karunaratne also stated that, both the salaries and the amounts of loans taken by the employees of the Public Authority, ‘finally should be paid by the general public who consumes LP Gas…’with the increase in the selling price of LP Gas in the market.",
        "In its Order available here, the Commission stated that, ‘the Public Authority is a leading provider of domestic cooking gas to the public in Sri Lanka, functions on public funds and utilises the same for the information asked’, which should be released before September 28th 2022. The Commission had earlier dismissed an objection brought by lawyers appearing for LITRO Gas that, it did not fall within the ambit of a Public Authority in the RTI Act.",
        "LITRO Gas has been warned that failure to comply with the Order will result in the Information Officer and the Public Authority being prosecuted before the relevant Magistrate’s Court under Section 39 of the Right to Information Act No. 12 of 2016."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "The Sri Lanka Police Department",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Thursday September 1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "2022",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "January 1st 2020",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "January 1st 2022",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the Right to Information Commission",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Police Department",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "more than five years old",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Kishali Pinto-Jayawardena",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Liyana Arachchi",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Department",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "three",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Centre for Society and Religion",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the Department of the Police",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Section 7",
            "label": "LAW"
          },
          {
            "text": "3",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "the RTI Act",
            "label": "LAW"
          },
          {
            "text": "the year, 2017",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "12 years",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "that year",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Order",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "28th July 2022",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the RTI Commission",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Upaly Abeyratne",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kishali Pinto-Jayawardena",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Liyana Arachchi",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Department of the Police",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the RTI Act",
            "label": "LAW"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Inspector General of Police",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Thursday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Order",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the RTI Commission",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Monday August 29th",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "WKS Karunaratne",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "LITRO Gas",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Commission",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "LITRO Gas",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "LIRO",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Karunaratne",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Public Authority",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "LP Gas",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "LP Gas",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Order",
            "label": "PRODUCT"
          },
          {
            "text": "Commission",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Public Authority",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "September 28th 2022",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "The Commission",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "LITRO Gas",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "a Public Authority",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the RTI Act",
            "label": "LAW"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Order",
            "label": "PRODUCT"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Public Authority",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Magistrate",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Section 39",
            "label": "LAW"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Right to Information Act No.",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "12",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "‘අරගලය’ විරෝධතාකරුවන් කඳුළු ගෑස් සහ ලිට්‍රෝ ගෑස් සඳහා RTI පනත භාවිත කරයි!",
      "author": "COLOMBO Telegraph",
      "body_lines": [
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකා පොලිස් දෙපාර්තමේන්තුව, 2022 සැප්තැම්බර් 1 වැනි බ්‍රහස්පතින්දා, ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ ප්‍රමුඛ පෙළේ 'අරගලය' විරෝධතාකරුවන් පිරිසකට 2020 ජනවාරි 1 සිට 2022 ජනවාරි 1 දක්වා කාලය තුළ ශ්‍රී ලංකාවට ගෙන එන ලද කඳුළු ගෑස් ප්‍රමාණය සහ ඒ සඳහා වැය කළ මුදල් පිළිබඳ තොරතුරු සැපයීමට එකඟ විය. අරමුණ, සියලුම ලියකියවිලි, ටෙන්ඩර් ලේඛන, ප්‍රසම්පාදන කමිටු වාර්තා ආදිය.",
        "ඒ, තොරතුරු දැනගැනීමේ අයිතිවාසිකම කොමිසම හමුවේ පැවති නඩු විභාගයකදී පොලිස් දෙපාර්තමේන්තුව විරෝධතාකරුවන්ට ප්‍රකාශ කර ඇත්තේ ඔවුන් වයස අවුරුදු පහකට වැඩි බැවින් අදාළ ලිපි ලේඛන නිකුත් කළ බවයි.",
        "සමාජය හා ආගමික මධ්‍යස්ථානය විසින් ගොනු කර ඇති තොරතුරු ඉල්ලීම් තුනෙහි තොරතුරු ප්‍රතික්ෂේප කිරීමට දෙපාර්තමේන්තුව පරස්පර හා වෙනස් පැහැදිලි කිරීම් ලබා දුන්නේ මන්දැයි කොමසාරිස්වරුන් වන කිෂාලි පින්ටෝ-ජයවර්ධන සහ ජගත් ලියන ආරච්චි පොලිසියෙන් දීර්ඝ ලෙස ප්‍රශ්න කළහ.",
        "පොලිස් දෙපාර්තමේන්තුවේ අභ්‍යන්තර චක්‍රලේඛ මගින්ම මෙය තහනම් කර ඇති බැවින් ලේඛන නොමැතිවීම හෝ ලියකියවිලි විනාශ කිරීම නිදහසට කරුණක් ලෙස සැහැල්ලුවෙන් කළ නොහැකි බවත්, තොරතුරු දැනගැනීමේ පනතේ 7 (3) වගන්තියෙන් නව වාර්තා විනාශ කිරීම තහනම් කර ඇති බවත් පෙන්වා දෙන ලදී. 2017 වසරේ සිට, එම වසරේ සිට වසර 12ක් සඳහා.",
        "2022 ජූලි 28 වැනි දින තොරතුරු දැනගැනීමේ පනත යටතේ නීත්‍යානුකූල පදනමක් නොමැති බව පොලිස් දෙපාර්තමේන්තුව විසින් පිළිගෙන තිබූ RTI කොමිසමේ සභාපති සහ කොමසාරිස්වරුන් වන උපාලි අබේරත්න, කිෂාලි පින්ටෝ-ජයවර්ධන සහ ජගත් ලියන ආරච්චි විසින් නිකුත් කරන ලද පෙර නියෝගයක් කොමසාරිස්වරුන් විසින් යොමු කරන ලදී. වෙනත් තොරතුරු ඉල්ලීමක් සම්බන්ධයෙන් තොරතුරු ප්‍රතික්ෂේප කිරීමට.",
        "කල් ඉකුත් වූ කඳුළු ගෑස් ප්‍රහාර එල්ල කළ බවට චෝදනා කරමින් සෞඛ්‍ය ප්‍රතිවිපාකවලට ලක්වූ මාධ්‍යවේදීන් සහ ක්‍රියාකාරීන් ශ්‍රී ලංකාවට ගෙන එන ලද කඳුළු ගෑස් සම්බන්ධයෙන් පොලිසිය විසින් ප්‍රතික්ෂේප කරන ලද ආරක්ෂාව පිළිබඳ විස්තර ද ඉල්ලා තිබුණි. ජාතික ආරක්ෂාව. ජාතික ආරක්ෂාව පදනම් කර ගනිමින් එම තොරතුරු ලබාදීම ප්‍රතික්ෂේප කිරීම දැඩි ලෙස සාධාරණීකරණය කරන ලෙස කොමිසම පොලිස්පතිවරයාගෙන් ඉල්ලා සිටියේය. අභියාචනය සිදුවෙමින් පවතී.",
        "බ්‍රහස්පතින්දා නඩු විභාගය අගෝස්තු 29 සඳුදා  RTI කොමිසම විසින් වෙනත් ‘ගෑස්’ කාරණයක් සම්බන්ධයෙන් තොරතුරු නිකුත් කිරීමට නියෝග කරන ලද නියෝගයකින් පසුව සිදු විය. ඒ, ලිට්‍රෝ ගෑස් සමාගමේ ඉහළ කළමනාකාරීත්වයේ වැටුප් සහ ඔවුන් ලබාගෙන ඇති ණය ප්‍රමාණය පිළිබඳව පුරවැසියෙකු වන ඩබ්ලිව්.කේ.එස්. කරුණාරත්න මහතා කළ ඉල්ලීමකට පිළිතුරු වශයෙනි. LITRO ගෑස් සමාගම තොරතුරු ලබාදීම ප්‍රතික්ෂේප කිරීමට එරෙහිව ඔහු කොමිසමට අභියාචනයක් ගොනුකර තිබුණේ මහජන අවශ්‍යතාවලට ආකර්ෂණය වන මහජන මුදල් ආරක්ෂා කිරීම සඳහා පනවා ඇති රජයේ ප්‍රතිපත්ති කඩ කරමින් LIRO සේවකයන්ගේ වැටුප් සහ දීමනා ‘අවිශාල ලෙස වැඩි කර ඇති’ බවයි. .",
        "LP ගෑස්වල විකුණුම් මිල ඉහළ යාමත් සමඟ රාජ්‍ය අධිකාරියේ සේවකයින්ගේ වැටුප් සහ ණය ප්‍රමාණයන් දෙකම අවසාන වශයෙන් ගෙවිය යුත්තේ LP ගෑස් පරිභෝජනය කරන සාමාන්‍ය ජනතාව විසින් බව ද කරුණාරත්න මහතා ප්‍රකාශ කළේය. වෙලඳපොල.",
        "කොමිෂන් සභාව මෙහි ලබා ගත හැකි එහි නියෝගයේ සඳහන් කර ඇත්තේ, 'මහජන අධිකාරිය ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ මහජනතාවට ගෘහස්ථ ආහාර පිසීමේ ගෑස් සපයන ප්‍රමුඛයා වන අතර, මහජන මුදලින් ක්‍රියාත්මක වන අතර අසන තොරතුරු සඳහා එයම භාවිතා කරයි', එය සැප්තැම්බර් මාසයට පෙර නිකුත් කළ යුතුය. 2022 28. LITRO ගෑස් සඳහා පෙනී සිටින නීතීඥයින් විසින් ගෙන එන ලද විරෝධතාවක්, තොරතුරු දැනගැනීමේ පනතේ පොදු අධිකාරියකට අයත් නොවන බවට කොමිසම මීට පෙර ප්‍රතික්ෂේප කර තිබුණි.",
        "එම නියෝගය පිළිපැදීමට අපොහොසත් වුවහොත් 2016 අංක 12 දරන තොරතුරු දැනගැනීමේ අයිතිය පිළිබඳ පනතේ 39 වැනි වගන්තිය යටතේ තොරතුරු නිලධාරියාට සහ පොදු අධිකාරියට අදාළ මහේස්ත්‍රාත් අධිකරණය හමුවේ නඩු පවරන බවට LITRO ගෑස් අනතුරු අඟවා ඇත."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකා පොලිස් දෙපාර්තමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "සැප්තැම්බර් 1 බ්රහස්පතින්දා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "2022",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "2020 ජනවාරි 1",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "2022 ජනවාරි 1",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "තොරතුරු දැනගැනීමේ අයිතිය කොමිසම",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "පොලිස් දෙපාර්තමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "අවුරුදු පහකට වඩා පැරණි",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "කිෂාලි පින්ටෝ-ජයවර්ධන",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ලියන ආරච්චි",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ෙදපාර්තෙම්න්තුෙව්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "තුන්",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "සමාජය සහ ආගම සඳහා මධ්යස්ථානය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "පොලිස් දෙපාර්තමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "7 වන වගන්තිය",
            "label": "LAW"
          },
          {
            "text": "3",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "RTI පනත",
            "label": "LAW"
          },
          {
            "text": "වසර, 2017",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "අවුරුදු 12 යි",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "එම වසරේ",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "නියෝග",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "2022 ජූලි 28",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "RTI කොමිසම",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "උපාලි අබේරත්න",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "කිෂාලි පින්ටෝ-ජයවර්ධන",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ලියන ආරච්චි",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "පොලිස් දෙපාර්තමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "RTI පනත",
            "label": "LAW"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "පොලිස්පති",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "බ්රහස්පතින්දා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "නියෝග",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "RTI කොමිසම",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "අගෝස්තු 29 සඳුදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඩබ්ලිව්.කේ.එස් කරුණාරත්න",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "LITRO ගෑස්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "කොමිසම",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "LITRO ගෑස්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "LIRO",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "කරුණාරත්න ය",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "පොදු අධිකාරිය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "LP ගෑස්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "LP ගෑස්",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "නියෝග",
            "label": "PRODUCT"
          },
          {
            "text": "කොමිසම",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "පොදු අධිකාරිය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "2022 සැප්තැම්බර් 28",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "කොමිසම",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "LITRO ගෑස්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "පොදු අධිකාරියක්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "RTI පනත",
            "label": "LAW"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "නියෝග",
            "label": "PRODUCT"
          },
          {
            "text": "පොදු අධිකාරිය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "මහේස්ත්රාත්වරයා",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "39 වගන්තිය",
            "label": "LAW"
          },
          {
            "text": "තොරතුරු දැනගැනීමේ අයිතිය පිළිබඳ පනත අංක.",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "12",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "‘அரகலயா’ எதிர்ப்பாளர்களால் கண்ணீர்ப்புகை மற்றும் லிட்ரோ எரிவாயு மீது பயன்படுத்தப்படும் RTI சட்டம்!",
      "author": "கொழும்பு டெலிகிராப்",
      "body_lines": [
        "இலங்கை பொலிஸ் திணைக்களம், வியாழன் 1, 2022 அன்று, இலங்கையின் முன்னணி 'அறகலய' எதிர்ப்பாளர்கள் குழுவிற்கு ஜனவரி 1, 2020 - ஜனவரி 1, 2022 வரை இலங்கைக்கு கொண்டு வரப்பட்ட கண்ணீர் புகையின் அளவு மற்றும் அதற்காக செலவிடப்பட்ட பணம் பற்றிய தகவல்களை வழங்க ஒப்புக்கொண்டது. நோக்கம், அனைத்து ஆவணங்கள், டெண்டர் ஆவணங்கள், கொள்முதல் குழு அறிக்கைகள் போன்றவை.",
        "தகவல் அறியும் உரிமை ஆணைக்குழுவில் இடம்பெற்ற விசாரணையின் போது, ​​ஐந்து வருடங்களுக்கும் மேலாக உள்ளதால் உரிய ஆவணங்களை வழங்கியுள்ளதாக பொலிஸ் திணைக்களம் ஆர்ப்பாட்டக்காரர்களிடம் தெரிவித்திருந்தது.",
        "ஆணையாளர்கள் கிஷாலி பின்டோ-ஜெயவர்தன மற்றும் ஜகத் லியன ஆராச்சி ஆகியோர், சமூகம் மற்றும் சமய மையத்தால் தாக்கல் செய்யப்பட்ட மூன்று தகவல் கோரிக்கைகளில் உள்ள தகவலை மறுப்பதற்கு ஏன் திணைக்களம் முரண்பாடான மற்றும் வேறுபட்ட விளக்கங்களை வழங்கியது என பொலிஸாரிடம் நீண்ட நேரம் கேள்வி எழுப்பினர்.",
        "பொலிஸ் திணைக்களத்தின் உள்ளக சுற்றறிக்கையே இதனைத் தடைசெய்வதால் ஆவணங்கள் இல்லை என்றோ ஆவணங்களை அழிப்பதென்றோ சாக்குப்போக்கு இலகுவாகச் செய்ய முடியாது எனவும் மேலும், RTI சட்டத்தின் பிரிவு 7 (3) புதிய பதிவுகளை அழிப்பதைத் தடைசெய்கிறது எனவும் சுட்டிக்காட்டப்பட்டது. 2017 ஆம் ஆண்டிலிருந்து, அந்த ஆண்டிலிருந்து 12 ஆண்டுகளுக்கு.",
        "RTI ஆணைக்குழுவின் தலைவர் மற்றும் ஆணையாளர்களான உபாலி அபேரத்ன, கிஷாலி பின்டோ-ஜெயவர்தன மற்றும் ஜகத் லியன ஆராச்சி ஆகியோரால் வெளியிடப்பட்ட 28 ஜூலை 2022 இன் முந்தைய ஆணையை ஆணையாளர்கள் குறிப்பிட்டுள்ளனர். மற்றொரு தகவல் கோரிக்கை தொடர்பான தகவலை மறுப்பது.",
        "காலாவதியான கண்ணீர் புகைக்குண்டுகள் பயன்படுத்தப்பட்டதாக குற்றம் சாட்டப்பட்டதன் விளைவாக உடல்நல பாதிப்புகளை சந்தித்த ஊடகவியலாளர்கள் மற்றும் ஆர்வலர்கள், இலங்கைக்கு கொண்டு வரப்பட்ட கண்ணீர்ப்புகைக்கு எதிரான பாதுகாப்பு சோதனைகள் பற்றிய விவரங்களையும் கேட்டனர். தேசிய பாதுகாப்பு. தேசிய பாதுகாப்பின் அடிப்படையில் தகவல்களை வழங்க மறுத்ததை கண்டிப்பாக நியாயப்படுத்துமாறு ஆணைக்குழு பொலிஸ் மா அதிபருக்கு அழைப்பு விடுத்துள்ளது. மேல்முறையீடு நடந்து வருகிறது.",
        "வியாழன் விசாரணை, RTI கமிஷன் ஆகஸ்ட் 29 திங்கட்கிழமை பிறப்பித்த உத்தரவைத் தொடர்ந்து  வேறு ஒரு ‘எரிவாயு’ விவகாரத்தில் தகவல்களை வெளியிடுமாறு அறிவுறுத்தப்பட்டது. LITRO Gas இன் உயர்மட்ட நிர்வாகத்தின் சம்பளம் மற்றும் அவர்கள் பெற்ற கடன் தொகையின் விவரங்களைக் கேட்ட ஒரு குடிமகன், WKS கருணாரத்னவின் பதில் இது. பொது நலனைக் கவரும் பொதுப் பணத்தைப் பாதுகாப்பதற்காக விதிக்கப்பட்ட அரசாங்கக் கொள்கைகளை மீறி, LIRO ஊழியர்களின் சம்பளம் மற்றும் கொடுப்பனவுகள் 'பாரியளவில் அதிகரிக்கப்பட்டுள்ளன' என, LITRO Gas நிறுவனம் தகவல் கொடுக்க மறுத்ததற்கு எதிராக அவர் ஆணைக்குழுவில் மேன்முறையீடு செய்திருந்தார். .",
        "திரு கருணாரத்ன மேலும் கூறுகையில், பொது அதிகார சபையின் ஊழியர்களால் பெறப்பட்ட சம்பளம் மற்றும் கடன் தொகை ஆகிய இரண்டும், LP எரிவாயுவை பயன்படுத்தும் பொது மக்களே இறுதியாக செலுத்த வேண்டும்... சந்தை.",
        "ஆணைக்குழு இங்கு கிடைக்கப்பெற்ற தனது உத்தரவில், 'பொது அதிகாரசபையானது இலங்கையில் பொதுமக்களுக்கு உள்நாட்டு சமையல் எரிவாயு வழங்கும் முன்னணி நிறுவனமாகும், பொது நிதியில் செயற்படுகிறது மற்றும் கேட்கப்படும் தகவல்களுக்குப் பயன்படுத்துகிறது', இது செப்டம்பர் மாதத்திற்கு முன்னர் வெளியிடப்பட வேண்டும். 28, 2022. RTI சட்டத்தில் பொது அதிகாரசபையின் வரம்பிற்குள் வராது என்று LITRO Gas க்காக ஆஜரான வழக்கறிஞர்கள் முன்வைத்த ஆட்சேபனையை ஆணையம் முன்பு நிராகரித்தது.",
        "இந்த உத்தரவை பின்பற்றத் தவறினால், தகவல் அறியும் உரிமைச் சட்டம் எண். 12, 2016 இன் பிரிவு 39ன் கீழ், சம்பந்தப்பட்ட மாஜிஸ்திரேட் நீதிமன்றத்தில் தகவல் அதிகாரி மற்றும் பொது அதிகாரசபை வழக்குத் தொடரப்படும் என்று லிட்ரோ கேஸ் எச்சரிக்கப்பட்டுள்ளது."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை பொலிஸ் திணைக்களம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "செப்டம்பர் 1 வியாழன்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "2022",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜனவரி 1, 2020",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜனவரி 1, 2022",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "தகவல் அறியும் உரிமை ஆணையம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "காவல் துறை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஐந்து வயதுக்கு மேல்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "கிஷாலி பின்டோ-ஜெயவர்தன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "லியானா ஆராச்சி",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "துறை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "மூன்று",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "சமூகம் மற்றும் மதத்திற்கான மையம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "காவல் துறை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "பிரிவு 7",
            "label": "LAW"
          },
          {
            "text": "3",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "RTI சட்டம்",
            "label": "LAW"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆண்டு, 2017",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "12 ஆண்டுகள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "அந்த வருடம்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஆர்டர்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "28 ஜூலை 2022",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "RTI கமிஷன்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "உபாலி அபேரத்ன",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "கிஷாலி பின்டோ-ஜெயவர்தன",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "லியானா ஆராச்சி",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "காவல் துறை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "RTI சட்டம்",
            "label": "LAW"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்ஸ்பெக்டர் ஜெனரல் ஆஃப் போலீஸ்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "வியாழன்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆர்டர்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "RTI கமிஷன்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆகஸ்ட் 29 திங்கட்கிழமை",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "டபிள்யூ.கே.எஸ் கருணாரத்ன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "லிட்ரோ எரிவாயு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "தரகு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "லிட்ரோ எரிவாயு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "லிரோ",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "கருணாரத்ன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "பொது அதிகாரசபை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "எல்பி எரிவாயு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "எல்பி எரிவாயு",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஆர்டர்",
            "label": "PRODUCT"
          },
          {
            "text": "தரகு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "பொது அதிகாரசபை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "செப்டம்பர் 28, 2022",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆணையம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "லிட்ரோ எரிவாயு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஒரு பொது அதிகாரம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "RTI சட்டம்",
            "label": "LAW"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஆர்டர்",
            "label": "PRODUCT"
          },
          {
            "text": "பொது அதிகாரசபை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "மாஜிஸ்திரேட்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "பிரிவு 39",
            "label": "LAW"
          },
          {
            "text": "தகவல் அறியும் உரிமைச் சட்டம் எண்.",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "12",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}