{
  "newspaper_id": "ada-lk",
  "url": "https://www.ada.lk/breaking_news/හයුන්ඩායි-වාහන-එකලස්-කිරීමේ-කර්මාන්ත-ශාලාවක්-ලංකාවටත්/11-396458",
  "time_ut": 1660963916,
  "original_lang": "si",
  "original_title": "හයුන්ඩායි වාහන එකලස් කිරීමේ කර්මාන්ත ශාලාවක් ලංකාවටත්",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "A Hyundai vehicle assembly factory to Sri Lanka",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "Hyundai Motor Company, the world's sixth largest car manufacturer, has entered into an agreement with Abans Auto for assembly in Sri Lanka.",
        "Thus, Abans Auto Company has received permission to assemble and manufacture Hyundai cars and accessories in Sri Lanka.",
        "Hyundai is a car manufacturer in Korea and Abans Auto Company is the authorized distributor of these cars in Sri Lanka.",
        "This agreement has been signed as a result of a long discussion started in 2020 for the assembly of those cars in Sri Lanka.",
        "Hyundai has extensive experience in setting up automobile assembly plants around the world and currently operates in eight countries, including the United States, the Czech Republic and India.",
        "Similarly, the proposed assembly plant for Sri Lanka has been designed by Hyundai and will include modern technologies, tools and equipment that are in line with Industry 4.0 standards, ensuring that the brand's stringent quality expectations are maintained.",
        "Some components needed to assemble these cars are also going to be manufactured in Sri Lanka."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Hyundai",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "Sri Lanka",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Hyundai Motor Company",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "sixth",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Abans Auto",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Abans Auto Company",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Hyundai",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Hyundai",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Korea",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Abans Auto Company",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "2020",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Hyundai",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "eight",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "the United States",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Czech Republic",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "India",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Hyundai",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Industry 4.0",
            "label": "LAW"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "හයුන්ඩායි වාහන එකලස් කිරීමේ කර්මාන්ත ශාලාවක් ලංකාවටත්",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "ලොව හයවන විශාලතම මෝටර් රථ නිෂ්පාදකයා වන හයුන්ඩායි මෝටර් රථ සමාගම ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ එකලස් කිරීම වෙනුවෙන් අබාන්ස් ඔටෝ සමඟ ගිවිසුමකට එළඹ තිබේ.",
        "මේ අනුව හයුන්ඩායි  මෝටර් රථ සහ උපාංග ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ එකලස් කර නිෂ්පාදනය කිරීමට අබාන්ස් ඔටෝ සමාගමට අවසර ලැබී තිබේ.",
        "හයුන්ඩායි කොරියාවේ මෝටර් රථ නිෂ්පාදකයෙක් වන අතර එම රථ ලංකාවේ බලයලත් බෙදාහරින්නා වන්නේ අබාන්ස් ඔටෝ සමාගමයි.",
        "එම මෝටර් රථ ලංකාවේ එකලස් කිරීම වෙනුවෙන් 2020 දී ආරම්භ කරන ලද දීර්ඝ සාකච්ඡාවක ප්‍රතිඵලයක් ලෙස මෙම ගිවිසුමට අත්සන් කර තිබේ.",
        "Hyundai සමාගමට ලොව පුරා මෝටර් රථ එකලස් කිරීමේ කම්හල් පිහිටුවීමේ පුළුල් අත්දැකීම් ඇති අතර දැනට එක්සත් ජනපදය, චෙක් ජනරජය සහ ඉන්දියාව ඇතුළු රටවල් අටක ක්‍රියාත්මක වේ.",
        "ඒ හා සමානව, ශ්‍රී ලංකාව සඳහා යෝජිත එකලස් කිරීමේ කර්මාන්ත ශාලාව හයුන්ඩායි විසින් නිර්මාණය කර ඇති අතර සන්නාමයේ දැඩි තත්ත්ව අපේක්ෂාවන් පවත්වා ගැනීම සහතික කරමින් කර්මාන්තයේ 4.0 ප්‍රමිතීන්ට අනුකූල වන නවීන තාක්ෂණයන්, මෙවලම් සහ උපකරණ ඇතුළත් වේ.",
        "මෙම මෝටර් රථ එකලස් කිරීමට අවශ්‍ය උපාංග කිහිපයක්ද ලංකාවේ නිශ්පාදනය කිරීමට නියමිතය."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "හයුන්ඩායි",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Hyundai මෝටර් සමාගම",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "හය වන",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "අබාන්ස් ඔටෝ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "අබාන්ස් ඔටෝ සමාගම",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "හයුන්ඩායි",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "හයුන්ඩායි",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "කොරියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "අබාන්ස් ඔටෝ සමාගම",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "2020",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "හයුන්ඩායි",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "අට",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "එක්සත් ජනපදය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "චෙක් ජනරජය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "හයුන්ඩායි",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "කර්මාන්තය 4.0",
            "label": "LAW"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "இலங்கைக்கான ஹூண்டாய் வாகன அசெம்பிளி தொழிற்சாலை",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "உலகின் ஆறாவது பெரிய கார் உற்பத்தி நிறுவனமான ஹூண்டாய் மோட்டார் நிறுவனம், இலங்கையில் அசெம்பிள் செய்வதற்கான அபான்ஸ் ஆட்டோவுடன் ஒப்பந்தம் செய்துள்ளது.",
        "இதனால் அபான்ஸ் ஆட்டோ நிறுவனம் ஹூண்டாய் கார்கள் மற்றும் துணைக்கருவிகளை இலங்கையில் அசெம்பிள் செய்து தயாரிக்கும் அனுமதியை பெற்றுள்ளது.",
        "ஹூண்டாய் கொரியாவில் கார் உற்பத்தியாளர் மற்றும் அபான்ஸ் ஆட்டோ நிறுவனம் இந்த கார்களை இலங்கையில் அங்கீகரிக்கப்பட்ட விநியோகஸ்தராகும்.",
        "அந்த கார்களை இலங்கையில் அசெம்பிள் செய்வது தொடர்பாக 2020ல் தொடங்கிய நீண்ட விவாதத்தின் விளைவாக இந்த ஒப்பந்தம் கைச்சாத்திடப்பட்டுள்ளது.",
        "உலகம் முழுவதும் ஆட்டோமொபைல் அசெம்பிளி ஆலைகளை அமைப்பதில் ஹூண்டாய் விரிவான அனுபவத்தைக் கொண்டுள்ளது மற்றும் தற்போது அமெரிக்கா, செக் குடியரசு மற்றும் இந்தியா உட்பட எட்டு நாடுகளில் செயல்படுகிறது.",
        "அதேபோன்று, இலங்கைக்கான உத்தேசிக்கப்பட்ட அசெம்பிளி ஆலை ஹூண்டாய் நிறுவனத்தால் வடிவமைக்கப்பட்டுள்ளது மற்றும் தொழில்துறை 4.0 தரநிலைகளுக்கு இணங்க நவீன தொழில்நுட்பங்கள், கருவிகள் மற்றும் உபகரணங்களை உள்ளடக்கி, வர்த்தக நாமத்தின் கடுமையான தர எதிர்பார்ப்புகள் பேணப்படுவதை உறுதி செய்யும்.",
        "இந்த கார்களை அசெம்பிள் செய்வதற்கு தேவையான சில உதிரிபாகங்களும் இலங்கையில் தயாரிக்கப்பட உள்ளன."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ஹூண்டாய்",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "இலங்கை",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ஹூண்டாய் மோட்டார் நிறுவனம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆறாவது",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "அபான்ஸ் ஆட்டோ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "அபான்ஸ் ஆட்டோ நிறுவனம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஹூண்டாய்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஹூண்டாய்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "கொரியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "அபான்ஸ் ஆட்டோ நிறுவனம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "2020",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஹூண்டாய்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "எட்டு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஐக்கிய நாடுகள்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "செ குடியரசு",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்தியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஹூண்டாய்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "தொழில் 4.0",
            "label": "LAW"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}