{
  "newspaper_id": "ada-lk",
  "url": "https://www.ada.lk/picture_story/අගමැති-වැඩ-අරඹයි/10-395720",
  "time_ut": 1658739635,
  "original_lang": "si",
  "original_title": "අගමැති වැඩ අරඹයි",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Prime Minister starts work",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "Prime Minister Dinesh Gunawardena took office today (25th) at the Prime Minister's Office. Prime Minister's Secretary Mr. Anura Dissanayake, Prime Minister's Additional Secretary Mr. Harsha Wijewardene and other government officials as well as former Minister Namal Rajapaksa, former State Ministers Sisira Jayakodi, Arundika Fernando, Dr. Suren Raghavan, Members of Parliament Yadamini Gunawardena, Sagara Kariyawasam, Jagath Kumara, Manjula. Dissanayake and a group of people's representatives were also present."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Dinesh Gunawardena",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Anura Dissanayake",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Harsha Wijewardene",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Namal Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sisira Jayakodi",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Arundika Fernando",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Suren Raghavan",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament Yadamini Gunawardena",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sagara Kariyawasam",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Manjula",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Dissanayake",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "අගමැති වැඩ අරඹයි",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "අග්‍රාමාත්‍ය දිනේෂ් ගුණවර්ධන මහතා අද (25දා) අග්‍රාමාත්‍ය කාර්යාලයේදී වැඩ භාරගත්තේය. මෙම අවස්ථාවට අග්‍රාමාත්‍ය ලේකම් අනුර දිසානායක මහතා, අග්‍රාමාත්‍ය අතිරේක ලේකම් හර්ෂ විජේවර්ධන මහතා ඇතුළු රාජ්‍ය නිලධාරීහු මෙන්ම හිටපු අමාත්‍ය නාමල් රාජපක්ෂ ,හිටපු රාජ්‍ය අමාත්‍යවරු වන සිසිර ජයකොඩි, අරුන්දික ප්‍රනාන්දු, ආචාර්ය සුරේන් රාඝවන්,පාර්ලිමේන්තු මන්ත්‍රීවරු වන යදාමිණි ගුණවර්ධන,  සාගර කාරියවසම්, ජගත් කුමාර, මංජුලා දිසානායක ආදි ජනතා නියෝජිතයෝ පිරිසක්ද එක්ව සිටියහ."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "දිනේෂ් ගුණවර්ධන",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "අනුර දිසානායක",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "හර්ෂ විජේවර්ධන",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "නාමල් රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "සිසිර ජයකොඩි",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "අරුන්දික ප්‍රනාන්දු",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "සුරේන් රාඝවන්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තු යදාමිණි ගුණවර්ධන",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "සාගර කාරියවසම්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "මංජුල",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "දිසානායක",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "பிரதமர் பணியைத் தொடங்கினார்",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "பிரதமர் தினேஷ் குணவர்தன இன்று (25) பிரதமர் அலுவலகத்தில் பதவியேற்றார். பிரதமரின் செயலாளர் திரு அனுர திஸாநாயக்க, பிரதமரின் மேலதிக செயலாளர் திரு ஹர்ஷ விஜேவர்தன மற்றும் அரச அதிகாரிகள் மற்றும் முன்னாள் அமைச்சர் நாமல் ராஜபக்ஷ, முன்னாள் இராஜாங்க அமைச்சர்களான சிசிர ஜயகொடி, அருந்திக பெர்னாண்டோ, கலாநிதி சுரேன் ராகவன், பாராளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர்களான யாதாமினி குணவர்தன, சாகர காரியவசம் ஆகியோர் கலந்துகொண்டனர். , ஜகத் குமார, மஞ்சுள.திஸாநாயக்க மற்றும் மக்கள் பிரதிநிதிகள் குழுவினரும் கலந்து கொண்டனர்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "தினேஷ் குணவர்தன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "அனுர திஸாநாயக்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஹர்ஷ விஜேவர்தன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "நாமல் ராஜபக்ச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "சிசிர ஜெயக்கொடி",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "அருந்திக பெர்னாண்டோ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "சுரேன் ராகவன்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம் யாதாமினி குணவர்தன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "சாகர காரியவசம்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "மஞ்சுளா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "திசாநாயக்க",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}