{
  "newspaper_id": "news-first-lk",
  "url": "https://www.newsfirst.lk/2022/08/14/victimized-slpp-seniors-pushing-compensation-report/",
  "time_ut": 1660483980,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "‘Victimized’ SLPP seniors pushing compensation: Report",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "‘Victimized’ SLPP seniors pushing compensation: Report",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); A number of SLPP Parliamentarians have pushed for approval for a Cabinet paper recommending compensation of over Rs. 117 million for state officials who had been subjected to alleged “political victimisation” under the previous Yahapalanaya administration of 2015-2019, the Sunday Times reports.",
        "The Sunday Times reports, that a number of Sri Lanka Podujana Peramuna Parliamentarians have pushed for approval for a Cabinet paper recommending compensation of over Rs. 117 million for state officials who had been subjected to alleged “political victimisation” from 2015-2019.",
        "According to the report the Cabinet paper was drafted by former Prime Minister Mahinda Rajapaksa in line with the recommendations of a committee headed by the former Chief Justice Asoka de Silva, however was not submitted for approval due to Rajapaksa's resignation on 9th of May.",
        "Yet, according to the report, attempts are now being made to submit the paper to the Cabinet after Prime Minister Dinesh Gunawardena assumed office.",
        "Moreover, the report states that it understands that senior SLPP members are attempting to secure compensation for officials identified by the committee.",
        "A total of 27 officials are due to receive monetary compensation, which  ranges from Rs. 700,000 to Rs. 25 million as per recommendations of the committee.",
        "Will support from Opposition until Tamil people are satisfied: C.V. Wigneswaran"
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "News 1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Cabinet",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "117 million",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Yahapalanaya",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "2015-2019",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sunday Times",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "The Sunday Times",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Podujana Peramuna Parliamentarians",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Cabinet",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "117 million",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "2015-2019",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Cabinet",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Mahinda Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Asoka de Silva",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Rajapaksa",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "9th",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "May",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Cabinet",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Dinesh Gunawardena",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "SLPP",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "27",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "25 million",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "C.V. Wigneswaran",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "‘වින්දිත’ ශ්‍රී ලංකා පොදුජන පෙරමුණේ ජ්‍යෙෂ්ඨයින් වන්දි ලබා දීමට තල්ලු කරයි: වාර්තාව",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); ශ්‍රී ලංකා පොදුජන පෙරමුණේ පාර්ලිමේන්තු මන්ත්‍රීවරුන් කිහිප දෙනෙකු විසින් රුපියල් කෝටියකට අධික වන්දියක් නිර්දේශ කරන ලද කැබිනට් පත්‍රිකාවක් සඳහා අනුමැතිය ඉල්ලා ඇත. පසුගිය 2015-2019 යහපාලන රජය යටතේ \"දේශපාලන පලිගැනීම්\" වලට ලක් වූ රාජ්‍ය නිලධාරීන් සඳහා රුපියල් මිලියන 117ක් ලබා දී ඇති බව සන්ඩේ ටයිම්ස් වාර්තා කරයි.",
        "රුපියල් කෝටියකට අධික වන්දියක් ලබාදීමට නිර්දේශ කෙරෙන කැබිනට් පත්‍රිකාවක් සඳහා අනුමැතිය සඳහා ශ්‍රී ලංකා පොදුජන පෙරමුණේ පාර්ලිමේන්තු මන්ත්‍රීවරුන් රැසක් ඉදිරිපත්ව ඇති බව සන්ඩේ ටයිම්ස් පුවත්පත වාර්තා කරයි. 2015-2019 දක්වා \"දේශපාලන පලිගැනීම්\" වලට ලක් වූ රාජ්‍ය නිලධාරීන් සඳහා රුපියල් මිලියන 117ක්.",
        "වාර්තාවට අනුව හිටපු අගවිනිසුරු අශෝක ද සිල්වාගේ ප්‍රධානත්වයෙන් යුත් කමිටුවේ නිර්දේශ අනුව හිටපු අග්‍රාමාත්‍ය මහින්ද රාජපක්ෂ විසින් කැබිනට් පත්‍රිකාව සම්පාදනය කළ නමුත් රාජපක්ෂ මැයි 9 වැනිදා ඉල්ලා අස්වීම හේතුවෙන් අනුමැතිය සඳහා ඉදිරිපත් නොකළ බව වාර්තාවේ.",
        "එහෙත් වාර්තාවට අනුව දිනේෂ් ගුණවර්ධන අග්‍රාමාත්‍ය ධූරයට පත්වීමෙන් පසු එම පත්‍රිකාව කැබිනට් මණ්ඩලයට ඉදිරිපත් කිරීමට දැන් උත්සාහ දරමින් සිටී.",
        "එපමණක් නොව, කමිටුව විසින් හඳුනාගත් නිලධාරීන් සඳහා වන්දි ලබා ගැනීමට ශ්‍රී ලංකා පොදුජන පෙරමුණේ ජ්‍යෙෂ්ඨ සාමාජිකයින් උත්සාහ කරන බව තමන්ට වැටහෙන බව වාර්තාවේ සඳහන් වේ.",
        "නිලධාරීන් 27 දෙනෙකුට මුදල් වන්දි ලැබීමට නියමිත අතර එය රු. 700,000 සිට රු. කමිටුවේ නිර්දේශ අනුව රුපියල් මිලියන 25 කි.",
        "දෙමළ ජනතාව තෘප්තිමත් වන තුරු විපක්ෂයේ සහය දෙනවා: සී.වී. විග්නේෂ්වරන්"
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "News 1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මණ්ඩල",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "මිලියන 117 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "යහපාලනය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "2015-2019",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉරිදා ටයිම්ස්",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "සන්ඩේ ටයිම්ස්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "පොදුජන පෙරමුණේ පාර්ලිමේන්තු මන්ත්‍රීවරු",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "මණ්ඩල",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "මිලියන 117 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "2015-2019",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "මණ්ඩල",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "මහින්ද රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "අශෝක ද සිල්වා",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "9 වැනි",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "මැයි",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "මණ්ඩල",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "දිනේෂ් ගුණවර්ධන",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "SLPP",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "27",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "මිලියන 25 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "CV. විග්නේෂ්වරන්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "‘பாதிக்கப்பட்ட’ SLPP மூத்தவர்கள் இழப்பீடு வழங்க அழுத்தம்: அறிக்கை",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); பல SLPP பாராளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர்கள் ஒரு அமைச்சரவை பத்திரத்திற்கு அனுமதி கோரியுள்ளனர். 2015-2019 க்கு முந்தைய யஹபாலனயா நிர்வாகத்தின் கீழ் \"அரசியல் பழிவாங்கலுக்கு\" உட்பட்டதாகக் கூறப்படும் அரச அதிகாரிகளுக்கு 117 மில்லியன் ரூபாய் வழங்கப்பட்டுள்ளது என்று சண்டே டைம்ஸ் தெரிவித்துள்ளது.",
        "ஶ்ரீலங்கா பொதுஜன பெரமுனவின் பாராளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர்கள் பலர் 2000 கோடி ரூபாவிற்கும் அதிகமான நட்டஈட்டைப் பரிந்துரைக்கும் அமைச்சரவைப் பத்திரத்திற்கு அங்கீகாரம் வழங்க முன்வந்துள்ளதாக சண்டே டைம்ஸ் செய்தி வெளியிட்டுள்ளது. 2015-2019 வரை \"அரசியல் பழிவாங்கலுக்கு\" உட்படுத்தப்பட்ட அரச அதிகாரிகளுக்கு 117 மில்லியன்.",
        "முன்னாள் பிரதம நீதியரசர் அசோக டி சில்வா தலைமையிலான குழுவின் பரிந்துரைகளுக்கு அமைவாக முன்னாள் பிரதமர் மஹிந்த ராஜபக்ஷவினால் அமைச்சரவைப் பத்திரம் தயாரிக்கப்பட்டதாகவும், மே மாதம் 9ஆம் திகதி ராஜபக்ச ராஜினாமா செய்ததன் காரணமாக ஒப்புதலுக்காக சமர்ப்பிக்கப்படவில்லை எனவும் தெரிவிக்கப்பட்டுள்ளது.",
        "எனினும், அந்த அறிக்கையின்படி, பிரதம மந்திரி தினேஷ் குணவர்தன பதவியேற்றதன் பின்னர் அமைச்சரவையில் பத்திரத்தை சமர்ப்பிக்க முயற்சிகள் மேற்கொள்ளப்பட்டு வருகின்றன.",
        "மேலும், குழுவால் அடையாளம் காணப்பட்ட அதிகாரிகளுக்கு இழப்பீடு வழங்க மூத்த SLPP உறுப்பினர்கள் முயற்சித்து வருகின்றனர் என்பதை புரிந்துகொள்வதாக அறிக்கை கூறுகிறது.",
        "மொத்தம் 27 அதிகாரிகள் பண இழப்பீடு பெற உள்ளனர், இது ரூ. 700,000 முதல் ரூ. குழுவின் பரிந்துரைகளின்படி 25 மில்லியன்.",
        "தமிழ் மக்கள் திருப்தி அடையும் வரை எதிர்க்கட்சிகளின் ஆதரவு: சி.வி. விக்னேஸ்வரன்"
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "News 1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "மந்திரி சபை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "117 மில்லியன்",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "யஹபாலனாய",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "2015-2019",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சண்டே டைம்ஸ்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "தி சண்டே டைம்ஸ்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "பொதுஜன பெரமுன பாராளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர்கள்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "மந்திரி சபை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "117 மில்லியன்",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "2015-2019",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "மந்திரி சபை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "மஹிந்த ராஜபக்ஷ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "அசோக டி சில்வா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ராஜபக்சே",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "9வது",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "மே",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "மந்திரி சபை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "தினேஷ் குணவர்தன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "எஸ்.எல்.பி.பி",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "27",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "25 மில்லியன்",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "சுயவிவரம். விக்னேஸ்வரன்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}