{
  "newspaper_id": "ada-derana-lk",
  "url": "http://www.adaderana.lk/news/83988/51-year-old-man-shot-dead-in-kotahena",
  "time_ut": 1659239280,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "51-year-old man shot dead in Kotahena",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "51-year-old man shot dead in Kotahena",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "A person has been killed in a shooting incident on Vivekananda Road in the Foreshore Police Area in Colombo.",
        "The shooting had been carried out by two unidentified gunmen who had arrived on a motorcycle last night (30).",
        "The 51-year-old shooting victim had succumbed to injuries after being rushed to the Colombo National Hospital.",
        "The incident had been recorded in a nearby CCTV camera while police are probing the motive behind the shooting."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "51-year-old",
          "label": "DATE"
        },
        {
          "text": "Kotahena",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Vivekananda Road",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Colombo",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "two",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "51-year-old",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Colombo National Hospital",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "CCTV",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "කොටහේන ප්‍රදේශයේදී 51 හැවිරිදි පුද්ගලයෙකු වෙඩි තබා ඝාතනය කර තිබේ",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "කොළඹ, ෆොරෂෝර් පොලිස් බල ප්‍රදේශයේ විවේකානන්ද පාරේ සිදුවූ වෙඩි තැබීමකින් පුද්ගලයෙකු ජීවිතක්ෂයට පත්ව තිබෙනවා.",
        "ඊයේ (30) රාත්‍රියේ යතුරුපැදියකින් පැමිණි නාඳුනන තුවක්කුකරුවන් දෙදෙනෙකු විසින් මෙම වෙඩි තැබීම සිදුකර තිබේ.",
        "වෙඩි තැබීමෙන් තුවාල ලැබූ 51 හැවිරිදි පුද්ගලයා කොළඹ ජාතික රෝහලට ඇතුළත් කිරීමෙන් පසු මියගොස් තිබේ.",
        "වෙඩි තැබීමට හේතුව කුමක් දැයි පොලිසිය පරීක්‍ෂණ පවත්වද්දී ඒ අසල තිබූ සීසීටීවී කැමරාවක මෙම සිද්ධිය සටහන් වී තිබිණි."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "51 හැවිරිදිය",
          "label": "DATE"
        },
        {
          "text": "කොටහේන",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "විවේකානන්ද පාර",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "කොළඹ",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "දෙක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "51 හැවිරිදිය",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "කොළඹ ජාතික රෝහල",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "සීසීටීවී",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "கொட்டாஞ்சேனையில் 51 வயதுடைய நபர் சுட்டுக்கொலை செய்யப்பட்டுள்ளார்",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "கொழும்பு, ஃபோர்ஷோர் பொலிஸ் பிரிவுக்குட்பட்ட விவேகானந்தா வீதியில் இடம்பெற்ற துப்பாக்கிச் சூட்டுச் சம்பவத்தில் ஒருவர் உயிரிழந்துள்ளார்.",
        "நேற்று (30) இரவு மோட்டார் சைக்கிளில் வந்த இனந்தெரியாத ஆயுததாரிகள் இருவரால் இந்த துப்பாக்கிச் சூடு நடத்தப்பட்டுள்ளது.",
        "துப்பாக்கிச் சூட்டுக்கு இலக்கான 51 வயதுடைய நபர், கொழும்பு தேசிய வைத்தியசாலையில் அனுமதிக்கப்பட்ட பின்னர் உயிரிழந்துள்ளார்.",
        "துப்பாக்கிச்சூடு நடத்தியதற்கான காரணம் குறித்து போலீசார் விசாரணை நடத்தி வரும் நிலையில், இந்த சம்பவம் அருகில் உள்ள சிசிடிவி கேமராவில் பதிவாகியுள்ளது."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "51 வயது",
          "label": "DATE"
        },
        {
          "text": "கொட்டாஞ்சேனை",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "விவேகானந்தா சாலை",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "கொழும்பு",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இரண்டு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "51 வயது",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "கொழும்பு தேசிய வைத்தியசாலை",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "மறைகாணி",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}