{
  "newspaper_id": "lankadeepa-lk",
  "url": "https://www.lankadeepa.lk/latest_news/එක්-දින-පාස්පෝට්-සේවය-තවත්-දිස්ත්‍රික්ක-තුනකින්/1-615609",
  "time_ut": 1656499755,
  "original_lang": "si",
  "original_title": "එක් දින පාස්පෝට් සේවය තවත් දිස්ත්‍රික්ක තුනකින්",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "One-day passport service in three more districts",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "The one-day passport issuance service will be available in three more districts from next Monday (4), said Investment Promotion Minister Dhammika Perera.",
        "Accordingly, the issuance of passports under the one day service will commence from next Monday from the offices of the Department of Immigration and Emigration in Matara, Kandy and Vavuniya, the Minister said.",
        "Dhammika Perera also said that the one year visa valid for foreigners married to Sri Lankans will be extended to 5 years.",
        "Dhammika Perera, Hon. Minister of Investment Promotion, visited the Department of Immigration and Emigration today (29) and said that these steps will be taken to address the problems faced by the public who come to seek its services.",
        "Minister Dhammika Perera also said that a separate counter will be opened at the Head Office of the Department of Immigration and Emigration in Suhurupaya, Battaramulla to issue passports to those who have completed the required documents to go for foreign employment.",
        "Accordingly, those who have the relevant documents can go to this special counter and obtain their passports without having to wait in the usual queue, the Minister said.",
        "The Minister also took steps to provide a photocopying database to the Department of Immigration and Emigration at his own expense at a cost of Rs. have.",
        "The number of tourists arriving in the country should be announced daily on the social media network Twitter from next Monday (4) and accordingly the number of tourists who arrived the previous day will be announced every day from next Monday at 9.00 am on the Twitter account of the Department of Immigration and Emigration.",
        "The Minister said that the importation of foreign exchange through the 'Golden Paradise' visa program proposed to the government by Dhammika Perera before he became a Minister was still being delayed due to the fact that the Central Bank of Sri Lanka has not yet given approval to commercial banks to accept such deposits.",
        "Mr. Dhammika Perera stated that discussions will be held with the Central Bank officials in this regard and a solution will be worked out expeditiously."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "One-day",
          "label": "DATE"
        },
        {
          "text": "three",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "one-day",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "three",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "next Monday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "4",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Investment Promotion",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Dhammika Perera",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "one day",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "next Monday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Department of Immigration and Emigration",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Matara",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kandy",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Vavuniya",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Dhammika Perera",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "one year",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lankans",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "5 years",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Dhammika Perera",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Hon",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Investment Promotion",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Department of Immigration and Emigration",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "29",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Dhammika Perera",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Head Office of the Department of Immigration and Emigration",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "the Department of Immigration and Emigration",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "daily",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "next Monday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "4",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "the previous day",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "every day",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "next Monday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "9.00",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Twitter",
            "label": "PRODUCT"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Department of Immigration and Emigration",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Dhammika Perera",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Central Bank of Sri Lanka",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Dhammika Perera",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Central Bank",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "එක් දින පාස්පෝට් සේවය තවත් දිස්ත්‍රික්ක තුනකින්",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "විදෙස් ගමන් බලපත්‍ර නිකුත් කිරීමේ එක්දින සේවාව ලබන සඳුදා (4) සිට තවත් දිස්ත්‍රික්ක තුනක දී ලබාගත හැකිබව ආයෝජන ප්‍රවර්ධන අමාත්‍ය ධම්මික පෙරේරා මහතා පැවසීය.",
        "ඒ අනුව මාතර, මහනුවර සහ වව්නියාව යන නගරවල පිහිටි ආගමන විගමන දෙපාර්තමේන්තු කාර්යාලවලින් ලබන සඳුදා සිට එක්දින සේවාව යටතේ විදෙස් ගමන් බලපත්‍ර නිකුත් කිරීම ආරම්භ කරන බවයි අමාත්‍යවරයා ප්‍රකාශ කළේය.",
        "ශ්‍රී ලාංකිකයින් සමග විවාහ වූ විදේශිකයින්ට මෙරටදී මෙතෙක් ලැබුණු වසරක වීසා කාලය වසර 5 දක්වා දීර්ඝ කරන බව ද ධම්මික පෙරේරා මහතා කීවේය.",
        "ආයෝජන ප්‍රවර්ධන ගරු අමාත්‍ය ධම්මික පෙරේරා මහතා අද (29) ආගමන විගමන දෙපාර්තමේන්තුවේ හදිසි නිරීක්ෂණ චාරිකාවකට එක්වූ අතර, එහි සේවය ලබා ගැනීමට පැමිණෙන මහජනතාව මුහුණ දෙන ගැටලු විසඳීම සඳහා මෙම පියවර ගන්නා බව ද පැවසීය.",
        "විදෙස් රැකියා සඳහා යාමට ලියකියවිලි සම්පූර්ණ කරගෙන ඇති පුද්ගලයින්ට කඩිනමින් විදෙස් ගමන් බලපත්‍ර ලබාදීමට බත්තරමුල්ල, සුහුරුපායේ පිහිටි ආගමන විගමන දෙපාර්තමේන්තුවේ පිහිටි ප්‍රධාන කාර්යාලයේ වෙනම කවුන්ටරයක් විවෘත කරන බව ද අමාත්‍ය ධම්මික පෙරේරා මහතා කීවේය.",
        "ඒ අනුව අදාළ ලේඛන ඇති අයට සාමාන්‍ය පෝලිමෙහි නොසිට මෙම විශේෂ කවුන්ටරයට ගොස් ඉක්මනින් විදෙස් ගමන් බලපත්‍ර ලබාගැනීමට හැකි බවයි අමාත්‍යවරයා සඳහන් කළේය.",
        "විදෙස් ගමන් බලපත්‍ර සඳහා අනුමත ඡායාරූප ශාලාවලින් ලබාගන්නා ඡායාරූප ආගමන විගමන දෙපාර්තමේන්තුවේ දත්ත පද්ධතියට යොමු කිරීමේදී උද්ගත වී ඇති ගැටලුවට දිගු කාලීන විසඳුමක් සොයාගන්නා තෙක් තම පුද්ගලික මුදලින් රුපියල් ලක්ෂ 9ක් වැයකර එම දෙපාර්තමේන්තුව වෙත කුලී පදනම මත ඡායාරූප යොමුකිරීමේ දත්ත පද්ධතියක් (ිැරඩැර) ලබාදීමට ද ඇමතිවරයා පියවර ගෙන ඇත.",
        "මෙරටට පැමිණෙන සංචාරකයින් සංඛ්‍යාව ලබන සඳුදා (4) සිට ට්විටර් සමාජ මාධ්‍ය ජාලය ඔස්සේ දිනපතා ප්‍රකාශ කළ යුතු බවත්, ඒ අනුව පෙර දින පැමිණි සංචාරකයින් සංඛ්‍යාව ලබන සඳුදා සිට සෑම දිනකම උදෑසන 9.00 ට ආගමන විගමන දෙපාර්තමේන්තුවේ ට්විටර් ගිණුම ඔස්සේ නිවේදනය කෙරනු ඇති බවත් ඇමතිවරයා කීය.",
        "ධම්මික පෙරේරා මහතා අමාත්‍යධුරයට පත්වීමට පෙර රජයට යෝජනා කළ ”ස්වර්ණමය පාරාදීසය” වීසා වැඩසටහන ඔස්සේ මෙරටට විදේශ විනිමය ගෙන්වා ගැනීම තවමත් ප්‍රමාද වෙමින් පවතින බව කී ඇමතිවරයා එම මුදල් තැන්පතු භාරගැනීම සඳහා ශ්‍රී ලංකා මහබැංකුව විසින් වාණිජ බැංකුවලට තවමත් අනුමැතිය ලබා නොදීම ඊට හේතුවී ඇතැයි කීය.",
        "මේ සම්බන්ධයෙන් මහබැංකු නිලධාරීන් සමග සාකච්ඡා කර කඩිනමින් විසඳුමක් ලබාදීමට ක්‍රියාකරන බව ධම්මික පෙරේරා මහතා සඳහන් කළේය."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "එක දවසක්",
          "label": "DATE"
        },
        {
          "text": "තුන්",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "එක දවසක්",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "තුන්",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ලබන සඳුදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "4",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ආයෝජන ප්රවර්ධනය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ධම්මික පෙරේරා",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "එක දවසක්",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ලබන සඳුදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ආගමන හා විගමන දෙපාර්තමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "මාතර",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මහනුවර",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "වවුනියාව",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ධම්මික පෙරේරා",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "වසරක්",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලාංකිකයන්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "වසර 5 ක්",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ධම්මික පෙරේරා",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගරු",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ආයෝජන ප්රවර්ධනය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ආගමන හා විගමන දෙපාර්තමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "29",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ධම්මික පෙරේරා",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ආගමන හා විගමන දෙපාර්තමේන්තුවේ ප්‍රධාන කාර්යාලය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "ආගමන හා විගමන දෙපාර්තමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "දිනපතා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ලබන සඳුදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "4",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "පෙර දින",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "සෑම දිනම",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ලබන සඳුදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "9.00",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ට්විටර්",
            "label": "PRODUCT"
          },
          {
            "text": "ආගමන හා විගමන දෙපාර්තමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ධම්මික පෙරේරා",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකා මහ බැංකුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ධම්මික පෙරේරා",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "මහ බැංකුව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "மேலும் மூன்று மாவட்டங்களில் ஒரு நாள் பாஸ்போர்ட் சேவை",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "ஒரு நாள் கடவுச்சீட்டு வழங்கும் சேவை எதிர்வரும் திங்கட்கிழமை (4) மேலும் மூன்று மாவட்டங்களில் நடைமுறைப்படுத்தப்படும் என முதலீட்டு ஊக்குவிப்பு அமைச்சர் தம்மிக்க பெரேரா தெரிவித்துள்ளார்.",
        "இதன்படி, மாத்தறை, கண்டி மற்றும் வவுனியாவில் உள்ள குடிவரவு குடியகல்வு திணைக்கள அலுவலகங்களில் ஒரு நாள் சேவையின் கீழ் கடவுச்சீட்டு வழங்கும் பணிகள் எதிர்வரும் திங்கட்கிழமை முதல் ஆரம்பிக்கப்படும் என அமைச்சர் தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "இலங்கையர்களை திருமணம் செய்யும் வெளிநாட்டினருக்கு ஒரு வருட வீசா செல்லுபடியாகும் காலம் 5 வருடங்களாக நீடிக்கப்படும் எனவும் தம்மிக்க பெரேரா தெரிவித்துள்ளார்.",
        "கௌரவ முதலீட்டு ஊக்குவிப்பு அமைச்சர் தம்மிக்க பெரேரா அவர்கள் இன்று (29) குடிவரவு மற்றும் குடியகல்வு திணைக்களத்திற்கு விஜயம் செய்து அதன் சேவைகளை பெற வரும் பொதுமக்கள் எதிர்நோக்கும் பிரச்சினைகளுக்கு தீர்வு காணும் நோக்கில் இந்த நடவடிக்கை எடுக்கப்படுவதாக தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "வெளிநாட்டு வேலைவாய்ப்பிற்கு செல்வதற்கு தேவையான ஆவணங்களை பூர்த்தி செய்தவர்களுக்கு கடவுச்சீட்டை வழங்குவதற்காக பத்தரமுல்ல சுஹுருபாயவில் அமைந்துள்ள குடிவரவு குடியகல்வு திணைக்களத்தின் தலைமை அலுவலகத்தில் தனியான கவுன்டர் திறக்கப்படும் எனவும் அமைச்சர் தம்மிக்க பெரேரா தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "இதன்படி உரிய ஆவணங்களை வைத்திருப்பவர்கள் வழமையான வரிசையில் காத்திருக்காமல் இந்த விசேட கவுன்டருக்குச் சென்று கடவுச்சீட்டுகளை பெற்றுக்கொள்ள முடியும் என அமைச்சர் தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "குடிவரவு மற்றும் குடியகல்வு திணைக்களத்திற்கு தனது சொந்த செலவில் 1000 ரூபா செலவில் புகைப்பட நகல் தரவுத்தளத்தை வழங்க அமைச்சர் நடவடிக்கை எடுத்தார்.",
        "எதிர்வரும் திங்கட்கிழமை (4) முதல் நாட்டிற்கு வரும் சுற்றுலாப் பயணிகளின் எண்ணிக்கை ட்விட்டர் சமூக ஊடக வலையமைப்பில் அறிவிக்கப்பட வேண்டும், அதன்படி முந்தைய நாள் வந்த சுற்றுலாப் பயணிகளின் எண்ணிக்கை வரும் திங்கட்கிழமை முதல் ஒவ்வொரு நாளும் காலை 9.00 மணிக்கு ட்விட்டர் கணக்கில் அறிவிக்கப்படும். குடிவரவு மற்றும் குடியகல்வு திணைக்களம்.",
        "தம்மிக்க பெரேரா அமைச்சராவதற்கு முன்னர் அரசாங்கத்திற்கு முன்மொழிந்த 'கோல்டன் பாரடைஸ்' வீசா திட்டத்தின் ஊடாக அந்நிய செலாவணியை இறக்குமதி செய்வதற்கு இலங்கை மத்திய வங்கி இன்னும் அனுமதி வழங்காத காரணத்தினால் இன்னும் தாமதமாகி வருவதாக அமைச்சர் தெரிவித்தார். வணிக வங்கிகள் அத்தகைய வைப்புகளை ஏற்க வேண்டும்.",
        "இது தொடர்பில் மத்திய வங்கி அதிகாரிகளுடன் கலந்துரையாடி துரித கதியில் தீர்வு எட்டப்படும் என தம்மிக்க பெரேரா குறிப்பிட்டுள்ளார்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ஒரு நாள்",
          "label": "DATE"
        },
        {
          "text": "மூன்று",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ஒரு நாள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "மூன்று",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "அடுத்த திங்கள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "4",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "முதலீட்டு ஊக்குவிப்பு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "தம்மிக்க பெரேரா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஒரு நாள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "அடுத்த திங்கள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "குடிவரவு மற்றும் குடியகல்வு திணைக்களம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "மாத்தறை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "கண்டி",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "வவுனியா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "தம்மிக்க பெரேரா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஒரு வருடம்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கையர்கள்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "5 ஆண்டுகள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "தம்மிக்க பெரேரா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "கௌரவ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "முதலீட்டு ஊக்குவிப்பு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "குடிவரவு மற்றும் குடியகல்வு திணைக்களம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "29",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "தம்மிக்க பெரேரா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "குடிவரவு மற்றும் குடியகல்வு திணைக்களத்தின் தலைமை அலுவலகம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "குடிவரவு மற்றும் குடியகல்வு திணைக்களம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "தினசரி",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "அடுத்த திங்கள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "4",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "முந்தைய நாள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "தினமும்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "அடுத்த திங்கள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "9.00",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ட்விட்டர்",
            "label": "PRODUCT"
          },
          {
            "text": "குடிவரவு மற்றும் குடியகல்வு திணைக்களம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "தம்மிக்க பெரேரா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை மத்திய வங்கி",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "தம்மிக்க பெரேரா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "மத்திய வங்கி",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}