{
  "newspaper_id": "virakesari-lk",
  "url": "http://www.virakesari.lk/article/132378",
  "time_ut": 1658933372,
  "original_lang": "ta",
  "original_title": "இலங்கை சீனாவுடன் கடன் மறுசீரமைப்பு தொடர்பான பேச்சுவார்த்தைகளை ஆரம்பிக்கவேண்டும்- சர்வதேச நாணயநிதியம்",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Sri Lanka to start debt restructuring talks with China - IMF",
      "author": "Rajeeban",
      "body_lines": [
        "International Monetary Fund has said that Sri Lanka should start debt restructuring talks with China.",
        "Krishna Srinivasan, Director for Asia Pacific of the International Monetary Fund, said that China, the biggest creditor of Sri Lanka, should negotiate positively with China regarding debt restructuring.",
        "The country of 22 million people is facing an economic and political crisis like never before in its history.",
        "Ranil Wickremesinghe, who served six times as Prime Minister, has been sworn in as the President following the removal of the previous President due to a massive popular uprising following months of fuel, food and medicine shortages.",
        "Sri Lanka owes China $6.5 billion in debt, the International Monetary Fund has said.",
        "The world's second largest economy has invested in highways, ports and airports.",
        "Krishna Srinivasan has said that Sri Lanka should enter into debt restructuring negotiations with its private and public creditors.",
        "He mentioned that Sri Lanka should do this to ensure that creditworthiness is re-established.",
        "Sri Lanka has asked the International Monetary Fund to come up with a recovery plan to recover from its worst economic crisis since independence.",
        "Sri Lanka, which has been struggling to make payments to key importers, defaulted on its 12 billion foreign debt and defaulted in April.",
        "The official of the International Monetary Fund has said that we need to see progress on some issues, however, he refused to comment on the major reforms that Sri Lanka needs to carry out in order to achieve compliance with the International Monetary Fund."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Sri Lanka",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "China",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "International Monetary Fund",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "China",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Krishna Srinivasan",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Asia Pacific",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the International Monetary Fund",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "China",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "China",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "22 million",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "six",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "months",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "China",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "$6.5 billion",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "the International Monetary Fund",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "second",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Krishna Srinivasan",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the International Monetary Fund",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "12 billion",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "April",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the International Monetary Fund",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the International Monetary Fund",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "ශ්‍රී ලංකාව චීනය සමඟ ණය ප්‍රතිව්‍යුහගත කිරීමේ සාකච්ඡා අරඹයි - IMF",
      "author": "රජීබන්",
      "body_lines": [
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකාව චීනය සමඟ ණය ප්‍රතිව්‍යුහගත කිරීමේ සාකච්ඡා ආරම්භ කළ යුතු බව ජාත්‍යන්තර මූල්‍ය අරමුදල පවසා තිබේ.",
        "ජාත්‍යන්තර මූල්‍ය අරමුදලේ ආසියා ශාන්තිකර කලාපීය අධ්‍යක්ෂ ක්‍රිෂ්ණ ශ්‍රීනිවාසන් මහතා පැවසුවේ, ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ විශාලතම ණය හිමියා වන චීනය, ණය ප්‍රතිව්‍යුහගත කිරීම සම්බන්ධයෙන් චීනය සමඟ ධනාත්මකව සාකච්ඡා කළ යුතු බවයි.",
        "මිලියන 22 ක ජනතාවක් වෙසෙන රට ඉතිහාසයේ කිසිදා නොවූ විරූ ආකාරයේ ආර්ථික හා දේශපාලන අර්බුදයකට මුහුණ දී සිටී.",
        "මාස ගණනක ඉන්ධන, ආහාර සහ ඖෂධ හිඟයෙන් පසු ඇති වූ දැවැන්ත ජනතා නැගිටීම හේතුවෙන් හිටපු ජනාධිපතිවරයා ඉවත් කිරීමෙන් පසු හය වතාවක් අගමැති ධුරය දැරූ රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතා ජනාධිපතිවරයා ලෙස දිවුරුම් දී තිබේ.",
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකාව චීනයට ඩොලර් බිලියන 6.5 ක ණය මුදලක් ගෙවිය යුතු බව ජාත්‍යන්තර මූල්‍ය අරමුදල පවසයි.",
        "ලෝකයේ දෙවන විශාලතම ආර්ථිකය මහාමාර්ග, වරාය සහ ගුවන් තොටුපල සඳහා ආයෝජනය කර ඇත.",
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකාව සිය පෞද්ගලික සහ රාජ්‍ය ණය හිමියන් සමඟ ණය ප්‍රතිව්‍යුහගත කිරීමේ සාකච්ඡාවලට එළඹිය යුතු බව ක්‍රිෂ්ණ ශ්‍රීනිවාසන් පවසා තිබේ.",
        "ණය යෝග්‍යතාවය නැවත ස්ථාපිත කිරීම සහතික කිරීම සඳහා ශ්‍රී ලංකාව මෙය කළ යුතු බව ඔහු සඳහන් කළේය.",
        "නිදහසින් පසු ශ්‍රී ලංකාව මුහුණ දුන් දරුණුතම ආර්ථික අර්බුදයෙන් ගොඩ ඒම සඳහා ප්‍රකෘතිමත් සැලැස්මක් ඉදිරිපත් කරන ලෙස ශ්‍රී ලංකාව ජාත්‍යන්තර මූල්‍ය අරමුදලෙන් ඉල්ලා තිබේ.",
        "ප්‍රධාන ආනයනකරුවන්ට ගෙවීම් කිරීමට පොරබදමින් සිටින ශ්‍රී ලංකාව, බිලියන 12 ක විදේශ ණය ගෙවීම පැහැර හරින ලද අතර අප්‍රේල් මාසයේදී පැහැර හරින ලදී.",
        "ජාත්‍යන්තර මූල්‍ය අරමුදලේ නිලධාරියා පවසා ඇත්තේ සමහර කරුණු සම්බන්ධයෙන් අපට ප්‍රගතියක් දැකිය යුතු බවත්, කෙසේ වෙතත්, ජාත්‍යන්තර මූල්‍ය අරමුදලට අනුකූල වීම සඳහා ශ්‍රී ලංකාව සිදු කළ යුතු ප්‍රධාන ප්‍රතිසංස්කරණ පිළිබඳව අදහස් දැක්වීම ඔහු ප්‍රතික්ෂේප කළේය."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "චීනය",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ජාත්යන්තර මූල්ය අරමුදල",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "චීනය",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ක්‍රිෂ්ණ ශ්‍රීනිවාසන්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ආසියා පැසිෆික්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජාත්‍යන්තර මුල්‍ය අරමුදල",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "චීනය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "චීනය",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "මිලියන 22 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "හය",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "මාස",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "චීනය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඩොලර් බිලියන 6.5 කි",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජාත්‍යන්තර මුල්‍ය අරමුදල",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "දෙවැනි",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ක්‍රිෂ්ණ ශ්‍රීනිවාසන්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජාත්‍යන්තර මුල්‍ය අරමුදල",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "බිලියන 12 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "අප්රේල්",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ජාත්‍යන්තර මුල්‍ය අරමුදල",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජාත්‍යන්තර මුල්‍ය අරමුදල",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "இலங்கை சீனாவுடன் கடன் மறுசீரமைப்பு தொடர்பான பேச்சுவார்த்தைகளை ஆரம்பிக்கவேண்டும்- சர்வதேச நாணயநிதியம்",
      "author": "Rajeeban",
      "body_lines": [
        "இலங்கை சீனாவுடன் கடன் மறுசீரமைப்பு தொடர்பான பேச்சுவார்த்தைகளை ஆரம்பிக்கவேண்டும் என சர்வதேச நாணயநிதியம் தெரிவித்துள்ளது.",
        "சீனா பெரிய கடன்வழங்கும் நாடு இலங்கை கடன்மறுசீரமைப்பு தொடர்பில் சீனாவுடன் சாதகமான விதத்தில் பேச்சுவார்த்தைகளை மேற்கொள்ளவேண்டும் என சர்வதேச நாணயநிதியத்தின் ஆசிய பசுபிக்கிற்கான இயக்குநர் கிருஸ்ணா ஸ்ரீனிவாசன் தெரிவித்துள்ளார்.",
        "22 மில்லியன் மக்களை கொண்ட நாடு அதன் வரலாற்றில் ஒருபோதும் இல்லாத பொருளாதார அரசியல் நெருக்கடியை  எதிர்கொண்டுள்ளது.",
        "பலமாத எரிபொருள் உணவு மற்றும் மருந்து தட்டுப்பாட்டினை தொடர்ந்து உருவான பாரிய மக்கள் எழுச்சி காரணமாக முன்னைய ஜனாதிபதி பதவி நீக்கப்பட்டதை தொடர்ந்து ஆறு தடவை பிரதமராக பதவி வகித்த ரணில்விக்கிரமசிங்க ஜனாதிபதியாக பதவியேற்றுள்ளார்.",
        "இலங்கை சீனாவிற்கு 6.5 பில்லியன் டொலர்க கடனை செலுத்தவேண்டியுள்ளது என சர்வதேச நிதி நிறுவகம் தெரிவித்துள்ளது.",
        "உலகின் இரண்டாவது மிகப்பெரிய பொருளாதார நாடு பெருந்தெருக்கள் துறைமுகம் விமானம் நிலையம் ஆகியவற்றில் முதலீடு செய்துள்ளது.",
        "இலங்கை அதற்கு கடன்வழங்கிய தனியார் மற்றும் அரச கடன்வழங்குநர்களிடம் கடன் மறுசீரமைப்பு தொடர்பில் பேச்சுவார்த்தைகளை மேற்கொள்ளவேண்டும்,என கிருஸ்ணா ஸ்ரீனிவாசன் தெரிவித்துள்ளார்.",
        "கடன்பேண்தகுதன்மை மீண்டும் நிலைநாட்டப்படுவதை உறுதி செய்வதற்காக இதனை இலங்கை செய்யவேண்டும் என அவர் குறிப்பிட்டுள்ளார்.",
        "சுதந்திரத்திற்கு பின்னரான தனது மோசமான பொருளாதார நெருக்கடியிலிருந்து மீள்வதற்காக இலங்கை மீட்சி திட்டமொன்றை முன்வைக்குமாறு சர்வதேச நாணயநிதியத்திடம் கோரியுள்ளது.",
        "அடிப்படை இறக்குமிகளிற்கான பணத்தை செலுத்துவதற்காக பெரும் சிரமத்தை எதிர்கொண்டுள்ள இலங்கை அதன் 12 பில்லியன் வெளிநாட்டுக்கடனில் பிணைமுறி கடன்கொடுப்பனவை செலுத்த முடியாமல் ஏப்பிரலில் வங்குரோத்து நிலைக்கு தள்ளப்பட்டது.",
        "சில விடயங்களில் நாங்கள் முன்னேற்றத்தை காணவேண்டியுள்ளது என தெரிவித்துள்ள சர்வதேச நாணயநிதியத்தின் அதிகாரி எனினும் சர்வதேச நாணயநிதியத்துடன் இணக்கப்பாட்டை எட்டுவதற்காக இலங்கை முன்னெடுக்கவேண்டிய  முக்கிய சீர்திருத்தங்கள் குறித்து கருத்து தெரிவிக்க மறுத்துவிட்டார்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "இலங்கை",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "சீனா",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "சர்வதேச நாணய நிதியம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சீனா",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "கிருஷ்ணா சீனிவாசன்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆசிய பசிபிக்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "சர்வதேச நாணய நிதியம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "சீனா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சீனா",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "22 மில்லியன்",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆறு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "மாதங்கள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சீனா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "$6.5 பில்லியன்",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "சர்வதேச நாணய நிதியம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இரண்டாவது",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "கிருஷ்ணா சீனிவாசன்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சர்வதேச நாணய நிதியம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "12 பில்லியன்",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஏப்ரல்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "சர்வதேச நாணய நிதியம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சர்வதேச நாணய நிதியம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}