{
  "newspaper_id": "news-first-lk",
  "url": "https://www.newsfirst.lk/2022/07/08/basl-questions-grounds-to-declare-curfew/",
  "time_ut": 1657296360,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "BASL questions grounds to declare curfew",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "BASL questions grounds to declare curfew",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); The Bar Association of Sri Lanka has expressed strong protest at the imposition of a purported police curfew within parts of the Western Province by the IGP.",
        "The BASL states that the police ordinance does not have a provision for the imposition of such a curfew and wishes to ask the IGP under what authority has he declared such a curfew.",
        "The BASL said that the declaration of curfew is clearly intended to stifle the freedom of expression and dissent and is totally unacceptable and undemocratic and will gravely harm Sri Lanka’s economy and political stability.",
        "BASL said the failure to withdraw the purported curfew order will have severe consequences for the country.",
        "Govt should Not Try and Curtail The People’s Right of Expression – Sajith"
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "The Bar Association of Sri Lanka",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Western Province",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "IGP",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "BASL",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "IGP",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "BASL",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka’s",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "BASL",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Govt",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "BASL ඇඳිරි නීතිය ප්‍රකාශ කිරීමට හේතු ප්‍රශ්න කරයි",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); පොලිස්පතිවරයා විසින් බස්නාහිර පළාතේ ප්‍රදේශ කිහිපයකට පොලිස් ඇඳිරි නීතිය පැනවීමට එරෙහිව ශ්‍රී ලංකා නීතීඥ සංගමය දැඩි විරෝධය පළ කර තිබේ.",
        "එවැනි ඇඳිරි නීතියක් පැනවීමට පොලිස් ආඥාපනතෙහි ප්‍රතිපාදන නොමැති බවත්, කුමන අධිකාරියක් යටතේ එවැනි ඇඳිරි නීතියක් ප්‍රකාශ කර ඇත්දැයි පොලිස්පතිවරයාගෙන් විමසීමට කැමති බවත් BASL පවසයි.",
        "ඇඳිරි නීතිය ප්‍රකාශ කිරීම පැහැදිලිවම අදහස් කරන්නේ අදහස් ප්‍රකාශ කිරීමේ සහ විසම්මුතියේ නිදහස යටපත් කිරීමට බවත් එය සම්පූර්ණයෙන්ම පිළිගත නොහැකි සහ ප්‍රජාතන්ත්‍ර විරෝධී බවත් ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ ආර්ථිකයට සහ දේශපාලන ස්ථාවරත්වයට බරපතල ලෙස හානි කරන බවත් BASL පවසයි.",
        "ප්‍රකාශිත ඇඳිරි නීතිය ඉවත් කිරීමට අපොහොසත් වීම රටට දැඩි ප්‍රතිවිපාක ගෙන දෙන බව BASL පවසයි.",
        "ජනතාවගේ අදහස් ප්‍රකාශ කිරීමේ අයිතිය කප්පාදු කිරීමට රජය උත්සාහ නොකළ යුතුයි - සජිත්"
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකා නීතිඥ සංගමය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "බස්නාහිර පළාත",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "පොලිස්පති",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "BASL",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "පොලිස්පති",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "BASL",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "BASL",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "රජය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "ஊரடங்கு உத்தரவை அறிவிப்பதற்கான காரணங்களை BASL கேள்வி எழுப்புகிறது",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); பொலிஸ் மா அதிபரினால் மேல் மாகாணத்தின் சில பகுதிகளில் பொலிஸ் ஊரடங்குச் சட்டம் அமுல்படுத்தப்பட்டதற்கு இலங்கை சட்டத்தரணிகள் சங்கம் கடும் எதிர்ப்பை வெளியிட்டுள்ளது.",
        "பொலிஸ் கட்டளைச் சட்டத்தில் அத்தகைய ஊரடங்குச் சட்டத்தை அமுல்படுத்துவதற்கான ஏற்பாடு இல்லை என்றும், எந்த அதிகாரத்தின் கீழ் அவர் அத்தகைய ஊரடங்கு உத்தரவை அறிவித்தார் என்று ஐஜிபியிடம் கேட்க விரும்புவதாகவும் BASL கூறுகிறது.",
        "ஊரடங்கு உத்தரவு பிரகடனம் என்பது கருத்துச் சுதந்திரம் மற்றும் கருத்து வேறுபாடுகளை நசுக்கும் நோக்கம் கொண்டது என்றும் அது முற்றிலும் ஏற்றுக்கொள்ள முடியாதது மற்றும் ஜனநாயகமற்றது என்றும் இலங்கையின் பொருளாதாரம் மற்றும் அரசியல் ஸ்திரத்தன்மைக்கு கடுமையாகப் பாதிப்பை ஏற்படுத்தும் என்றும் BASL தெரிவித்துள்ளது.",
        "கூறப்பட்ட ஊரடங்கு உத்தரவை திரும்பப் பெறத் தவறினால் நாட்டிற்கு கடுமையான விளைவுகள் ஏற்படும் என்று BASL தெரிவித்துள்ளது.",
        "மக்களின் கருத்து உரிமையை பறிக்க அரசு முயற்சிக்கக் கூடாது - சஜித்"
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை சட்டத்தரணிகள் சங்கம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "மேல் மாகாணம்",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஐ.ஜி.பி",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "BASL",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஐ.ஜி.பி",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "BASL",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கையின்",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "BASL",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "அரசு",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}