{
  "newspaper_id": "daily-mirror-lk",
  "url": "https://www.dailymirror.lk/latest_news/Legal-action-against-occupants-loitering-within-a-50-meter-radius-of-SWRD-statue/342-241500",
  "time_ut": 1658379294,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Legal action against occupants loitering within a 50-meter radius of SWRD statue",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Legal action against occupants loitering within a 50-meter radius of SWRD statue",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "The Fort Police said they would take legal action against those who are still occupying the area that comes within 50-meter radius of the statue of SWRD Bandaranaike is situated at the Galle Face in Colombo.",
        "A senior police officer said that still, a group is loitering near the statue defying the court order.",
        "The Colombo Fort Magistrate's Court yesterday issued an order preventing anyone from reaching the 50-meter radius of the  statue.",
        "Colombo Fort Magistrate Thilina Gamage made this order pursuant to a request made by Fort Police that they have received information regarding the possibility of causing damages to the statue.",
        "The police said they will inform the Magistrate about the developments and will take legal action against those disobeying the court order. (Darshsna Sanjeewa Balasuriya)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "50-meter",
          "label": "QUANTITY"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "The Fort Police",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "50-meter",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "SWRD Bandaranaike",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Galle Face",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "Colombo",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "The Colombo Fort Magistrate's",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "yesterday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "50-meter",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Fort Police",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Magistrate",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "SWRD ප්‍රතිමාවේ මීටර් 50ක අරය තුළ ගැවසෙන නිවැසියන්ට එරෙහිව නීතිමය පියවර",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "කොළඹ ගාලු මුවදොර පිහිටි එස්.ඩබ්ලිව්.ආර්.ඩී.බණ්ඩාරනායක පිළිරුවට මීටර් 50ක අරය තුළ ඇති ප්‍රදේශය තවමත් අල්ලාගෙන සිටින පුද්ගලයින්ට එරෙහිව නීතිමය පියවර ගන්නා බව කොටුව පොලිසිය පවසයි.",
        "ජ්‍යෙෂ්ඨ පොලිස් නිලධාරියෙකු පැවසුවේ තවමත් අධිකරණ නියෝගය නොතකා පිරිසක් පිළිරුව අසල ගැවසෙන බවයි.",
        "ප්‍රතිමාවේ මීටර් 50ක අරයට කිසිවෙකුට පැමිණීම වළක්වාලමින් කොළඹ කොටුව මහේස්ත්‍රාත් අධිකරණය ඊයේ නියෝගයක් නිකුත් කළා.",
        "කොළඹ කොටුව මහේස්ත්‍රාත් තිළිණ ගමගේ මහතා මෙම නියෝගය කළේ ප්‍රතිමාවට අලාභහානි කිරීමට ඇති හැකියාව පිළිබඳ තොරතුරු ලැබී ඇති බවට කොටුව පොලිසිය කළ ඉල්ලීමකට අනුවය.",
        "සිද්ධිය සම්බන්ධයෙන් මහේස්ත්‍රාත්වරයා දැනුවත් කරන බවත් අධිකරණ නියෝගයට අවනත නොවන පුද්ගලයන්ට එරෙහිව නීතිමය ක්‍රියාමාර්ග ගන්නා බවත් පොලිසිය ප්‍රකාශ කළේය. (දර්ශණ සංජීව බාලසූරිය)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "මීටර් 50",
          "label": "QUANTITY"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "කොටුව පොලිසිය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "මීටර් 50",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "SWRD බණ්ඩාරනායක",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගාලු මුවදොර",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "කොළඹ",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "ඒ කොළඹ කොටුව මහේස්ත්‍රාත්වරයා විසින්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඊයේ",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මීටර් 50",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "කොටුව පොලිසිය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "මහේස්ත්රාත්වරයා",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "SWRD சிலையின் 50 மீட்டர் சுற்றளவில் ஆக்கிரமிப்பாளர்கள் மீது சட்ட நடவடிக்கை",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "கொழும்பு காலி முகத்திடலில் அமைந்துள்ள எஸ்.டபிள்யூ.ஆர்.டி பண்டாரநாயக்கவின் சிலைக்கு 50 மீற்றர் சுற்றளவிற்குள் இன்னும் ஆக்கிரமிப்பு செய்பவர்களுக்கு எதிராக சட்ட நடவடிக்கை எடுக்கவுள்ளதாக கோட்டை பொலிஸார் தெரிவித்துள்ளனர்.",
        "அப்போதும், நீதிமன்ற உத்தரவை மீறி ஒரு கும்பல் சிலை அருகே சுற்றித்திரிகிறது என்று மூத்த போலீஸ் அதிகாரி ஒருவர் தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "சிலையின் 50 மீற்றர் சுற்றளவிற்கு எவரும் வரக்கூடாது என கொழும்பு கோட்டை நீதவான் நீதிமன்றம் நேற்று உத்தரவு பிறப்பித்துள்ளது.",
        "சிலைக்கு சேதம் விளைவிப்பதற்கான சாத்தியக்கூறுகள் குறித்து தகவல் கிடைத்துள்ளதாக கோட்டை பொலிசார் விடுத்த கோரிக்கைக்கு அமைய கொழும்பு கோட்டை நீதவான் திலின கமகே இந்த உத்தரவை பிறப்பித்துள்ளார்.",
        "இந்த சம்பவங்கள் குறித்து மாஜிஸ்திரேட்டுக்கு தெரியப்படுத்துவதாகவும், நீதிமன்ற உத்தரவை மீறுபவர்களுக்கு எதிராக சட்ட நடவடிக்கை எடுக்கப்படும் என்றும் போலீசார் தெரிவித்தனர். (தர்ஷ்ன சஞ்சீவ பாலசூரிய)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "50-மீட்டர்",
          "label": "QUANTITY"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "கோட்டை போலீஸ்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "50-மீட்டர்",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "எஸ்.டபிள்யூ.ஆர்.டி பண்டாரநாயக்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "காலி முகம்",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "கொழும்பு",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "கொழும்பு கோட்டை நீதவான்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "நேற்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "50-மீட்டர்",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "கோட்டை போலீஸ்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "மாஜிஸ்திரேட்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}