{
  "newspaper_id": "daily-mirror-lk",
  "url": "https://www.dailymirror.lk/breaking_news/Possible-recession-in-eurozone-likely-to-worsen-SLs-forex-woes/108-241216",
  "time_ut": 1657919669,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Possible recession in eurozone likely to worsen SL’s forex woes",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Possible recession in eurozone likely to worsen SL’s forex woes",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "Fitch Ratings says eurozone recession could negatively affect SL’s export and tourism sectors",
        "Says drop in Russian gas supply to Europe indicates strong possibility of recession in eurozone",
        "“Any shock to external demand in Sri Lanka is likely to exacerbate pressure stemming from its already acute shortage of foreign exchange”- Fitch Ratings",
        "Forecasts prospects of a drop-off in outbound European tourism, if Europe falls into a recession",
        "Fitch Ratings this week warned that Sri Lanka’s export and tourism sectors are likely to take a hit from the possible recession in the eurozone and it could further exacerbate the country’s actuate foreign exchange shortage.",
        "“A recession in Europe, which is becoming more likely, would increase external strains and growth challenges for some vulnerable non-European sovereigns, including several in north Africa and south Asia that have high export exposure to the EU,” Fitch Ratings said on Wednesday.",
        "It highlighted that the recent sharp drop in gas export volume from Russia to Europe has raised the likelihood of gas rationing, making a technical recession in the eurozone an increasing possibility.",
        "For the first five month of the year, the European Union (EU) accounted for over a quarter of Sri Lanka’s merchandise export earnings. In the period, Sri Lanka’s merchandise exports to the EU (excluding the United Kingdom) grew by 4.84 percent year-on-year to US $ 1.19 billion, as the second largest export region for the country behind the United States.",
        "“Exports to the EU are also substantial for a number of South Asian markets, including Bangladesh, at 38 percent, Pakistan, 26 percent and Sri Lanka, 24 percent. Any shock to external demand in Sri Lanka is likely to exacerbate the pressure stemming from its already acute shortage of foreign exchange and the supply-chain disruption confronting exporters,” Fitch Ratings cautioned.",
        "In addition, recession fears are also looming in the United Kingdom, which remains Sri Lanka’s second largest single export destination.",
        "Meanwhile, the global rating agency weighed in on prospects of a drop-off in outbound European tourism, if Europe falls into a recession, which could likely to impact Sri Lanka’s struggling",
        "“This could hold back tourism recoveries after the COVID-19 pandemic in markets that have traditionally seen a large share of European arrivals. Europeans have also traditionally formed a large share of arrivals in Asian EMs, including the Maldives and Sri Lanka and accounted for close to 40 percent of arrivals in Thailand in 5M22,” it added.",
        "Apart from the United Kingdom, the European countries such as Germany and France are among top 10 source markets for Sri Lanka tourism.  For the first 10 days of July, the United Kingdom ranked as the largest tourist traffic generator for the country, followed by India and France."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Fitch Ratings",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Russian",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Europe",
            "label": "LOC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Fitch Ratings",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "European",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Europe",
            "label": "LOC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Fitch Ratings",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "this week",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka’s",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Europe",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "non-European",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "north Africa",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Asia",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "EU",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Fitch Ratings",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Wednesday",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Russia",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Europe",
            "label": "LOC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the first five month of the year",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the European Union",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "EU",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "over a quarter of",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka’s",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka’s",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "EU",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the United Kingdom",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "4.84 percent",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "US",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "$ 1.19 billion",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "second",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "the United States",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "EU",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "South Asian",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Bangladesh",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "38 percent",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "Pakistan",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "26 percent",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "24 percent",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Fitch Ratings",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the United Kingdom",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka’s",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "second",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "European",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Europe",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka’s",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "European",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Europeans",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Asian",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "close to 40 percent",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "Thailand",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "5M22",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the United Kingdom",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "European",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Germany",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "France",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "10",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the first 10 days of July",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the United Kingdom",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "India",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "France",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "යුරෝ කලාපයේ ඇති විය හැකි අවපාතය ශ්‍රී ලංකා විදේශ විනිමය දුක්ඛිත තත්වය වඩාත් නරක අතට හැරවීමට ඉඩ ඇත",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "Fitch Ratings පවසන්නේ යුරෝ කලාපීය අවපාතය ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ අපනයන සහ සංචාරක ක්ෂේත්‍රවලට අහිතකර ලෙස බලපෑ හැකි බවයි",
        "යුරෝපයට රුසියානු ගෑස් සැපයුම පහත වැටීම යුරෝ කලාපයේ අවපාතයේ දැඩි හැකියාව පෙන්නුම් කරයි",
        "\"ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ විදේශ ඉල්ලුමට සිදුවන ඕනෑම කම්පනයක් දැනටමත් එහි උග්‍ර විදේශ විනිමය හිඟයෙන් පැන නගින පීඩනය උග්‍ර කිරීමට ඉඩ ඇත\" - ෆිච් ශ්‍රේණිගත කිරීම්",
        "යුරෝපය අවපාතයකට වැටුනහොත් පිටතට යන යුරෝපීය සංචාරක කර්මාන්තය පහත වැටීමේ අපේක්ෂාවන් පුරෝකථනය කරයි",
        "Fitch Ratings මේ සතියේ අනතුරු ඇඟවූයේ යුරෝ කලාපයේ ඇති විය හැකි අවපාතයෙන් ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ අපනයන සහ සංචාරක ක්ෂේත්‍රවලට පහරක් එල්ල විය හැකි බවත් එය රටේ පවතින විදේශ විනිමය හිඟය තවදුරටත් උග්‍ර කළ හැකි බවත්ය.",
        "\"යුරෝපයේ අවපාතයක්, බොහෝ දුරට ඉඩ ඇති අතර, යුරෝපා සංගමයට ඉහළ අපනයන නිරාවරණයක් ඇති උතුරු අප්‍රිකාවේ සහ දකුණු ආසියාවේ කිහිප දෙනෙකු ඇතුළුව අවදානමට ලක්විය හැකි යුරෝපීය නොවන ස්වෛරීවරුන් සඳහා බාහිර වික්‍රියා සහ වර්ධන අභියෝග වැඩි කරනු ඇත\" යනුවෙන් Fitch Ratings බදාදා ප්‍රකාශ කළේය. .",
        "රුසියාවේ සිට යුරෝපයට ගෑස් අපනයන පරිමාවේ මෑත කාලීන තියුනු පහත වැටීම ගෑස් සලාකයේ සම්භාවිතාව ඉහල නංවා ඇති අතර, යුරෝ කලාපයේ තාක්ෂණික අවපාතයක් වැඩි වීමේ හැකියාවක් බවට පත් කර ඇත.",
        "වසරේ පළමු මාස ​​පහ තුළ, ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ වෙළඳ භාණ්ඩ අපනයන ආදායමෙන් හතරෙන් එකකට වඩා වැඩි ප්‍රමාණයක් යුරෝපා සංගමය (EU) සතු විය. එම කාලපරිච්ඡේදය තුළ, ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ යුරෝපා සංගමයට (එක්සත් රාජධානිය හැර) භාණ්ඩ අපනයනය වසරින් වසර සියයට 4.84 කින් එක්සත් ජනපද ඩොලර් බිලියන 1.19 දක්වා වර්ධනය වී ඇති අතර එය එක්සත් ජනපදයට පිටුපසින් රටේ දෙවන විශාලතම අපනයන කලාපය ලෙස වර්ධනය විය.",
        "“යුරෝපා සංගමයට අපනයන ද බංගලිදේශය ඇතුළු දකුණු ආසියාතික වෙලඳපොලවල් ගනනාවක් සඳහා සැලකිය යුතු වේ, සියයට 38, පකිස්ථානය, සියයට 26 සහ ශ්‍රී ලංකාව, සියයට 24. ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ බාහිර ඉල්ලුමට සිදුවන ඕනෑම කම්පනයක් දැනටමත් එහි උග්‍ර විදේශ විනිමය හිඟය සහ අපනයනකරුවන් මුහුණ දෙන සැපයුම් දාම කඩාකප්පල් වීම හේතුවෙන් පැන නගින පීඩනය තවත් උග්‍ර කිරීමට ඉඩ ඇත,” ෆිච් රේටින්ග්ස් අනතුරු ඇඟවීය.",
        "මීට අමතරව, ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ දෙවන විශාලතම තනි අපනයන ගමනාන්තය ලෙස පවතින එක්සත් රාජධානියේ ද අවපාත බිය මතුවෙමින් තිබේ.",
        "මේ අතර, යුරෝපය අවපාතයකට ඇද වැටුණහොත්, ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ අරගලයට බලපෑම් කළ හැකි, පිටතට යන යුරෝපීය සංචාරක ව්‍යාපාරය පහත වැටීමේ අපේක්ෂාවන් පිළිබඳව ගෝලීය ශ්‍රේණිගත කිරීමේ ආයතනය කිරා මැන බලයි.",
        "“මෙය සාම්ප්‍රදායිකව යුරෝපීය පැමිණීම්වල විශාල කොටසක් දැක ඇති වෙළඳපලවල COVID-19 වසංගතයෙන් පසු සංචාරක ප්‍රකෘතිය වළක්වා ගත හැකිය. යුරෝපීයයන් සාම්ප්‍රදායිකව මාලදිවයින සහ ශ්‍රී ලංකාව ඇතුළු ආසියානු ඊඑම් වෙත පැමිණීමෙන් විශාල කොටසක් පිහිටුවා ඇති අතර තායිලන්තයට 5M22 හි පැමිණීමෙන් සියයට 40 කට ආසන්න ප්‍රමාණයක් පැමිණ ඇත.",
        "එක්සත් රාජධානිය හැරුණු විට ජර්මනිය සහ ප්‍රංශය වැනි යුරෝපීය රටවල් ශ්‍රී ලංකා සංචාරක ව්‍යාපාරය සඳහා හොඳම මූලාශ්‍ර 10 අතර වේ. ජූලි මාසයේ පළමු දින 10 සඳහා, එක්සත් රාජධානිය රට සඳහා විශාලතම සංචාරක ගමනාගමන උත්පාදක ලෙස ශ්‍රේණිගත කර ඇති අතර, ඉන්දියාව සහ ප්‍රංශය අනුගමනය කරයි."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ෆිච් ශ්‍රේණිගත කිරීම්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "රුසියානු",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "යුරෝපය",
            "label": "LOC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ෆිච් ශ්‍රේණිගත කිරීම්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "යුරෝපා",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "යුරෝපය",
            "label": "LOC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ෆිච් ශ්‍රේණිගත කිරීම්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "මෙම සතිය",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "යුරෝපය",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "යුරෝපීය නොවන",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "උතුරු අප්රිකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ආසියාව",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "EU",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ෆිච් ශ්‍රේණිගත කිරීම්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "බදාදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "රුසියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "යුරෝපය",
            "label": "LOC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "වසරේ මුල් මාස පහ",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "යුරෝපා සංගමය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "EU",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "හතරෙන් පංගුවකට වඩා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "EU",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "එක්සත් රාජධානිය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "සියයට 4.84 කි",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "එක්සත් ජනපදය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඩොලර් බිලියන 1.19 කි",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "දෙවැනි",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "එක්සත් ජනපදය",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "EU",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "දකුණු ආසියානු",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "බංග්ලාදේශය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "සියයට 38 කි",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "පකිස්ථානය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "සියයට 26 කි",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "සියයට 24 කි",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ෆිච් ශ්‍රේණිගත කිරීම්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "එක්සත් රාජධානිය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "දෙවැනි",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "යුරෝපා",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "යුරෝපය",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "යුරෝපා",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "යුරෝපීයයන්",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ආසියානු",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "සියයට 40කට ආසන්නයි",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "තායිලන්තය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "5M22",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "එක්සත් රාජධානිය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "යුරෝපා",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජර්මනිය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ප්රංශය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "10",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජූලි පළමු දින 10",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "එක්සත් රාජධානිය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ප්රංශය",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "யூரோப்பகுதியில் சாத்தியமான மந்தநிலை SL இன் அந்நிய செலாவணி துயரங்களை மோசமாக்கும்",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "யூரோப் பகுதியின் மந்தநிலை இலங்கையின் ஏற்றுமதி மற்றும் சுற்றுலாத் துறைகளை எதிர்மறையாகப் பாதிக்கும் என Fitch Ratings கூறுகிறது.",
        "ஐரோப்பாவிற்கான ரஷ்ய எரிவாயு விநியோகத்தில் வீழ்ச்சி யூரோப்பகுதியில் மந்தநிலையின் வலுவான சாத்தியத்தை குறிக்கிறது",
        "\"இலங்கையில் வெளித் தேவைக்கு ஏதேனும் அதிர்ச்சி ஏற்பட்டால் அது ஏற்கனவே கடுமையான அந்நியச் செலாவணி பற்றாக்குறையால் உருவாகும் அழுத்தத்தை அதிகரிக்கக்கூடும்\"- ஃபிட்ச் மதிப்பீடுகள்",
        "ஐரோப்பா மந்தநிலையில் விழுந்தால், வெளிச்செல்லும் ஐரோப்பிய சுற்றுலாவில் வீழ்ச்சி ஏற்படும் வாய்ப்புகளை முன்னறிவிக்கிறது",
        "யூரோ வலயத்தில் ஏற்படக்கூடிய மந்தநிலையால் இலங்கையின் ஏற்றுமதி மற்றும் சுற்றுலாத் துறைகள் பாதிப்படைய வாய்ப்புள்ளதாகவும் அது நாட்டின் அந்நியச் செலாவணி பற்றாக்குறையை மேலும் அதிகரிக்கச் செய்யும் எனவும் Fitch Ratings இந்த வாரம் எச்சரித்துள்ளது.",
        "\"ஐரோப்பாவில் ஏற்படும் மந்தநிலை, ஐரோப்பிய ஒன்றியத்திற்கு அதிக ஏற்றுமதியை வெளிப்படுத்தும் வட ஆபிரிக்கா மற்றும் தெற்காசியாவில் உள்ள பல பாதிப்புக்குள்ளான ஐரோப்பிய அல்லாத இறையாண்மைகளுக்கு வெளிப்புற விகாரங்கள் மற்றும் வளர்ச்சி சவால்களை அதிகரிக்கும்\" என்று Fitch Ratings புதன்கிழமை கூறியது. .",
        "ரஷ்யாவில் இருந்து ஐரோப்பாவிற்கு எரிவாயு ஏற்றுமதி அளவின் சமீபத்திய கூர்மையான சரிவு எரிவாயு விநியோகத்தின் சாத்தியக்கூறுகளை உயர்த்தியுள்ளது, இது யூரோப்பகுதியில் தொழில்நுட்ப மந்தநிலையை அதிகரிக்கும் சாத்தியத்தை உருவாக்குகிறது.",
        "ஆண்டின் முதல் ஐந்து மாதங்களில், ஐரோப்பிய ஒன்றியம் (EU) இலங்கையின் சரக்கு ஏற்றுமதி வருவாயில் நான்கில் ஒரு பங்கைக் கொண்டிருந்தது. இக்காலப்பகுதியில், ஐரோப்பிய ஒன்றியத்திற்கான இலங்கையின் சரக்கு ஏற்றுமதிகள் (யுனைடெட் கிங்டம் தவிர்த்து) ஆண்டுக்கு ஆண்டு 4.84 வீதத்தால் 1.19 பில்லியன் அமெரிக்க டொலர்களாக அதிகரித்து, அமெரிக்காவிற்குப் பின்னால் நாட்டிற்கான இரண்டாவது பெரிய ஏற்றுமதி பிராந்தியமாக உள்ளது.",
        "\"ஐரோப்பிய ஒன்றியத்திற்கான ஏற்றுமதிகள் பல தெற்காசிய சந்தைகளுக்கு கணிசமானவை, வங்காளதேசம் உட்பட 38 சதவீதம், பாகிஸ்தான் 26 சதவீதம் மற்றும் இலங்கை 24 சதவீதம். இலங்கையில் வெளித் தேவைக்கு ஏற்படும் எந்த அதிர்ச்சியும், ஏற்கனவே கடுமையான அந்நியச் செலாவணி பற்றாக்குறை மற்றும் ஏற்றுமதியாளர்களை எதிர்கொள்ளும் விநியோகச் சங்கிலி சீர்குலைவு ஆகியவற்றிலிருந்து உருவாகும் அழுத்தத்தை அதிகப்படுத்தலாம்,” என்று Fitch Ratings எச்சரித்துள்ளது.",
        "கூடுதலாக, இலங்கையின் இரண்டாவது பெரிய ஒற்றை ஏற்றுமதி இடமாக இருக்கும் ஐக்கிய இராச்சியத்திலும் மந்தநிலை அச்சம் நிலவுகிறது.",
        "இதற்கிடையில், ஐரோப்பா மந்தநிலையில் விழுந்தால், இலங்கையின் போராட்டத்தை பாதிக்கக்கூடிய, வெளிச்செல்லும் ஐரோப்பிய சுற்றுலாவில் வீழ்ச்சி ஏற்படும் வாய்ப்புகள் குறித்து உலகளாவிய தரமதிப்பீட்டு நிறுவனம் எடைபோட்டுள்ளது.",
        "\"இது பாரம்பரியமாக ஐரோப்பிய வருகையின் பெரும் பங்கைக் கண்ட சந்தைகளில் COVID-19 தொற்றுநோய்க்குப் பிறகு சுற்றுலா மீட்புகளைத் தடுக்கலாம். ஐரோப்பியர்கள் பாரம்பரியமாக மாலத்தீவுகள் மற்றும் இலங்கை உட்பட ஆசிய EM களில் பெரும் பங்கை உருவாக்கியுள்ளனர் மற்றும் 5M22 இல் தாய்லாந்திற்கு வந்தவர்களில் 40 சதவீதத்திற்கு அருகில் உள்ளனர், ”என்று அது மேலும் கூறியது.",
        "ஐக்கிய இராச்சியம் தவிர, ஜேர்மனி மற்றும் பிரான்ஸ் போன்ற ஐரோப்பிய நாடுகளும் இலங்கை சுற்றுலாத்துறைக்கான சிறந்த 10 மூலச் சந்தைகளில் உள்ளன. ஜூலை மாதத்தின் முதல் 10 நாட்களுக்கு, ஐக்கிய இராச்சியம் நாட்டிற்கான மிகப்பெரிய சுற்றுலாப் போக்குவரத்து ஜெனரேட்டராக தரவரிசையில் உள்ளது, அதைத் தொடர்ந்து இந்தியா மற்றும் பிரான்ஸ் உள்ளன."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ஃபிட்ச் மதிப்பீடுகள்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ரஷ்யன்",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஐரோப்பா",
            "label": "LOC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஃபிட்ச் மதிப்பீடுகள்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஐரோப்பிய",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஐரோப்பா",
            "label": "LOC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஃபிட்ச் மதிப்பீடுகள்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்த வாரம்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கையின்",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஐரோப்பா",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஐரோப்பியர் அல்லாதவர்",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "வட ஆப்பிரிக்கா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆசியா",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "EU",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஃபிட்ச் மதிப்பீடுகள்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "புதன்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ரஷ்யா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஐரோப்பா",
            "label": "LOC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஆண்டின் முதல் ஐந்து மாதங்கள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஐரோப்பிய ஒன்றியம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "EU",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "கால் பகுதிக்கு மேல்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கையின்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கையின்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "EU",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஐக்கிய இராச்சியம்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "4.84 சதவீதம்",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "எங்களுக்கு",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "$ 1.19 பில்லியன்",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "இரண்டாவது",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஐக்கிய நாடுகள்",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "EU",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "தெற்காசிய",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "பங்களாதேஷ்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "38 சதவீதம்",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாகிஸ்தான்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "26 சதவீதம்",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "24 சதவீதம்",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஃபிட்ச் மதிப்பீடுகள்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஐக்கிய இராச்சியம்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கையின்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இரண்டாவது",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஐரோப்பிய",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஐரோப்பா",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கையின்",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஐரோப்பிய",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஐரோப்பியர்கள்",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆசிய",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "40 சதவீதத்திற்கு அருகில்",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "தாய்லாந்து",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "5M22",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஐக்கிய இராச்சியம்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஐரோப்பிய",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜெர்மனி",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "பிரான்ஸ்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "10",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜூலை முதல் 10 நாட்கள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஐக்கிய இராச்சியம்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்தியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "பிரான்ஸ்",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}