{
  "newspaper_id": "daily-mirror-lk",
  "url": "https://www.dailymirror.lk/latest_news/Services-at-Registrar-Generals-Dept-during-next-10-days-announced/342-239971",
  "time_ut": 1656429833,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Services at Registrar General’s Dept. during next 10 days announced",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Services at Registrar General’s Dept. during next 10 days announced",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "The Registrar General's Department has decided to limit the services provided by the District offices to two days a week within the next 10 days.",
        "While issuing a notice, Registrar General P.S.P. Abeywardane said the issuing of birth, marriage and death certificates by District Secretariats will only take place on Monday and Wednesday from 8.30 am to 4.00 pm.",
        "However, the Registrar General's department at the Suhurupaya, Battaramulla and branch offices in Kurunegala, Kandy and the branch office at the Immigration and Emmigration department in Matara will provide their services for five days of the week as usual.",
        "All services provided by the Land Registrar offices will be on Mondays and Wednesdays from 8.30 am to 4.00 pm.",
        "There is a possibility of amending these days following the policy decisions taken by the government in the future. (Chaturanga Samarawickrama)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "next 10 days",
          "label": "DATE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "The Registrar General's",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "two days",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the next 10 days",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Abeywardane",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "District Secretariats",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Monday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Wednesday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "8.30 am to",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the Registrar General's",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Suhurupaya",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kurunegala",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kandy",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Immigration and Emmigration department",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Matara",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "five days of the week",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Land Registrar",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Mondays",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Wednesdays",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "8.30 am to",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "these days",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Chaturanga Samarawickrama",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "ඉදිරි දින 10 තුළ රෙජිස්ට්‍රාර් ජනරාල් දෙපාර්තමේන්තුවේ සේවාවන් නිවේදනය කෙරේ",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "ඉදිරි දින 10 තුළ දිස්ත්‍රික් කාර්යාල මඟින් සපයනු ලබන සේවාවන් සතියකට දින දෙකකට සීමා කිරීමට රෙජිස්ට්‍රාර් ජනරාල් දෙපාර්තමේන්තුව තීරණය කර තිබේ.",
        "නිවේදනයක් නිකුත් කරමින් රෙජිස්ට්‍රාර් ජනරාල් පී.එස්.පී. අබේවර්ධන මහතා පැවසුවේ දිස්ත්‍රික් ලේකම් කාර්යාල මගින් උප්පැන්න, විවාහ සහ මරණ සහතික නිකුත් කිරීම සඳුදා සහ බදාදා පෙරවරු 8.30 සිට පස්වරු 4.00 දක්වා පමණක් සිදුවන බවයි.",
        "කෙසේ වෙතත්, බත්තරමුල්ල, සුහුරුපායේ රෙජිස්ට්‍රාර් ජනරාල් දෙපාර්තමේන්තුව සහ කුරුණෑගල, මහනුවර ශාඛා කාර්යාල සහ මාතර ආගමන හා විගමන දෙපාර්තමේන්තුවේ ශාඛා කාර්යාලය සුපුරුදු පරිදි සතියේ දින පහේම සිය සේවාවන් සපයනු ලැබේ.",
        "ඉඩම් රෙජිස්ට්‍රාර් කාර්යාල මගින් සපයනු ලබන සියලුම සේවාවන් සඳුදා සහ බදාදා දිනවල පෙරවරු 8.30 සිට පස්වරු 4.00 දක්වා සිදු කෙරේ.",
        "ඉදිරියේදී රජය ගන්නා ප්‍රතිපත්තිමය තීරණ අනුව මේ දිනවල සංශෝධන සිදුකිරීමට හැකියාව තිබෙනවා. (චතුරංග සමරවික්‍රම)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ඉදිරි දින 10",
          "label": "DATE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "රෙජිස්ට්රාර් ජනරාල්ගේ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "දින දෙකක්",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉදිරි දින 10",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "අබේවර්ධන ය",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "දිස්ත්‍රික් ලේකම් කාර්යාල",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "සඳුදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "බදාදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "8.30 දක්වා",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "රෙජිස්ට්රාර් ජනරාල්ගේ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "සුහුරුපාය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "කුරුණෑගල",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මහනුවර",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ආගමන හා විගමන දෙපාර්තමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "මාතර",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "සතියේ දින පහක්",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ඉඩම් රෙජිස්ට්රාර්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "සඳුදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "බදාදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "8.30 දක්වා",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "මෙම දිනවල",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "චතුරංග සමරවික්‍රම",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "அடுத்த 10 நாட்களில் பதிவாளர் ஜெனரல் பிரிவில் சேவைகள் அறிவிக்கப்பட்டுள்ளன",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "எதிர்வரும் 10 நாட்களுக்குள் மாவட்ட அலுவலகங்களினால் வழங்கப்படும் சேவைகளை வாரத்தில் இரண்டு நாட்களுக்கு மட்டுப்படுத்த பதிவாளர் நாயகம் திணைக்களம் தீர்மானித்துள்ளது.",
        "அறிவிப்பை வெளியிடும் போது, ​​பதிவாளர் ஜெனரல் பி.எஸ்.பி. மாவட்ட செயலகங்களினால் பிறப்பு, திருமணம் மற்றும் இறப்பு சான்றிதழ் வழங்கும் பணி திங்கள் மற்றும் புதன் கிழமைகளில் காலை 8.30 மணி முதல் மாலை 4.00 மணி வரை மட்டுமே நடைபெறும் என அபேவர்தன தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "எவ்வாறாயினும், சுஹுருபாய, பத்தரமுல்லை ஆகியவற்றில் உள்ள பதிவாளர் நாயகம் திணைக்களம் மற்றும் குருநாகல், கண்டி ஆகிய கிளை அலுவலகங்களும், மாத்தறையில் உள்ள குடிவரவு குடியகல்வு திணைக்களத்தின் கிளை அலுவலகமும் வாரத்தின் ஐந்து நாட்களுக்கு வழமை போன்று தமது சேவைகளை வழங்கும்.",
        "நிலப் பதிவாளர் அலுவலகங்களால் வழங்கப்படும் அனைத்து சேவைகளும் திங்கள் மற்றும் புதன்கிழமைகளில் காலை 8.30 மணி முதல் மாலை 4.00 மணி வரை இருக்கும்.",
        "எதிர்காலத்தில் அரசாங்கம் எடுக்கும் கொள்கை முடிவுகளைத் தொடர்ந்து இந்த நாட்களில் திருத்தங்கள் மேற்கொள்ளப்பட வாய்ப்புகள் உள்ளன. (சதுரங்க சமரவிக்ரம)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "அடுத்த 10 நாட்கள்",
          "label": "DATE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "பதிவாளர் ஜெனரல்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இரண்டு நாட்கள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "அடுத்த 10 நாட்கள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "அபேவர்தன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "மாவட்ட செயலகங்கள்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "திங்கட்கிழமை",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "புதன்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "காலை 8.30 முதல்",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பதிவாளர் ஜெனரல்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஸுஹுருபாய",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "குருநாகல்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "கண்டி",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "குடிவரவு மற்றும் குடியகல்வு துறை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "மாத்தறை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "வாரத்தில் ஐந்து நாட்கள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "நிலப் பதிவாளர்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "திங்கட்கிழமைகள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "புதன்கிழமைகள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "காலை 8.30 முதல்",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இந்த நாட்களில்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சதுரங்க சமரவிக்ரம",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}