{
  "newspaper_id": "daily-ft-lk",
  "url": "https://www.ft.lk/news/Saman-Ekanayake-appointed-Secretary-to-President/56-737767",
  "time_ut": 1658444810,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Saman Ekanayake appointed Secretary to President",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Saman Ekanayake appointed Secretary to President",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "New President Ranil Wickremesinghe has appointed Saman Ekanayake as the new Secretary to the President.",
        "Ekanayake previously served as the Secretary to the Prime Minister when Ranil Wickremesinghe was serving as the Premier from May until the resignation of the President Gotabaya Rajapaksa. Earlier Ekanayake has been the Secretary to the Prime Minister Ranil Wickremesinghe three times during the period 2015-2019 and has been appointed to the post for the fourth time. Ekanayake is a Special Grade Retired Officer in the Sri Lanka Administrative Service."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Saman Ekanayake",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Saman Ekanayake",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "May",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Gotabaya Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "three",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "the period 2015-2019",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "fourth",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Sri Lanka Administrative Service",
            "label": "LOC"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "සමන් ඒකනායක ජනාධිපති ලේකම්",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "නව ජනාධිපති රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතා විසින් නව ජනාධිපති ලේකම්වරයා ලෙස සමන් ඒකනායක මහතා පත් කර තිබේ.",
        "ඒකනායක මහතා මීට පෙර අග්‍රාමාත්‍ය ලේකම්වරයා ලෙස කටයුතු කළේ රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතා මැයි මාසයේ සිට ජනාධිපති ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ මහතා ඉල්ලා අස්වන තෙක් අග්‍රාමාත්‍යවරයා ලෙස කටයුතු කරන විටය. ඒකනායක මහතා මීට පෙර 2015-2019 කාලසීමාව තුළ තුන් වතාවක් අග්‍රාමාත්‍ය රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතාගේ ලේකම්වරයා ලෙස කටයුතු කර ඇති අතර සිව්වැනි වරටත් එම ධූරයට පත්වී ඇත. ඒකනායක ශ්‍රී ලංකා පරිපාලන සේවයේ විශේෂ ශ්‍රේණියේ විශ්‍රාමික නිලධාරියෙකි."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "සමන් ඒකනායක",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "සමන් ඒකනායක",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "මැයි",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "තුන්",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "2015-2019 කාලය",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "හතරවන",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකා පරිපාලන සේවය",
            "label": "LOC"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "சமன் ஏக்கநாயக்க ஜனாதிபதியின் செயலாளராக நியமிக்கப்பட்டுள்ளார்",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "புதிய ஜனாதிபதி ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க, ஜனாதிபதியின் புதிய செயலாளராக சமன் ஏக்கநாயக்கவை நியமித்துள்ளார்.",
        "ஏக்கநாயக்க இதற்கு முன்னர் ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க பிரதமராக இருந்த போது மே மாதம் முதல் ஜனாதிபதி கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ஷ பதவி விலகும் வரை பிரதமரின் செயலாளராக பணியாற்றினார். இதற்கு முன்னர் 2015-2019 காலப்பகுதியில் மூன்று தடவைகள் பிரதமர் ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்கவின் செயலாளராக இருந்த ஏக்கநாயக்க நான்காவது தடவையாக அப்பதவிக்கு நியமிக்கப்பட்டுள்ளார். ஏகநாயக்க இலங்கை நிர்வாக சேவையில் விசேட தர ஓய்வு பெற்ற அதிகாரியாவார்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "சமன் ஏகநாயக்க",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "சமன் ஏகநாயக்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "மே",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "மூன்று",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "காலம் 2015-2019",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "நான்காவது",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை நிர்வாக சேவை",
            "label": "LOC"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}