{
  "newspaper_id": "news-first-lk",
  "url": "https://www.newsfirst.lk/2022/07/19/health-sector-facing-risk-of-collapse/",
  "time_ut": 1658211960,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Health Sector facing risk of collapse",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Health Sector facing risk of collapse",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); The Government Medical Officers Association (GMOA) says that there is a risk of Sri Lanka’s health sector collapsing.",
        "Dr. Chamil Wijesinghe, the spokesperson for the GMOA said that health workers are facing serious issues in accessing transport to report to work due to the shortage of fuel.",
        "The Secretary of the Ministry of Health Janaka Sri Chandragupta says that steps have been taken to discuss this matter with the Ministry of Power and Energy.",
        "The secretary further said that at present only essential services are being carried out in the hospitals.",
        "Dullas, Ranil, Anura to contest for President; Vote on Wednesday (20)",
        "Nomination Day today (19) : Process of electing President by Parliament"
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "News 1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "The Government Medical Officers Association",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Chamil Wijesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the Ministry of Health Janaka Sri Chandragupta",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Ministry of Power and Energy",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "Dullas, Ranil,",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Anura",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Wednesday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "20",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Nomination Day",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "19",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "සෞඛ්‍ය අංශය කඩාවැටීමේ අවදානමකට මුහුණ දී සිටී",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ සෞඛ්‍ය ක්ෂේත්‍රය කඩාවැටීමේ අවදානමක් මතුව ඇතැයි රජයේ වෛද්‍ය නිලධාරීන්ගේ සංගමය (GMOA) පවසයි.",
        "රජයේ වෛද්‍ය නිලධාරීන්ගේ සංගමයේ ප්‍රකාශක වෛද්‍ය චමිල් විජේසිංහ කියා සිටියේ ඉන්ධන හිඟය හේතුවෙන් සෞඛ්‍ය සේවකයින් සේවයට වාර්තා කිරීම සඳහා ප්‍රවාහන පහසුකම් ලබාගැනීමේදී බරපතල ගැටළුවලට මුහුණ පා ඇති බවයි.",
        "සෞඛ්‍ය අමාත්‍යාංශයේ ලේකම් ජානක ශ්‍රී චන්ද්‍රගුප්ත මහතා පවසන්නේ මේ සම්බන්ධයෙන් විදුලිබල හා බලශක්ති අමාත්‍යාංශය සමඟ සාකච්ඡා කිරීමට පියවර ගෙන ඇති බවයි.",
        "මේ වන විට රෝහල්වල අත්‍යාවශ්‍ය සේවා පමණක් සිදු කෙරෙන බව ලේකම්වරයා වැඩිදුරටත් පැවසීය.",
        "ඩලස්,රනිල්,අනුර ජනපතිට තරග කරයි; බදාදා (20) ඡන්දය",
        "නාමයෝජනා දිනය අද (19) : පාර්ලිමේන්තුව විසින් ජනාධිපතිවරයා තෝරා පත් කර ගැනීමේ ක්‍රියාවලිය"
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "News 1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "රජයේ වෛද්‍ය නිලධාරීන්ගේ සංගමය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "චමිල් විජේසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "සෞඛ්‍ය අමාත්‍යාංශය ජානක ශ්‍රී චන්ද්‍රගුප්ත",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "විදුලිබල හා බලශක්ති අමාත්යාංශය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "ඩලස්, රනිල්,",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "අනුර",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "බදාදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "20",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "නාමයෝජනා දිනය",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "19",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "சுகாதாரத் துறை வீழ்ச்சியடையும் அபாயத்தில் உள்ளது",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); இலங்கையின் சுகாதாரத் துறை வீழ்ச்சியடையும் அபாயம் இருப்பதாக அரசாங்க மருத்துவ அதிகாரிகள் சங்கம் (GMOA) தெரிவித்துள்ளது.",
        "எரிபொருள் தட்டுப்பாடு காரணமாக சுகாதார ஊழியர்கள் வேலைக்குச் செல்வதற்கான போக்குவரத்தை அணுகுவதில் பாரிய பிரச்சினைகளை எதிர்கொள்வதாக GMOAவின் பேச்சாளர் டொக்டர் சமில் விஜேசிங்க தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "இது தொடர்பில் மின்சாரம் மற்றும் எரிசக்தி அமைச்சுடன் கலந்துரையாட நடவடிக்கை எடுக்கப்பட்டுள்ளதாக சுகாதார அமைச்சின் செயலாளர் ஜனக ஸ்ரீ சந்திரகுப்த தெரிவித்துள்ளார்.",
        "தற்போது வைத்தியசாலைகளில் அத்தியாவசிய சேவைகள் மாத்திரமே முன்னெடுக்கப்படுவதாக செயலாளர் மேலும் தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "ஜனாதிபதி தேர்தலில் டலஸ், ரணில், அனுர; புதன்கிழமை (20) வாக்களிப்பு",
        "நியமன தினம் இன்று (19) : ஜனாதிபதியை பாராளுமன்றம் தெரிவு செய்யும் நடைமுறை"
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "News 1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "அரச வைத்திய அதிகாரிகள் சங்கம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "சமில் விஜேசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "சுகாதார அமைச்சு ஜனக ஸ்ரீ சந்திரகுப்தா",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "மின்சாரம் மற்றும் எரிசக்தி அமைச்சகம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "டலஸ், ரணில்,",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "அனுர",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "புதன்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "20",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "நியமன நாள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "19",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}