{
  "newspaper_id": "lankadeepa-lk",
  "url": "https://www.lankadeepa.lk/news/කඳුකර-කොටියා-ගැන-වාර්තාව-ඇමැතිට/101-618716",
  "time_ut": 1661404307,
  "original_lang": "si",
  "original_title": "කඳුකර කොටියා ගැන වාර්තාව ඇමැතිට",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "The report about the mountain tiger to the minister",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "The final report of the three-member committee appointed to investigate the death of the mountain tiger that died on August 7 due to being caught in a trap at Summerhill Estate has been handed over to the Minister of Agriculture, Wildlife and Forest Resources Conservation Mr. Mahinda Amaraweera.",
        "This report was handed over to the minister by the secretary of the ministry, Mrs. Chandra Herath, and the additional secretary H. D. Ratnayake, Taraka Prasad Director (Health Management), Director Operations (National Zoo Department) H. that. Mr. Anoma Priyadarshini participated in this event.",
        "The committee that investigated the death of the mountain tiger has made 25 recommendations regarding the protection of the mountain tiger population in this report.",
        "Also, in this Summerhill incident, the investigation revealed that the tiger had died due to the damage to its internal organs due to being caught in a trap made of wire and hanging from a tall tree for hours, and that the animal had not fallen under the tree."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "three",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "August 7",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Summerhill Estate",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Forest Resources Conservation",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Mahinda Amaraweera",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Chandra Herath",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "H. D. Ratnayake",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Taraka Prasad",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "National Zoo Department",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Anoma Priyadarshini",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "25",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Summerhill",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "hours",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "කඳුකර කොටියා ගැන වාර්තාව ඇමැතිට",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "සමර්හිල් වතුයායේ දී මද්දකට හසුවීම නිසා අගෝස්තු 07 වැනිදා  මරණයට පත් වූ කඳුකර කොටියාගේ මරණය සම්බන්ධයෙන්  සොයන්නට  පත් කළ ත්‍රිපුද්ගල කමිටුවේ අවසන් වාර්තාව කෘෂිකර්ම, වනජීවී හා වනසම්පත් සංරක්ෂණ අමාත්‍ය මහින්ද අමරවීර මහතාට බාර දී තිබේ.",
        "මෙම වාර්තාව අමාත්‍යාංශයේ ලේකම් චන්ද්‍රා හේරත් මහත්මිය විසින් ඇමැතිවරයාට බාරදුන් අතර එම අවස්ථාවට සිද්ධිය සම්බන්ධව විමර්ශනය සඳහා පත් කළ කමිටූවට අයත් අතිරේක ලේකම් එච්. ඩී. රත්නායක, තාරක ප්‍රසාද් අධ්‍යක්ෂ (සෞඛ්‍ය කළමනාකරණ), අධ්‍යක්ෂ මෙහෙයුම් ( ජාතික සත්වෝද්‍යාන දෙපාර්තමේන්තුව) එච්. ඒ. අනෝමා ප්‍රියදර්ශනී මහත්ම මහත්මීහු මෙම අවස්ථාවට සහභාගී වූහ.",
        "කඳුකර කොටියාගේ මරණය සම්බන්ධව විමර්ශනය කළ කමිටුව විසින් කඳුකර කොටිගහණය ආරක්ෂා කර ගැනීම සම්බන්ධව නිර්දේශ 25ක් මෙම වාර්තාව මගින් ඉදිරිපත් කර තිබේ.",
        "එසේම මෙම සමර්හිල් සිදුවීමේ දී එකී කොටියා කම්බියකින් සැකසූ මද්දට හසුවී උස ගසක පහතට පැය ගණනක් තිස්සේ එල්ලී සිටීම නිසා සිරුර අභ්‍යන්තරයේ ඉන්ද්‍රියයන්ට සිදුවූ හානිය නිසා මරණයට පත් ව ඇති බවත්, එම සතා ගසට යටවී නොමැති බවත් සිදු කළ විමර්ශනවල දී අනාවරණය වූ බව කමිටුව සඳහන් කරයි."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "තුන්",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "අගෝස්තු 7",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "සමර්හිල් වතුයාය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "වන සම්පත් සංරක්ෂණය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "මහින්ද අමරවීර",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "චන්ද්‍රා හේරත්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "එච්.ඩී රත්නායක",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "තාරකා ප්‍රසාද්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජාතික සත්වෝද්යාන දෙපාර්තමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "අනෝමා ප්‍රියදර්ශනී",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "25",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ගිම්හාන හිල්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "පැය",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "அமைச்சருக்கு மலைப்புலி பற்றிய அறிக்கை",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "சம்மர்ஹில் தோட்டத்தில் பொறியில் சிக்கி உயிரிழந்த மலைப்புலியின் மரணம் தொடர்பாக விசாரணை நடத்த நியமிக்கப்பட்ட மூவரடங்கிய குழுவின் இறுதி அறிக்கை விவசாயம், வனவிலங்கு மற்றும் வன வளங்கள் பாதுகாப்பு அமைச்சர் திரு. மஹிந்த அமரவீர.",
        "இந்த அறிக்கையை அமைச்சின் செயலாளர் திருமதி சந்திரா ஹேரத் மற்றும் மேலதிக செயலாளர் எச். டி. ரத்நாயக்க, தாரக பிரசாத் பணிப்பாளர் (சுகாதார முகாமைத்துவம்), பணிப்பாளர் செயற்பாடுகள் (தேசிய மிருகக்காட்சிசாலை திணைக்களம்) எச். அந்த. இந்நிகழ்வில் திரு.அனோமா பிரியதர்ஷினி கலந்து கொண்டார்.",
        "மலைப்புலியின் மரணம் குறித்து விசாரணை நடத்திய குழு, இந்த அறிக்கையில் மலைப்புலிகளின் பாதுகாப்பு தொடர்பாக 25 பரிந்துரைகளை முன்வைத்துள்ளது.",
        "மேலும், இந்த சம்மர்ஹில் சம்பவத்தில், கம்பியால் செய்யப்பட்ட வலையில் சிக்கி, உயரமான மரத்தில் மணிக்கணக்கில் தொங்கியதால், உள் உறுப்புகள் பாதிக்கப்பட்டு புலி இறந்துள்ளதும், விலங்கு கீழே விழவில்லை என்பதும் விசாரணையில் தெரியவந்தது. மரம்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "மூன்று",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆகஸ்ட் 7",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சம்மர்ஹில் எஸ்டேட்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "வன வளங்கள் பாதுகாப்பு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "மஹிந்த அமரவீர",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "சந்திர ஹேரத்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "எச்.டி. ரத்நாயக்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "தாரக பிரசாத்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "தேசிய உயிரியல் பூங்கா துறை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "அனோமா பிரியதர்ஷினி",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "25",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "சம்மர்ஹில்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "மணி",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}