{
  "newspaper_id": "ada-derana-lk",
  "url": "http://www.adaderana.lk/news/83569/showers-expected-in-parts-of-the-country",
  "time_ut": 1657505940,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Showers expected in parts of the country",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Showers expected in parts of the country",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "The Department of Meteorology says several spells of showers will occur in Sabaragamuwa Province and in Nuwara-Eliya and Kandy districts.",
        "A few showers may occur in Western province and in Galle and Matara districts.",
        "Strong winds about 40-50 kmph can be expected at times in the western slopes of the Central hills and in Western, Southern and Sabaragamuwa provinces.",
        "A few showers may occur in the sea areas off the coast extending from Colombo to Mataravia Galle.",
        "Winds will be Westerly to South-westerly and wind speed will be 30-40 kmph. Wind speed can increase up to 50-55 kmph in the sea areas off the coast extending from Negombo to Kankasanturai via Puttalam and Mannar and in the sea areas off the coast extending fromGalle to Pottuvil via Matara and Hambantota.",
        "The sea areas off the coast extending from Negombo to Kankasanturai via Puttalam and Mannar and in the sea areas off the coast extending fromGalle to Pottuvil via Matara and Hambantota will be rough at times."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "The Department of Meteorology",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sabaragamuwa Province",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Nuwara-Eliya",
            "label": "PRODUCT"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kandy",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Galle",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Matara",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "about 40-50",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Southern",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sabaragamuwa",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Mataravia Galle",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "South",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "30-40 kmph",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "Negombo",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Mannar",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Matara",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Hambantota",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Negombo",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Mannar",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Matara",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Hambantota",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "දිවයිනේ සමහර ප්‍රදේශවලට වැසි අපේක්ෂා කෙරේ",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "සබරගමුව පළාතේත් නුවරඑළිය සහ මහනුවර දිස්ත්‍රික්කවලත් වැසි වාර කිහිපයක් ඇති විය හැකි බව කාලගුණ විද්‍යා දෙපාර්තමේන්තුව පවසයි.",
        "බස්නාහිර පළාතේ සහ ගාල්ල සහ මාතර දිස්ත්‍රික්කවල වැසි ස්වල්පයක් ඇති විය හැක.",
        "මධ්‍යම කඳුකරයේ බටහිර බෑවුම් ප්‍රදේශවලත් බස්නාහිර, දකුණ සහ සබරගමුව පළාත්වලත් විටින් විට හමන පැ.කි.මී.40-50 පමණ තද සුළං බලාපොරොත්තු විය හැක.",
        "කොළඹ සිට මාතරවිය ගාල්ල දක්වා වෙරළට ඔබ්බෙන් වන මුහුදු ප්‍රදේශවල වැසි ස්වල්පයක් ඇති විය හැක.",
        "සුළං බස්නාහිර සිට නිරිත දෙසින් හමන අතර සුළගේ වේගය පැ.කි.මී.30-40 පමණ වේ. මීගමුව සිට පුත්තලම සහ මන්නාරම හරහා කන්කසන්තුරය දක්වා වෙරළට ඔබ්බෙන් වන මුහුදු ප්‍රදේශවල සහ ගාල්ල සිට මාතර සහ හම්බන්තොට හරහා පොතුවිල් දක්වා වෙරළට ඔබ්බෙන් වන මුහුදු ප්‍රදේශවල සුළගේ වේගය පැ.කි.මී.50-55 දක්වා වැඩි විය හැක.",
        "මීගමුව සිට පුත්තලම සහ මන්නාරම හරහා කන්කසන්තුරය දක්වා වෙරළට ඔබ්බෙන් වන මුහුදු ප්‍රදේශ සහ ගාල්ල සිට මාතර සහ හම්බන්තොට හරහා පොතුවිල් දක්වා වෙරළට ඔබ්බෙන් වන මුහුදු ප්‍රදේශ විටින් විට රළු වේ."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "කාලගුණ විද්‍යා දෙපාර්තමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "සබරගමුව පළාත",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "නුවරඑළිය",
            "label": "PRODUCT"
          },
          {
            "text": "මහනුවර",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ගාල්ල",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මාතර",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "40-50 පමණ වේ",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "දකුණු",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "සබරගමුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "මාතරවිය ගාල්ල",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "දකුණු",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "30-40 kmph",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "මීගමුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "මන්නාරම",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "මාතර",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "හම්බන්තොට",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "මීගමුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "මන්නාරම",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "මාතර",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "හම්බන්තොට",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "நாட்டின் சில பகுதிகளில் மழை எதிர்பார்க்கப்படுகிறது",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "சப்ரகமுவ மாகாணத்திலும் நுவரெலியா மற்றும் கண்டி மாவட்டங்களிலும் பல தடவைகள் மழை பெய்யும் என வளிமண்டலவியல் திணைக்களம் தெரிவித்துள்ளது.",
        "மேல் மாகாணத்திலும் காலி மற்றும் மாத்தறை மாவட்டங்களிலும் சிறிதளவு மழை பெய்யக்கூடும்.",
        "மத்திய மலைநாட்டின் மேற்கு சரிவுகளிலும் மேற்கு, தெற்கு மற்றும் சப்ரகமுவ மாகாணங்களிலும் அவ்வப்போது மணித்தியாலத்துக்கு 40-50 கிலோமீற்றர் வேகத்தில் பலத்த காற்று வீசக்கூடும்.",
        "கொழும்பில் இருந்து மாதராவியா காலி வரையான கடற்கரைக்கு அப்பாற்பட்ட கடற்பரப்புகளில் சிறிதளவு மழை பெய்யக்கூடும்.",
        "காற்றானது மேற்கு முதல் தென்மேற்கு திசையில் வீசும் மற்றும் காற்றின் வேகம் மணிக்கு 30-40 கி.மீ. நீர்கொழும்பிலிருந்து புத்தளம் மற்றும் மன்னார் ஊடாக காங்கேசன்துறை வரையான கடற்பரப்புகளிலும் காலியிலிருந்து மாத்தறை மற்றும் ஹம்பாந்தோட்டை ஊடாக பொத்துவில் வரையான கடற்பரப்புகளிலும் காற்றின் வேகமானது மணித்தியாலத்துக்கு 50-55 கிலோ மீற்றர் வரை அதிகரித்து வீசக்கூடும்.",
        "நீர்கொழும்பில் இருந்து புத்தளம் மற்றும் மன்னார் ஊடாக காங்கேசன்துறை வரையான கடற்பரப்புகளும் காலியிலிருந்து மாத்தறை மற்றும் ஹம்பாந்தோட்டை ஊடாக பொத்துவில் வரையான கடற்பரப்புகளும் அவ்வப்போது கொந்தளிப்பாக காணப்படும்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "வளிமண்டலவியல் திணைக்களம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "சப்ரகமுவ மாகாணம்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "நுவரெலியா",
            "label": "PRODUCT"
          },
          {
            "text": "கண்டி",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "காலி",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "மாத்தறை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "சுமார் 40-50",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "தெற்கு",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "சப்ரகமுவ",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "மாதராவியா காலி",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "தெற்கு",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "மணிக்கு 30-40 கி.மீ",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "நீர்கொழும்பு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "மன்னார்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "மாத்தறை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஹம்பாந்தோட்டை",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "நீர்கொழும்பு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "மன்னார்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "மாத்தறை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஹம்பாந்தோட்டை",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}