{
  "newspaper_id": "ada-lk",
  "url": "https://www.ada.lk/uncategorized/ග්‍රහලෝක-5ක්-එකම-රේඛාවක/1-394877",
  "time_ut": 1656317692,
  "original_lang": "si",
  "original_title": "ග්‍රහලෝක 5ක් එකම රේඛාවක",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "5 planets in the same line",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "There are five planets in our solar system that can be observed with the naked eye. They are Mercury, Venus, Mars, Jupiter, and Saturn. These planets can be observed in the night sky separately at different times of the year, and these days it is special to be able to observe all 5 planets in the sky at the same line at the same time.",
        "The image above shows how all 5 planets are in the same line on June 29, 2022 (5 am).",
        "Saturn is located slightly above the sky, so it may be difficult to identify the other planets, but the other planets can be easily identified by drawing an imaginary line connecting the brightest planets, Venus and Jupiter.",
        "This phenomenon can be most clearly observed in the sky from 4:40 am on Wednesday, June 29 (Wednesday), when the effect of the moon's light is minimal. This phenomenon can be observed until the end of the first week of July, if the horizon is clearly visible.",
        "As Mercury approaches the Sun after the first week of July, it will not be visible, but the other planets will remain in this linear position until the first week of August 4.",
        "If the solar system were completely flat, the position of the planets could be frequently observed in this way. But in reality, the orbits of the planets are seldom at right angles, so it is rare for the planets to appear in such a linear position."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "5",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "five",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Mercury",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Venus",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Mars",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "Jupiter",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "Saturn",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the year",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "5",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "5",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "June 29, 2022",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "5 am",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Saturn",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Venus",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "Jupiter",
            "label": "LOC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "4:40 am",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "Wednesday, June 29",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Wednesday",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Mercury",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sun",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the first week of July",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the first week of August 4",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        []
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "ග්‍රහලෝක 5ක් එකම රේඛාවක",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "පියවි ඇසින් නිරීක්ෂණය කල හැකි අප සෞරග්‍රහ මණ්ඩලයට අයත් ග්‍රහලෝක පහකි. ඒවා නම් බුධ, සිකුරු, අඟහරු, බ්‍රහස්පති, සහ සෙනසුරු ය. වසරේ එක් එක කාලයෙ දී මෙම ග්‍රහලෝක වෙන වෙනම රාත්‍රී අහසේ නිරීක්ෂණය කල හැකි අතර, මෙම දිනවල විශේෂයක් වන්නේ මෙම ග්‍රහලෝක 5ම එකම රේඛාවක එකවර අහසේ නිරීක්ෂණය කල හැකි වීමයි.",
        "2022 ජුනි 29 දින (පෙ.ව. 5)ග්‍රහලෝක 5ම එකම රේඛාවක පිහිටා ඇතිආකාරයඉහත රූපයෙන් දැක්වේ.",
        "සෙනසුරු ග්‍රහලෝකය තරමක් අහස මුදුනට වන්නට පිහිටා ඇති බැවින් එම ග්‍රහලෝකය හඳුනා ගැනීම තරමක් අපහසු විය හැකි නමුත් ඉතාමත් දීප්තිමත්ව දර්ශනය වන සිකුරු හා බ්‍රහස්පති ග්‍රහලෝක මනසින් යා කරමින් මනඃකල්පිතරේඛාවක් ඇඳීමෙන් අනෙක් ග්‍රහලෝක පහසුවෙන් හඳුනා ගත හැකි වනු ඇත.",
        "චන්ද්‍රයාගේ ආලෝකයේ බලපෑම අවම වන ජුනි 29 (බදාදා) දින අලුයම අහසේ 4:40 සිට හිරු උදාව දක්වා මෙම සංසිද්ධිය වඩාත් ම පැහැදිලිව නිරීක්ෂණය කල හැකි වේ. පැහැදිලිව ක්ෂිතිජය නිරීක්ෂණය කල හැකි ස්ථානයක සිට නිරීක්ෂණය කරන්නේ නම් මෙම සංසිද්ධිය ජුලි මස පළමු සතිය අවසානය දක්වා ම නිරීක්ෂණය කල හැක.",
        "ජුලි මස පළමු සතියෙන් පසු බුධ ග්‍රහලෝකය සූර්යයා ආසන්නයට ගමන් කිරීම නිසා එම ග්‍රහලෝකය නිරීක්ෂණය නොවන නමුත් අනෙකුත්ග්‍රහලෝක 4 අගෝස්තු පළමු සතිය දක්වා ම මෙම රේඛීය පිහිටුමේ පවතින ආකාරය දර්ශනය වේ.",
        "සෞරග්‍රහ මණ්ඩලය සම්පුර්ණයෙන් පැතලි ආකාරයට සැකසී තිබිණි නම් මේ ආකාරයට ග්‍රහලෝක පිහිටීම නිතර නිරීක්ෂණය කල හැකි වේ. නමුත් සැබවින්ම ග්‍රහලෝක වල කක්ෂ, එකිනෙකට ආනත තල වල පිහිටා ඇති බැවින් ග්‍රහලෝක මේ ආකාරයට රේඛීය පිහිටුමක දර්ශනය වීම කලාතුරකින් සිදු වේ.නැවත මෙලෙස ග්‍රහලෝක 5ක් රේඛීය පිහිටුමක දැකිය හැක්කේ 2040 වසරේ දී ය."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "5",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "පහ",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "රසදිය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "සිකුරු",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "අඟහරු",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "බ්රහස්පති",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "සෙනසුරු",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "වසර",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "5",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "5",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "2022 ජූනි 29",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "5 am",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "සෙනසුරු",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "සිකුරු",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "බ්රහස්පති",
            "label": "LOC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "4:40 පෙ.ව",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජූනි 29 බදාදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "බදාදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "රසදිය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "හිරු",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජූලි පළමු සතිය",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "අගෝස්තු 4 මුල් සතියේ",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        []
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "ஒரே வரிசையில் 5 கிரகங்கள்",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "நமது சூரிய குடும்பத்தில் நிர்வாணக் கண்ணால் பார்க்கக்கூடிய ஐந்து கிரகங்கள் உள்ளன. அவை புதன், வெள்ளி, செவ்வாய், வியாழன் மற்றும் சனி. இந்த கோள்களை இரவு வானில் தனித்தனியாக ஆண்டின் வெவ்வேறு நேரங்களில் அவதானிக்க முடியும், மேலும் இந்த நாட்களில் வானில் உள்ள 5 கோள்களையும் ஒரே கோட்டில் ஒரே நேரத்தில் அவதானிக்க முடிவது சிறப்பு.",
        "ஜூன் 29, 2022 அன்று (காலை 5 மணி) 5 கிரகங்களும் ஒரே கோட்டில் எப்படி உள்ளன என்பதை மேலே உள்ள படம் காட்டுகிறது.",
        "சனி வானத்திலிருந்து சற்று மேலே அமைந்திருப்பதால் மற்ற கிரகங்களை அடையாளம் காண்பது கடினமாக இருக்கலாம், ஆனால் பிரகாசமான கிரகங்களான வீனஸ் மற்றும் வியாழனை இணைக்கும் கற்பனைக் கோட்டை வரைவதன் மூலம் மற்ற கிரகங்களை எளிதில் அடையாளம் காண முடியும்.",
        "நிலவின் ஒளியின் தாக்கம் குறைவாக இருக்கும் ஜூன் 29 புதன்கிழமை (புதன்கிழமை) அதிகாலை 4:40 மணி முதல் இந்த நிகழ்வை வானில் மிகத் தெளிவாகக் காணலாம். அடிவானம் தெளிவாகத் தெரிந்தால், ஜூலை முதல் வார இறுதி வரை இந்த நிகழ்வைக் காணலாம்.",
        "ஜூலை முதல் வாரத்திற்குப் பிறகு புதன் சூரியனை நெருங்குவதால், அது கண்ணுக்குத் தெரியாது, ஆனால் ஆகஸ்ட் 4 முதல் வாரம் வரை மற்ற கிரகங்கள் இந்த நேரியல் நிலையில் இருக்கும்.",
        "சூரிய குடும்பம் முற்றிலும் தட்டையாக இருந்தால், கோள்களின் நிலையை அடிக்கடி இந்த வழியில் கவனிக்க முடியும். ஆனால் உண்மையில், கோள்களின் சுற்றுப்பாதைகள் அரிதாகவே சரியான கோணத்தில் இருக்கும், எனவே கோள்கள் இத்தகைய நேர்கோட்டு நிலையில் தோன்றுவது அரிது."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "5",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ஐந்து",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாதரசம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "வீனஸ்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "செவ்வாய்",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "வியாழன்",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "சனி",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆண்டு",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "5",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "5",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜூன் 29, 2022",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "காலை 5 மணி",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "சனி",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "வீனஸ்",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "வியாழன்",
            "label": "LOC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "காலை 4:40 மணி",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜூன் 29 புதன்கிழமை",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "புதன்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பாதரசம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "சூரியன்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜூலை முதல் வாரம்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆகஸ்ட் 4 முதல் வாரம்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        []
      ]
    }
  }
}