{
  "newspaper_id": "daily-ft-lk",
  "url": "https://www.ft.lk/business/ACME-Printing-Packaging-mulls-buying-of-JF-Packaging/34-737063",
  "time_ut": 1656971633,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "ACME Printing & Packaging mulls buying of JF Packaging",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "ACME Printing & Packaging mulls buying of JF Packaging",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "ACME Printing & Packaging has entered into preliminary discussions with the board of the company’s parent company, Lankem Ceylon PLC(LCPLC) to negotiate the acquisition of a controlling stake of 51% or above of LCPLC’s Equity holding in its subsidiary J F Packaging Ltd., (JFP).",
        "ACME said the proposal is very much in its infancy and no material decisions have been made in respect thereof as to whether or not the acquisition will proceed, including the terms thereof. Further, it said the potential transaction would also be dependent inter alia, on both parties agreeing to a valuation of the shares of J F Packaging Ltd. and obtaining the necessary regulatory as well as shareholder approvals (as may be required) to proceed with the transaction if the boards of directors of each company consider it viable to do so.",
        "ACME said this discussion although is currently at its initial stages, is being disseminated to the market in accordance with the company’s obligations to do so in terms of the listing rules of the Colombo Stock Exchange, to provide the shareholders full disclosure of the affairs of the company when considering the rights issue (Rs. 556 million) which was approved by the shareholders at the extraordinary general meeting held on 23 June and currently pending closure.",
        "Lankem Group owns 88.27% stake in ACME. Lankem’s cost of investment in JF Packaging is stated at Rs. 1.12 billion.",
        "ACME Group revenue for the year ended on 31 March was Rs. 948 million, down by 33% from the previous year. It reported a loss from operations amounting to Rs. 161 million, as against a profit of Rs. 34 million. After tax loss was Rs. 309 million, up from Rs. 119 million. As at 31 March, accumulated losses amounted to Rs. 701 million at company level and Rs. 1 billion at group level.",
        "In December ACME announced a 3 for 1 rights issue at Rs. 4.50 each in a bid to raise Rs. 555.68 million for the purpose of meeting working capital. Yesterday the share price of ACME closed at Rs. 6.30, up by 10 cents."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ACME Printing & Packaging",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ACME Printing & Packaging",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Lankem Ceylon",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "51%",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "LCPLC",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "J F Packaging Ltd.",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "JFP",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ACME",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "J F Packaging Ltd.",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ACME",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Colombo Stock Exchange",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "556 million",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "23 June",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Lankem Group",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "88.27%",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "ACME",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "Lankem",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Packaging",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "1.12 billion",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ACME Group",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the year ended on 31 March",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "948 million",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "33%",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "the previous year",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "161 million",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "34 million",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "309 million",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "119 million",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "31 March",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "701 million",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "1 billion",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "December",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ACME",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "3",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "4.50",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "555.68 million",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Yesterday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ACME",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "6.30",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "10 cents",
            "label": "MONEY"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "ACME මුද්‍රණ සහ ඇසුරුම් JF ඇසුරුම් මිලදී ගැනීමට අදහස් කරයි",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "ACME මුද්‍රණ සහ ඇසුරුම් සමාගම විසින් එහි අනුබද්ධිත J F Packaging Ltd. හි LCPLC හි කොටස් හිමිකාරීත්වයෙන් 51% හෝ ඊට වැඩි පාලන කොටස් අත්පත් කර ගැනීම සඳහා සාකච්ඡා කිරීම සඳහා සමාගමේ මව් සමාගම වන Lankem Ceylon PLC (LCPLC) හි මණ්ඩලය සමඟ මූලික සාකච්ඡාවලට එළඹ ඇත. JFP).",
        "ACME පැවසුවේ මෙම යෝජනාව බොහෝ දුරට ආරම්භක අවධියේ පවතින අතර එහි කොන්දේසි ඇතුළුව අත්පත් කර ගැනීම සිදුවේද නැද්ද යන්න සම්බන්ධයෙන් කිසිදු ප්‍රමාණාත්මක තීරණ ගෙන නොමැති බවයි. තවද, J F Packaging Ltd. හි කොටස් තක්සේරු කිරීමට දෙපාර්ශවයම එකඟ වීම සහ ගනුදෙනුව ඉදිරියට ගෙන යාමට අවශ්‍ය නියාමන මෙන්ම කොටස් හිමියන්ගේ අනුමැතියන් (අවශ්‍ය පරිදි) ලබා ගැනීම මතද විභව ගනුදෙනුව රඳා පවතිනු ඇතැයි එහි සඳහන් වේ. එක් එක් සමාගමේ අධ්‍යක්ෂ මණ්ඩල එසේ කිරීම ශක්‍ය බව සලකන්නේ නම්.",
        "ACME පැවසුවේ, මෙම සාකච්ඡාව දැනට එහි මූලික අදියරේ පවතින නමුත්, කොළඹ කොටස් වෙළඳපොලේ ලැයිස්තුගත කිරීමේ නීතිරීතිවලට අනුව, කොටස් හිමියන්ට එහි කටයුතු පිළිබඳ පූර්ණ හෙළිදරව්වක් ලබා දීම සඳහා සමාගමේ වගකීම්වලට අනුකූලව වෙළඳපොළට බෙදා හරින බවයි. සමාගම ජුනි 23 වැනි දින පැවති අසාමාන්‍ය මහා සභා රැස්වීමේදී කොටස් හිමියන් විසින් අනුමත කරන ලද සහ දැනට වසා දැමීමට නියමිත හිමිකම් නිකුතුව (රු. මිලියන 556) සලකා බලන විට.",
        "ලංකෙම් සමූහයට ACME හි 88.27% ක කොටස් හිමිවේ. JF ඇසුරුම්කරණය සඳහා ලංකෙම් හි ආයෝජන පිරිවැය රු. බිලියන 1.12 කි.",
        "මාර්තු 31 දිනෙන් අවසන් වූ වර්ෂය සඳහා ACME සමූහයේ ආදායම රු. මිලියන 948, පෙර වසරට වඩා 33% කින් අඩු විය. එය මෙහෙයුම් වලින් රු. මිලියන 161 ක ලාභයකට සාපේක්ෂව රු. මිලියන 34 කි. බදු ගෙවීමෙන් පසු පාඩුව රු. මිලියන 309 සිට රු. මිලියන 119 කි. මාර්තු 31 වන විට සමුච්චිත පාඩු රු. මිලියන 701 ක් සහ සමාගම් මට්ටමින් රු. කණ්ඩායම් මට්ටමින් බිලියන 1.",
        "දෙසැම්බර් මාසයේදී ACME විසින් 3 සඳහා 1 හිමිකම් නිකුතුවක් රු. 4.50 බැගින් රු. කාරක ප්‍රාග්ධනය සපුරාලීම සඳහා මිලියන 555.68 කි. ඊයේ ACME හි කොටසක මිල රු. 6.30, ශත 10 කින් වැඩි විය."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ACME මුද්‍රණ සහ ඇසුරුම්",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ACME මුද්‍රණ සහ ඇසුරුම්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ලංකෙම් සිලෝන්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "51%",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "LCPLC",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "J F Packaging Ltd.",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජේ.එෆ්.පී",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ACME",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "J F Packaging Ltd.",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ACME",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "කොළඹ කොටස් වෙළෙඳපොළ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "මිලියන 556 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "23 ජූනි",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ලංකෙම් සමූහය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "88.27%",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "ACME",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "ලංකෙම්",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඇසුරුම්කරණය",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "බිලියන 1.12 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ACME සමූහය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "මාර්තු 31 වැනිදා වසර අවසන් විය",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මිලියන 948 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "33%",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "පෙර වසරේ",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මිලියන 161 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "මිලියන 34 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "මිලියන 309 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "මිලියන 119 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "මාර්තු 31",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මිලියන 701 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "බිලියන 1 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "දෙසැම්බර්",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ACME",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "3",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "4.50 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "මිලියන 555.68 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඊයේ",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ACME",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "6.30",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශත 10 යි",
            "label": "MONEY"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "ACME பிரிண்டிங் & பேக்கேஜிங் JF பேக்கேஜிங் வாங்குவதற்கு முயல்கிறது",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "ACME பிரிண்டிங் & பேக்கேஜிங், அதன் துணை நிறுவனமான J F Packaging Ltd., (LCPLC இன் ஈக்விட்டியில் 51% அல்லது அதற்கும் அதிகமான பங்குகளை வாங்குவதற்கு, நிறுவனத்தின் தாய் நிறுவனமான லங்கெம் சிலோன் பிஎல்சி (LCPLC) குழுவுடன் பூர்வாங்க விவாதங்களில் ஈடுபட்டுள்ளது. JFP).",
        "ACME இந்த முன்மொழிவு மிகவும் ஆரம்ப நிலையில் இருப்பதாகவும், அதன் விதிமுறைகள் உட்பட கையகப்படுத்தல் தொடருமா இல்லையா என்பது குறித்து எந்த முக்கிய முடிவுகளும் எடுக்கப்படவில்லை என்றும் கூறினார். மேலும், சாத்தியமான பரிவர்த்தனையானது, J F பேக்கேஜிங் லிமிடெட் பங்குகளின் மதிப்பீட்டிற்கு இரு தரப்பினரும் ஒப்புக்கொள்வது மற்றும் பரிவர்த்தனையைத் தொடர தேவையான ஒழுங்குமுறை மற்றும் பங்குதாரர்களின் ஒப்புதல்கள் (தேவைப்படக்கூடியது) ஆகியவற்றைப் பெறுவதைச் சார்ந்து இருக்கும் என்றும் அது கூறியது. ஒவ்வொரு நிறுவனத்தின் இயக்குநர்கள் குழுவும் அவ்வாறு செய்வது சாத்தியமானதாக கருதினால்.",
        "இந்த கலந்துரையாடல் தற்போது ஆரம்ப கட்டத்தில் இருந்தாலும், கொழும்பு பங்குச் சந்தையின் பட்டியலிடுதல் விதிகளின்படி, பங்குதாரர்களுக்கு பங்குதாரர்களுக்கு பங்குதாரர்களின் விவகாரங்களை முழுமையாக வெளிப்படுத்தும் வகையில், நிறுவனத்தின் கடமைகளுக்கு இணங்க, சந்தைக்கு பரப்பப்பட்டு வருவதாக ACME தெரிவித்துள்ளது. நிறுவனம் ஜூன் 23 அன்று நடைபெற்ற அசாதாரண பொதுக் கூட்டத்தில் பங்குதாரர்களால் அங்கீகரிக்கப்பட்ட உரிமை வெளியீட்டை (ரூ. 556 மில்லியன்) பரிசீலிக்கும் போது, ​​தற்போது மூடப்பட உள்ளது.",
        "லங்கெம் குழுமம் ACME இல் 88.27% பங்குகளை வைத்துள்ளது. JF பேக்கேஜிங்கில் லங்கெமின் முதலீட்டுச் செலவு ரூ. 1.12 பில்லியன்.",
        "மார்ச் 31 அன்று முடிவடைந்த ஆண்டிற்கான ACME குழுமத்தின் வருவாய் ரூ. 948 மில்லியன், முந்தைய ஆண்டை விட 33% குறைந்துள்ளது. இது நடவடிக்கைகளால் ரூ. 161 மில்லியன், லாபம் ரூ. 34 மில்லியன். வரி இழப்பு ரூ. 309 மில்லியன், ரூ. 119 மில்லியன். மார்ச் 31 நிலவரப்படி, திரட்டப்பட்ட இழப்புகள் ரூ. நிறுவன மட்டத்தில் 701 மில்லியன் மற்றும் ரூ. குழு மட்டத்தில் 1 பில்லியன்.",
        "டிசம்பரில் ACME ஆனது 3 க்கு 1 உரிமை வெளியீட்டை ரூ. 4.50 உயர்த்த ஏலத்தில் தலா ரூ. 555.68 மில்லியன் செயல்பாட்டு மூலதனத்தை சந்திக்கும் நோக்கத்திற்காக. நேற்று ACME பங்கு விலை ரூ. 6.30, 10 சென்ட் உயர்ந்தது."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ACME பிரிண்டிங் & பேக்கேஜிங்",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ACME பிரிண்டிங் & பேக்கேஜிங்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "லங்கேம் சிலோன்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "51%",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "LCPLC",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜே எஃப் பேக்கேஜிங் லிமிடெட்.",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜே.எஃப்.பி",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ACME",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜே எஃப் பேக்கேஜிங் லிமிடெட்.",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ACME",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "கொழும்பு பங்குச் சந்தை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "556 மில்லியன்",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "23 ஜூன்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "லங்கெம் குழுமம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "88.27%",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "ACME",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "லங்கேம்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "பேக்கேஜிங்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "1.12 பில்லியன்",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ACME குழு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆண்டு மார்ச் 31 அன்று முடிந்தது",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "948 மில்லியன்",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "33%",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "முந்தைய ஆண்டு",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "161 மில்லியன்",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "34 மில்லியன்",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "309 மில்லியன்",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "119 மில்லியன்",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "31 மார்ச்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "701 மில்லியன்",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "1 பில்லியன்",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "டிசம்பர்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ACME",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "3",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "4.50",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "555.68 மில்லியன்",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "நேற்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ACME",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "6.30",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "10 சென்ட்",
            "label": "MONEY"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}