{
  "newspaper_id": "ada-lk",
  "url": "https://www.ada.lk/breaking_news/විපක්ෂ-මන්ත්‍රීවරුන්ගේ-විරෝධතා-මැද-ජනපති-පාර්ලිමේන්තුවෙන්-යයි/11-395111",
  "time_ut": 1656999585,
  "original_lang": "si",
  "original_title": "විපක්ෂ මන්ත්‍රීවරුන්ගේ විරෝධතා මැද ජනපති පාර්ලිමේන්තුවෙන් යයි",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "The President leaves the Parliament amidst the protests of the opposition members",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "The opposition members of the Parliament strongly objected to President Gotabhaya Rajapaksa who came to join the Parliament session.",
        "As soon as the Prime Minister Ranil Wickremesinghe's statement ended, the opposition MPs started protesting and the President left the Parliament amid the protests."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Parliament",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Gotabhaya Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "විපක්ෂ මන්ත්‍රීවරුන්ගේ විරෝධතා මැද ජනපති පාර්ලිමේන්තුවෙන් යයි",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "පාර්ලිමේන්තු සැසිවාරය සදහා එක්වීමට පැමිණි ජනපති ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ මහතා වෙත පාර්ලිමේන්තුවේ විපක්ෂ මන්ත්‍රීවරුන් දැඩි විරෝධයක් එල්ල කළේය.",
        "අග්‍රාමාත්‍ය රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතාගේ ප්‍රකාශය අවසන්වීමත් සමග විපක්ෂ මන්ත්‍රීවරුන් විරෝධතා දැක්වීම ආරම්භ කළ අතර එම විරෝධතා මධ්‍යයේ ජනපතිවරයා පාර්ලිමේන්තුවෙන් ඉවත්ව ගියේය."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "எதிர்க்கட்சி உறுப்பினர்களின் எதிர்ப்புக்கு மத்தியில் ஜனாதிபதி பாராளுமன்றத்தை விட்டு வெளியேறினார்",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "பாராளுமன்ற அமர்வில் கலந்து கொள்வதற்காக வந்த ஜனாதிபதி கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ஷவிற்கு பாராளுமன்றத்தில் எதிர்க்கட்சி உறுப்பினர்கள் கடும் எதிர்ப்பு தெரிவித்தனர்.",
        "பிரதமர் ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்கவின் அறிக்கை முடிவடைந்தவுடன், எதிர்க்கட்சி எம்.பி.க்கள் ஆர்ப்பாட்டத்தில் ஈடுபடத் தொடங்கியதையடுத்து, எதிர்ப்புக்கு மத்தியில் ஜனாதிபதி பாராளுமன்றத்தை விட்டு வெளியேறினார்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "கோத்தபாய ராஜபக்ச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}