{
  "newspaper_id": "ada-derana-lk",
  "url": "http://www.adaderana.lk/news/83291/sltb-says-adequate-buses-will-be-operated",
  "time_ut": 1656348720,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "SLTB says adequate buses will be operated",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "SLTB says adequate buses will be operated",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "The Chairman of the Sri Lanka Transport Board (SLTB) Kingsley Ranawaka says that adequate SLTB buses will be operated and that bus services will not be affected by the current restrictions.",
        "Meanwhile Sri Lanka Railways also said that train services will operate under normal schedules tomorrow (28).",
        "The government today announced that only vehicles attached to essential services will be supplied fuel with effect from midnight today (June 27) until the 10th of July.",
        "Cabinet Spokesperson, Minister Bandula Gunawardena said the Cabinet of Ministers decided to continue essential services and suspend other operations until the 10th of July.",
        "He added that inter-provincial transport services will be temporarily halted due to the availability of limited stocks of fuel.",
        "He said that a mechanism to provide a continuous supply of LP gas and fuel would be in place after the 10th of July."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "SLTB",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "the Sri Lanka Transport Board",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "SLTB",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kingsley Ranawaka",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "SLTB",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "tomorrow",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "28",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "midnight today",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "June 27",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the 10th of July",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Bandula Gunawardena",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Cabinet of Ministers",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the 10th of July",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "10th of July",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "ප්‍රමාණවත් බස් රථ ධාවනය කරන බව ලංගම කියයි",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "ප්‍රමාණවත් ලෙස ලංගම බස් රථ ධාවනය කරන බවත් දැනට පනවා ඇති සීමා කිරීම් හේතුවෙන් බස් රථ ධාවනයට බාධාවක් නොවන බවත් ශ්‍රී ලංකා ගමනාගමන මණ්ඩලයේ සභාපති කිංස්ලි රණවක මහතා පවසයි.",
        "මේ අතර, හෙට (28) සාමාන්‍ය කාලසටහන් යටතේ දුම්රිය සේවා ක්‍රියාත්මක වන බව ද ශ්‍රී ලංකා දුම්රිය දෙපාර්තමේන්තුව පවසයි.",
        "අද (ජුනි 27) මධ්‍යම රාත්‍රියේ සිට ජූලි 10 දක්වා ක්‍රියාත්මක වන පරිදි අත්‍යාවශ්‍ය සේවාවන්ට අනුයුක්ත වාහන සඳහා පමණක් ඉන්ධන සපයන බව රජය අද නිවේදනය කළේය.",
        "කැබිනට් ප්‍රකාශක, අමාත්‍ය බන්දුල ගුණවර්ධන මහතා පැවසුවේ අත්‍යාවශ්‍ය සේවා අඛණ්ඩව පවත්වාගෙන යාමට සහ අනෙකුත් මෙහෙයුම් ජූලි 10 වැනිදා දක්වා අත්හිටුවීමට අමාත්‍ය මණ්ඩලය තීරණය කළ බව ය.",
        "සීමිත ඉන්ධන තොග ප්‍රමාණයක් තිබීම හේතුවෙන් අන්තර් පළාත් ප්‍රවාහන සේවා තාවකාලිකව නවතා දමන බවද ඔහු සඳහන් කළේය.",
        "ජුලි 10 වැනිදායින් පසු අඛණ්ඩව LP ගෑස් සහ ඉන්ධන සැපයීමේ යාන්ත්‍රණයක් ක්‍රියාත්මක කරන බව ඔහු පැවසීය."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ලංගම",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකා ගමනාගමන මණ්ඩලය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ලංගම",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "කිංස්ලි රණවක",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ලංගම",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "හෙට",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "28",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "අද මධ්‍යම රාත්‍රිය",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජූනි 27",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජූලි 10 වෙනිදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "බන්දුල ගුණවර්ධන",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "අමාත්ය මණ්ඩලය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජූලි 10 වෙනිදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "ජූලි 10 වැනිදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "போதுமான பேருந்துகள் இயக்கப்படும் என இலங்கை போக்குவரத்து சபை தெரிவித்துள்ளது",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "இலங்கை போக்குவரத்து சபையின் போதியளவு பேருந்துகள் இயக்கப்படும் எனவும் தற்போதைய தடைகளினால் பேருந்து சேவைகள் பாதிக்கப்படாது எனவும் இலங்கை போக்குவரத்து சபையின் தலைவர் கிங்ஸ்லி ரணவக்க தெரிவித்துள்ளார்.",
        "இதேவேளை, நாளை (28) வழமையான கால அட்டவணையின் கீழ் ரயில் சேவைகள் இடம்பெறும் எனவும் இலங்கை ரயில்வே தெரிவித்துள்ளது.",
        "இன்று (ஜூன் 27) நள்ளிரவு முதல் ஜூலை 10 ஆம் தேதி வரை அத்தியாவசிய சேவைகளுக்கு இணைக்கப்பட்ட வாகனங்களுக்கு மட்டுமே எரிபொருள் விநியோகிக்கப்படும் என அரசாங்கம் இன்று அறிவித்துள்ளது.",
        "அத்தியாவசிய சேவைகளை தொடர்வதற்கும் ஏனைய நடவடிக்கைகளை ஜூலை 10 ஆம் திகதி வரை இடைநிறுத்துவதற்கும் அமைச்சரவை தீர்மானித்துள்ளதாக அமைச்சரவை பேச்சாளர் அமைச்சர் பந்துல குணவர்தன தெரிவித்துள்ளார்.",
        "மட்டுப்படுத்தப்பட்ட எரிபொருள் இருப்பு காரணமாக மாகாணங்களுக்கிடையிலான போக்குவரத்து சேவைகள் தற்காலிகமாக நிறுத்தப்படும் என அவர் மேலும் தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "எல்.பி எரிவாயு மற்றும் எரிபொருளை தொடர்ச்சியாக வழங்குவதற்கான பொறிமுறையானது ஜூலை 10 ஆம் திகதிக்குப் பின்னர் அமுல்படுத்தப்படும் என்றும் அவர் கூறினார்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "SLTB",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை போக்குவரத்து சபை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "SLTB",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "கிங்ஸ்லி ரணவக்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "SLTB",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "நாளை",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "28",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று நள்ளிரவு",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜூன் 27",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜூலை 10 ஆம் தேதி",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பந்துல குணவர்தன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "மந்திரிசபை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜூலை 10 ஆம் தேதி",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஜூலை 10 ஆம் தேதி",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}