{
  "newspaper_id": "ada-derana-lk",
  "url": "http://www.adaderana.lk/news/84725/eu-welcomes-imf-sri-lanka-agreement",
  "time_ut": 1662192660,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "EU welcomes IMF - Sri Lanka agreement",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "EU welcomes IMF - Sri Lanka agreement",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "The delegation of the European Union to Sri Lanka says it welcomes the staff-level agreement between the International Monetary Fund (IMF) and Sri Lanka.",
        "Taking to its official Twitter handle, the EU delegation said it looks forward to continuing cooperation on public finance management and green economy, including export industries."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "EU",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "IMF - Sri Lanka",
          "label": "LOC"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "the European Union to Sri Lanka",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the International Monetary Fund",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Twitter",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "EU",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "IMF - Sri Lanka ගිවිසුම යුරෝපා සංගමය පිළිගනී",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "ජාත්‍යන්තර මූල්‍ය අරමුදල (IMF) සහ ශ්‍රී ලංකාව අතර කාර්ය මණ්ඩල මට්ටමේ එකඟතාව පිළිගන්නා බව යුරෝපා සංගමයේ ශ්‍රී ලංකාවට පැමිණි නියෝජිත පිරිස පවසයි.",
        "සිය නිල ට්විටර් හසුරුව වෙත ගෙන යමින් යුරෝපා සංගම් නියෝජිත පිරිස කියා සිටියේ අපනයන කර්මාන්ත ඇතුළු රාජ්‍ය මූල්‍ය කළමනාකරණය සහ හරිත ආර්ථිකය පිළිබඳ අඛණ්ඩ සහයෝගීතාව අපේක්ෂා කරන බවයි."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "EU",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "IMF - ශ්‍රී ලංකාව",
          "label": "LOC"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "යුරෝපා සංගමය ශ්‍රී ලංකාවට",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජාත්‍යන්තර මුල්‍ය අරමුදල",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ට්විටර්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "EU",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "IMF - இலங்கை ஒப்பந்தத்தை ஐரோப்பிய ஒன்றியம் வரவேற்கிறது",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "சர்வதேச நாணய நிதியத்திற்கும் (IMF) இலங்கைக்கும் இடையிலான பணியாளர் மட்ட ஒப்பந்தத்தை வரவேற்பதாக ஐரோப்பிய ஒன்றியத்தின் இலங்கைக்கான பிரதிநிதிகள் குழு தெரிவித்துள்ளது.",
        "அதன் அதிகாரப்பூர்வ ட்விட்டர் கைப்பிடியில், EU பிரதிநிதிகள் பொது நிதி மேலாண்மை மற்றும் ஏற்றுமதி தொழில்கள் உட்பட பசுமைப் பொருளாதாரம் ஆகியவற்றில் தொடர்ந்து ஒத்துழைப்பை எதிர்நோக்குகிறோம் என்று கூறியது."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "EU",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "IMF - இலங்கை",
          "label": "LOC"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ஐரோப்பிய ஒன்றியம் இலங்கைக்கு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "சர்வதேச நாணய நிதியம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ட்விட்டர்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "EU",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}