{
  "newspaper_id": "lankadeepa-lk",
  "url": "https://www.lankadeepa.lk/news/’’කඩෙි’’-බිස්නස්-පාඩු-කළාට-මුදලාලිලා--මැනේජර්ලා--කැෂියර්ලා-වග-කිව-යුතුයි/101-619135",
  "time_ut": 1662030481,
  "original_lang": "si",
  "original_title": "’’කඩෙි’’ බිස්නස් පාඩු කළාට මුදලාලිලා, මැනේජර්ලා, කැෂියර්ලා වග කිව යුතුයි",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "The moneylenders, managers and cashiers should be held responsible for the loss of the \"shop\" business",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "Mr. Chamara Sampath Dasanayake, Member of Badulla District Podujana Peramuna said in the Parliament that the moneylenders, managers and cashiers who have worked in the shop since Ronnie the Mal moneylenders should be held responsible for the loss of the \"kadei\" business.",
        "\"At least we have not done nattami work in the shop. We worked for a short time. We worked in the local council. Garbage tax is collected only from Srilankan Ella local council. If you want, look for it. I did it. That's why none of the shops we ran went bankrupt. Mr. Chamara Sampath said while joining the budget debate."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Chamara Sampath Dasanayake",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Badulla District",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Podujana Peramuna",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Mal",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Srilankan Ella",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Chamara Sampath",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "’’කඩෙි’’ බිස්නස් පාඩු කළාට මුදලාලිලා, මැනේජර්ලා, කැෂියර්ලා වග කිව යුතුයි",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "\"කඩෙි\" බිස්නස් පාඩු කළාට රොනී ද මැල් මුදලාලිලගේ  සිට කඩෙි වැඩ කළ මුදලාලිලා, මැනේජර්ලා, කැෂියර්ලා වග කිව යුතු බව බදුල්ල දිස්ත්‍රික් පොදුජන පෙරමුණේ මන්ත්‍රී චාමර සම්පත් දසනායක මහතා පාර්ලිමේන්තුවේ දී පැවසීය.",
        "\"අපි අඩුම වශයෙන් කඩේ නාට්ටාමි වැඩක් වත් අපි කරලා නැහැ. පොඩි කාලෙකට හරි වැඩ කළා. අපි ප්‍රාදේශීය සභාවේ වැඩ කළා. ලංකාවෙන් ඇල්ල ප්‍රාදේශීය සභාවෙන් විතරයි කසල බදු අය කරන්නේ.ඕනෑ නම් හොයලා බලන්න. ඒක කළේ මමයි. ඒ හින්දා අපි දුවපු කඩවල් එකක්වත් බංකොලොත් වෙලා නැහැ\"යනුවෙන්ද අයවැය විවාදයට එක්වෙමින් චාමර සම්පත් මහතා පැවසීය."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "චාමර සම්පත් දසනායක",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "බදුල්ල දිස්ත්‍රික්කය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "පොදුජන පෙරමුණ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "මල්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකන් ඇල්ල",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "චාමර සම්පත්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "\"கடை\" வியாபாரம் நஷ்டம் அடைந்ததற்கு, கந்துவட்டிக்காரர்கள், மேலாளர்கள் மற்றும் காசாளர்களே பொறுப்பேற்க வேண்டும்",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "ரொனி த மல் கந்து வட்டிக்காரர்கள் முதல் கடையில் பணியாற்றிய கந்துவட்டிக்காரர்கள், முகாமையாளர்கள் மற்றும் காசாளர்களே \"கடேய்\" வியாபார நஷ்டத்திற்கு பொறுப்பேற்க வேண்டும் என பதுளை மாவட்ட பொதுஜன பெரமுனவின் உறுப்பினர் திரு.சாமர சம்பத் தசநாயக்க பாராளுமன்றத்தில் தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "\"குறைந்த பட்சம் கடையில் நாட்டாமி வேலை செய்யவில்லை. கொஞ்ச காலம் வேலை செய்தோம். உள்ளூராட்சி மன்றத்தில் வேலை செய்தோம். குப்பை வரி இலங்கை எல்ல உள்ளூராட்சி மன்றத்தில்தான் வசூலிக்கப்படுகிறது. வேண்டுமானால் தேடுங்கள். நான் செய்தேன். அதனால்தான் நாங்கள் நடத்திய எந்தக் கடையும் திவாலாகவில்லை. பட்ஜெட் விவாதத்தில் கலந்து கொண்டு திரு.சாமர சம்பத் கூறினார்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "சாமர சம்பத் தசநாயக்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "பதுளை மாவட்டம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "பொதுஜன பெரமுன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "மல்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை எல்ல",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "சாமர சம்பத்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}