{
  "newspaper_id": "d-b-s-jeyaraj-com",
  "url": "https://dbsjeyaraj.com/dbsj/archives/78132",
  "time_ut": 1655754060,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Samagi Jana Balawegaya (SJB) and  JVP-led National People’s Power (NPP) along with “independent” MPs Champika Ranawaka and  Athureliya Ratana Thera walk out after announcing they will boycott Parliament sittings this week in protest against Govt .",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Samagi Jana Balawegaya (SJB) and  JVP-led National People’s Power (NPP) along with “independent” MPs Champika Ranawaka and  Athureliya Ratana Thera walk out after announcing they will boycott Parliament sittings this week in protest against Govt .",
      "author": "Administrator",
      "body_lines": [
        "The main Opposition Samagi Jana Balawegaya (SJB), the JVP-led National People’s Power (NPP) and several independent MPs walked out of the Chamber yesterday after announcing they will boycott Parliament sittings this week in protest at the Government’s failure to address any of the problems faced by the people.",
        "Joining the walkout were independent MPs Patali Champika Ranawaka and Ven. Athureliye Ratana Thera.",
        "Opposition Leader Sajith Premadasa who announced the decision by the SJB MPs to boycott sittings said that the President and the Prime Minister are both a failure and they have no solution to the people’s problems.",
        "“We will not be a party to the scam that is being enacted by this Government. We have stood up with people in the past, we will stand up with them now and will do so in the future,” Premadasa said.",
        "JVP MP Anura Kumara Dissanayake said the Government has been wasting time with no specific program to solve the problems of the people.",
        "“We want a road map detailing how the Government plans to overcome this problem. There is no point having any debates here unless there is such a program placed before the House,” he said.",
        "Dissanayake said the President is nothing but a puppet and the demand by the people for him to step down is justified.",
        "“If you can’t find solutions to people’s problems, what is the use of having such a leader? The President ignored all the proposals to form an all-party Government and appointed Ranil Wickremesinghe but within one-and-a-half months he has shown he and the Government are incapable of solving the people’s problems,” Dissanayake said.",
        "The Government also came in for severe criticism from SLFP MP Dayasiri Jayasekera and MP Wimal Weerawansa who said the President had ignored the proposals to form an all-party Government and had picked Ranil Wickremesinghe who had been rejected by the people.",
        "“We will not boycott Parliament. We will stay on and try to shake this Government out of its slumber,” Weerawansa said.",
        "Ven. Aturaliye Ratana Thera said this is an anti-democratic Government and hence is incapable of getting assistance from the international community.",
        "“It is not possible for this Government to remain in office. It has been rejected by the people,” Ratana Thera said."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Samagi Jana Balawegaya",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "National People’s Power",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "Parliament",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "this week",
          "label": "DATE"
        },
        {
          "text": "Govt",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Opposition Samagi Jana Balawegaya",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "JVP",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "National People’s Power",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Chamber",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "yesterday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "this week",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Ratana Thera",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sajith Premadasa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Premadasa",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Anura Kumara Dissanayake",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "House",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Dissanayake",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "one-and-a-half months",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Dissanayake",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "SLFP",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Dayasiri Jayasekera",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Wimal Weerawansa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Ratana Thera",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Ratana Thera",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "සමගි ජන බලවේගය (SJB) සහ JVP ප්‍රමුඛ ජාතික ජන බලවේගය (NPP) සහ \"ස්වාධීන\" මන්ත්‍රීවරුන් වන චම්පික රණවක සහ අතුරලියේ රතන හිමි රජයට විරෝධය පළ කරමින් මේ සතියේ පාර්ලිමේන්තු රැස්වීම් වර්ජනය කරන බව ප්‍රකාශ කිරීමෙන් පසු පිටව ගියහ.",
      "author": "පරිපාලක",
      "body_lines": [
        "ප්‍රධාන විපක්ෂය වන සමගි ජන බලවේගය (SJB), ජනතා විමුක්ති පෙරමුණ ප්‍රමුඛ ජාතික ජන බලවේගය (NPP) සහ ස්වාධීන මන්ත්‍රීවරුන් කිහිප දෙනෙකු ඊයේ පාර්ලිමේන්තු රැස්වීම් වර්ජනය කරන බව ප්‍රකාශ කිරීමෙන් පසු සභා ගර්භයෙන් පිටව ගියේ රජය විසින් කිසිඳු කරුණකට පිළිතුරු නොදීමට විරෝධය පළ කරමිනි. ජනතාව මුහුණ දෙන ගැටලු.",
        "පාගමනට එක්වූයේ ස්වාධීන මන්ත්‍රීවරුන් වන පාඨලී චම්පික රණවක සහ පූජ්‍ය නාහිමියන්ය. අතුරලියේ රතන හිමි.",
        "SJB මන්ත්‍රීවරුන් රැස්වීම් වර්ජනය කිරීමට ගත් තීරණය ප්‍රකාශයට පත් කළ විපක්ෂ නායක සජිත් ප්‍රේමදාස කියා සිටියේ ජනාධිපතිවරයා සහ අග්‍රාමාත්‍යවරයා දෙදෙනාම අසාර්ථක බවත් ඔවුන්ට ජනතා ප්‍රශ්නවලට විසඳුම් නොමැති බවත්ය.",
        "“මේ ආණ්ඩුව කරන මගඩියට අපි හවුල් වෙන්නේ නැහැ. අපි අතීතයේ මිනිසුන් සමඟ නැඟී සිටිමු, අපි ඔවුන් සමඟ දැන් සිටිමු, අනාගතයේදීත් එසේ කරන්නෙමු, ”ප්‍රේමදාස පැවසීය.",
        "ජනතා විමුක්‌ති පෙරමුණේ පාර්ලිමේන්තු මන්ත්‍රී අනුර කුමාර දිසානායක මහතා පැවසුවේ රජය ජනතාවගේ ප්‍රශ්න විසඳීමට නිශ්චිත වැඩපිළිවෙළක්‌ නොමැතිව කාලය කා දමමින් සිටින බවයි.",
        "“මෙම ගැටලුව ජය ගැනීමට රජය සැලසුම් කරන ආකාරය විස්තර කරන මාර්ග සිතියමක් අපට අවශ්‍යයි. එවැනි වැඩපිළිවෙලක් සභාව හමුවේ තබන්නේ නැත්නම් මෙහි වාද විවාද කිරීමෙන් පලක් නැහැ,” ඔහු පැවසීය.",
        "දිසානායක කියා සිටියේ ජනාධිපතිවරයා රූකඩයක් මිස අන් කිසිවක් නොවන බවත් ඔහුට ඉවත් වන ලෙස ජනතාව කරන ඉල්ලීම සාධාරණ බවත්ය.",
        "“ජනතාවගේ ප්‍රශ්නවලට විසඳුම් හොයන්න බැරි නම් එහෙම නායකයෙක් ඉඳලා තියෙන ප්‍රයෝජනය මොකක්ද? සර්ව පාක්ෂික ආණ්ඩුවක් පිහිටුවීමේ යෝජනා සියල්ල නොසලකා හරිමින් ජනාධිපතිවරයා රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතා පත් කළත් මාස එකහමාරක් ඇතුළත ජනතා ප්‍රශ්න විසඳීමට තමන්ටත් රජයටත් හැකියාවක් නොමැති බව පෙන්වා දී තිබෙනවා.” දිසානායක මහතා පැවසීය.",
        "සර්ව පාක්ෂික ආණ්ඩුවක් පිහිටුවීමේ යෝජනා ජනාධිපතිවරයා නොසලකා හැර ජනතාව ප්‍රතික්ෂේප කළ රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතා තෝරා ගත් බව පවසමින් ශ්‍රීලනිප පාර්ලිමේන්තු මන්ත්‍රී දයාසිරි ජයසේකර සහ පාර්ලිමේන්තු මන්ත්‍රී විමල් වීරවංශ යන මහත්වරුන්ගෙන්ද රජයට දැඩි විවේචන එල්ල විය.",
        "“අපි පාර්ලිමේන්තුව වර්ජනය කරන්නේ නැහැ. අපි දිගටම ඉඳලා මේ ආණ්ඩුව නිදිමතෙන් හොල්ලන්න උත්සාහ කරනවා” යැයි වීරවංශ මහතා පැවසීය.",
        "හාමුදුරුවෝ. මෙය ප‍්‍රජාතන්ත‍්‍ර විරෝධී ආණ්ඩුවක් බැවින් ජාත්‍යන්තරයෙන් ආධාර ලබාගැනීමට හැකියාවක් නොමැති බව අතුරලියේ රතන හිමියෝ පැවසූහ.",
        "“මේ ආණ්ඩුවට දිගටම බලයේ ඉන්න බැහැ. ඒක ජනතාව ප්‍රතික්ෂේප කරලා.” රතන හිමියෝ පැවසූහ."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "සමගි ජන බලවේගය",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "ජාතික ජනතා බලය",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "මෙම සතිය",
          "label": "DATE"
        },
        {
          "text": "රජය",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "විපක්ෂය සමගි ජන බලවේගය",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජ.වි.පෙ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජාතික ජනතා බලය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "කුටිය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඊයේ",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "මෙම සතිය",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "රතන හිමි",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "සජිත් ප්‍රේමදාස",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ප්‍රේමදාස ය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "අනුර කුමාර දිසානායක",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "නිවස",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "දිසානායක",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "මාස එකහමාරක්",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "දිසානායක",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රීලනිප",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "දයාසිරි ජයසේකර",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "විමල් වීරවංශ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "රතන හිමි",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "රතන හිමි",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "சமகி ஜன பலவேகய (SJB) மற்றும் ஜேவிபி தலைமையிலான தேசிய மக்கள் சக்தி (NPP) மற்றும் \"சுயேச்சை\" பாராளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர்களான சம்பிக்க ரணவக்க மற்றும் அத்துரெலிய ரதன தேரர் ஆகியோர் அரசாங்கத்திற்கு எதிராக இந்த வாரம் பாராளுமன்ற அமர்வுகளை புறக்கணிக்கப்போவதாக அறிவித்த பின்னர் வெளிநடப்பு செய்தனர்.",
      "author": "நிர்வாகி",
      "body_lines": [
        "பிரதான எதிர்க்கட்சியான சமகி ஜன பலவேகய (SJB), ஜேவிபி தலைமையிலான தேசிய மக்கள் சக்தி (NPP) மற்றும் பல சுயேச்சை எம்பிக்கள் இந்த வாரம் பாராளுமன்ற அமர்வுகளை புறக்கணிக்கப்போவதாக அறிவித்து நேற்று அவையில் இருந்து வெளிநடப்பு செய்தனர். மக்கள் எதிர்கொள்ளும் பிரச்சனைகள்.",
        "சுயேட்சை நாடாளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர்களான பாட்டலி சம்பிக்க ரணவக்க மற்றும் வண. அத்துரலியே ரதன தேரர்.",
        "SJB பாராளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர்கள் சபைகளை புறக்கணிக்கும் தீர்மானத்தை அறிவித்துள்ள எதிர்க்கட்சித் தலைவர் சஜித் பிரேமதாச, ஜனாதிபதி மற்றும் பிரதமர் இருவரும் தோல்வியடைந்தவர்கள் எனவும், அவர்களால் மக்களின் பிரச்சினைகளுக்கு தீர்வு இல்லை எனவும் தெரிவித்துள்ளார்.",
        "“இந்த அரசாங்கத்தால் இயற்றப்படும் ஊழலில் நாங்கள் ஒரு கட்சியாக இருக்க மாட்டோம். கடந்த காலத்தில் மக்களுடன் நாங்கள் எழுந்து நின்றோம், இப்போதும் அவர்களுடன் எழுந்து நிற்போம், எதிர்காலத்திலும் அதைச் செய்வோம் என பிரேமதாச கூறினார்.",
        "மக்களின் பிரச்சினைகளை தீர்ப்பதற்கு அரசாங்கம் குறிப்பிட்ட வேலைத்திட்டம் எதுவுமின்றி காலத்தை வீணடித்து வருவதாக ஜே.வி.பி பாராளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர் அனுரகுமார திஸாநாயக்க தெரிவித்துள்ளார்.",
        "“இந்தச் சிக்கலைச் சமாளிக்க அரசாங்கம் எவ்வாறு திட்டமிட்டுள்ளது என்பதை விவரிக்கும் ஒரு சாலை வரைபடத்தை நாங்கள் விரும்புகிறோம். இது போன்ற ஒரு நிகழ்ச்சியை அவையில் முன்வைக்காத வரை இங்கு விவாதம் நடத்துவதில் அர்த்தமில்லை,'' என்றார்.",
        "திஸாநாயக்க, ஜனாதிபதி ஒரு பொம்மையன்றி வேறில்லை எனவும், அவர் பதவி விலக வேண்டும் என மக்கள் முன்வைத்த கோரிக்கை நியாயமானது எனவும் தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "“மக்கள் பிரச்சினைகளுக்கு தீர்வு காண முடியாவிட்டால், இப்படிப்பட்ட ஒரு தலைவரால் என்ன பயன்? சர்வகட்சி அரசாங்கத்தை அமைப்பதற்கான அனைத்து முன்மொழிவுகளையும் ஜனாதிபதி புறக்கணித்து ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்கவை நியமித்தார், ஆனால் ஒன்றரை மாதங்களுக்குள் தானும் அரசாங்கமும் மக்களின் பிரச்சினைகளுக்குத் தீர்வு காண இயலாது என்பதை அவர் காட்டியுள்ளார்” என்று திஸாநாயக்க கூறினார்.",
        "ஸ்ரீலங்கா சுதந்திரக் கட்சியின் பாராளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர் தயாசிறி ஜயசேகர மற்றும் பாராளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர் விமல் வீரவன்ச ஆகியோரின் கடுமையான விமர்சனங்களுக்கு உள்ளாகிய அரசாங்கம், சர்வகட்சி அரசாங்கத்தை அமைக்கும் முன்மொழிவுகளை ஜனாதிபதி புறக்கணித்ததாகவும், மக்களால் நிராகரிக்கப்பட்ட ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்கவை தெரிவு செய்ததாகவும் கூறியுள்ளனர்.",
        "“நாங்கள் பாராளுமன்றத்தை புறக்கணிக்க மாட்டோம். நாங்கள் தொடர்ந்து இந்த அரசாங்கத்தை உறக்கத்தில் இருந்து அசைக்க முயற்சிப்போம்” என வீரவன்ச கூறினார்.",
        "வண. இது ஜனநாயக விரோத அரசாங்கம் எனவும், எனவே சர்வதேச சமூகத்தின் உதவிகளை பெற முடியாது எனவும் அத்துரலியே ரதன தேரர் தெரிவித்துள்ளார்.",
        "“இந்த அரசாங்கம் பதவியில் நீடிப்பது சாத்தியமில்லை. அது மக்களால் நிராகரிக்கப்பட்டுள்ளது” என ரதன தேரர் கூறினார்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "சமகி ஜன பலவேகயா",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "தேசிய மக்கள் சக்தி",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "இந்த வாரம்",
          "label": "DATE"
        },
        {
          "text": "அரசு",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "எதிர்க்கட்சி சமகி ஜன பலவேகயா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜே.வி.பி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "தேசிய மக்கள் சக்தி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "அறை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "நேற்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்த வாரம்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ரதன தேரர்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "சஜித் பிரேமதாச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பிரேமதாச",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "அனுரகுமார திஸாநாயக்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "வீடு",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "திசாநாயக்க",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஒன்றரை மாதங்கள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "திசாநாயக்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஸ்ரீ.ல.சு.க",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "தயாசிறி ஜயசேகர",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "விமல் வீரவன்ச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ரதன தேரர்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ரதன தேரர்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}