{
  "newspaper_id": "economy-next-com",
  "url": "https://economynext.com/protestors-march-to-sri-lanka-prime-ministers-office-facing-police-tear-gas-97328/",
  "time_ut": 1657689960,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Protestors march to Sri Lanka prime minister’s office facing police tear gas",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Protestors march to Sri Lanka prime minister’s office facing police tear gas",
      "author": "Chanka Jayasinghe",
      "body_lines": [
        "ECONOMYNEXT – Sri Lanka police fired teargas at protestors marching to the Prime Minister’s office located on Flower Road, Colombo, after reports emerged that President Gotabaya Rajapaksa fled the country leading to speculation that Prime Minister Ranil Wickremesinghe will be sworn in as Acting President.",
        "The protestors have managed to break through a police barricade near the PM’s office, despite tear gas and water canon fire.",
        "The protestors are now heading towards the PM’s office. (Colombo/Jul13/2022)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Sri Lanka",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Flower Road",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "Gotabaya Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "PM",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Colombo/Jul13/2022",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "විරෝධතාකරුවෝ පොලිස් කඳුළු ගෑස්වලට මුහුණ දෙමින් ශ්‍රී ලංකා අගමැති කාර්යාලය වෙත පා ගමනක් ගියහ",
      "author": "චංක ජයසිංහ",
      "body_lines": [
        "EconomyNext - අගමැති රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ වැඩබලන ජනාධිපතිවරයා ලෙස දිවුරුම් දෙනු ඇතැයි අනුමාන කරමින් ජනාධිපති ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ රටින් පලා ගිය බවට වාර්තා වීමත් සමඟ කොළඹ මල් පාරේ පිහිටි අග්‍රාමාත්‍ය කාර්යාලය වෙත පාගමනින් පැමිණි විරෝධතාකරුවන්ට ශ්‍රී ලංකා පොලිසිය කඳුළු ගෑස් ප්‍රහාරයක් එල්ල කළේය.",
        "කඳුළු ගෑස් සහ ජල ප්‍රහාර නොතකා අගමැති කාර්යාලය අසල තිබූ පොලිස් බාධක බිඳ දැමීමට විරෝධතාකරුවන් සමත් වී තිබේ.",
        "විරෝධතාකරුවන් දැන් අගමැති කාර්යාලය දෙසට යමින් සිටිති. (කොළඹ/ජූලි13/2022)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මල් පාර",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "PM",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "කොළඹ/ජූලි13/2022",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "சிறிலங்கா பிரதமர் அலுவலகத்தை நோக்கி ஆர்ப்பாட்டக்காரர்கள் பொலிஸ் கண்ணீர் புகைக்குண்டுகளை எதிர்கொண்டனர்",
      "author": "சங்க ஜெயசிங்க",
      "body_lines": [
        "பொருளாதாரம் - ஜனாதிபதி கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ச நாட்டை விட்டு வெளியேறியதாக வெளியான செய்திகளை அடுத்து, பிரதமர் ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க பதில் ஜனாதிபதியாக பதவிப் பிரமாணம் செய்து கொள்வார் என்ற ஊகங்களைத் தொடர்ந்து, கொழும்பு மலர் வீதியில் அமைந்துள்ள பிரதமர் அலுவலகத்திற்கு பேரணியாகச் சென்ற ஆர்ப்பாட்டக்காரர்கள் மீது இலங்கை பொலிஸார் கண்ணீர் புகை குண்டுகளை வீசினர்.",
        "கண்ணீர் புகை குண்டுகள் மற்றும் தண்ணீர் கேன்களை வீசிய போதிலும், போராட்டக்காரர்கள் பிரதமர் அலுவலகத்திற்கு அருகே இருந்த போலீஸ் தடுப்புகளை உடைத்துச் சென்றனர்.",
        "போராட்டக்காரர்கள் இப்போது பிரதமர் அலுவலகம் நோக்கிச் செல்கின்றனர். (கொழும்பு/ஜூலை13/2022)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "இலங்கை",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "மலர் சாலை",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "மாலை",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "கொழும்பு/ஜூலை13/2022",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}