{
  "newspaper_id": "ada-derana-lk",
  "url": "http://www.adaderana.lk/news/84686/imf-deal-a-testimony-of-govts-commitment-to-carry-out-necessary-reforms-president",
  "time_ut": 1662027180,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "IMF deal a testimony of govt’s commitment to carry out necessary reforms – President",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "IMF deal a testimony of govt’s commitment to carry out necessary reforms – President",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "Reacting to Sri Lanka’s staff-level agreement with the International Monetary Fund (IMF) for a loan of about $2.9 billion, President Ranil Wickremesinghe said the agreement is a testimony of the government’s commitment to carry out the necessary reforms to offer a better life to Sri Lankan citizens.",
        "He said it paves the way for the provision of financial support from the IMF and other development partners that should help the country to address current external imbalances and to restart Sri Lanka’s growth engine.",
        "“I am grateful to the IMF team, the Ministry of Finance and the Central Bank of Sri Lanka for the hard work and dedication shown to come to that agreement in record time,” he said.",
        "The authorities of the Democratic Socialist Republic of Sri Lanka announced today that they have reached Staff-Level Agreement with the IMF on a four-year program to be supported by an arrangement under the Extended Fund Facility (EFF) in the amount of about US$ 2.9 billion.",
        "The announcement was made at the end of the mission conducted from August 24 in Colombo, where the IMF staff team for Sri Lanka held numerous meetings with the Ministry of Finance and the Central Bank of Sri Lanka to agree a package of reforms aimed at restoring macroeconomic stability and public finance sustainability in the country.",
        "Upon the announcement, Ranil Wickremesinghe, the President of Sri Lanka and Minister of Finance, issued the following statement: “This agreement is a testimony of our commitment to carry out the necessary reforms to offer a better life to our fellow citizens. It paves the way for the provision of financial support from the IMF and other development partners that should help us to address current external imbalances and to restart our growth engine. I am grateful to the IMF team, the Ministry of Finance and the Central Bank of Sri Lanka for the hard work and dedication shown to come to that agreement in record time”.",
        "The agreed economic reform package is designed to address comprehensively the challenges currently faced by Sri Lanka. The Program’s objectives are (i) to restore public finance sustainability through fiscal adjustment and debt restructuring, while protecting the most vulnerable and preserving financial stability, (ii) to bring back price stability and build external buffers, and (iii) to unlock the country’s growth potential through structural reforms and improvement in governance.",
        "Reaching Staff Level Agreement with the IMF was one of the immediate objectives of the Government and a directive by the President since he was elected last month, the Finance Minister said in a statement.",
        "The Sri Lankan government will now work on implementing the prior actions agreed under the Staff Level Agreement and on securing the financing assurances needed from Sri Lanka’s official bilateral creditors in order to obtain adoption of the Program by the IMF Executive Board, it said.",
        "Sri Lankan authorities have been working with their international financial and legal advisors on their debt restructuring strategy. The authorities further intend to make a presentation to creditors in the next few weeks to update them on the most recent macroeconomic developments in the country, the main areas of the reform package agreed with the IMF staff and the next steps of the debt restructuring process, the statement added."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the International Monetary Fund",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "about $2.9 billion",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lankan",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "IMF",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the Ministry of Finance",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Central Bank of Sri Lanka",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the Democratic Socialist Republic of Sri Lanka",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "IMF",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "four-year",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Extended Fund Facility",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "EFF",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "about US$ 2.9 billion",
            "label": "MONEY"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "August 24",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Colombo",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "IMF",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Ministry of Finance",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Central Bank of Sri Lanka",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "IMF",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Ministry of Finance",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Central Bank of Sri Lanka",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Program",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "last month",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Finance",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lankan",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka’s",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the IMF Executive Board",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lankan",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "the next few weeks",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "IMF",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "අවශ්‍ය ප්‍රතිසංස්කරණ සිදුකිරීමට රජයේ කැපවීම පිළිබඳ IMF සාක්ෂියක් - ජනපති",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "ඩොලර් බිලියන 2.9 ක පමණ ණයක් සඳහා ජාත්‍යන්තර මූල්‍ය අරමුදල (IMF) සමඟ ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ කාර්ය මණ්ඩල මට්ටමේ ගිවිසුමට ප්‍රතිචාර දක්වමින් ජනාධිපති රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතා, මෙම ගිවිසුම ශ්‍රී ලංකාවට යහපත් ජීවිතයක් ලබා දීම සඳහා අවශ්‍ය ප්‍රතිසංස්කරණ සිදු කිරීමට රජය දක්වන කැපවීම පිළිබඳ සාක්ෂියක් බව පැවසීය. ලංකා පුරවැසියන්.",
        "වත්මන් බාහිර අසමතුලිතතාවයන් විසඳීමට සහ ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ වර්ධන එන්ජිම නැවත ආරම්භ කිරීමට රටට උපකාර කළ යුතු ජාත්‍යන්තර මූල්‍ය අරමුදලේ සහ අනෙකුත් සංවර්ධන හවුල්කරුවන්ගේ මූල්‍ය ආධාර සැපයීමට එය මග පාදයි.",
        "\"වාර්තාගත කාලයකින් එම ගිවිසුමට එළැඹීමට දැක්වූ වෙහෙස සහ කැපවීම පිළිබඳව IMF කණ්ඩායමට, මුදල් අමාත්‍යාංශයට සහ ශ්‍රී ලංකා මහ බැංකුවට මම කෘතඥ වෙනවා,\" ඔහු පැවසීය.",
        "ඇ.ඩො. බිලියන 2.9 කි.",
        "සාර්ව ආර්ථිකය යථා තත්ත්වයට පත් කිරීම අරමුණු කරගත් ප්‍රතිසංස්කරණ පැකේජයකට එකඟ වීම සඳහා ශ්‍රී ලංකාව සඳහා වූ IMF කාර්ය මණ්ඩල කණ්ඩායම මුදල් අමාත්‍යාංශය සහ ශ්‍රී ලංකා මහ බැංකුව සමඟ රැස්වීම් ගණනාවක් පැවැත්වූ අතර එහිදී අගෝස්තු 24 සිට කොළඹදී පවත්වන ලද මෙහෙයුම අවසානයේ මෙම නිවේදනය නිකුත් කරන ලදී. රටේ ස්ථාවරත්වය සහ රාජ්‍ය මූල්‍ය තිරසාරත්වය.",
        "නිවේදනයෙන් පසු ශ්‍රී ලංකා ජනාධිපති සහ මුදල් අමාත්‍ය රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතා පහත ප්‍රකාශය නිකුත් කළේය: “මෙම ගිවිසුම අපගේ සහෝදර පුරවැසියන්ට වඩා හොඳ ජීවිතයක් ලබා දීම සඳහා අවශ්‍ය ප්‍රතිසංස්කරණ සිදු කිරීමට අපගේ කැපවීම පිළිබඳ සාක්ෂියකි. වත්මන් බාහිර අසමතුලිතතාවයන් විසඳීමට සහ අපගේ වර්ධන එන්ජිම නැවත ආරම්භ කිරීමට අපට උපකාර කළ යුතු IMF සහ අනෙකුත් සංවර්ධන හවුල්කරුවන්ගෙන් මූල්‍ය ආධාර සැපයීමට එය මග පාදයි. IMF කණ්ඩායමට, මුදල් අමාත්‍යාංශයට සහ ශ්‍රී ලංකා මහ බැංකුවට මම කෘතඥ වෙනවා වාර්තාගත කාලයකින් එම ගිවිසුමට එළැඹීමට දැක්වූ වෙහෙස සහ කැපවීම පිළිබඳව.”",
        "එකඟ වූ ආර්ථික ප්‍රතිසංස්කරණ පැකේජය නිර්මාණය කර ඇත්තේ ශ්‍රී ලංකාව දැනට මුහුණ දී සිටින අභියෝගවලට පුළුල් ලෙස ආමන්ත්‍රණය කිරීම සඳහා ය. වැඩසටහනේ අරමුණු වනුයේ (i) මූල්‍ය ගැලපීම් සහ ණය ප්‍රතිව්‍යුහගත කිරීම තුළින් රාජ්‍ය මූල්‍ය තිරසාරභාවය ප්‍රතිෂ්ඨාපනය කිරීම, වඩාත්ම අවදානමට ලක්විය හැකි සහ මූල්‍ය ස්ථායීතාවය ආරක්ෂා කරන අතරම, (ii) මිල ස්ථායීතාවය නැවත ගෙන ඒම සහ බාහිර බෆර ගොඩනැගීම සහ (iii) රටේ අගුලු හැරීමයි. ව්‍යුහාත්මක ප්‍රතිසංස්කරණ සහ පාලනය වැඩිදියුණු කිරීම තුළින් වර්ධන විභවය.",
        "ජාත්‍යන්තර මූල්‍ය අරමුදල සමඟ මාණ්ඩලික මට්ටමේ ගිවිසුමකට එළැඹීම රජයේ ආසන්නතම අරමුණක් වූ අතර පසුගිය මාසයේ ජනාධිපති ධුරයට පත් වූ දා සිට ජනාධිපතිවරයාගේ නියෝගයක් බව මුදල් අමාත්‍යවරයා නිවේදනයක් නිකුත් කරමින් කියා සිටියේය.",
        "මාණ්ඩලික මට්ටමේ ගිවිසුම යටතේ එකඟ වූ පූර්ව ක්‍රියාමාර්ග ක්‍රියාත්මක කිරීමට සහ IMF විධායක මණ්ඩලය විසින් වැඩසටහන සම්මත කර ගැනීම සඳහා ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ නිල ද්විපාර්ශ්වික ණය හිමියන්ගෙන් අවශ්‍ය මූල්‍ය සහතික ලබා ගැනීමට ශ්‍රී ලංකා රජය දැන් කටයුතු කරනු ඇති බව එහි සඳහන් වේ.",
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකා බලධාරීන් ඔවුන්ගේ ණය ප්‍රතිව්‍යුහගත කිරීමේ උපාය මාර්ගය සම්බන්ධයෙන් ඔවුන්ගේ ජාත්‍යන්තර මූල්‍ය සහ නීති උපදේශකයන් සමඟ කටයුතු කරමින් සිටිති. රටේ නවතම සාර්ව ආර්ථික වර්ධනයන්, ජාත්‍යන්තර මූල්‍ය අරමුදලේ කාර්ය මණ්ඩලය සමඟ එකඟ වූ ප්‍රතිසංස්කරණ පැකේජයේ ප්‍රධාන ක්ෂේත්‍ර සහ ණය ප්‍රතිව්‍යුහගත කිරීමේ ක්‍රියාවලියේ මීළඟ පියවර පිළිබඳව යාවත්කාලීන කිරීම සඳහා ඉදිරි සති කිහිපය තුළ ණය හිමියන් වෙත ඉදිරිපත් කිරීමක් කිරීමට බලධාරීන් තවදුරටත් අදහස් කරයි. ප්රකාශය වැඩිදුරටත් සඳහන් කළේය."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජාත්‍යන්තර මුල්‍ය අරමුදල",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඩොලර් බිලියන 2.9 ක් පමණ",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලාංකික",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "IMF",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "මුදල් අමාත්යාංශය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකා මහ බැංකුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකා ප්‍රජාතාන්ත්‍රික සමාජවාදී ජනරජය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "IMF",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "අවුරුදු හතරක්",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "විස්තීරණ අරමුදල් පහසුකම",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "EFF",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඇමරිකානු ඩොලර් බිලියන 2.9 ක් පමණ වේ",
            "label": "MONEY"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "අගෝස්තු 24",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "කොළඹ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "IMF",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මුදල් අමාත්යාංශය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකා මහ බැංකුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "IMF",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "මුදල් අමාත්යාංශය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකා මහ බැංකුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "වැඩසටහන",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "පසුගිය මාසයේ",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මූල්ය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලාංකික",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "IMF විධායක මණ්ඩලය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලාංකික",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉදිරි සති කිහිපය",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "IMF",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "தேவையான சீர்திருத்தங்களை மேற்கொள்வதற்கான அரசாங்கத்தின் உறுதிப்பாட்டின் சாட்சியமாக IMF ஒப்பந்தம் - ஜனாதிபதி",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "சுமார் 2.9 பில்லியன் டொலர் கடனுக்காக சர்வதேச நாணய நிதியத்துடன் (IMF) இலங்கை மேற்கொண்டுள்ள ஊழியர் மட்ட ஒப்பந்தத்திற்கு பதிலளித்த ஜனாதிபதி ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க, இலங்கைக்கு சிறந்த வாழ்க்கையை வழங்குவதற்கு தேவையான சீர்திருத்தங்களை மேற்கொள்வதற்கான அரசாங்கத்தின் அர்ப்பணிப்புக்கு இந்த ஒப்பந்தம் சாட்சியமாகும் என்றார். இலங்கை குடிமக்கள்.",
        "சர்வதேச நாணய நிதியம் மற்றும் ஏனைய அபிவிருத்தி பங்காளிகளிடமிருந்து நிதி உதவிகளை வழங்குவதற்கு இது வழி வகுத்து, தற்போதைய வெளிப்புற ஏற்றத்தாழ்வுகளை நிவர்த்தி செய்வதற்கும் இலங்கையின் வளர்ச்சி இயந்திரத்தை மீள ஆரம்பிப்பதற்கும் நாட்டுக்கு உதவுவதாக அவர் கூறினார்.",
        "\"இந்த ஒப்பந்தத்தை சாதனை நேரத்தில் எட்டுவதற்கு காட்டிய கடின உழைப்பு மற்றும் அர்ப்பணிப்புக்காக IMF குழு, நிதி அமைச்சகம் மற்றும் இலங்கை மத்திய வங்கி ஆகியவற்றுக்கு நான் நன்றி கூறுகிறேன்,\" என்று அவர் கூறினார்.",
        "இலங்கை ஜனநாயக சோசலிசக் குடியரசின் அதிகாரிகள், IMF உடன் நான்காண்டு கால வேலைத்திட்டத்தில் பணியாளர்கள் மட்ட உடன்படிக்கையை எட்டியுள்ளதாக இன்று அறிவித்துள்ளனர். 2.9 பில்லியன்.",
        "ஆகஸ்ட் 24 முதல் கொழும்பில் நடத்தப்பட்ட பணியின் முடிவில் இந்த அறிவிப்பு வெளியிடப்பட்டது, அங்கு இலங்கைக்கான IMF ஊழியர்கள் குழு நிதி அமைச்சகம் மற்றும் இலங்கை மத்திய வங்கியுடன் பல சந்திப்புகளை நடத்தியது. நாட்டில் ஸ்திரத்தன்மை மற்றும் பொது நிதி நிலைத்தன்மை.",
        "இந்த அறிவிப்பின் பேரில், சிறிலங்காவின் ஜனாதிபதியும் நிதி அமைச்சருமான ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க பின்வரும் அறிக்கையை வெளியிட்டார்: “எமது சக குடிமக்களுக்கு சிறந்த வாழ்க்கையை வழங்குவதற்கு தேவையான சீர்திருத்தங்களை மேற்கொள்வதற்கான எங்களின் அர்ப்பணிப்புக்கு இந்த ஒப்பந்தம் ஒரு சாட்சி. இது தற்போதைய வெளிப்புற ஏற்றத்தாழ்வுகளை நிவர்த்தி செய்வதற்கும் நமது வளர்ச்சி இயந்திரத்தை மறுதொடக்கம் செய்வதற்கும் உதவும் IMF மற்றும் பிற மேம்பாட்டு பங்காளிகளிடமிருந்து நிதி உதவியை வழங்குவதற்கு வழி வகுக்கிறது. சாதனை நேரத்தில் அந்த உடன்படிக்கைக்கு வருவதற்கு காட்டிய கடின உழைப்பு மற்றும் அர்ப்பணிப்புக்காக IMF குழு, நிதி அமைச்சகம் மற்றும் இலங்கை மத்திய வங்கி ஆகியோருக்கு நான் நன்றி கூறுகிறேன்”.",
        "ஒப்புக்கொள்ளப்பட்ட பொருளாதார சீர்திருத்தப் பொதியானது தற்போது இலங்கை எதிர்கொள்ளும் சவால்களை விரிவாக எதிர்கொள்ளும் வகையில் வடிவமைக்கப்பட்டுள்ளது. திட்டத்தின் நோக்கங்கள் (i) நிதி சரிசெய்தல் மற்றும் கடன் மறுசீரமைப்பு மூலம் பொது நிதி நிலைத்தன்மையை மீட்டெடுப்பது, அதே நேரத்தில் மிகவும் பாதிக்கப்படக்கூடிய மற்றும் நிதி ஸ்திரத்தன்மையைப் பாதுகாத்தல், (ii) விலை ஸ்திரத்தன்மையை மீண்டும் கொண்டு வருதல் மற்றும் வெளிப்புற இடையகங்களை உருவாக்குதல் மற்றும் (iii) நாட்டின் பூட்டைத் திறப்பது. கட்டமைப்பு சீர்திருத்தங்கள் மற்றும் நிர்வாகத்தில் முன்னேற்றம் மூலம் வளர்ச்சி சாத்தியம்.",
        "IMF உடனான பணியாளர் நிலை ஒப்பந்தத்தை எட்டுவது அரசாங்கத்தின் உடனடி நோக்கங்களில் ஒன்றாகும் மற்றும் கடந்த மாதம் அவர் தேர்ந்தெடுக்கப்பட்டதிலிருந்து ஜனாதிபதியின் உத்தரவு என்று நிதி அமைச்சர் ஒரு அறிக்கையில் தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "பணியாளர் மட்ட உடன்படிக்கையின் கீழ் ஒப்புக் கொள்ளப்பட்ட முன்னைய நடவடிக்கைகளை நடைமுறைப்படுத்துவதற்கும் இலங்கையின் உத்தியோகபூர்வ இருதரப்பு கடனாளர்களிடமிருந்து தேவையான நிதி உத்தரவாதங்களைப் பெற்றுக்கொள்வதற்கும் இலங்கை அரசாங்கம் இப்போது வேலை செய்யும்.",
        "இலங்கை அதிகாரிகள் தமது சர்வதேச நிதி மற்றும் சட்ட ஆலோசகர்களுடன் தமது கடன் மறுசீரமைப்பு மூலோபாயத்தில் செயற்பட்டு வருகின்றனர். நாட்டின் மிக சமீபத்திய மேக்ரோ பொருளாதார முன்னேற்றங்கள், IMF ஊழியர்களுடன் ஒப்புக்கொள்ளப்பட்ட சீர்திருத்தப் பொதியின் முக்கிய பகுதிகள் மற்றும் கடன் மறுசீரமைப்பு செயல்முறையின் அடுத்த படிகள் குறித்து அடுத்த சில வாரங்களில் கடன் வழங்குநர்களுக்கு விளக்கமளிக்க அதிகாரிகள் உத்தேசித்துள்ளனர். அறிக்கை மேலும் கூறியது."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சர்வதேச நாணய நிதியம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "சுமார் $2.9 பில்லியன்",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "IMF",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "நிதி அமைச்சகம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை மத்திய வங்கி",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை ஜனநாயக சோசலிச குடியரசு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "IMF",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "நான்கு ஆண்டுகள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "விரிவாக்கப்பட்ட நிதி வசதி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "EFF",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "சுமார் 2.9 பில்லியன் அமெரிக்க டாலர்கள்",
            "label": "MONEY"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஆகஸ்ட் 24",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "கொழும்பு",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "IMF",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "நிதி அமைச்சகம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை மத்திய வங்கி",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "IMF",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "நிதி அமைச்சகம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை மத்திய வங்கி",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "நிரல்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "கடந்த மாதம்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "நிதி",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கையின்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "IMF நிர்வாக வாரியம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "அடுத்த சில வாரங்கள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "IMF",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}