{
  "newspaper_id": "ada-derana-lk",
  "url": "http://www.adaderana.lk/news/83714/parliament-entry-roads-closed-off-as-security-tightened",
  "time_ut": 1658112540,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Parliament entry roads closed off as security tightened",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Parliament entry roads closed off as security tightened",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "The security around the Parliament complex has been tightened and all the entry roads leading to it have been closed off with roadblocks, according to Ada Derana reporter.",
        "Meanwhile, the Parliament is scheduled to convene tomorrow (19) at 10.00 a.m. chaired by the Speaker Mahinda Yapa Abeywardena.",
        "Due to the current political crisis in the country, the calling of nominations to appoint a successor president is scheduled to be held tomorrow.",
        "The voting related to this will be held as a secret ballot in the Parliament the next day (20).",
        "It has already been announced that five members, including Acting President Ranil Wickramasinghe and Opposition Leader Sajith Premadasa, will contest the election to appoint the successor president.",
        "Accordingly, tomorrow, their nominations will be handed over to the General Secretary of the Parliament and then he will announce it before the Parliament.",
        "The candidate who gets more than 50 percent of the votes of the Members of Parliament who will vote on the day of the polling will be elected as the new president.",
        "Each political party in the parliament has already announced the candidate they will support while the SLFP has said it will abstain from voting.",
        "It is said that the votes of the members of the Sri Lanka Podujana Peramuna (SLPP), which controls the majority power in the Parliament, is a strong factor in electing the new president.",
        "SLPP has 145 parliamentary seats in the current parliament and Samagi Jana Balawegaya (SJB) has 54 parliamentary seats.",
        "Illankai Tamil Arasu Kadchi (ITAK) has 10 seats, National People’s Power (NPP) has 3 seats, Eelam People’s Party and Akila Ilankei Tamil Congress have 2 seats each.",
        "Apart from this, Tamil Makkal Vidudalep Pulikal (TMVP), Sri Lanka Freedom Party (SLFP), Muslim National Alliance, Tamil Makkal Thesia Kuttani, Ahila Ilangei Mahajana Congress, National Congress, Sri Lanka Muslim Congress, United National Party and Ape Janabala Pakshaya have one seat each."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Parliament",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ada Derana",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "tomorrow",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "19",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "10.00 a.m.",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "Mahinda Yapa Abeywardena",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "tomorrow",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the next day",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "20",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "five",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickramasinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Opposition",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sajith Premadasa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "tomorrow",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "more than 50 percent",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the day",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "SLFP",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "Podujana Peramuna",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "145",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Samagi",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Jana Balawegaya",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "SJB",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "54",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Illankai Tamil",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Arasu Kadchi",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ITAK",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "10",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "National People’s Power",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "NPP",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "3",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Eelam People’s Party",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Akila Ilankei Tamil Congress",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "2",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Tamil Makkal",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Vidudalep Pulikal",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "TMVP",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka Freedom Party",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Muslim National Alliance",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Tamil Makkal",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Thesia Kuttani",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "Mahajana Congress",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "National Congress",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka Muslim Congress",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "United National Party",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ape Janabala Pakshaya",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "one",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "ආරක්ෂාව තර කිරීමත් සමඟ පාර්ලිමේන්තුවට ඇතුළු වන මාර්ග වසා දැමිණි",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "පාර්ලිමේන්තු සංකීර්ණය අවට ආරක්ෂාව තර කර ඇති අතර ඒ වෙත පිවිසෙන සියලුම පිවිසුම් මාර්ග මාර්ග බාධක යොදා වසා දමා ඇති බව අද දෙරණ වාර්තාකරු පවසයි.",
        "මේ අතර, පාර්ලිමේන්තුව හෙට (19) පෙරවරු 10.00ට කථානායක මහින්ද යාපා අබේවර්ධන මහතාගේ ප්‍රධානත්වයෙන් රැස්වීමට නියමිතය.",
        "රට තුළ පවතින දේශපාලන අර්බුදය හේතුවෙන් අනුප්‍රාප්තික ජනාධිපතිවරයෙකු පත් කිරීම සඳහා නාමයෝජනා කැඳවීම හෙට සිදුකිරීමට නියමිතයි.",
        "ඊට අදාළ ඡන්ද විමසීම අනිද්දා (20) පාර්ලිමේන්තුවේදී රහස් ඡන්දයක් ලෙස පැවැත්වීමට නියමිතය.",
        "අනුප්‍රාප්තික ජනාධිපතිවරයා පත් කිරීම සඳහා වැඩබලන ජනාධිපති රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ, විපක්ෂ නායක සජිත් ප්‍රේමදාස ඇතුළු මන්ත්‍රීවරුන් පස් දෙනෙකු මැතිවරණයට ඉදිරිපත් වන බව දැනටමත් ප්‍රකාශ කර තිබේ.",
        "ඒ අනුව හෙට දිනයේ ඔවුන්ගේ නාමයෝජනා පාර්ලිමේන්තු මහලේකම්වරයා වෙත භාරදීමට නියමිත අතර ඉන් අනතුරුව ඔහු එය පාර්ලිමේන්තුව හමුවේ ප්‍රකාශ කිරීමට නියමිතයි.",
        "ඡන්ද විමසීම පැවැත්වෙන දිනයේ ඡන්දය ප්‍රකාශ කරන මන්ත්‍රීවරුන්ගේ ඡන්දවලින් සියයට 50කට වැඩි ඡන්ද ප්‍රතිශතයක් ලබා ගන්නා අපේක්ෂකයා නව ජනාධිපතිවරයා ලෙස තේරී පත් වේ.",
        "පාර්ලිමේන්තුවේ සෑම දේශපාලන පක්ෂයක්ම තමන් සහාය දෙන අපේක්ෂකයා මේ වන විට ප්‍රකාශයට පත් කර ඇති අතර ශ්‍රී ලංකා නිදහස් පක්ෂය ඡන්දය ප්‍රකාශ කිරීමෙන් වැළකී සිටින බව පවසා තිබේ.",
        "පාර්ලිමේන්තුවේ බහුතර බලය හිමි ශ්‍රී ලංකා පොදුජන පෙරමුණේ (SLPP) මන්ත්‍රීවරුන්ගේ ඡන්දය නව ජනාධිපතිවරයා තෝරා ගැනීමට ප්‍රබල සාධකයක් බව පැවසේ.",
        "වත්මන් පාර්ලිමේන්තුවේ ශ්‍රී ලංකා පොදුජන පෙරමුණට පාර්ලිමේන්තු ආසන 145ක් ඇති අතර සමගි ජන බලවේගයට (SJB) පාර්ලිමේන්තු ආසන 54ක් ඇත.",
        "Ilankai Tamil Arasu Kadchi (ITAK) ආසන 10, ජාතික ජනතා බලය (NPP) ආසන 3, ඊළාම් ජනතා පක්ෂය සහ අකිල ඉලංකෙයි තමිල් කොංග්‍රසයට ආසන 2 බැගින් හිමි වේ.",
        "මීට අමතරව තමිල් මක්කල් විඩුදලෙප් පුලිකල් (ටීඑම්වීපී), ශ්‍රී ලංකා නිදහස් පක්ෂය, මුස්ලිම් ජාතික සන්ධානය, තමිල් මක්කල් තේසියා කුට්ටනි, අහිල ඉලංගෙයි මහජන කොංග්‍රසය, ජාතික කොංග්‍රසය, ශ්‍රී ලංකා මුස්ලිම් කොංග්‍රසය, එක්සත් ජාතික පක්ෂය සහ අපේ ජනබල පක්ෂය එක් ආසනයක් බැගින්."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "අද දෙරණ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "හෙට",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "19",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "10.00 පෙ.ව.",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "මහින්ද යාපා අබේවර්ධන",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "හෙට",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඊළඟ දිනය",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "20",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "පහ",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "විපක්ෂ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "සජිත් ප්‍රේමදාස",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "හෙට",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "සියයට 50කට වඩා වැඩියි",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "දවස",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රීලනිප",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "පොදුජන පෙරමුණ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "145",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "සමගි",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජන බලවේගය",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "එස්.ජේ.බී",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "54",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ඉලංකෙයි දෙමළ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Arasu Kadchi",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ITAK",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "10",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජාතික ජනතා බලය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "එන්පීපී",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "3",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඊළාම් ජනතා පක්ෂය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "අකිල ඉලංකෙයි දෙමළ කොංග්‍රසය",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "2",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "දෙමළ මක්කල්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "විඩුඩලෙප් පුලිකල්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ටීඑම්වීපී",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකා නිදහස් පක්ෂය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "මුස්ලිම් ජාතික සන්ධානය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "දෙමළ මක්කල්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "තීසියා කුට්ටනි",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "මහජන කොංග්‍රසය",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජාතික කොංග්රසය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකා මුස්ලිම් කොංග්‍රසය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "එක්සත් ජාතික පක්ෂය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "අපේ ජනබල පක්ෂය",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "එක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "பாதுகாப்பு பலப்படுத்தப்பட்டதால், நாடாளுமன்ற நுழைவுச் சாலைகள் மூடப்பட்டன",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "நாடாளுமன்ற வளாகத்தைச் சுற்றி பாதுகாப்பு பலப்படுத்தப்பட்டுள்ளதுடன், அதற்குச் செல்லும் அனைத்து நுழைவு வீதிகளும் வீதித் தடைகளால் மூடப்பட்டுள்ளதாக அத தெரண செய்தியாளர் தெரிவித்துள்ளார்.",
        "இதேவேளை, பாராளுமன்றம் நாளை (19) காலை 10.00 மணிக்கு சபாநாயகர் மஹிந்த யாப்பா அபேவர்தன தலைமையில் கூடவுள்ளது.",
        "நாட்டில் தற்போது நிலவும் அரசியல் நெருக்கடி காரணமாக வாரிசான ஜனாதிபதியை நியமிப்பதற்கான வேட்புமனு தாக்கல் நாளை நடைபெறவுள்ளது.",
        "இது தொடர்பான வாக்கெடுப்பு நாளை மறுதினம் (20) பாராளுமன்றத்தில் இரகசிய வாக்கெடுப்பாக நடைபெறவுள்ளது.",
        "பதில் ஜனாதிபதியை நியமிப்பதற்காக, பதில் ஜனாதிபதி ரணில் விக்ரமசிங்க, எதிர்க்கட்சித் தலைவர் சஜித் பிரேமதாச உள்ளிட்ட ஐந்து உறுப்பினர்கள் தேர்தலில் போட்டியிடவுள்ளதாக ஏற்கனவே அறிவிக்கப்பட்டுள்ளது.",
        "அதன்படி, நாளை அவர்களது வேட்புமனுக்கள் நாடாளுமன்ற பொதுச் செயலாளரிடம் கையளிக்கப்பட்டு, அதன்பின்னர் நாடாளுமன்றத்தில் அவர் அறிவிப்பார்.",
        "வாக்களிக்கும் நாளில் வாக்களிக்கும் பாராளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர்களின் 50 சதவீதத்திற்கும் அதிகமான வாக்குகளைப் பெறும் வேட்பாளர் புதிய ஜனாதிபதியாகத் தெரிவு செய்யப்படுவார்.",
        "பாராளுமன்றத்தில் உள்ள ஒவ்வொரு அரசியல் கட்சிகளும் தாம் ஆதரிக்கும் வேட்பாளரை ஏற்கனவே அறிவித்துவிட்ட நிலையில், ஸ்ரீலங்கா சுதந்திரக் கட்சி வாக்களிப்பில் இருந்து விலகிக் கொள்வதாக கூறியுள்ளது.",
        "பாராளுமன்றத்தில் பெரும்பான்மை பலத்தை கட்டுப்படுத்தும் ஸ்ரீலங்கா பொதுஜன பெரமுன (SLPP) உறுப்பினர்களின் வாக்குகள் புதிய ஜனாதிபதியை தெரிவு செய்வதற்கு பலமான காரணியாக அமைந்துள்ளதாக கூறப்படுகிறது.",
        "தற்போதைய பாராளுமன்றத்தில் SLPP 145 பாராளுமன்ற இடங்களையும், சமகி ஜன பலவேகய (SJB) 54 பாராளுமன்ற இடங்களையும் கொண்டுள்ளது.",
        "இலங்கை தமிழ் அரசு கட்சி (ஐடிஏகே) 10 இடங்களையும், தேசிய மக்கள் சக்தி (என்பிபி) 3 இடங்களையும், ஈழ மக்கள் கட்சி மற்றும் அகில இலங்கை தமிழ் காங்கிரஸ் தலா 2 இடங்களையும் பெற்றுள்ளன.",
        "இது தவிர தமிழ் மக்கள் விடுதலைப் புலிகள் (TMVP), ஸ்ரீலங்கா சுதந்திரக் கட்சி (SLFP), முஸ்லிம் தேசியக் கூட்டமைப்பு, தமிழ் மக்கள் தீசிய குட்டானி, அகில இளங்கேயி மகாஜன காங்கிரஸ், தேசிய காங்கிரஸ், ஸ்ரீலங்கா முஸ்லிம் காங்கிரஸ், ஐக்கிய தேசியக் கட்சி மற்றும் Ape Janabala Pakshaya தலா ஒரு இருக்கை."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "அட தெரண",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "நாளை",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "19",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "காலை 10.00 மணி",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "மஹிந்த யாப்பா அபேவர்தன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "நாளை",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "அடுத்த நாள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "20",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஐந்து",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "எதிர்ப்பு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "சஜித் பிரேமதாச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "நாளை",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "50 சதவீதத்திற்கும் மேல்",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "தினம்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஸ்ரீ.ல.சு.க",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "பொதுஜன பெரமுன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "145",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "சமகி",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜன பலவேகயா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "எஸ்.ஜே.பி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "54",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கைத் தமிழ்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Arasu Kadchi",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஐ.டி.ஏ.கே",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "10",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "தேசிய மக்கள் சக்தி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "NPP",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "3",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஈழ மக்கள் கட்சி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "அகில இலங்கை தமிழ் காங்கிரஸ்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "2",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "தமிழ் மக்கள்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "விடுதலைப் புலிகள்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "டி.எம்.வி.பி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஸ்ரீலங்கா சுதந்திரக் கட்சி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "முஸ்லிம் தேசிய கூட்டமைப்பு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "தமிழ் மக்கள்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "தீசியா குட்டானி",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "மகாஜன காங்கிரஸ்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "தேசிய காங்கிரஸ்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஸ்ரீலங்கா முஸ்லிம் காங்கிரஸ்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஐக்கிய தேசிய கட்சி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "அபே ஜநபல பக்ஷய",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஒன்று",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}