{
  "newspaper_id": "ada-lk",
  "url": "https://www.ada.lk/breaking_news/කතරගම-පෙරහැරට-යාල-මැදින්-එන-ජනතාවට-වනජීවියෙන්-පහසුකම්/11-395699",
  "time_ut": 1658650495,
  "original_lang": "si",
  "original_title": "කතරගම පෙරහැරට යාල මැදින් එන ජනතාවට වනජීවියෙන් පහසුකම්",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Wildlife facilities for the people coming from Yala for the Kataragama parade",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "Thousands of devotees from the Eastern Province are coming on foot through the Yala forest for the historic Asala Maha Perahera held annually at the Kataragama temple.",
        "Minister Mahinda Amaraweera advised the Director General of Wildlife to prepare a special program for the facilities needed by those people and to protect them from wild animals.",
        "Accordingly, the Wildlife Department has started a special program to protect the devotees from drinking water and other facilities as well as wild animals.",
        "Necessary financial allocations have been allocated for this purpose."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Kataragama",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Thousands",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Eastern Province",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Yala",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Asala Maha Perahera",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "annually",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kataragama",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Mahinda Amaraweera",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the Wildlife Department",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        []
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "කතරගම පෙරහැරට යාල මැදින් එන ජනතාවට වනජීවියෙන් පහසුකම්",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "වාර්ෂිකව කතරගම දේවාලයේ පැවැත්වෙන ඓතිහාසික ඇසල මහ පෙරහැරට මෙවරත් නැගෙනහිර පළාතේ සිට දහස් ගණනක් බැතිමතුන් යාල වනාන්තරය හරහා පා ගමනින් පැමිණෙමින් සිටිති.",
        "එම ජනතාවට අවශ්‍ය පහසුකම් හා වනසතුන්ගෙන් ආරක්ෂාවීම සඳහා විශේෂ වැඩපිළිවෙළක් සකසන ලෙස අමාත්‍ය මහින්ද අමරවීර මහතා වනජීවි අධ්‍යක්ෂ  ජනරාල්වරයාට උපදෙස් දුන්නේය.",
        "ඒ අනුව එම බැතිමතුන්ට අවශ්‍ය පානීය ජලය හා වෙනත් පහසුකම් මෙන්ම වනසතුන්ගෙන් ආරක්ෂා වීම සඳහා විශේෂ වැඩපිලිවෙලක්  වනජීවී දෙපාර්තමේන්තුව  විසින් අරඹා තිබේ.",
        "මේ සඳහා අවශ්‍ය මූල්‍ය ප්‍රතිපාදන ද වෙන් කර තිබේ..පෙරහැර කාලසීමාව අවසන් වන තෙක් යාල වනාන්තරය තුළ දී මෙම වැඩපිලිවෙල ක්‍රියාත්මක කිරීමට විෂය බාර අමාත්‍යවරයා උපදෙස් දී තිබේ"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "කතරගම",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "දහස්",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "නැගෙනහිර පළාත",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "යාල",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඇසල මහා පෙරහැර",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "වාර්ෂිකව",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "කතරගම",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "මහින්ද අමරවීර",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "වනජීවී දෙපාර්තමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        []
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "கதிர்காம அணிவகுப்புக்காக யாலயிலிருந்து வரும் மக்களுக்கு வனவிலங்கு வசதிகள்",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "கதிர்காமம் விகாரையில் வருடாந்தம் இடம்பெறும் வரலாற்றுச் சிறப்புமிக்க அசல மகா பெரஹெரவிற்கு கிழக்கு மாகாணத்தில் இருந்து ஆயிரக்கணக்கான பக்தர்கள் யால காடு ஊடாக பாதயாத்திரையாக வருகின்றனர்.",
        "அந்த மக்களுக்குத் தேவையான வசதிகள் மற்றும் வன விலங்குகளிடமிருந்து அவர்களைப் பாதுகாப்பதற்கு விசேட வேலைத்திட்டம் ஒன்றை தயாரிக்குமாறு அமைச்சர் மஹிந்த அமரவீர வனஜீவராசிகள் பணிப்பாளர் நாயகத்திற்கு ஆலோசனை வழங்கினார்.",
        "அதன்படி, பக்தர்களை குடிநீர் மற்றும் இதர வசதிகள் மற்றும் வன விலங்குகளிடமிருந்து பாதுகாக்கும் வகையில் வனஜீவராசிகள் திணைக்களம் விசேட வேலைத்திட்டத்தை ஆரம்பித்துள்ளது.",
        "இதற்காக தேவையான நிதி ஒதுக்கீடுகள் செய்யப்பட்டுள்ளன."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "கதிர்காமம்",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ஆயிரக்கணக்கில்",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "கிழக்கு மாகாணம்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "யால",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "அசலா மஹா பெரஹெரா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆண்டுதோறும்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "கதிர்காமம்",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "மஹிந்த அமரவீர",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "வனவிலங்கு திணைக்களம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        []
      ]
    }
  }
}