{
  "newspaper_id": "lankadeepa-lk",
  "url": "https://www.lankadeepa.lk/news/ඉන්දීය-පොහොර-’’විභාගය’’-සමත්-වෙි/101-616286",
  "time_ut": 1657604733,
  "original_lang": "si",
  "original_title": "ඉන්දීය පොහොර ’’විභාගය’’ සමත් වෙි",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Indian fertilizers have passed the \"test\".",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "The National Fertilizer Secretariat informed the Agriculture Minister Mahinda Amaraweera that the urea fertilizer given from India is suitable for rice cultivation in Sri Lanka and other crops.",
        "The National Fertilizer Secretariat obtained a standard report in Sri Lanka regarding the urea fertilizer provided by the Government of India, and accordingly sent fertilizer samples to a laboratory in Sri Lanka and obtained a report regarding the percentage of biurate contained in them.",
        "The report has confirmed that the biurate percentage of the urea fertilizer is 0.9% and since the biurate percentage of the urea used in Sri Lanka was generally at the level of 1%, there is no problem in using Indian fertilizer for cultivation, the Fertilizer Secretariat has informed.",
        "Earlier, 03 international laboratory reports were obtained regarding this fertilizer, and those reports also stated that the percentage of biurate is 0.65%.",
        "According to the Ministry of Agriculture, Sri Lanka Commercial Fertilizer Company has arranged to distribute this fertilizer to agricultural service centers all over the island from today."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Indian",
          "label": "NORP"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Agriculture",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Mahinda Amaraweera",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "India",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "0.9%",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "1%",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "Indian",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Fertilizer Secretariat",
            "label": "FAC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "03",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "0.65%",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the Ministry of Agriculture",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "ඉන්දීය පොහොර ’’විභාගය’’ සමත් වෙි",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "ඉන්දියාවෙන් දුන් යූරියා පොහොර ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ වී වගාව ඇතුළු අනෙකුත් වගාවන් සඳහා යෙදීමට සුදුසු බව ජාතික පොහොර ලේකම් කාර්යාලය කෘෂිකර්ම අමාත්‍ය මහින්ද අමරවීර මහතාට වෙත දැනුම් දුන්නේය.",
        "ඉන්දීය රජය විසින් මෙරටට ලබාදුන් යූරියා පොහොර සම්බන්ධව ජාතික පොහොර ලේකම් කාර්යාලය විසින් මෙරට දී ප්‍රමිති වාර්තාවක් ලබා ගත් අතර ඒ අනුව මෙරට රසායනාගාරයකට පොහොර සාම්පල් යවා ඒවායේ අන්තර්ගත බයියුරේට් ප්‍රතිශතය සම්බන්ධව වාර්තාවක් ලබා ගෙන තිබෙි.",
        "එම යූරියා පොහොරවල බයියුරේට් ප්‍රතිශතය 0.9% ක් බව එම වාර්තාව සනාථ කර තිබෙන බවත් සාමාන්‍යයෙන් ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ භාවිත කරන ලද යූරියා වල බයියුරේට් ප්‍රතිශතය 1%ක මට්ටමේ පැවති හෙයින් ඉන්දීය පොහොර වගා සඳහා යෙදීම ගැටලුවක් නැතැයි පොහොර ලේකම් කාර්යාලය දැනුම් දී තිබේ.",
        "මීට පෙර මෙම පොහොර සම්බන්ධව අන්තර්ජාතික රසායනාගාර වාර්තා 03ක් ලබාගත් අතර, එම වාර්තා ද සඳහන් කර තිබුණේ බයියුරේට් ප්‍රතිශතය 0.65%ක අගයක් ගන්නා බවයි.",
        "ඒ අනුව මෙම පොහොර වී, බඩඉරිඟු ඇතුළු බෝග සඳහා අද දින සිට ලංකා කොමර්ෂල් පො‍හොර සමාගම විසින් දිවයින පුරා පිහිටි ගොවිජන සේවා මධ්‍යස්ථාන වෙත බෙදා හැරීමට කටයුතු යොදා ඇතැයි කෘෂිකර්ම අමාත්‍යාංශය පවසයි."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ඉන්දීය",
          "label": "NORP"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "කෘෂිකර්ම",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "මහින්ද අමරවීර",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "0.9%",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "1%",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දීය",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "පොහොර ලේකම් කාර්යාලය",
            "label": "FAC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "03",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "0.65%",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "කෘෂිකර්ම අමාත්‍යාංශය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "இந்திய உரங்கள் \"சோதனை\"யில் தேர்ச்சி பெற்றுள்ளன.",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "இந்தியாவில் இருந்து வழங்கப்படும் யூரியா உரமானது இலங்கையின் நெற்பயிர்ச் செய்கைக்கும் ஏனைய பயிர்களுக்கும் ஏற்றது என தேசிய உர செயலகம் விவசாய அமைச்சர் மஹிந்த அமரவீரவிடம் தெரிவித்துள்ளது.",
        "இந்திய அரசினால் வழங்கப்பட்ட யூரியா உரம் தொடர்பாக தேசிய உர செயலகம் இலங்கையில் தரநிலை அறிக்கையை பெற்று, அதன்படி உர மாதிரிகளை இலங்கையில் உள்ள ஆய்வகத்திற்கு அனுப்பி அதில் உள்ள பைரேட்டின் சதவீதம் குறித்த அறிக்கையை பெற்றுள்ளது.",
        "யூரியா உரத்தின் பையூரேட் சதவீதம் 0.9% என்றும், இலங்கையில் பயன்படுத்தப்படும் யூரியாவின் பைரேட் சதவீதம் பொதுவாக 1% அளவில் இருந்ததால், சாகுபடிக்கு இந்திய உரத்தைப் பயன்படுத்துவதில் எந்தப் பிரச்னையும் இல்லை என, அந்த அறிக்கை உறுதி செய்துள்ளது உரச் செயலகம். தெரிவித்திருக்கிறார்.",
        "முன்னதாக, இந்த உரம் தொடர்பாக 03 சர்வதேச ஆய்வுக்கூட அறிக்கைகள் பெறப்பட்டது, மேலும் அந்த அறிக்கைகளில் பைரேட்டின் சதவீதம் 0.65% என்றும் குறிப்பிடப்பட்டுள்ளது.",
        "இந்த உரத்தை இன்று முதல் நாடளாவிய ரீதியில் உள்ள விவசாய சேவை நிலையங்களுக்கு விநியோகிக்க இலங்கை வர்த்தக உர நிறுவனம் ஏற்பாடு செய்துள்ளதாக விவசாய அமைச்சு தெரிவித்துள்ளது."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "இந்தியன்",
          "label": "NORP"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "வேளாண்மை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "மஹிந்த அமரவீர",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்தியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "0.9%",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "1%",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்தியன்",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "உர செயலகம்",
            "label": "FAC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "03",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "0.65%",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "விவசாய அமைச்சகம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}