{
  "newspaper_id": "ada-derana-lk",
  "url": "http://www.adaderana.lk/news/84599/saudi-crown-prince-receives-written-message-from-sri-lanka-president",
  "time_ut": 1661746080,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Saudi Crown Prince receives written message from Sri Lanka President",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Saudi Crown Prince receives written message from Sri Lanka President",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "Saudi Arabia’s Crown Prince Mohammed bin Salman, Deputy Prime Minister and Minister of Defense, received on Sunday a written message from President of Sri Lanka Ranil Wickremesinghe, reported the Saudi Press Agency.",
        "The message tackled bilateral relations that connect the two friendly countries and peoples and means to develop them in all fields.",
        "The message was received by Deputy Foreign Minister Waleed bin Abdulkarim Al-Khuraiji, on behalf of Foreign Minister Prince Faisal bin Farhan bin Abdullah, during a meeting with Special Envoy of the Sri Lankan President, Minister of Environment of Sri Lanka Naseer Ahamed.",
        "Their meeting tackled bilateral ties between Saudi Arabia and Sri Lanka and ways of boosting them in various fields."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Saudi",
          "label": "NORP"
        },
        {
          "text": "Sri Lanka",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Saudi Arabia’s",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Mohammed bin Salman",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sunday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Saudi Press Agency",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "two",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Waleed bin Abdulkarim Al-Khuraiji",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Prince Faisal bin Farhan bin Abdullah",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lankan",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Naseer Ahamed",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Saudi Arabia",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "සෞදි ඔටුන්න හිමි කුමරුට ශ්‍රී ලංකා ජනාධිපතිවරයාගෙන් ලිඛිත පණිවිඩයක්",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "සෞදි අරාබියේ ඔටුන්න හිමි නියෝජ්‍ය අගමැති සහ ආරක්ෂක අමාත්‍ය මොහොමඩ් බින් සල්මාන් කුමරුට ඉරිදා ශ්‍රී ලංකා ජනාධිපති රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතාගෙන් ලිඛිත පණිවිඩයක් ලැබුණු බව සෞදි පුවත්පත් ඒජන්සිය වාර්තා කළේය.",
        "මෙම පණිවුඩය මගින් මිත්‍ර රටවල් සහ ජාතීන් දෙක සම්බන්ධ කරන ද්විපාර්ශ්වික සබඳතා සහ ඒවා සෑම ක්ෂේත්‍රයකම දියුණු කිරීමට අදහස් කරන ලදී.",
        "විදේශ අමාත්‍ය ෆයිසාල් බින් ෆර්හාන් බින් අබ්දුල්ලා කුමරු වෙනුවෙන් නියෝජ්‍ය විදේශ අමාත්‍ය Waleed bin Abdulkarim Al-Khuraiji විසින් ශ්‍රී ලංකා ජනාධිපතිවරයාගේ විශේෂ නියෝජිත, ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ පරිසර අමාත්‍ය Naseer Ahamed සමඟ පැවති සාකච්ඡාවකදී මෙම පණිවිඩය ලැබිණි.",
        "ඔවුන්ගේ හමුවේදී සෞදි අරාබිය සහ ශ්‍රී ලංකාව අතර ද්විපාර්ශ්වික සබඳතා සහ විවිධ ක්ෂේත්‍රවල ඒවා නංවාලීමේ ක්‍රම පිළිබඳව සාකච්ඡා කෙරිණි."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "සෞදි",
          "label": "NORP"
        },
        {
          "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "සෞදි අරාබියේ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මොහොමඩ් බින් සල්මාන්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉරිදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "සෞදි පුවත්පත් ඒජන්සිය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "දෙක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "වලීඩ් බින් අබ්දුල්කරීම් අල්-කුරයිජි",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ෆයිසාල් බින් ෆර්හාන් බින් අබ්දුල්ලා කුමරු",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලාංකික",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "නසීර් අහමඩ්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "සවුදි අරාබිය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "சவூதி இளவரசர் இலங்கை ஜனாதிபதியிடமிருந்து எழுத்துமூல செய்தியைப் பெற்றுள்ளார்",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "சவூதி அரேபியாவின் பட்டத்து இளவரசர் மொஹமட் பின் சல்மான், பிரதிப் பிரதமரும் பாதுகாப்பு அமைச்சருமான இலங்கை ஜனாதிபதி ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்கவிடமிருந்து ஞாயிற்றுக்கிழமை எழுத்துப்பூர்வ செய்தியைப் பெற்றதாக சவுதி செய்தி நிறுவனம் தெரிவித்துள்ளது.",
        "இரு நாட்டு நட்பு நாடுகளையும் மக்களையும் இணைக்கும் இருதரப்பு உறவுகள் மற்றும் அவற்றை அனைத்து துறைகளிலும் மேம்படுத்துவதற்கான வழிமுறைகளை இந்த செய்தி கையாள்கிறது.",
        "இலங்கை ஜனாதிபதியின் விசேட தூதுவர், இலங்கையின் சுற்றாடல் அமைச்சர் நசீர் அஹமட் உடனான சந்திப்பின் போது, ​​வெளிவிவகார அமைச்சர் இளவரசர் பைசல் பின் ஃபர்ஹான் பின் அப்துல்லாவின் சார்பாக பிரதி வெளிவிவகார அமைச்சர் வலீத் பின் அப்துல்கரீம் அல்-குரைஜி இந்தச் செய்தியைப் பெற்றுக்கொண்டார்.",
        "சவூதி அரேபியாவுக்கும் இலங்கைக்கும் இடையிலான இருதரப்பு உறவுகள் மற்றும் பல்வேறு துறைகளில் அவற்றை மேம்படுத்துவதற்கான வழிகள் குறித்து அவர்களது சந்திப்பில் பேசப்பட்டது."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "சவுதி",
          "label": "NORP"
        },
        {
          "text": "இலங்கை",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "சவுதி அரேபியாவின்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "முகமது பின் சல்மான்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஞாயிற்றுக்கிழமை",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "சவுதி பத்திரிகை நிறுவனம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இரண்டு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "வலீத் பின் அப்துல்கரீம் அல்-குரைஜி",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இளவரசர் பைசல் பின் ஃபர்ஹான் பின் அப்துல்லா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "நசீர் அகமது",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "சவூதி அரேபியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}