{
  "newspaper_id": "daily-mirror-lk",
  "url": "https://www.dailymirror.lk/latest_news/Would-not-get-support-from-Security-council-UK/342-239980",
  "time_ut": 1656470756,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Would not get support from Security council: UK",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Would not get support from Security council: UK",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "\"It would not advance the cause of accountability for an ICC referral to fail to win Security Council support or to be vetoed\"",
        "Britain on Monday said that, while Sri Lanka is a human rights priority country for the Foreign, Commonwealth and Development Office, its assessment was that a referral to the International Criminal Court (ICC) against those responsible for alleged human rights violations in Sri Lanka would not have the required support from members of the UN Security Council.",
        "Vicky Ford, Parliamentary Under-Secretary (Foreign, Commonwealth and Development Office) was responding to a question raised in the British parliament by Labour MP Stephen Morgan, who asked whether her Department is taking steps to ensure that those responsible for human rights violations against the Tamil community in Sri Lanka are brought to justice in the International Criminal Court.",
        "“It would not advance the cause of accountability for an ICC referral to fail to win Security Council support or to be vetoed,” Parliamentary Under-Secretary Vicky Ford stated in a written answer.",
        "We, alongside our partners in the Core Group on Sri Lanka, have led international efforts over many years to promote accountability, reconciliation and human rights in Sri Lanka. On 23 March 2021 the UN Human Rights Council (UNHRC) adopted resolution 46/1, which provides a continued framework for international engagement on human rights. It calls on the government of Sri Lanka to make progress on human rights and stresses the importance of a comprehensive accountability process for all violations and abuses committed in Sri Lanka. The Minister of State for South Asia, Lord (Tariq) Ahmad of Wimbledon, visited Sri Lanka in January 2022. He travelled to the North and East as well as Colombo and met a range of civil society groups, including Tamil representatives, to discuss human rights. The Minister also urged the Government of Sri Lanka to take steps to deliver justice and accountability. (Sunil Jayasiri)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "UK",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Security Council",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Britain",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Monday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Commonwealth and Development Office",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the International Criminal Court",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the UN Security Council",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Vicky Ford",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Commonwealth and Development Office",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "British",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Stephen Morgan",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Tamil",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the International Criminal Court",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Security Council",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Vicky Ford",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the Core Group on Sri Lanka",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "many years",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "23 March 2021",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the UN Human Rights Council",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "UNHRC",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "resolution 46/1",
            "label": "LAW"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "South Asia",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "January 2022",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "North",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "East",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "Tamil",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sunil Jayasiri",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "ආරක්ෂක කවුන්සිලයේ සහාය නොලැබේ: එක්සත් රාජධානිය",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "\"ආරක්ෂක කවුන්සිලයේ සහාය දිනා ගැනීමට හෝ නිෂේධ බලයට පත්වීමට අපොහොසත් වීමට ICC යොමු කිරීම සඳහා වගවීමේ හේතුව එය ඉදිරියට ගෙන නොයනු ඇත\"",
        "විදේශ, පොදුරාජ්‍ය මණ්ඩලීය සහ සංවර්ධන කාර්යාලය සඳහා ශ්‍රී ලංකාව මානව හිමිකම් ප්‍රමුඛතා රටක් වන අතර, ශ්‍රී ලංකාව තුළ සිදු වූ බව කියන මානව හිමිකම් කඩකිරීම් සම්බන්ධයෙන් වගකිවයුත්තන්ට එරෙහිව ජාත්‍යන්තර අපරාධ අධිකරණයට (ICC) යොමු කිරීම තම තක්සේරුව බව බ්‍රිතාන්‍යය සඳුදා ප්‍රකාශ කළේය. එක්සත් ජාතීන්ගේ ආරක්ෂක කවුන්සිලයේ සාමාජිකයින්ගෙන් අවශ්ය සහාය නොලැබේ.",
        "විකී ෆෝඩ්, පාර්ලිමේන්තු උපලේකම් (විදේශ, පොදුරාජ්‍ය මණ්ඩලීය සහ සංවර්ධන කාර්යාලය) බ්‍රිතාන්‍ය පාර්ලිමේන්තුවේදී කම්කරු මන්ත්‍රී ස්ටීවන් මෝගන් විසින් මතු කරන ලද ප්‍රශ්නයකට පිළිතුරු දෙමින්, මානව හිමිකම් කඩකිරීම් සම්බන්ධයෙන් වගකිව යුත්තන් සහතික කිරීමට තම දෙපාර්තමේන්තුව පියවර ගන්නේ දැයි විමසීය. ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ දෙමළ ප්‍රජාව ජාත්‍යන්තර අපරාධ අධිකරණයේ නීතිය හමුවට පමුණුවයි.",
        "\"ආරක්ෂක මණ්ඩලයේ සහාය දිනා ගැනීමට හෝ නිෂේධ බලය ලබා ගැනීමට අපොහොසත් වීම ICC යොමු කිරීම සඳහා වගවීමේ හේතුව ඉදිරියට ගෙන නොයනු ඇත,\" පාර්ලිමේන්තු උපලේකම් විකී ෆෝඩ් ලිඛිත පිළිතුරක සඳහන් කළේය.",
        "අපි, ශ්‍රී ලංකාව පිළිබඳ Core Group හි අපගේ හවුල්කරුවන් සමඟ එක්ව, ශ්‍රී ලංකාව තුළ වගවීම, ප්‍රතිසන්ධානය සහ මානව හිමිකම් ප්‍රවර්ධනය කිරීම සඳහා වසර ගණනාවක් පුරා ජාත්‍යන්තර ප්‍රයත්නයන් මෙහෙයවීය. 2021 මාර්තු 23 දින එක්සත් ජාතීන්ගේ මානව හිමිකම් කවුන්සිලය (UNHRC) මානව හිමිකම් පිළිබඳ ජාත්‍යන්තර මැදිහත්වීම සඳහා අඛණ්ඩ රාමුවක් සපයන 46/1 යෝජනාව සම්මත කළේය. එය මානව හිමිකම් සම්බන්ධයෙන් ප්‍රගතියක් ඇති කරන ලෙස ශ්‍රී ලංකා රජයෙන් ඉල්ලා සිටින අතර ශ්‍රී ලංකාව තුළ සිදු කරන ලද සියලුම උල්ලංඝනය කිරීම් සහ අපයෝජනයන් සඳහා පුළුල් වගවීමේ ක්‍රියාවලියක වැදගත්කම අවධාරණය කරයි. දකුණු ආසියාවේ රාජ්‍ය අමාත්‍ය, විම්බල්ඩන්හි සාමිවරයා (තාරික්) අහමඩ් 2022 ජනවාරි මාසයේදී ශ්‍රී ලංකාවට පැමිණියේය. ඔහු උතුරු නැගෙනහිරට මෙන්ම කොළඹටද ගොස් දෙමළ නියෝජිතයන් ඇතුළු සිවිල් සමාජ කණ්ඩායම් ගණනාවක් හමුවී මනුෂ්‍යත්වය පිළිබඳව සාකච්ඡා කළේය. අයිතිවාසිකම්. යුක්තිය සහ වගවීම ලබාදීමට පියවර ගන්නා ලෙස ද අමාත්‍යවරයා ශ්‍රී ලංකා රජයෙන් ඉල්ලා සිටියේය. (සුනිල් ජයසිරි)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "එක්සත් රාජධානිය",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ආරක්ෂක මණ්ඩලය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "බ්රිතාන්යය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "සඳුදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "පොදුරාජ්‍ය මණ්ඩලීය හා සංවර්ධන කාර්යාලය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජාත්‍යන්තර අපරාධ අධිකරණය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "එක්සත් ජාතීන්ගේ ආරක්ෂක මණ්ඩලය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "විකී ෆෝඩ්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "පොදුරාජ්‍ය මණ්ඩලීය හා සංවර්ධන කාර්යාලය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "බ්රිතාන්ය",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ස්ටීවන් මෝගන්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "දෙමළ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජාත්‍යන්තර අපරාධ අධිකරණය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ආරක්ෂක මණ්ඩලය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "විකී ෆෝඩ්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකාව පිළිබඳ මූලික කණ්ඩායම",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "වර්ෂ බොහෝ ගණනක්",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "2021 මාර්තු 23",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "එක්සත් ජාතීන්ගේ මානව හිමිකම් කවුන්සිලය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "UNHRC",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "විභේදනය 46/1",
            "label": "LAW"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "දකුණු ආසියාව",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "2022 ජනවාරි",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "උතුරු",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "නැගෙනහිර",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "දෙමළ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "සුනිල් ජයසිරි",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "பாதுகாப்பு கவுன்சிலின் ஆதரவைப் பெற முடியாது: இங்கிலாந்து",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "\"பாதுகாப்புக் குழுவின் ஆதரவைப் பெறத் தவறியதற்கு அல்லது வீட்டோ செய்யப்படுவதற்கு ஐ.சி.சி பரிந்துரையின் பொறுப்புக்கூறலின் காரணத்தை இது முன்னெடுக்காது\"",
        "வெளிநாட்டு, பொதுநலவாய மற்றும் அபிவிருத்தி அலுவலகத்தின் மனித உரிமைகளுக்கு முன்னுரிமை அளிக்கும் நாடாக இலங்கை விளங்கும் அதே வேளையில், இலங்கையில் இடம்பெற்றதாகக் கூறப்படும் மனித உரிமை மீறல்களுக்குப் பொறுப்பானவர்களுக்கு எதிராக சர்வதேச குற்றவியல் நீதிமன்றத்திற்கு (ஐ.சி.சி.) பரிந்துரைக்கப்படும் என பிரித்தானியா திங்கட்கிழமை தெரிவித்துள்ளது. ஐநா பாதுகாப்பு கவுன்சிலின் உறுப்பினர்களிடமிருந்து தேவையான ஆதரவு இல்லை.",
        "மனித உரிமை மீறல்களுக்கு காரணமானவர்களை உறுதிப்படுத்த தனது துறை நடவடிக்கை எடுக்கிறதா என்று கேட்ட தொழிலாளர் எம்.பி ஸ்டீபன் மோர்கன் பிரிட்டன் நாடாளுமன்றத்தில் எழுப்பிய கேள்விக்கு நாடாளுமன்ற துணைச் செயலர் (வெளிநாட்டு, காமன்வெல்த் மற்றும் மேம்பாட்டு அலுவலகம்) விக்கி ஃபோர்ட் பதிலளித்தார். இலங்கையில் உள்ள தமிழ் சமூகம் சர்வதேச குற்றவியல் நீதிமன்றத்தில் நீதி விசாரணைக்கு கொண்டுவரப்பட்டுள்ளது.",
        "\"பாதுகாப்புக் குழுவின் ஆதரவைப் பெறத் தவறியதற்கு அல்லது வீட்டோ செய்யப்படுவதற்கு ஐ.சி.சி பரிந்துரையின் பொறுப்புக்கூறலை இது முன்னெடுத்துச் செல்லாது\" என்று நாடாளுமன்ற துணைச் செயலர் விக்கி ஃபோர்ட் எழுத்துப்பூர்வமாக பதிலளித்தார்.",
        "இலங்கை தொடர்பான முக்கிய குழுவில் உள்ள எங்களது பங்காளிகளுடன் சேர்ந்து, இலங்கையில் பொறுப்புக்கூறல், நல்லிணக்கம் மற்றும் மனித உரிமைகளை மேம்படுத்துவதற்காக பல ஆண்டுகளாக சர்வதேச முயற்சிகளை நாங்கள் முன்னெடுத்துள்ளோம். 23 மார்ச் 2021 அன்று UN மனித உரிமைகள் கவுன்சில் (UNHRC) 46/1 தீர்மானத்தை ஏற்றுக்கொண்டது, இது மனித உரிமைகள் மீதான சர்வதேச ஈடுபாட்டிற்கான தொடர்ச்சியான கட்டமைப்பை வழங்குகிறது. மனித உரிமைகளில் முன்னேற்றம் காணுமாறு இலங்கை அரசாங்கத்திற்கு அழைப்பு விடுப்பதுடன், இலங்கையில் இழைக்கப்பட்ட அனைத்து மீறல்கள் மற்றும் துஷ்பிரயோகங்களுக்கும் விரிவான பொறுப்புக்கூறல் செயல்முறையின் முக்கியத்துவத்தை வலியுறுத்துகிறது. தெற்காசியாவின் இராஜாங்க அமைச்சர், விம்பிள்டன் பிரபு (தாரிக்) அஹ்மட், ஜனவரி 2022 இல் இலங்கைக்கு விஜயம் செய்தார். அவர் வடக்கு மற்றும் கிழக்கு மற்றும் கொழும்புக்கு பயணம் செய்து, தமிழ் பிரதிநிதிகள் உட்பட பல சிவில் சமூக குழுக்களைச் சந்தித்து மனிதநேயத்துடன் கலந்துரையாடினார். உரிமைகள். நீதி மற்றும் பொறுப்புக்கூறலை வழங்குவதற்கு இலங்கை அரசாங்கம் நடவடிக்கை எடுக்க வேண்டும் என்றும் அமைச்சர் வலியுறுத்தினார். (சுனில் ஜயசிறி)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "யுகே",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "பாதுகாப்பு கவுன்சில்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பிரிட்டன்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "திங்கட்கிழமை",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "காமன்வெல்த் மற்றும் மேம்பாட்டு அலுவலகம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "சர்வதேச குற்றவியல் நீதிமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஐநா பாதுகாப்பு கவுன்சில்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "விக்கி ஃபோர்டு",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "காமன்வெல்த் மற்றும் மேம்பாட்டு அலுவலகம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "பிரிட்டிஷ்",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஸ்டீபன் மோர்கன்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "தமிழ்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சர்வதேச குற்றவியல் நீதிமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பாதுகாப்பு கவுன்சில்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "விக்கி ஃபோர்டு",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை தொடர்பான முக்கிய குழு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "பல ஆண்டுகள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "23 மார்ச் 2021",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஐ.நா மனித உரிமைகள் பேரவை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "UNHRC",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "தீர்மானம் 46/1",
            "label": "LAW"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "தெற்காசியா",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜனவரி 2022",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "வடக்கு",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "கிழக்கு",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "தமிழ்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "சுனில் ஜயசிறி",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}