{
  "newspaper_id": "daily-ft-lk",
  "url": "https://www.ft.lk/news/Prime-Minister-urges-UNDP-assistance-to-develop-small-and-medium-sector-enterprises/56-738631",
  "time_ut": 1660330217,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Prime Minister urges UNDP assistance to develop small and medium sector enterprises",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Prime Minister urges UNDP assistance to develop small and medium sector enterprises",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "Prime Minister Dinesh Gunawardena yesterday urged the United Nations Development Program to increase assistance to development of small and medium enterprises of rural community based organisations. He also urged support for community enterprises of the urban poor.",
        "Gunawardena made this request when UNDP Deputy Regional Director for Asia and Pacific Christophe Bahuet called on him at the Prime Minister’s Office.",
        "“We assure continuous support to Sri Lanka, a country we consider as an important partner,” Bahuet said recalling the close partnership since 1967. He said that he paid a visit to several centres where UNDP programs are being implemented and expressed satisfaction of the progress made.",
        "He added that the productive and creative work carried out by the Citra Social Innovation Lab, which was set up with UNDP support was highly impressive and expressed confidence that the Citra Lab would successfully respond to the current socioeconomic crisis as it strongly focuses on public sector innovation.",
        "The Prime Minister thanked Bahuet for the UNDP’s assistance to development activities in Sri Lanka. He also thanked for the support for renewable energy sector and environmental projects under the Green Climate Fund of which the UNDP is an Accredited Agency.",
        "Secretary to the Prime Minister Anura Dissanayake and UNDP Policy Specialist Fadhil Bakeer Markar were also present on this occasion."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "UNDP",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Dinesh Gunawardena",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "yesterday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the United Nations Development Program",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Gunawardena",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "UNDP",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Asia",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "Pacific Christophe Bahuet",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Bahuet",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "1967",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "UNDP",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the Citra Social Innovation Lab",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "UNDP",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Bahuet",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "UNDP",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Green Climate Fund",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "UNDP",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "an Accredited Agency",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Anura Dissanayake",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "UNDP Policy Specialist Fadhil",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Markar",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "කුඩා හා මධ්‍යම අංශයේ ව්‍යවසායන් දියුණු කිරීම සඳහා UNDP ආධාර ලබාදෙන ලෙස අගමැති ඉල්ලා සිටී",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "ග‍්‍රාමීය ප‍්‍රජා මූලික සංවිධානවල කුඩා හා මධ්‍ය පරිමාණ ව්‍යවසායක සංවර්ධනය සඳහා ආධාර වැඩි කරන ලෙස අගමැති දිනේෂ් ගුණවර්ධන මහතා එක්සත් ජාතීන්ගේ සංවර්ධන වැඩසටහනෙන් ඊයේ ඉල්ලා සිටියේය. නාගරික දුප්පතුන්ගේ ප්‍රජා ව්‍යවසායන් සඳහා සහාය දෙන ලෙස ද ඔහු ඉල්ලා සිටියේය.",
        "ගුණවර්ධන මහතා මෙම ඉල්ලීම කළේ UNDP හි ආසියා සහ පැසිෆික් කලාපයේ නියෝජ්‍ය ප්‍රාදේශීය අධ්‍යක්ෂ Christophe Bahuet මහතා අග්‍රාමාත්‍ය කාර්යාලයේදී ඔහු හමුවූ අවස්ථාවේදීය.",
        "\"වැදගත් හවුල්කරුවෙකු ලෙස අප සලකන රටක් වන ශ්‍රී ලංකාවට අඛණ්ඩ සහයෝගයක් ලබා දෙන බව අපි සහතික වෙනවා,\" 1967 සිට සමීප හවුල්කාරිත්වය සිහිපත් කරමින් බහුඑට් පැවසීය. ඔහු UNDP වැඩසටහන් ක්‍රියාත්මක කරන මධ්‍යස්ථාන කිහිපයක සංචාරය කළ බවත් ප්‍රගතිය පිළිබඳව තෘප්තිමත් වූ බවත් පැවසීය. හැදුවා.",
        "UNDP සහය ඇතිව පිහිටුවන ලද Citra Social Innovation Lab මගින් සිදුකරන ඵලදායී හා නිර්මාණාත්මක කටයුතු ඉතා ආකර්ෂණීය බවත් රාජ්‍ය අංශයේ නවෝත්පාදන කෙරෙහි දැඩි අවධානයක් යොමු කරන බැවින් වත්මන් සමාජ ආර්ථික අර්බුදයට Citra Lab සාර්ථකව ප්‍රතිචාර දක්වනු ඇතැයි විශ්වාසය පළ කළේය. .",
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ සංවර්ධන කටයුතු සඳහා UNDP ලබාදුන් සහය පිළිබඳව අග්‍රාමාත්‍යවරයා Bahuet වෙත ස්තුතිය පුද කළේය. UNDP ප්‍රතීතනය ලත් නියෝජිතායතනයක් වන හරිත දේශගුණික අරමුදල යටතේ පුනර්ජනනීය බලශක්ති ක්ෂේත්‍රය සහ පාරිසරික ව්‍යාපෘති සඳහා ලබා දෙන සහයෝගය පිළිබඳව ද ඔහු ස්තූතිවන්ත විය.",
        "මෙම අවස්ථාවට අග්‍රාමාත්‍ය ලේකම් අනුර දිසානායක සහ UNDP ප්‍රතිපත්ති විශේෂඥ ෆාදිල් බාකීර් මාකර් යන මහත්වරුද එක්ව සිටියහ."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "UNDP",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "දිනේෂ් ගුණවර්ධන",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඊයේ",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "එක්සත් ජාතීන්ගේ සංවර්ධන වැඩසටහන",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ගුණවර්ධන ය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "UNDP",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ආසියාව",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "පැසිෆික් Christophe Bahuet",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "බහුඑට්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "1967",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "UNDP",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Citra Social Innovation Lab",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "UNDP",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "බහුඑට්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "UNDP",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "හරිත දේශගුණික අරමුදල",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "UNDP",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "පිළිගත් නියෝජිතායතනයක්",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "අනුර දිසානායක",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "UNDP ප්‍රතිපත්ති විශේෂඥ ෆාදිල්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "මාකර්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "சிறு மற்றும் நடுத்தர நிறுவனங்களை மேம்படுத்த UNDP உதவியை பிரதமர் வலியுறுத்துகிறார்",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "கிராமிய சமூகம் சார்ந்த நிறுவனங்களின் சிறு மற்றும் நடுத்தர தொழில் முயற்சிகளின் அபிவிருத்திக்கான உதவிகளை அதிகரிக்குமாறு ஐக்கிய நாடுகளின் அபிவிருத்தித் திட்டத்திடம் பிரதமர் தினேஷ் குணவர்தன நேற்று வலியுறுத்தினார். நகர்ப்புற ஏழைகளின் சமூக நிறுவனங்களுக்கு ஆதரவளிக்கவும் அவர் வலியுறுத்தினார்.",
        "UNDPயின் ஆசிய மற்றும் பசுபிக் பிராந்தியத்திற்கான பிரதிப் பிராந்திய பணிப்பாளர் கிறிஸ்டோப் பஹூட் பிரதமர் அலுவலகத்தில் அவரை சந்தித்த போது குணவர்தன இந்தக் கோரிக்கையை விடுத்தார்.",
        "\"முக்கியமான பங்காளியாக நாங்கள் கருதும் நாடான இலங்கைக்கு தொடர்ச்சியான ஆதரவை நாங்கள் உறுதியளிக்கிறோம்,\" என்று 1967 ஆம் ஆண்டு முதல் நெருங்கிய கூட்டாண்மையை நினைவு கூர்ந்த பஹூட் கூறினார். UNDP திட்டங்கள் நடைமுறைப்படுத்தப்படும் பல மையங்களுக்கு விஜயம் செய்து முன்னேற்றம் குறித்து திருப்தி தெரிவித்தார். செய்யப்பட்டது.",
        "யுஎன்டிபி ஆதரவுடன் அமைக்கப்பட்ட சிட்ரா சோஷியல் இன்னோவேஷன் ஆய்வகத்தின் உற்பத்தி மற்றும் ஆக்கப்பூர்வமான பணிகள் மிகவும் சுவாரஸ்யமாக இருப்பதாகவும், தற்போதைய சமூகப் பொருளாதார நெருக்கடிக்கு சிட்ரா லேப் வெற்றிகரமாக பதிலளிக்கும் என்றும் நம்பிக்கை தெரிவித்தார். .",
        "இலங்கையின் அபிவிருத்தி நடவடிக்கைகளுக்கு UNDP வழங்கிய உதவிக்கு பிரதமர் பஹூட்க்கு நன்றி தெரிவித்தார். UNDP அங்கீகாரம் பெற்ற ஏஜென்சியாக இருக்கும் பசுமை காலநிலை நிதியத்தின் கீழ் புதுப்பிக்கத்தக்க எரிசக்தி துறை மற்றும் சுற்றுச்சூழல் திட்டங்களுக்கான ஆதரவுக்கும் அவர் நன்றி தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "இந்த நிகழ்வில் பிரதமரின் செயலாளர் அனுர திஸாநாயக்க மற்றும் UNDP கொள்கை நிபுணர் ஃபாதில் பாக்கீர் மார்க்கர் ஆகியோரும் கலந்துகொண்டனர்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "யுஎன்டிபி",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "தினேஷ் குணவர்தன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "நேற்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஐக்கிய நாடுகளின் வளர்ச்சித் திட்டம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "குணவர்தன",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "யுஎன்டிபி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆசியா",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "பசிபிக் Christophe Bahuet",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Bahuet",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "1967",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "யுஎன்டிபி",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "சிட்ரா சமூக கண்டுபிடிப்பு ஆய்வகம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "யுஎன்டிபி",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Bahuet",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "யுஎன்டிபி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "பசுமை காலநிலை நிதியம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "யுஎன்டிபி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஒரு அங்கீகாரம் பெற்ற ஏஜென்சி",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "அனுர திஸாநாயக்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "UNDP கொள்கை நிபுணர் ஃபாதில்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "மார்க்கர்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}