{
  "newspaper_id": "lankadeepa-lk",
  "url": "https://www.lankadeepa.lk/latest_news/එක්ස්ප්‍රස්-පර්ල්-වන්දිය-රුපියල්-බිලියන-1-3-යි/1-618889",
  "time_ut": 1661705616,
  "original_lang": "si",
  "original_title": "එක්ස්ප්‍රස් පර්ල් වන්දිය රුපියල් බිලියන 1.3 යි",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Express Pearl compensation is Rs 1.3 billion",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "Ms. Darshanee Lahadapura, Chairperson of the Maritime Environment Protection Authority, said that the general treasury has received an amount of 1.3 billion rupees from the ship's insurance company for cleaning up the beach by removing plastic and waste released from the sinking of the Express Pearl ship.",
        "She said that the cabinet paper submitted requesting 903,857,293 rupees from the treasury to settle the payment related to beach cleaning has been approved.",
        "Mrs. Lahadapura also said that the first interim report has been sent to the Australian Bar Association after calculating the environmental damage caused to the coastline and coastline due to the Express Pearl container ship that sank in Sri Lankan waters on May 20 last year while carrying goods under the Singapore flag. .",
        "She also mentioned that after receiving the instructions from that institution, further legal steps will be taken together with the Attorney General's Department."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Pearl",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "Rs 1.3 billion",
          "label": "LAW"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Darshanee Lahadapura",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Maritime Environment Protection Authority",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "1.3 billion",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "903,857,293",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Lahadapura",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "first",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Australian Bar Association",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Express Pearl",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lankan",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "May 20 last year",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Singapore",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        []
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "එක්ස්ප්‍රස් පර්ල් වන්දිය රුපියල් බිලියන 1.3 යි",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "එක්ස්ප්‍රස් පර්ල් නෞකාව ගිලී යෑමෙන් නිකුත්වූ ප්ලාස්ටික් හා අපද්‍රව්‍ය ඉවත්කොට වෙරළ තීරය පිරිසිදු කිරීමේ කටයුතු වෙනුවෙන් නෞකාවේ රක්ෂණ සමාගමෙන් රුපියල් බිලියන 1.3 ක මුදලක් මහා භාණ්ඩාගාරයට ලැබී ඇතැයි සමුද්‍රීය පරිසර ආරක්ෂණ අධිකාරියේ සභාපතිනී නීතීඥ දර්ශනී ළහදපුර මහත්මිය පැවසුවාය.",
        "වෙරළ පිරිසිදු කිරීමට අදාල ගෙවීම් කටයුතු පියවීම සදහා එම මුදලින් රුපියල් 903,857,293 ක් මහා භාණ්ඩාගාරයෙන් ඉල්ලමින් ඉදිරිපත් කරන ලද කැබිනට් පත්‍රිකාවට මේ වන විට අනුමැතිය ලබා දී ඇති බවද ඇය පැවසුවාය.",
        "සිංගප්පූරු ධජය යටතේ භාණ්ඩ රැගෙන යාත්‍ර කරමින් තිබියදී ඉකුත් වසරේ මැයි මස 20 වැනිදා මෙරට මුහුදු සීමාවේදී ගිලී ගිය එක්ස්ප්‍රස් පර්ල් බහාලුම් ප්‍රවාහන නෞකාව හේතුවෙන් මුහුදු තීරයට හා වෙරළ තීරයට සිදුවූ පරිසර හානිය ගණනය කර සකස්කළ පළමු අතුරු වාර්තාව ඕස්ට්‍රේලියානු නීතිඥ ආයතනය වෙත යවා තිබෙන බව ද ළහදපුර මහත්මිය පැවසුවාය.",
        "එම ආයතනයෙන් උපදෙස් ලැබුණු පසු නීතිපති දෙපාර්තමේන්තුව සමඟ එක්ව ඉදිරි නීතිමය පියවර ගන්නා බවද ඇය සඳහන් කළාය."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "මුතු ඇටය",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "රුපියල් බිලියන 1.3 කි",
          "label": "LAW"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "දර්ශනී ලහදපුර",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "සමුද්‍රීය පරිසර ආරක්ෂණ අධිකාරිය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "බිලියන 1.3 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "903,857,293 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ලහඩපුර",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "පළමුවන",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඕස්ට්රේලියානු නීතිඥ සංගමය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "එක්ස්ප්රස් පර්ල්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලාංකික",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගිය අවුරුද්දේ මැයි 20",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "සිංගප්පූරුව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        []
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "எக்ஸ்பிரஸ் பேர்ல் இழப்பீடு ரூ.1.3 பில்லியன்",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "எக்ஸ்பிரஸ் பேர்ல் கப்பல் மூழ்கியதில் இருந்து வெளியேறும் பிளாஸ்டிக் மற்றும் கழிவுகளை அகற்றி கடற்கரையை சுத்தம் செய்வதற்காக கப்பலின் காப்புறுதி நிறுவனத்திடம் இருந்து பொது கருவூலத்திற்கு 1.3 பில்லியன் ரூபா கிடைத்துள்ளதாக கடல்சார் சுற்றாடல் பாதுகாப்பு அதிகார சபையின் தலைவி திருமதி தர்ஷனி லஹதபுர தெரிவித்தார். .",
        "கடற்கரையை சுத்தப்படுத்துதல் தொடர்பான கொடுப்பனவுகளை செலுத்துவதற்காக திறைசேரியில் இருந்து 903,857,293 ரூபாவை கோரி சமர்ப்பிக்கப்பட்ட அமைச்சரவை பத்திரத்திற்கு அங்கீகாரம் கிடைத்துள்ளதாக அவர் கூறினார்.",
        "கடந்த மே மாதம் 20ஆம் திகதி இலங்கை கடற்பரப்பில் சரக்குகளை ஏற்றிச் சென்ற போது கடலில் மூழ்கிய எக்ஸ்பிரஸ் பேர்ல் கொள்கலன் கப்பல் காரணமாக கரையோரப் பகுதிக்கும் கரையோரப் பகுதிக்கும் ஏற்பட்ட சுற்றாடல் பாதிப்புகளை கணக்கிட்டு முதலாவது இடைக்கால அறிக்கை அவுஸ்திரேலிய சட்டத்தரணிகள் சங்கத்திற்கு அனுப்பி வைக்கப்பட்டுள்ளதாகவும் திருமதி லஹதபுர தெரிவித்தார். சிங்கப்பூர் கொடியின் கீழ்..",
        "அந்த நிறுவனத்திடம் இருந்து அறிவுறுத்தல்கள் கிடைத்த பின்னர், சட்டமா அதிபர் திணைக்களத்துடன் இணைந்து மேலதிக சட்ட நடவடிக்கைகள் மேற்கொள்ளப்படும் எனவும் அவர் குறிப்பிட்டுள்ளார்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "முத்து",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "ரூ 1.3 பில்லியன்",
          "label": "LAW"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "தர்ஷநீ லஹதபுரா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "கடல்சார் சுற்றுச்சூழல் பாதுகாப்பு ஆணையம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "1.3 பில்லியன்",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "903,857,293",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "லஹதபுரா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "முதலில்",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆஸ்திரேலிய பார் அசோசியேஷன்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "எக்ஸ்பிரஸ் பேர்ல்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "கடந்த ஆண்டு மே 20",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சிங்கப்பூர்",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        []
      ]
    }
  }
}