{
  "newspaper_id": "daily-mirror-lk",
  "url": "https://www.dailymirror.lk/breaking_news/T-N-BJP-will-continue-to-press-for-retrieval-of-Katchatheevu-Annamalai/108-243031",
  "time_ut": 1660500504,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "T.N. BJP will continue to press for retrieval of Katchatheevu: Annamalai",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "T.N. BJP will continue to press for retrieval of Katchatheevu: Annamalai",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "The Tamil Nadu Bharatiya Janata Party will continue to pressurise the Union government to retrieve the Katchatheevu island from Sri Lanka as it would facilitate the fishermen in Tamil Nadu to engage in fishing activities along the Palk Straits without any insecurity and threat from the Sri Lankan Navy personnel, said its state president K Annamalai in Rameshwaram on Sunday.",
        "The BJP Ramanathapuram district functionaries organised a series of events on the visit of their state leader. With a host of fishermen, the BJP functionaries led by Mr Annamalai took a boat ride waving the Indian Tricolour flag in Rameswaram. He visited the memorial of APJ Abdul Kalam and paid tributes at Peikarumbu and went to Kundukal fish landing jetty.",
        "Speaking to reporters, he said that though the Katchatheevu was handed over to Sri Lanka by the then Prime Minister Indira Gandhi in 1972 and it had been described as a “settled matter,” steps are being taken now to retrieve it. The government led by Narendra Modi is keen to protect the welfare of the fishermen. So, the BJP unit from TN would keep pressurising the Centre on this issue.",
        "The Katchatheevu, according to the fishermen here, would be more useful and productive for the fishermen from TN than those from Sri Lanka. While the fishermen can get catch only in Katchatheevu islet, it would be logically perfect to be demarcated with in the Indian waters, he explained.",
        "After 2014, when Mr Modi assumed office, the number of incidents of arrests of fishermen by the Sri Lankan Navy had reduced phenomenally. Even in the case of any arrests, the Union government intervened and brought them back safely. Thus, retrieving Katchatheevu would be the only option for a peaceful fishing, which would be taken up by the BJP, he underlined.",
        "When reporters asked his comment on the Madurai airport incident on Saturday in which a few BJP cadres had allegedly hurled chappal at the Finance Minister Palanivel Thiaga Rajan’s car and the late night development in which the Madurai BJP district president Saravanan had announced to quit the party, Mr Annamalai said that quitting or joining a party is the prerogative of a person. The incident was condemnable as the BJP cadre should not have indulged in such an act. At the same time, Mr Thiaga Rajan should not have degraded his position by picking up a quarrel with the BJP men. Anyway, the police are investigating into the issue.",
        "The BJP has a long tradition of giving respect to every individual irrespective of the caste, creed and community. The party would not tolerate indiscipline in any manner. In the Madurai incident, the BJP party had organised to pay homage to martyr D Lakshmanan. It was a solemn ceremony and such an act had lowered the dignity and hoped it would not recur anywhere in future, he added."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "T.N. BJP",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "Katchatheevu",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Katchatheevu",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Tamil Nadu",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Palk Straits",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Sri Lankan Navy",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "K Annamalai",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Rameshwaram",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sunday",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "BJP Ramanathapuram",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "BJP",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Annamalai",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Indian",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Rameswaram",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Abdul Kalam",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Peikarumbu",
            "label": "WORK_OF_ART"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kundukal",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Katchatheevu",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Indira Gandhi",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "1972",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Narendra Modi",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "BJP",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "TN",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Centre",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Katchatheevu",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Katchatheevu",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Indian",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "2014",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Sri Lankan Navy",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Katchatheevu",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "BJP",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Madurai",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Saturday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "BJP",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Finance",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Thiaga Rajan’s",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "late night",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "Madurai BJP",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Saravanan",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Annamalai",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "BJP",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Thiaga Rajan",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "BJP",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "BJP",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Madurai",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "BJP",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "D Lakshmanan",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "ටී.එන්. කච්චතිව් නැවත ලබා ගැනීම සඳහා BJP දිගටම බලපෑම් කරනු ඇත: අන්නමලෙයි",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "තමිල්නාඩු භාරතීය ජනතා පක්ෂය ශ්‍රී ලංකා නාවික හමුදාවේ කිසිදු අනාරක්ෂිත භාවයකින් සහ තර්ජනයකින් තොරව තමිල්නාඩුවේ ධීවරයින්ට පෝක් සමුද්‍ර සන්ධිය ඔස්සේ ධීවර කටයුතුවල යෙදීමට පහසුකම් සැලසෙන බැවින් කච්චතිව් දූපත ශ්‍රී ලංකාවෙන් ලබාගන්නා ලෙස මධ්‍යම රජයට දිගින් දිගටම බලපෑම් කරනු ඇත. , ඉරිදා රාමේෂ්වරම්හිදී එහි ප්‍රාන්ත සභාපති කේ අන්නාමලෙයි පැවසීය.",
        "භාරතීය ජනතා පක්ෂ රාමනාතපුරම් දිස්ත්‍රික් ක්‍රියාකාරීන් ඔවුන්ගේ රාජ්‍ය නායකයාගේ සංචාරය පිළිබඳ වැඩසටහන් මාලාවක් සංවිධානය කළහ. ධීවරයින් රැසක් සමඟින් අන්නමලෙයි මහතා ප්‍රමුඛ භාරතීය ජනතා පක්ෂ ක්‍රියාකාරීන් රාමේෂ්වරම් හි ඉන්දීය ත්‍රිවර්ණ ධජය ලෙළවමින් බෝට්ටු සවාරියක නිරත වූහ. ඒ.පී.ජේ.අබ්දුල් කලාම්ගේ ස්මාරකය වෙත ගොස් පේකාරුම්බුහිදී උපහාර දැක්වු ඔහු කුණ්ඩුකල් මාළු ගොඩබෑමේ ජැටිය වෙත ගියේය.",
        "මාධ්‍යවේදීන් අමතමින් ඔහු කියා සිටියේ 1972 දී එවකට අගමැතිනි ඉන්දිරා ගාන්ධි විසින් කච්චතිව් ශ්‍රී ලංකාවට පවරා දී එය \"සමථයකට පත් වූ කරුණක්\" ලෙස විස්තර කර තිබුණද එය නැවත ලබා ගැනීමට දැන් පියවර ගනිමින් සිටින බවයි. නරේන්ද්‍ර මෝදිගේ නායකත්වයෙන් යුත් රජය ධීවර ජනතාවගේ සුබසාධනය ආරක්ෂා කිරීමට උනන්දු වෙනවා. එබැවින්, TN හි BJP ඒකකය මෙම ප්‍රශ්නය සම්බන්ධයෙන් මධ්‍යස්ථානයට දිගින් දිගටම බලපෑම් කරනු ඇත.",
        "කච්චතිව්, මෙහි ධීවරයින් පවසන පරිදි, ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ ධීවරයින්ට වඩා TN හි ධීවරයින්ට වඩාත් ප්‍රයෝජනවත් සහ ඵලදායී වනු ඇත. ධීවරයින්ට අල්ලා ගත හැක්කේ කච්චතිව් දූපතෙන් පමණක් වන අතර, එය ඉන්දීය මුහුදේ සීමා කිරීම තාර්කිකව පරිපූර්ණ බව ඔහු පැහැදිලි කළේය.",
        "2014 වසරෙන් පසු මෝදි මහතා බලයට පත්වීමෙන් පසු ශ්‍රී ලංකා නාවික හමුදාව විසින් ධීවරයින් අත්අඩංගුවට ගැනීමේ සිද්ධීන් අතිවිශිෂ්ට ලෙස අඩු වී ඇත. කිසියම් අත්අඩංගුවට ගැනීමකදී පවා, මධ්‍යම රජය මැදිහත් වී ඔවුන් ආරක්ෂිතව ආපසු ගෙන එන ලදී. මේ අනුව, කච්චතිව් නැවත ලබා ගැනීම සාමකාමී ධීවර කර්මාන්තයක් සඳහා ඇති එකම විකල්පය වනු ඇති අතර එය භාරතීය ජනතා පක්ෂය විසින් ගනු ඇති බව ඔහු අවධාරණය කළේය.",
        "මාධ්‍යවේදීන් සෙනසුරාදා මදුරෙයි ගුවන් තොටුපළ සිද්ධිය සම්බන්ධයෙන් භාරතීය ජනතා පක්ෂ සාමාජිකයින් කිහිප දෙනෙකු මුදල් අමාත්‍ය පලනිවෙල් ත්‍යාග රාජන්ගේ මෝටර් රථයට චප්පල් ප්‍රහාරයක් එල්ල කළ බව කියන සිද්ධිය සහ මදුරෙයි භාරතීය ජනතා පක්ෂයේ දිස්ත්‍රික් සභාපති සරවනන් පක්ෂයෙන් ඉවත් වන බව ප්‍රකාශ කළ මහ රෑ සංවර්ධනය පිළිබඳව ඔහුගේ අදහස විමසූ විට. අන්නමලෙයි මහතා ප්‍රකාශ කළේ පක්ෂයකින් ඉවත්වීම හෝ එක්වීම පුද්ගලයෙකුගේ පරම බලයක් බවයි. මෙම සිදුවීම හෙළා දැකිය යුතු කරුණක් වූයේ භාරතීය ජනතා පක්ෂය එවැනි ක්‍රියාවකට නොපැමිණිය යුතු බැවිනි. ඒ අතරම, ත්‍යාග රාජන් මහතා භාරතීය ජනතා පක්ෂය සමඟ ආරවුලක් ඇති කර ගනිමින් තම තනතුර පහත් කර නොගත යුතුව තිබුණි. කෙසේ හෝ මේ සම්බන්ධයෙන් පොලිසිය පරීක්ෂණ පවත්වයි.",
        "කුල, ආගම සහ ප්‍රජාව නොසලකා සෑම පුද්ගලයෙකුටම ගෞරවය ලබා දීමේ දිගු සම්ප්‍රදායක් භාරතීය ජනතා පක්ෂයට ඇත. පක්ෂය කිසිම ආකාරයකින් විනය විරෝධී ක්‍රියා ඉවසන්නේ නැහැ. මදුරෙයි සිද්ධියේදී, භාරතීය ජනතා පක්ෂය ප්‍රාණ පරිත්‍යාගික ඩී ලක්ෂ්මනන්ට උපහාර දැක්වීමට සංවිධානය කර තිබුණි. එය උත්කර්ෂවත් උත්සවයක් බවත්, එවැනි ක්‍රියාවක් නිසා ගෞරවය පහත වැටී ඇති බවත්, එය අනාගතයේ කොතැනකවත් නැවත සිදු නොවනු ඇතැයි බලාපොරොත්තු වන බවත් ඔහු වැඩිදුරටත් පැවසීය."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ටී.එන්. බී.ජේ.පී",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "කච්චතිව්",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "කච්චතිව්",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "තමිල්නාඩුව",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "පෝක් සමුද්ර සන්ධිය",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකා නාවික හමුදාව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "කේ අන්නාමලෙයි",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "රාමේෂ්වරම්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉරිදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "BJP රාමනාතපුරම්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "බී.ජේ.පී",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "අන්නමලෙයි",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දීය",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "රාමේෂ්වරම්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "අබ්දුල් කලාම්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "පීකරඹු",
            "label": "WORK_OF_ART"
          },
          {
            "text": "කුණ්ඩුකල්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "කච්චතිව්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දිරා ගාන්ධි",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "1972",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "නරේන්ද්‍ර මෝදි",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "බී.ජේ.පී",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "TN",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "මධ්යස්ථානය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "කච්චතිව්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "කච්චතිව්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දීය",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "2014",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකා නාවික හමුදාව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "කච්චතිව්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "බී.ජේ.පී",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "මදුරෙයි",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "සෙනසුරාදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "බී.ජේ.පී",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "මූල්ය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "තියාග රාජන්ගේ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "මහ රෑ",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "මදුරෙයි බී.ජේ.පී",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "සරවනන්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "අන්නමලෙයි",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "බී.ජේ.පී",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "තියාග රාජන්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "බී.ජේ.පී",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "බී.ජේ.පී",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "මදුරෙයි",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "බී.ජේ.පී",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඩී ලක්ෂ්මන්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "டி.என். கச்சத்தீவை மீட்க பாஜக தொடர்ந்து அழுத்தம் கொடுக்கும்: அண்ணாமலை",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "இலங்கை கடற்படையினரின் பாதுகாப்பு மற்றும் அச்சுறுத்தல் இன்றி தமிழக மீனவர்கள் பாக் ஜலசந்தியில் மீன்பிடி தொழிலில் ஈடுபடுவதற்கு வசதியாக, கச்சத்தீவு இலங்கையிடம் இருந்து மீட்கப்பட வேண்டும் என மத்திய அரசுக்கு தமிழக பாரதிய ஜனதா கட்சி தொடர்ந்து அழுத்தம் கொடுக்கும். , ராமேஸ்வரத்தில் அதன் மாநிலத் தலைவர் கே.அண்ணாமலை ஞாயிற்றுக்கிழமை தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "மாநில தலைவர் வருகையையொட்டி ராமநாதபுரம் மாவட்ட பாஜக நிர்வாகிகள் பல்வேறு நிகழ்ச்சிகளுக்கு ஏற்பாடு செய்தனர். ராமேஸ்வரத்தில் இந்திய மூவர்ணக் கொடியை அசைத்தபடி ஏராளமான மீனவர்களுடன், திரு அண்ணாமலை தலைமையில் பாஜக நிர்வாகிகள் படகு சவாரி செய்தனர். ஏபிஜே அப்துல் கலாமின் நினைவிடத்துக்குச் சென்று பேய்க்கரும்புவில் அஞ்சலி செலுத்திவிட்டு குண்டுகால் மீன் இறங்குதளத்துக்குச் சென்றார்.",
        "செய்தியாளர்களிடம் பேசிய அவர், 1972-ம் ஆண்டு அப்போதைய பிரதமர் இந்திரா காந்தியால் கச்சத்தீவு இலங்கையிடம் ஒப்படைக்கப்பட்டு, அது தீர்க்கப்பட்ட விவகாரம் என்று கூறப்பட்டாலும், அதை மீட்பதற்கான நடவடிக்கைகள் தற்போது மேற்கொள்ளப்பட்டு வருவதாகவும் கூறினார். நரேந்திர மோடி தலைமையிலான அரசு மீனவர்களின் நலன் காக்க தீவிரம் காட்டி வருகிறது. எனவே, தமிழக பாஜக பிரிவு இந்த விவகாரத்தில் மத்திய அரசுக்கு தொடர்ந்து அழுத்தம் கொடுக்கும்.",
        "கச்சத்தீவு, இங்குள்ள மீனவர்களின் கூற்றுப்படி, இலங்கை மீனவர்களை விட, தமிழக மீனவர்களுக்கு மிகவும் பயனுள்ளதாகவும் பயனுள்ளதாகவும் இருக்கும். கச்சத்தீவு பகுதியில் மட்டுமே மீனவர்கள் மீன்பிடிக்க முடியும் என்றாலும், இந்திய கடல் எல்லைக்குள் எல்லை நிர்ணயம் செய்வது தர்க்கரீதியாக சரியானதாக இருக்கும் என்று அவர் விளக்கினார்.",
        "2014ஆம் ஆண்டுக்குப் பிறகு, மோடி பதவியேற்ற பிறகு, இலங்கைக் கடற்படையினரால் மீனவர்கள் கைது செய்யப்படும் சம்பவங்களின் எண்ணிக்கை வெகுவாகக் குறைந்துள்ளது. கைது செய்யப்பட்டாலும், மத்திய அரசு தலையிட்டு அவர்களை பத்திரமாக அழைத்து வந்தது. எனவே, கச்சத்தீவை மீட்பதுதான் அமைதியான மீன்பிடிக்கான ஒரே வழி, அதை பாஜக மேற்கொள்ளும் என்று அவர் அடிக்கோடிட்டுக் காட்டினார்.",
        "நிதியமைச்சர் பழனிவேல் தியாகராஜனின் கார் மீது பாஜகவினர் சிலர் சரமாரியாக சரமாரியாக வீசிய சம்பவம் குறித்தும், மதுரை மாவட்ட பாஜக தலைவர் சரவணன் கட்சியில் இருந்து விலகுவதாக அறிவித்தது குறித்தும் செய்தியாளர்கள் சனிக்கிழமை அவரிடம் கருத்துக் கேட்டபோது. கட்சியில் இருந்து விலகுவது அல்லது சேர்வது என்பது ஒருவரின் தனிச் சிறப்பு என்று திரு அண்ணாமலை கூறினார். பாஜகவினர் இதுபோன்ற செயலில் ஈடுபட்டிருக்கக் கூடாது என்பதால் இந்தச் சம்பவம் கண்டனத்துக்குரியது. அதே சமயம் திரு தியாக ராஜன் பிஜேபி ஆட்களுடன் சண்டை போட்டு தன் பதவியை தாழ்த்திக் கொண்டிருக்கக் கூடாது. எப்படியிருந்தாலும், இந்த விவகாரம் குறித்து போலீசார் விசாரணை நடத்தி வருகின்றனர்.",
        "ஜாதி, மதம், சமூகம் என்ற பாகுபாடின்றி ஒவ்வொரு தனி மனிதருக்கும் மரியாதை அளிக்கும் பாரம்பரியம் பாஜகவுக்கு உண்டு. எந்த வகையிலும் ஒழுங்கீனத்தை கட்சி பொறுத்துக் கொள்ளாது. மதுரை சம்பவத்தில் தியாகி டி.லட்சுமணனுக்கு அஞ்சலி செலுத்த பாஜக கட்சியினர் ஏற்பாடு செய்திருந்தனர். இது ஒரு புனிதமான விழாவாகும், இது போன்ற செயல் கண்ணியத்தை குறைத்துவிட்டதாகவும், எதிர்காலத்தில் இது எங்கும் நிகழாது என்றும் அவர் நம்புகிறார்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "டி.என். பா.ஜ.க",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "கச்சத்தீவு",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "கச்சத்தீவு",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "தமிழ்நாடு",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "பால்க் ஜலசந்தி",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை கடற்படை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "கே அண்ணாமலை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ராமேஸ்வரம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஞாயிற்றுக்கிழமை",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பாஜக ராமநாதபுரம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "பா.ஜ.க",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "அண்ணாமலை",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்தியன்",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ராமேஸ்வரம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "அப்துல் கலாம்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "பேய்க்கரும்பு",
            "label": "WORK_OF_ART"
          },
          {
            "text": "குண்டுகால்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "கச்சத்தீவு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்திரா காந்தி",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "1972",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "நரேந்திர மோடி",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "பா.ஜ.க",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "TN",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "மையம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "கச்சத்தீவு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "கச்சத்தீவு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்தியன்",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "2014",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை கடற்படை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "கச்சத்தீவு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "பா.ஜ.க",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "மதுரை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "சனிக்கிழமை",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "பா.ஜ.க",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "நிதி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "தியாக ராஜனின்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "பின்னிரவு",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "மதுரை பா.ஜ.க",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "சரவணன்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "அண்ணாமலை",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "பா.ஜ.க",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "தியாக ராஜன்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "பா.ஜ.க",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பா.ஜ.க",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "மதுரை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "பா.ஜ.க",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "டி லட்சுமணன்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}