{
  "newspaper_id": "virakesari-lk",
  "url": "http://www.virakesari.lk/article/131771",
  "time_ut": 1658212983,
  "original_lang": "ta",
  "original_title": "சஜித்தை  பிரதமராக ஏற்றுக்கொள்ள ஸ்ரீலங்கா பொதுஜனபெரமுன தயார் -  ஜி.எல்.பீரிஸ்",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Sri Lanka Podujanaperam is ready to accept Sajith as Prime Minister - GL Peiris",
      "author": "T. Saranya",
      "body_lines": [
        "Sri Lanka Podujanaperamuna is ready to accept Sajith Premadasa as the Prime Minister, said the party's leader Professor G. L. Peiris.",
        "He said that the expectation of the people is to find a solution to the major problems by joining the two parties.",
        "He noted that many members of parliament are ready to support the Dulles unit."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Sajith",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "- GL Peiris",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Podujanaperamuna",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "G. L. Peiris",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "two",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Dulles",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "සජිත් අගමැති ලෙස පිළිගැනීමට ශ්‍රී ලංකා පොදුජනපෙරම සූදානම් - ජී එල් පීරිස්",
      "author": "T. Saranya",
      "body_lines": [
        "සජිත් ප්‍රේමදාස මහතා අග්‍රාමාත්‍යවරයා ලෙස පිළිගැනීමට ශ්‍රී ලංකා පොදුජන පෙරමුණ සූදානම් බව එම පක්ෂයේ නායක මහාචාර්ය ජී.එල්.පීරිස් මහතා පවසයි.",
        "පක්‍ෂ දෙකට එකතු වී ප‍්‍රධාන ගැටලූවලට විසඳුම් සෙවීම ජනතාවගේ අපේක්ෂාව බවද හෙතෙම කීය.",
        "පාර්ලිමේන්තු මන්ත්‍රීවරුන් රැසක් ඩලස් ඒකකයට සහය දැක්වීමට සූදානම් බව ඔහු සඳහන් කළේය."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "සජිත්",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "- ජී එල් පීරිස්",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "පොදුජනපෙරමුණ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජී.එල්. පීරිස්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "දෙක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ඩලස්",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "சஜித்தை  பிரதமராக ஏற்றுக்கொள்ள ஸ்ரீலங்கா பொதுஜனபெரமுன தயார் -  ஜி.எல்.பீரிஸ்",
      "author": "T. Saranya",
      "body_lines": [
        "சஜித்பிரேமதாசவை பிரதமராக ஏற்றுக்கொள்ள ஸ்ரீலங்கா பொதுஜனபெரமுன தயார் என கட்சியின் தலைவர் பேராசிரியர் ஜி.எல்.பீரிஸ் தெரிவித்துள்ளார்.",
        "இரு கட்சிகளை இணைத்து முக்கிய பிரச்சினைகளிற்கு தீர்வைக் காணவேண்டும் என்பதே மக்களின் எதிர்பார்ப்பு என அவர் தெரிவித்துள்ளார்.",
        "அனேகமான பாராளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர்கள் டலஸ் அலகப்பெருமவிற்கு ஆதரவளிக்க தயார் என அவர் குறிப்பிட்டுள்ளார்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "சஜித்",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "- ஜி.எல்.பீரிஸ்",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "பொதுஜன பெரமுன",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜி.எல்.பீரிஸ்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இரண்டு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "டல்லஸ்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}