{
  "newspaper_id": "economy-next-com",
  "url": "https://economynext.com/sri-lanka-to-release-fuel-for-essential-services-only-cabinet-96544/",
  "time_ut": 1656341040,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Sri Lanka to release fuel for essential services only: cabinet",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Sri Lanka to release fuel for essential services only: cabinet",
      "author": "",
      "body_lines": [
        "ECONOMYNEXT – Sri Lanka’s cabinet of ministers has approved a proposal to limit the release of fuel to essential services from midnight June 27 to July 10, cabinet spokesman Minister Bandula Gunawardena said.",
        "Minister Gunawardena requested the public to limit nonessential travel and use fuel sparingly.",
        "Sri Lanka is going through a deepening fuel crisis with refusing to confirm letters of credit issued by the country’s state banks, and oil suppliers are also rejecting them due to the country’s inability to pay in dollars.",
        "Foreign banks refuse to confirm Sri Lanka state bank letters of credit: Minister",
        "Sri Lanka bus operators want tariff hike to account for central bank actions",
        "Sri Lanka has been depending on Indian credit lines for fuel, and according to Power and Energy Minister Kanchana Wijesekara, the state run Ceylon Petroleum Corporation (CPC) will need the help of the Treasury for repayments.",
        "The fuel crisis has left Sri Lanka’s roads bare, with even the most populated roads looking like ghost towns. Drivers line up for days in fuel queues, and it has become common to see abandoned vehicles waiting in line for fuel that, according to authorities, is simply not available. (Colombo/Jun27/2022)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Sri Lanka",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "midnight June 27 to July 10",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Bandula Gunawardena",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Gunawardena",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Indian",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Power and Energy",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kanchana Wijesekara",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ceylon Petroleum Corporation",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "CPC",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Treasury",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka’s",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "days",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Colombo/Jun27/2022",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "ශ්‍රී ලංකාව අත්‍යවශ්‍ය සේවා සඳහා පමණක් ඉන්ධන නිකුත් කරයි: කැබිනට් මණ්ඩලය",
      "author": "",
      "body_lines": [
        "ECONOMYNEXT - ජූනි 27 මධ්‍යම රාත්‍රියේ සිට ජූලි 10 දක්වා අත්‍යාවශ්‍ය සේවා සඳහා ඉන්ධන නිකුත් කිරීම සීමා කිරීමේ යෝජනාවක් ශ්‍රී ලංකා අමාත්‍ය මණ්ඩලය විසින් අනුමත කර ඇති බව කැබිනට් ප්‍රකාශක අමාත්‍ය බන්දුල ගුණවර්ධන මහතා පැවසීය.",
        "අත්‍යවශ්‍ය නොවන ගමන් බිමන් සීමා කර ඉන්ධන අරපිරිමැස්මෙන් භාවිත කරන ලෙස අමාත්‍ය ගුණවර්ධන ජනතාවගෙන් ඉල්ලීමක් කළා.",
        "රටේ රාජ්‍ය බැංකු විසින් නිකුත් කරන ලද ණයවර ලිපි තහවුරු කිරීම ප්‍රතික්ෂේප කිරීමත් සමඟ ශ්‍රී ලංකාව ගැඹුරු වන ඉන්ධන අර්බුදයකට මුහුණ දෙමින් සිටින අතර, ඩොලර් වලින් ගෙවීමට රටට ඇති නොහැකියාව හේතුවෙන් තෙල් සැපයුම්කරුවන් ද ඒවා ප්‍රතික්ෂේප කරති.",
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකා රාජ්‍ය බැංකු ණයවර ලිපි තහවුරු කිරීම විදේශීය බැංකු ප්‍රතික්ෂේප කරයි: ඇමති",
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකා බස් රථ ක්‍රියාකරුවන්ට මහ බැංකු ක්‍රියාමාර්ග සඳහා ගාස්තු වැඩි කිරීමට අවශ්‍යයි",
        "ඉන්ධන සඳහා ශ්‍රී ලංකාව ඉන්දියානු ණය මාර්ග මත යැපෙන අතර, විදුලිබල හා බලශක්ති අමාත්‍ය කංචන විජේසේකර පවසන පරිදි, රජය විසින් පවත්වාගෙන යනු ලබන ලංකා ඛනිජ තෙල් නීතිගත සංස්ථාවට (CPC) ආපසු ගෙවීම සඳහා භාණ්ඩාගාරයේ සහාය අවශ්‍ය වනු ඇත.",
        "ඉන්ධන අර්බුදය හේතුවෙන් ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ මාර්ග හිස්ව ඇති අතර, වඩාත්ම ජනාකීර්ණ මාර්ග පවා අවතාර නගර මෙන් පෙනේ. රියදුරන් ඉන්ධන පෝලිම්වල දින ගණන් පෝලිම් ගැසී සිටින අතර බලධාරීන් පවසන පරිදි ඉන්ධන ලබා ගැනීමට නොහැකි ලෙස අතහැර දැමූ වාහන පෝලිමේ සිටීම සාමාන්‍ය දෙයක් බවට පත්ව ඇත. (කොළඹ/ජුනි27/2022)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ජුනි 27 සිට ජූලි 10 දක්වා මධ්‍යම රාත්‍රිය",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "බන්දුල ගුණවර්ධන",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ගුණවර්ධන ය",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දීය",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "විදුලි බල හා බලශක්ති",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "කාංචන විජේසේකර",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ලංකා ඛනිජ තෙල් නීතිගත සංස්ථාව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "CPC",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "භාණ්ඩාගාර",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "දින",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "කොළඹ/ජුනි27/2022",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "அத்தியாவசிய சேவைகளுக்கு மட்டும் எரிபொருளை விடுவிக்க இலங்கை: அமைச்சரவை",
      "author": "",
      "body_lines": [
        "பொருளாதாரம் - ஜூன் 27 நள்ளிரவு முதல் ஜூலை 10 வரை அத்தியாவசிய சேவைகளுக்கு எரிபொருளை வெளியிடுவதை மட்டுப்படுத்துவதற்கான யோசனைக்கு இலங்கையின் அமைச்சரவை ஒப்புதல் அளித்துள்ளது என்று அமைச்சரவைப் பேச்சாளர் அமைச்சர் பந்துல குணவர்தன தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "அத்தியாவசியமற்ற பயணங்களை மட்டுப்படுத்தி எரிபொருளை சிக்கனமாக பயன்படுத்துமாறு அமைச்சர் குணவர்தன பொதுமக்களிடம் கோரிக்கை விடுத்துள்ளார்.",
        "நாட்டின் அரச வங்கிகளால் வழங்கப்பட்ட கடன் கடிதங்களை உறுதிப்படுத்த மறுப்பதன் மூலம் இலங்கை ஆழ்ந்த எரிபொருள் நெருக்கடியை எதிர்கொண்டுள்ளது, மேலும் எண்ணெய் வழங்குநர்களும் நாட்டின் டாலர்களில் செலுத்த இயலாமை காரணமாக அவற்றை நிராகரித்து வருகின்றனர்.",
        "இலங்கை அரச வங்கி கடன் கடிதங்களை வெளிநாட்டு வங்கிகள் உறுதிப்படுத்த மறுக்கின்றன: அமைச்சர்",
        "இலங்கை பேருந்து நடத்துநர்கள் மத்திய வங்கியின் நடவடிக்கைகளுக்குக் கணக்குக் காட்ட கட்டண உயர்வைக் கோருகின்றனர்",
        "எரிபொருளுக்காக இலங்கை இந்திய கடன் வரிகளை நம்பியிருக்கிறது, மேலும் மின்சக்தி மற்றும் எரிசக்தி அமைச்சர் காஞ்சன விஜேசேகரவின் கருத்துப்படி, அரசு நடத்தும் சிலோன் பெட்ரோலியம் கூட்டுத்தாபனத்திற்கு (CPC) திருப்பிச் செலுத்துவதற்கு திறைசேரியின் உதவி தேவைப்படும்.",
        "எரிபொருள் நெருக்கடி இலங்கையின் சாலைகளை வெறுமையாக்கியுள்ளது, அதிக மக்கள் தொகை கொண்ட சாலைகள் கூட பேய் நகரங்கள் போல் காட்சியளிக்கின்றன. ஓட்டுநர்கள் எரிபொருள் வரிசையில் பல நாட்கள் வரிசையில் நிற்கிறார்கள், மேலும் அதிகாரிகள் படி, வெறுமனே எரிபொருள் கிடைக்காத வகையில் கைவிடப்பட்ட வாகனங்கள் வரிசையில் காத்திருப்பதைப் பார்ப்பது வழக்கமாகிவிட்டது. (கொழும்பு/ஜூன்27/2022)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "இலங்கை",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ஜூன் 27 முதல் ஜூலை 10 வரை நள்ளிரவு",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "பந்துல குணவர்தன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "குணவர்தன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்தியன்",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "சக்தி மற்றும் ஆற்றல்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "காஞ்சனா விஜேசேகர",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை பெற்றோலியக் கூட்டுத்தாபனம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "CPC",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "கருவூலம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கையின்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "நாட்களில்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "கொழும்பு/ஜூன்27/2022",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}