{
  "newspaper_id": "ada-derana-lk",
  "url": "http://www.adaderana.lk/news/83749/tna-pledges-support-for-dullas",
  "time_ut": 1658250420,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "TNA pledges support for Dullas",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "TNA pledges support for Dullas",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "MP M.A. Sumanthiran says the Tamil National Alliance (TNA) will also back presidential hopeful Dullas Alahapperuma in the parliamentary vote tomorrow (July 20).",
        "Meanwhile, 06 parliamentarians of Sri Lanka Freedom Party (SLPP) including MP Anura Priyadarshana Yapa, who are sitting independently in the parliament, have decided to support Alahapperuma.",
        "Further, Opposition Leader Sajith Premadasa, Sri Lanka Freedom Party (SLFP), the Union of Independent Parties led by MPs Wimal Weerawansa, Udaya Gammanpila and Vasudeva Nanayakkara and MP Mano Ganesan-led Tamil Progressive Alliance also pledged support for Alahapperuma earlier today.",
        "He will face off Acting President Ranil Wickremesinghe and NPP leader Anura Kumara Dissanayake at the parliamentary vote for the office of President, which was left vacant by the stepping down of Gotabaya Rajapaksa last week."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Dullas",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "M.A. Sumanthiran",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Tamil National Alliance",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "TNA",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Dullas Alahapperuma",
            "label": "WORK_OF_ART"
          },
          {
            "text": "tomorrow",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "July 20",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "06",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka Freedom Party",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Anura Priyadarshana Yapa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sajith Premadasa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka Freedom Party",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Union of Independent Parties",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Wimal Weerawansa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Udaya Gammanpila",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Vasudeva Nanayakkara",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Mano Ganesan",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Tamil Progressive Alliance",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "earlier today",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "NPP",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Anura Kumara Dissanayake",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Gotabaya Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "last week",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "ඩලස්ට සහය දෙන බවට TNA ප්‍රතිඥා දෙයි",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "හෙට (ජූලි 20) පැවැත්වෙන පාර්ලිමේන්තු ඡන්ද විමසීමේදී දෙමළ ජාතික සන්ධානය (ටීඑන්ඒ) ද ජනාධිපති අපේක්ෂක ඩලස් අලහප්පෙරුම මහතාට සහාය දෙන බව පාර්ලිමේන්තු මන්ත්‍රී එම්.ඒ.සුමන්තිරන් මහතා පවසයි.",
        "මේ අතර, පාර්ලිමේන්තුවේ ස්වාධීනව අසුන්ගෙන සිටින පාර්ලිමේන්තු මන්ත්‍රී අනුර ප්‍රියදර්ශන යාපා ඇතුළු ශ්‍රී ලංකා නිදහස් පක්ෂයේ පාර්ලිමේන්තු මන්ත්‍රීවරුන් 06 දෙනෙකු අලහප්පෙරුම මහතාට සහය පළ කිරීමට තීරණය කර තිබෙනවා.",
        "මීට අමතරව, විපක්ෂ නායක සජිත් ප්‍රේමදාස, ශ්‍රී ලංකා නිදහස් පක්ෂය, පාර්ලිමේන්තු මන්ත්‍රීවරුන් වන විමල් වීරවංශ, උදය ගම්මන්පිල, වාසුදේව නානායක්කාර ප්‍රමුඛ නිදහස් පක්ෂ එකමුතුව සහ මනෝ ගනේෂන් ප්‍රමුඛ දෙමළ ප්‍රගතිශීලී සන්ධානය ද අලහප්පෙරුම මහතාට සහය පළ කිරීමට අද පෙරේදා ප්‍රකාශ කළා.",
        "පසුගිය සතියේ ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ මහතා ඉල්ලා අස්වීමත් සමඟ පුරප්පාඩු වූ ජනාධිපති ධුරය සඳහා වන පාර්ලිමේන්තු ඡන්ද විමසීමේදී ඔහු වැඩ බලන ජනාධිපති රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ සහ එන්පීපී නායක අනුර කුමාර දිසානායක යන මහත්වරුන්ට මුහුණ දෙනු ඇත."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ඩලස්",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "එම්.ඒ.සුමන්තිරන්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "දෙමළ ජාතික සන්ධානය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ටීඑන්ඒ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඩලස් අලහප්පෙරුම",
            "label": "WORK_OF_ART"
          },
          {
            "text": "හෙට",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජූලි 20",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "06",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකා නිදහස් පක්ෂය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "අනුර ප්‍රියදර්ශන යාපා",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "සජිත් ප්‍රේමදාස",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකා නිදහස් පක්ෂය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ස්වාධීන පක්ෂ සංගමය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "විමල් වීරවංශ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "උදය ගම්මන්පිල",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "වාසුදේව නානායක්කාර",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Mano Ganesan",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "දෙමළ ප්‍රගතිශීලී සන්ධානය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "අද කලින්",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "එන්පීපී",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "අනුර කුමාර දිසානායක",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගිය සතිය",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "டல்லாஸுக்கு ஆதரவளிப்பதாக TNA உறுதியளித்துள்ளது",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "நாளை (ஜூலை 20) நடைபெறவுள்ள நாடாளுமன்ற வாக்கெடுப்பில் தமிழ்த் தேசியக் கூட்டமைப்பும் ஜனாதிபதி வேட்பாளர் டலஸ் அழகப்பெருமவுக்கு ஆதரவளிக்கும் என நாடாளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர் எம்.ஏ.சுமந்திரன் தெரிவித்துள்ளார்.",
        "இதேவேளை, பாராளுமன்றத்தில் சுயேச்சையாக அமர்ந்துள்ள ஸ்ரீலங்கா சுதந்திரக் கட்சியின் பாராளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர் அனுர பிரியதர்சன யாப்பா உள்ளிட்ட 06 நாடாளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர்கள் அழகப்பெருமவுக்கு ஆதரவளிக்க தீர்மானித்துள்ளனர்.",
        "மேலும், எதிர்க்கட்சித் தலைவர் சஜித் பிரேமதாச, ஸ்ரீலங்கா சுதந்திரக் கட்சி (SLFP), பாராளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர்களான விமல் வீரவன்ச, உதய கம்மன்பில, வாசுதேவ நாணயக்கார மற்றும் பாராளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர் மனோ கணேசன் தலைமையிலான தமிழ் முற்போக்குக் கூட்டமைப்பு ஆகியனவும் அழகப்பெருமவுக்கு ஆதரவளிப்பதாக உறுதியளித்துள்ளன.",
        "கடந்த வாரம் கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ச பதவி விலகியதன் மூலம் வெற்றிடமாக இருந்த ஜனாதிபதி பதவிக்கான பாராளுமன்ற வாக்கெடுப்பில் அவர் பதில் ஜனாதிபதி ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க மற்றும் NPP தலைவர் அனுரகுமார திஸாநாயக்க ஆகியோரை எதிர்கொள்வார்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "டல்லாஸ்",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "எம்.ஏ.சுமந்திரன்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "தமிழ் தேசிய கூட்டமைப்பு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "TNA",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "டலஸ் அழகப்பெரும",
            "label": "WORK_OF_ART"
          },
          {
            "text": "நாளை",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜூலை 20",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "06",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஸ்ரீலங்கா சுதந்திரக் கட்சி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "அனுர பிரியதர்ஷன யாப்பா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "சஜித் பிரேமதாச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஸ்ரீலங்கா சுதந்திரக் கட்சி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "சுதந்திரக் கட்சிகளின் ஒன்றியம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "விமல் வீரவன்ச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "உதய கம்மன்பில",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "வாசுதேவ நாணயக்கார",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Mano Ganesan",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "தமிழ் முற்போக்கு கூட்டணி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "முன்னதாக இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "NPP",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "அனுரகுமார திஸாநாயக்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "கடந்த வாரம்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}