{
  "newspaper_id": "lankadeepa-lk",
  "url": "https://www.lankadeepa.lk/news/සුද්දො-බාගෙට-බාගයකට-ලංකාව-එපා-වෙලා/101-617263",
  "time_ut": 1659110553,
  "original_lang": "si",
  "original_title": "සුද්දො බාගෙට බාගයකට ලංකාව එපා වෙලා",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Half of the whites are tired of Sri Lanka",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "Sri Lanka Tourism Development Authority Chairperson Mrs Dhammika Wijesinghe told Lankadeepa that about 45 percent of the hotel reservations made by foreign tourists before coming to Sri Lanka have been suddenly canceled due to the struggles.",
        "It had a very negative impact on the tourism industry and lack of fuel, gas and electricity cuts were another major reason for the decrease in tourist arrivals.",
        "Mrs. Wijesinghe said that the arrival of tourists has increased by ten percent so far this month, forty two thousand nine hundred and twenty five tourists have arrived so far.",
        "Generally, these days, the number of tourists who come on a weekday (average value) is 1533. Mrs. Dhammika Wijesinghe said that it was 1900 on a weekend day.",
        "The Director General said that August is usually the time when more tourists come to Sri Lanka, so a special program was started to attract more tourists to the country during that time.",
        "Mrs. Wijesinghe said that a tourism promotion program has been started targeting the Kandy Perahara to attract tourists and mentioned that they are also working to provide various other facilities including providing fuel for the transportation of tourists.",
        "The largest number of tourists this month came from England. That number is 8304.",
        "After that, the largest group of tourists came from India and the number is 5416.",
        "In addition to this, the Director General further mentioned that more tourists have come to this country from countries like Germany, France and Canada."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Half",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "Sri Lanka",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka Tourism Development Authority Chairperson Mrs Dhammika Wijesinghe",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Lankadeepa",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "about 45 percent",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "Wijesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ten percent",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "this month",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "forty two thousand nine hundred and twenty five",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "these days",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "1533",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Dhammika Wijesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "1900",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "August",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Wijesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Kandy Perahara",
            "label": "FAC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "this month",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "England",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "8304",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "India",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "5416",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Germany",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "France",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Canada",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "සුද්දො බාගෙට බාගයකට ලංකාව එපා වෙලා",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "විදේශීය සංචාරකයන්  මෙරටට පැමිණීමට පෙර කළ හෝටල් වෙන් කිරීම්වලින් සියයට 45  ක් පමණ අරගල හේතුවෙන්  හදිසියේම  අවලංගු කරගෙන ඇතැයි ශ්‍රී ලංකා සංචාරක සංවර්ධන  අධිකාරියේ සභාපතිනී  ධම්මිකා විජේසිංහ මහත්මිය ලංකාදීපයට පැවසුවාය.",
        "එය සංචාරක කර්මාන්තයට ඉතා අහිතකර ලෙස බලපෑ බවත්  ඉන්ධන, ගෑස්  හිඟය  සහ විදුලිය කැපීමද  සංචාරකයන්ගේ පැමිණීම අඩුවීමට තවත් ප්‍රධාන හේතුවක්වූ  බවත්",
        "සංචාරකයන්ගේ පැමිණීම මේ වනවිට සියයට දහයකින් පමණ වැඩි කරගෙන ඇතැයි පැවසූ විජේසිංහ මහත්මිය  මේ මාසයේ  මේ දක්වා සංචාරකයන් හතළිස් දෙදහස් නව සිය විසි පහක්  පැමිණ ඇතැයිද සඳහන් කළාය.",
        "සාමාන්‍යයෙන්  මේ දිනවල සතියේ  දිනක පැමිණෙන සංචාරකයන්ගේ  සංඛ්‍යාව (සාමාන්‍ය අගය) 1533 කි. සති අන්ත දිනෙක එය 1900ක් බව ධම්මිකා විජේසිංහ මහත්මිය කීවාය.",
        "සාමාන්‍යයෙන් අගෝස්තු මාසය මෙරටට සංචාරකයන් වැඩි වශයෙන් පැමිණෙන කාලයක් වන හෙයින්  එම කාලයේදී සංචාරකයන් රටට වැඩි වශයෙන් අද්දවා ගැනීම සඳහා විශේෂ වැඩපිළිවෙළක් ආරම්භ කළ බවද  අධ්‍යක්ෂ ජනරාල්වරිය පැවසුවාය.",
        "සංචාරකයන් අද්දවා ගැනීම සඳහා මහනුවර පෙරහර  ඉලක්ක කර  සංචාරක ප්‍රවර්ධන වැඩසටහනක් ආරම්භ  කළ බව පැවසූ විජේසිංහ මහත්මිය සංචාරකයන් ප්‍රවාහනය සඳහා ඉන්ධන සැපයීම ඇතුළු වෙනත් විවිධ පහසුකම් සැලසීමටද  කටයුතු කරගෙන යන බව  සඳහන් කළාය.",
        "මේ මාසයේ වැඩිම වැඩිම සංචාරකයන් පිරිසක් පැමිණ ඇත්තේ එංගලන්තයෙනි. එම සංඛ්‍යාව 8304කි.",
        "ඊට පසු වැඩිම සංචාරකයන් පිරිසක් පැමිණ ඇත්තේ ඉන්දියාවෙන් වන අතර එම සංඛ්‍යාව 5416කි.",
        "මෙයට අමතරව ජර්මනිය, ප්‍රංශය සහ කැනඩාව යනාදි රටවලින්ද සංචාරකයන් මෙරටට වැඩි වශයෙන් පැමිණ ඇති බව අධ්‍යක්ෂ ජනරාල්වරිය වැඩිදුරටත්  සඳහන් කළාය."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "අඩක්",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකා සංචාරක සංවර්ධන අධිකාරියේ සභාපතිනී ධම්මිකා විජේසිංහ මහත්මිය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ලංකාදීප",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "සියයට 45 ක් පමණ",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "විජේසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "සියයට දහයක්",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "මේ මාසයේ",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "හතළිස් දෙදහස් නවසිය විසිපහයි",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "මෙම දිනවල",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "1533",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ධම්මික විජේසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "1900",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "අගෝස්තු",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "විජේසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "මහනුවර පෙරහර",
            "label": "FAC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "මේ මාසයේ",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "එංගලන්තය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "8304",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "5416",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ජර්මනිය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ප්රංශය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "කැනඩාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "வெள்ளையர்களில் பாதி பேர் இலங்கையை பார்த்து அலுத்துவிட்டனர்",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "வெளிநாட்டு சுற்றுலாப் பயணிகள் இலங்கைக்கு வருவதற்கு முன்னர் மேற்கொண்டிருந்த ஹோட்டல் முன்பதிவுகளில் சுமார் 45 சதவீதமானவை போராட்டங்கள் காரணமாக திடீரென ரத்து செய்யப்பட்டுள்ளதாக இலங்கை சுற்றுலா அபிவிருத்தி அதிகார சபையின் தலைவி திருமதி தம்மிகா விஜேசிங்க லங்காதீபவிடம் தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "இது சுற்றுலாத் துறையில் மிகவும் எதிர்மறையான தாக்கத்தை ஏற்படுத்தியது மற்றும் எரிபொருள் பற்றாக்குறை, எரிவாயு மற்றும் மின்சார வெட்டுக்கள் சுற்றுலாப் பயணிகளின் வருகை குறைவதற்கு மற்றொரு முக்கிய காரணமாகும்.",
        "இம்மாதத்தில் இதுவரை சுற்றுலாப் பயணிகளின் வருகை பத்து வீதத்தால் அதிகரித்துள்ளதாகவும், இதுவரை நாற்பத்தி இரண்டாயிரத்து தொள்ளாயிரத்து இருபத்தைந்து சுற்றுலாப் பயணிகள் வருகை தந்துள்ளதாகவும் திருமதி விஜேசிங்க தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "பொதுவாக, இந்த நாட்களில், ஒரு வார நாளில் வரும் சுற்றுலாப் பயணிகளின் எண்ணிக்கை (சராசரி மதிப்பு) 1533 ஆகும். ஒரு வார இறுதி நாளில் 1900 என்று திருமதி தம்மிகா விஜேசிங்க கூறினார்.",
        "பொதுவாக ஆகஸ்ட் மாதம் இலங்கைக்கு அதிகளவான சுற்றுலாப் பயணிகள் வரும் காலமாகும், எனவே அக்காலப்பகுதியில் அதிகளவான சுற்றுலாப் பயணிகளை நாட்டிற்கு வரவழைக்கும் விசேட வேலைத்திட்டம் ஆரம்பிக்கப்பட்டதாக பணிப்பாளர் நாயகம் தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "சுற்றுலாப் பயணிகளை கவரும் வகையில் கண்டி பெரஹராவை இலக்காகக் கொண்டு சுற்றுலா ஊக்குவிப்பு வேலைத்திட்டமொன்று ஆரம்பிக்கப்பட்டுள்ளதாகத் தெரிவித்த திருமதி விஜேசிங்க, சுற்றுலாப் பயணிகளின் போக்குவரத்திற்கு எரிபொருள் வழங்குதல் உள்ளிட்ட பல்வேறு வசதிகளை வழங்குவதற்கும் செயற்பட்டு வருவதாகக் குறிப்பிட்டார்.",
        "இந்த மாதத்தில் அதிக எண்ணிக்கையிலான சுற்றுலா பயணிகள் இங்கிலாந்தில் இருந்து வந்துள்ளனர். அந்த எண் 8304.",
        "அதன்பிறகு, இந்தியாவில் இருந்து அதிக எண்ணிக்கையிலான சுற்றுலாப் பயணிகள் வந்துள்ளனர் மற்றும் எண்ணிக்கை 5416 ஆகும்.",
        "இதற்கு மேலதிகமாக ஜேர்மனி, பிரான்ஸ், கனடா போன்ற நாடுகளில் இருந்து அதிகளவான சுற்றுலாப் பயணிகள் இந்நாட்டுக்கு வந்துள்ளதாக பணிப்பாளர் நாயகம் மேலும் குறிப்பிட்டுள்ளார்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "பாதி",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "இலங்கை",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை சுற்றுலா அபிவிருத்தி அதிகார சபையின் தலைவர் திருமதி தம்மிகா விஜேசிங்க",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "லங்காதீப",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "சுமார் 45 சதவீதம்",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "விஜேசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "பத்து சதவீதம்",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்த மாதம்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "நாற்பத்தி இரண்டாயிரத்து தொள்ளாயிரத்து இருபத்தைந்து",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இந்த நாட்களில்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "1533",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "தம்மிக்க விஜேசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "1900",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஆகஸ்ட்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "விஜேசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "கண்டி பெரஹரா",
            "label": "FAC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இந்த மாதம்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இங்கிலாந்து",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "8304",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இந்தியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "5416",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஜெர்மனி",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "பிரான்ஸ்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "கனடா",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}