{
  "newspaper_id": "ada-lk",
  "url": "https://www.ada.lk/breaking_news/’’ගෝරිල්ලා-රංජි’’--සහ-සහෝදරයා-මත්කුඩු-සමග-මාට්ටූ/11-395789",
  "time_ut": 1658915198,
  "original_lang": "si",
  "original_title": "’’ගෝරිල්ලා රංජි’’  සහ සහෝදරයා මත්කුඩු සමග මාට්ටූ",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "\"Gorilla Ranji\" and his brother were killed with drugs",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "The Police Special Task Force says that two brothers from the same family, who are the two main disciples of Sinnaiya Gunasekaram or Kimbulale Guna, a leader who runs the organized crime and drug network, have been arrested along with a consignment of drugs worth nearly 8 lakh rupees.",
        "Police say that the arrested are Ratnam Ranjith Kumar alias \"Gorilla Ranji\" and his brother.",
        "The police have taken 74 880 mg of drugs in the possession of those persons.",
        "The police say that Ratnam Ranjith Kumar aka \"Gorilla Ranji\" runs the drug network of Sinnaiya Gunasekaram aka Kimbula Ale Guna Nematta, an organized crime gang leader who was arrested in a joint operation conducted by the security forces of South India and Sri Lanka.",
        "According to the information received by the officers of the Police Special Task Force Organized Crime Unit 2, a team of officers including the Station Commander Police Inspector CR Paramullage arrested the two suspects during a raid in Madampitiya area of ​​Blumandel Police Domain.",
        "On the twelfth last day in Madampitiya area, the police said that it was revealed that Ratnam Ranjith Kumar aka Gorilla Ranji had given instructions to shoot and kill a man named Pradeepan who was riding a motorcycle with his wife.",
        "Police also believe that the brother of the arrested gorilla Ranji is a resident of Ganemulla.",
        "According to the orders and instructions of the Police Special Task Force Commanding Officer, DIG Advocate Mr. Warna Jayasundara, a team including the Station Commander of the Special Task Force Organized Crime Unit 2, Police Inspector CR Para Mullage, arrested the suspects."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Ranji",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "two",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "two",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sinnaiya Gunasekaram",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kimbulale Guna",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the organized crime and drug network",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "nearly 8",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Ratnam Ranjith Kumar",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ranji",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "74",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "880",
            "label": "FAC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sinnaiya Gunasekaram",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "South India",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "2",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "CR Paramullage",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "two",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "twelfth",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "last day",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ratnam Ranjith",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "aka Gorilla Ranji",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Pradeepan",
            "label": "WORK_OF_ART"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Ranji",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ganemulla",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Warna Jayasundara",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "CR Para Mullage",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "’’ගෝරිල්ලා රංජි’’  සහ සහෝදරයා මත්කුඩු සමග මාට්ටූ",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "සංවිධානාත්මක අපරාධ හා මත්ද්‍රව්‍ය ජාලය මෙහෙයවන නායකයෙකු වන සින්නයියා ගුණසේකරම් නොහොත් කිඹුලාඇලේ ගුණා ගෙ ප්‍රධාන ගෝලයන් දෙදෙනෙකු වන එකම පවුලේ සහෝදරයන් දෙදෙනෙකු රුපියල් ලක්ෂ 8 කට ආසන්න වටිනා හොරයින් මත්කුඩු තොගයක් සමග  අත්අඩංගුවට ගත් බව පොලිස් විශේෂ කාර්ය බළකාය පවසයි.",
        "මෙලෙස අත්අඩංගුවට ගෙන ඇත්තේ  රත්නම් රංජිත් කුමාර් නොහොත් \"ගෝරිල්ලා රංජි\" නැමැත්තා  සහ ඔහුගේ සහෝදරයා බව පොලිසිය කියයි",
        "එම පුද්ගලයන් සන්තකයේ තිබී හොරයින් මත්කුඩු ගෑම්  74 මිලිග්‍රෑම්  880 ක්  පොලිසිය භාරයට ගෙන ඇත",
        "දකුණු ඉන්දියාව හා මෙරට ආරක්ෂක අංශ ඒකාබද්ධව සිදුකළ මෙහෙයුමකදී  අත්අඩංගුවට ගත් සංවිධානාත්මක අපරාධ කල්ලි නායකයකු වන සින්නයියා ගුණසේකරම් නොහොත් කිඹුලා ඇලේ ගුණා නැමැත්තා ගේ  මත්ද්‍රව්‍ය ජාලය මෙහෙයවන්නෙ රත්නම්  රංජිත් කුමාර් නොහොත් \"ගෝරිල්ලා  රංජි \"බව පොලිසිය කියයි.",
        "පොලිස් විශේෂ කාර්ය බලකා සංවිධානාත්මක අපරාධ මර්ධන ඒකක 2හි නිලධාරීන්ට ලද තොරතුරකට අනුව එහි ස්ථානාධිපති පොලිස් පරීක්ෂක සි ආර් පාරමුල්ලගේ  මහතා ඇතුළු නිලධාරීන් කණ්ඩායමක්  බ්ලූමැන්ඩල් පොලිස් වසමේ මාදම්පිටිය ප්‍රදේශයේ සිදුකළ වැටලීමකදී  සැකකරුවන් දෙදෙනා අත්අඩංගුවට ගෙන ඇත.",
        "ඉකුත් දොළොස්වෙනි දින මාදම්පිටිය ප්‍රදේශයේ දී සිය බිරිඳ සමඟ යතුරුපැදියකින් ගමන් කරමින් සිටි ප්‍රදීපන් නැමැති පුද්ගලයාට වෙඩි තබා ඝාතනය කිරීම සඳහා  උපදෙස් ලබා ලබාදී ඇත්තේ රත්නම් රංජිත් කුමාර නොහොත්   ගෝරිල්ලා රංජි බව  විමර්ශනවලදී අනාවරණය වූ බව පොලිසිය කියයි.",
        "අත්අඩංගුවට ගත් ගෝරිල්ලා  රංජි ගේ සහෝදරයා  ගණේමුල්ල  පදිංචිකරුවෙකු බවත් පොලිසිය පනසයි.",
        "පොලිස් විශේෂ කාර්යය බලකා අණදෙන නිලධාරී නියෝජ්‍ය පොලිස්පති නීතිඥ වර්ණ ජයසුන්දර මහතාගේ නියෝග හා උපදෙස් පරිදි විශේෂ කාර්ය බලකා සංවිධානාත්මක අපරාධ මර්දනය ඒකක දෙකෙහි 2හි ස්ථානාධිපතිවරයාට දෙකෙහි ස්ථානාධිපති පොලිස් පරීක්ෂක සි ආර් පාර මුල්ලගේ මහතා ඇතුළු කණ්ඩායමක් සැකකරුවන් අත්අඩංගුවට ගෙන ඇත."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "රංජි",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "දෙක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "දෙක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "සින්නයියා ගුණසේකරම්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "කිඹුලාලේ ගුණ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "සංවිධානාත්මක අපරාධ සහ මත්ද්‍රව්‍ය ජාලය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ආසන්න වශයෙන් 8",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "රත්නම් රංජිත් කුමාර",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "රංජි",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "74",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "880",
            "label": "FAC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "සින්නයියා ගුණසේකරම්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "දකුණු ඉන්දියාව",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "2",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "සීආර් පරමුල්ලගේ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "දෙක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "දොළොස්වන",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "අවසන් දිනය",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "රත්නම් රංජිත්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "aka Gorilla Ranji",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ප්‍රදීපන්",
            "label": "WORK_OF_ART"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "රංජි",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගනේමුල්ල",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "වර්ණ ජයසුන්දර",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "සීආර් පැරා මුල්ලගේ",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "\"கொரில்லா ரஞ்சி\" மற்றும் அவரது சகோதரர் போதைப்பொருளால் கொல்லப்பட்டனர்",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "ஒழுங்கமைக்கப்பட்ட குற்றங்கள் மற்றும் போதைப்பொருள் வலையமைப்பை நடத்தும் தலைவரான சின்னையா குணசேகரம் அல்லது கிம்புலாலே குணாவின் பிரதான சீடர்களான ஒரே குடும்பத்தைச் சேர்ந்த சகோதரர்கள் இருவர், ஏறக்குறைய பெறுமதியான போதைப்பொருளுடன் கைது செய்யப்பட்டுள்ளதாக பொலிஸ் விசேட அதிரடிப்படை தெரிவித்துள்ளது. 8 லட்சம் ரூபாய்.",
        "கைது செய்யப்பட்டவர்கள் “கொரில்லா ரஞ்சி” எனப்படும் ரத்னம் ரஞ்சித் குமார் மற்றும் அவரது சகோதரர் என பொலிஸார் தெரிவிக்கின்றனர்.",
        "அந்த நபர்களிடம் இருந்து 74 880 மில்லி கிராம் போதைப்பொருளை பொலிஸார் கைப்பற்றியுள்ளனர்.",
        "தென்னிந்தியா மற்றும் இலங்கை பாதுகாப்புப் படையினரால் நடத்தப்பட்ட கூட்டு நடவடிக்கையில் கைது செய்யப்பட்ட ஒரு ஒழுங்கமைக்கப்பட்ட குற்றக் கும்பல் தலைவரான சின்னையா குணசேகரம் அல்லது கிம்புலா அலே குண நேமட்டாவின் போதைப்பொருள் வலையமைப்பை \"கொரில்லா ரஞ்சி\" என்ற ரத்தினம் ரஞ்சித் குமார் நடத்துகிறார் என்று காவல்துறை கூறுகிறது.",
        "பொலிஸ் விசேட அதிரடிப்படையின் ஒழுங்கமைக்கப்பட்ட குற்றத்தடுப்பு பிரிவு 2 அதிகாரிகளுக்கு கிடைத்த தகவலின் பிரகாரம், நிலைய கட்டளைத் தளபதி பொலிஸ் பரிசோதகர் சி.ஆர்.பரமுல்லகே உள்ளிட்ட அதிகாரிகள் குழுவினர், புளூமண்டல் பொலிஸ் பிரிவிற்குட்பட்ட மாதம்பிட்டிய பகுதியில் மேற்கொண்ட சுற்றிவளைப்பின் போது சந்தேக நபர்கள் இருவரையும் கைது செய்துள்ளனர்.",
        "கடந்த பன்னிரண்டாம் திகதி மாதம்பிட்டிய பகுதியில், தனது மனைவியுடன் மோட்டார் சைக்கிளில் சென்ற பிரதீபன் என்ற நபரை சுட்டுக் கொல்லுமாறு கொரில்லா ரஞ்சி என்ற ரட்னம் ரஞ்சித் குமார் பணிப்புரை வழங்கியதாக பொலிஸார் தெரிவித்தனர்.",
        "கைது செய்யப்பட்ட கொரில்லா ரஞ்சியின் சகோதரர் கணேமுல்லையில் வசிப்பவர் என்றும் பொலிஸார் நம்புகின்றனர்.",
        "பொலிஸ் விசேட அதிரடிப்படையின் கட்டளை அதிகாரியான DIG சட்டத்தரணி திரு. வர்ண ஜயசுந்தரவின் உத்தரவு மற்றும் அறிவுறுத்தல்களின்படி, விசேட அதிரடிப்படையின் ஒழுங்கமைக்கப்பட்ட குற்றப்பிரிவு 2 இன் நிலைய கட்டளைத் தளபதி, பொலிஸ் பரிசோதகர் CR பரா முல்லகே உள்ளிட்ட குழுவினர் சந்தேக நபர்களை கைது செய்தனர்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ரஞ்சி",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "இரண்டு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "இரண்டு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "சின்னையா குணசேகரம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "கிம்புலாலே குணா",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஒழுங்கமைக்கப்பட்ட குற்றம் மற்றும் போதைப்பொருள் வலையமைப்பு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "கிட்டத்தட்ட 8",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ரத்னம் ரஞ்சித் குமார்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரஞ்சி",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "74",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "880",
            "label": "FAC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "சின்னையா குணசேகரம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "தென் இந்தியா",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "2",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "சிஆர் பரமுல்லகே",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இரண்டு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பன்னிரண்டாவது",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "கடைசி நாள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரத்னம் ரஞ்சித்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "aka Gorilla Ranji",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "பிரதீபன்",
            "label": "WORK_OF_ART"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ரஞ்சி",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "கணேமுல்ல",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "வர்ண ஜெயசுந்தர",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "சிஆர் பாரா முல்லேஜ்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}