{
  "newspaper_id": "virakesari-lk",
  "url": "http://www.virakesari.lk/article/130770",
  "time_ut": 1656929883,
  "original_lang": "ta",
  "original_title": "வவுனியா ரயில் விபத்தில் குடும்பஸ்தர் பரிதாபமாக உயிரிழப்பு",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Family members tragically lost their lives in Vavuniya train accident",
      "author": "T Yuwaraj",
      "body_lines": [
        "A family member tragically died in a train accident in Vavuniya Chettikulam area today.",
        "The accident occurred today (04) afternoon when the train from Colombo to Thalaimannar was traveling in Vavuniya Chettikulam area.",
        "The family member who was injured in the accident was immediately rescued and admitted to the Chettikulam Divisional Hospital, but he died without treatment.",
        "A 33-year-old family member named Ruksan from Gandhinagar area died in the incident. It is to be noted that he is the Chettikulam Regional Coordinator of the Tamil Eelam Liberation Movement (SIRRELO).",
        "It is noteworthy that the train continued its journey only after a delay of a few hours due to the accident."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Vavuniya",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Vavuniya Chettikulam",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "04) afternoon",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "Thalaimannar",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Vavuniya Chettikulam",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the Chettikulam Divisional Hospital",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "33-year-old",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ruksan",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Chettikulam Regional Coordinator",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Tamil Eelam Liberation Movement",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "a few hours",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "වවුනියාව දුම්රිය අනතුරින් පවුලේ සාමාජිකයින්ට ඛේදජනක ලෙස ජීවිත අහිමි විය",
      "author": "ටී යුවරාජ්",
      "body_lines": [
        "වව්නියාව චෙට්ටිකුලම ප්‍රදේශයේදී අද සිදුවූ දුම්රිය අනතුරකින් පවුලේ සාමාජිකයෙකු අවාසනාවන්ත ලෙස මිය ගියා.",
        "අද (04) පස්වරුවේ කොළඹ සිට තලෙයිමන්නාරම බලා ධාවනය වූ දුම්රිය වවුනියාව චෙට්ටිකුලම ප්‍රදේශයේදී ධාවනය වෙමින් තිබියදී මෙම අනතුර සිදුව තිබේ.",
        "අනතුරින් තුවාල ලැබූ පවුලේ සාමාජිකයා වහා බේරාගෙන චෙට්ටිකුලම ප්‍රාදේශීය රෝහලට ඇතුළත් කර ඇතත් ප්‍රතිකාර නොලබා ඔහු මිය ගියේය.",
        "සිද්ධියෙන් මියගොස් ඇත්තේ ගාන්ධිනගර් ප්‍රදේශයේ පදිංචි 33 හැවිරිදි රුක්සාන් නමැති පවුලේ සාමාජිකයෙකි. ඔහු දෙමළ ඊළාම් විමුක්ති ව්‍යාපාරයේ (SIRRELO) චෙට්ටිකුලම් ප්‍රාදේශීය සම්බන්ධීකාරකවරයා බව සඳහන් කළ යුතුය.",
        "අනතුර හේතුවෙන් පැය කිහිපයක ප්‍රමාදයකින් පසුව පමණක් දුම්රිය ගමනාගමනය සිදු කිරීම විශේෂත්වයකි."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "වවුනියාව",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "වවුනියාව චෙට්ටිකුලම",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "04) සවස",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "තලෙයිමන්නාරම",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "වවුනියාව චෙට්ටිකුලම",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "චෙට්ටිකුලම් ප්‍රාදේශීය රෝහල",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "33 හැවිරිදිය",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "රුක්සාන්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "චෙට්ටිකුලම් ප්‍රාදේශීය සම්බන්ධීකාරක",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "දෙමළ ඊළාම් විමුක්ති ව්‍යාපාරය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "පැය කිහිපයක්",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "வவுனியா ரயில் விபத்தில் குடும்பஸ்தர் பரிதாபமாக உயிரிழப்பு",
      "author": "T Yuwaraj",
      "body_lines": [
        "வவுனியா செட்டிகுளம் பகுதியில் இன்று இடம்பெற்ற ரயில் விபத்தில் குடும்பஸ்தர் ஒருவர் பரிதாபகரமாக மரணமடைந்துள்ளார்.",
        "இன்று(04) பிற்பகல் கொழும்பில் இருந்து தலைமன்னார் நோக்கி சென்ற ரயில் வவுனியா செட்டிகுளம் பகுதியில் சென்று கொண்டிருந்த போது குறித்த விபத்து இடம்பெற்றுள்ளது.",
        "விபத்தில் காயமடைந்த குடும்பஸ்தர் உடனடியாக மீட்கப்பட்டு செட்டிகுளம் பிரதேச வைத்தியாசாலையில் அனுமதிக்கப்பட்ட போதிலும் அவர் சிகிச்சை பலனின்றி மரணமடைந்தார்.",
        "சம்பவத்தில் காந்திநகர் பகுதியை சேர்ந்த 33 வயதான ருக்சன் என்ற குடும்பஸ்தரே மரணமடைந்துள்ளார். அவர் தமிழ் ஈழ விடுதலை இயக்கத்தின் (சிறிரெலோ) செட்டிகுளம் பிரதேச இணைப்பாளர் என்பது குறிப்பிடத்தக்கது.",
        "விபத்து காரணமாக சில மணி நேர தாமதத்தின் பின்னரே ரயில் தனது பயணத்தை தொடர்ந்திருந்தமை குறிப்பிடத்தக்கது."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "வவுனியா",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "வவுனியா செட்டிக்குளம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "04) பிற்பகல்",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "தலைமன்னார்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "வவுனியா செட்டிக்குளம்",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "செட்டிகுளம் பிரதேச வைத்தியசாலை",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "33 வயது",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ருக்ஸான்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "செட்டிகுளம் பிராந்திய இணைப்பாளர்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "தமிழீழ விடுதலை இயக்கம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஒரு சில மணி நேரம்",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}