{
  "newspaper_id": "d-b-s-jeyaraj-com",
  "url": "https://dbsjeyaraj.com/dbsj/archives/79326",
  "time_ut": 1662058620,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Ex-president Gotabaya Rajapaksa Returns to Sri Lanka From Thailand by Singapore Airlines Flight; ariives at Katunayake Airport amidst tight security ;welcomed by SLPP MPs ,ministers and ex-ministers who take him to Colombo in a motorcade",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Ex-president Gotabaya Rajapaksa Returns to Sri Lanka From Thailand by Singapore Airlines Flight; ariives at Katunayake Airport amidst tight security ;welcomed by SLPP MPs ,ministers and ex-ministers who take him to Colombo in a motorcade",
      "author": "Administrator",
      "body_lines": [
        "Former Sri Lankan president Gotabaya Rajapaksa on Friday returned to the country from Thailand, nearly two months after he fled the country following a massive uprising against his government over the island nation’s worst-ever economic crisis.",
        "Mr. Rajapaksa, 73, fled the country on July 13 after months-long mass public demonstrations demanding his immediate resignation on July 9 gained momentum after protesters stormed the President’s House in Colombo and several other state buildings in the capital.",
        "Mr. Rajapaksa arrived at the Bandaranaike International Airport amidst a heavy security presence. After being received at the airport by several ministers and Parliamentarians of the ruling Sri Lanka Podujana Peramuna (SLPP) party, Mr. Rajapaksa left the airport in a heavily-guarded motorcade.",
        "The ex-president returned to Sri Lanka on a Singapore Airlines flight. He travelled from Thailand to Singapore to take the flight as there are no direct flights between Bangkok and Colombo, sources said.",
        "Mr. Rajapaksa will be living in a state bungalow close to Wijerama Mawatha in Colombo while a large security contingency will be appointed to maintain security in the area, Daily Mirror Lanka reported.",
        "As a former president, Mr. Rajapaksa is entitled to a government house, security and other privileges.",
        "Mr. Rajapaksa fled Sri Lanka to the Maldives on a Sri Lanka Airforce plane and then proceeded to Singapore, from where he sent in his resignation on July 14.",
        "Later, he flew to Thailand, seeking temporary shelter. Thailand had said that Mr. Rajapaksa can stay in the country for 90 days because he is still a diplomatic passport holder.",
        "However, Mr. Rajapaksa was not allowed to engage in political activities in Thailand. He was confined to a hotel and surrounded by security personnel.",
        "Local media reports on August 19 quoted Mr. Rajapaksa’s Sri Lanka Podujana Peramuna SLPP General Secretary Sagara Kariyawasam as saying that his party had requested the president to facilitate the former president’s return and “ensure security and necessary facilities”.",
        "After Mr. Rajapaksa was ousted, Sri Lanka’s parliament elected then-Acting President and six-time former Prime Minister Ranil Wickremesinghe as the new Head of State.",
        "Mr. Wickremesinghe has a mandate to serve out the rest of Mr. Rajapaksa’s term, which ends in November 2024.",
        "Mr. Rajapaksa, an ex-military officer, became president in November 2019.",
        "Sri Lanka is going through its worst economic crisis since its independence in 1948 which was triggered by a severe paucity of foreign exchange reserves.",
        "The IMF on Thursday announced that it will provide Sri Lanka with a loan of about $2.9 billion over four years under a preliminary agreement to help the bankrupt island nation tide over its worst economic crisis and protect the livelihoods of the people."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Gotabaya Rajapaksa Returns",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "Sri Lanka",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "Thailand",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "Singapore Airlines Flight",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "Katunayake Airport",
          "label": "FAC"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lankan",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Gotabaya Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Friday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Thailand",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "nearly two months",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "73",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "July 13 after months-long",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "July 9",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "House",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Colombo",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Bandaranaike International Airport",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliamentarians",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "Podujana Peramuna",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Singapore Airlines",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Thailand",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Singapore",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Bangkok",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Colombo",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Wijerama Mawatha",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Colombo",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Daily Mirror Lanka",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Singapore",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "July 14",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Thailand",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Thailand",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "90 days",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Thailand",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "August 19",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "Podujana Peramuna",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sagara Kariyawasam",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka’s",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "six",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "State",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "November 2024",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "November 2019",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "1948",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Thursday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "about $2.9 billion",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "four years",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "හිටපු ජනාධිපති ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ තායිලන්තයේ සිට සිංගප්පූරු ගුවන් යානයෙන් ශ්‍රී ලංකාවට පැමිණෙයි; දැඩි ආරක්‍ෂාව මධ්‍යයේ කටුනායක ගුවන් තොටුපළට පැමිණෙයි; ශ්‍රී ලංකා පොදුජන පෙරමුණේ මැති ඇමතිවරුන් සහ හිටපු ඇමතිවරුන් විසින් පිළිගනු ලබන අතර ඔහුව රථ පෙළපාලියකින් කොළඹට රැගෙන යයි",
      "author": "පරිපාලක",
      "body_lines": [
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකා හිටපු ජනාධිපති ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ සිකුරාදා තායිලන්තයේ සිට ආපසු දිවයිනට පැමිණියේ දිවයින ජාතියේ දරුණුතම ආර්ථික අර්බුදය සම්බන්ධයෙන් තම රජයට එරෙහි දැවැන්ත නැගිටීමෙන් පසු රටින් පලා ගොස් මාස දෙකකට පමණ පසුවය.",
        "73 හැවිරිදි රාජපක්ෂ මහතා, ජුලි 9 වැනි දින, කොළඹ ජනාධිපති මන්දිරයට සහ අගනුවර තවත් රාජ්‍ය ගොඩනැගිලි කිහිපයකට කඩා වැදීමෙන් පසු, ජුලි 9 වැනි දින ඔහුට වහා ඉල්ලා අස්වන ලෙස බලකරමින් මාස ගනනාවක් තිස්සේ පැවති මහජන මහජන උද්ඝෝෂණ වලින් පසු ජුලි 13 දින රටින් පලා ගියේය.",
        "රාජපක්ෂ මහතා දැඩි ආරක්ෂක රැකවල් මධ්‍යයේ බණ්ඩාරනායක ජාත්‍යන්තර ගුවන් තොටුපළ වෙත ළඟා විය. පාලක ශ්‍රී ලංකා පොදුජන පෙරමුණේ (SLPP) මැති ඇමතිවරුන් කිහිප දෙනෙකු විසින් ගුවන් තොටුපළේදී පිළිගැනීමෙන් අනතුරුව දැඩි ආරක්ෂක රථ පෙළපාලියකින් රාජපක්ෂ මහතා ගුවන් තොටුපළෙන් පිටත් විය.",
        "හිටපු ජනාධිපතිවරයා සිංගප්පූරු ගුවන් සේවයට අයත් ගුවන් යානයකින් යළි ශ්‍රී ලංකාවට පැමිණියේය. බැංකොක් සහ කොළඹ අතර සෘජු ගුවන් ගමන් නොමැති නිසා ඔහු තායිලන්තයේ සිට සිංගප්පූරුවට ගොස් ඇති බව ආරංචි මාර්ග පවසයි.",
        "රාජපක්ෂ මහතා කොළඹ විජේරාම මාවතට නුදුරින් පිහිටි රජයේ බංගලාවක පදිංචිව සිටින අතර ප්‍රදේශයේ ආරක්‍ෂාව සඳහා විශාල ආරක්‍ෂක භට පිරිසක් පත් කිරීමට නියමිත බව ඩේලි මිරර් ලංකා වාර්තා කරයි.",
        "හිටපු ජනාධිපතිවරයෙකු ලෙස රාජපක්ෂ මහතාට රජයේ නිවසක්, ආරක්ෂාව සහ වෙනත් වරප්‍රසාද හිමිවේ.",
        "රාජපක්ෂ මහතා ශ්‍රී ලංකා ගුවන් හමුදාවට අයත් ගුවන් යානයකින් ශ්‍රී ලංකාවෙන් මාලදිවයිනට පලා ගොස් සිංගප්පූරුවට ගිය අතර, එතැන් සිට ජූලි 14 වැනි දින සිය ඉල්ලා අස්වීමේ ලිපිය යවා ඇත.",
        "පසුව ඔහු තාවකාලික නවාතැන් පතා තායිලන්තයට පියාසර කළේය. රාජපක්ෂ මහතා තවමත් රාජ්‍ය තාන්ත්‍රික විදේශ ගමන් බලපත්‍ර හිමියෙකු බැවින් ඔහුට දින 90ක් මෙරට රැඳී සිටිය හැකි බව තායිලන්තය පවසා තිබුණි.",
        "කෙසේ වෙතත්, රාජපක්ෂ මහතාට තායිලන්තයේ දේශපාලන කටයුතුවල නිරත වීමට ඉඩ ලබා දුන්නේ නැහැ. ඔහු හෝටලයකට කොටු වූ අතර ආරක්ෂක නිලධාරීන් විසින් වට කරන ලදී.",
        "රාජපක්ෂ මහතාගේ ශ්‍රී ලංකා පොදුජන පෙරමුණේ ශ්‍රී ලංකා පොදුජන පෙරමුණේ ප්‍රධාන ලේකම් සාගර කාරියවසම් මහතා උපුටා දක්වමින් අගෝස්තු 19 වැනි දින ප්‍රාදේශීය මාධ්‍ය වාර්තා කළේ, හිටපු ජනාධිපතිවරයාගේ නැවත පැමිණීමට පහසුකම් සපයන ලෙසත් “ආරක්ෂාව සහ අවශ්‍ය පහසුකම් සහතික කරන ලෙසත්” තම පක්ෂය ජනාධිපතිවරයාගෙන් ඉල්ලා ඇති බවයි.",
        "රාජපක්ෂ මහතා නෙරපා හැරීමෙන් පසු, ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ පාර්ලිමේන්තුව විසින් නව රාජ්‍ය නායකයා ලෙස එවකට වැඩබලන ජනාධිපති සහ හය වතාවක් හිටපු අගමැති රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ තේරී පත් විය.",
        "2024 නොවැම්බරයෙන් අවසන් වන රාජපක්ෂ මහතාගේ ඉතිරි ධූර කාලය ද ඉටු කිරීමට වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතාට ජනවරමක් ඇත.",
        "හිටපු හමුදා නිලධාරියෙකු වූ රාජපක්ෂ මහතා 2019 නොවැම්බර් මාසයේදී ජනාධිපති විය.",
        "1948 නිදහස ලැබීමෙන් පසු ශ්‍රී ලංකාව එහි දරුණුතම ආර්ථික අර්බුදයට මුහුණ දෙමින් සිටින අතර එය විදේශ විනිමය සංචිතවල උග්‍ර හිඟයක් නිසා ඇති විය.",
        "බංකොලොත් දූපත් ජාතියට එහි දරුණුතම ආර්ථික අර්බුදයෙන් මිදීමට සහ ජනතාවගේ ජීවනෝපාය ආරක්ෂා කිරීමට මූලික ගිවිසුමක් යටතේ වසර හතරක් තුළ ශ්‍රී ලංකාවට ඩොලර් බිලියන 2.9 ක පමණ ණයක් ලබා දෙන බව IMF බ්‍රහස්පතින්දා නිවේදනය කළේය."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ යළි එයි",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "තායිලන්තය",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "සිංගප්පූරු ගුවන් සේවය",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "කටුනායක ගුවන් තොටුපළ",
          "label": "FAC"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලාංකික",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "සිකුරාදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "තායිලන්තය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මාස දෙකකට ආසන්න කාලයක්",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "73",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මාස ගණනාවකට පසු ජූලි 13",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජූලි 9",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "නිවස",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "කොළඹ",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "බණ්ඩාරනායක ජාත්‍යන්තර ගුවන්තොටුපළ",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තු මන්ත්‍රීවරු",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "පොදුජන පෙරමුණ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "සිංගප්පූරු ගුවන් සේවය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "තායිලන්තය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "සිංගප්පූරුව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "බැංකොක්",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "කොළඹ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "විජේරාම මාවත",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "කොළඹ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඩේලි මිරර් ලංකා",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "සිංගප්පූරුව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජූලි 14",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "තායිලන්තය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "තායිලන්තය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "දින 90 යි",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "තායිලන්තය",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "අගෝස්තු 19",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "පොදුජන පෙරමුණ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "සාගර කාරියවසම්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "හය",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "රජයේ",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "2024 නොවැම්බර්",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "2019 නොවැම්බර්",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "1948",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "බ්රහස්පතින්දා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඩොලර් බිලියන 2.9 ක් පමණ",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "අවුරුදු හතරක්",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "முன்னாள் ஜனாதிபதி கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ச தாய்லாந்தில் இருந்து சிங்கப்பூர் ஏர்லைன்ஸ் விமானம் மூலம் இலங்கை திரும்பினார்; பலத்த பாதுகாப்புக்கு மத்தியில் கட்டுநாயக்க விமான நிலையத்திற்கு வருகை; SLPP பாராளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர்கள், அமைச்சர்கள் மற்றும் முன்னாள் அமைச்சர்கள் அவரை மோட்டார் வாகன பேரணியில் கொழும்புக்கு அழைத்து சென்றனர்",
      "author": "நிர்வாகி",
      "body_lines": [
        "இலங்கையின் முன்னாள் ஜனாதிபதி கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ச, தீவு நாட்டின் மிக மோசமான பொருளாதார நெருக்கடி தொடர்பாக தனது அரசாங்கத்திற்கு எதிரான பாரிய கிளர்ச்சியைத் தொடர்ந்து நாட்டை விட்டு வெளியேறிய சுமார் இரண்டு மாதங்களுக்குப் பிறகு, வெள்ளிக்கிழமை தாய்லாந்தில் இருந்து நாடு திரும்பினார்.",
        "73 வயதான திரு. ராஜபக்சே, ஜூலை 9 அன்று கொழும்பில் உள்ள ஜனாதிபதி மாளிகை மற்றும் தலைநகரில் உள்ள பல அரச கட்டிடங்களை எதிர்ப்பாளர்கள் முற்றுகையிட்டதை அடுத்து, ஜூலை 9 அன்று அவர் உடனடியாக பதவி விலகக் கோரி பல மாதங்களாக நடந்த வெகுஜன பொது ஆர்ப்பாட்டங்களுக்குப் பிறகு ஜூலை 13 அன்று நாட்டை விட்டு வெளியேறினார்.",
        "பலத்த பாதுகாப்புக்கு மத்தியில் பண்டாரநாயக்கா சர்வதேச விமான நிலையத்தை வந்தடைந்த திரு. ஆளும் ஸ்ரீலங்கா பொதுஜன பெரமுன (SLPP) கட்சியின் பல அமைச்சர்கள் மற்றும் நாடாளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர்களால் விமான நிலையத்தில் வரவேற்கப்பட்ட பின்னர், திரு. ராஜபக்ஷ பலத்த பாதுகாப்புடன் விமான நிலையத்திலிருந்து புறப்பட்டார்.",
        "சிங்கப்பூர் ஏர்லைன்ஸ் விமானத்தில் முன்னாள் ஜனாதிபதி இலங்கை திரும்பினார். பாங்காக் மற்றும் கொழும்பு இடையே நேரடி விமானங்கள் இல்லாததால் அவர் தாய்லாந்தில் இருந்து சிங்கப்பூருக்கு விமானத்தில் பயணம் செய்ததாக தகவல்கள் தெரிவிக்கின்றன.",
        "கொழும்பில் உள்ள விஜேராம மாவத்தைக்கு அருகில் உள்ள அரச பங்களா ஒன்றில் திரு. ராஜபக்ச வசிப்பார் என்றும், அப்பகுதியில் பாதுகாப்பைப் பேணுவதற்கு பாரிய பாதுகாப்புப் படையொன்று நியமிக்கப்படும் என்றும் டெய்லி மிரர் லங்கா தெரிவித்துள்ளது.",
        "ஒரு முன்னாள் ஜனாதிபதியாக, திரு. ராஜபக்சவுக்கு அரசாங்க வீடு, பாதுகாப்பு மற்றும் இதர சலுகைகள் உள்ளன.",
        "திரு. ராஜபக்சே இலங்கை விமானப்படை விமானத்தில் இலங்கையிலிருந்து மாலத்தீவுக்கு தப்பிச் சென்று பின்னர் சிங்கப்பூர் சென்றார், அங்கிருந்து ஜூலை 14 அன்று ராஜினாமா கடிதம் அனுப்பினார்.",
        "பின்னர், அவர் தற்காலிக தங்குமிடம் தேடி தாய்லாந்து சென்றார். ராஜபக்ச இன்னும் ராஜதந்திர கடவுச்சீட்டு வைத்திருப்பவர் என்பதால் அவர் 90 நாட்கள் நாட்டில் தங்கலாம் என்று தாய்லாந்து கூறியிருந்தது.",
        "எனினும், தாய்லாந்தில் அரசியல் நடவடிக்கைகளில் ஈடுபடுவதற்கு திரு. அவர் ஒரு ஹோட்டலில் அடைத்து வைக்கப்பட்டார் மற்றும் பாதுகாப்புப் பணியாளர்களால் சூழப்பட்டார்.",
        "ஆகஸ்ட் 19 அன்று உள்ளூர் ஊடக அறிக்கைகள் திரு. ராஜபக்சவின் ஸ்ரீலங்கா பொதுஜன பெரமுன SLPP பொதுச் செயலாளர் சாகர காரியவசம், முன்னாள் ஜனாதிபதியின் நாடு திரும்புவதற்கு வசதி செய்து தருமாறும், \"பாதுகாப்பு மற்றும் தேவையான வசதிகளை உறுதி செய்யுமாறு\" ஜனாதிபதியிடம் கோரிக்கை விடுத்ததாகக் கூறியதாகக் கூறியது.",
        "திரு. ராஜபக்சே வெளியேற்றப்பட்ட பிறகு, இலங்கையின் நாடாளுமன்றம் அப்போதைய செயல் அதிபரும் ஆறு முறை முன்னாள் பிரதமருமான ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்கவை புதிய அரச தலைவராகத் தேர்ந்தெடுத்தது.",
        "2024 நவம்பரில் முடிவடையும் திரு. ராஜபக்சேவின் எஞ்சிய பதவிக் காலத்தை நிறைவேற்ற திரு. விக்கிரமசிங்கவுக்கு ஆணை உள்ளது.",
        "முன்னாள் ராணுவ அதிகாரியான திரு. ராஜபக்சே 2019 நவம்பரில் அதிபரானார்.",
        "1948 ஆம் ஆண்டு சுதந்திரம் பெற்ற பின்னர், அந்நிய செலாவணி கையிருப்பின் கடுமையான பற்றாக்குறையால் தூண்டப்பட்ட மிக மோசமான பொருளாதார நெருக்கடியை இலங்கை சந்தித்து வருகிறது.",
        "திவாலான தீவு தேசத்தின் மோசமான பொருளாதார நெருக்கடியில் இருந்து விடுபடவும், மக்களின் வாழ்வாதாரத்தைப் பாதுகாக்கவும் உதவும் பூர்வாங்க ஒப்பந்தத்தின் கீழ் நான்கு ஆண்டுகளில் சுமார் 2.9 பில்லியன் டாலர் கடனை இலங்கைக்கு வழங்குவதாக IMF வியாழன் அன்று அறிவித்தது."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ச நாடு திரும்புகிறார்",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "இலங்கை",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "தாய்லாந்து",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "சிங்கப்பூர் ஏர்லைன்ஸ் விமானம்",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "கட்டுநாயக்க விமான நிலையம்",
          "label": "FAC"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "வெள்ளி",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "தாய்லாந்து",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "கிட்டத்தட்ட இரண்டு மாதங்கள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ராஜபக்சே",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "73",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "பல மாதங்கள் கழித்து ஜூலை 13",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜூலை 9",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "வீடு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "கொழும்பு",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ராஜபக்சே",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "பண்டாரநாயக்கா சர்வதேச விமான நிலையம்",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர்கள்",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "பொதுஜன பெரமுன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ராஜபக்சே",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சிங்கப்பூர் ஏர்லைன்ஸ்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "தாய்லாந்து",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சிங்கப்பூர்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாங்காக்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "கொழும்பு",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ராஜபக்சே",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "விஜேராம மாவத்தை",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "கொழும்பு",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "டெய்லி மிரர் லங்கா",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ராஜபக்சே",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ராஜபக்சே",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சிங்கப்பூர்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜூலை 14",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "தாய்லாந்து",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "தாய்லாந்து",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ராஜபக்சே",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "90 நாட்கள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ராஜபக்சே",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "தாய்லாந்து",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஆகஸ்ட் 19",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ராஜபக்சே",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "பொதுஜன பெரமுன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "சாகர காரியவசம்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ராஜபக்சே",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கையின்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆறு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "நிலை",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ராஜபக்சே",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "நவம்பர் 2024",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ராஜபக்சே",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "நவம்பர் 2019",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "1948",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "வியாழன்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சுமார் $2.9 பில்லியன்",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "நான்கு வருடங்கள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}