{
  "newspaper_id": "news-first-lk",
  "url": "https://www.newsfirst.lk/2022/07/08/rakna-arakshaka-lanka-ltd-moved-under-dhammika/",
  "time_ut": 1657277580,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Rakna Arakshaka Lanka Ltd moved under Dhammika",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Rakna Arakshaka Lanka Ltd moved under Dhammika",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); Rakna Arakshaka Lanka Ltd that was directly under the Ministry of Defence, was moved under the Ministry of Investment Promotion via an Extraordinary Gazette on Thursday (7) night.",
        "Certain agreements Rakna Arakshaka Lanka Ltd had inked to deploy its personnel, who are retired military servicemen from the three-armed forces and the police, for sea marshal services, led to controversy in the recent past.",
        "The tie-up between Rakna Arakshaka Lanka Limited (RALL) and the privately owned Avant Garde Maritime Services Ltd. (AGMSL) sparked serious concern during the Yahapala Administration.",
        "In addition, Selendiva Investments Ltd that was under the Ministry of Urban Development and Housing was also moved under the Ministry of Investment Promotion of which Dhammika Perera is the Minister.",
        "Hotel Developers (Lanka) Ltd, another a 100 % Government Owned company was also moved under Dhammika Perera.",
        "Multiple government property was lifted for investments via Selendiva Investments Ltd & Hotel Developers (Lanka) Ltd."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Rakna Arakshaka Lanka Ltd",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Rakna Arakshaka Lanka Ltd",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Ministry of Defence",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Ministry of Investment Promotion",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Thursday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "7) night",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Rakna Arakshaka Lanka Ltd",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "three",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Rakna Arakshaka Lanka Limited",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Avant Garde Maritime Services Ltd.",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "AGMSL",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Yahapala Administration",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Selendiva Investments Ltd",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Ministry of Urban Development and Housing",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Ministry of Investment Promotion",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Dhammika Perera",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "100 %",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "Dhammika Perera",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Selendiva Investments Ltd & Hotel Developers",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "සීමාසහිත රක්නා ආරක්ෂක ලංකා සමාගම ධම්මික යටතට පත් විය",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); සෘජුවම ආරක්‍ෂක අමාත්‍යාංශය යටතේ පැවති සීමාසහිත රක්නා ආරක්‍ෂක ලංකා සමාගම බ්‍රහස්පතින්දා (7) රාත්‍රියේ අති විශේෂ ගැසට් පත්‍රයක් මගින් ආයෝජන ප්‍රවර්ධන අමාත්‍යාංශය යටතට පත් කරන ලදී.",
        "සීමාසහිත රක්නා ආරක්ෂක ලංකා සමාගම ත්‍රිවිධ හමුදාවේ සහ පොලිසියේ විශ්‍රාමික හමුදා සෙබළුන් සී මාර්ෂල් සේවය සඳහා යෙදවීමට අත්සන් කර තිබූ ඇතැම් ගිවිසුම් පසුගිය කාලයේ ආන්දෝලනයට තුඩු දුන්නේය.",
        "Rakna Arakshaka Lanka Limited (RALL) සහ පුද්ගලිකව හිමි Avant Garde Maritime Services Ltd (AGMSL) අතර ඇති වූ සම්බන්ධය යහපාලන පරිපාලනය තුළ බරපතල කනස්සල්ලට හේතු විය.",
        "මීට අමතරව නාගරික සංවර්ධන හා නිවාස අමාත්‍යාංශය යටතේ තිබූ Selendiva Investments Ltd ආයතනය ද ධම්මික පෙරේරා අමාත්‍යවරයා වන ආයෝජන ප්‍රවර්ධන අමාත්‍යාංශය යටතට ගෙන යන ලදී.",
        "100% රජය සතු තවත් සමාගමක් වන Hotel Developers (Lanka) Ltd ද ධම්මික පෙරේරා යටතට ගෙන යන ලදී.",
        "Selendiva Investments Ltd සහ Hotel Developers (Lanka) Ltd හරහා රජයේ දේපළ කිහිපයක් ආයෝජන සඳහා ඉවත් කරන ලදී."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "සීමාසහිත රක්නා ආරක්ෂක ලංකා",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "සීමාසහිත රක්නා ආරක්ෂක ලංකා",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ආරක්ෂක අමාත්යාංශය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ආයෝජන ප්‍රවර්ධන අමාත්‍යාංශය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "බ්රහස්පතින්දා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "7) රාත්රිය",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "සීමාසහිත රක්නා ආරක්ෂක ලංකා",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "තුන්",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "සීමාසහිත රක්නා ආරක්ෂක ලංකා",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Avant Garde Maritime Services Ltd.",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "AGMSL",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "යහපාලන පරිපාලනය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Selendiva Investments Ltd",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "නාගරික සංවර්ධන හා නිවාස අමාත්‍යාංශය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ආයෝජන ප්‍රවර්ධන අමාත්‍යාංශය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ධම්මික පෙරේරා",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "100%",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "ධම්මික පෙරේරා",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Selendiva Investments Ltd සහ Hotel Developers",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "ரக்னா பாதுகாப்பு லங்கா லிமிடெட் தம்மிக்காவின் கீழ் மாறியது",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); பாதுகாப்பு அமைச்சின் கீழ் நேரடியாக இயங்கி வந்த ரக்னா பாதுகாப்பு லங்கா லிமிடெட், வியாழன் (7) இரவு ஒரு அசாதாரண வர்த்தமானி மூலம் முதலீட்டு ஊக்குவிப்பு அமைச்சின் கீழ் மாற்றப்பட்டது.",
        "Rakna Arakshaka Lanka Ltd, முப்படை மற்றும் பொலிஸில் இருந்து ஓய்வுபெற்ற இராணுவ வீரர்களை கடல் மார்ஷல் சேவைகளுக்காக ஈடுபடுத்துவதற்கு கையொப்பமிட்ட சில ஒப்பந்தங்கள் சமீப காலங்களில் சர்ச்சையை ஏற்படுத்தியது.",
        "Rakna Arakshaka Lanka Limited (RALL) மற்றும் தனியாருக்குச் சொந்தமான Avant Garde Maritime Services Ltd. (AGMSL) ஆகியவற்றுக்கு இடையேயான பிணைப்பு யஹபால நிர்வாகத்தின் போது கடுமையான கவலையைத் தூண்டியது.",
        "மேலும், நகர அபிவிருத்தி மற்றும் வீடமைப்பு அமைச்சின் கீழ் இருந்த Selendiva Investments Ltd நிறுவனமும் தம்மிக்க பெரேரா அமைச்சராக இருக்கும் முதலீட்டு ஊக்குவிப்பு அமைச்சின் கீழ் மாற்றப்பட்டது.",
        "ஹோட்டல் டெவலப்பர்ஸ் (லங்கா) லிமிடெட், 100% அரசாங்கத்திற்கு சொந்தமான மற்றொரு நிறுவனமும் தம்மிக்க பெரேராவின் கீழ் மாற்றப்பட்டது.",
        "செலண்டிவா இன்வெஸ்ட்மென்ட்ஸ் லிமிடெட் மற்றும் ஹோட்டல் டெவலப்பர்ஸ் (லங்கா) லிமிடெட் மூலம் முதலீடுகளுக்காக பல அரசாங்க சொத்துக்கள் அகற்றப்பட்டன."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ரக்னா பாதுகாப்பு லங்கா லிமிடெட்",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ரக்னா பாதுகாப்பு லங்கா லிமிடெட்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாதுகாப்பு அமைச்சகம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "முதலீட்டு ஊக்குவிப்பு அமைச்சகம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "வியாழன்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "7) இரவு",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ரக்னா பாதுகாப்பு லங்கா லிமிடெட்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "மூன்று",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ரக்னா பாதுகாப்பு லங்கா லிமிடெட்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Avant Garde Maritime Services Ltd.",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஏஜிஎம்எஸ்எல்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "யஹாபால நிர்வாகம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "செலண்டிவா இன்வெஸ்ட்மென்ட்ஸ் லிமிடெட்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "நகர்ப்புற வளர்ச்சி மற்றும் வீட்டுவசதி அமைச்சகம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "முதலீட்டு ஊக்குவிப்பு அமைச்சகம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "தம்மிக்க பெரேரா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "100 %",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "தம்மிக்க பெரேரா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Selendiva Investments Ltd & Hotel Developers",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}