{
  "newspaper_id": "lankadeepa-lk",
  "url": "https://www.lankadeepa.lk/latest_news/225ම-මැරා-ප්‍රශ්නය-විසැඳිය-හැකි-ද-/1-615586",
  "time_ut": 1656483645,
  "original_lang": "si",
  "original_title": "225ම මැරා ප්‍රශ්නය විසැඳිය හැකි ද?",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Is it possible to solve the problem by killing all 225?",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "Speaker Mahinda Yapa Abeywardena questioned whether the country's problems could be solved by killing the 225 members of parliament or setting fire to their houses.",
        "He was addressing a workshop for Parliamentary Journalists at the Cinnamon Grand Hotel in Colombo yesterday (28).",
        "The theme of the workshop was \"Parliament: Media: Public: Building Positive Correlation\" and was organized by the Department of Parliamentary Communications.",
        "He also said that there are people who are responsible for the problem that has arisen in the country at present.",
        "The Speaker said that the mob had destroyed a number of properties, including the houses of several members of parliament, and that the police and army were watching as the rioters proceeded.",
        "He also said that the barbaric incident of a group of men and women being stoned to death while trying to land on the Beira Lake was unacceptable.",
        "Mr. Mahinda Yapa Abeywardena said that it was difficult for MPs to even get to parliament today due to the oil crisis, adding that MPs from far-flung areas had to spend more than Rs. 40,000 a day on fuel.",
        "He said it was a big challenge to run the parliament in this situation.",
        "The Speaker said that it was important for the Members of Parliament to be exemplary and that the Members of Parliament today could set a great example by observing the past proceedings of Mr. NM Perera, Colvin R. de Silva or listening to their speeches.",
        "He also said that he had instructed the heads of the Parliamentary Library to compile the speeches of Colvin R. de Silva NM Perera and hand them over to the Members of Parliament.",
        "Addressing the workshop, Secretary General of Parliament Dhammika Dasanayake said that the media is the fourth government in a country.",
        "The Secretary General of Parliament said that the media today has a special role and responsibility for the people of a country and it is important to understand that responsibility and act accordingly.",
        "Mr. Dassmika Dassanayake said that it was important to prioritize important abstract speeches and programs in Parliament, and that by increasingly reporting and highlighting the issues at the outset, some MPs seemed to be behaving in such a manner in the hope of publicity.",
        "Chief of Staff to Parliament, Deputy Secretary General, Attorney-at-Law Kushani Rohanadeera said it was important to understand parliamentary privileges in reporting and to act accordingly.",
        "The Deputy Secretary General pointed out that various actions have been taken throughout history, including the imposition of fines on journalists and newspaper editors who report in violation of parliamentary privileges.",
        "Certificates were presented to the journalists who participated in the workshop by the Secretary General of Parliament Dhammika Dasanayake and the Assistant Secretary General Tikiri Jayatilleke.",
        "The workshop was attended by Assistant Secretary General of Parliament Tikiri Jayatilake, Director (Legislature) Janakantha Silva, Serjeant-at-Arms Narendra Fernando, Director of Parliament (Information Systems and Management) Mahesh Perera, Senior Journalist Shan Wijetunga and senior members of NDI. A group also commented.",
        "Mr. Lalith Adhikari, Chief Coordinating Engineer, Parliament and Mrs. Nimmi Hathiyaldeniya, Media Manager, Department of Parliamentary Communications were also present on the occasion."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "225",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Mahinda Yapa Abeywardena",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "225",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the Cinnamon Grand Hotel",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "yesterday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "28",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Department of Parliamentary Communications",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "the Beira Lake",
            "label": "LOC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Mahinda Yapa Abeywardena",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "40,000",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "the Members of Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "NM Perera",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Colvin R. de Silva",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Colvin R. de Silva NM",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Perera",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "fourth",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Dassmika Dassanayake",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "Tikiri Jayatilleke",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Tikiri Jayatilake",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Legislature",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Janakantha Silva",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament (Information Systems and Management",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Mahesh Perera",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Shan Wijetunga",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "NDI",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Lalith",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Nimmi Hathiyaldeniya",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Media Manager",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Department of Parliamentary Communications",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "225ම මැරා ප්‍රශ්නය විසැඳිය හැකි ද?",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "රටේ ප්‍රශ්න පාර්ලිමේන්තුවේ මන්ත්‍රීවරුන් 225 දෙනා මරා දැමීමෙන් හෝ ඔවුන්ගේ නිවාස ගිනි තැබීමෙන්  විසඳිය හැකි දැයි කතානායක මහින්ද යාපා අබේවර්ධන මහතා ප්‍රශ්න කළේය.",
        "කතානායකවරයා මෙසේ පැවසුවේ කොළඹ සිනමන් ග්‍රෑන්ඩ් හෝටලයේදී ඊයේ (28)   පැවැති  පාර්ලිමේන්තු මාධ්‍යවේදීන් සඳහාවූ   වැඩමුළුව අමතමිනි.",
        "\"පාර්ලිමේන්තුව:ජනමාධ්‍ය:මහජනතාව: ධනාත්මක සහසම්බන්ධයක් ගොඩනැගීම \"යන තේමාව යටතේ පැවැති  මෙම වැඩමුළුව සංවිධානය කරනු ලැබුවේ පාර්ලිමේන්තු සන්නිවේදන දෙපාර්තමේන්තුව  විසිනි.",
        "රටේ වර්තමානයේ උද්ගතව ඇති ප්‍රශ්නයට  වගකිවයුතු පිරිසක් සිටින බවද  ඔහු කීවේය.",
        "ප්‍රචණ්ඩකාරී පිරිස් විසින් මන්ත්‍රීවරුන් රැසකගේ නිවාස  ඇතුළු  දේපළ රැසක් විනාශ කරනු ලැබූ බවත්  ප්‍රචණ්ඩකාරීන්  මෙලෙස කටයුතු කරද්දී පොලිසිය හමුදාව ඔහේ බලාගෙන සිටිය බවත් කතානායකවරයා ප්‍රකාශ කළේය.",
        "පිරිමින් කාන්තාවන් පිරිසක්  බේරේ වැවට දමා  ගොඩට එන්න හදද්දි ගල්වලින් පහර දුන් ම්ලේච්ඡ සිද්ධිය  කිසිසේත්ම අනුමත කළ නොහැක්කක් බවද  හෙතෙම පැවසීය.",
        "තෙල් ප්‍රශ්නය නිසා මන්ත්‍රීවරුන්ට පාර්ලිමේන්තුවට පැමිණීම පවා අද දවසේ දුෂ්කරවී ඇතැයි පැවසූ  මහින්ද යාපා අබේවර්ධන මහතා ඈත දුර බැහැර ප්‍රදේශවල සිට පැමිණෙන මන්ත්‍රීවරුන්ට රුපියල්  40,000 කට වැඩි මුදලක් ඉන්ධන වෙනුවෙන් දෛනිකව වැය කිරීමට සිදුව ඇතැයිද  සඳහන් කළේය.",
        "මේ තත්වය යටතේ පාර්ලිමේන්තුවේ කටයුතු පවත්වාගෙන යෑමද විශාල අභියෝගයක් බව  ඔහු පැවසුවේය.",
        "පාර්ලිමේන්තු මන්ත්‍රීවරුන්  ඉතා ආදර්ශමත් පිරිසක් ලෙස කටයුතු කිරීම ඉතා වැදගත් බවත් ඇන් ඇම් පෙරේරා කොල්වින් ආර් ද සිල්වා යන මහත්වරුන් පාර්ලිමේන්තු සභාගර්භයේ අතීතයේ  කටයුතු කළ ආකාරය නිරීක්ෂණය කිරීමෙන් හෝ ඔවුන්ගේ කතා  ශ්‍රවණය කිරීමෙන් අද මන්ත්‍රීවරුන්ට ලොකු ආදර්ශයක් ලබාගත හැකි බවත්   කතානායකවරයා කීවේය.",
        "කොල්වින් ආර් ද සිල්වා ඇන් ඇම් පෙරේරා යන මහත්වරුන් ගේ පාර්ලිමේන්තු කතා  ඒකරාශී කර   මන්ත්‍රීවරුන්ට ලබා දෙන්නැයි  පාර්ලිමේන්තු පුස්තකාලයේ ප්‍රධානීන්ට තමා උපදෙස්දී ඇතැයිද හෙතෙම සඳහන් කළේය.",
        "මෙම වැඩමුළුව  ඇමතූ පාර්ලිමේන්තුවේ මහලේකම් ධම්මික දසනායක මහතා පැවසුවේ ජනමාධ්‍ය යනු  රටක සිවු වැනි   ආණ්ඩුව බවයි.",
        "රටක ජනතාව වෙනුවෙන් සුවිශේෂ කාර්යභාරයක් සහ  වගකීමක් ජනමාධ්‍ය වෙත අද දවසේ පැවරී ඇතැයි පැවසූ  පාර්ලිමේන්තු මහ ලේකම්වරයා ඒ වගකීම තේරුම් ගෙන  කටයුතු කිරීම වැදගත් බවද සඳහන් කළේය.",
        "පාර්ලිමේන්තුවේ වැදගත් සාරගර්භ කතා  සහ  වැඩසටහන් වලට   ප්‍රමුඛත්වයදී වාර්තා කිරීම ඉතා වැදගත් බවත්  එසේ නැතිව අවරගණයේ දේවල් වැඩි වැඩියෙන් වාර්තා කිරීමෙන් සහ  උලුප්පා  පෙන්වීමෙන් සමහර  මන්ත්‍රීවරුන් ප්‍රචාරයක් බලාපොරොත්තුවෙන් ඒ ආකාරයට දිගටම හැසිරෙන තත්වයක් පෙනෙන්නට ඇති  බවත්   ධම්මික දසනායක මහතා  පැවැසීය.",
        "පාර්ලිමේන්තුවේ කාර්ය මණ්ඩල ප්‍රධානී ,නියෝජ්‍ය මහලේකම් නීතිඥ  කුෂාණී  රෝහණදීර  මහත්මිය මෙහිදී පැවසුවේ වාර්තාකරණයේදී පාර්ලිමේන්තු වරප්‍රසාද ගැන  අවබෝධ කරගෙන  ඊට අනුකූලව කටයුතු කිරීම ඉතා වැදගත් බවයි.",
        "පාර්ලිමේන්තු වරප්‍රසාද උල්ලංඝනය කරමින්  වාර්තා කරන කටයුතුවල යෙදුණු ජනමාධ්‍යවේදීන්ට සහ පුවත්පත් කතුවරුන්ට දඩ මුදල් පැනවීම ඇතුළු  විවිධ ක්‍රියාමාර්ග ගැනීම ඉතිහාසය පුරා සිදුවී ඇති  බව පැවසූ නියෝජ්‍ය මහ ලේකම්වරිය  ඊට  උදාහරණ ගණනාවක්ද පෙන්වා දුන්නාය.",
        "වැඩමුළුවට සහභාගිවූ ජනමාධ්‍යවේදීන්ට සහතික පත්‍ර ප්‍රදානය කිරීම පාර්ලිමේන්තු මහලේකම් ධම්මික දසනායක සහ  සහකාර මහලේකම් ටිකිරි ජයතිලක  යන මහත්වරුන් අතින් සිදුවිය.",
        "මෙම වැඩමුළුවේදී  පාර්ලිමේන්තුවේ   සහකාර මහලේකම් ටිකිරි ජයතිලක, අධ්‍යක්ෂ (ව්‍යවස්ථාදායක) ජනකාන්ත සිල්වා, වේත්‍රධාරී නරේන්ද්‍ර ප්‍රනාන්දු, පාර්ලිමේන්තුවේ අධ්‍යක්ෂ  (තොරතුරු  පද්ධති සහ කළමනාකරණ)මහේෂ් පෙරේරා, ජ්‍යෙෂ්ඨ මාධ්‍යවේදී ශාන් විජේතුංග සහ  එන්.ඩී.අයි ආයතනයේ  ජ්‍යෙෂ්ඨ නේවාසික  අධ්‍යක්ෂිකා  තුසිතා පිලපිටිය යන මහත්ම මහත්මීන් ඇතුළු පිරිසක්ද අදහස් දැක්වූහ.",
        "මේ අවස්ථාවට  පාර්ලිමේන්තුවේ ප්‍රධාන සම්බන්ධීකරණ  ඉංජිනේරු ලලිත්  අධිකාරි මහතා සහ  පාර්ලිමේන්තු සන්නිවේදන දෙපාර්තමේන්තුවේ මාධ්‍ය කළමනාකාරිණී නිම්මි හාතියල්දෙණිය  මහත්මිය ඇතුළු පිරිසක්ද සහභාගී  වූහ."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "225",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "මහින්ද යාපා අබේවර්ධන",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "225",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "සිනමන් ග්‍රෑන්ඩ් හෝටලය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඊයේ",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "28",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තු සන්නිවේදන දෙපාර්තමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "බේරේ වැව",
            "label": "LOC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "මහින්ද යාපා අබේවර්ධන",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "40,000 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තු මන්ත්‍රීවරුන්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "එන් එම් පෙරේරා",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "කොල්වින් ආර් ද සිල්වා",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "කොල්වින් ආර් ද සිල්වා එන්.එම්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "පෙරේරා",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "හතරවන",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "දස්මික දසනායක",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "ටිකිරි ජයතිලක",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ටිකිරි ජයතිලක",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ව්යවස්ථාදායකය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජනකාන්ත සිල්වා",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව (තොරතුරු පද්ධති සහ කළමනාකරණය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "මහේෂ් පෙරේරා",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශාන් විජේතුංග",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "NDI",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ලලිත්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "නිම්මි හතියල්දෙණිය",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "මාධ්ය කළමනාකරු",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තු සන්නිවේදන දෙපාර්තමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "225 பேரையும் கொன்று பிரச்சனையை தீர்க்க முடியுமா?",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "225 நாடாளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர்களை கொன்று அல்லது அவர்களின் வீடுகளுக்கு தீ வைப்பதன் மூலம் நாட்டின் பிரச்சினைகளுக்கு தீர்வு காண முடியுமா என சபாநாயகர் மஹிந்த யாப்பா அபேவர்தன கேள்வி எழுப்பினார்.",
        "கொழும்பு சினமன் கிரான்ட் ஹோட்டலில் நேற்று (28) இடம்பெற்ற பாராளுமன்ற ஊடகவியலாளர்களுக்கான செயலமர்வில் கலந்து கொண்டு உரையாற்றும் போதே அவர் இவ்வாறு தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "\"பாராளுமன்றம்: ஊடகம்: பொது: நேர்மறை தொடர்புகளை உருவாக்குதல்\" என்ற தொனிப்பொருளில் இந்த செயலமர்வு பாராளுமன்ற தகவல் தொடர்புத் திணைக்களத்தினால் ஏற்பாடு செய்யப்பட்டிருந்தது.",
        "தற்போது நாட்டில் ஏற்பட்டுள்ள பிரச்சினைக்கு காரணமானவர்கள் இருப்பதாகவும் அவர் கூறினார்.",
        "நாடாளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர்கள் பலரது வீடுகள் உட்பட பல சொத்துக்களை இந்த கும்பல் அழித்துள்ளதாகவும், கலவரக்காரர்கள் செல்வதை பொலிஸாரும் இராணுவத்தினரும் பார்த்துக் கொண்டிருப்பதாகவும் சபாநாயகர் தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "பேரா ஏரியில் தரையிறங்க முயன்ற ஆண்களும் பெண்களும் கல்லெறிந்து கொல்லப்பட்ட காட்டுமிராண்டித்தனமான சம்பவத்தை ஏற்றுக்கொள்ள முடியாது என்றும் அவர் கூறினார்.",
        "எண்ணெய் நெருக்கடி காரணமாக பாராளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர்கள் இன்று பாராளுமன்றத்திற்கு செல்வது கூட சிரமமாக உள்ளதாக தெரிவித்த மஹிந்த யாப்பா அபேவர்தன, தூர பிரதேசங்களைச் சேர்ந்த பாராளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர்கள் நாளொன்றுக்கு எரிபொருளுக்காக 40,000 ரூபாவுக்கு மேல் செலவிட நேரிட்டுள்ளதாகவும் தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "இந்த நிலையில் நாடாளுமன்றத்தை நடத்துவது பெரும் சவாலாக உள்ளது என்றார்.",
        "பாராளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர்கள் முன்னுதாரணமாக இருப்பது முக்கியம் எனவும், திரு.என்.எம்.பெரேரா, கொல்வின் ஆர்.டி.சில்வா ஆகியோரின் கடந்த கால நடவடிக்கைகளை அவதானிப்பதன் மூலமோ அல்லது அவர்களின் உரைகளை கேட்பதன் மூலமோ இன்றைய பாராளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர்களால் சிறந்த முன்னுதாரணமாக இருக்க முடியும் எனவும் சபாநாயகர் தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "கொல்வின் ஆர்.டி.சில்வா என்.எம்.பெரேராவின் உரைகளைத் தொகுத்து நாடாளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர்களிடம் கையளிக்குமாறு நாடாளுமன்ற நூலகத் தலைவர்களுக்கு பணிப்புரை விடுத்துள்ளதாகவும் அவர் கூறினார்.",
        "இந்த செயலமர்வில் உரையாற்றிய நாடாளுமன்றத்தின் செயலாளர் நாயகம் தம்மிக்க தசநாயக்க, ஊடகத்துறை ஒரு நாட்டில் நான்காவது அரசாங்கம் என தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "இன்று ஊடகங்களுக்கு ஒரு நாட்டு மக்களுக்கு விசேட பாத்திரமும் பொறுப்பும் உள்ளதாகவும், அந்தப் பொறுப்பை உணர்ந்து செயற்படுவது அவசியமானது எனவும் பாராளுமன்ற செயலாளர் நாயகம் தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "பாராளுமன்றத்தில் முக்கியமான சொற்பொழிவுகள் மற்றும் நிகழ்ச்சிகளுக்கு முன்னுரிமை அளிப்பது முக்கியம் என்றும், ஆரம்பத்தில் பிரச்சினைகளை அதிகளவில் அறிக்கையிட்டு முன்னிலைப்படுத்தியதன் மூலம், சில எம்.பி.க்கள் விளம்பரத்தை எதிர்பார்த்து அவ்வாறான முறையில் நடந்துகொள்வதாகத் தோன்றுவதாகவும் திரு.தஸ்மிக தசநாயக்க தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "அறிக்கையிடலில் பாராளுமன்ற சிறப்புரிமைகளை புரிந்து கொண்டு அதற்கேற்ப செயற்படுவது முக்கியம் என பாராளுமன்றத்தின் தலைமை அதிகாரி, பிரதி செயலாளர் நாயகம், சட்டத்தரணி குஷானி ரோஹனதீர தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "பாராளுமன்ற சிறப்புரிமைகளை மீறி செய்தி வெளியிடும் ஊடகவியலாளர்கள் மற்றும் பத்திரிகை ஆசிரியர்களுக்கு அபராதம் விதிப்பது உட்பட பல்வேறு நடவடிக்கைகள் வரலாற்றில் மேற்கொள்ளப்பட்டுள்ளதாக பிரதி செயலாளர் நாயகம் சுட்டிக்காட்டினார்.",
        "செயலமர்வில் பங்குபற்றிய ஊடகவியலாளர்களுக்கு பாராளுமன்ற செயலாளர் நாயகம் தம்மிக்க தசநாயக்க மற்றும் உதவி செயலாளர் நாயகம் டிக்கிரி ஜயதிலக்க ஆகியோரினால் சான்றிதழ்கள் வழங்கி வைக்கப்பட்டன.",
        "இந்த செயலமர்வில் பாராளுமன்றத்தின் உதவிச் செயலாளர் நாயகம் டிக்கிரி ஜயதிலக, பணிப்பாளர் (சட்டமன்றம்) ஜனகாந்த சில்வா, சார்ஜென்ட் நரேந்திர பெர்னாண்டோ, பாராளுமன்றத்தின் பணிப்பாளர் (தகவல் அமைப்புகள் மற்றும் முகாமைத்துவம்) மகேஷ் பெரேரா, சிரேஷ்ட ஊடகவியலாளர் ஷான் விஜேதுங்க மற்றும் NDI இன் சிரேஷ்ட உறுப்பினர்கள் கலந்துகொண்டனர். ஒரு குழுவும் கருத்து தெரிவித்தது.",
        "இந்நிகழ்வில் பாராளுமன்றத்தின் பிரதம ஒருங்கிணைப்பு பொறியியலாளர் திரு.லலித் அதிகாரி மற்றும் பாராளுமன்ற தொடர்பாடல் திணைக்களத்தின் ஊடக முகாமையாளர் திருமதி நிம்மி ஹதியால்தெனிய ஆகியோரும் கலந்துகொண்டனர்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "225",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "மஹிந்த யாப்பா அபேவர்தன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "225",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "சினமன் கிராண்ட் ஹோட்டல்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "நேற்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "28",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்ற தகவல் தொடர்பு துறை",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "பெய்ரா ஏரி",
            "label": "LOC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "மஹிந்த யாப்பா அபேவர்தன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "40,000",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர்கள்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "என்.எம் பெரேரா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "கொல்வின் ஆர். டி சில்வா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "கொல்வின் ஆர். டி சில்வா என்.எம்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "பெரேரா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "நான்காவது",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "தஸ்மிகா தசநாயக்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "திகிரி ஜயதிலக்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "திகிரி ஜயதிலக",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "சட்டமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜனகாந்த சில்வா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம் (தகவல் அமைப்புகள் மற்றும் மேலாண்மை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "மகேஷ் பெரேரா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஷான் விஜேதுங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "NDI",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "லலித்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "நிம்மி ஹதியால்தெனிய",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஊடக மேலாளர்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்ற தகவல் தொடர்பு துறை",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}