{
  "newspaper_id": "virakesari-lk",
  "url": "http://www.virakesari.lk/article/131739",
  "time_ut": 1658163229,
  "original_lang": "ta",
  "original_title": "சம்பிக்கவுக்கு எதிரான வழக்கு ஒத்திவைப்பு",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Adjournment of case against Sambika",
      "author": "T Yuwaraj",
      "body_lines": [
        "The case against Member of Parliament Patali Sampika Ranawaka for driving dangerously and injuring one person in Welikada police station has been adjourned till August 31.",
        "The case will be taken up for hearing on August 31 to give an opportunity to put forward the basic objection that the defendant side, Sampika Ranavaka intends to put forward that the said case cannot be taken forward.",
        "The case came up for hearing on Monday (18) before Colombo High Court Judge Namal Palalle. Deputy Solicitor General Madhava Thennakone appeared in the court on behalf of the Attorney General. President's Counsel Sarath Jayamanna appeared in the forum on behalf of Sampika Ranavaka.",
        "Accordingly, the president's lawyer Sarath Jayamanna, who presented the issues in the forum, put forward a basic objection that the case could not be taken forward.",
        "At this stage, the case was adjourned till August 31 for presentation of arguments on the basic objections."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Parliament Patali Sampika Ranawaka",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Welikada",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "August 31",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "August 31",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sampika Ranavaka",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Monday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Colombo High Court",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Namal Palalle",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Madhava Thennakone",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sampika Ranavaka",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sarath Jayamanna",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "August 31",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "සම්බිකට එරෙහි නඩුව කල් තැබීම",
      "author": "ටී යුවරාජ්",
      "body_lines": [
        "පාර්ලිමේන්තු මන්ත්‍රී පාඨලී සම්පික රණවක මහතාට වැලිකඩ පොලිස් ස්ථානයේදී අනතුරුදායක ලෙස රිය පදවා එක් පුද්ගලයෙකුට තුවාල සිදුකිරීම සම්බන්ධයෙන් වන නඩුව අගෝස්තු 31 වැනිදා දක්වා කල් තැබුණා.",
        "එම නඩුව ඉදිරියට ගෙන යා නොහැකි බවට විත්ති පාර්ශ්වය ඉදිරිපත් කිරීමට අදහස් කරන මූලික විරෝධතාවය ඉදිරිපත් කිරීමට අවස්ථාවක් ලබාදීම සඳහා නඩුව අගෝස්තු 31 වැනිදා විභාගයට ගැනීමට නියමිතයි.",
        "මෙම නඩුව සඳුදා (18) කොළඹ මහාධිකරණ විනිසුරු නාමල් පලාල්ල මහතා ඉදිරියේ විභාගයට ගැනිණි. නියෝජ්‍ය සොලිසිටර් ජනරාල් මාධව තෙන්නකෝන් මහතා නීතිපතිවරයා වෙනුවෙන් අධිකරණයේ පෙනී සිටියේය. සම්පික රණවක මහතා වෙනුවෙන් ජනාධිපති නීතිඥ සරත් ජයමාන්න මහතා සංසදයේ පෙනී සිටියේය.",
        "ඒ අනුව එම සංසදයේ කරුණු ඉදිරිපත් කළ ජනාධිපති නීතිඥ සරත් ජයමාන්න මහතා නඩුව ඉදිරියට ගෙන යා නොහැකි බවට මූලික විරෝධයක් ඉදිරිපත් කළේය.",
        "මෙම අවස්ථාවේදී මූලික විරෝධතා පිළිබඳ තර්ක ඉදිරිපත් කිරීම සඳහා නඩුව අගෝස්තු 31 වැනිදාට කල් තැබිණි."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තු පාඨලී සම්පික රණවක",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "වැලිකඩ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "අගෝස්තු 31",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "අගෝස්තු 31",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "සම්පික රණවක",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "සඳුදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "කොළඹ මහාධිකරණය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "නාමල් පලාල්ලේ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "මාධව තෙන්නකෝන්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "සම්පික රණවක",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "සරත් ජයමාන්න",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "අගෝස්තු 31",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "சம்பிக்கவுக்கு எதிரான வழக்கு ஒத்திவைப்பு",
      "author": "T Yuwaraj",
      "body_lines": [
        "வெலிக்கடை பொலிஸ் பிரிவில் அபாயகரமாக வாகனம் செலுத்தி ஒருவருக்கு படுகாயம் ஏற்படுத்தியமை தொடர்பில் பாராளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர் பாட்டலி சம்பிக்க ரணவக்கவுக்கு எதிராக தொடரப்பட்டுள்ள வழக்கு எதிர்வரும் ஆகஸ்ட் 31 வரைவரை ஒத்தி வைக்கப்பட்டுள்ளது.",
        "குறித்த வழக்கை முன்னெடுத்து செல்ல முடியாது என பிரதிவாதி தரப்பானர், சம்பிக்க ரணவக்க தரப்பினர்  முன் வைக்க  உத்தேசித்துள்ள அடிப்படை ஆட்சேபனத்தை முன் வைக்க சந்தர்ப்பம் அளிக்கும் விதமாக ஆகஸ்ட் 31 இல் இவ்வழக்கு விசாரணைக்கு எடுக்கப்படவுள்ளது.",
        "திங்கட்கிழமை (18) இந்த வழக்கு, கொழும்பு மேல் நீதிமன்ற நீதிபதி நாமல் பலல்லே முன்னிலையில் விசாரணைக்கு வந்தது. இதன்போது வழக்குத் தொடுநர் சட்ட மா அதிபர் சார்பில் மன்றில் பிரதி சொலிசிட்டர் ஜெனரால் மாதவ தென்னகோன் ஆஜரானார். சம்பிக்க ரணவக்க சார்பில் மன்றில் ஜனாதிபதி சட்டத்தரணி சரத் ஜயமான்ன ஆஜரானார்.",
        "அதன்படி மன்றில் விடயங்களை முன் வைத்த ஜனாதிபதி சட்டத்தரணி சரத் ஜயமான்ன இவ்வழக்கை முன்னெடுத்து செல்ல முடியாது என அடிப்படை ஆட்சேபனத்தை முன் வைத்தார்.",
        "இந் நிலையிலேயே அடிப்படை ஆட்சேபனைகள் குறித்த வாதங்களை  முன் வைப்பதற்காக வழக்கானது எதிர்வரும் ஆகஸ்ட் 31 வரை ஒத்தி வைக்கப்பட்டது."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம் பாட்டலி சம்பிக்க ரணவக்க",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "வெலிக்கடை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆகஸ்ட் 31",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஆகஸ்ட் 31",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சம்பிக்க ரணவக்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "திங்கட்கிழமை",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "கொழும்பு உயர் நீதிமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "நாமல் பலல்லே",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "மாதவ தென்னகோன்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "சம்பிக்க ரணவக்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "சரத் ​​ஜயமான்ன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஆகஸ்ட் 31",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}