{
  "newspaper_id": "news-first-lk",
  "url": "https://www.newsfirst.lk/2022/08/26/sri-lankas-reviews-renewable-energy-plans/",
  "time_ut": 1661530020,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Sri Lankas reviews Renewable Energy Plans",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Sri Lankas reviews Renewable Energy Plans",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); The Minister of Power and Energy Kanchana Wijsekara says that a productive discussion was held between the Ceylon Electricity Board and officials from the Sustainable Energy Authorities this morning (26) to review the progress on Renewable Energy Plans.",
        "\"Discussed proposed 100 MW Solar plant in Siyambalanduwa, EOIs, Floating Solar, Tariffs, Grid Capacity, Signing of PPA. Appointed a joint committee with CEB & SEA officials to finalize RE plans\", Minister Kanchana said.",
        "Linking lives and villages: Gammadda launches bridge construction in remote Kegalle",
        "Children need to be at heart of resolving SL crisis: UNICEF regional director"
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "News 1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Ceylon Electricity Board",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Sustainable Energy Authorities",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "this morning",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "26",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Renewable Energy Plans",
            "label": "WORK_OF_ART"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "100",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "MW Solar",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Siyambalanduwa",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Floating Solar, Tariffs, Grid Capacity",
            "label": "WORK_OF_ART"
          },
          {
            "text": "PPA",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "CEB & SEA",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "RE",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kanchana",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Kegalle",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        []
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "ශ්‍රී ලංකාව පුනර්ජනනීය බලශක්ති සැලසුම් සමාලෝචනය කරයි",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); පුනර්ජනනීය බලශක්ති සැලසුම්වල ප්‍රගතිය සමාලෝචනය කිරීම සඳහා ලංකා විදුලිබල මණ්ඩලය සහ සුනිත්‍ය බලශක්ති අධිකාරියේ නිලධාරීන් අතර ඵලදායී සාකච්ඡාවක් අද (26) පෙරවරුවේ පැවති බව විදුලිබල හා බලශක්ති අමාත්‍ය කාංචන විජේසේකර මහතා පවසයි.",
        "\"සියඹලාණ්ඩුවේ යෝජිත MW 100 සූර්ය බලාගාරය, EOIs, Floating Solar, Tariffs, Grid Capacity, Signing of PPA ගැන සාකච්ඡා කළා. RE සැලසුම් අවසන් කිරීම සඳහා CEB සහ SEA නිලධාරීන් සමඟ ඒකාබද්ධ කමිටුවක් පත් කළා\", අමාත්‍ය කාංචන පැවසීය.",
        "ජීවිත සහ ගම් සම්බන්ධ කිරීම: ගම්මැද්ද දුර බැහැර කෑගල්ලේ පාලම් ඉදිකිරීම ආරම්භ කරයි",
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකා අර්බුදය විසඳීමේ හදවතේ දරුවන් සිටිය යුතුයි: යුනිසෙෆ් කලාපීය අධ්‍යක්ෂ"
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "News 1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ලංකා විදුලිබල මණ්ඩලය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "තිරසාර බලශක්ති අධිකාරීන්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "මේ උදෑසන",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "26",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "පුනර්ජනනීය බලශක්ති සැලසුම්",
            "label": "WORK_OF_ART"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "100",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "MW සූර්ය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "සියඹලාණ්ඩුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාවෙන සූර්ය, තීරුබදු, ජාල ධාරිතාව",
            "label": "WORK_OF_ART"
          },
          {
            "text": "PPA",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ලංවිම සහ මුහුද",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "RE",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "කාංචනා",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "කෑගල්ල",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        []
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "புதுப்பிக்கத்தக்க ஆற்றல் திட்டங்களை இலங்கை மதிப்பாய்வு செய்கிறது",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); புதுப்பிக்கத்தக்க எரிசக்தி திட்டங்களின் முன்னேற்றத்தை மீளாய்வு செய்வதற்காக இலங்கை மின்சார சபை மற்றும் நிலையான சக்தி அதிகார சபை அதிகாரிகளுக்கு இடையில் இன்று (26) காலை ஆக்கபூர்வமான கலந்துரையாடல் இடம்பெற்றதாக மின்வலு மற்றும் எரிசக்தி அமைச்சர் காஞ்சன விஜேசேகர தெரிவித்துள்ளார்.",
        "\"சியாம்பலாண்டுவவில் முன்மொழியப்பட்ட 100 மெகாவாட் சோலார் ஆலை, EOIகள், மிதக்கும் சோலார், கட்டணங்கள், கிரிட் திறன், PPA கையொப்பமிடுதல் பற்றி விவாதிக்கப்பட்டது. RE திட்டங்களை இறுதி செய்ய CEB & SEA அதிகாரிகளுடன் ஒரு கூட்டுக் குழுவை நியமித்தது\", அமைச்சர் காஞ்சனா கூறினார்.",
        "வாழ்க்கையையும் கிராமங்களையும் இணைக்கிறது: கேகாலை தொலைவில் பாலம் கட்டும் பணியை கம்மத்தா தொடங்கினார்",
        "இலங்கை நெருக்கடியைத் தீர்ப்பதில் குழந்தைகள் இதயத்தில் இருக்க வேண்டும்: யுனிசெஃப் பிராந்திய இயக்குநர்"
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "News 1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை மின்சார சபை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "நிலையான எரிசக்தி அதிகாரிகள்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று காலை",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "26",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "புதுப்பிக்கத்தக்க ஆற்றல் திட்டங்கள்",
            "label": "WORK_OF_ART"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "100",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "MW சோலார்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "சியம்பலாண்டுவ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "மிதக்கும் சோலார், கட்டணங்கள், கிரிட் திறன்",
            "label": "WORK_OF_ART"
          },
          {
            "text": "பிபிஏ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "CEB & SEA",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "RE",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "காஞ்சனா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "கேகாலை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        []
      ]
    }
  }
}