{
  "newspaper_id": "island-lk",
  "url": "http://island.lk/kehelgamuwas-football-skills-and-president-premadasas-political-sagacity/",
  "time_ut": 1656936540,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Kehelgamuwa’s football skills and President Premadasa’s political sagacity",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Kehelgamuwa’s football skills and President Premadasa’s political sagacity",
      "author": "Sahan Weerasooriya",
      "body_lines": [
        "T.B. Kehelgamuwa, the cricketer who needs no plaudits from anyone, is well known. He represented then Ceylon and, later, Sri Lanka as a fearsome fast bowler during the pre-Test era. His contemporaries still talk about Kehel with great respect. Once S Skanda Kumar, the well-known cricketer, cricket commentator and former High Commissioner for Sri Lanka to Australia, proudly told me about his playing cricket with Kehelgamuwa. Bandu Samarasinghe, a Sri Lanka film star, on a TV programme vividly demonstrated how he faced Kehelgamuwa in a Sara Trophy game. That was the top-level tournament in the country.",
        "This note is to share my watching Kehelgamuwa playing soccer when he was not so young. Then, though his grey hair was visible, he ran fast and played hard like a teenager. This was during President Ranasinghe Premadasa’s tenure. Returning from The Netherlands, after my postgraduate studies, I lived in Pelawatta, near the Sri Lanka Parliament and my workplace – International Irrigation Management Institute headquarters. I used to enjoy walking on Parliament grounds. That day was unique because the game between the President’s soccer team, comprising parliamentarians, and the Sri Lanka Police team, was played there.",
        "President Premadasa was well known for his political sagacity, especially in manipulating any situation in his favour. For instance, the day Anura Bandaranayake became the Opposition Leader, Premadasa, praised Anura stating, “Anura is the best Opposition Leader we have.” He further requested that Anura join the ruling party and become a minister and also marry a girl from a prominent ruling party family. But within weeks, he was critical of Anura. One day an Opposition member asked him, “You said Anura was our best Opposition leader a few weeks ago but now criticise.” His reply was this: “Yes, I said so because Anura is the best Opposition leader for us, the ruling party, not for the Opposition. For the Opposition, the best leader is Sarath Muththetuwegama!”",
        "A few weeks before the scheduled encounter between the Parliamentarians and the Police football team, there was a game between the Parliamentarians and the Colombo Municipality team. Premadasa captained the Parliamentarians and kicked the winning goal. I remember a cartoon in a newspaper where the Municipality team goalkeeper withdrew so that Premadasa could score the goal at his will.",
        "During the game against the Police, Premadasa did not play but visibly played the role of the coach of the Parliamentarian team. Unlike the Municipality players, the Police played the game seriously. Kehelgamuwa represented the Police team that scored five goals by halftime, and the Parliamentarian team was nil. At halftime, Premadasa replaced the Parliamentarian goalkeeper with Jayawickerama Perera. Yet, the Police team recorded a sound victory.",
        "I thought Premadasa was upset due to this defeat for his team. But no. Premadasa claimed victory: “I am happy that my team won the game by beating the Parliamentarians today! Being the Executive President, I do not belong to the Parliament. However, as the Commander-in-Chief, the Police come under my purview, so my team won today!”",
        "Leave a Reply Cancel replyYour email address will not be published. Required fields are marked *Comment Name *",
        "Save my name, email, and website in this browser for the next time I comment."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Premadasa",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "T.B. Kehelgamuwa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the pre-Test",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kehel",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Skanda Kumar",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Australia",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kehelgamuwa",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Bandu Samarasinghe",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kehelgamuwa",
            "label": "PRODUCT"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sara Trophy",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Kehelgamuwa",
            "label": "PRODUCT"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ranasinghe Premadasa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Netherlands",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Pelawatta",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Sri Lanka Parliament",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "International Irrigation Management Institute",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Sri Lanka Police",
            "label": "LOC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Premadasa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Anura",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Opposition",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Premadasa",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Anura",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Anura",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Anura",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "weeks",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Anura",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "One day",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Opposition",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Anura",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Opposition",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "a few weeks ago",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Anura",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Opposition",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Opposition",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Opposition",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "A few weeks",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliamentarians",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliamentarians",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliamentarians",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Premadasa",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Parliamentarian",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kehelgamuwa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliamentarian",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Premadasa",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliamentarian",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Jayawickerama Perera",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Premadasa",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliamentarians",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [],
        []
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "කෙහෙල්ගමුවේ පාපන්දු කුසලතාව සහ ජනාධිපති ප්‍රේමදාසගේ දේශපාලන ඥානවන්තභාවය",
      "author": "සහන් වීරසූරිය",
      "body_lines": [
        "ටී.බී. කාගෙන්වත් ප්‍රශංසා අවශ්‍ය නැති ක්‍රිකට් ක්‍රීඩකයා කෙහෙල්ගමුව ප්‍රසිද්ධයි. ඔහු එවකට ලංකාව සහ පසුව ශ්‍රී ලංකාව නියෝජනය කළේ ටෙස්ට් පූර්ව යුගයේ බිහිසුණු වේග පන්දු යවන්නෙකු ලෙසය. ඔහුගේ සමකාලීනයන් තවමත් කෙහෙල් ගැන කතා කරන්නේ මහත් ගෞරවයෙනි. සුප්‍රසිද්ධ ක්‍රිකට් ක්‍රීඩකයෙක්, ක්‍රිකට් විස්තර විචාරකයෙක් සහ ඔස්ට්‍රේලියාවේ හිටපු ශ්‍රී ලංකා මහ කොමසාරිස් එස් ස්කන්ධ කුමාර් වරක් කෙහෙල්ගමුව සමඟ ක්‍රිකට් ක්‍රීඩා කිරීම ගැන ආඩම්බරයෙන් මට කීවේය. ශ්‍රී ලංකා සිනමා තරුවක් වන බන්දු සමරසිංහ සරා කුසලාන තරගයකදී කෙහෙල්ගමුවට මුහුණ දුන් ආකාරය රූපවාහිනී වැඩසටහනකදී මනාව නිරූපණය කළේය. ඒ මෙරට පැවැති ඉහළ පෙළේ තරගාවලියයි.",
        "මේ සටහන කෙහෙල්ගමුව එතරම් කුඩා කාලයේ පාපන්දු ක්‍රීඩා කරන අයුරු මා නරඹන අයුරු බෙදා ගැනීමටයි. එවිට ඔහුගේ පැසුණු හිසකෙස් පෙනෙන්නට තිබුණත්, ඔහු වේගයෙන් දිව ගොස් යෞවනයෙකු මෙන් වෙහෙස මහන්සි වී සෙල්ලම් කළේය. ඒ රණසිංහ ප්‍රේමදාස ජනාධිපතිවරයාගේ පාලන සමයේදීය. නෙදර්ලන්තයේ සිට ආපසු පැමිණ, මගේ පශ්චාත් උපාධි අධ්‍යාපනයෙන් පසු, මම ශ්‍රී ලංකා පාර්ලිමේන්තුව සහ මගේ සේවා ස්ථානය - ජාත්‍යන්තර වාරි කළමනාකරණ ආයතන මූලස්ථානය අසල පැලවත්තේ ජීවත් වුණෙමි. මම පාර්ලිමේන්තු පිට්ටනියේ ඇවිදීමෙන් සතුටක් ලැබුවා. එම දිනය සුවිශේෂී වූයේ පාර්ලිමේන්තු මන්ත්‍රීවරුන්ගෙන් සමන්විත ජනාධිපතිවරයාගේ පාපන්දු කණ්ඩායම සහ ශ්‍රී ලංකා පොලිස් කණ්ඩායම අතර තරගය එහි පැවැත්වුණු බැවිනි.",
        "ප්‍රේමදාස ජනාධිපතිවරයා ප්‍රසිද්ධියට පත් වූයේ ඔහුගේ දේශපාලන ඥානාන්විතභාවය, විශේෂයෙන්ම ඕනෑම තත්වයක් තමන්ට වාසිදායක ලෙස හසුරුවා ගැනීම සඳහා ය. උදාහරණයක් වශයෙන්, අනුර බණ්ඩාරනායක විපක්ෂ නායක වූ දින ප්‍රේමදාස අනුර ප්‍රශංසා කළේ “අපට සිටින හොඳම විපක්ෂ නායකයා අනුර” යනුවෙනි. අනුර ආණ්ඩු පක්‍ෂයට එකතු වී ඇමැතිවරයකු වී ආණ්ඩු පක්‍ෂයේ ප්‍රකට පවුලක තරුණියක් විවාහ කර ගන්නා ලෙසද ඔහු වැඩිදුරටත් ඉල්ලා සිටියේය. නමුත් සති කිහිපයකින් ඔහු අනුරට විවේචනය කළේය. දිනක් විපක්ෂයේ මන්ත්‍රීවරයෙක් ඔහුගෙන් ඇසුවේ “සති කීපයකට කලින් අනුර අපේ හොඳම විපක්ෂ නායක කියලා ඔබ කිව්වා නමුත් දැන් විවේචනය කරනවා” යනුවෙනි. ඔහුගේ පිළිතුර වූයේ මෙයයි: “ඔව්, මම එහෙම කිව්වේ විපක්ෂයට නෙවෙයි ආණ්ඩු පක්ෂයට අපිට හොඳම විපක්ෂ නායක අනුර නිසා. විපක්ෂයට හොඳම නායකයා සරත් මුත්තෙටුවේගම!”",
        "පාර්ලිමේන්තු මන්ත්‍රීවරුන් සහ පොලිස් පාපන්දු කණ්ඩායම අතර පැවැත්වීමට නියමිතව තිබූ ගැටුමට සති කිහිපයකට පෙර පාර්ලිමේන්තු මන්ත්‍රීවරුන් සහ කොළඹ නගර සභා කණ්ඩායම අතර තරගයක් පැවැත්විණි. ප්‍රේමදාස මන්ත්‍රීවරුන්ගේ නායකත්වයෙන් ජයග්‍රාහී ගෝලයට පයින් ගැසීය. ප්‍රේමදාසට තම අභිමතය පරිදි ගෝලය ලබා ගත හැකි වන පරිදි නගරසභාව කණ්ඩායමේ ගෝල් රකින්නා ඉවත් වූ අයුරු පුවත්පතක කාටූනයක් තිබුණා මට මතකයි.",
        "පොලිසියට එරෙහි තරගයේදී ප්‍රේමදාස ක්‍රීඩා නොකළ නමුත් පාර්ලිමේන්තු කණ්ඩායමේ පුහුණුකරුගේ භූමිකාව දෘශ්‍යමාන ලෙස ඉටු කළේය. නගර සභා ක්‍රීඩකයන් මෙන් නොව පොලිසිය බැරෑරුම් ලෙස ක්‍රීඩා කළේය. කෙහෙල්ගමුව අර්ධ කාලය වන විට ගෝල 5ක් රැස් කළ පොලිස් කණ්ඩායම නියෝජනය කළ අතර, පාර්ලිමේන්තු මන්ත්‍රී කණ්ඩායම බිංදු විය. අර්ධ වේලාවේදී ප්‍රේමදාස පාර්ලිමේන්තු ගෝල රකින්නා වෙනුවට ජයවික්‍රම පෙරේරා පත් කළේය. එහෙත් පොලිස් කණ්ඩායම විශිෂ්ට ජයක් වාර්තා කළේය.",
        "මම හිතුවේ ප්‍රේමදාස එයාගේ කණ්ඩායමට මේ පරාජය නිසා කලබල වෙලා කියලා. නමුත් නැහැ. ප්‍රේමදාස ජයග්‍රහණය ප්‍රකාශ කළේය: “අද පාර්ලිමේන්තු මන්ත්‍රීවරුන් පරදවා මගේ කණ්ඩායම තරගය ජයග්‍රහණය කිරීම ගැන මම සතුටු වෙනවා! විධායක ජනාධිපති හැටියට මම පාර්ලිමේන්තුවට අයිති නැහැ. කෙසේ වෙතත්, සේනාධිනායකයා ලෙස පොලිසිය මගේ විෂය පථයට අයත් වන බැවින් මගේ කණ්ඩායම අද දිනුවා!”",
        "පිළිතුරක් දෙන්න පිළිතුර අවලංගු කරන්න ඔබගේ විද්‍යුත් තැපැල් ලිපිනය ප්‍රකාශයට පත් නොකෙරේ. අවශ්‍ය ක්ෂේත්‍ර සලකුණු කර ඇත *අදහස් නම *",
        "මම ඊළඟ වතාවේ අදහස් දැක්වීම සඳහා මගේ නම, විද්‍යුත් තැපෑල සහ වෙබ් අඩවිය මෙම බ්‍රවුසරයේ සුරකින්න."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ප්‍රේමදාස ය",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ටී.බී. කෙහෙල්ගමුව",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "පූර්ව ටෙස්ට්",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "කෙහෙල්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ස්කන්ධ කුමාර",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඕස්ට්රේලියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "කෙහෙල්ගමුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "බන්දු සමරසිංහ",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "කෙහෙල්ගමුව",
            "label": "PRODUCT"
          },
          {
            "text": "සාරා කුසලානය",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "කෙහෙල්ගමුව",
            "label": "PRODUCT"
          },
          {
            "text": "රණසිංහ ප්‍රේමදාස",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "නෙදර්ලන්තය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "පැලවත්ත",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකා පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජාත්‍යන්තර වාරි කළමනාකරණ ආයතනය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකා පොලිසිය",
            "label": "LOC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ප්‍රේමදාස ය",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "අනුර",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "විපක්ෂ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ප්‍රේමදාස ය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "අනුර",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "අනුර",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "අනුර",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "සති",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "අනුර",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "එක දවසක්",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "විපක්ෂ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "අනුර",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "විපක්ෂ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "සති කිහිපයකට පෙර",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "අනුර",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "විපක්ෂ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "විපක්ෂ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "විපක්ෂ",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "සති කිහිපයක්",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තු මන්ත්‍රීවරු",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තු මන්ත්‍රීවරු",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තු මන්ත්‍රීවරු",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ප්‍රේමදාස ය",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තු මන්ත්‍රී",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "කෙහෙල්ගමුව",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තු මන්ත්‍රී",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ප්‍රේමදාස ය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තු මන්ත්‍රී",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජයවික්‍රම පෙරේරා",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ප්‍රේමදාස ය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තු මන්ත්‍රීවරු",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [],
        []
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "கெஹல்கமுவவின் கால்பந்தாட்டத் திறமை மற்றும் ஜனாதிபதி பிரேமதாசவின் அரசியல் சாதுரியம்",
      "author": "சஹான் வீரசூரிய",
      "body_lines": [
        "டி.பி. கெஹல்கமுவ, யாருடைய பாராட்டுக்களும் தேவையில்லாத கிரிக்கெட் வீரர் என்பது அனைவரும் அறிந்ததே. அவர் அப்போதைய சிலோனைப் பிரதிநிதித்துவப்படுத்தினார், பின்னர், டெஸ்ட் போட்டிக்கு முந்தைய காலத்தில் ஒரு பயமுறுத்தும் வேகப்பந்து வீச்சாளராக இலங்கையை பிரதிநிதித்துவப்படுத்தினார். அவரது சமகாலத்தவர்கள் இன்றும் கெஹலைப் பற்றி மிகுந்த மரியாதையுடன் பேசுகிறார்கள். பிரபல கிரிக்கெட் வீரரும், கிரிக்கெட் வர்ணனையாளரும், அவுஸ்திரேலியாவுக்கான இலங்கைக்கான முன்னாள் உயர்ஸ்தானிகருமான எஸ் ஸ்கந்த குமார், கெஹல்கமுவவுடன் கிரிக்கெட் விளையாடியதைப் பற்றி பெருமையுடன் என்னிடம் கூறினார். இலங்கைத் திரைப்பட நட்சத்திரமான பாண்டு சமரசிங்க, ஒரு தொலைக்காட்சி நிகழ்ச்சி ஒன்றில், சாரா டிராபி ஆட்டத்தில் கெஹல்கமுவவை எப்படி எதிர்கொண்டார் என்பதைத் தெளிவாகக் காட்டினார். அதுதான் நாட்டின் உயர்மட்டப் போட்டி.",
        "கெஹல்கமுவ சிறுவயதில் கால்பந்தாட்டம் விளையாடியதை நான் பார்த்துக் கொண்டிருந்ததை பகிர்ந்து கொள்வதற்காகவே இந்த குறிப்பு. அப்போது, ​​நரைத்த தலைமுடி தெரிந்தாலும், வேகமாக ஓடி, வாலிபரைப் போல் கடுமையாக விளையாடினார். இது ஜனாதிபதி ரணசிங்க பிரேமதாசவின் காலத்தில் இடம்பெற்றது. நெதர்லாந்தில் இருந்து திரும்பி, எனது முதுகலைப் படிப்பிற்குப் பிறகு, நான் இலங்கை பாராளுமன்றம் மற்றும் எனது பணியிடமான சர்வதேச நீர்ப்பாசன மேலாண்மை நிறுவன தலைமையகத்திற்கு அருகிலுள்ள பெலவத்தையில் வசித்து வந்தேன். நான் பார்லிமென்ட் மைதானத்தில் நடப்பதை ரசித்தேன். பாராளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர்கள் அடங்கிய ஜனாதிபதியின் உதைபந்தாட்ட அணிக்கும் இலங்கை பொலிஸ் அணிக்கும் இடையிலான ஆட்டம் அங்கு இடம்பெற்றதால் அன்றைய தினம் தனித்துவமானது.",
        "ஜனாதிபதி பிரேமதாச தனது அரசியல் சாதுர்யத்திற்கு, குறிப்பாக எந்த ஒரு சூழ்நிலையையும் தனக்கு சாதகமாக கையாள்வதில் நன்கு அறியப்பட்டவர். உதாரணமாக, அநுர பண்டாரநாயக்க எதிர்க்கட்சித் தலைவராக பதவியேற்ற நாளில், பிரேமதாச, அனுரவைப் புகழ்ந்து, \"நம்மிடம் இருக்கும் சிறந்த எதிர்க்கட்சித் தலைவர் அநுரா\" என்று குறிப்பிட்டார். மேலும், அனுர ஆளும் கட்சியில் இணைந்து அமைச்சராகி, ஆளும் கட்சியைச் சேர்ந்த முக்கிய குடும்பத்தைச் சேர்ந்த பெண்ணை திருமணம் செய்து கொள்ள வேண்டும் என்றும் அவர் வேண்டுகோள் விடுத்துள்ளார். ஆனால் சில வாரங்களிலேயே அவர் அனுராவை விமர்சித்தார். ஒரு நாள் எதிர்க்கட்சி உறுப்பினர் ஒருவர் அவரிடம், “சில வாரங்களுக்கு முன்னர் அனுரா எங்களின் சிறந்த எதிர்க்கட்சித் தலைவர் என்று நீங்கள் சொன்னீர்கள் ஆனால் இப்போது விமர்சிக்கிறீர்கள்” என்று கேட்டார். அதற்கு அவர் அளித்த பதில் இதுதான்: “ஆம், ஆளும் கட்சியான எமக்கு அநுரா சிறந்த எதிர்க்கட்சித் தலைவர் என்பதாலேயே அவ்வாறு கூறினேன், எதிர்க்கட்சிக்கு அல்ல. எதிர்க்கட்சிக்கு சிறந்த தலைவர் சரத் முத்தெடுவேகம!",
        "பாராளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர்களுக்கும் பொலிஸ் உதைபந்தாட்ட அணிக்கும் இடையில் திட்டமிடப்பட்ட மோதலுக்கு சில வாரங்களுக்கு முன்னர் பாராளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர்களுக்கும் கொழும்பு மாநகர சபை அணியினருக்கும் இடையில் ஆட்டம் ஒன்று இடம்பெற்றது. பிரேமதாச பாராளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர்களுக்கு தலைமை தாங்கி வெற்றி இலக்கை உதைத்தார். பிரேமதாசா தனது விருப்பப்படி கோல் அடிக்க வேண்டும் என்பதற்காக, மாநகரசபை அணியின் கோல் காப்பாளர் விலகிக்கொண்ட கார்ட்டூன் செய்தித்தாளில் வந்தது எனக்கு நினைவிருக்கிறது.",
        "பொலிஸாருக்கு எதிரான ஆட்டத்தின் போது, ​​பிரேமதாச விளையாடவில்லை, ஆனால் நாடாளுமன்ற அணியின் பயிற்றுவிப்பாளராக வெளிப்படையாகவே நடித்தார். முனிசிபாலிட்டி வீரர்களைப் போலல்லாமல், காவல்துறை தீவிரமாக விளையாடியது. இடைவேளையில் ஐந்து கோல்களைப் பெற்ற பொலிஸ் அணியை கெஹல்கமுவ பிரதிநிதித்துவப்படுத்தினார், மேலும் பாராளுமன்ற அணி பூஜ்ஜியமாக இருந்தது. இடைவேளையில், பிரேமதாச பாராளுமன்ற கோல் கீப்பருக்குப் பதிலாக ஜெயவிக்ரம பெரேராவைக் கொண்டு வந்தார். ஆனாலும், போலீஸ் அணி அபார வெற்றியை பதிவு செய்தது.",
        "தனது அணிக்கு ஏற்பட்ட இந்த தோல்வியால் பிரேமதாச வருத்தமடைந்தார் என நினைத்தேன். ஆனால் இல்லை. பிரேமதாச வெற்றியைப் பெற்றார்: “இன்று பாராளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர்களை வீழ்த்தி எனது அணி வெற்றி பெற்றதில் நான் மகிழ்ச்சியடைகிறேன்! நிறைவேற்று ஜனாதிபதியாக இருப்பதால் நான் பாராளுமன்றத்தை சேர்ந்தவன் அல்ல. இருப்பினும், தலைமைத் தளபதியாக, காவல்துறை எனது வரம்பிற்குள் வருவதால், எனது அணி இன்று வெற்றி பெற்றது!",
        "ஒரு பதிலை விடுங்கள் பதிலை ரத்துசெய் உங்கள் மின்னஞ்சல் முகவரி வெளியிடப்படாது. தேவையான புலங்கள் குறிக்கப்பட்டுள்ளன *கருத்து பெயர் *",
        "அடுத்த முறை நான் கருத்து தெரிவிக்க, எனது பெயர், மின்னஞ்சல் மற்றும் இணையதளத்தை இந்த உலாவியில் சேமிக்கவும்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "பிரேமதாச",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "டி.பி. கெஹல்கமுவ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "முன் சோதனை",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "கெஹல்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஸ்கந்த குமார்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆஸ்திரேலியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "கெஹல்கமுவ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாண்டு சமரசிங்க",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "கெஹல்கமுவ",
            "label": "PRODUCT"
          },
          {
            "text": "சாரா டிராபி",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "கெஹல்கமுவ",
            "label": "PRODUCT"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரணசிங்க பிரேமதாச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "நெதர்லாந்து",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "பெலவத்த",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "சர்வதேச நீர்ப்பாசன மேலாண்மை நிறுவனம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை காவல்துறை",
            "label": "LOC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பிரேமதாச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "அனுர",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "எதிர்ப்பு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "பிரேமதாச",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "அனுர",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "அனுர",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "அனுர",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "வாரங்கள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "அனுர",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஒரு நாள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "எதிர்ப்பு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "அனுர",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "எதிர்ப்பு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "சில வாரங்களுக்கு முன்பு",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "அனுர",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "எதிர்ப்பு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "எதிர்ப்பு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "எதிர்ப்பு",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஒரு சில வாரங்கள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர்கள்",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர்கள்",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர்கள்",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "பிரேமதாச",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர்",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "கெஹல்கமுவ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர்",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "பிரேமதாச",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர்",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜெயவிக்ரம பெரேரா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பிரேமதாச",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர்கள்",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [],
        []
      ]
    }
  }
}