{
  "newspaper_id": "daily-ft-lk",
  "url": "https://www.ft.lk/news/President-Ranil-a-leader-with-foresight-who-can-rebuild-SL-Dr-Dhammarathana-Nayaka-Thera/56-738956",
  "time_ut": 1661115106,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "‘President Ranil a leader with foresight who can rebuild SL’: Dr. Dhammarathana Nayaka Thera",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "‘President Ranil a leader with foresight who can rebuild SL’: Dr. Dhammarathana Nayaka Thera",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "President Ranil Wickremesinghe, who has assumed the responsibility of this country is a leader with foresight who will definitely rebuild the country, said Mihintale Raja Maha Viharadhipathi Ven. Dr. Walavahangunaweve Dhammarathana Nayaka Thera.",
        "The Thera said that President Wickremesinghe’s appointment proves the saying that “if something is destined to happen, it will happen to the most suited”, adding that today Wickremesinghe has taken charge of this country and is shouldering the responsibility of rebuilding the country, which is a blessing in disguise.",
        "The President who visited Mihintale sacred site yesterday engaged in religious observances and received blessings. Thereafter, the President paid a courtesy call on Chief Incumbent Ven. Dr. Walavahangunaweve Dhammaratana Thera and inquired about his wellbeing. The Thera made this brief exhortation during the meeting.",
        "The Maha Sangha chanted Seth Pirith and invoked blessings on the President and the ‘Mihinthala Memorandum’ was also presented to the President.",
        "“As descendants of Mihidu Maha Rahathan, we are happy and bestow our blessings on our President who has come here to receive blessings after having taken over this country. We bestow our blessings upon him and congratulate him. The Caucasian chalk circle (Hunu Wataye Kathawa) states that ‘If something is to happen, it should happen to someone who deserves it’.",
        "Ven. Dr. Walavahangunaweve Dhammaratana Thera said: “Back then, many media and politicians assassinated your character. Some politicians went to the South and called you a terrorist. Several electronic and print media created a slogan ‘Ranil can’t’, and created that notion. Yet, Mangala Samaraweera corrected this and stated that ‘Ranil should be given the presidency’. The other person was Sripathi Sooriyarachchi. There are several others too.",
        "“Finally, we know there were two or three wars. There was the LTTE in 1989, on one side and the Janata Vimukthi Peramuna (JVP) on the other side. Transformers and factories were set on fire on fire, while bombs exploded from the other side. Yet, even during that time, the country never faced so much pressure or hardships.",
        "“Today, on one side, the COVID epidemic, on the other side, political instability. There is racism, as well as religious prejudice. We all know that although there was a country, eventually there was no law and order in the country.",
        "“It was those who were under the influence of drugs who checked the Police vehicles. They took the law into their hands and started attacking the Police. They stole weapons and engaged in various atrocities. Eventually, you stepped forward as a blessing in disguise, to do good for the country. Even your house is written to Royal College.",
        "“You don’t hold even an inch of land anywhere in the world or even in Sri Lanka. Everything you had, you have donated to universities and other institutions. Our President Ranil Wickremesinghe is such a selfless character.",
        "“During the recent past, people took what he said lightly and they ridiculed him. Yet, eventually he undertook this task which is like placing his neck to the train. He accepted the Premiership and then the Presidency.",
        "“Others were invited to come forward and accept the Presidency, but they did not. Whatever said and done, one must have the merit to receive such a post.",
        "“It is a good fortune to be in charge of Sri Lanka, to be in charge of these great sacred treasures, to be in charge of all these different religions and different races.”",
        "Former Ministers and MPs  S.M. Chandrasena, Duminda Dissanayake, Shehan Semasinghe, Chief of Staff to the President and Senior Advisor to the President on National Security Sagala Ratnayake, former Ministers Daya Gamage, Anoma Gamage and others attended the event."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Ranil",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "Dhammarathana Nayaka",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Mihintale Raja Maha Viharadhipathi Ven",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Walavahangunaweve Dhammarathana Nayaka Thera",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Thera",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Mihintale",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "yesterday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Incumbent Ven",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Walavahangunaweve Dhammaratana",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Thera",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Seth Pirith",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Mihidu Maha Rahathan",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Caucasian",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Hunu Wataye Kathawa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Walavahangunaweve Dhammaratana",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Thera",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "South",
            "label": "LOC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "two",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "LTTE",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "1989",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Janata Vimukthi Peramuna",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "JVP",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Today",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "one",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Royal College",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Premiership",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "S.M. Chandrasena",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Duminda Dissanayake",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Shehan Semasinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "National Security Sagala Ratnayake",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ministers Daya Gamage",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Anoma Gamage",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "‘ජනාධිපති රනිල් ශ්‍රී ලංකාව යළි ගොඩනැගිය හැකි දූරදර්ශී නායකයෙක්’ – ආචාර්ය ධම්මරතන නාහිමි",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "මේ රටේ වගකීම භාරගත් ජනාධිපති රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතා නියත වශයෙන්ම රට ගොඩනඟන දූරදර්ශී නායකයකු බව මිහින්තලා රජමහා විහාරාධිපති පූජ්‍ය පූජ්‍ය මිහින්තලේ රජමහා විහාරාධිපති හිමියෝ පැවැසූහ. ආචාර්ය වලවාහැංගුණවැවේ ධම්මරතන නායක හිමි.",
        "“යමක් සිදුවීමට නියමිතවුවහොත් එය සුදුසුම දේට සිදුවේ” යන කියමන ජනාධිපති වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතාගේ පත්වීමෙන් සනාථ වන බව පැවසූ උන්වහන්සේ අද වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතා මේ රට භාරගෙන රට ගොඩනැගීමේ වගකීමට උර දෙමින් සිටින බවද සඳහන් කළේය. වෙස්වළාගත් ආශීර්වාදයක්.",
        "ඊයේ මිහින්තලා පුදබිම වෙත ගිය ජනාධිපතිතුමා ආගමික වතාවත්වල නිරත වී ආශිර්වාද ලබා ගත්තේය. ඉන් අනතුරුව ජනාධිපතිතුමා විහාරාධිපති නාහිමියන් බැහැදුටුවා. ආචාර්ය වලවාහැංගුණවැවේ ධම්මරතන හිමියෝ උන්වහන්සේගේ සුවදුක් විමසා සිටියහ. එම හමුවේදී උන්වහන්සේ මෙම කෙටි අනුශාසනාව කළහ.",
        "මහා සංඝරත්නය සෙත් පිරිත් සජ්ඣායනා කර ජනාධිපතිතුමා වෙත ආශිර්වාද පළ කළ අතර ‘මිහින්තලා සංදේශය’ ද ජනාධිපතිතුමා වෙත පිළිගැන්විණි.",
        "“මේ රට භාරගෙන ආශිර්වාද ලබා ගැනීමට මෙහි පැමිණි අපේ ජනාධිපතිතුමාට මිහිදු මහ රහතන් වහන්සේගෙන් පැවත එන අපි සතුටු වෙනවා වගේම අපේ ආශිර්වාදයත් පිරිනමනවා. අපි එතුමාට අපේ ආශිර්වාදය පුදකර සුබ පතනවා. කොකේසියානු හුණු කවයේ (හුණු වටයේ කතාව) සඳහන් වන්නේ ‘යමක් සිදු වීමට නම්, එය ලැබිය යුතු කෙනෙකුට එය සිදු විය යුතු’ බවයි.",
        "හාමුදුරුවෝ. ආචාර්ය වලවාහැංගුණවැවේ ධම්මරතන හිමියෝ මෙසේ පැවසූහ: “එදා බොහෝ මාධ්‍ය සහ දේශපාලනඥයන් ඔබේ චරිතය ඝාතනය කළා. සමහර දේශපාලකයෝ දකුණට ගිහින් ත්‍රස්තවාදියෙක් කිව්වා. විද්‍යුත් සහ මුද්‍රිත මාධ්‍ය කිහිපයක් ‘රනිල්ට බැහැ’ සටන් පාඨයක් නිර්මාණය කර, එම අදහස ඇති කළේය. එහෙත් මංගල සමරවීර එය නිවැරදි කරමින් ප්‍රකාශ කළේ ‘රනිල්ට ජනාධිපතිකම දිය යුතු’ බවයි. අනෙක් පුද්ගලයා ශ්‍රීපති සූරියආරච්චිය. තවත් කිහිප දෙනෙක් ද සිටිති.",
        "“අවසාන වශයෙන්, අපි දන්නවා යුද්ධ දෙක තුනක් තිබුණා. 1989 එල්ටීටීඊ එක පැත්තකින් ජනතා විමුක්ති පෙරමුණ (ජවිපෙ) හිටියා. ට්‍රාන්ස්ෆෝමර් සහ කර්මාන්තශාලා ගිනිබත් කළ අතර අනෙක් පැත්තෙන් බෝම්බ පිපිරී ගියේය. එහෙත් ඒ කාලය තුළ පවා මෙතරම් පීඩනයකට හෝ දුෂ්කරතාවලට රට මුහුණ දුන්නේ නැත.",
        "“අද, එක් පැත්තකින්, COVID වසංගතය, අනෙක් පැත්තෙන්, දේශපාලන අස්ථාවරත්වය. ජාතිවාදය වගේම ආගම්වාදයත් තියෙනවා. රටක් තිබුනත් අවසානයේ රටේ නීතියක් හා සාමයක් නැති බව අපි කවුරුත් දන්නවා.",
        "“පොලිස් වාහන පරීක්ෂා කළේ කුඩු බීපු අය. ඔවුන් නීතිය අතට ගෙන පොලිසියට පහර දෙන්නට පටන් ගත්හ. ඔවුන් ආයුධ සොරකම් කර විවිධ අමානුෂික ක්‍රියාවල නිරත වූහ. අවසානයේ ඔබ රටට යහපතක් කිරීමට වෙස් වලාගත් ආශිර්වාදයක් ලෙස ඉදිරියට ගියේය. ඔබේ නිවස පවා රාජකීය විද්‍යාලයට ලියා ඇත.",
        "“ඔබට ලෝකයේ හෝ ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ කිසිම තැනක බිම් අඟලක්වත් අයිති නැහැ. ඔබ සතුව තිබූ සියල්ල ඔබ විශ්වවිද්‍යාලවලට සහ වෙනත් ආයතනවලට පරිත්‍යාග කර ඇත. අපේ රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ ජනාධිපතිතුමා එවැනි පරාර්ථකාමී චරිතයක්.",
        "“පසුගිය කාලය තුළ මිනිසුන් ඔහු කියන දේ සැහැල්ලුවට ගත් අතර ඔවුන් ඔහුට සමච්චල් කළා. එහෙත් අවසානයේ ඔහු මෙම කාර්යයට අත ගැසුවේ දුම්රියට බෙල්ල තැබීම වැනි කාර්යයකි. එතුමා අගමැතිකමත් ඊට පස්සේ ජනාධිපතිකමත් බාරගත්තා.",
        "“අනිත් අයට ඉදිරිපත් වෙලා ජනාධිපතිකම පිළිගන්න කියලා ආරාධනා කළා, නමුත් ඔවුන් කළේ නැහැ. මොනවා කිව්වත් කළත් මේ වගේ තනතුරක් ලබන්න පින තියෙන්න ඕන.",
        "“ශ්‍රී ලංකාව භාරව සිටීම, මේ මහා පූජනීය වස්තු භාරව සිටීම, මේ විවිධ ආගම් සහ විවිධ ජාතීන් භාරව සිටීම වාසනාවකි.",
        "හිටපු මැති ඇමතිවරුන් එස්.එම්. චන්ද්‍රසේන, දුමින්ද දිසානායක, ජනාධිපති කාර්ය මණ්ඩල ප්‍රධානී ෂෙහාන් සේමසිංහ සහ ජාතික ආරක්ෂාව පිළිබඳ ජනාධිපති ජ්‍යෙෂ්ඨ උපදේශක සාගල රත්නායක, හිටපු අමාත්‍යවරුන් වන දයා ගමගේ, අනෝමා ගමගේ ඇතුළු පිරිසක් මෙම අවස්ථාවට එක්ව සිටියහ."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "රනිල්",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "ධම්මරතන නායක",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "මිහින්තලේ රජමහා විහාරාධිපති පූජ්‍ය පූජ්‍ය පූජ්‍ය",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "වලවාහැංගුණවැවේ ධම්මරතන නායක හිමි",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "හිමියෝය",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "මිහින්තලේ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඊයේ",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "විහාරාධිපති හාමුදුරුවෝ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "වලවාහැංගුනවැවේ ධම්මරතන",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "හිමියෝය",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "සෙත් පිරිත්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "මිහිදු මහ රහතන් වහන්සේ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "කොකේසියානු",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "හුණු වටයේ කතාව",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "වලවාහැංගුනවැවේ ධම්මරතන",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "හිමියෝය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "දකුණු",
            "label": "LOC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "දෙක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "එල්ටීටීඊය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "1989",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජනතා විමුක්ති පෙරමුණ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජ.වි.පෙ",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "එක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "රාජකීය විද්‍යාලය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "අගමැතිකම",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "එස්.එම්. චන්ද් රසේන",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "දුමින්ද දිසානායක",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ෂෙහාන් සේමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජාතික ආරක්ෂාව සාගල රත්නායක",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඇමැතිවරුන් දයා ගමගේ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "අනෝමා ගමගේ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "இலங்கையை மீண்டும் கட்டியெழுப்பக்கூடிய தொலைநோக்கு பார்வை கொண்ட தலைவர் ஜனாதிபதி ரணில்: கலாநிதி தம்மரதன நாயக்க தேரர்",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "இந்த நாட்டின் பொறுப்பை ஏற்றுள்ள ஜனாதிபதி ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க, நிச்சயமாக நாட்டைக் கட்டியெழுப்பக்கூடிய தொலைநோக்கு பார்வை கொண்ட தலைவர் என மிஹிந்தலை ரஜமஹா விஹாராதிபதி வண. கலாநிதி வலவஹங்குனவேவே தம்மரதன நாயக்க தேரர்.",
        "ஜனாதிபதி விக்ரமசிங்கவின் நியமனம், “ஏதேனும் நடக்குமென்றால், அது மிகவும் பொருத்தமானதுக்கே நடக்கும்” என்ற வாசகத்தை நிரூபிப்பதாகத் தெரிவித்த தேரர், இன்று விக்ரமசிங்க இந்த நாட்டைப் பொறுப்பேற்று, நாட்டைக் கட்டியெழுப்பும் பொறுப்பை ஏற்றுள்ளார். மாறுவேடத்தில் ஒரு ஆசி.",
        "மிஹிந்தலை புனித தலத்திற்கு நேற்று விஜயம் செய்த ஜனாதிபதி சமய வழிபாடுகளில் ஈடுபட்டு ஆசீர்வாதங்களைப் பெற்றுக்கொண்டார். அதனைத் தொடர்ந்து, ஜனாதிபதி அவர்கள், மாதா மாண்புமிகு வண. கலாநிதி வலவஹங்குனவேவே தம்மரதன தேரரை சந்தித்து நலம் விசாரித்தார். இந்த சந்திப்பின் போதே தேரர் இந்த சுருக்கமான அறிவுறுத்தலை விடுத்தார்.",
        "மகாசங்கத்தினர் செத்பிரித் ஓதி ஜனாதிபதிக்கு ஆசீர்வாதம் வழங்கியதுடன், ‘மிஹிந்தலா நினைவுச் சின்னமும்’ ஜனாதிபதியிடம் கையளிக்கப்பட்டது.",
        "“மிஹிது மஹா ரஹதனின் வழித்தோன்றல்கள் என்ற வகையில், இந்த நாட்டைக் கைப்பற்றியதன் பின்னர் இங்கு வந்து ஆசிர்வாதங்களைப் பெற வந்துள்ள எமது ஜனாதிபதிக்கு நாம் மகிழ்ச்சியடைவதுடன் எமது ஆசிகளையும் வழங்குகின்றோம். அவருக்கு நமது ஆசிகளை வழங்கி வாழ்த்துவோம். காகசியன் சுண்ணாம்பு வட்டம் (ஹுனு வதயே கதாவா) 'ஏதாவது நடக்க வேண்டும் என்றால், அது தகுதியான ஒருவருக்கு நடக்க வேண்டும்' என்று கூறுகிறது.",
        "வண. கலாநிதி வலவஹங்குனவேவே தம்மரதன தேரர் கூறினார்: “அப்போது, ​​பல ஊடகங்கள் மற்றும் அரசியல்வாதிகள் உங்கள் பாத்திரத்தை படுகொலை செய்தனர். சில அரசியல்வாதிகள் தென்னிலங்கைக்கு சென்று உங்களை பயங்கரவாதி என்பார்கள். பல இலத்திரனியல் மற்றும் அச்சு ஊடகங்கள் ‘ரணிலால் முடியாது’ என்ற கோஷத்தை உருவாக்கி, அந்தக் கருத்தை உருவாக்கின. ஆனாலும், மங்கள சமரவீர இதனைத் திருத்திக் கொண்டு ‘ரணிலுக்கு ஜனாதிபதி பதவி வழங்கப்பட வேண்டும்’ எனத் தெரிவித்தார். மற்றைய நபர் ஸ்ரீபதி சூரியராச்சி ஆவார். மேலும் பலர் உள்ளனர்.",
        "\"இறுதியாக, இரண்டு அல்லது மூன்று போர்கள் இருந்தன என்பதை நாங்கள் அறிவோம். 1989ல் விடுதலைப் புலிகள் ஒரு புறமும், ஜனதா விமுக்தி பெரமுனா (ஜேவிபி) மறுபுறமும் இருந்தனர். மின்மாற்றிகள் மற்றும் தொழிற்சாலைகளுக்கு தீவைக்கப்பட்டது, மறுபுறம் குண்டுகள் வெடித்தன. ஆயினும்கூட, அந்தக் காலத்திலும், நாடு இவ்வளவு அழுத்தங்களையோ கஷ்டங்களையோ சந்தித்ததில்லை.",
        "“இன்று, ஒரு பக்கம், கோவிட் தொற்றுநோய், மறுபுறம், அரசியல் ஸ்திரமின்மை. இனவாதமும், மதவெறியும் உள்ளது. ஒரு நாடு இருந்தாலும், இறுதியில் நாட்டில் சட்டம் ஒழுங்கு இல்லாமல் போனதை நாம் அனைவரும் அறிவோம்.",
        "“போதைப் போதையில் இருந்தவர்கள்தான் போலீஸ் வாகனங்களை சோதனை செய்தனர். சட்டத்தை கையில் எடுத்துக்கொண்டு காவல்துறையை தாக்க ஆரம்பித்தனர். ஆயுதங்களை திருடி பல்வேறு அட்டூழியங்களில் ஈடுபட்டுள்ளனர். இறுதியில், நாட்டுக்கு நல்லது செய்ய, மாறுவேடத்தில் ஆசீர்வாதமாக நீங்கள் முன்னேறினீர்கள். உங்கள் வீடு கூட ராயல் கல்லூரிக்கு எழுதப்பட்டுள்ளது.",
        "“உலகில் அல்லது இலங்கையில் கூட நீங்கள் ஒரு அங்குல நிலத்தைக் கூட வைத்திருக்கவில்லை. உங்களிடமிருந்த அனைத்தும் பல்கலைக்கழகங்களுக்கும் பிற நிறுவனங்களுக்கும் நன்கொடை அளித்துள்ளீர்கள். எமது ஜனாதிபதி ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க அத்தகைய சுயநலமற்ற குணம் கொண்டவர்.",
        "\"சமீப காலங்களில், மக்கள் அவர் சொன்னதை இலகுவாக எடுத்துக் கொண்டனர், அவர்கள் அவரை கேலி செய்தனர். ஆனாலும், கடைசியில் ரயிலுக்கு கழுத்தை வைப்பது போன்ற பணியை அவர் மேற்கொண்டார். அவர் பிரதமர் பதவியையும் பின்னர் ஜனாதிபதி பதவியையும் ஏற்றுக்கொண்டார்.",
        "“மற்றவர்கள் முன் வந்து ஜனாதிபதி பதவியை ஏற்றுக்கொள்ளுமாறு அழைக்கப்பட்டனர், ஆனால் அவர்கள் அவ்வாறு செய்யவில்லை. எதைச் சொன்னாலும் செய்தாலும், அத்தகைய பதவியைப் பெற ஒரு தகுதி இருக்க வேண்டும்.",
        "\"இலங்கையின் பொறுப்பாளராக இருப்பது, இந்த பெரிய புனித பொக்கிஷங்களுக்குப் பொறுப்பாக இருப்பது, இந்த வெவ்வேறு மதங்கள் மற்றும் வெவ்வேறு இனங்களுக்குப் பொறுப்பாக இருப்பது ஒரு நல்ல அதிர்ஷ்டம்.\"",
        "முன்னாள் அமைச்சர்கள் மற்றும் எம்.பி.க்கள் எஸ்.எம். சந்திரசேன, துமிந்த திஸாநாயக்க, ஜனாதிபதியின் பணிப்பாளர் பிரதானி ஷெஹான் சேமசிங்க, தேசிய பாதுகாப்பு தொடர்பான ஜனாதிபதியின் சிரேஷ்ட ஆலோசகர் சாகல ரத்நாயக்க, முன்னாள் அமைச்சர்களான தயா கமகே, அனோமா கமகே மற்றும் பலர் இந்நிகழ்வில் கலந்துகொண்டனர்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ரணில்",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "தம்மரதன நாயகம்",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "மிஹிந்தலை ராஜ மகா விஹாராதிபதி வண",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "வலவஹங்குனவேவே தம்மரதன நாயக்க தேரர்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "தேரா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "மிஹிந்தலை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "நேற்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "பொறுப்பாளர் வே",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "வலவஹங்குனவேவே தம்மரதன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "தேரா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "சேத் பிரித்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "மிஹிது மகா ரஹதன்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "காகசியன்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஹுனு வதயே கதவ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "வலவஹங்குனவேவே தம்மரதன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "தேரா",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "தெற்கு",
            "label": "LOC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இரண்டு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "விடுதலைப் புலிகள்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "1989",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜனதா விமுக்தி பெரமுனா",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜே.வி.பி",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஒன்று",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ராயல் கல்லூரி",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பிரீமியர்ஷிப்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "எஸ்.எம். சந்திரசேன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "துமிந்த திசாநாயக்க",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஷெஹான் சேமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "தேசிய பாதுகாப்பு சாகல ரத்நாயக்க",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "அமைச்சர்கள் தயா கமகே",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "அனோமா கமகே",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}