{
  "newspaper_id": "d-b-s-jeyaraj-com",
  "url": "https://dbsjeyaraj.com/dbsj/archives/78539",
  "time_ut": 1657629000,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Fight at “Temple Trees” between factions supporting Fonseka and JVP over food served to visiting crowds  Results in 10  Pewrsons Being Hospitalised with Injuries",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Fight at “Temple Trees” between factions supporting Fonseka and JVP over food served to visiting crowds  Results in 10  Pewrsons Being Hospitalised with Injuries",
      "author": "Administrator",
      "body_lines": [
        "At least 10 people were injured during a clash yesterday (12) in the premises of the Prime Minister’s official residence, the Temple Trees, which was taken over by the people during the massive public protests on 9 July.",
        "When contacted by The Morning, a person who was near the Temple Trees premises mentioned that the conflict is believed to have arisen due to a long-running conversation between two groups regarding the food prepared at the premises to be distributed to the visiting crowd.",
        "It was also reported that the clash took place between a group of supporters of the Samagi Jana Balawegaya (SJB) MP Field Marshal Sarath Fonseka and another group of supporters of the National People’s Power (NPP) led by the Janatha Vimukthi Peramuna (JVP), both of which are engaged in the ongoing struggle.",
        "At least 10 people who were injured in the clash have been admitted to the National Hospital of Sri Lanka (NHSL) in Colombo and two of them have since been discharged after receiving treatment.",
        "Meanwhile, speaking to The Morning, Police Media Spokesman, Senior Superintendent of Police (SSP), and Attorney-at-Law (AAL) Nihal Thalduwa said that an investigation is currently being conducted regarding the incident. He also said that some of the injured had sustained cut wounds during the clash.",
        "Another tense situation had erupted at the Temple Trees premises on Monday (11) night, following a group of persons who were staying at a room inside the Temple Trees being questioned by another group.",
        "A massive public protest demanding the resignation of President Gotabaya Rajapaksa, Prime Minister Ranil Wickremesinghe, and the Government was held in Colombo on 9 July. Security forces used various methods, such as tear gassing, to drive the protestors away on that day; however, the protestors were able to seize control of the President’s house (the President’s official residence), the Presidential Secretariat, and the Temple Trees. Since then, people in large numbers are seen waiting in long queues to visit these buildings, to which the general public had not been given access previously."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Temple Trees",
          "label": "WORK_OF_ART"
        },
        {
          "text": "Fonseka",
          "label": "NORP"
        },
        {
          "text": "JVP",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "10",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "At least 10",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "yesterday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "12",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Temple Trees",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "9 July",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "The Morning",
            "label": "WORK_OF_ART"
          },
          {
            "text": "two",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Samagi",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Jana Balawegaya",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "SJB",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the National People’s Power",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "NPP",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Janatha Vimukthi Peramuna",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "JVP",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "At least 10",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "the National Hospital of Sri Lanka",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "NHSL",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Colombo",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "two",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "The Morning",
            "label": "WORK_OF_ART"
          },
          {
            "text": "Nihal Thalduwa",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Monday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "11) night",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Gotabaya Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Colombo",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "9 July",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "that day",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Temple Trees",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "පැමිණි පිරිසට කෑම බීම සම්බන්ධයෙන් ෆොන්සේකාට සහ ජවිපෙට සහය දෙන පාර්ශවයන් අතර අරලියගහ මන්දිරයේ ඇතිවූ ගැටුමක් ප්‍රතිඵලයක් ලෙස පීවර්සන් 10 දෙනෙකු තුවාල ලබා රෝහල් ගත කෙරේ.",
      "author": "පරිපාලක",
      "body_lines": [
        "ජුලි 9 වැනි දා පැවති දැවැන්ත මහජන විරෝධතාවයේ දී ජනතාව විසින් අත්පත් කර ගත් අග්‍රාමාත්‍ය නිල නිවස වන අරලියගහ මන්දිරය පරිශ්‍රයේ ඊයේ (12) ඇති වූ ගැටුමකින් පුද්ගලයන් 10 දෙනෙකු තුවාල ලබා තිබේ.",
        "The Morning කළ විමසීමකදී අරලියගහ මන්දිරය අසල සිටි අයෙක් සඳහන් කළේ පැමිණෙන පිරිසට ලබාදීමට එම පරිශ්‍රයේ සකස් කළ ආහාර සම්බන්ධයෙන් දෙපිරිසක් අතර ඇති වූ දීර්ඝ සංවාදයක් හේතුවෙන් මෙම ගැටුම හටගෙන ඇති බවයි.",
        "සමගි ජන බලවේගයේ (SJB) පාර්ලිමේන්තු මන්ත්‍රී ෆීල්ඩ් මාර්ෂල් සරත් ෆොන්සේකාගේ ආධාරකරුවන් පිරිසක් සහ ජනතා විමුක්ති පෙරමුණ ප්‍රමුඛ ජාතික ජන බලවේගයේ (NPP) තවත් ආධාරකරුවන් පිරිසක් අතර මෙම ගැටුම හටගෙන ඇති බවද වාර්තා විය. දෙදෙනාම අඛණ්ඩ අරගලයක නිරතව සිටිති.",
        "ගැටුමෙන් තුවාල ලැබූ අවම වශයෙන් පුද්ගලයින් 10 දෙනෙකු කොළඹ ජාතික රෝහලට (NHSL) ඇතුළත් කර ඇති අතර ඉන් දෙදෙනෙකු ප්‍රතිකාර ලබා පිටව ගොස් ඇත.",
        "මේ අතර, The Morning වෙත අදහස් දක්වමින් පොලිස් මාධ්‍ය ප්‍රකාශක, ජ්‍යෙෂ්ඨ පොලිස් අධිකාරී (ජ්‍යෙෂ්ඨ පොලිස් අධිකාරී) සහ නීතීඥ (AAL) නිහාල් තල්දූව කියා සිටියේ සිද්ධිය සම්බන්ධයෙන් මේ වනවිට පරීක්ෂණයක් පැවැත්වෙන බවයි. ගැටුමේදී තුවාල ලැබූ ඇතැමුන්ට කැපුම් තුවාල ඇති බවද ඔහු කියා සිටියේය.",
        "සඳුදා (11) රාත්‍රියේ අරලියගහ මන්දිරයේ කාමරයක රැඳී සිටි පිරිසක් තවත් පිරිසක් විසින් ප්‍රශ්න කිරීමත් සමඟ අරලියගහ මන්දිරය පරිශ්‍රයේ තවත් නොසන්සුන්කාරී තත්ත්වයක් හටගෙන තිබුණි.",
        "ජනාධිපති ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ, අග්‍රාමාත්‍ය රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ සහ රජයට ඉල්ලා අස්විය යුතු බවට බලකරමින් දැවැන්ත මහජන විරෝධතාවක් ජූලි 9 වැනිදා කොළඹදී පැවැත්විණි. එදින විරෝධතාකරුවන් පලවා හැරීමට ආරක්ෂක හමුදා කඳුළු ගෑස් ප්‍රහාර වැනි විවිධ ක්‍රම භාවිත කළහ. කෙසේ වෙතත්, විරෝධතාකරුවන්ට ජනාධිපති මන්දිරය (ජනාධිපති නිල නිවස), ජනාධිපති ලේකම් කාර්යාලය සහ අරලියගහ මන්දිරයේ බලය අත්පත් කර ගැනීමට හැකි විය. එතැන් සිට, සාමාන්‍ය ජනතාවට මීට පෙර ප්‍රවේශය ලබා දී නොතිබූ මෙම ගොඩනැගිලි නැරඹීමට විශාල පිරිසක් දිගු පෝලිම්වල රැඳී සිටිනු දක්නට ලැබේ."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "අරලියගහ මන්දිරය",
          "label": "WORK_OF_ART"
        },
        {
          "text": "ෆොන්සේකා",
          "label": "NORP"
        },
        {
          "text": "ජ.වි.පෙ",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "10",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "අවම වශයෙන් 10",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඊයේ",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "12",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "අරලියගහ මන්දිරය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "9 ජූලි",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "උදෑසන",
            "label": "WORK_OF_ART"
          },
          {
            "text": "දෙක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "සමගි",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජන බලවේගය",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "එස්.ජේ.බී",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජාතික ජනතා බලය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "එන්පීපී",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජනතා විමුක්ති පෙරමුණ",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජ.වි.පෙ",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "අවම වශයෙන් 10",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ ජාතික රෝහල",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "NHSL",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "කොළඹ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "දෙක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "උදෑසන",
            "label": "WORK_OF_ART"
          },
          {
            "text": "නිහාල් තල්දූව",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "සඳුදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "11) රාත්රිය",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "කොළඹ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "9 ජූලි",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "එදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "අරලියගහ මන්දිරය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "பொன்சேகாவிற்கும் ஜே.வி.பிக்கும் ஆதரவளிக்கும் தரப்பினருக்கும் இடையில் “கோவில் மரங்களில்” நடந்த சண்டை, வருகை தரும் கூட்டத்திற்கு வழங்கப்படும் உணவு தொடர்பாக 10 பேர் காயங்களுடன் மருத்துவமனையில் அனுமதிக்கப்பட்டுள்ளனர்.",
      "author": "நிர்வாகி",
      "body_lines": [
        "ஜுலை 9ஆம் திகதி இடம்பெற்ற பாரிய பொதுப் போராட்டத்தின் போது மக்களால் கையகப்படுத்தப்பட்ட பிரதமரின் உத்தியோகபூர்வ இல்லமான அலரிமாளிகை வளாகத்தில் நேற்று (12) இடம்பெற்ற மோதலில் குறைந்தது 10 பேர் காயமடைந்தனர்.",
        "தி மோர்னிங்கை தொடர்பு கொண்ட போது, ​​அலரிமாளிகை வளாகத்திற்கு அருகில் இருந்த ஒருவர், வருகை தரும் கூட்டத்திற்கு வழங்குவதற்காக வளாகத்தில் தயாரிக்கப்பட்ட உணவு தொடர்பாக இரு குழுக்களுக்கிடையில் நீண்ட நேர உரையாடல் காரணமாக மோதல் ஏற்பட்டதாக நம்பப்படுகிறது.",
        "சமகி ஜன பலவேகய (SJB) பாராளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர் பீல்ட் மார்ஷல் சரத் பொன்சேகாவின் ஆதரவாளர்கள் குழுவிற்கும் மக்கள் விடுதலை முன்னணி (ஜேவிபி) தலைமையிலான தேசிய மக்கள் சக்தியின் (NPP) ஆதரவாளர்கள் குழுவிற்கும் இடையில் மோதல் ஏற்பட்டுள்ளதாகவும் தெரிவிக்கப்பட்டுள்ளது. இருவரும் தொடர்ந்து போராட்டத்தில் ஈடுபட்டு வருகின்றனர்.",
        "மோதலில் காயமடைந்த குறைந்தது 10 பேர் கொழும்பில் உள்ள இலங்கை தேசிய மருத்துவமனையில் (NHSL) அனுமதிக்கப்பட்டுள்ளனர், அவர்களில் இருவர் சிகிச்சையின் பின்னர் வெளியேற்றப்பட்டுள்ளனர்.",
        "இதற்கிடையில், தி மோனிங்கிடம் பேசிய பொலிஸ் ஊடகப் பேச்சாளர், சிரேஷ்ட பொலிஸ் அத்தியட்சகர் (எஸ்எஸ்பி) மற்றும் சட்டத்தரணி (ஏஏஎல்) நிஹால் தல்துவா, சம்பவம் தொடர்பில் தற்போது விசாரணை நடத்தப்பட்டு வருவதாகத் தெரிவித்தார். மோதலின் போது காயமடைந்த சிலருக்கு வெட்டுக் காயங்கள் ஏற்பட்டதாகவும் அவர் கூறினார்.",
        "திங்கட்கிழமை (11) இரவு அலரிமாளிகை வளாகத்தில் உள்ள அறையில் தங்கியிருந்த ஒரு குழுவினர் மற்றுமொரு குழுவினரால் விசாரணைக்கு உட்படுத்தப்பட்டதைத் தொடர்ந்து, அலரிமாளிகை வளாகத்தில் மற்றுமொரு பதற்றமான சூழ்நிலை ஏற்பட்டது.",
        "ஜனாதிபதி கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ஷ, பிரதமர் ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க மற்றும் அரசாங்கம் பதவி விலகக் கோரி கடந்த ஜூலை 9 ஆம் திகதி கொழும்பில் மாபெரும் மக்கள் போராட்டம் நடத்தப்பட்டது. அன்றைய தினம் போராட்டக்காரர்களை விரட்டுவதற்கு பாதுகாப்புப் படையினர் கண்ணீர் புகைக் குண்டுகளை வீசுதல் போன்ற பல்வேறு முறைகளைப் பயன்படுத்தினர்; எவ்வாறாயினும், ஜனாதிபதியின் இல்லம் (ஜனாதிபதியின் உத்தியோகபூர்வ இல்லம்), ஜனாதிபதி செயலகம் மற்றும் அலரிமாளிகை ஆகியவற்றின் கட்டுப்பாட்டை போராட்டக்காரர்களால் கைப்பற்ற முடிந்தது. அப்போதிருந்து, இந்த கட்டிடங்களை பார்வையிட அதிக எண்ணிக்கையிலான மக்கள் நீண்ட வரிசையில் காத்திருப்பதைக் காணலாம், இதற்கு முன்பு பொதுமக்களுக்கு அனுமதி வழங்கப்படவில்லை."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "கோவில் மரங்கள்",
          "label": "WORK_OF_ART"
        },
        {
          "text": "பொன்சேகா",
          "label": "NORP"
        },
        {
          "text": "ஜே.வி.பி",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "10",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "குறைந்தது 10",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "நேற்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "12",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "கோவில் மரங்கள்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "9 ஜூலை",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "தி மார்னிங்",
            "label": "WORK_OF_ART"
          },
          {
            "text": "இரண்டு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "சமகி",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜன பலவேகயா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "எஸ்.ஜே.பி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "தேசிய மக்கள் சக்தி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "NPP",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜனதா விமுக்தி பெரமுனா",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜே.வி.பி",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "குறைந்தது 10",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கையின் தேசிய மருத்துவமனை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "NHSL",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "கொழும்பு",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இரண்டு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "தி மார்னிங்",
            "label": "WORK_OF_ART"
          },
          {
            "text": "நிஹால் தல்துவா",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "திங்கட்கிழமை",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "11) இரவு",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "கொழும்பு",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "9 ஜூலை",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "அந்த நாள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "கோவில் மரங்கள்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}