{
  "newspaper_id": "d-b-s-jeyaraj-com",
  "url": "https://dbsjeyaraj.com/dbsj/archives/78738",
  "time_ut": 1658774340,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Indian Prime Minister Narendra Modi sends Congratulatory Message to New Sri Lankan President Ranil Wickremesinghe days after Chinese President Xi Jinping and Russian President Vladimir Putin sent messages; Modi says India would continue to be supportive of the quest of the people of Sri Lanka",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Indian Prime Minister Narendra Modi sends Congratulatory Message to New Sri Lankan President Ranil Wickremesinghe days after Chinese President Xi Jinping and Russian President Vladimir Putin sent messages; Modi says India would continue to be supportive of the quest of the people of Sri Lanka",
      "author": "Administrator",
      "body_lines": [
        "Prime Minister Narendra Modi has sent a congratulatory message to Sri Lanka’s newly elected President Ranil Wickremesinghe, nearly a week after his rise to the island nation’s helm amid political upheaval triggered by a severe economic meltdown.",
        "Mr. Modi’s outreach to Mr. Wickremesinghe follows messages from Chinese President Xi Jinping and Russian President Vladimir Putin to the Sri Lankan leader, who is counting on urgent international support to cope with the deepening crisis. The Indian High Commission in Colombo, which put out a tweet on July 20 — the day of Mr. Wickremesinghe’s election in Parliament — noted the development but stopped short of congratulating him. This was hours after the Indian mission “categorically denied” media reports of India attempting to “influence” the key parliament vote.",
        "“You have assumed the high office at a critical time for Sri Lanka,” Mr. Modi said in the letter dated July 25. Expressing hope that Mr. Wickremesinghe’s tenure would “nurture” economic stability and “fulfill the aspirations of all citizens”, the Indian Prime Minister said: “As a close friend and neighbour of Sri Lanka, India will continue to be supportive of the quest of the people of Sri Lanka for stability and economic recovery, through established democratic means, institutions and constitutional framework.”",
        "The message reiterated India’s emphasis on assisting the “people of Sri Lanka”. “I look forward to working closely with you for the mutual benefit of our people,” Mr. Modi said in the letter.",
        "On Tuesday, Indian High Commissioner Gopal Baglay paid “a courtesy call” on newly appointed Prime Minister Dinesh Gunawardena and Foreign Minister Ali Sabry.",
        "As Sri Lanka’s economic crisis aggravated from the beginning of this year, India emerged its top creditor, stepping in with crucial assistance of $ 3.8 billion so far, by way of currency swaps, loan deferments and credit lines for essential imports. On Tuesday, a large consignment of rice, milk powder and medicines arrived as part of donations from the government of Tamil Nadu. This was the third consignment from the southern State, which has extended nearly 40,000 MT of rice, 500 MT of milk powder and more than 100 MT of medicines totalling some $ 22 million.",
        "After pre-emptively defaulting on its $ 51 billion-foreign debt in April, Colombo has been holding talks with the International Monetary Fund (IMF), hoping for a package that would enable its recovery. However, with the IMF indicating that its support would depend on Sri Lanka’s creditors expressing confidence over the government’s debt restructure strategy, the Wickremesinghe government is in urgent need for bridge financing to meet the requirements of the next few months.",
        "Meanwhile, the economic downturn is not Sri Lanka’s only challenge, while the world closely tracks the prospects for political stability in the island. Although elected with an impressive majority in Parliament, Mr. Wickremesinghe faces considerable criticism from Sri Lankans who see him as an ally of the discredited Rajapaksas, who were ousted by stunning citizens’ protests.",
        "More recently, the military’s ruthless pre-dawn raid at Colombo’s main agitation site, just after he assumed charge, drew wide condemnation by the international community, including the United Nations. Protests against Mr. Wickremesinghe and the military assault on protesters continue in different parts of the country.",
        "On Tuesday, over 150 academics and South Asia scholars from the world over released a statement urging Mr. Wickremesinghe to protect citizens’ right to dissent. “Wickremasinghe was elected by Parliament to take on the presidency, which was vacated due to the non-violent pro-democracy movement against authoritarianism and failed governance.",
        "His decision to follow in the footsteps of his predecessors is deeply alarming and does not offer the prospect of Sri Lanka progressing beyond the current crisis it is in,” the scholars said in a statement. Pointing to the Sri Lankan President’s reference to protesters as “fascists”, the academics noted it was “totally inaccurate, inappropriate and damaging” and that it “weaponises the term to provide an excuse for the use of extreme force.”"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Indian",
          "label": "NORP"
        },
        {
          "text": "Narendra Modi",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "Congratulatory Message to New Sri Lankan",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "Ranil Wickremesinghe",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "days",
          "label": "DATE"
        },
        {
          "text": "Chinese",
          "label": "NORP"
        },
        {
          "text": "Xi Jinping",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "Russian",
          "label": "NORP"
        },
        {
          "text": "Vladimir Putin",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "Modi",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "India",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "Sri Lanka",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Narendra Modi",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka’s",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "nearly a week",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Modi",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Chinese",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Xi Jinping",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Russian",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Vladimir Putin",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lankan",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "The Indian High Commission",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Colombo",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "July 20 — the day",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Indian",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "India",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Modi",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "July 25",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Indian",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "India",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "democratic",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "India",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Modi",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Tuesday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Indian",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Gopal Baglay",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Dinesh Gunawardena",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ali Sabry",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the beginning of this year",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "India",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "$ 3.8 billion",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "Tuesday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Tamil Nadu",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "third",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "State",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "nearly 40,000",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "500",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "more than 100",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "some $ 22 million",
            "label": "MONEY"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "$ 51 billion",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "April",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Colombo",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the International Monetary Fund",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "the next few months",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka’s",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lankans",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Rajapaksas",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Colombo",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the United Nations",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Tuesday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "over 150",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "South Asia",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Wickremasinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "චීන ජනාධිපති ෂී ජින්පින් සහ රුසියානු ජනාධිපති ව්ලැඩිමීර් පුටින් පණිවුඩ යවා දින කිහිපයකට පසු ඉන්දීය අගමැති නරේන්ද්‍ර මෝදි නව ශ්‍රී ලංකා ජනාධිපති රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ වෙත සුබපැතුම් පණිවිඩයක් යවයි; ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ ජනතාවගේ ගවේෂණයට ඉන්දියාව තවදුරටත් සහාය දෙන බව මෝදි පවසයි",
      "author": "පරිපාලක",
      "body_lines": [
        "දරුණු ආර්ථික කඩාවැටීමක් හේතුවෙන් ඇති වූ දේශපාලන පෙරළියක් මධ්‍යයේ ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ අභිනවයෙන් තේරී පත් වූ ජනාධිපති රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතාට සතියකට පමණ පසු අග්‍රාමාත්‍ය නරේන්ද්‍ර මෝදි මහතා සුබපැතුම් පණිවිඩයක් එවා තිබේ.",
        "මෝදි මහතා වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතා වෙත කරන ලද ප්‍රවේශය, ගැඹුරු වන අර්බුදයට මුහුණ දීම සඳහා හදිසි ජාත්‍යන්තර සහයෝගය අපේක්ෂා කරන ශ්‍රී ලංකා නායකයා වෙත චීන ජනාධිපති ෂී ජින්පින් සහ රුසියානු ජනාධිපති ව්ලැඩිමීර් පුටින් විසින් කරන ලද පණිවිඩ වලින් පසුවය. වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතා පාර්ලිමේන්තුවට තේරී පත් වූ දින ජූලි 20 දා ට්විටර් පණිවිඩයක් නිකුත් කළ කොළඹ ඉන්දීය මහ කොමසාරිස් කාර්යාලය, වර්ධනය ගැන සඳහන් කළ නමුත් ඔහුට සුබ පැතීම නතර කළේය. මෙය සිදු වූයේ, ප්‍රධාන පාර්ලිමේන්තු ඡන්දයට \"බලපෑමට\" ඉන්දියාව උත්සාහ කිරීම පිලිබඳ මාධ්‍ය වාර්තා ඉන්දියානු මෙහෙයුම \"තදින් ප්‍රතික්ෂේප කර\" පැය කිහිපයකට පසුවය.",
        "\"ඔබ ශ්‍රී ලංකාවට තීරණාත්මක අවස්ථාවක දී ඉහළ තනතුරක් භාරගෙන ඇත\" යනුවෙන් ජුලි 25 දිනැති ලිපියේ මෝදි මහතා ප්‍රකාශ කළේය. වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතාගේ ධුර කාලය ආර්ථික ස්ථාවරත්වය \"පෝෂණය\" කර \"සියලු පුරවැසියන්ගේ අභිලාෂයන් ඉටු කරනු ඇතැයි\" බලාපොරොත්තු පළ කරමින්. \"ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ සමීප මිතුරෙකු සහ අසල්වැසියෙකු ලෙස, ඉන්දියාව ස්ථාපිත ප්‍රජාතන්ත්‍රවාදී මාධ්‍යයන්, ආයතන සහ ව්‍යවස්ථාමය රාමුව හරහා ස්ථාවරත්වය සහ ආර්ථික ප්‍රකෘතිය සඳහා ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ ජනතාවගේ ගවේෂණයට අඛණ්ඩව සහාය දක්වනු ඇත\" යනුවෙන් ඉන්දීය අග්‍රාමාත්‍යවරයා පැවසීය.",
        "\"ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ ජනතාවට\" සහය වීම සම්බන්ධයෙන් ඉන්දියාව අවධාරණය කරන බව එම පණිවිඩයෙන් යළිත් අවධාරණය කෙරිණි. “අපේ ජනතාවගේ අන්‍යෝන්‍ය ප්‍රයෝජනය සඳහා ඔබ සමඟ සමීපව කටයුතු කිරීමට මම බලාපොරොත්තු වෙනවා,” මෝදි මහතා එම ලිපියේ සඳහන් කර ඇත.",
        "අඟහරුවාදා ඉන්දීය මහ කොමසාරිස් ගෝපාල් බග්ලේ, අලුතින් පත් කරන ලද අගමැති දිනේෂ් ගුණවර්ධන සහ විදේශ අමාත්‍ය අලි සබ්රි වෙත “ආචාරශීලී හමුවීමක්” පැවැත්වීය.",
        "මේ වසර ආරම්භයේ සිට ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ ආර්ථික අර්බුදය උග්‍ර වූ විට, මුදල් හුවමාරු කිරීම්, ණය කල් දැමීම් සහ අත්‍යවශ්‍ය ආනයන සඳහා ණය මාර්ග ඔස්සේ මේ දක්වා ඩොලර් බිලියන 3.8 ක තීරණාත්මක ආධාර ලබා ගනිමින් ඉන්දියාව එහි ඉහළම ණයකරුවා බවට පත්විය. අඟහරුවාදා දින සහල්, කිරිපිටි සහ ඖෂධ විශාල තොගයක් තමිල්නාඩු රජයේ පරිත්‍යාගවල කොටසක් ලෙස පැමිණියේය. සහල් මෙට්‍රික් ටොන් 40,000කට ආසන්න ප්‍රමාණයක්, කිරිපිටි මෙට්‍රික් ටොන් 500ක් සහ ඖෂධ මෙට්‍රික් ටොන් 100කට වැඩි ප්‍රමාණයක් ඩොලර් මිලියන 22ක් පමණ දීර්ඝ කර ඇති දකුණු ප්‍රාන්තයේ තුන්වැනි තොගය මෙය විය.",
        "අප්‍රේල් මාසයේදී එහි ඩොලර් බිලියන 51 විදේශ නය කල්තියා පැහැර හැරීමෙන් පසු, කොළඹ ජාත්‍යන්තර මූල්‍ය අරමුදල (IMF) සමඟ සාකච්ඡා පවත්වමින් එහි ප්‍රකෘතිමත් වීමට හැකි පැකේජයක් අපේක්ෂා කරයි. කෙසේ වෙතත්, ජාමූඅ එහි සහාය ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ ණයහිමියන් ආන්ඩුවේ ණය ප්‍රතිව්‍යුහගත කිරීමේ ක්‍රමෝපාය පිලිබඳ විශ්වාසය පළ කිරීම මත රඳා පවතිනු ඇති බව පෙන්වා දීමත් සමග, ඉදිරි මාස කිහිපයේ අවශ්‍යතා සපුරාලීම සඳහා වික්‍රමසිංහ ආන්ඩුවට පාලම් මූල්‍යකරණයේ හදිසි අවශ්‍යතාවයක් පවතී.",
        "මේ අතර, ආර්ථික අවපාතය ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ එකම අභියෝගය නොවන අතර, දිවයිනේ දේශපාලන ස්ථාවරත්වය සඳහා වන අපේක්ෂාවන් ලෝකය සමීපව නිරීක්ෂණය කරයි. පාර්ලිමේන්තුවේ විශ්මයජනක බහුතරයකින් තේරී පත් වුවද, වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතා විශ්මය ජනක පුරවැසි විරෝධතාවලින් නෙරපා හරින ලද අපකීර්තිමත් රාජපක්ෂවරුන්ගේ හිතවතෙකු ලෙස දකින ශ්‍රී ලාංකිකයන්ගෙන් සැලකිය යුතු විවේචනවලට ලක් වේ.",
        "වඩාත් මෑතක දී, ඔහු බලයට පත්වීමෙන් පසුව, කොළඹ ප්‍රධාන උද්ඝෝෂණ භූමියේ දී මිලිටරිය විසින් සිදු කරන ලද නිර්දය පූර්ව ප්‍රහාරය, එක්සත් ජාතීන්ගේ සංවිධානය ඇතුළු ජාත්‍යන්තර ප්‍රජාව විසින් පුලුල් හෙලා දැකීමට ලක් විය. වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතාට එරෙහි විරෝධතා සහ විරෝධතාකරුවන්ට හමුදා ප්‍රහාර එල්ල කිරීම සම්බන්ධයෙන් රටේ විවිධ ප්‍රදේශවල අඛණ්ඩව විරෝධතා පැවැත්වේ.",
        "අඟහරුවාදා, ලොව පුරා සිටින 150 කට අධික විද්වතුන් සහ දකුණු ආසියාවේ විද්වතුන් ප්‍රකාශයක් නිකුත් කරමින් වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතාට විරුද්ධ වීමට පුරවැසියන්ගේ අයිතිය ආරක්ෂා කරන ලෙස ඉල්ලා සිටියහ. “ඒකාධිපතිවාදයට සහ අසාර්ථක පාලනයට එරෙහි අවිහිංසාවාදී ප්‍රජාතන්ත්‍රවාදී ව්‍යාපාරය හේතුවෙන් පුරප්පාඩු වූ ජනාධිපති ධුරය භාර ගැනීමට වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතා පාර්ලිමේන්තුවෙන් තේරී පත් විය.",
        "ඔහුගේ පූර්වගාමීන්ගේ අඩිපාරේ යාමට ඔහු ගත් තීරණය අතිශයින් තැතිගන්වන සුළු වන අතර ශ්‍රී ලංකාව පවතින අර්බුදයෙන් ඔබ්බට ප්‍රගතියක් ලබා ගැනීමේ අපේක්ෂාව ඉදිරිපත් නොකරයි, ”විද්වතුන් නිවේදනයක් නිකුත් කරමින් කියා සිටියේය. විරෝධතාකරුවන් \"ෆැසිස්ට්වාදීන්\" ලෙස ශ්‍රී ලංකා ජනාධිපතිවරයා සඳහන් කිරීම පෙන්වා දෙමින්, විද්වතුන් එය \"සම්පූර්ණයෙන්ම සාවද්‍ය, නුසුදුසු සහ හානිදායක\" බවත්, \"අතිශයින් බලය භාවිතා කිරීම සඳහා නිදහසට කරුණක් සැපයීම සඳහා මෙම යෙදුම ආයුධ කරන\" බවත් සඳහන් කළහ."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ඉන්දීය",
          "label": "NORP"
        },
        {
          "text": "නරේන්ද්‍ර මෝදි",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "නව ශ්‍රී ලාංකිකයාට සුබ පැතුම් පණිවිඩයක්",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "දින",
          "label": "DATE"
        },
        {
          "text": "චීන",
          "label": "NORP"
        },
        {
          "text": "Xi Jinping",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "රුසියානු",
          "label": "NORP"
        },
        {
          "text": "ව්ලැඩිමීර් පුටින්",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "මෝඩි",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "ඉන්දියාව",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "නරේන්ද්‍ර මෝදි",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "සතියකට ආසන්න කාලයක්",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "මෝඩි",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "චීන",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Xi Jinping",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "රුසියානු",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ව්ලැඩිමීර් පුටින්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලාංකික",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දීය මහ කොමසාරිස් කාර්යාලය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "කොළඹ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජූලි 20 - දිනය",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දීය",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මෝඩි",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජූලි 25",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දීය",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ප්රජාතන්ත්රවාදී",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මෝඩි",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "අඟහරුවාදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දීය",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගෝපාල් බග්ලේ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "දිනේෂ් ගුණවර්ධන",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "අලි සබ්රි",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "සමාජවාදී",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඩොලර් බිලියන 3.8 කි",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "අඟහරුවාදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "තමිල්නාඩුව",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "තෙවන",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "රජයේ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "40,000කට ආසන්නයි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "500",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "100 ට වැඩි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඩොලර් මිලියන 22 ක් පමණ",
            "label": "MONEY"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ඩොලර් බිලියන 51 කි",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "අප්රේල්",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "කොළඹ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජාත්‍යන්තර මුල්‍ය අරමුදල",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉදිරි මාස කිහිපය",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලාංකිකයන්",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "රාජපක්ෂලා",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "කොළඹ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "එක්සත් ජාතීන්ගේ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "අඟහරුවාදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "150 ට වැඩි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "දකුණු ආසියාව",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "சீன ஜனாதிபதி ஜி ஜின்பிங் மற்றும் ரஷ்ய ஜனாதிபதி விளாடிமிர் புடின் செய்திகளை அனுப்பிய சில நாட்களுக்குப் பிறகு, புதிய இலங்கை ஜனாதிபதி ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்கவுக்கு இந்தியப் பிரதமர் நரேந்திர மோடி வாழ்த்துச் செய்தியை அனுப்பினார்; இலங்கை மக்களின் முயற்சிக்கு இந்தியா தொடர்ந்து உறுதுணையாக இருக்கும் என்று மோடி தெரிவித்துள்ளார்",
      "author": "நிர்வாகி",
      "body_lines": [
        "இலங்கையின் புதிய ஜனாதிபதி ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்கே, கடுமையான பொருளாதார வீழ்ச்சியால் தூண்டப்பட்ட அரசியல் எழுச்சிக்கு மத்தியில், தீவு நாட்டின் தலைமைப் பதவிக்கு ஏறக்குறைய ஒரு வாரத்திற்குப் பிறகு, பிரதமர் நரேந்திர மோடி வாழ்த்துச் செய்தியை அனுப்பியுள்ளார்.",
        "சீன ஜனாதிபதி ஜி ஜின்பிங் மற்றும் ரஷ்ய ஜனாதிபதி விளாடிமிர் புடின் ஆகியோர் இலங்கைத் தலைவருக்கு அனுப்பிய செய்திகளைத் தொடர்ந்து திரு. விக்கிரமசிங்கவிற்கு திரு. மோடியின் தொடர்பு ஆழமடைந்து வரும் நெருக்கடியைச் சமாளிக்க அவசர சர்வதேச ஆதரவை எதிர்பார்க்கிறது. பாராளுமன்றத்தில் திரு. விக்கிரமசிங்க தேர்ந்தெடுக்கப்பட்ட நாளான ஜூலை 20 அன்று ட்வீட் ஒன்றை வெளியிட்ட கொழும்பில் உள்ள இந்திய உயர் ஸ்தானிகராலயம், வளர்ச்சியைக் குறிப்பிட்டது, ஆனால் அவரை வாழ்த்துவதை நிறுத்தியது. பாராளுமன்றத்தின் முக்கிய வாக்கெடுப்பில் இந்தியா \"செல்வாக்கு செலுத்த\" முயற்சிக்கிறது என்ற ஊடக அறிக்கைகளை இந்திய தூதரகம் \"முற்றிலும் மறுத்த\" சில மணிநேரங்களுக்குப் பிறகு இது நடந்தது.",
        "\"இலங்கைக்கு ஒரு முக்கியமான நேரத்தில் நீங்கள் உயர் பதவியை ஏற்றுள்ளீர்கள்\" என்று திரு. மோடி ஜூலை 25 தேதியிட்ட கடிதத்தில் கூறினார். திரு. விக்கிரமசிங்கவின் பதவிக்காலம் பொருளாதார ஸ்திரத்தன்மையை \"வளர்க்கும்\" மற்றும் \"அனைத்து குடிமக்களின் அபிலாஷைகளை நிறைவேற்றும்\" என்று நம்பிக்கை தெரிவித்தார். \"இலங்கையின் நெருங்கிய நண்பராகவும் அண்டை நாடாகவும், நிறுவப்பட்ட ஜனநாயக வழிமுறைகள், நிறுவனங்கள் மற்றும் அரசியலமைப்பு கட்டமைப்பின் மூலம், ஸ்திரத்தன்மை மற்றும் பொருளாதார மீட்சிக்கான இலங்கை மக்களின் தேடலுக்கு இந்தியா தொடர்ந்து ஆதரவளிக்கும்\" என்று இந்தியப் பிரதமர் கூறினார்.",
        "\"இலங்கை மக்களுக்கு\" உதவுவதில் இந்தியாவின் முக்கியத்துவத்தை இந்த செய்தி மீண்டும் வலியுறுத்தியது. \"எங்கள் மக்களின் பரஸ்பர நன்மைக்காக உங்களுடன் நெருக்கமாக பணியாற்ற நான் எதிர்நோக்குகிறேன்\" என்று திரு. மோடி கடிதத்தில் தெரிவித்துள்ளார்.",
        "செவ்வாயன்று, இந்திய உயர்ஸ்தானிகர் கோபால் பாக்லே, புதிதாக நியமிக்கப்பட்ட பிரதம மந்திரி தினேஷ் குணவர்தன மற்றும் வெளியுறவு அமைச்சர் அலி சப்ரி ஆகியோரை \"மரியாதைச் சந்தித்தார்\".",
        "இந்த ஆண்டின் தொடக்கத்தில் இருந்து இலங்கையின் பொருளாதார நெருக்கடி மோசமடைந்ததால், நாணய பரிமாற்றம், கடன் ஒத்திவைப்பு மற்றும் அத்தியாவசிய இறக்குமதிகளுக்கான கடன் வரிகள் ஆகியவற்றின் மூலம் இதுவரை 3.8 பில்லியன் டாலர் முக்கிய உதவியுடன் இந்தியா தனது முதல் கடனாளியாக உருவெடுத்துள்ளது. செவ்வாய்க்கிழமை, தமிழக அரசின் நன்கொடையின் ஒரு பகுதியாக அரிசி, பால் பவுடர் மற்றும் மருந்துகள் ஒரு பெரிய சரக்கு வந்தன. இது தென் மாநிலத்தின் மூன்றாவது சரக்கு ஆகும், இது கிட்டத்தட்ட 40,000 மெட்ரிக் டன் அரிசி, 500 மெட்ரிக் டன் பால் பவுடர் மற்றும் 100 மெட்ரிக் டன் மருந்துகளை மொத்தமாக 22 மில்லியன் டாலர்களை நீட்டித்துள்ளது.",
        "ஏப்ரல் மாதத்தில் அதன் $51 பில்லியன் வெளிநாட்டுக் கடனை முன்கூட்டியே திருப்பிச் செலுத்தாத பின்னர், கொழும்பு சர்வதேச நாணய நிதியத்துடன் (IMF) பேச்சுவார்த்தைகளை நடத்தி வருகிறது, அதன் மீட்சியை செயல்படுத்தும் ஒரு பொதியை எதிர்பார்க்கிறது. எவ்வாறாயினும், அரசாங்கத்தின் கடன் மறுசீரமைப்பு மூலோபாயத்தின் மீது நம்பிக்கையை வெளிப்படுத்தும் இலங்கையின் கடனாளிகள் மீது அதன் ஆதரவு தங்கியிருக்கும் என்று IMF சுட்டிக்காட்டியுள்ள நிலையில், விக்கிரமசிங்க அரசாங்கம் அடுத்த சில மாதங்களின் தேவைகளைப் பூர்த்தி செய்வதற்கு பாலம் நிதியளிப்புக்கான அவசரத் தேவையில் உள்ளது.",
        "இதற்கிடையில், பொருளாதார வீழ்ச்சி இலங்கையின் ஒரே சவாலாக இல்லை, அதே நேரத்தில் தீவில் அரசியல் ஸ்திரத்தன்மைக்கான வாய்ப்புகளை உலகம் உன்னிப்பாகக் கண்காணிக்கிறது. பாராளுமன்றத்தில் கணிசமான பெரும்பான்மையுடன் தேர்ந்தெடுக்கப்பட்ட போதிலும், திரு. விக்கிரமசிங்கே, அதிர்ச்சியூட்டும் குடிமக்களின் எதிர்ப்புகளால் வெளியேற்றப்பட்ட, மதிப்பிழந்த ராஜபக்சேக்களின் கூட்டாளியாக அவரைப் பார்க்கும் இலங்கையர்களிடமிருந்து கணிசமான விமர்சனங்களை எதிர்கொள்கிறார்.",
        "மிக சமீபத்தில், கொழும்பின் பிரதான கிளர்ச்சி தளத்தில் இராணுவத்தின் இரக்கமற்ற முன்கூட்டிய சோதனை, அவர் பொறுப்பேற்றவுடன், ஐக்கிய நாடுகள் சபை உட்பட சர்வதேச சமூகத்தின் பரந்த கண்டனத்தை ஈர்த்தது. திரு. விக்கிரமசிங்கவுக்கு எதிரான போராட்டங்கள் மற்றும் போராட்டக்காரர்கள் மீதான இராணுவத் தாக்குதல் ஆகியவை நாட்டின் பல்வேறு பகுதிகளில் தொடர்கின்றன.",
        "செவ்வாயன்று, உலகெங்கிலும் உள்ள 150 க்கும் மேற்பட்ட கல்வியாளர்கள் மற்றும் தெற்காசிய அறிஞர்கள், கருத்து வேறுபாடுகளுக்கு குடிமக்களின் உரிமையைப் பாதுகாக்க திரு. விக்கிரமசிங்கவை வலியுறுத்தும் அறிக்கையை வெளியிட்டனர். “எதேச்சாதிகாரம் மற்றும் தோல்வியுற்ற ஆட்சிக்கு எதிரான அகிம்சை ஜனநாயக சார்பு இயக்கத்தின் காரணமாக வெற்றிடமடைந்த ஜனாதிபதி பதவியை ஏற்க விக்கிரமசிங்க பாராளுமன்றத்தால் தேர்ந்தெடுக்கப்பட்டார்.",
        "அவரது முன்னோடிகளின் அடிச்சுவடுகளைப் பின்பற்றுவதற்கான அவரது முடிவு மிகவும் ஆபத்தானது மற்றும் இலங்கை தற்போதைய நெருக்கடிக்கு அப்பால் முன்னேறும் வாய்ப்பை வழங்கவில்லை, ”என்று அறிஞர்கள் ஒரு அறிக்கையில் தெரிவித்தனர். எதிர்ப்பாளர்களை \"பாசிஸ்டுகள்\" என்று இலங்கை ஜனாதிபதி குறிப்பிடுவதை சுட்டிக்காட்டிய கல்வியாளர்கள், இது \"முற்றிலும் துல்லியமற்றது, பொருத்தமற்றது மற்றும் சேதம் விளைவிக்கக்கூடியது\" என்றும், \"அதிக பலத்தைப் பயன்படுத்துவதற்கான ஒரு சாக்குப்போக்கை வழங்குவதற்காக இந்த வார்த்தையை ஆயுதமாக்குகிறது\" என்றும் குறிப்பிட்டனர்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "இந்தியன்",
          "label": "NORP"
        },
        {
          "text": "நரேந்திர மோடி",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "புதிய இலங்கையருக்கு வாழ்த்துச் செய்தி",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "நாட்களில்",
          "label": "DATE"
        },
        {
          "text": "சீன",
          "label": "NORP"
        },
        {
          "text": "Xi Jinping",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "ரஷ்யன்",
          "label": "NORP"
        },
        {
          "text": "விளாடிமிர் புடின்",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "மோடி",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "இந்தியா",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "இலங்கை",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "நரேந்திர மோடி",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கையின்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "கிட்டத்தட்ட ஒரு வாரம்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "மோடி",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "சீன",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Xi Jinping",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரஷ்யன்",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "விளாடிமிர் புடின்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்திய உயர் ஸ்தானிகராலயம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "கொழும்பு",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜூலை 20 - நாள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்தியன்",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்தியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "மோடி",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜூலை 25",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்தியன்",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்தியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜனநாயக",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இந்தியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "மோடி",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "செவ்வாய்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்தியன்",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "கோபால் பாக்லே",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "தினேஷ் குணவர்தன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "அலி சப்ரி",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்த ஆண்டின் தொடக்கத்தில்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்தியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "$ 3.8 பில்லியன்",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "செவ்வாய்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "தமிழ்நாடு",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "மூன்றாவது",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "நிலை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "கிட்டத்தட்ட 40,000",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "500",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "100க்கு மேல்",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "சுமார் $22 மில்லியன்",
            "label": "MONEY"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "$ 51 பில்லியன்",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஏப்ரல்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "கொழும்பு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "சர்வதேச நாணய நிதியம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "அடுத்த சில மாதங்கள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கையின்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கையர்கள்",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ராஜபக்சேக்கள்",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "கொழும்பு",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஐக்கிய நாடுகள்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "செவ்வாய்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "150க்கு மேல்",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "தெற்காசியா",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}