{
  "newspaper_id": "virakesari-lk",
  "url": "http://www.virakesari.lk/article/130914",
  "time_ut": 1657098489,
  "original_lang": "ta",
  "original_title": "சொகுசு வாகனத்தில் கேரளா கஞ்சா கடத்திய ஒருவர் கைது",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "A man was arrested for smuggling Kerala ganja in a luxury vehicle",
      "author": "Digital Desk 5",
      "body_lines": [
        "A suspect who smuggled Kerala ganja from Karpiti to Colombo in a luxury vehicle was arrested today (06).",
        "The said vehicle was intercepted with the help of the Navy at the checkpoint in Karambai area of ​​Kapiti Colombo main road and conducted search operations.",
        "Nuraichol police said that 212 kg of Kerala Ganja was seized from the said vehicle.",
        "A 32-year-old man from Colombo Grandpass has been arrested on suspicion.",
        "They said that steps are being taken to produce the arrested suspect, the seized Kerala ganja and the luxury van used for smuggling in the Puttalam court."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Kerala",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Kerala",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Karpiti to Colombo",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "06",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Navy",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Karambai",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "​​Kapiti Colombo",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Nuraichol",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "212 kg",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kerala Ganja",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "32-year-old",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Kerala",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Puttalam",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "සුඛෝපභෝගී වාහනයකින් කේරළ ගංජා ප්‍රවාහනය කරමින් සිටි පුද්ගලයෙකු අත්අඩංගුවට ගෙන තිබෙනවා",
      "author": "ඩිජිටල් මේසය 5",
      "body_lines": [
        "කර්පිටි ප්‍රදේශයේ සිට කොළඹ දක්වා සුඛෝපභෝගී වාහනයකින් කේරළ ගංජා ප්‍රවාහනය කළ සැකකරුවෙකු අද (06) අත්අඩංගුවට ගෙන තිබෙනවා.",
        "එම රථය නාවික හමුදාවේ සහය ඇතිව කැපිටි කොළඹ ප්‍රධාන මාර්ගයේ කරම්බායි ප්‍රදේශයේ මුරපොලේදී අත්අඩංගුවට ගෙන සෝදිසි මෙහෙයුම් සිදු කර ඇත.",
        "එම මෝටර් රථයේ තිබී කේරළ ගංජා කිලෝග්‍රෑම් 212ක් අත්අඩංගුවට ගත් බව නුරයිචෝල් පොලිසිය පවසයි.",
        "සැකපිට අත්අඩංගුවට ගෙන ඇත්තේ කොළඹ ග්‍රෑන්ඩ්පාස් ප්‍රදේශයේ පදිංචි 32 හැවිරිදි පුද්ගලයෙකි.",
        "අත්අඩංගුවට ගත් සැකකරු, අත්අඩංගුවට ගත් කේරළ ගංජා තොගය සහ ජාවාරමට යොදාගත් සුඛෝපබෝගී වෑන් රථය පුත්තලම අධිකරණයට ඉදිරිපත් කිරීමට පියවර ගනිමින් සිටින බවද ඔවුහු පැවසූහ."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "කේරල",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "කේරල",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "කර්පිටි කොළඹට",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "06",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "නාවික",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "කරම්බායි",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "කැපිටි කොළඹ",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "නුරයිචෝල්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "කිලෝ ග්රෑම් 212 කි",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "කේරළ ගංජා",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "32 හැවිරිදිය",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "කේරල",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "පුත්තලම",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "சொகுசு வாகனத்தில் கேரளா கஞ்சா கடத்திய ஒருவர் கைது",
      "author": "Digital Desk 5",
      "body_lines": [
        "கற்பிட்டியிலிருந்து கொழும்பிற்கு சொகுசு வாகனத்தில் கேரளா கஞ்சா கடத்திய சந்தேகநபர் ஒருவர் இன்று (06) கைது செய்யப்பட்டுள்ளார்.",
        "கற்பிட்டி கொழும்பு பிரதான வீதியின் கரம்பை பகுதியில் உள்ள சோதனைச் சாவடியில் கடற்படையிரின் உதவியுடன் குறித்த வாகனத்தை மறித்து சோதனை நடவடிக்கைகளை மேற்கொண்டுள்ளனர்.",
        "இதன்போது குறித்த வாகனத்தில் 212 கிலோ கேரளா கஞ்சா கைப்பற்றப்பட்டதாக நுரைச்சோலைப் பொலிஸார் தெரிவித்தனர்.",
        "கொழும்பு கிராண்ட்பாஸ் பகுதியைச் சேர்ந்த 32 வயதுடைய ஒருவர் சந்தேகத்தின் பேரில் கைது செய்யப்பட்டுள்ளார்.",
        "கைது செய்யப்பட்ட சந்தேக நபரையும் கைப்பற்றப்பட்ட கேரளா கஞ்சா மற்றும் கடத்தலுக்கு பயன்படுத்தப்பட்ட சொகுசு வேனையும் புத்தளம் நீதிமன்றத்தில் ஆஜர்படுத்த நடவடிக்கைகளை மேற்கொள்ளப்பட்டு வருவதாக தெரிவித்தனர்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "கேரளா",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "கேரளா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "கற்பிட்டிக்கு கொழும்பு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "06",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "கடற்படை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "கரம்பை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "கபிடி கொழும்பு",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "நுரைச்சோல்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "212 கிலோ",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "கேரள கஞ்சா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "32 வயது",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "கேரளா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "புத்தளம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}