{
  "newspaper_id": "lankadeepa-lk",
  "url": "https://www.lankadeepa.lk/news/සජිත්---මෛත්‍රී-හමුවක්/101-615858",
  "time_ut": 1656934386,
  "original_lang": "si",
  "original_title": "සජිත් - මෛත්‍රී හමුවක්",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "A friendly meeting between Sajith and Maitri",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "Leader of the Opposition Sajith Premadasa, former President Maithripala Sirisena and a group of political party representatives and civil society activists met today at the office of the Leader of the Opposition and engaged in a special discussion.",
        "This was held as a crucial meeting in the program of \"National Reform and Forward Movement\" to rebuild the country, which has fallen into serious disrepair.",
        "The leader of the opposition who spoke there said that in the past 3 years, the rulers of this country have not listened to what other people have to say and think that they are the only ones who are right.",
        "In order to get rid of it, everyone should come together and go for social, economic and political reform, the opposition leader said.",
        "The opposition leader also said that the country can be built through a social reform that listens to everyone's opinions without dictatorship, so the proposals and ideas of the progressive parties will be listened to.",
        "The opposition leader further said that the aim of the opposition is to rebuild the country through a common national agenda that can bring together the diversified ideas and through that agenda the lost breath of the people of the country can be given again.",
        "Former President Maithripala Sirisena, who attended the event, said that the Sri Lanka Freedom Party will give full support to the \"National Reform and Forward Journey\" programme.",
        "The former president also said that in order to build the country strong, we should resort to a constitutional reform program that did not exist before.",
        "Mr. Sirisena mentioned that friendly countries like Japan are far away from Sri Lanka and the current government is responsible for that.",
        "The former president further said that because the people involved in the struggle and the youth community think about the country in a more democratic way, everyone should think about a new government that will make their dreams come true.",
        "Samagi Jana Balawega General Secretary Ranjith Maddumabandara, President Sarath Fonseka, National Organizer Tissa Attanayake, Dr. Rajitha Senaratne, Mano Ganesan, Rauf Hakeem, P. Digambaram, many political leaders and a large number of civil activists including senior journalist Victor Ivan, Gamini Viyangoda, Rohan Samarajeeva also participated in this event."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Sajith",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "Maitri",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "the Opposition Sajith Premadasa",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Maithripala Sirisena",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Opposition",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "the past 3 years",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "Maithripala Sirisena",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Sri Lanka Freedom Party",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "the \"National Reform and Forward Journey",
            "label": "LAW"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sirisena",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Japan",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "Samagi Jana Balawega",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ranjith Maddumabandara",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sarath Fonseka",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "National Organizer Tissa Attanayake",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Rajitha Senaratne",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Mano Ganesan",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Rauf Hakeem",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "P. Digambaram",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Victor Ivan",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Gamini Viyangoda",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Rohan Samarajeeva",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "සජිත් - මෛත්‍රී හමුවක්",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "විපක්ෂ නායක සජිත් ප්‍රේමදාස, හිටපු ජනාධිපති මෛත්‍රීපාල සිරිසේන යන මහත්වරුන් සහ දේශපාලන පක්ෂ නියෝජිතයන් සහ සිවිල් සමාජ ක්‍රියාකාරීන් ඇතුළු පිරිසක්  විපක්ෂනායක කාර්යාලයේ දී අද හමුවී විශේෂ සාකච්ඡාවක නිරත වූහ.",
        "බරපතළ ලෙස කඩා වැටී ඇති දේශය ගොඩනැගීම උදෙසා වූ \"ජාතික ප්‍රතිසංස්කරණ හා ඉදිරි ගමන\" වැඩසටහනේ තීරණාත්මක හමුවක් ලෙස මෙය පැවැත්විණි.",
        "පසුගිය වසර 3කට ආසන්න කාලය තුළ මේ රටේ පාලකයන් අනෙක් පුද්ගලයන්  කියන දේ ඇහුම්කම් නොදී තමන් පමණක් හරි බවට සිතා කටයුතු කිරීම නිසා වර්තමානයේ රට විශාල අගාධයකට පත්ව ඇති බව එහිදී අදහස් දැක්වූ විපක්ෂ නායකවරයා සඳහන් කළේය.",
        "ඉන් මිදීමට නම් සියලු දෙනා එකට එකතු වී සමාජ, ආර්ථික හා දේශපාලන ප්‍රතිසංස්කරණයකට යා යුතු බවත් විපක්ෂ නායකවරයා සඳහන් කළේය.",
        "ඒකාධිපතීත්වයෙන් තොරව සියලු දෙනාගේ මතවලට ඇහුම්කන් දෙන සමාජ ප්‍රතිසංස්කරණයක් තුළින් රට ගොඩනැගිය හැකි බැවින් ඒ සඳහා ප්‍රගතිශීලී පක්ෂයන්ගේ යෝජනා සහ අදහස්වලට ඇහුම්කන් දෙන බවත් විපක්ෂ නායකවරයා එහිදී කියා සිටියේය.",
        "විපක්ෂයේ අරමුණ වන්නේ විවිධාංගීකරණයට ලක් වූ අදහස් එකට එකතු කළ හැකි පොදු ජාතික න්‍යාය පත්‍රයක් හරහා රට නැවතත් ගොඩනැගීම බවත් එම න්‍යාය පත්‍රය තුළින් රටේ ජනතාවගේ අහිමි වී ගිය හුස්ම නැවතත් ලබා දිය හැකි බවද විපක්ෂ නායකවරයා එහිදී වැඩිදුරටත් කියා සිටියේය.",
        "ජාතික ප්‍රතිසංස්කරණ හා ඉදිරි ගමන\" වැඩසටහන සදහා ශ්‍රි ලංකා නිදහස් පක්ෂයේ පූර්ණ සහයෝගය ලබාදෙන බව එම අවස්ථාවට එක්වූ හිටපු ජනාධිපති මෛත්‍රීපාල සිරිසේන මහතා ප්‍රකාශ කළේය.",
        "රට ශක්තිමත්ව ගොඩ නැගීම සඳහා මෙයට පෙර නොතිබූ ආකාරයේ ආණ්ඩුක්‍රම ප්‍රතිසංස්කරණ වැඩපිළිවෙලකට යොමු විය යුතු බවත් හිටපු ජනාධිපතිවරයා පැවසීය.",
        "ජපානය වැනි ශ්‍රී ලංකාව සමඟ මිතුරු රටවල් අද වන විට බොහෝ දුරට ඈත්ව ඇති බවත් වත්මන් ආණ්ඩුව එයට වගකිව යුතු බවත් සිරිසේන මහතා සඳහන් කළේය.",
        "අරගලයේ නියුතු පිරිස්, තරුණ ප්‍රජාව රට ගැන වඩාත් ප්‍රජාතන්ත්‍රවාදී ආකාරයෙන් සිතන බැවිනි ඔවුන්ගේ සිහින සැබෑ වන නව ආණ්ඩුක්‍රමයක් පිළිබඳ සියලු දෙනා කල්පනා කළ යුතු බවත් හිටපු ජනාධිපතිවරයා එහිදී තවදුරටත් තව දුරටත් කීවේය.",
        "සමගි ජන බලවේගයේ මහ ලේකම් රංජිත් මද්දුමබණ්ඩාර, සභාපති සරත් ෆොන්සේකා, ජාතික සංවිධායක තිස්ස අත්තනායක, වෛද්‍ය රාජිත සේනාරත්න, මනෝ ගනේෂන්, රවුෆ් හකීම්, පී. දිගම්බරම්, ඇතුළු දේශපාලන නායකයින් රැසක් ද, ජේෂ්ඨ මාධ්‍යවේදී වික්ටර් අයිවන්, ගාමිණී වියංගොඩ, රොහාන් සමරජීව ඇතුලු සිවිල් ක්‍රියාකාරීන් විශාල පිරිසක්ද මෙම අවස්ථාවට එක්ව සිටියහ."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "සජිත්",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "මෛත්‍රී",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "විපක්ෂය සජිත් ප්‍රේමදාස",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "මෛත්‍රීපාල සිරිසේන",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "විපක්ෂ",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "පසුගිය වසර 3",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "මෛත්‍රීපාල සිරිසේන",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකා නිදහස් පක්ෂය",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "\"ජාතික ප්‍රතිසංස්කරණ සහ ඉදිරි ගමන",
            "label": "LAW"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "සිරිසේන",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජපානය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "සමගි ජන බලවේගය",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "රංජිත් මද්දුමබණ්ඩාර",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "සරත් ෆොන්සේකා",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජාතික සංවිධායක තිස්ස අත්තනායක",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "රාජිත සේනාරත්න",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Mano Ganesan",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "රවුෆ් හකීම්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "පී.දිගම්බරම්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "වික්ටර් අයිවන්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගාමිණී වියන්ගොඩ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "රොහාන් සමරජීව",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "சஜித்துக்கும் மைத்திரிக்கும் இடையிலான நட்புறவு சந்திப்பு",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "எதிர்க்கட்சித் தலைவர் சஜித் பிரேமதாச, முன்னாள் ஜனாதிபதி மைத்திரிபால சிறிசேன மற்றும் அரசியல் கட்சிப் பிரதிநிதிகள் மற்றும் சிவில் சமூக ஆர்வலர்கள் ஆகியோர் இன்று எதிர்க்கட்சித் தலைவர் அலுவலகத்தில் சந்தித்து விசேட கலந்துரையாடலில் ஈடுபட்டனர்.",
        "மிகவும் சீரழிந்து கிடக்கும் நாட்டை மீளக் கட்டியெழுப்புவதற்கான \"தேசிய சீர்திருத்தம் மற்றும் முன்னோக்கு இயக்கம்\" நிகழ்ச்சித் திட்டத்தில் இது ஒரு முக்கியமான கூட்டமாக நடைபெற்றது.",
        "அங்கு பேசிய எதிர்க்கட்சித் தலைவர், கடந்த 3 வருடங்களில் இந்த நாட்டின் ஆட்சியாளர்கள் பிறர் சொல்வதைக் காதில் வாங்கிக் கொண்டு தாங்கள்தான் சரி என்று நினைக்கவில்லை.",
        "அதிலிருந்து விடுபட அனைவரும் ஒன்றிணைந்து சமூக, பொருளாதார, அரசியல் சீர்திருத்தங்களுக்கு செல்ல வேண்டும் என எதிர்க்கட்சித் தலைவர் தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "சர்வாதிகாரம் இன்றி அனைவரது கருத்துக்களுக்கும் செவிசாய்க்கும் சமூக சீர்திருத்தத்தின் ஊடாக நாட்டை கட்டியெழுப்ப முடியும் எனவே முற்போக்கு கட்சிகளின் முன்மொழிவுகளுக்கும் யோசனைகளுக்கும் செவிசாய்க்கப்படும் எனவும் எதிர்கட்சி தலைவர் தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "பன்முகத்தன்மை கொண்ட சிந்தனைகளை ஒன்றிணைக்கக்கூடிய பொதுவான தேசிய நிகழ்ச்சி நிரலின் ஊடாக நாட்டை மீளக் கட்டியெழுப்புவதும், அந்த நிகழ்ச்சி நிரலின் ஊடாக நாட்டு மக்களின் இழந்த மூச்சுக்காற்றை மீண்டும் வழங்குவதும் எதிர்க்கட்சிகளின் நோக்கமாகும் என எதிர்க்கட்சித் தலைவர் மேலும் தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "இந்த நிகழ்வில் கலந்து கொண்ட முன்னாள் ஜனாதிபதி மைத்திரிபால சிறிசேன, “தேசிய மறுசீரமைப்பு மற்றும் முன்னோக்கிய பயணம்” வேலைத்திட்டத்திற்கு ஸ்ரீலங்கா சுதந்திரக் கட்சி பூரண ஆதரவை வழங்கும் என தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "நாட்டை வலுவாக கட்டியெழுப்புவதற்கு முன்னர் இல்லாத அரசியலமைப்பு மறுசீரமைப்பு வேலைத்திட்டத்தை நாட வேண்டும் எனவும் முன்னாள் ஜனாதிபதி மேலும் தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "ஜப்பான் போன்ற நட்பு நாடுகள் இலங்கையில் இருந்து வெகு தொலைவில் இருப்பதாகவும் அதற்கு தற்போதைய அரசாங்கமே பொறுப்பு என்றும் திரு சிறிசேன குறிப்பிட்டுள்ளார்.",
        "போராட்டத்தில் ஈடுபட்டுள்ள மக்களும், இளைஞர் சமூகமும் ஜனநாயக ரீதியில் நாட்டைப் பற்றி சிந்திப்பதால், தமது கனவுகளை நனவாக்கும் புதிய அரசாங்கம் தொடர்பில் அனைவரும் சிந்திக்க வேண்டுமென முன்னாள் ஜனாதிபதி மேலும் தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "சமகி ஜன பலவேகவின் பொதுச் செயலாளர் ரஞ்சித் மத்துமபண்டார, தலைவர் சரத் பொன்சேகா, தேசிய அமைப்பாளர் திஸ்ஸ அத்தநாயக்க, டொக்டர் ராஜித சேனாரத்ன, மனோ கணேசன், ரவூப் ஹக்கீம், பி. திகாம்பரம், சிரேஷ்ட ஊடகவியலாளர் விக்டர் ஐவன், காமினி வியங்கொட, ரொஹான் சமரஜீவ உட்பட பல அரசியல் தலைவர்கள் மற்றும் பெருந்தொகையான சிவில் செயற்பாட்டாளர்களும் இந்நிகழ்வில் கலந்துகொண்டனர்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "சஜித்",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "மைத்ரி",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "எதிர்க்கட்சியான சஜித் பிரேமதாச",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "மைத்திரிபால சிறிசேன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "எதிர்ப்பு",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "கடந்த 3 ஆண்டுகளாக",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "மைத்திரிபால சிறிசேன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஸ்ரீலங்கா சுதந்திரக் கட்சி",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "\"தேசிய சீர்திருத்தம் மற்றும் முன்னோக்கி பயணம்",
            "label": "LAW"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "சிறிசேனா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜப்பான்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "சமகி ஜன பலவேகா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரஞ்சித் மத்துமபண்டார",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "சரத் ​​பொன்சேகா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "தேசிய அமைப்பாளர் திஸ்ஸ அத்தநாயக்க",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ராஜித சேனாரத்ன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Mano Ganesan",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரவூப் ஹக்கீம்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "பி.திகாம்பரம்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "விக்டர் இவான்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "காமினி வியங்கொட",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரொஹான் சமரஜீவ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}