{
  "newspaper_id": "daily-ft-lk",
  "url": "https://www.ft.lk/business/Dialog-promotes-best-data-plans-for-entire-family/34-738889",
  "time_ut": 1660931586,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Dialog promotes best data plans for entire family",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Dialog promotes best data plans for entire family",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "Dialog Home Broadband has introduced exclusive affordable Data Plans for the entire family.",
        "For just Rs. 1,299 + taxes, you can now enjoy unlimited data for Netflix and the ViU App, along with 100GB of data for Apple TV, Amazon Prime and Spotify for a full 30 days.",
        "If you’d like to make that even more affordable or flexible to meet your requirements, you can enjoy the seven-day plan for only Rs. 499 + Taxes; with unlimited data for Netflix and the ViU App along with 20GB of data for Apple TV, Amazon Prime and Spotify. If you’re more a music person than anything else, you can get 10GB of data for Spotify for 30 days at a very affordable Rs. 179 + taxes."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Home Broadband",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "1,299",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Netflix",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "100",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Apple TV",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Amazon Prime",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Spotify",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "a full 30 days",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "seven-day",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "499",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Netflix",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "20",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Apple TV",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Amazon Prime",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Spotify",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "10",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Spotify",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "30 days",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "179",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "Dialog මුළු පවුලටම හොඳම දත්ත සැලසුම් ප්‍රවර්ධනය කරයි",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "ඩයලොග් හෝම් බ්‍රෝඩ්බෑන්ඩ් විසින් මුළු පවුලටම සුවිශේෂී දැරිය හැකි දත්ත සැලසුම් හඳුන්වා දී ඇත.",
        "යන්තම් රු. 1,299 + බදු, ඔබට දැන් සම්පූර්ණ දින 30ක් පුරා Apple TV, Amazon Prime සහ Spotify සඳහා 100GB දත්ත සමඟ Netflix සහ ViU App සඳහා අසීමිත දත්ත භුක්ති විඳිය හැක.",
        "ඔබේ අවශ්‍යතා සපුරාලීම සඳහා එය වඩාත් දැරිය හැකි හෝ නම්‍යශීලී කිරීමට ඔබ කැමති නම්, ඔබට දින හතක සැලසුම භුක්ති විඳිය හැක්කේ රු. 499 + බදු; Netflix සහ ViU App සඳහා අසීමිත දත්ත සමඟ Apple TV, Amazon Prime සහ Spotify සඳහා 20GB දත්ත. ඔබ අන් සියල්ලටම වඩා සංගීත අයෙක් නම්, ඔබට දින 30ක් සඳහා Spotify සඳහා 10GB දත්ත ඉතා පහසු මිලකට රු. 179 + බදු."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Home Broadband",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "1,299 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Netflix",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "100",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඇපල් ටීවී",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Amazon Prime",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Spotify",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "සම්පූර්ණ දින 30 ක්",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "දින හතක්",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "499",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Netflix",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "20",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඇපල් ටීවී",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Amazon Prime",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Spotify",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "10",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Spotify",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "දින 30",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "179",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "Dialog முழு குடும்பத்திற்கும் சிறந்த தரவுத் திட்டங்களை ஊக்குவிக்கிறது",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "Dialog Home Broadband ஆனது முழு குடும்பத்திற்கும் பிரத்தியேகமான மலிவு டேட்டா திட்டங்களை அறிமுகப்படுத்தியுள்ளது.",
        "வெறும் ரூ. 1,299 + வரிகள், நீங்கள் இப்போது Netflix மற்றும் ViU ஆப்ஸிற்கான வரம்பற்ற டேட்டாவுடன் Apple TV, Amazon Prime மற்றும் Spotify ஆகியவற்றுக்கான 100GB டேட்டாவை முழு 30 நாட்களுக்கு அனுபவிக்க முடியும்.",
        "உங்கள் தேவைகளைப் பூர்த்தி செய்ய நீங்கள் அதை இன்னும் மலிவு அல்லது நெகிழ்வானதாக மாற்ற விரும்பினால், ஏழு நாள் திட்டத்தை ரூ. 499 + வரிகள்; Netflix மற்றும் ViU ஆப்ஸிற்கான வரம்பற்ற டேட்டாவுடன் Apple TV, Amazon Prime மற்றும் Spotify ஆகியவற்றுக்கான 20GB டேட்டாவுடன். நீங்கள் எல்லாவற்றையும் விட இசையமைப்பாளராக இருந்தால், Spotifyக்கு 10ஜிபி டேட்டாவை 30 நாட்களுக்கு மிகவும் மலிவு விலையில் பெறலாம். 179 + வரிகள்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "முகப்பு பிராட்பேண்ட்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "1,299",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "நெட்ஃபிக்ஸ்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "100",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆப்பிள் டிவி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "அமேசான் பிரைம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Spotify",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "முழு 30 நாட்கள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஏழு நாள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "499",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "நெட்ஃபிக்ஸ்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "20",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆப்பிள் டிவி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "அமேசான் பிரைம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Spotify",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "10",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Spotify",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "30 நாட்கள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "179",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}