{
  "newspaper_id": "island-lk",
  "url": "http://island.lk/sme-businesses-in-puttalam-enriched-by-seylan-bank-and-ccc-workshop/",
  "time_ut": 1660756920,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "SME businesses in Puttalam enriched by Seylan Bank and CCC workshop",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "SME businesses in Puttalam enriched by Seylan Bank and CCC workshop",
      "author": "Sahan Weerasooriya",
      "body_lines": [
        "Seylan Bank, the Bank with a Heart, in partnership with the Ceylon Chamber of Commerce (CCC) Centre for SMEs and CIMA, conducted a workshop in Puttalam for owners of SME businesses from the area. Over the years, Seylan Bank has taken up the role of mentor towards the SME sector in Sri Lanka, with the strong belief that it is the backbone of the country’s economy, and that the sector should be empowered through relevant financial solutions and knowledge sharing. It is under this vision that the Bank conducts a series of workshops across the country with the aim of developing the regional SME industry.",
        "The workshop was facilitated by Channa Gunawardana, CEO of Dankotuwa Porcelain, covering key areas of Appropriate customer segmentation, Branding and its importance, Marketing and its challenges, Technology and the need for digitalization, Plan setting and acting on the plan, and Financial solutions. SMEs representing sectors including agriculture, trading, IT, salt manufacturing, spice exports, garments, dry fish manufacturing and construction took part in the workshop. This was the third workshop in the series, preceded by similar workshops in Ratnapura and Anuradhapura.",
        "“Through initiatives such as this workshop, Seylan Bank aims at opening avenues for further business opportunities to SMEs and thereby help unlock their potential. We believe that those with the right mindset to learn, adapt and challenge the status quo, will pave the way for the country’s development during these turbulent times. We saw how important the SME sector is, especially during the past few years, and therefore, have kept it as one of our core areas of focus. It’s a published fact that Seylan was the third largest contributor amongst private banks in funding SME sector activity in 2020 – and we have continued to support this sector. We are honoured to partner with the CCC and CIMA for such a project where we can create financial literacy on products and solutions that can help regional SMEs. The growth of SMEs is crucial to the national economy and Seylan Bank has always opened avenues that will enrich this backbone of the economy,” stated Ranil Dissanayake, Assistant General Manager, Branch Credit at Seylan Bank.",
        "The regional workshops are organized by the CCC in collaboration with CIMA under the initiative ‘Forward Together’, with the objective of bridging the knowledge, skills, and financial and technological awareness gaps amongst the local SMEs. 45% of employment in Sri Lanka rely on the effective functioning of SMEs. ‘Forward Together’ was launched to assure the sustainable impact on SMEs that largely impacts the national economy.",
        "Sri Lanka Insurance enters into a strategic tie-up with Ceylon Motor Traders Association",
        "Dialog Axiata extends its support to the Sri Dalada Perahera for the 16th consecutive year",
        "Leave a Reply Cancel replyYour email address will not be published. Required fields are marked *Comment Name *",
        "Save my name, email, and website in this browser for the next time I comment."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "SME",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "Puttalam",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "Seylan Bank",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "CCC",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Seylan Bank",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Bank",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Ceylon Chamber of Commerce",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "CIMA",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Puttalam",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "SME",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the years",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Seylan Bank",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "SME",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Bank",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "SME",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Channa Gunawardana",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Appropriate",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Branding",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "third",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ratnapura",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Anuradhapura",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Seylan Bank",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "SME",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the past few years",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Seylan",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "third",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "SME",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "2020",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "CCC",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "CIMA",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Seylan Bank",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ranil Dissanayake",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Seylan Bank",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "CCC",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "CIMA",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "45%",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka Insurance",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ceylon Motor Traders Association",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the Sri Dalada Perahera",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the 16th consecutive year",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [],
        []
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "පුත්තලමේ කුඩා හා මධ්‍ය පරිමාණ ව්‍යාපාර සෙලාන් බැංකුව සහ CCC වැඩමුළුව මගින් පොහොසත් කර ඇත",
      "author": "සහන් වීරසූරිය",
      "body_lines": [
        "හදවතක් ඇති බැංකුව වන සෙලාන් බැංකුව, කුඩා හා මධ්‍ය පරිමාණ ව්‍යාපාර සඳහා ලංකා වාණිජ මණ්ඩලය (CCC) මධ්‍යස්ථානය සහ CIMA සමග එක්ව පුත්තලම ප්‍රදේශයේ කුඩා හා මධ්‍ය පරිමාණ ව්‍යාපාර හිමිකරුවන් සඳහා වැඩමුළුවක් පවත්වන ලදී. වසර ගණනාවක් පුරා, සෙලාන් බැංකුව ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ කුඩා හා මධ්‍ය පරිමාණ ව්‍යවසායක අංශය සඳහා උපදේශකයාගේ භූමිකාව භාරගෙන ඇති අතර, එය රටේ ආර්ථිකයේ කොඳු නාරටිය බවත්, අදාළ මූල්‍ය විසඳුම් සහ දැනුම හුවමාරු කර ගැනීම තුළින් එම අංශය සවිබල ගැන්විය යුතු බවත් දැඩි විශ්වාසයක් ඇත. කලාපීය කුඩා හා මධ්‍ය පරිමාණ ව්‍යවසායකත්ව කර්මාන්තය දියුණු කිරීමේ අරමුණින් බැංකුව රට පුරා වැඩමුළු මාලාවක් පවත්වන්නේ මෙම දැක්ම යටතේය.",
        "සුදුසු පාරිභෝගික ඛණ්ඩනය, සන්නාමකරණය සහ එහි වැදගත්කම, අලෙවිකරණය සහ එහි අභියෝග, තාක්ෂණය සහ ඩිජිටල්කරණයේ අවශ්‍යතාවය, සැලැස්ම සැකසීම සහ ක්‍රියා කිරීම සහ මූල්‍ය විසඳුම් යන ප්‍රධාන ක්ෂේත්‍ර ආවරණය කරමින් දංකොටුව පෝසිලේන් හි ප්‍රධාන විධායක නිලධාරී චන්න ගුණවර්ධන විසින් මෙම වැඩමුළුව සඳහා පහසුකම් සපයන ලදී. කෘෂිකාර්මික, වෙළෙඳ, තොරතුරු තාක්ෂණ, ලුණු නිෂ්පාදන, කුළුබඩු අපනයන, ඇඟලුම්, වියළි මාළු නිෂ්පාදනය සහ ඉදිකිරීම් ඇතුළු අංශ නියෝජනය කරන කුඩා හා මධ්‍ය පරිමාණ ව්‍යවසායකයින් මෙම වැඩමුළුවට සහභාගී විය. මෙම වැඩමුළු මාලාවේ තුන්වන වැඩමුළුව මෙය වූ අතර ඊට පෙර රත්නපුරයේ සහ අනුරාධපුරයේද මෙවැනිම වැඩමුළු පැවැත්විණි.",
        "“මෙම වැඩමුළුව වැනි මුලපිරීම් හරහා, සෙලාන් බැංකුව කුඩා හා මධ්‍ය පරිමාණ ව්‍යවසායකයින්ට තවදුරටත් ව්‍යාපාරික අවස්ථා සඳහා මංපෙත් විවර කිරීම සහ එමගින් ඔවුන්ගේ හැකියාවන් විවෘත කිරීමට ඉවහල් වේ. පවතින තත්ත්වයට ඉගෙනීමට, අනුවර්තනය වීමට සහ අභියෝග කිරීමට නිවැරදි මානසිකත්වයක් ඇති අය, මෙම කැලඹිලි සහිත කාලවලදී රටේ සංවර්ධනයට මග පාදනු ඇතැයි අපි විශ්වාස කරමු. විශේෂයෙන්ම පසුගිය වසර කිහිපය තුළ කුඩා හා මධ්‍ය පරිමාණ ව්‍යවසාය අංශය කෙතරම් වැදගත් දැයි අපි දුටුවෙමු, එබැවින් එය අපගේ අවධානයට ලක් වූ ප්‍රධාන අංශයක් ලෙස තබා ගෙන ඇත. 2020 දී කුඩා හා මධ්‍ය පරිමාණ ව්‍යවසායක අංශයේ ක්‍රියාකාරකම් සඳහා අරමුදල් සැපයීමේ දී පුද්ගලික බැංකු අතර තුන්වන විශාලතම දායකයා සෙලාන් බව ප්‍රකාශිත කරුණකි - අපි මෙම අංශයට අඛණ්ඩව සහයෝගය ලබා දී ඇත. කලාපීය කුඩා හා මධ්‍ය පරිමාණ ව්‍යවසායකයින්ට උපකාර කළ හැකි නිෂ්පාදන සහ විසඳුම් පිළිබඳ මූල්‍ය සාක්ෂරතාව ඇති කළ හැකි එවැනි ව්‍යාපෘතියක් සඳහා CCC සහ CIMA සමඟ හවුල් වීමට ලැබීම අපට ගෞරවයක්. කුඩා හා මධ්‍ය පරිමාණ ව්‍යවසායකයන්ගේ වර්ධනය ජාතික ආර්ථිකයට තීරණාත්මක වන අතර සෙලාන් බැංකුව සෑම විටම ආර්ථිකයේ මෙම කොඳු නාරටිය පොහොසත් කරන මංපෙත් විවර කර දී ඇත,” සෙලාන් බැංකුවේ ශාඛා ණය සහකාර සාමාන්‍යාධිකාරී රනිල් දිසානායක මහතා පැවසීය.",
        "දේශීය කුඩා හා මධ්‍ය පරිමාණ ව්‍යවසායකයින් අතර ඇති දැනුම, කුසලතා සහ මූල්‍ය හා තාක්‍ෂණික දැනුවත් කිරීමේ හිඩැස් මඟහරවා ගැනීමේ අරමුණ ඇතිව, ‘එකට ඉදිරියට යන්න’ මුලපිරීම යටතේ CIMA සමඟ සහයෝගයෙන් CCC විසින් කලාපීය වැඩමුළු සංවිධානය කරනු ලැබේ. ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ රැකියාවලින් 45% ක් කුඩා හා මධ්‍ය පරිමාණ ව්‍යවසායකයන්ගේ ඵලදායී ක්‍රියාකාරිත්වය මත රඳා පවතී. ජාතික ආර්ථිකයට විශාල වශයෙන් බලපාන සුළු හා මධ්‍ය පරිමාණ ව්‍යවසායකයින් කෙරෙහි තිරසාර බලපෑම සහතික කිරීම සඳහා ‘එකට ඉදිරියට යන්න’ දියත් කරන ලදී.",
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකා ඉන්ෂුවරන්ස් ලංකා මෝටර් රථ වෙළෙඳ සංගමය සමඟ උපාය මාර්ගික ගිවිසුමකට එළඹෙයි",
        "Dialog Axiata අඛණ්ඩව 16 වන වරටත් ශ්‍රී දළදා පෙරහැරට සිය සහය",
        "පිළිතුරක් දෙන්න පිළිතුර අවලංගු කරන්න ඔබගේ විද්‍යුත් තැපැල් ලිපිනය ප්‍රකාශයට පත් නොකෙරේ. අවශ්‍ය ක්ෂේත්‍ර සලකුණු කර ඇත *අදහස් නම *",
        "මම ඊළඟ වතාවේ අදහස් දැක්වීම සඳහා මගේ නම, විද්‍යුත් තැපෑල සහ වෙබ් අඩවිය මෙම බ්‍රවුසරයේ සුරකින්න."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "SME",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "පුත්තලම",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "සෙලාන් බැංකුව",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "CCC",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "සෙලාන් බැංකුව",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "බැංකුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ලංකා වාණිජ මණ්ඩලය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "CIMA",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "පුත්තලම",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "SME",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "වසර",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "සෙලාන් බැංකුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "SME",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "බැංකුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "SME",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "චන්න ගුණවර්ධන",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "සුදුසු",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "වෙළඳ නාමකරණය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "තෙවන",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "රත්නපුරය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "අනුරාධපුර",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "සෙලාන් බැංකුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "SME",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "පසුගිය වසර කිහිපය",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "සෙලාන්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "තෙවන",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "SME",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "2020",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "CCC",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "CIMA",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "සෙලාන් බැංකුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "රනිල් දිසානායක",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "සෙලාන් බැංකුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "CCC",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "CIMA",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "45%",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකා ඉන්ෂුවරන්ස්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ලංකා මෝටර් රථ වෙළෙඳ සංගමය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී දළදා පෙරහැර",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "අඛණ්ඩව 16 වන වසර",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [],
        []
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "புத்தளத்தில் உள்ள SME வணிகங்கள் செலான் வங்கி மற்றும் CCC பட்டறை மூலம் வளப்படுத்தப்படுகின்றன",
      "author": "சஹான் வீரசூரிய",
      "body_lines": [
        "செலான் வங்கி, இதயம் கொண்ட வங்கி, SMEs மற்றும் CIMA க்கான சிலோன் சேம்பர் ஆஃப் காமர்ஸ் (CCC) மையத்துடன் இணைந்து, புத்தளத்தில் உள்ள SME வணிக உரிமையாளர்களுக்காக ஒரு செயலமர்வை நடத்தியது. பல ஆண்டுகளாக, செலான் வங்கியானது, இலங்கையின் SME துறைக்கான வழிகாட்டியின் பங்கை ஏற்றுக்கொண்டது, இது நாட்டின் பொருளாதாரத்தின் முதுகெலும்பு என்ற வலுவான நம்பிக்கையுடன், தொடர்புடைய நிதி தீர்வுகள் மற்றும் அறிவுப் பகிர்வு மூலம் இந்தத் துறை வலுவூட்டப்பட வேண்டும். இந்த தொலைநோக்குப் பார்வையின் கீழ், பிராந்திய SME தொழில்துறையை மேம்படுத்தும் நோக்கத்துடன் வங்கி நாடு முழுவதும் தொடர்ச்சியான பட்டறைகளை நடத்துகிறது.",
        "தங்கொடுவ பீங்கான் நிறுவனத்தின் பிரதம நிறைவேற்று அதிகாரி சன்ன குணவர்தனவினால், பொருத்தமான வாடிக்கையாளர் பிரிவு, வர்த்தக முத்திரை மற்றும் அதன் முக்கியத்துவம், சந்தைப்படுத்தல் மற்றும் அதன் சவால்கள், தொழில்நுட்பம் மற்றும் டிஜிட்டல் மயமாக்கலின் அவசியம், திட்டம் அமைத்தல் மற்றும் செயற்படுதல் மற்றும் நிதித் தீர்வுகள் ஆகியவற்றின் முக்கிய பகுதிகளை உள்ளடக்கியதாக இந்த செயலமர்வு நடத்தப்பட்டது. விவசாயம், வர்த்தகம், தகவல் தொழில்நுட்பம், உப்பு உற்பத்தி, மசாலா ஏற்றுமதி, ஆடைகள், உலர் மீன் உற்பத்தி மற்றும் கட்டுமானம் உள்ளிட்ட துறைகளை பிரதிநிதித்துவப்படுத்தும் சிறு, நடுத்தர நிறுவனங்கள் பயிலரங்கில் பங்கேற்றன. இரத்தினபுரி மற்றும் அநுராதபுரத்தில் இதேபோன்ற பட்டறைகள் நடத்தப்பட்ட இந்தத் தொடரின் மூன்றாவது பட்டறை இதுவாகும்.",
        "“இந்தப் பட்டறை போன்ற முன்முயற்சிகள் மூலம், SME களுக்கு மேலும் வணிக வாய்ப்புகளுக்கான வழிகளைத் திறப்பதை செலான் வங்கி இலக்காகக் கொண்டுள்ளது. தற்போதைய நிலையைக் கற்றுக் கொள்ளவும், மாற்றியமைக்கவும், சவால் விடவும் சரியான மனநிலை உள்ளவர்கள், இந்தக் கொந்தளிப்பான காலங்களில் நாட்டின் வளர்ச்சிக்கு வழி வகுக்கும் என்று நாங்கள் நம்புகிறோம். குறிப்பாக கடந்த சில ஆண்டுகளில் SME துறை எவ்வளவு முக்கியத்துவம் வாய்ந்தது என்பதை நாங்கள் பார்த்தோம், எனவே, அதை எங்கள் முக்கிய பகுதிகளில் ஒன்றாக வைத்துள்ளோம். 2020 ஆம் ஆண்டில் SME துறை நடவடிக்கைகளுக்கு நிதியளிப்பதில் தனியார் வங்கிகளில் செலான் மூன்றாவது பெரிய பங்களிப்பாளராக இருந்தது என்பது வெளியிடப்பட்ட உண்மை - மேலும் இந்தத் துறைக்கு நாங்கள் தொடர்ந்து ஆதரவளித்து வருகிறோம். பிராந்திய SME களுக்கு உதவக்கூடிய தயாரிப்புகள் மற்றும் தீர்வுகள் குறித்த நிதி அறிவை உருவாக்கக்கூடிய அத்தகைய திட்டத்திற்காக CCC மற்றும் CIMA உடன் கூட்டு சேர்வதில் நாங்கள் பெருமை கொள்கிறோம். SME களின் வளர்ச்சியானது தேசிய பொருளாதாரத்திற்கு மிகவும் முக்கியமானது மற்றும் செலான் வங்கியானது பொருளாதாரத்தின் முதுகெலும்பை வளப்படுத்தும் வழிகளை எப்போதும் திறந்து வைத்துள்ளது,” என செலான் வங்கியின் கிளைக் கடன் உதவிப் பொது முகாமையாளர் ரணில் திஸாநாயக்க தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "உள்ளூர் SMEக்களிடையே உள்ள அறிவு, திறன்கள் மற்றும் நிதி மற்றும் தொழில்நுட்ப விழிப்புணர்வு இடைவெளிகளைக் குறைக்கும் நோக்கத்துடன், 'ஒன்றாக முன்னோக்கி' என்ற முன்முயற்சியின் கீழ், CIMA உடன் இணைந்து CCC ஆல் பிராந்திய பட்டறைகள் ஏற்பாடு செய்யப்பட்டுள்ளன. இலங்கையில் 45% வேலை வாய்ப்புகள் SME களின் வினைத்திறனான செயல்பாட்டில் தங்கியுள்ளன. தேசிய பொருளாதாரத்தை பெருமளவில் பாதிக்கும் SME களில் நிலையான தாக்கத்தை உறுதி செய்வதற்காக ‘Forward Together’ தொடங்கப்பட்டது.",
        "இலங்கை இன்சூரன்ஸ், சிலோன் மோட்டார் வர்த்தகர்கள் சங்கத்துடன் ஒரு மூலோபாய உறவுக்குள் நுழைந்துள்ளது.",
        "Dialog Axiata தொடர்ந்து 16வது ஆண்டாக ஸ்ரீ தலதா பெரஹெராவிற்கு தனது ஆதரவை வழங்குகிறது",
        "ஒரு பதிலை விடுங்கள் பதிலை ரத்துசெய் உங்கள் மின்னஞ்சல் முகவரி வெளியிடப்படாது. தேவையான புலங்கள் குறிக்கப்பட்டுள்ளன *கருத்து பெயர் *",
        "அடுத்த முறை நான் கருத்து தெரிவிக்க, எனது பெயர், மின்னஞ்சல் மற்றும் இணையதளத்தை இந்த உலாவியில் சேமிக்கவும்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "SME",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "புத்தளம்",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "செலான் வங்கி",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "CCC",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "செலான் வங்கி",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "வங்கி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை வர்த்தக சபை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "CIMA",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "புத்தளம்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "SME",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆண்டுகள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "செலான் வங்கி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "SME",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "வங்கி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "SME",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "சன்ன குணவர்தன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "பொருத்தமானது",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "பிராண்டிங்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "மூன்றாவது",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "இரத்தினபுரி",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "அனுராதபுரம்",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "செலான் வங்கி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "SME",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "கடந்த சில ஆண்டுகளாக",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "செலான்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "மூன்றாவது",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "SME",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "2020",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "CCC",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "CIMA",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "செலான் வங்கி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரணில் திசாநாயக்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "செலான் வங்கி",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "CCC",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "CIMA",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "45%",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை காப்புறுதி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை மோட்டார் வர்த்தகர்கள் சங்கம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஸ்ரீ தலதா பெரஹெரா",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "தொடர்ந்து 16வது ஆண்டு",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [],
        []
      ]
    }
  }
}