{
  "newspaper_id": "ada-lk",
  "url": "https://www.ada.lk/breaking_news/ඉන්ධන-පෝලිමේ-අයෙක්-ටිපර්-රථයක-ගැටී-මරුට/11-394934",
  "time_ut": 1656478645,
  "original_lang": "si",
  "original_title": "ඉන්ධන පෝලිමේ අයෙක් ටිපර් රථයක ගැටී මරුට",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Fuel queue collision kills tipper truck",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "Aluthgama Police said that a man who was queuing for diesel for a lorry at the IOC petrol station in Dharga Town last night (28) had collided with a tipper heading towards Welipenna from Aluthgama while crossing the road in front of the petrol station.",
        "The suspect driver who had caused the accident had gone to Aluthgama town for dinner from the fuel queue in Dharga Town and was returning to Dharga Town when he had crossed the road in front of the fuel depot in Dharga Town at around 11.20 pm and died on the spot, Aluthgama Police said.",
        "The deceased has been identified as Singappulige Ananda (58), a resident of 187/3, Alawatugoda, Puwakwatta, Dharganagara.",
        "The victim was waiting in line at a petrol station with a lorry belonging to another person that night when he was crossing the road in front of the petrol station in Dharga Town on the Welipenna Southern Expressway in Aluthgama.",
        "The body of the deceased has been placed at the Aluthgama Hospital and will be taken to the Nagoda Hospital in Kalutara for postmortem examination.",
        "The suspect tipper driver who caused the accident has been arrested by the Aluthgama Police and is due to be produced before the Kalutara Magistrate's Court today (29)."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Aluthgama Police",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "IOC",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Dharga Town",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "last night",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "28",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Welipenna",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Aluthgama",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Aluthgama",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Dharga Town",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "Dharga Town",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "around 11.20 pm",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "Aluthgama Police",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Singappulige Ananda",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "58",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "187/3",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Alawatugoda",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Puwakwatta",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Dharganagara",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Dharga Town",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Welipenna Southern Expressway",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "Aluthgama",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the Aluthgama Hospital",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Nagoda Hospital",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kalutara",
            "label": "PRODUCT"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the Aluthgama Police",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Kalutara Magistrate's Court",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "29",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "ඉන්ධන පෝලිමේ අයෙක් ටිපර් රථයක ගැටී මරුට",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "දර්ගා නගරයේ අයි.ඕ.සී ඉන්ධන හලේ ඊයේ (28දා) රාත්‍රී  ලොරි රථයකට ඩීසල් ලබා ගැනීමට කුලී පදනම මත පෝලිමේ සිටි පුද්ගලයෙකු ඉන්ධන හල ඉදිරිපිට  ප්‍රධාන මාර්ගය හරහා  පාර මාරුවීමට යාමේදී  අලුත්ගම දෙසින්   වැලිපැන්න දෙසට ගමන් ගත් ටිපර් රථයක ගැටී මියගොස් ඇතැයි අලූත්ගම පොලිසිය පවසයි.",
        "අනතුර සිදු කළ බව කියන සැකකාර  රියදුරු දර්ගා නගරයේ ඉන්ධන  පෝලිමේ සිට රාත්‍රී ආහාර ගැනීමට අලුත්ගම නගරයට ගොස් නැවත    දර්ගා නගරය දෙසට පැමිණීමේදී රාත්‍රී 11.20 ට පමණ දර්ගා දර්ගානගරයේ  ඉන්ධන හල ඉදිරිපිට  පාර මාරු වූ  පුද්ගලයා  මෙම ටිපර් රථයෙගැටී මියගොස් ඇති බව පරීක්ෂණ සිදුකරන අලුත්ගම  පොලිසිය කියයි.",
        "මෙම අනතුරෙන් මියගොස් ඇත්තේ   දර්ගානගරය,  පුවක් වත්ත ,අලවතුගොඩ  අංක187/3 ලිපිනයේ පදිංචිව සිටි සිංගප්පුලිගේ ආනන්ද(58) නැමැති විවාහකයෙකු බව පොලිසිය කියයි.",
        "මියගිය පුද්ගලයා වෙනත් අයෙකුට අයිති ලොරි රථයකට ඩීසල් ලබාගැනීම වෙනුවෙන් එදින රාත්‍රියේ  එම ලොරියත් සමඟ ඉන්ධනහල් පෝලිමේ ගත කරමින් සිටියදී අලුත්ගම වැලිපැන්න දක්ශින අධිවේගී ප්‍රවේශ මාර්ගය හරහා දර්ගා නගරයේ ඉන්ධන හල ඉදිරිපිටින් පාර  මාරු වීමට යාමේදී සිදුවූ අනතුරෙන් මියගොස් තිබේ.",
        "මිය ගිය පුද්ගලයාගේ මෘත දේහය අලුත්ගම රෝහලේ තැන්පත් කර ඇති අතර පශ්චාත් මරණ පරීක්ෂණ කටයුතු සඳහා  කළුතර නාගොඩ රෝහලට  රැගෙන යාමට නියමිතය.",
        "අනතුර සිදු කළ සැකකාර ටිපර් රථ රියදුරු  අලුත්ගම පොලිසිය මගින් අත්අඩංගුවට ගෙන ඇති අතර අද(29දා) කළුතර අධිකරණයට ඉදිරිපත් කිරීමට නියමිතය."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "අලුත්ගම පොලිසිය",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "IOC",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "දර්ගා නගරය",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "අවසන් රාත්රිය",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "28",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "වැලිපැන්න",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "අලුත්ගම",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "අලුත්ගම",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "දර්ගා නගරය",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "දර්ගා නගරය",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "11.20ට පමණ",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "අලුත්ගම පොලිසිය",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "සිංගප්පුලිගේ ආනන්ද",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "58",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "187/3",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "අලවතුගොඩ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "පුවක්වත්ත",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "දර්ගානගර",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "දර්ගා නගරය",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "වැලිපැන්න දක්ෂිණ අධිවේගී මාර්ගය",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "අලුත්ගම",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "අලුත්ගම රෝහල",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "නාගොඩ රෝහල",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "කළුතර",
            "label": "PRODUCT"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "අලුත්ගම පොලිසිය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඒ කළුතර මහේස්ත්‍රාත් අධිකරණයේදීයි",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "29",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "எரிபொருள் வரிசை மோதி டிப்பர் லாரி பலி",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "நேற்று (28) இரவு தர்கா நகரிலுள்ள ஐஓசி பெற்றோல் நிலையத்தில் லொறி ஒன்றிற்கு டீசலுக்கு வரிசையில் நின்ற ஒருவர், எரிபொருள் நிரப்பு நிலையத்திற்கு முன்பாக வீதியைக் கடக்கும்போது அளுத்கமவிலிருந்து வெலிபென்ன நோக்கிச் சென்ற டிப்பர் வாகனத்துடன் மோதியுள்ளதாக அளுத்கம பொலிஸார் தெரிவித்தனர்.",
        "விபத்தை ஏற்படுத்திய சந்தேகநபர் தர்கா நகரில் உள்ள எரிபொருள் வரிசையில் இருந்து இரவு உணவிற்காக அளுத்கம நகருக்குச் சென்றுவிட்டு தர்கா நகருக்குத் திரும்பிக் கொண்டிருந்த போது தர்கா நகரில் உள்ள எரிபொருள் களஞ்சியசாலைக்கு முன்பாக இரவு 11.20 மணியளவில் வீதியைக் கடந்த போது உயிரிழந்துள்ளார். சம்பவ இடம் அளுத்கம பொலிஸார் தெரிவித்தனர்.",
        "187/3, அலவத்துகொட, புவக்வத்தை, தர்காநகரை சேர்ந்த சிங்கப்புலிகே ஆனந்த (58) என்பவரே இவ்வாறு உயிரிழந்துள்ளார்.",
        "அளுத்கம, வெலிபென்ன தெற்கு அதிவேக நெடுஞ்சாலையில் தர்கா நகரில் உள்ள எரிபொருள் நிரப்பு நிலையத்திற்கு முன்பாக வீதியைக் கடக்கும் போது பாதிக்கப்பட்ட நபர் அன்றிரவு மற்றுமொரு நபருக்கு சொந்தமான லொறியுடன் எரிபொருள் நிரப்பு நிலையத்தில் வரிசையில் காத்திருந்தார்.",
        "உயிரிழந்தவரின் சடலம் அளுத்கம வைத்தியசாலையில் வைக்கப்பட்டுள்ளதுடன், பிரேத பரிசோதனைக்காக களுத்துறை நாகொட வைத்தியசாலைக்கு கொண்டு செல்லப்படவுள்ளது.",
        "விபத்தை ஏற்படுத்திய சந்தேக நபர் டிப்பர் சாரதி அளுத்கம பொலிஸாரால் கைது செய்யப்பட்டுள்ளதுடன், இன்று (29) களுத்துறை நீதவான் நீதிமன்றில் ஆஜர்படுத்தப்படவுள்ளார்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "அளுத்கம பொலிஸ்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஐஓசி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "தர்கா நகரம்",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "நேற்று இரவு",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "28",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "வெலிபென்ன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "அளுத்கம",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "அளுத்கம",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "தர்கா நகரம்",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "தர்கா நகரம்",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "சுமார் 11.20 இரவு",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "அளுத்கம பொலிஸ்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "சிங்கப்புலிகே ஆனந்த",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "58",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "187/3",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "அலவத்துகொட",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "புவக்வத்த",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "தர்காநகரா",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "தர்கா நகரம்",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "வெலிபென்ன தெற்கு அதிவேக நெடுஞ்சாலை",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "அளுத்கம",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "அளுத்கம வைத்தியசாலை",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "நாகொட வைத்தியசாலை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "களுத்துறை",
            "label": "PRODUCT"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "அளுத்கம காவல்துறை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "களுத்துறை நீதவான் நீதிமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "29",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}