{
  "newspaper_id": "lankadeepa-lk",
  "url": "https://www.lankadeepa.lk/news/ඉදිරි-ආණ්ඩුව-පිහිටුවීමේ-වැඩි-වාසි-තිබෙන්නේ-ශ්‍රීලනිපයටයි/101-619208",
  "time_ut": 1662121427,
  "original_lang": "si",
  "original_title": "ඉදිරි ආණ්ඩුව පිහිටුවීමේ වැඩි වාසි තිබෙන්නේ ශ්‍රීලනිපයටයි",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "SLFP has more advantages in forming the next government",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "According to the current situation in the country, there are signs that any election will be held soon and an alliance led by the SLFP will have the greatest advantage in forming the next government, said the party chairman of the Sri Lanka Freedom Party, former President Maithripala Sirisena.",
        "The former president also mentioned that 42 MPs who represented the ruling party had to sit in the opposition and become independent because the majority of the Sri Lanka Podujana Peramuna is not ready to work together for the country.",
        "Mr. Maithripala Sirisena said that forming an alliance with the left progressive political camp and forming a government will be mandatory in the future and he also said that he will request the party organizers to immediately start reconciliation work by including the disgruntled Pohottu members.",
        "The former president said this while addressing the party's 71st anniversary celebrations held today (2) at the Maharagama Youth Council Auditorium.",
        "This year's party anniversary celebration was organized under the theme 'Let us give life to our character - Let us take up the challenge - Let us shoulder the mission of the era'.",
        "The former president, who said that if Mr. Ranil Wickramasinghe, who had fallen to nothing, could become the president, it was impossible for the Sri Lanka Freedom Party to rise again, he also said that the former president has the ability to win again."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "SLFP",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Sri Lanka Freedom Party",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Maithripala Sirisena",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "42",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "Podujana Peramuna",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Maithripala Sirisena",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "71st",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "2",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Maharagama Youth Council Auditorium",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "year",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickramasinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Sri Lanka Freedom Party",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "ඉදිරි ආණ්ඩුව පිහිටුවීමේ වැඩි වාසි තිබෙන්නේ ශ්‍රීලනිපයටයි",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "රටේ පවතින තත්වය අනුව ළඟදීම කුමන හෝ මැතිවරණයක් පැවැත්වීමේ ලකුණු ඇති බවත් ඉදිරි ආණ්ඩුවක් පිහිටුවීමේ වැඩිම වාසිය ඇත්තේ ශ්‍රී.ල.නි.පය ප්‍රමුඛ සන්ධානයකට බවත් ශ්‍රී ලංකා නිදහස් පක්‍ෂයේ පක්ෂ සභාපති, හිටපු ජනාධිපති මෛත්‍රීපාල සිරිසේන මහතා පැවසීය.",
        "ආණ්ඩු පක්‍ෂය නියෝජනය කළ මන්ත්‍රීවරුන් 42 දෙනෙකුට විපක්‍ෂයේ අසුන්ගැනීමට හා ස්වාධීනවීමට සිදුව ඇත්තේ ශ්‍රී ලංකා පොදුජන පෙරමුණේ බහුතරය රට වෙනුවෙන් එකතු වී වැඩකිරීමට සූදානම් නැති නිසා යැයි ද හිටපු ජනාධිපතිවරයා සඳහන් කළේය.",
        "වාම ප්‍රගතිශීලී දේශපාලන කඳවුර සමඟ සන්ධානයක් ගොඩනගා ආණ්ඩුවක් පිහිටුවීම ඉදිරියේදී අනිවාර්යයෙන් කරන බව කී මෛත්‍රීපාල සිරිසේන මහතා කළකිරී සිටින පොහොට්ටු සාමාජිකයන් ද එක්කරගනිමින් වහාම ප්‍රතිසන්ධාන කටයුතු අරඹන්නැයි පක්‍ෂ සංවිධායකවරුන්ගෙන් ඉල්ලීමක් කරන බව ද කීවේය.",
        "හිටපු ජනාධිපතිවරයා මේ බව පැවසුවේ මහරගම තරුණ සේවා සභා ශ්‍රවණාගාරයේදී අද (2) පැවති එම පක්ෂයේ 71 වන සංවත්සරය සැමරුම් උත්සවය අමතමිනි.",
        "‘අපේ කමට පණ දෙමු - අභියෝගය අතට ගමු - යුග මෙහෙවරට උර දෙමු’ යන තේමාව යටතේ මෙවර පක්ෂ සංවත්සර සැමරුම සංවිධානය කර තිබිණි.",
        "බින්දුවට වැටී සිටි රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතාට ජනාධිපති විය හැකි නම් ශ්‍රී ලංකා නිදහස් පක්‍ෂයට යළි නැගී සිටීමේ නොහැකියාවක් නැතැයි කී හිටපු ජනාධිපතිවරයා නැවත ජයග්‍රහණය කරායාමේ හැකියාව තිබෙන බව ද පැවසීය."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රීලනිප",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකා නිදහස් පක්ෂය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "මෛත්‍රීපාල සිරිසේන",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "42",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "පොදුජන පෙරමුණ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "මෛත්‍රීපාල සිරිසේන",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "71 වැනි",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "2",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "මහරගම තරුණ සභා ශ්‍රවණාගාරයේදී",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "වර්ෂය",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකා නිදහස් පක්ෂය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "அடுத்த அரசாங்கத்தை அமைப்பதில் ஸ்ரீலங்கா சுதந்திரக் கட்சிக்கு அதிக அனுகூலங்கள் உள்ளன",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "நாட்டின் தற்போதைய நிலவரப்படி விரைவில் எந்தத் தேர்தலும் நடத்தப்படும் என்பதற்கான அறிகுறிகள் தென்படுவதாகவும் ஸ்ரீலங்கா சுதந்திரக் கட்சி தலைமையிலான கூட்டணிக்கு அடுத்த அரசாங்கத்தை அமைப்பதில் அதிக நன்மை கிடைக்கும் என ஸ்ரீலங்கா சுதந்திரக் கட்சியின் தலைவரும், முன்னாள் ஜனாதிபதியுமான தெரிவித்துள்ளார். மைத்திரிபால சிறிசேன.",
        "ஶ்ரீலங்கா பொதுஜன பெரமுனவின் பெரும்பான்மையானவர்கள் நாட்டுக்காக ஒன்றிணைந்து செயற்படத் தயாரில்லாமையால் ஆளும் கட்சியை பிரதிநிதித்துவப்படுத்திய 42 பாராளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர்கள் எதிர்க்கட்சியில் அமர்ந்து சுயேட்சையாக மாற நேரிட்டதாகவும் முன்னாள் ஜனாதிபதி குறிப்பிட்டுள்ளார்.",
        "எதிர்காலத்தில் இடதுசாரி முற்போக்கு அரசியல் முகாமுடன் கூட்டணி அமைத்து ஆட்சி அமைப்பது கட்டாயமாகும் என தெரிவித்த மைத்திரிபால சிறிசேன, அதிருப்தியில் உள்ள பொஹொட்டு உறுப்பினர்களை இணைத்து நல்லிணக்க பணிகளை உடனடியாக ஆரம்பிக்குமாறு கட்சி அமைப்பாளர்களிடம் கோரிக்கை விடுப்பதாகவும் தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "மஹரகம இளைஞர் பேரவை கேட்போர் கூடத்தில் இன்று (2) நடைபெற்ற கட்சியின் 71வது ஆண்டு நிறைவு விழாவில் கலந்து கொண்டு உரையாற்றும் போதே முன்னாள் ஜனாதிபதி மேற்கண்டவாறு தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "'நம் குணத்திற்கு உயிர் கொடுப்போம் - சவாலை ஏற்போம் - சகாப்தத்தின் பணியை தோளில் ஏற்றுவோம்' என்ற தொனிப்பொருளில் இந்த ஆண்டுக்கான கட்சி ஆண்டு விழா ஏற்பாடு செய்யப்பட்டது.",
        "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க ஜனாதிபதியாக வரமுடிந்தால், ஸ்ரீலங்கா சுதந்திரக் கட்சி மீண்டும் எழுச்சி பெறுவது சாத்தியமற்றது எனத் தெரிவித்த முன்னாள் ஜனாதிபதி, மீண்டும் வெற்றிபெறும் திறன் முன்னாள் ஜனாதிபதிக்கு இருப்பதாகவும் தெரிவித்தார். ."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ஸ்ரீ.ல.சு.க",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஸ்ரீலங்கா சுதந்திரக் கட்சி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "மைத்திரிபால சிறிசேன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "42",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "பொதுஜன பெரமுன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "மைத்திரிபால சிறிசேன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "71வது",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "2",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "மஹரகம இளைஞர் பேரவை கேட்போர் கூடம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஆண்டு",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஸ்ரீலங்கா சுதந்திரக் கட்சி",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}