{
  "newspaper_id": "news-first-lk",
  "url": "https://www.newsfirst.lk/2022/06/24/imf-looking-forward-to-help-sri-lanka/",
  "time_ut": 1656084480,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "IMF looking forward to help Sri Lanka",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "IMF looking forward to help Sri Lanka",
      "author": "",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); A delegation from the International Monetary Fund (IMF) called on President Gotabaya Rajapaksa on Friday (24) afternoon at the President’s house, in Colombo.",
        "The delegations will stay in Sri Lanka for a week to gather facts and discuss policies for a staff-level agreement. The delegations briefed the President on the discussion with the Prime Minister, Minister of Finance, Governor of the Central Bank of Sri Lanka, and other authorities and also experts on the current situation.",
        "The delegations said that they look forward to assisting Sri Lanka in this difficult situation within the policies of the International Monetary Fund (IMF).",
        "President Rajapaksa thanked the delegation for their support to Sri Lanka during these trying times.",
        "Peter Breuer, Chief of the Debt Capital Markets Division, Monetary and Capital Market Department",
        "Masahiro Nozaki, Senior Economist in the Fiscal Affairs Department of the International Monetary Fund.",
        "Tubagus Feridhanu Setyawan, International Monetary Fund Resident Representative to Sri Lanka",
        "Anne-Marie Gulde-Wolf, Deputy Director of the Asia and Pacific Department",
        "Two men arrested for illegal stockpiling; over 2,000l diesel recovered"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Sri Lanka",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "the International Monetary Fund",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Gotabaya Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Friday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "24) afternoon",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "a week",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Central Bank of Sri Lanka",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the International Monetary Fund",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Peter Breuer",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Debt Capital Markets Division",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Monetary and Capital Market Department",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Masahiro Nozaki",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Senior Economist",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Fiscal Affairs Department of the International Monetary Fund",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "International Monetary Fund Resident Representative",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Anne-Marie Gulde-Wolf",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Asia",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "Pacific Department",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Two",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "over 2,000l",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "IMF ශ්‍රී ලංකාවට උදව් කිරීමට බලාපොරොත්තු වේ",
      "author": "",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); ජාත්‍යන්තර මූල්‍ය අරමුදලේ (IMF) නියෝජිත පිරිසක් සිකුරාදා (24) පස්වරුවේ කොළඹ ජනාධිපති මන්දිරයේ දී ජනාධිපති ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ මහතා හමුවිය.",
        "දූත පිරිස සතියක කාලයක් ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ රැඳී සිට කරුණු එක්රැස් කිරීමට සහ කාර්ය මණ්ඩල මට්ටමේ ගිවිසුමක් සඳහා ප්‍රතිපත්ති සාකච්ඡා කිරීමට නියමිතය. වත්මන් තත්ත්වය පිළිබඳව අග්‍රාමාත්‍යවරයා, මුදල් අමාත්‍යවරයා, ශ්‍රී ලංකා මහ බැංකු අධිපතිවරයා ඇතුළු බලධාරීන් සහ විශේෂඥයින් සමඟ පැවති සාකච්ඡාව පිළිබඳව නියෝජිත පිරිස ජනාධිපතිවරයා වෙත කරුණු දැක්වූහ.",
        "ජාත්‍යන්තර මූල්‍ය අරමුදලේ (IMF) ප්‍රතිපත්ති තුළ ශ්‍රී ලංකාවට මෙම දුෂ්කර තත්ත්වය තුළ සහාය වීමට බලාපොරොත්තු වන බව නියෝජිතයෝ පැවසූහ.",
        "මෙම දුෂ්කර කාලවලදී ශ්‍රී ලංකාවට ලබාදුන් සහයෝගය පිළිබඳව ජනාධිපතිතුමා නියෝජිත පිරිසට ස්තුතිය පුද කළේය.",
        "Peter Breuer, ණය ප්‍රාග්ධන වෙළෙඳපොළ අංශයේ ප්‍රධානී, මුදල් හා ප්‍රාග්ධන වෙළෙඳපොළ දෙපාර්තමේන්තුව",
        "Masahiro Nozaki, ජාත්‍යන්තර මූල්‍ය අරමුදලේ මූල්‍ය කටයුතු දෙපාර්තමේන්තුවේ ජ්‍යෙෂ්ඨ ආර්ථික විද්‍යාඥ.",
        "Tubagus Feridhanu Setyawan, ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ ජාත්‍යන්තර මුල්‍ය අරමුදලේ නේවාසික නියෝජිත",
        "Anne-Marie Gulde-Wolf, ආසියානු පැසිෆික් දෙපාර්තමේන්තුවේ නියෝජ්‍ය අධ්‍යක්ෂ",
        "නීතිවිරෝධී ලෙස ගබඩා කළ පුද්ගලයින් දෙදෙනෙකු අත්අඩංගුවට ඩීසල් ලීටර් 2000කට වැඩි ප්‍රමාණයක් සොයා ගන්නා ලදී"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ජාත්‍යන්තර මුල්‍ය අරමුදල",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "සිකුරාදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "24) සවස",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "සතියක්",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකා මහ බැංකුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජාත්‍යන්තර මුල්‍ය අරමුදල",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "පීටර් බෲවර්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ණය ප්රාග්ධන වෙළෙඳපොළ අංශය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "මුදල් හා ප්රාග්ධන වෙළෙඳපොළ දෙපාර්තමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Masahiro Nozaki",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජ්යෙෂ්ඨ ආර්ථික විද්යාඥ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජාත්‍යන්තර මූල්‍ය අරමුදලේ මූල්‍ය කටයුතු දෙපාර්තමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ජාත්‍යන්තර මුල්‍ය අරමුදලේ නේවාසික නියෝජිතයා",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ඈන්-මාරි ගුල්ඩ්-වුල්ෆ්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ආසියාව",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "පැසිෆික් දෙපාර්තමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "දෙක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "2,000l ට වැඩි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "சர்வதேச நாணய நிதியம் இலங்கைக்கு உதவ எதிர்பார்த்துள்ளது",
      "author": "",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); சர்வதேச நாணய நிதியத்தின் (IMF) பிரதிநிதிகள் குழுவொன்று ஜனாதிபதி கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ஷவை வெள்ளிக்கிழமை (24) பிற்பகல் கொழும்பில் உள்ள ஜனாதிபதி இல்லத்தில் சந்தித்தது.",
        "தூதுக்குழுவினர் ஒருவாரம் இலங்கையில் தங்கியிருந்து உண்மைகளை சேகரிக்கவும், ஊழியர்கள் மட்ட ஒப்பந்தத்திற்கான கொள்கைகளை விவாதிக்கவும் உள்ளனர். பிரதமர், நிதியமைச்சர், இலங்கை மத்திய வங்கியின் ஆளுநர் மற்றும் ஏனைய அதிகாரிகள் மற்றும் நிபுணர்களுடனான கலந்துரையாடல் குறித்து பிரதிநிதிகள் ஜனாதிபதிக்கு விளக்கமளித்தனர்.",
        "சர்வதேச நாணய நிதியத்தின் (IMF) கொள்கைகளுக்கு உட்பட்டு இந்த இக்கட்டான சூழ்நிலையில் இலங்கைக்கு உதவுவதற்கு எதிர்பார்த்துள்ளதாக பிரதிநிதிகள் தெரிவித்தனர்.",
        "இந்த கடினமான காலங்களில் இலங்கைக்கு வழங்கிய ஆதரவிற்காக ஜனாதிபதி ராஜபக்ஷ தூதுக்குழுவிற்கு நன்றி தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "பீட்டர் ப்ரூயர், கடன் மூலதனச் சந்தைப் பிரிவின் தலைவர், நாணய மற்றும் மூலதனச் சந்தைத் துறை",
        "மசாஹிரோ நோசாகி, சர்வதேச நாணய நிதியத்தின் நிதி விவகாரத் துறையில் மூத்த பொருளாதார நிபுணர்.",
        "Tubagus Feridhanu Setyawan, சர்வதேச நாணய நிதியத்தின் இலங்கைக்கான வதிவிடப் பிரதிநிதி",
        "Anne-Marie Gulde-Wolf, ஆசிய மற்றும் பசிபிக் துறையின் துணை இயக்குனர்",
        "சட்டவிரோதமாக பதுக்கி வைத்திருந்த இருவர் கைது; 2,000 லிட்டருக்கும் அதிகமான டீசல் மீட்கப்பட்டது"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "இலங்கை",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "சர்வதேச நாணய நிதியம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "வெள்ளி",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "24) பிற்பகல்",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஒரு வாரம்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை மத்திய வங்கி",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "சர்வதேச நாணய நிதியம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ராஜபக்சே",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பீட்டர் ப்ரூயர்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "கடன் மூலதன சந்தை பிரிவு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "நாணய மற்றும் மூலதன சந்தை துறை",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Masahiro Nozaki",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "மூத்த பொருளாதார நிபுணர்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "சர்வதேச நாணய நிதியத்தின் நிதி விவகாரத் துறை",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "சர்வதேச நாணய நிதியத்தின் வதிவிடப் பிரதிநிதி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "அன்னே-மேரி குல்டே-ஓநாய்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆசியா",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "பசிபிக் துறை",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இரண்டு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "2,000லிக்கு மேல்",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  },
  "title": "IMF looking forward to help Sri Lanka",
  "body_lines": [
    "COLOMBO (News 1st); A delegation from the International Monetary Fund (IMF) called on President Gotabaya Rajapaksa on Friday (24) afternoon at the President’s house, in Colombo.",
    "The delegations will stay in Sri Lanka for a week to gather facts and discuss policies for a staff-level agreement. The delegations briefed the President on the discussion with the Prime Minister, Minister of Finance, Governor of the Central Bank of Sri Lanka, and other authorities and also experts on the current situation.",
    "The delegations said that they look forward to assisting Sri Lanka in this difficult situation within the policies of the International Monetary Fund (IMF).",
    "President Rajapaksa thanked the delegation for their support to Sri Lanka during these trying times.",
    "Peter Breuer, Chief of the Debt Capital Markets Division, Monetary and Capital Market Department",
    "Masahiro Nozaki, Senior Economist in the Fiscal Affairs Department of the International Monetary Fund.",
    "Tubagus Feridhanu Setyawan, International Monetary Fund Resident Representative to Sri Lanka",
    "Anne-Marie Gulde-Wolf, Deputy Director of the Asia and Pacific Department",
    "Two men arrested for illegal stockpiling; over 2,000l diesel recovered"
  ],
  "translate": {
    "en": {
      "title": "IMF looking forward to help Sri Lanka",
      "author": "",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); A delegation from the International Monetary Fund (IMF) called on President Gotabaya Rajapaksa on Friday (24) afternoon at the President’s house, in Colombo.",
        "The delegations will stay in Sri Lanka for a week to gather facts and discuss policies for a staff-level agreement. The delegations briefed the President on the discussion with the Prime Minister, Minister of Finance, Governor of the Central Bank of Sri Lanka, and other authorities and also experts on the current situation.",
        "The delegations said that they look forward to assisting Sri Lanka in this difficult situation within the policies of the International Monetary Fund (IMF).",
        "President Rajapaksa thanked the delegation for their support to Sri Lanka during these trying times.",
        "Peter Breuer, Chief of the Debt Capital Markets Division, Monetary and Capital Market Department",
        "Masahiro Nozaki, Senior Economist in the Fiscal Affairs Department of the International Monetary Fund.",
        "Tubagus Feridhanu Setyawan, International Monetary Fund Resident Representative to Sri Lanka",
        "Anne-Marie Gulde-Wolf, Deputy Director of the Asia and Pacific Department",
        "Two men arrested for illegal stockpiling; over 2,000l diesel recovered"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Sri Lanka",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "the International Monetary Fund",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Gotabaya Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Friday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "24) afternoon",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "a week",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Central Bank of Sri Lanka",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the International Monetary Fund",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Peter Breuer",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Debt Capital Markets Division",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Monetary and Capital Market Department",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Masahiro Nozaki",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Senior Economist",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Fiscal Affairs Department of the International Monetary Fund",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "International Monetary Fund Resident Representative",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Anne-Marie Gulde-Wolf",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Asia",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "Pacific Department",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Two",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "over 2,000l",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "IMF ශ්‍රී ලංකාවට උදව් කිරීමට බලාපොරොත්තු වේ",
      "author": "",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); ජාත්‍යන්තර මූල්‍ය අරමුදලේ (IMF) නියෝජිත පිරිසක් සිකුරාදා (24) පස්වරුවේ කොළඹ ජනාධිපති මන්දිරයේ දී ජනාධිපති ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ මහතා හමුවිය.",
        "දූත පිරිස සතියක කාලයක් ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ රැඳී සිට කරුණු එක්රැස් කිරීමට සහ කාර්ය මණ්ඩල මට්ටමේ ගිවිසුමක් සඳහා ප්‍රතිපත්ති සාකච්ඡා කිරීමට නියමිතය. වත්මන් තත්ත්වය පිළිබඳව අග්‍රාමාත්‍යවරයා, මුදල් අමාත්‍යවරයා, ශ්‍රී ලංකා මහ බැංකු අධිපතිවරයා ඇතුළු බලධාරීන් සහ විශේෂඥයින් සමඟ පැවති සාකච්ඡාව පිළිබඳව නියෝජිත පිරිස ජනාධිපතිවරයා වෙත කරුණු දැක්වූහ.",
        "ජාත්‍යන්තර මූල්‍ය අරමුදලේ (IMF) ප්‍රතිපත්ති තුළ ශ්‍රී ලංකාවට මෙම දුෂ්කර තත්ත්වය තුළ සහාය වීමට බලාපොරොත්තු වන බව නියෝජිතයෝ පැවසූහ.",
        "මෙම දුෂ්කර කාලවලදී ශ්‍රී ලංකාවට ලබාදුන් සහයෝගය පිළිබඳව ජනාධිපතිතුමා නියෝජිත පිරිසට ස්තුතිය පුද කළේය.",
        "Peter Breuer, ණය ප්‍රාග්ධන වෙළෙඳපොළ අංශයේ ප්‍රධානී, මුදල් හා ප්‍රාග්ධන වෙළෙඳපොළ දෙපාර්තමේන්තුව",
        "Masahiro Nozaki, ජාත්‍යන්තර මූල්‍ය අරමුදලේ මූල්‍ය කටයුතු දෙපාර්තමේන්තුවේ ජ්‍යෙෂ්ඨ ආර්ථික විද්‍යාඥ.",
        "Tubagus Feridhanu Setyawan, ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ ජාත්‍යන්තර මුල්‍ය අරමුදලේ නේවාසික නියෝජිත",
        "Anne-Marie Gulde-Wolf, ආසියානු පැසිෆික් දෙපාර්තමේන්තුවේ නියෝජ්‍ය අධ්‍යක්ෂ",
        "නීතිවිරෝධී ලෙස ගබඩා කළ පුද්ගලයින් දෙදෙනෙකු අත්අඩංගුවට ඩීසල් ලීටර් 2000කට වැඩි ප්‍රමාණයක් සොයා ගන්නා ලදී"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ජාත්‍යන්තර මුල්‍ය අරමුදල",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "සිකුරාදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "24) සවස",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "සතියක්",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකා මහ බැංකුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජාත්‍යන්තර මුල්‍ය අරමුදල",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "පීටර් බෲවර්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ණය ප්රාග්ධන වෙළෙඳපොළ අංශය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "මුදල් හා ප්රාග්ධන වෙළෙඳපොළ දෙපාර්තමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Masahiro Nozaki",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජ්යෙෂ්ඨ ආර්ථික විද්යාඥ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජාත්‍යන්තර මූල්‍ය අරමුදලේ මූල්‍ය කටයුතු දෙපාර්තමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ජාත්‍යන්තර මුල්‍ය අරමුදලේ නේවාසික නියෝජිතයා",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ඈන්-මාරි ගුල්ඩ්-වුල්ෆ්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ආසියාව",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "පැසිෆික් දෙපාර්තමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "දෙක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "2,000l ට වැඩි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "சர்வதேச நாணய நிதியம் இலங்கைக்கு உதவ எதிர்பார்த்துள்ளது",
      "author": "",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); சர்வதேச நாணய நிதியத்தின் (IMF) பிரதிநிதிகள் குழுவொன்று ஜனாதிபதி கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ஷவை வெள்ளிக்கிழமை (24) பிற்பகல் கொழும்பில் உள்ள ஜனாதிபதி இல்லத்தில் சந்தித்தது.",
        "தூதுக்குழுவினர் ஒருவாரம் இலங்கையில் தங்கியிருந்து உண்மைகளை சேகரிக்கவும், ஊழியர்கள் மட்ட ஒப்பந்தத்திற்கான கொள்கைகளை விவாதிக்கவும் உள்ளனர். பிரதமர், நிதியமைச்சர், இலங்கை மத்திய வங்கியின் ஆளுநர் மற்றும் ஏனைய அதிகாரிகள் மற்றும் நிபுணர்களுடனான கலந்துரையாடல் குறித்து பிரதிநிதிகள் ஜனாதிபதிக்கு விளக்கமளித்தனர்.",
        "சர்வதேச நாணய நிதியத்தின் (IMF) கொள்கைகளுக்கு உட்பட்டு இந்த இக்கட்டான சூழ்நிலையில் இலங்கைக்கு உதவுவதற்கு எதிர்பார்த்துள்ளதாக பிரதிநிதிகள் தெரிவித்தனர்.",
        "இந்த கடினமான காலங்களில் இலங்கைக்கு வழங்கிய ஆதரவிற்காக ஜனாதிபதி ராஜபக்ஷ தூதுக்குழுவிற்கு நன்றி தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "பீட்டர் ப்ரூயர், கடன் மூலதனச் சந்தைப் பிரிவின் தலைவர், நாணய மற்றும் மூலதனச் சந்தைத் துறை",
        "மசாஹிரோ நோசாகி, சர்வதேச நாணய நிதியத்தின் நிதி விவகாரத் துறையில் மூத்த பொருளாதார நிபுணர்.",
        "Tubagus Feridhanu Setyawan, சர்வதேச நாணய நிதியத்தின் இலங்கைக்கான வதிவிடப் பிரதிநிதி",
        "Anne-Marie Gulde-Wolf, ஆசிய மற்றும் பசிபிக் துறையின் துணை இயக்குனர்",
        "சட்டவிரோதமாக பதுக்கி வைத்திருந்த இருவர் கைது; 2,000 லிட்டருக்கும் அதிகமான டீசல் மீட்கப்பட்டது"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "இலங்கை",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "சர்வதேச நாணய நிதியம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "வெள்ளி",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "24) பிற்பகல்",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஒரு வாரம்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை மத்திய வங்கி",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "சர்வதேச நாணய நிதியம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ராஜபக்சே",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பீட்டர் ப்ரூயர்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "கடன் மூலதன சந்தை பிரிவு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "நாணய மற்றும் மூலதன சந்தை துறை",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Masahiro Nozaki",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "மூத்த பொருளாதார நிபுணர்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "சர்வதேச நாணய நிதியத்தின் நிதி விவகாரத் துறை",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "சர்வதேச நாணய நிதியத்தின் வதிவிடப் பிரதிநிதி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "அன்னே-மேரி குல்டே-ஓநாய்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆசியா",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "பசிபிக் துறை",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இரண்டு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "2,000லிக்கு மேல்",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}