{
  "newspaper_id": "daily-mirror-lk",
  "url": "https://www.dailymirror.lk/top_story/Private-jet-arrives-in-Maldives-to-transport-GR-to-Singapore/155-241067",
  "time_ut": 1657776232,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Private jet arrives in Maldives to transport GR to Singapore",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Private jet arrives in Maldives to transport GR to Singapore",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "A private jet has landed in the Maldives capital Male a short while ago and President Gotabaya Rajapaksa is all set to depart the island country for Singapore, the Daily Mirror learns.",
        "Rajapaksa, his wife Ioma Rajapaksa and two security officials were to board a Singapore Airlines flight last night from Male to Singapore but did not go ahead as scheduled due to security concerns.",
        "Rajapaksa had then requested for a private jet to depart the Maldives and discussions had begun by the Maldives authorities late night.",
        "The Daily Mirror learns that the jet arrived at the Velana International Airport a short while ago and Gotabaya Rajapaksa will depart the Maldives in a short while.",
        "The President is expected to announce his resignation after he reaches Singapore later today. (JAMILA HUSAIN)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Maldives",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "Singapore",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Maldives",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Gotabaya Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Singapore",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Daily Mirror",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Rajapaksa",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ioma Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "two",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Singapore Airlines",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "last night",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "Male",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Singapore",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Maldives",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Maldives",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "late night",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "The Daily Mirror",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Velana International Airport",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "Gotabaya Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Maldives",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Singapore",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "JAMILA HUSAIN",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "GR සිංගප්පූරුවට ප්‍රවාහනය කිරීමට පුද්ගලික ජෙට් යානයක් මාලදිවයිනට පැමිණේ",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "පෞද්ගලික ජෙට් යානයක් මීට සුළු මොහොතකට පෙර මාලදිවයිනේ මාලේ අගනුවරට ගොඩබස්වා ඇති අතර ජනාධිපති ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ මහතා දිවයිනෙන් සිංගප්පූරුව බලා පිටත්ව යාමට සූදානම් වන බව ඩේලි මිරර් වෙත වාර්තා වේ.",
        "රාජපක්ෂ, ඔහුගේ බිරිඳ අයෝමා රාජපක්ෂ සහ ආරක්ෂක නිලධාරීන් දෙදෙනකු ඊයේ රාත්‍රියේ මාලේ සිට සිංගප්පූරුව බලා යාමට සිංගප්පූරු ගුවන් සේවයට අයත් ගුවන් යානයකට ගොඩවීමට නියමිතව තිබූ නමුත් ආරක්ෂක හේතූන් මත නියමිත පරිදි ගමන් කළේ නැත.",
        "රාජපක්ෂ මහතා මාලදිවයිනෙන් පිටත්වීම සඳහා පෞද්ගලික ජෙට් යානයක් ඉල්ලා ඇති අතර මාලදිවයිනේ බලධාරීන් විසින් සාකච්ඡා ආරම්භ කර තිබුණේ රාත්‍රියේය.",
        "මෙම ජෙට් යානය මීට සුළු මොහොතකට පෙර වේලාන ජාත්‍යන්තර ගුවන් තොටුපළට පැමිණි බවත් ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ තව සුළු මොහොතකින් මාලදිවයිනෙන් පිටත්ව යන බවත් ඩේලි මිරර් වෙත වාර්තා වේ.",
        "අද පස්වරුවේ සිංගප්පූරුවට ළඟාවීමෙන් පසු ජනාධිපතිවරයා සිය ඉල්ලා අස්වීම ප්‍රකාශ කිරීමට නියමිතයි. (ජමිලා හුසේන්)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "මාලදිවයින",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "සිංගප්පූරුව",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "මාලදිවයින",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "සිංගප්පූරුව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඩේලි මිරර්",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "අයෝමා රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "දෙක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "සිංගප්පූරු ගුවන් සේවය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "අවසන් රාත්රිය",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "පිරිමි",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "සිංගප්පූරුව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "මාලදිවයින",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "මාලදිවයින",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "මහ රෑ",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ඩේලි මිරර්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "වේලාන ජාත්‍යන්තර ගුවන්තොටුපළ",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "මාලදිවයින",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "සිංගප්පූරුව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජමිලා හුසේන්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "GR ஐ சிங்கப்பூருக்கு ஏற்றிச் செல்ல தனியார் ஜெட் விமானம் மாலத்தீவுக்கு வந்தது",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "மாலைதீவு தலைநகர் மாலேயில் தனியார் ஜெட் விமானம் ஒன்று சற்று முன்னர் தரையிறங்கியுள்ளதுடன், ஜனாதிபதி கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ஷ தீவு நாட்டிலிருந்து சிங்கப்பூர் செல்லவுள்ளதாக டெய்லி மிரர் செய்தி வெளியிட்டுள்ளது.",
        "ராஜபக்சே, அவரது மனைவி அயோமா ராஜபக்சே மற்றும் இரண்டு பாதுகாப்பு அதிகாரிகள் நேற்று இரவு சிங்கப்பூர் ஏர்லைன்ஸ் விமானத்தில் மாலேயில் இருந்து சிங்கப்பூர் செல்ல இருந்தனர், ஆனால் பாதுகாப்புக் காரணங்களால் திட்டமிட்டபடி செல்லவில்லை.",
        "மாலத்தீவில் இருந்து புறப்படுவதற்கு ராஜபக்சே ஒரு தனியார் ஜெட் விமானத்தை கோரியிருந்தார் மற்றும் மாலைதீவு அதிகாரிகளால் நள்ளிரவில் பேச்சுவார்த்தைகள் தொடங்கப்பட்டன.",
        "இந்த ஜெட் விமானம் சற்று நேரத்திற்கு முன்னர் வேலனை சர்வதேச விமான நிலையத்தை வந்தடைந்ததாகவும், கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ச இன்னும் சிறிது நேரத்தில் மாலைதீவு புறப்படுவார் எனவும் டெய்லி மிரர் செய்தி வெளியிட்டுள்ளது.",
        "ஜனாதிபதி இன்று சிங்கப்பூர் சென்றடைந்த பின்னர் தனது பதவி விலகலை அறிவிப்பார் என எதிர்பார்க்கப்படுகிறது. (ஜமிலா ஹுசைன்)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "மாலத்தீவுகள்",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "சிங்கப்பூர்",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "மாலத்தீவுகள்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "சிங்கப்பூர்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "டெய்லி மிரர்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ராஜபக்சே",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "அயோமா ராஜபக்ச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இரண்டு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "சிங்கப்பூர் ஏர்லைன்ஸ்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "நேற்று இரவு",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆண்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சிங்கப்பூர்",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ராஜபக்சே",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "மாலத்தீவுகள்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "மாலத்தீவுகள்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "பின்னிரவு",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "டெய்லி மிரர்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "வேலனா சர்வதேச விமான நிலையம்",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "மாலத்தீவுகள்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "சிங்கப்பூர்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜமிலா ஹுசைன்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}