{
  "newspaper_id": "d-b-s-jeyaraj-com",
  "url": "https://dbsjeyaraj.com/dbsj/archives/78520",
  "time_ut": 1657479960,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "If Gotabaya Resigns on July 13, Parliament would be summoned on July 15.  nominations for Presidency would be made on July 19 and a parliamentary vote will be held on July 20 to elect a new President",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "If Gotabaya Resigns on July 13, Parliament would be summoned on July 15.  nominations for Presidency would be made on July 19 and a parliamentary vote will be held on July 20 to elect a new President",
      "author": "Administrator",
      "body_lines": [
        "Sri Lanka on Monday was rife with speculation over President Gotabaya Rajapaksa’s whereabouts, and uncertainty over the island’s political future, two days after citizens mounted massive resistance against the two leaders over an unprecedented economic crisis.",
        "President Gotabaya, who has promised to resign on July 13, was on Monday flown to an airbase near the main international airport in Katunayake, near Colombo, AFP reported. When The Hindu contacted spokespersons of the island’s Civil Aviation Authority and the Air Force, both said they were unaware of such a development.",
        "There is no official word from the President’s office on his current location, except a statement that said all messages issued by President Gotabaya would henceforth be released by the Speaker.",
        "“Therefore, kindly request that only the announcements issued by the Speaker to be considered as official announcements issued by the President,” the Presidential Media Division said. Speaker Mahinda Yapa Abeywardena, who earlier told BBC that the President was in a “nearby country” and was expected to return by Wednesday, backtracked on the statement later. “I made a mistake,” he said, further fuelling rumours of the President “fleeing” the country to a Gulf capital.",
        "Meanwhile, the Speaker convened a party leaders’ meeting for the second time since angry protesters stormed the homes and offices of the President and the PM on Saturday, in a dramatic takeover of the buildings, pushing both leaders to agree to resign. Neither has formally stepped down yet, but opposition parties have been holding talks on forming a caretaker government with all parties in it, for a short period.",
        "Opposition leader Sajith Premadasa, who leads the Samagi Jana Balawegaya (SJB or United People’s Power), said President Gotabaya, PM Ranil Wickremesinghe, and the ruling party had “lost legitimacy”. “We will form a new government with a new President & a new PM. All those who oppose this process will be responsible for the ensuing anarchy,” he said in a tweet on Monday.",
        "“As the largest opposition party, we believe that any interim government we form must be led by Sajith Premadasa as President,” said SJB lawmaker Eran Wickramaratne.",
        "“We are very clear that this must be an interim, short-term arrangement to address immediate economic issues. We must soon go in for elections because people must be given an opportunity to give us a mandate. Otherwise, fringe elements may try to capture the space,” he told The Hindu.",
        "The SJB, with about 50 seats in the 225-member Parliament, is counting on “independent” MPs and dissenting members from the ruling camp to join its MPs and put forward a Prime Ministerial candidate, but political sources said they were far from an agreement on the matter.",
        "At the party leaders’ meeting on Monday, it was also decided that should President Gotabaya resign on July 13, as has been assured by him, Parliament would be summoned on July 15. A nomination for Presidency would be made on July 19 and a parliamentary vote will be held on July 20."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Gotabaya Resigns",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "July 13",
          "label": "DATE"
        },
        {
          "text": "Parliament",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "July 15",
          "label": "DATE"
        },
        {
          "text": "July 19",
          "label": "DATE"
        },
        {
          "text": "July 20",
          "label": "DATE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Monday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Gotabaya Rajapaksa’s",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "two days",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "two",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Gotabaya",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "July 13",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Monday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Katunayake",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Colombo",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "AFP",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Hindu",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Civil Aviation Authority",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Air Force",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Gotabaya",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the Presidential Media Division",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Mahinda Yapa Abeywardena",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "BBC",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Wednesday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Gulf",
            "label": "LOC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "second",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Saturday",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sajith Premadasa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Samagi",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Jana Balawegaya",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "SJB",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "United People’s Power",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Gotabaya",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Monday",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sajith Premadasa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "SJB",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Eran Wickramaratne",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Hindu",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "SJB",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "about 50",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "225",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Monday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Gotabaya",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "July 13",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "July 15",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "July 19",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "July 20",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "ගෝඨාභය ජුලි 13 ඉල්ලා අස් වුවහොත් පාර්ලිමේන්තුව ජූලි 15 කැඳවයි. ජනාධිපති ධූරය සඳහා නාමයෝජනා ජූලි 19 වනදා සිදු කෙරෙන අතර නව ජනාධිපතිවරයෙකු තෝරා පත් කර ගැනීම සඳහා ජූලි 20 වනදා පාර්ලිමේන්තු ඡන්ද විමසීමක් පැවැත්වීමට නියමිතයි.",
      "author": "පරිපාලක",
      "body_lines": [
        "පෙර නොවූ විරූ ආර්ථික අර්බුදයක් සම්බන්ධයෙන් පුරවැසියන් නායකයන් දෙදෙනාට එරෙහිව දැවැන්ත ප්‍රතිරෝධයක් දියත් කිරීමෙන් දින දෙකකට පසුව, ජනාධිපති ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ මහතා සිටින ස්ථානය සහ දිවයිනේ දේශපාලන අනාගතය පිළිබඳ අවිනිශ්චිතතාවයෙන් සඳුදා ශ්‍රී ලංකාව පිරී ගියේය.",
        "ජූලි 13 වැනිදා ඉල්ලා අස්වීමට පොරොන්දු වූ ජනාධිපති ගෝඨාභය සඳුදා කොළඹට නුදුරින් කටුනායක ප්‍රධාන ජාත්‍යන්තර ගුවන් තොටුපළ අසල පිහිටි ගුවන් කඳවුරකට රැගෙන ගිය බව AFP වාර්තා කරයි. ද හින්දු පුවත්පත දිවයිනේ සිවිල් ගුවන් සේවා අධිකාරියේ සහ ගුවන් හමුදාවේ ප්‍රකාශකයින් ඇමතූ විට ඔවුන් දෙදෙනාම කියා සිටියේ එවැනි වර්ධනයක් පිළිබඳව තමන් නොදන්නා බවයි.",
        "ජනාධිපති ගෝඨාභය විසින් නිකුත් කරන ලද සියලුම පණිවිඩ මින් ඉදිරියට කථානායකවරයා විසින් නිකුත් කරන බවට ප්‍රකාශයක් හැරුණු විට, ඔහු දැනට සිටින ස්ථානය පිළිබඳව ජනාධිපති කාර්යාලයෙන් නිල වචනයක් නොමැත.",
        "එබැවින් කථානායකවරයා නිකුත් කරන නිවේදන පමණක් ජනාධිපතිවරයා විසින් නිකුත් කරන ලද නිල නිවේදන ලෙස සලකන ලෙස කාරුණිකව ඉල්ලා සිටින බවද ජනාධිපති මාධ්‍ය අංශය පවසයි. ජනාධිපතිවරයා “ළඟ රටක” සිටින බවත් බදාදා වන විට ආපසු පැමිණීමට අපේක්ෂා කරන බවත් මීට පෙර බීබීසීයට පැවසූ කථානායක මහින්ද යාපා අබේවර්ධන පසුව එම ප්‍රකාශයෙන් පසුබැස්සේය. “මම වැරැද්දක් කළා,” ඔහු කීවේ ජනාධිපතිවරයා රටින් ගල්ෆ් අගනුවරකට “පලා යාම” පිළිබඳ කටකතා තවදුරටත් වර්ධනය කරමිනි.",
        "මේ අතර, කෝපයට පත් විරෝධතාකරුවන් සෙනසුරාදා ජනාධිපතිවරයාගේ සහ අග්‍රාමාත්‍යවරයාගේ නිවෙස්වලට හා කාර්යාලවලට කඩා වැදී, නාටකාකාර ලෙස ගොඩනැගිලි අත්පත් කර ගැනීමත් සමඟ නායකයින් දෙදෙනාම ඉල්ලා අස්වීමට එකඟ වීමට තල්ලු කිරීමෙන් පසු කථානායකවරයා දෙවන වරටත් පක්ෂ නායක රැස්වීමක් කැඳවීය. දෙදෙනාම තවමත් නිල වශයෙන් ඉවත් වී නැත, නමුත් විපක්ෂයේ පක්ෂ කෙටි කාලයක් සඳහා භාරකාර ආණ්ඩුවක් පිහිටුවීම පිළිබඳ සාකච්ඡා පවත්වයි.",
        "සමගි ජන බලවේගය (SJB හෝ එක්සත් ජනතා බලය) නායකත්වය දරන විපක්ෂ නායක සජිත් ප්‍රේමදාස මහතා පැවසුවේ ජනාධිපති ගෝඨාභය, අගමැති රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ සහ ආණ්ඩු පක්ෂයට “නීත්‍යානුකූලභාවය අහිමි වී ඇති” බවයි. “අපි අලුත් ජනාධිපතිවරයෙක් සහ අලුත් අගමැතිවරයෙක් සමඟ අලුත් ආණ්ඩුවක් පිහිටුවනවා. මෙම ක්‍රියාවලියට විරුද්ධ වන සියලුම දෙනා ඊළඟ අරාජිකත්වයට වගකිව යුතුය, ”ඔහු සඳුදා ට්විටර් පණිවුඩයක් නිකුත් කරමින් කියා සිටියේය.",
        "\"විපක්‍ෂයේ විශාලතම පක්ෂය ලෙස අපි විශ්වාස කරනවා අපි පිහිටුවන ඕනෑම අන්තර්වාර ආණ්ඩුවක් ජනාධිපති ලෙස සජිත් ප්‍රේමදාස විසින් මෙහෙයවිය යුතු බව\" යනුවෙන් SJB පාර්ලිමේන්තු මන්ත්‍රී ඉරාන් වික්‍රමරත්න පැවසීය.",
        "“මෙය ක්ෂනික ආර්ථික ප්‍රශ්න ආමන්ත්‍රණය කිරීම සඳහා අන්තර්කාලීන, කෙටිකාලීන වැඩපිළිවෙළක් විය යුතු බව අපට ඉතා පැහැදිලිය. අපි ඉක්මනින්ම මැතිවරණයකට යා යුතුයි මොකද අපිට ජනවරමක් දෙන්න ජනතාවට අවස්ථාවක් දිය යුතුයි. එසේ නොවුවහොත්, ආන්තික මූලද්‍රව්‍ය අවකාශය අල්ලා ගැනීමට උත්සාහ කළ හැකිය, ”ඔහු හින්දු වෙත පැවසීය.",
        "මන්ත්‍රීවරුන් 225කින් සමන්විත පාර්ලිමේන්තුවේ ආසන 50ක් පමණ ඇති SJB, “ස්වාධීන” මන්ත්‍රීවරුන් සහ පාලක කඳවුරේ විසම්මුතික මන්ත්‍රීවරුන් තම මන්ත්‍රීවරුන් සමඟ එකතු වී අගමැති අපේක්ෂකයෙකු ඉදිරිපත් කිරීමට ගණන් බලා ඇති නමුත් දේශපාලන ආරංචි මාර්ග පැවසුවේ ඔවුන් එකඟතාවයකින් බොහෝ දුරස් බව ය. කාරණය මත.",
        "සඳුදා පැවති පක්ෂ නායක රැස්වීමේදී ද තීරණය කර ඇත්තේ ජනාධිපති ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ මහතා ජුලි 13 වැනිදා ඉල්ලා අස් වුවහොත් පාර්ලිමේන්තුව ජූලි 15 වැනිදා කැඳවීමටයි.ජනාධිපතිධුරය සඳහා නාමයෝජනා ජුලි 19දා ඉදිරිපත් කර පාර්ලිමේන්තුවක් පැවැත්වීමටයි. ඡන්ද විමසීම ජූලි 20 වැනිදා පැවැත්වේ."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ගෝඨාභය ඉල්ලා අස්වෙයි",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "ජූලි 13",
          "label": "DATE"
        },
        {
          "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "ජූලි 15",
          "label": "DATE"
        },
        {
          "text": "ජූලි 19",
          "label": "DATE"
        },
        {
          "text": "ජූලි 20",
          "label": "DATE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "සඳුදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂගේ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "දින දෙකක්",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "දෙක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ගෝඨාභය",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජූලි 13",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "සඳුදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "කටුනායක",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "කොළඹ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "AFP",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "හින්දු",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "සිවිල් ගුවන් සේවා අධිකාරිය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගුවන් හමුදාව",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ගෝඨාභය",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ජනාධිපති මාධ්‍ය අංශය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "මහින්ද යාපා අබේවර්ධන",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "බීබීසී",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "බදාදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගල්ෆ්",
            "label": "LOC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "දෙවැනි",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "සෙනසුරාදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "සජිත් ප්‍රේමදාස",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "සමගි",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජන බලවේගය",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "එස්.ජේ.බී",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "එක්සත් ජනතා බලය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගෝඨාභය",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "සඳුදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "සජිත් ප්‍රේමදාස",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "එස්.ජේ.බී",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "එරාන් වික්‍රමරත්න",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "හින්දු",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "එස්.ජේ.බී",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "50 ක් පමණ",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "225",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "සඳුදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගෝඨාභය",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජූලි 13",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජූලි 15",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජූලි 19",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජූලි 20",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "ஜூலை 13 ஆம் தேதி கோட்டாபய ராஜினாமா செய்தால், ஜூலை 15 ஆம் தேதி பாராளுமன்றம் அழைக்கப்படும்",
      "author": "நிர்வாகி",
      "body_lines": [
        "ஜனாதிபதி கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்சவின் இருப்பிடம் மற்றும் தீவின் அரசியல் எதிர்காலம் குறித்த நிச்சயமற்ற தன்மை குறித்த ஊகங்களால் இலங்கை திங்கட்கிழமை நிறைந்திருந்தது, முன்னோடியில்லாத பொருளாதார நெருக்கடி தொடர்பாக குடிமக்கள் இரு தலைவர்களுக்கு எதிராக பாரிய எதிர்ப்பை இரண்டு நாட்களுக்குப் பிறகு.",
        "ஜூலை 13 ஆம் திகதி பதவி விலகுவதாக உறுதியளித்த ஜனாதிபதி கோட்டாபய, திங்கட்கிழமை கொழும்புக்கு அருகிலுள்ள கட்டுநாயக்கவில் உள்ள பிரதான சர்வதேச விமான நிலையத்திற்கு அருகிலுள்ள விமானத் தளத்திற்கு அழைத்துச் செல்லப்பட்டதாக AFP செய்தி வெளியிட்டுள்ளது. தீவின் சிவில் விமானப் போக்குவரத்து ஆணையம் மற்றும் விமானப்படையின் செய்தித் தொடர்பாளர்களை தி ஹிந்து தொடர்பு கொண்டபோது, ​​அவ்வாறான ஒரு வளர்ச்சி குறித்து தங்களுக்குத் தெரியாது என்று இருவரும் தெரிவித்தனர்.",
        "ஜனாதிபதி கோட்டாபயவினால் வெளியிடப்பட்ட அனைத்து செய்திகளும் இனி சபாநாயகரால் வெளியிடப்படும் என்று கூறப்பட்ட அறிக்கையைத் தவிர, அவர் தற்போதைய இருப்பிடம் குறித்து ஜனாதிபதியின் அலுவலகத்திலிருந்து உத்தியோகபூர்வ வார்த்தை எதுவும் இல்லை.",
        "எனவே, சபாநாயகரால் வெளியிடப்படும் அறிவிப்புகளை மாத்திரம் ஜனாதிபதியினால் வெளியிடப்படும் உத்தியோகபூர்வ அறிவிப்புகளாகக் கருதுமாறு அன்புடன் கேட்டுக்கொள்கின்றேன் என ஜனாதிபதி ஊடகப் பிரிவு தெரிவித்துள்ளது. ஜனாதிபதி \"அருகிலுள்ள நாட்டில்\" இருப்பதாகவும், புதன்கிழமைக்குள் திரும்பி வருவார் என எதிர்பார்க்கப்படுவதாகவும் முன்னதாக பிபிசியிடம் தெரிவித்த சபாநாயகர் மஹிந்த யாப்பா அபேவர்தன, பின்னர் அறிக்கையிலிருந்து பின்வாங்கினார். \"நான் ஒரு தவறு செய்துவிட்டேன்,\" என்று அவர் கூறினார், ஜனாதிபதி நாட்டை விட்டு வளைகுடா தலைநகருக்கு \"தப்பி ஓடுகிறார்\" என்ற வதந்திகளை மேலும் தூண்டினார்.",
        "இதற்கிடையில், கோபமான எதிர்ப்பாளர்கள் சனிக்கிழமையன்று ஜனாதிபதி மற்றும் பிரதமரின் வீடுகள் மற்றும் அலுவலகங்களை முற்றுகையிட்டதால், சபாநாயகர் இரண்டாவது முறையாக கட்சித் தலைவர்கள் கூட்டத்தை கூட்டினார். இருவரும் இன்னும் முறையாக பதவி விலகவில்லை, ஆனால் எதிர்க்கட்சிகள் அனைத்து கட்சிகளுடன் காபந்து அரசாங்கத்தை அமைப்பது குறித்து குறுகிய காலத்திற்கு பேச்சுவார்த்தை நடத்தி வருகின்றன.",
        "ஜனாதிபதி கோட்டாபய, பிரதமர் ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க மற்றும் ஆளும் கட்சி \"சட்டபூர்வமான தன்மையை இழந்துவிட்டன\" என சமகி ஜன பலவேகய (SJB அல்லது ஐக்கிய மக்கள் சக்தி) கட்சிக்கு தலைமை தாங்கும் எதிர்க்கட்சித் தலைவர் சஜித் பிரேமதாச தெரிவித்தார். “புதிய ஜனாதிபதி மற்றும் புதிய பிரதமருடன் புதிய அரசாங்கத்தை அமைப்போம். இந்த செயல்முறையை எதிர்க்கும் அனைவரும் அடுத்தடுத்த அராஜகத்திற்கு பொறுப்பாவார்கள், ”என்று அவர் திங்களன்று ஒரு ட்வீட்டில் கூறினார்.",
        "\"பெரிய எதிர்க்கட்சி என்ற வகையில், நாங்கள் அமைக்கும் எந்தவொரு இடைக்கால அரசாங்கமும் சஜித் பிரேமதாச ஜனாதிபதியாக இருக்க வேண்டும் என்று நாங்கள் நம்புகிறோம்\" என்று SJB பாராளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர் எரான் விக்கிரமரத்ன கூறினார்.",
        "\"இது உடனடி பொருளாதாரப் பிரச்சினைகளைத் தீர்ப்பதற்கான இடைக்கால, குறுகிய கால ஏற்பாடாக இருக்க வேண்டும் என்பதில் நாங்கள் மிகவும் தெளிவாக இருக்கிறோம். நாங்கள் விரைவில் தேர்தலுக்கு செல்ல வேண்டும், ஏனென்றால் எமக்கு ஆணையை வழங்க மக்கள் ஒரு வாய்ப்பை வழங்க வேண்டும். இல்லையெனில், விளிம்பு கூறுகள் இடத்தைக் கைப்பற்ற முயற்சி செய்யலாம், ”என்று அவர் தி இந்துவிடம் கூறினார்.",
        "225 உறுப்பினர்களைக் கொண்ட பாராளுமன்றத்தில் சுமார் 50 இடங்களைக் கொண்ட SJB, \"சுயேச்சையான\" எம்.பி.க்கள் மற்றும் ஆளும் முகாமில் இருந்து கருத்து வேறுபாடு கொண்ட உறுப்பினர்களை அதன் எம்.பி.க்களுடன் இணைந்து பிரதமர் வேட்பாளரை முன்வைக்க எண்ணுகிறது, ஆனால் அரசியல் வட்டாரங்கள் அவர்கள் ஒரு உடன்படிக்கைக்கு வெகு தொலைவில் இருப்பதாகக் கூறுகின்றன. விஷயத்தில்.",
        "திங்கட்கிழமை நடைபெற்ற கட்சித் தலைவர்கள் கூட்டத்தில், ஜனாதிபதி கோட்டாபய ஜூலை 13 ஆம் தேதி பதவி விலகினால், ஜூலை 15 ஆம் தேதி நாடாளுமன்றம் கூட்டப்படும் என்றும், ஜூலை 19 ஆம் தேதி ஜனாதிபதித் தேர்தலுக்கான வேட்புமனு தாக்கல் செய்யப்படும் என்றும், நாடாளுமன்றத் தேர்தல் நடத்தப்படும் என்றும் முடிவு செய்யப்பட்டது. ஜூலை 20-ம் தேதி வாக்குப்பதிவு நடைபெறும்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "கோட்டாபய ராஜினாமா",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "ஜூலை 13",
          "label": "DATE"
        },
        {
          "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "ஜூலை 15",
          "label": "DATE"
        },
        {
          "text": "ஜூலை 19",
          "label": "DATE"
        },
        {
          "text": "ஜூலை 20",
          "label": "DATE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "திங்கட்கிழமை",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்சவின்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இரண்டு நாட்கள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இரண்டு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "கோட்டாபய",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜூலை 13",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "திங்கட்கிழமை",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "கட்டுநாயக்கா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "கொழும்பு",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "AFP",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்து",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "சிவில் விமான போக்குவரத்து ஆணையம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "விமானப்படை",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "கோட்டாபய",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஜனாதிபதி ஊடகப் பிரிவு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "மஹிந்த யாப்பா அபேவர்தன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "பிபிசி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "புதன்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "வளைகுடா",
            "label": "LOC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இரண்டாவது",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "சனிக்கிழமை",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "சஜித் பிரேமதாச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "சமகி",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜன பலவேகயா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "எஸ்.ஜே.பி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஐக்கிய மக்கள் சக்தி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "கோட்டாபய",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "திங்கட்கிழமை",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "சஜித் பிரேமதாச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "எஸ்.ஜே.பி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "எரான் விக்கிரமரத்ன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இந்து",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "எஸ்.ஜே.பி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "சுமார் 50",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "225",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "திங்கட்கிழமை",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "கோட்டாபய",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜூலை 13",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜூலை 15",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜூலை 19",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜூலை 20",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}