{
  "newspaper_id": "economy-next-com",
  "url": "https://economynext.com/sri-lanka-aviation-minister-steps-down-president-orders-probe-97029/",
  "time_ut": 1657096920,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Sri Lanka aviation minister steps down, president orders probe",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Sri Lanka aviation minister steps down, president orders probe",
      "author": "",
      "body_lines": [
        "ECONOMYNEXT – Sri Lanka President Gotabaya Rajapaksa has ordered an probe over allegations made by the opposition leader while Aviation Minister Nimal Siripala de Silva will step down until its conclusion, a statement from the President’s media division said.",
        "“President Gotabaya Rajapaksa ordered an immediate formal investigation into the allegations leveled by the opposition leader in Parliament yesterday (05) regarding a transaction between the Ministry of Aviation with a private company,” the statement said.",
        "“Minister NimalSiripala De Silva will step down temporarily from the position of Minister of Ports, Shipping and Aviation Services on the instructions of the President until the investigations are concluded.",
        "Opposition leader Sajith Premadasa made allegations in parliament regarding a Japanese construction company.",
        "Minister de Silva had resigned denying the allegation and calling for an investigation, media reports said. (Colombo/Jul06/2022)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Sri Lanka",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Gotabaya Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Nimal Siripala de Silva",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Gotabaya Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "yesterday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "05",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Ministry of Aviation",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "NimalSiripala De Silva",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ports",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sajith Premadasa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Japanese",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "de Silva",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Colombo/Jul06/2022",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "ශ්‍රී ලංකා ගුවන්සේවා අමාත්‍ය ධුරයෙන් ඉල්ලා අස්වෙයි, ජනපති පරීක්ෂණයට නියෝග කරයි",
      "author": "",
      "body_lines": [
        "EconomyNext - ශ්‍රී ලංකා ජනාධිපති ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ මහතා විපක්ෂ නායකවරයාගේ චෝදනා සම්බන්ධයෙන් පරීක්ෂණයක් පවත්වන ලෙස නියෝග කර ඇති අතර, එය අවසන් වන තෙක් ගුවන් සේවා අමාත්‍ය නිමල් සිරිපාල ද සිල්වා මහතා ඉල්ලා අස්වන බව ජනාධිපති මාධ්‍ය අංශයේ නිවේදනයක් නිකුත් කරමින් කියා සිටියේය.",
        "“ගුවන්සේවා අමාත්‍යාංශය පෞද්ගලික සමාගමක් සමඟ සිදු කර ඇති ගණුදෙනුවක් සම්බන්ධයෙන් විපක්ෂ නායකවරයා ඊයේ (05) පාර්ලිමේන්තුවේදී කරන ලද චෝදනා සම්බන්ධයෙන් වහාම විධිමත් පරීක්ෂණයක් පවත්වන ලෙස ජනාධිපති ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ මහතා නියෝග කළේය.",
        "“ජනාධිපතිවරයාගේ උපදෙස් මත පරීක්ෂණ අවසන් වනතුරු නිමල්සිරිපාල ද සිල්වා අමාත්‍යවරයා වරාය, නාවික හා ගුවන් සේවා අමාත්‍ය ධූරයෙන් තාවකාලිකව ඉල්ලා අස්වෙනවා.",
        "ජපාන ඉදිකිරීම් සමාගමක් සම්බන්ධයෙන් විපක්ෂ නායක සජිත් ප්‍රේමදාස මහතා පාර්ලිමේන්තුවේදී චෝදනා කළා.",
        "ද සිල්වා අමාත්‍යවරයා ඉල්ලා අස්වී ඇත්තේ එම චෝදනාව ප්‍රතික්ෂේප කරමින් පරීක්ෂණයක් පවත්වන ලෙස ඉල්ලා සිටි බව මාධ්‍ය වාර්තා කළේය. (කොළඹ/ජූලි06/2022)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "නිමල් සිරිපාල ද සිල්වා",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඊයේ",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "05",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගුවන් සේවා අමාත්යාංශය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "නිමල්සිරිපාල ද සිල්වා",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "වරායන්",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "සජිත් ප්‍රේමදාස",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජපන්",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ද සිල්වා",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "කොළඹ/ජූලි 06/2022",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "இலங்கை விமான போக்குவரத்து அமைச்சர் பதவி விலகினார், ஜனாதிபதி விசாரணைக்கு உத்தரவிட்டார்",
      "author": "",
      "body_lines": [
        "பொருளாதாரம் - இலங்கை ஜனாதிபதி கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ஷ, எதிர்க்கட்சித் தலைவரின் குற்றச்சாட்டுகள் குறித்து விசாரணை நடத்த உத்தரவிட்டுள்ளார், அது முடியும் வரை விமானப் போக்குவரத்து அமைச்சர் நிமல் சிறிபால டி சில்வா பதவி விலகுவார் என்று ஜனாதிபதியின் ஊடகப் பிரிவு அறிக்கை தெரிவித்துள்ளது.",
        "தனியார் நிறுவனத்துடன் விமான போக்குவரத்து அமைச்சுக்கு இடையில் இடம்பெற்ற கொடுக்கல் வாங்கல் தொடர்பில் எதிர்க்கட்சித் தலைவர் நேற்று (05) பாராளுமன்றத்தில் முன்வைத்த குற்றச்சாட்டுக்கள் தொடர்பில் உடனடியாக முறையான விசாரணை நடத்துமாறு ஜனாதிபதி கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ஷ உத்தரவிட்டுள்ளார்.",
        "விசாரணைகள் முடியும் வரை ஜனாதிபதியின் பணிப்புரையின் பேரில் துறைமுகங்கள், கப்பல் மற்றும் விமான சேவைகள் அமைச்சர் பதவியில் இருந்து அமைச்சர் நிமல்சிறிபால டி சில்வா தற்காலிகமாக விலகுவார்.",
        "ஜப்பானிய நிர்மாண நிறுவனம் தொடர்பில் எதிர்க்கட்சித் தலைவர் சஜித் பிரேமதாச பாராளுமன்றத்தில் குற்றச்சாட்டுக்களை முன்வைத்தார்.",
        "குற்றச்சாட்டை நிராகரித்து விசாரணைக்கு அழைப்பு விடுத்து அமைச்சர் டி சில்வா ராஜினாமா செய்துள்ளதாக ஊடகங்கள் செய்தி வெளியிட்டுள்ளன. (கொழும்பு/ஜூலை06/2022)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "இலங்கை",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "நிமல் சிறிபால டி சில்வா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "நேற்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "05",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "விமான போக்குவரத்து அமைச்சகம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "நிமல்சிறிபால டி சில்வா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "துறைமுகங்கள்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "சஜித் பிரேமதாச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜப்பானியர்",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "டி சில்வா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "கொழும்பு/ஜூலை06/2022",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}