{
  "newspaper_id": "news-first-lk",
  "url": "https://www.newsfirst.lk/2022/08/31/china-s-achievements-an-inspiration-for-sri-lanka-ambassador-kohona/",
  "time_ut": 1661961600,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "China’s achievements an inspiration for Sri Lanka: Ambassador Kohona",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "China’s achievements an inspiration for Sri Lanka: Ambassador Kohona",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); The Ambassador of Sri Lanka to China, Palitha Kohona said that Sri Lanka has been inspired by China's achievements, and have to find its own strengths and work on them to become a country like China in the future.",
        "In an interview to Global Times, the Ambassador said that Sri Lanka currently is facing a myriad of challenges, and has many lessons to learn from China.",
        "Ambassador Kohona also pointed out that within the last decade, China has developed rapidly and has become the biggest source of foreign direct investment and the second biggest economy in the world, during which time, Sri Lanka's bilateral relations with China have expanded substantially and have prospered.",
        "\"Today, we hope that we can use these bonds to advance Sri Lanka's development,\" he said.",
        "According to the Ambassador, official and civil interaction between Sri Lanka and China over the last decade has covered a range of activities and projects in both countries, and both populations entertain a positive impression of each other.",
        "Ambassador Kohona, while mentioning that China has been a strong advocate of globalization, said that Sri Lanka has benefited from and firmly supports globalization, as globalized connectivity allows countries' exports to reach more lucrative markets easier.",
        "\"What China has done under the dedicated leadership for the Communist Party of China (CPC) is remarkable. It's unique. No other country has achieved the goal of eradicating extreme poverty at any time in history, while China has done this impressively,\" he mentioned.",
        "Kohona added that Sri Lanka also wants to eliminate extreme poverty, creating a better life, and ensuring a better living standard for its people.",
        "One-month-old infant abandoned at a motor garage with a letter",
        "Are you a victim of Cyber Crime? Police Unit ready to crackdown crime in the cyberspace"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "China",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "Sri Lanka",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "Kohona",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "News 1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "China",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Palitha Kohona",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "China",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "China",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Global Times",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "China",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Kohona",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the last decade",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "China",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "second",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka's",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "China",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Today",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka's",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "China",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the last decade",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Kohona",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "China",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "China",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Communist Party of China",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "CPC",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "China",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Kohona",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "One-month-old",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Cyber Crime",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "චීනයේ ජයග්‍රහණ ශ්‍රී ලංකාවට ආශ්වාදයක්: තානාපති කොහොන",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); චීනයේ ශ්‍රී ලංකා තානාපති පාලිත කොහොන මහතා ප්‍රකාශ කළේ චීනයේ ජයග්‍රහණවලින් ශ්‍රී ලංකාව ආශ්වාදයක් ලබා ඇති බවත්, අනාගතයේ දී චීනය වැනි රටක් බවට පත්වීම සඳහා ශ්‍රී ලංකාව තමන්ගේම ශක්තීන් සොයාගෙන ඒවා මත ක්‍රියා කළ යුතු බවත්ය.",
        "ග්ලෝබල් ටයිම්ස් වෙත සම්මුඛ සාකච්ඡාවකට එක්වෙමින් තානාපතිවරයා කියා සිටියේ ශ්‍රී ලංකාව දැනට අභියෝග රැසකට මුහුණ දී සිටින බවත් චීනයෙන් ඉගෙන ගැනීමට බොහෝ පාඩම් ඇති බවත්ය.",
        "පසුගිය දශකය තුළ චීනය ශීඝ්‍රයෙන් දියුණු වී සෘජු විදේශ ආයෝජන ප්‍රභවය සහ ලෝකයේ දෙවන විශාලතම ආර්ථිකය බවට පත්ව ඇති බවත්, එම කාලය තුළ චීනය සමඟ ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ ද්විපාර්ශ්වික සබඳතා සැලකිය යුතු ලෙස පුළුල් වී සමෘද්ධිමත් වූ බවත් තානාපති කොහොන පෙන්වා දුන්නේය. .",
        "“අද අපි බලාපොරොත්තු වෙනවා මේ බැඳුම්කර ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ සංවර්ධනයට ප්‍රගමනය කරන්න යොදාගන්න පුළුවන් වෙයි කියලා,” ඔහු පැවසීය.",
        "තානාපතිවරයාට අනුව, පසුගිය දශකය තුළ ශ්‍රී ලංකාව සහ චීනය අතර නිල සහ සිවිල් අන්තර්ක්‍රියා දෙරටේම ක්‍රියාකාරකම් සහ ව්‍යාපෘති රාශියක් ආවරණය කර ඇති අතර, ජනගහනය දෙකම එකිනෙකා කෙරෙහි ධනාත්මක හැඟීමක් ඇති කරයි.",
        "චීනය ගෝලීයකරණයේ ප්‍රබල අනුගාමිකයෙකු බව සඳහන් කළ තානාපති කොහොන, ශ්‍රී ලංකාව ගෝලීයකරණයෙන් ප්‍රතිලාභ ලබා ඇති බවත්, ගෝලීයකරණය වූ සම්බන්ධතාව නිසා රටවල්වල අපනයනවලට වඩා ලාභදායී වෙළෙඳපොළ වෙත පහසුවෙන් ළඟා වීමට ඉඩ සලසා දෙන බවත් ප්‍රකාශ කළේය.",
        "\"චීන කොමියුනිස්ට් පක්ෂය (CPC) වෙනුවෙන් කැපවූ නායකත්වය යටතේ චීනය කර ඇති දේ විශිෂ්ටයි. එය අද්විතීයයි. ඉතිහාසයේ කිසිම අවස්ථාවක අන්ත දිළිඳුකම තුරන් කිරීමේ ඉලක්කය වෙනත් කිසිම රටක් අත්කර ගෙන නොමැති අතර චීනය මෙය විශ්මය ජනක ලෙස කර ඇත,\" සඳහන් කර ඇත.",
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවට ද අවශ්‍ය වන්නේ අන්ත දරිද්‍රතාවය තුරන් කිරීම, යහපත් ජීවිතයක් නිර්මාණය කිරීම සහ එහි ජනතාවට වඩා හොඳ ජීවන තත්ත්වයක් සහතික කිරීම බව කොහොන වැඩිදුරටත් පැවසීය.",
        "ලිපියක් සමඟ මෝටර් රථ ගරාජයක දමා ගිය මාසයක් වයසැති ළදරුවා",
        "ඔබ සයිබර් අපරාධයට ගොදුරු වූවෙක්ද? සයිබර් අවකාශයේ සිදුවන අපරාධ මර්දනයට පොලිස් ඒකකය සූදානම්"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "චීනය",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "කොහොන",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "News 1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "චීනය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාලිත කොහොන",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "චීනය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "චීනය",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ග්ලෝබල් ටයිම්ස්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "චීනය",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "කොහොන",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "පසුගිය දශකය",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "චීනය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "දෙවැනි",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "චීනය",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "චීනය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "පසුගිය දශකය",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "කොහොන",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "චීනය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "චීනය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "චීනයේ කොමියුනිස්ට් පක්ෂය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "CPC",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "චීනය",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "කොහොන",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "මාසයක් වයසැති",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "සයිබර් අපරාධ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "சீனாவின் சாதனைகள் இலங்கைக்கு உத்வேகம்: தூதுவர் கொஹொனா",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); சீனாவின் சாதனைகளால் இலங்கை ஈர்க்கப்பட்டு, எதிர்காலத்தில் சீனாவைப் போன்ற ஒரு நாடாக மாறுவதற்கு அதன் சொந்த பலத்தைக் கண்டறிந்து அவற்றைச் செயல்படுத்த வேண்டும் என்று சீனாவுக்கான இலங்கைத் தூதுவர் பாலித கொஹொன தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "குளோபல் டைம்ஸுக்கு அளித்த பேட்டியில், இலங்கை தற்போது எண்ணற்ற சவால்களை எதிர்கொண்டு வருவதாகவும், சீனாவிடம் இருந்து கற்றுக்கொள்ள பல பாடங்கள் இருப்பதாகவும் தூதுவர் கூறினார்.",
        "கடந்த தசாப்தத்தில், சீனா வேகமாக வளர்ச்சியடைந்து, வெளிநாட்டு நேரடி முதலீட்டின் மிகப்பெரிய ஆதாரமாகவும், உலகின் இரண்டாவது பெரிய பொருளாதாரமாகவும் மாறியுள்ளதாகவும், இதன் போது, ​​சீனாவுடனான இலங்கையின் இருதரப்பு உறவுகள் கணிசமான அளவில் விரிவடைந்துள்ளதாகவும் தூதுவர் கொஹொன சுட்டிக்காட்டினார். .",
        "\"இன்று, இலங்கையின் அபிவிருத்தியை முன்னேற்றுவதற்கு இந்த பிணைப்புகளைப் பயன்படுத்த முடியும் என்று நாங்கள் நம்புகிறோம்,\" என்று அவர் கூறினார்.",
        "தூதுவரின் கூற்றுப்படி, கடந்த தசாப்தத்தில் இலங்கைக்கும் சீனாவுக்கும் இடையிலான உத்தியோகபூர்வ மற்றும் சிவில் தொடர்புகள் இரு நாடுகளிலும் பலவிதமான செயல்பாடுகள் மற்றும் திட்டங்களை உள்ளடக்கியது, மேலும் இரு மக்களும் ஒருவருக்கொருவர் நேர்மறையான தோற்றத்தைக் கொண்டுள்ளனர்.",
        "தூதுவர் கொஹொனா, சீனா உலகமயமாக்கலுக்கு வலுவான ஆதரவாளராக இருப்பதாகக் குறிப்பிடுகையில், இலங்கை உலகமயமாக்கலினால் பலனடைந்துள்ளது மற்றும் உறுதியாக ஆதரிக்கிறது, உலகமயமாக்கப்பட்ட இணைப்பு நாடுகளின் ஏற்றுமதிகள் அதிக லாபகரமான சந்தைகளை அடைய அனுமதிக்கிறது.",
        "\"சீன கம்யூனிஸ்ட் கட்சிக்கு (CPC) அர்ப்பணிப்புள்ள தலைமையின் கீழ் சீனா செய்தது குறிப்பிடத்தக்கது. இது தனித்துவமானது. வரலாற்றில் எந்த நேரத்திலும் தீவிர வறுமையை ஒழிக்கும் இலக்கை வேறு எந்த நாடும் அடையவில்லை, அதே நேரத்தில் சீனா இதை சிறப்பாக செய்துள்ளது,\" என்று அவர் கூறினார். குறிப்பிடப்பட்டுள்ளது.",
        "இலங்கையும் தீவிர வறுமையை அகற்றி, சிறந்த வாழ்க்கையை உருவாக்கி, அதன் மக்களுக்கு சிறந்த வாழ்க்கைத் தரத்தை உறுதிப்படுத்த விரும்புகிறது என்று கொஹொன மேலும் கூறினார்.",
        "கடிதத்துடன் மோட்டார் கேரேஜில் கைவிடப்பட்ட ஒரு மாத கைக்குழந்தை",
        "நீங்கள் சைபர் கிரைம் பாதிக்கப்பட்டவரா? சைபர்ஸ்பேஸ் குற்றங்களை ஒடுக்க போலீஸ் பிரிவு தயார்"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "சீனா",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "இலங்கை",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "கோஹோனா",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "News 1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சீனா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாலித கொஹோன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சீனா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சீனா",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "குளோபல் டைம்ஸ்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சீனா",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "கோஹோனா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "கடந்த தசாப்தம்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சீனா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இரண்டாவது",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கையின்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சீனா",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கையின்",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சீனா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "கடந்த தசாப்தம்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "கோஹோனா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "சீனா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "சீனா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சீன கம்யூனிஸ்ட் கட்சி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "CPC",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "சீனா",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "கோஹோனா",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஒரு மாத வயது",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "சைபர்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}