{
  "newspaper_id": "lankadeepa-lk",
  "url": "https://www.lankadeepa.lk/latest_news/ගෝනුන්ගේ-සිරුරු-නානුඔයේ-පාවෙයි/1-618389",
  "time_ut": 1660894794,
  "original_lang": "si",
  "original_title": "ගෝනුන්ගේ සිරුරු නානුඔයේ පාවෙයි",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "The bodies of the elk are floating in Nanu Oi",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "The bodies of a large number of elk roaming in the Hortonthanna Reserve are floating in the Nanuoya Ambewela Reservoir, according to the conservationists who are engaged in the conservation activities of the reservoir.",
        "Dhiwarain said that about ten elks die in the reservoir a week.",
        "A few hunters in the Ambewela area have trained and abandoned many dogs that bite the elk coming from Horton to find food and water and chase them into the reservoir. Says",
        "Dhiwarain claims that the bodies of many well-grown elk are currently floating on the Ambewela Reservoir, and due to the current situation, the environment of the reservoir has also been destroyed.",
        "The water released from Ambewela Reservoir is being used for drinking water and cultivation purposes in Welimada Rendapola and Talawakele area, and although the wildlife officers have been informed about this, the officers have not taken any action for this, according to the workers who are engaged in the excavation work of Ambewela Reservoir.",
        "Due to the current situation, there is a strong stench in the reservoir, and the owners of the Ambewela reservoir are asking the wildlife officials to take necessary steps to catch the dogs that hunt and kill the elk and take them to another area immediately."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Nanu Oi",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "the Hortonthanna Reserve",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Nanuoya Ambewela Reservoir",
            "label": "FAC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "a week",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Ambewela",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "elk",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Horton",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the Ambewela Reservoir",
            "label": "LOC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Ambewela Reservoir",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Welimada Rendapola",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Talawakele",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ambewela Reservoir",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Ambewela",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "ගෝනුන්ගේ සිරුරු නානුඔයේ පාවෙයි",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "හොර්ටන්තැන්න රක්ෂිතයේ සැරිසරන ගෝනුන් විශාල පිරිසකගේ සිරුරු නානුඔය අඹේවෙල ජලාශයේ පාවෙමින් තිබෙන බව එම ජලාශයේ ධිවර කටයුතු වල නියැලි සිටින ධිවරයින් කියා සිටියි.",
        "සතියකට ගෝනුන් දස දෙනෙකු පමණ ජලාශය තුල මිය යන බවයි ධිවරයින් කියා සිටියේ.",
        "අඹේවෙල ප්‍රදේශයේ දඩයම්කරුවන් කිහිප දෙනෙකු විසින් දඩයම් සදහා පුරුදු කර අත්හැර දමා ඇති සුනඛයින් රැසක් හොර්ටන්තැන්න සිට ආහාර සහ ජලය සොයා පැමිණෙන ගෝනුන් සපා කා ජලාශය තුලට පන්නා දමන බවත්, ඉතා ගැඹුරු අඹේවෙල ජලාශයේ එසේ පන්නා දමන ගෝනුන් දියේ ගිලි මියයන බව ජලාශයේ ධිවර කටයුතු වල නියැලි සිටින ධිවරයින් කියා සිටියි.",
        "කුඩා පැටවාගේ සිට හොදින් වැඩුණු ගෝනුන් රැසකගේ සිරුරු මේ වන විට අඹේවෙල ජලාශය මත නරක් වි පාවෙමින් පවතින බවත්, පවත්නා තත්ත්වය මත එම ජලාශයේ පරිසර විනාශයක්ද සිදු වි ඇති බවයි ධිවරයින් කියා සිටින්නේ.",
        "අඹේවෙල ජලාශයෙන් නිකුත් කරනු ලබන ජලය වැලිමඩ රෙන්දපොල සහ තලවකැලේ ප්‍රදේශයේ පානිය ජලය සහ වගා කටයුතු සදහා භාවිතා කරන බවත්,මේ පිලිබදව වනජිවි නිලධාරින් දැනුවත් කර තිබුණද ඒ සදහා මෙතෙක් එම නිලධාරින් කිසිදු පියවරක් ගෙන නොමැති බව අඹේවෙල ජලාශයේ ධිවර රැකියා වල නිරතව සිටින ධිවරයින් පවසයි.",
        "පවත්නා තත්ත්වය මත ජලාශයේ දැඩි දුගන්ධයක් හමන බවත්, ගෝනුන් දඩයම් කර මරා දමන සුනඛයින් අල්ලා වෙනත් ප්‍රදේශයකට කඩිනමින් රැගෙන යාමට අවශ්‍ය පියවර ගන්නා ලෙස අඹේවෙල ජලාශයේ ධිවරයින් වනජිවි නිලධාරින්ගෙන් ඉල්ලා සිටියි."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "නානු ඕයි",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "හෝර්ටන්තැන්න රක්ෂිතය",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "නානුඔය අඹේවෙල ජලාශය",
            "label": "FAC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "සතියක්",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "අඹේවෙල",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "එල්ක්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "හෝටන්",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "අඹේවෙල ජලාශය",
            "label": "LOC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "අඹේවෙල ජලාශය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "වැලිමඩ රේන්දපොල",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Talawakele",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "අඹේවෙල ජලාශය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "අඹේවෙල",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "நானு ஓயில் எலிகளின் உடல்கள் மிதக்கின்றன",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "நானுஓயா அம்பேவெல நீர்த்தேக்கத்தில் ஹொர்தொன்தன்ன காப்புக்காட்டில் சுற்றித் திரிந்த பெருந்தொகையான எல்க் மீன்களின் உடல்கள் மிதப்பதாக நீர்த்தேக்கத்தின் பாதுகாப்பு நடவடிக்கைகளில் ஈடுபட்டுள்ள பாதுகாவலர்கள் தெரிவித்துள்ளனர்.",
        "ஒரு வாரத்திற்கு சுமார் பத்து எலிகள் நீர்த்தேக்கத்தில் இறக்கின்றன என்று திவாரயின் கூறினார்.",
        "அம்பேவெல பிரதேசத்தில் உள்ள ஒரு சில வேட்டைக்காரர்கள் உணவு மற்றும் தண்ணீரைக் கண்டுபிடிக்க ஹோர்டனில் இருந்து வரும் எலிகளை கடிக்கும் பல நாய்களுக்கு பயிற்சி அளித்து விட்டு, அவற்றை நீர்த்தேக்கத்திற்குள் துரத்தியுள்ளனர்.",
        "அம்பேவெல நீர்த்தேக்கத்தில் தற்போது நன்கு வளர்ந்த பல எலிகளின் உடல்கள் மிதப்பதாகவும், தற்போதைய சூழ்நிலை காரணமாக நீர்த்தேக்கத்தின் சுற்றுச்சூழலும் அழிக்கப்பட்டுள்ளதாகவும் திவாரயின் கூறுகிறார்.",
        "அம்பேவெல நீர்த்தேக்கத்தில் இருந்து விடுவிக்கப்படும் நீர் வெலிமடை ரெண்டபொல மற்றும் தலவாக்கலை பிரதேசங்களின் குடிநீர் மற்றும் பயிர்ச்செய்கைக்கு பயன்படுத்தப்படுவதாகவும், இது தொடர்பில் வனஜீவராசி அதிகாரிகளுக்கு அறிவிக்கப்பட்டும் அதிகாரிகள் நடவடிக்கை எடுக்கவில்லை என தொழிலில் ஈடுபட்டுள்ள தொழிலாளர்கள் தெரிவிக்கின்றனர். அம்பேவெல நீர்த்தேக்கத்தின் அகழ்வு பணிகளில்.",
        "தற்போதைய நிலவரத்தால் நீர்த்தேக்கத்தில் கடும் துர்நாற்றம் வீசுவதுடன், வேட்டையாடி கொல்லும் நாய்களை பிடித்து வேறு பகுதிக்கு உடனடியாக கொண்டு செல்ல வனவிலங்கு அதிகாரிகள் நடவடிக்கை எடுக்குமாறு அம்பேவெல நீர்த்தேக்க உரிமையாளர்கள் கோரிக்கை விடுத்துள்ளனர்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "நானு ஓய்",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ஹார்டன்தன்னா காப்புக்காடு",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "நானுஓயா அம்பேவெல நீர்த்தேக்கம்",
            "label": "FAC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஒரு வாரம்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "அம்பேவெல",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "எல்க்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஹார்டன்",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "அம்பேவெல நீர்த்தேக்கம்",
            "label": "LOC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "அம்பேவெல நீர்த்தேக்கம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "வெலிமட ரெண்டபொல",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Talawakele",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "அம்பேவெல நீர்த்தேக்கம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "அம்பேவெல",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}