{
  "newspaper_id": "ada-lk",
  "url": "https://www.ada.lk/breaking_news/අද-පාර්ලිමේන්තුව-රැස්වෙයි---ජනපති-සටනට-එන-අයගේ-නාම-යෝජනා-කැඳවයි/11-395520",
  "time_ut": 1658196859,
  "original_lang": "si",
  "original_title": "අද පාර්ලිමේන්තුව රැස්වෙයි - ජනපති සටනට එන අයගේ නාම යෝජනා කැඳවයි",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Parliament will meet today - the President will call for nominations of those coming to the fray",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "The Parliament is scheduled to meet today to call for nominations from the candidates for the election to be held tomorrow in Parliament for the election of a President.",
        "With the resignation of Gotabaya Rajapaksa from the presidency, Mr. Ranil Wickramasinghe has constitutionally become the Acting President.",
        "Accordingly, nominations are being invited from members of parliament today to appoint a president for the vacant post of president.",
        "Acting President Ranil Wickramasinghe, opposition leader Sajith Premadama, Anura Kumara Dissanayake of the National People's Power and Dallas Alahapperuma representing the independent group of the Sri Lanka Podujana Peramuna have already announced that they will join the polls as candidates."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Parliament",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "today",
          "label": "DATE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "tomorrow",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Gotabaya Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickramasinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickramasinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sajith Premadama",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Anura",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kumara Dissanayake",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the National People's Power",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Dallas Alahapperuma",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "Podujana Peramuna",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "අද පාර්ලිමේන්තුව රැස්වෙයි - ජනපති සටනට එන අයගේ නාම යෝජනා කැඳවයි",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "හෙට දිනයේදි පාර්ලිමේන්තුවේදී ජනපතිවරයෙක් තෝරා ගැනීම වෙනුවෙන් පැවැත්විමට නියමිත ඡන්ද විමසිම සඳහා එක්වන අපේක්ෂකයන්ගෙන් නාම යෝජනා කැඳවිම වෙනුවෙන් අද දිනයේදි පාර්ලිමේන්තුව රැස්වීමට නියමිතව තිබේ.",
        "ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ මහතා ජනපතිධුරයෙන් ඉල්ලා අස්විමත් සමග වැඩබලන ජනපති ලෙස රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතා ව්‍යවස්ථානුකූලව පත්ව තිබේ.",
        "ඒ අනුව හිස්ව ඇති ජනපතිධුරය වෙනුවෙන් ජනපතිවරයෙක් පත්කර ගැනීම වෙනුවෙන් අද දිනයේදී පාර්ලිමේනතු මන්ත්‍රීවරුන්ගෙන් නාම යෝජන කැඳවයි.",
        "වැඩබලන ජනපති රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ, විපක්ෂනායක සජිත් ප්‍රේමදාම, ජාතික ජනබලවේගයේ අනුර කුමාර දිසානායක හා ශ්‍රි ලංකා පොදුජන පෙරමුණේ ස්වාධීන කණ්ඩායම නියෝජනය කරමින් ඩලස් අලහප්පෙරුම යන මහත්වරුන් අපේක්ෂකයන් ලෙස ඡන්ද විමසීමට එක්වන බවට දැනටමත් ප්‍රකාශ කර තිබේ."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "අද",
          "label": "DATE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "හෙට",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "සජිත් ප්‍රේමදාම",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "අනුර",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "කුමාර දිසානායක",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජාතික ජනතා බලය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඩලස් අලහප්පෙරුම",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "පොදුජන පෙරමුණ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "பாராளுமன்றம் இன்று கூடும் - ஜனாதிபதி வேட்புமனு தாக்கல் செய்ய வருபவர்களை அழைப்பார்",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "ஜனாதிபதியை தெரிவுசெய்வதற்காக பாராளுமன்றத்தில் நாளை நடைபெறவுள்ள தேர்தலுக்கான வேட்புமனுக்களை கோருவதற்காக இன்று பாராளுமன்றம் கூடவுள்ளது.",
        "ஜனாதிபதி பதவியிலிருந்து கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ச ராஜினாமா செய்ததன் மூலம், திரு.",
        "இதன்படி வெற்றிடமாகவுள்ள ஜனாதிபதி பதவிக்கு ஜனாதிபதி ஒருவரை நியமிப்பதற்கு பாராளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர்களிடமிருந்து இன்று வேட்புமனுக்கள் கோரப்படுகின்றன.",
        "பதில் ஜனாதிபதி ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க, எதிர்க்கட்சித் தலைவர் சஜித் பிரேமதாம, தேசிய மக்கள் சக்தியின் அனுரகுமார திஸாநாயக்க மற்றும் ஸ்ரீலங்கா பொதுஜன பெரமுனவின் சுயேச்சைக் குழுவை பிரதிநிதித்துவப்படுத்தும் டலஸ் அழகப்பெரும ஆகியோர் வேட்பாளராக களமிறங்கப் போவதாக ஏற்கனவே அறிவித்துள்ளனர்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "இன்று",
          "label": "DATE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "நாளை",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "சஜித் பிரேமதாம",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "அனுர",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "குமார திஸாநாயக்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "தேசிய மக்கள் சக்தி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "டலஸ் அழகப்பெரும",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "பொதுஜன பெரமுன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}