{
  "newspaper_id": "news-first-lk",
  "url": "https://www.newsfirst.lk/2022/08/29/sri-lanka-calls-for-eoi-for-srilankan-catering-ground-handling/",
  "time_ut": 1661758740,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Sri Lanka calls for EOI for SriLankan Catering & Ground Handling",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Sri Lanka calls for EOI for SriLankan Catering & Ground Handling",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); Sri Lanka has decided to call for Expression of Interest to revive its ailing National Carrier, SriLankan Airlines.",
        "Minister Nimal Siripala De Silva said that 49% shares in SriLankan Catering will be offered to the private sector for investments.",
        "In addition, Sri Lanka will also offer 49% of SriLankan Airlines Ground Handling while retaining 51% with the state.",
        "The Minister said that if Sri Lanka offers more than 50%, the country would lose its landing rights, however, if Sri Lankan investors join together and make an offer for 51% the government would consider such an investments.",
        "Aviation Minister Nimal Siripala de Silva also revealed that the total debt of Srilankan Airlines is USD 1.126 Billion which is approximately Rs. 401 Billion.",
        "Sri Lanka calls for EOI for SriLankan Catering & Ground Handling",
        "Over 1,000 people killed by Pakistan monsoon rains and floods"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Sri Lanka",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "EOI for SriLankan Catering & Ground Handling",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "News 1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "National Carrier",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "SriLankan Airlines",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Nimal Siripala De Silva",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "49%",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "SriLankan Catering",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "49%",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "SriLankan Airlines",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ground Handling",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "51%",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "more than 50%",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lankan",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "51%",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Nimal Siripala de Silva",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Srilankan Airlines",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "USD 1.126 Billion",
            "label": "MONEY"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "EOI for SriLankan Catering & Ground Handling",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "1,000",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Pakistan",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "SriLankan Catering & Ground Handling සඳහා ශ්‍රී ලංකාව EOI ඉල්ලා සිටී",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); ශ්‍රී ලංකාව සිය රෝගී ජාතික ගුවන් සේවය වන ශ්‍රී ලංකන් ගුවන් සේවය යළි පණ ගැන්වීම සඳහා උනන්දුව ප්‍රකාශ කිරීම කැඳවීමට තීරණය කර ඇත.",
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකන් කේටරින් සමාගමේ 49%ක කොටස් ආයෝජන සඳහා පෞද්ගලික අංශයට ලබා දෙන බව අමාත්‍ය නිමල් සිරිපාල ද සිල්වා මහතා පැවසීය.",
        "මීට අමතරව, ශ්‍රී ලංකන් එයාර්ලයින්ස් ග්‍රවුන්ඩ් හැන්ඩ්ලින් වලින් 49%ක් ශ්‍රී ලංකාව විසින් පිරිනමනු ලබන අතර 51%ක් රජය සමඟ රඳවා තබා ගනී.",
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකාව 50% ට වඩා වැඩි මුදලක් ඉදිරිපත් කළහොත් රටට ගොඩබෑමේ අයිතිය අහිමි වන බවත් කෙසේ වෙතත් ශ්‍රී ලංකා ආයෝජකයින් එකතු වී 51%කට යෝජනාවක් ඉදිරිපත් කළහොත් එවැනි ආයෝජනයක් සම්බන්ධයෙන් රජය සලකා බලන බවත් අමාත්‍යවරයා පැවසීය.",
        "ශ්‍රීලංකන් ගුවන් සමාගමේ මුළු ණය ප්‍රමාණය ඇමෙරිකානු ඩොලර් බිලියන 1.126ක් වන අතර එය ආසන්න වශයෙන් රුපියල් කෝටි 1126ක් වන බවද ගුවන් සේවා ඇමැති නිමල් සිරිපාල ද සිල්වා මහතා අනාවරණය කළේය. බිලියන 401 කි.",
        "SriLankan Catering & Ground Handling සඳහා ශ්‍රී ලංකාව EOI ඉල්ලා සිටී",
        "පකිස්ථානයේ මෝසම් වැසි සහ ගංවතුර හේතුවෙන් 1000කට අධික පිරිසක් මිය ගියහ"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකන් කේටරින් සහ බිම් හැසිරවීම සඳහා EOI",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "News 1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජාතික ගුවන් සේවය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකන් ගුවන් සේවය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "නිමල් සිරිපාල ද සිල්වා",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "49%",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකන් කේටරින්",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "49%",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකන් ගුවන් සේවය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "බිම් හැසිරවීම",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "51%",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "50% ට වඩා",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලාංකික",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "51%",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "නිමල් සිරිපාල ද සිල්වා",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකන් ගුවන් සේවය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඩොලර් බිලියන 1.126 කි",
            "label": "MONEY"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකන් කේටරින් සහ බිම් හැසිරවීම සඳහා EOI",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "1,000 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "පකිස්ථානය",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "SriLankan Catering & Ground Handling க்கான EOIக்கு இலங்கை அழைப்பு விடுத்துள்ளது",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); நலிவடைந்துள்ள அதன் தேசிய விமான சேவையான ஸ்ரீலங்கன் ஏர்லைன்ஸை மீண்டும் புதுப்பிக்க ஆர்வத்தை வெளிப்படுத்துமாறு இலங்கை தீர்மானித்துள்ளது.",
        "ஸ்ரீலங்கன் கேட்டரிங் நிறுவனத்தின் 49% பங்குகள் முதலீடுகளுக்காக தனியாருக்கு வழங்கப்படும் என அமைச்சர் நிமல் சிறிபால டி சில்வா தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "மேலும், ஸ்ரீலங்கன் ஏர்லைன்ஸ் தரைவழிக் கையாளுதலில் 49% வழங்கும் அதே வேளையில், 51% அரசிடம் இருக்கும்.",
        "இலங்கை 50% க்கு மேல் வழங்கினால், நாடு தரையிறங்கும் உரிமையை இழக்க நேரிடும் என்றும், எனினும், இலங்கை முதலீட்டாளர்கள் ஒன்றிணைந்து 51% வழங்கினால், அத்தகைய முதலீடுகளை அரசாங்கம் பரிசீலிக்கும் என்றும் அமைச்சர் கூறினார்.",
        "ஸ்ரீலங்கன் எயார்லைன்ஸ் நிறுவனத்தின் மொத்தக் கடன் 1.126 பில்லியன் அமெரிக்க டொலர்கள் எனவும், இது தோராயமாக ரூ. 401 பில்லியன்.",
        "SriLankan Catering & Ground Handling க்கான EOIக்கு இலங்கை அழைப்பு விடுத்துள்ளது",
        "பாகிஸ்தானில் பெய்த மழை மற்றும் வெள்ளத்தால் 1,000க்கும் மேற்பட்டோர் உயிரிழந்துள்ளனர்"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "இலங்கை",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "ஸ்ரீலங்கன் கேட்டரிங் & கிரவுண்ட் கையாளுதலுக்கான EOI",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "News 1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "தேசிய கேரியர்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஸ்ரீலங்கன் ஏர்லைன்ஸ்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "நிமல் சிறிபால டி சில்வா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "49%",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஸ்ரீலங்கன் கேட்டரிங்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "49%",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஸ்ரீலங்கன் ஏர்லைன்ஸ்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "தரையில் கையாளும்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "51%",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "50%க்கு மேல்",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "51%",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "நிமல் சிறிபால டி சில்வா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஸ்ரீலங்கன் ஏர்லைன்ஸ்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "USD 1.126 பில்லியன்",
            "label": "MONEY"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஸ்ரீலங்கன் கேட்டரிங் & கிரவுண்ட் கையாளுதலுக்கான EOI",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "1,000",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாகிஸ்தான்",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}