{
  "newspaper_id": "ada-derana-lk",
  "url": "http://www.adaderana.lk/news/83702/asia-cup-likely-to-be-shifted-from-sri-lanka-to-uae",
  "time_ut": 1658048880,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Asia Cup ‘likely’ to be shifted from Sri Lanka to UAE",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Asia Cup ‘likely’ to be shifted from Sri Lanka to UAE",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "The Asia Cup is “likely” to be moved out of Sri Lanka in the wake of political unrest in the island nation, SLC secretary Mohan de Silva said on Sunday, adding that the tournament could be played in the UAE.",
        "Sri Lanka, which has been battling an economic crisis, has witnessed widespread protests against the government for weeks.",
        "However, the situation worsened with president Gotabaya Rajapaksa fleeing the country on a military jet.",
        "“The Asia Cup is very likely that it will be held in the UAE,” Sri Lanka Cricket secretary de Silva told PTI when asked about a possible change in the venue of the T20 tournament.",
        "The dates for the six-team tournament are expected to remain the same as scheduled earlier from August 26 to September 11.",
        "A qualifier will also take place before the main event with Hong Kong, Singapore, Kuwait and UAE battling out for the one qualification spot.",
        "Afghanistan, Sri Lanka, Pakistan, India and Bangladesh will be the five full member teams.",
        "With Australia tour of Sri Lanka going off smoothly and Pakistan currently playing Test cricket in Sri Lanka, there were hopes that the SLC might be able to host the continental event.",
        "The tournament serves as good preparation for the Asian teams ahead of the T20 World Cup in Australia in October-November.",
        "An official announcement from the Asian Cricket Council (ACC) on the change in tournament venue is expected soon. The ACC is headed by BCCI secretary Jay Shah.",
        "Pakistan Cricket Board on Saturday said that it wanted Asia Cup to be played in Sri Lanka.",
        "“Our first preference is to support Sri Lanka and play the Asia Cup there. If this tournament does not take place in Sri Lanka, it will be a huge cricketing and financial loss for them. Australia’s recent tour of Sri Lanka went off without any problems,” said PCB chief executive Faisal Hasnain in a statement.",
        "“Similarly, there have been no issues with the ongoing Pakistan tour of Sri Lanka as we are constantly in touch with Sri Lanka Cricket (SLC) and our embassy in the country.",
        "“Our discussions with the ACC representatives have suggested that the tournament is on track at the moment as they are monitoring the situation very carefully and we will support their decision.” -PTI"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Asia Cup",
          "label": "EVENT"
        },
        {
          "text": "Sri Lanka",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "UAE",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "The Asia Cup",
            "label": "EVENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "SLC",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Mohan de Silva",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sunday",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "weeks",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Gotabaya Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "“The Asia Cup",
            "label": "WORK_OF_ART"
          },
          {
            "text": "de Silva",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "T20",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "six",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "August 26 to September 11",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Hong Kong",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Singapore",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kuwait",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "one",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Afghanistan",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Pakistan",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "India",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Bangladesh",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "five",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Australia",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Pakistan",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Asian",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "the T20 World Cup",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Australia",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "October-November",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the Asian Cricket Council",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ACC",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ACC",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "BCCI",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Jay Shah",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Pakistan Cricket Board",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Saturday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Asia Cup",
            "label": "EVENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "first",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Asia Cup",
            "label": "EVENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Australia",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "PCB",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Faisal Hasnain",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Pakistan",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ACC",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "ආසියානු කුසලානය ශ්‍රී ලංකාවෙන් එක්සත් අරාබි එමීර් රාජ්‍යයට ගෙන යාමට බොහෝ දුරට ඉඩ තිබේ",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "දිවයිනේ පවතින දේශපාලන නොසන්සුන්තාවය හේතුවෙන් ආසියානු කුසලානය ශ්‍රී ලංකාවෙන් ඉවත් කිරීමට බොහෝ දුරට ඉඩ ඇති බව ශ්‍රී ලංකා ක්‍රිකට් ලේකම් මොහාන් ද සිල්වා ඉරිදා ප්‍රකාශ කළේ තරඟාවලිය එක්සත් අරාබි එමීර් රාජ්‍යයේදී පැවැත්විය හැකි බවයි.",
        "ආර්ථික අර්බුදයකට මුහුණ දී සිටින ශ්‍රී ලංකාව සති ගනනාවක් තිස්සේ රජයට එරෙහිව පුලුල්ව පැතිරුනු විරෝධතා දැක තිබේ.",
        "කෙසේ වෙතත්, ජනාධිපති ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ හමුදා ජෙට් යානයකින් රටින් පලා යාමත් සමඟ තත්ත්වය වඩාත් නරක අතට හැරුණි.",
        "“ආසියානු කුසලානය එක්සත් අරාබි එමීර් රාජ්‍යයේ පැවැත්වීමට බොහෝ දුරට ඉඩ තිබේ,” ශ්‍රී ලංකා ක්‍රිකට් ලේකම් ද සිල්වා පීටීඅයි වෙත ප්‍රකාශ කළේ T20 තරඟාවලිය පැවැත්වෙන ස්ථානයේ සිදුවිය හැකි වෙනසක් පිළිබඳව විමසූ විටය.",
        "කණ්ඩායම් හයක තරඟාවලියේ දිනයන් අගෝස්තු 26 සිට සැප්තැම්බර් 11 දක්වා කලින් නියමිත පරිදිම පවතිනු ඇතැයි අපේක්ෂා කෙරේ.",
        "ප්‍රධාන ඉසව්වට පෙර සුදුසුකම් ලැබීමේ තරගයක් ද පැවැත්වෙන අතර හොංකොං, සිංගප්පූරුව, කුවේට් සහ එක්සත් අරාබි එමීර් රාජ්‍යය එක් සුදුසුකම් ලැබීමේ ස්ථානයක් සඳහා සටන් කරයි.",
        "ඇෆ්ගනිස්ථානය, ශ්‍රී ලංකාව, පකිස්ථානය, ඉන්දියාව සහ බංග්ලාදේශය පූර්ණ සාමාජික කණ්ඩායම් පහයි.",
        "ඕස්ට්‍රේලියානු ශ්‍රී ලංකා සංචාරය සහ පාකිස්තානය මේ වන විට ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ ටෙස්ට් ක්‍රිකට් ක්‍රීඩා කිරීම හේතුවෙන් ශ්‍රී ලංකා ක්‍රිකට් ආයතනය මහද්වීපික ඉසව්ව සත්කාරකත්වය ලබා දෙනු ඇතැයි බලාපොරොත්තු විය.",
        "ඔක්තෝබර්-නොවැම්බර් මාසවල ඕස්ට්‍රේලියාවේ පැවැත්වෙන T20 ලෝක කුසලානයට පෙර මෙම තරඟාවලිය ආසියානු කණ්ඩායම් සඳහා හොඳ සූදානමක් ලෙස සේවය කරයි.",
        "තරඟාවලියේ ස්ථානය වෙනස් කිරීම පිළිබඳව ආසියානු ක්‍රිකට් කවුන්සිලයේ (ACC) නිල නිවේදනය ළඟදීම බලාපොරොත්තු වේ. ACC හි ප්‍රධානියා BCCI ලේකම් ජේ ෂා විසිනි.",
        "පාකිස්ථාන ක්‍රිකට් ආයතනය සෙනසුරාදා ප්‍රකාශ කළේ ආසියානු කුසලානය ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ පැවැත්වීමට අවශ්‍ය බවයි.",
        "“අපේ පළමු මනාපය ශ්‍රී ලංකාවට සහය වෙමින් එහි දී ආසියානු කුසලානය ක්‍රීඩා කිරීමයි. මෙම තරගාවලිය ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ නොපැවැත්වුවහොත් එය ඔවුන්ට විශාල ක්‍රිකට් සහ මූල්‍යමය පාඩුවක් වනු ඇත. ඔස්ට්‍රේලියාවේ මෑත කාලීන ශ්‍රී ලංකා සංචාරය කිසිදු ගැටලුවකින් තොරව නිමා විය.",
        "“ඒ හා සමානව, අපි ශ්‍රී ලංකා ක්‍රිකට් (ශ්‍රී ලංකා ක්‍රිකට්) සහ රටෙහි ඇති අපගේ තානාපති කාර්යාලය සමඟ නිරන්තරයෙන් සම්බන්ධ වී සිටින බැවින් දැනට පවතින ශ්‍රී ලංකා පාකිස්ථාන සංචාරය සම්බන්ධයෙන් කිසිදු ගැටළුවක් නොමැත.",
        "\"ACC නියෝජිතයන් සමඟ අපගේ සාකච්ඡා යෝජනා කර ඇත්තේ ඔවුන් තත්ත්වය ඉතා සුපරීක්ෂාකාරීව නිරීක්ෂණය කරමින් සිටින අතර අපි ඔවුන්ගේ තීරණයට සහය දක්වන බැවින් තරඟාවලිය මේ මොහොතේ නියමිත පරිදි පවතින බවයි.\" - පී.ටී.අයි"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ආසියානු කුසලානය",
          "label": "EVENT"
        },
        {
          "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "UAE",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ආසියානු කුසලානය",
            "label": "EVENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකා ක්‍රිකට් ආයතනය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "මොහාන් ද සිල්වා",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉරිදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "සති",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "“ආසියානු කුසලානය",
            "label": "WORK_OF_ART"
          },
          {
            "text": "ද සිල්වා",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "T20",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "හය",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "අගෝස්තු 26 සිට සැප්තැම්බර් 11 දක්වා",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "හොංකොං",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "සිංගප්පූරුව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "කුවේට්",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "එක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ඇෆ්ගනිස්ථානය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "පකිස්ථානය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "බංග්ලාදේශය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "පහ",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ඕස්ට්රේලියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "පකිස්ථානය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ආසියානු",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "T20 ලෝක කුසලානය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඕස්ට්රේලියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඔක්තෝබර්-නොවැම්බර්",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ආසියානු ක්‍රිකට් කවුන්සිලය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ACC",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ACC",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "BCCI",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජේ ෂා",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "පාකිස්තාන ක්‍රිකට් මණ්ඩලය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "සෙනසුරාදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ආසියානු කුසලානය",
            "label": "EVENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "පළමුවන",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ආසියානු කුසලානය",
            "label": "EVENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඕස්ට්රේලියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "PCB",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ෆයිසාල් හස්නයින්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "පකිස්ථානය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ACC",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "ஆசிய கோப்பை இலங்கையில் இருந்து ஐக்கிய அரபு எமிரேட்ஸுக்கு மாற்றப்பட வாய்ப்பு உள்ளது",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "தீவு நாட்டில் நிலவும் அரசியல் அமைதியின்மை காரணமாக ஆசிய கோப்பை இலங்கையை விட்டு நகர்த்தப்பட வாய்ப்புள்ளது என்று SLC செயலாளர் மொஹான் டி சில்வா ஞாயிற்றுக்கிழமை தெரிவித்தார், போட்டியை ஐக்கிய அரபு எமிரேட்ஸில் விளையாடலாம் என்று கூறினார்.",
        "பொருளாதார நெருக்கடியில் சிக்கித் தவிக்கும் இலங்கை, அரசாங்கத்திற்கு எதிராக பல வாரங்களாகப் பரவலான போராட்டங்களைக் கண்டுள்ளது.",
        "எவ்வாறாயினும், ஜனாதிபதி கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ஷ இராணுவ ஜெட் விமானத்தில் நாட்டை விட்டு வெளியேறியதால் நிலைமை மோசமடைந்தது.",
        "\"ஆசியா கோப்பை ஐக்கிய அரபு எமிரேட்ஸில் நடைபெறுவதற்கான வாய்ப்புகள் அதிகம்\" என்று இலங்கை கிரிக்கெட் செயலாளர் டி சில்வா பிடிஐக்கு டி20 போட்டி நடைபெறும் இடத்தில் சாத்தியமான மாற்றம் குறித்து கேட்டபோது கூறினார்.",
        "ஆறு அணிகள் பங்கேற்கும் போட்டிக்கான தேதிகள் ஆகஸ்ட் 26 முதல் செப்டம்பர் 11 வரை திட்டமிடப்பட்டதைப் போலவே இருக்கும்.",
        "ஹாங்காங், சிங்கப்பூர், குவைத் மற்றும் ஐக்கிய அரபு எமிரேட்ஸ் ஆகிய அணிகள் ஒரு தகுதி இடத்திற்குப் போராடும் முக்கிய போட்டிக்கு முன் ஒரு தகுதிச் சுற்றும் நடைபெறும்.",
        "ஆப்கானிஸ்தான், இலங்கை, பாகிஸ்தான், இந்தியா மற்றும் வங்கதேசம் ஆகிய ஐந்து முழு உறுப்பினர் அணிகளாக இருக்கும்.",
        "அவுஸ்திரேலியாவின் இலங்கை சுற்றுப்பயணம் சுமூகமாக நடந்து கொண்டிருப்பதாலும், பாகிஸ்தான் தற்போது இலங்கையில் டெஸ்ட் கிரிக்கெட்டை விளையாடுவதாலும், SLC கண்ட நிகழ்வை நடத்தலாம் என்ற நம்பிக்கை இருந்தது.",
        "அக்டோபர்-நவம்பரில் ஆஸ்திரேலியாவில் நடைபெறவுள்ள டி20 உலகக் கோப்பைக்கு முன்னதாக ஆசிய அணிகளுக்கு இந்தப் போட்டி நல்லதொரு தயாரிப்பாக விளங்குகிறது.",
        "போட்டி நடைபெறும் இடம் மாற்றம் குறித்து ஆசிய கிரிக்கெட் கவுன்சிலின் (ஏசிசி) அதிகாரப்பூர்வ அறிவிப்பு விரைவில் வெளியாகும் என எதிர்பார்க்கப்படுகிறது. ஏசிசி பிசிசிஐ செயலாளர் ஜெய் ஷா தலைமையில் உள்ளது.",
        "ஆசிய கோப்பையை இலங்கையில் நடத்த விரும்புவதாக பாகிஸ்தான் கிரிக்கெட் வாரியம் சனிக்கிழமை தெரிவித்துள்ளது.",
        "“எங்கள் முதல் விருப்பம் இலங்கைக்கு ஆதரவளித்து அங்கு ஆசிய கோப்பையை விளையாட வேண்டும். இந்தப் போட்டி இலங்கையில் நடைபெறவில்லை என்றால், அது அவர்களுக்கு மிகப்பெரிய கிரிக்கெட் மற்றும் நிதி இழப்பாகும். அவுஸ்திரேலியாவின் இலங்கைக்கான சமீபத்திய சுற்றுப்பயணம் எந்த பிரச்சனையும் இன்றி முடிந்தது” என்று பிசிபி தலைமை நிர்வாகி பைசல் ஹஸ்னைன் ஒரு அறிக்கையில் தெரிவித்துள்ளார்.",
        "“அதேபோல், இலங்கை கிரிக்கெட் (எஸ்.எல்.சி) மற்றும் நாட்டில் உள்ள எங்கள் தூதரகத்துடன் நாங்கள் தொடர்ந்து தொடர்பில் இருப்பதால், இலங்கையில் நடந்து வரும் பாகிஸ்தான் சுற்றுப்பயணத்தில் எந்தப் பிரச்சினையும் இல்லை.",
        "\"ஏசிசி பிரதிநிதிகளுடனான எங்கள் கலந்துரையாடல்கள், அவர்கள் நிலைமையை மிகவும் கவனமாகக் கண்காணித்து வருவதால், போட்டிகள் தற்போது பாதையில் இருப்பதாகத் தெரிவித்துள்ளன, மேலும் அவர்களின் முடிவை நாங்கள் ஆதரிப்போம்.\" -பிடிஐ"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ஆசிய கோப்பை",
          "label": "EVENT"
        },
        {
          "text": "இலங்கை",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "ஐக்கிய அரபு எமிரேட்ஸ்",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ஆசிய கோப்பை",
            "label": "EVENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "எஸ்.எல்.சி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "மொஹான் டி சில்வா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஞாயிற்றுக்கிழமை",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "வாரங்கள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "“ஆசியா கோப்பை",
            "label": "WORK_OF_ART"
          },
          {
            "text": "டி சில்வா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "டி20",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஆறு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆகஸ்ட் 26 முதல் செப்டம்பர் 11 வரை",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஹாங்காங்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சிங்கப்பூர்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "குவைத்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஒன்று",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஆப்கானிஸ்தான்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாகிஸ்தான்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்தியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "பங்களாதேஷ்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஐந்து",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஆஸ்திரேலியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாகிஸ்தான்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஆசிய",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "டி20 உலகக் கோப்பை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆஸ்திரேலியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "அக்டோபர்-நவம்பர்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஆசிய கிரிக்கெட் கவுன்சில்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஏசிசி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஏசிசி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "பிசிசிஐ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜெய் ஷா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பாகிஸ்தான் கிரிக்கெட் வாரியம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "சனிக்கிழமை",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆசிய கோப்பை",
            "label": "EVENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "முதலில்",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆசிய கோப்பை",
            "label": "EVENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆஸ்திரேலியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "பிசிபி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "பைசல் ஹஸ்னைன்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பாகிஸ்தான்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஏசிசி",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}