{
  "newspaper_id": "daily-mirror-lk",
  "url": "https://www.dailymirror.lk/latest_news/PTA-a-must-to-tackle-terrorism-Cabinet-Spokesman/342-243581",
  "time_ut": 1661264930,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "PTA, a must to tackle terrorism: Cabinet Spokesman",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "PTA, a must to tackle terrorism: Cabinet Spokesman",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "The government today said that the Criminal Investigations Department (CID) sleuths are questioning several suspects including the convener of the IUSF Wasantha Mudalige detained under the provisions of Prevention of Terrorism Act (PTA) to determine whether there was a conspiracy to topple the government.",
        "The Prevention of Terrorism Act (PTA) was a must to tackle the recent wave of terrorism and as such no one would be arrested or charges filed against any Sri Lankan citizen who has not committed any act of violence during the protest campaigns, cabinet spokesman, Minister Bandula Gunawardana said addressing the weekly cabinet press briefing.",
        "He also said that the Convenor of the IUSF and two other IUSF members Ven. Galwewa Siridhamma Thera and Hashan Jeewantha would be detained under the provisions of Prevention of Terrorism Act (PTA) until the recording of their statements are concluded.",
        "The CID was still in the process of questioning them for further information on the matter, he added.",
        "He also said that the government was in the process of replacing the Prevention of Terrorism Act (PTA) with a new National Security Act (NSA) and Justice Minister Dr. Wijeyadasa Rajapakshe was attending to the task.",
        "Minister Gunawardana said the dastardly acts of violence that took place on May 9 this year was a stigma not only to the country but to the parliamentary democracy practiced in Sri Lanka for nearly 100 years.",
        "“I have never engaged in any kind of law breaking, violence or unbecoming action. I have never obtained the house allowance paid to ministers or lived in official residences. Never obtained an official weapon (revolver) for my personal use. I am living in a house built with earnings I raised from my blood and sweat. But what happened on May 9th. My house was set on fire destroying it totally with two of my vehicles. My family lived in total fear for several weeks. If these protesters do not let a law abiding, innocent Sri Lankan like me to live in peace with my family in my own house, who are they? Should not the PTA apply on them and take punitive action against them under the law of the land?” Minister Gunawardana asked.",
        "\"During the reign of terror on May 9th, residences and properties of 72 Parliamentarians, ministers and deputy and state ministers’ including houses had been subjected to arson attacks by hooligans. The SLPP Parliamentarian Amarakeerti Atukorale together with his bodyguard were murdered in a beastly manner incomprehensible. Should not these murderers be charged under the PTA?\" he asked.",
        "Minister Gunawardana assured that charges will be framed under the PTA only on those who have committed extreme violence on innocent civilians and politicians. Those who have committed petty crimes would be charged under the normal law, namely under the civil procedure code or criminal procedure code. (Sandun Jayasekera)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "PTA",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "Cabinet",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Criminal Investigations Department",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "CID",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Wasantha Mudalige",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Prevention of Terrorism Act",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "PTA",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "The Prevention of Terrorism Act",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "PTA",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lankan",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Bandula Gunawardana",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "weekly",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "two",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "IUSF",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ven",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Galwewa Siridhamma Thera",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Hashan",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Prevention of Terrorism Act",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "PTA",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "CID",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the Prevention of Terrorism Act",
            "label": "LAW"
          },
          {
            "text": "PTA",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "National Security Act",
            "label": "LAW"
          },
          {
            "text": "NSA",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Justice",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Wijeyadasa Rajapakshe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Gunawardana",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "May 9 this year",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "nearly 100 years",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "May 9th",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "two",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "several weeks",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lankan",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "PTA",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Gunawardana",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "May 9th",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "72",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliamentarians",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "PTA",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Gunawardana",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "PTA",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sandun Jayasekera",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "ත්‍රස්තවාදය මැඩලීමට ත්‍රස්තවාදය වැළැක්වීමේ පනත අත්‍යවශ්‍ය වේ: කැබිනට් ප්‍රකාශක",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "ත්‍රස්තවාදය වැලැක්වීමේ පනතේ (PTA) විධිවිධාන යටතේ රඳවාගෙන සිටින අන්තර් විශ්වවිද්‍යාල ශිෂ්‍ය බල මණ්ඩලයේ කැඳවුම්කරු වසන්ත මුදලිගේ ඇතුළු සැකකරුවන් කිහිප දෙනෙකුගෙන් රජය පෙරලීමේ කුමන්ත්‍රණයක් ක්‍රියාත්මක වූයේ දැයි සොයා බැලීමට අපරාධ පරීක්ෂණ දෙපාර්තමේන්තුවේ (CID) නිලධාරීන් ප්‍රශ්න කරමින් සිටින බව රජය පවසයි.",
        "මෑත කාලීන ත්‍රස්තවාදී රැල්ල මැඩපැවැත්වීම සඳහා ත්‍රස්තවාදය වැළැක්වීමේ පනත (PTA) අත්‍යවශ්‍ය වූවක් වූ අතර එම නිසා විරෝධතා ව්‍යාපාරවලදී කිසිදු ප්‍රචණ්ඩ ක්‍රියාවක් නොකළ ශ්‍රී ලාංකික පුරවැසියෙකු අත්අඩංගුවට ගැනීමක් හෝ චෝදනා ගොනු කිරීමක් සිදු නොකරන බව කැබිනට් ප්‍රකාශක සතිපතා පැවැත්වෙන කැබිනට් තීරණ දැනුම්දීමේ මාධ්‍ය හමුවට එක්වෙමින් අමාත්‍ය බන්දුල ගුණවර්ධන මහතා මේ බව පැවසීය.",
        "අන්තර් විශ්වවිද්‍යාල ශිෂ්‍ය බල මණ්ඩලයේ කැඳවුම්කරු සහ තවත් අන්තර් විශ්වවිද්‍යාල ශිෂ්‍ය බලමණ්ඩලයේ සාමාජිකයින් දෙදෙනෙකු වන පූජ්‍ය පූජ්‍ය පූජ්‍ය පූජ්‍ය පූජ්‍ය එස්. ගල්වැව සිරිධම්ම හිමියන් සහ හෂාන් ජීවන්ත ත්‍රස්තවාදය වැළැක්වීමේ පනතේ (PTA) ප්‍රතිපාදන යටතේ ප්‍රකාශ සටහන් කර ගැනීම අවසන් වනතුරු රඳවා තබා ගැනීමට නියමිතයි.",
        "මේ සම්බන්ධයෙන් වැඩිදුර තොරතුරු දැනගැනීම සඳහා අපරාධ පරීක්ෂණ දෙපාර්තමේන්තුව ඔවුන්ගෙන් තවදුරටත් ප්‍රශ්න කරමින් සිටින බවද ඔහු වැඩිදුරටත් පැවසීය.",
        "ත්‍රස්තවාදය වැළැක්වීමේ පනත (PTA) වෙනුවට නව ජාතික ආරක්ෂක පනතක් (NSA) ගෙන ඒමට රජය කටයුතු කරමින් සිටින බවත් අධිකරණ අමාත්‍ය ආචාර්ය විජයදාස රාජපක්ෂ එම කාර්යයට සහභාගී වෙමින් සිටින බවත් ඔහු පැවසීය.",
        "මේ වසරේ මැයි 9 වැනිදා සිදු වූ දරුණු ප්‍රචණ්ඩ ක්‍රියා රටට පමණක් නොව වසර 100කට ආසන්න කාලයක් ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ ක්‍රියාත්මක වූ පාර්ලිමේන්තු ප්‍රජාතන්ත්‍රවාදයට කැළලක් බව අමාත්‍ය ගුණවර්ධන මහතා පැවසීය.",
        "“මම කවදාවත් කිසිම ආකාරයක නීති කඩකිරීම්, ප්‍රචණ්ඩත්වය හෝ නුසුදුසු ක්‍රියාවක නිරත වී නැහැ. මම කවදාවත් ඇමැතිවරුන්ට ගෙවන නිවාස දීමනාව ලබාගෙන හෝ නිල නිවාසවල ජීවත් වුණේ නැහැ. මගේ පුද්ගලික භාවිතය සඳහා කිසිදා නිල අවියක් (රිවෝල්වරයක්) ලබා ගත්තේ නැත. මම ජීවත් වෙන්නේ මගේ ලෙයින් දහඩිය මහන්සියෙන් උපයාගත් මුදලින් හදපු ගෙදරක. නමුත් මැයි 9 වැනිදා මොකද වුණේ. මගේ නිවසට ගිනි තබා මගේ වාහන දෙකකින් එය සම්පූර්ණයෙන්ම විනාශ කළා. මගේ පවුලේ අය සති කිහිපයක් ජීවත් වුණේ හරිම බයෙන්. මා වැනි නීතිගරුක, අහිංසක ශ්‍රී ලාංකිකයෙකුට මගේ පවුලේ අය සමඟ මගේ නිවසේ සාමයෙන් ජීවත් වීමට මෙම විරෝධතාකරුවන් ඉඩ නොදෙන්නේ නම්, ඔවුන් කවුද? ඔවුන් සම්බන්ධයෙන් ත්‍රස්තවාදය වැළැක්වීමේ පනත ක්‍රියාත්මක කර රටේ නීතිය යටතේ ඔවුන්ට එරෙහිව දණ්ඩනීය ක්‍රියාමාර්ග ගත යුතු නොවේද?” ගුණවර්ධන ඇමැතිවරයා ඇසුවේය.",
        "\"මැයි 09 ත්‍රස්තවාදී පාලන සමයේදී පාර්ලිමේන්තු මන්ත්‍රීවරුන්, මැති ඇමතිවරුන්, නියෝජ්‍ය සහ රාජ්‍ය අමාත්‍යවරුන් 72 දෙනෙකුගේ නිවාස ඇතුළු දේපළ මැරයන් විසින් ගිනි තබා විනාශ කර තිබුණා. ශ්‍රී ලංකා පොදුජන පෙරමුණේ පාර්ලිමේන්තු මන්ත්‍රී අමරකීර්ති අතුකෝරළ මහතා සහ ඔහුගේ ආරක්ෂකයා තිරිසන් ලෙස ඝාතනය කර තිබුණා. මෙම මිනීමරුවන්ට ත්‍රස්තවාදය වැළැක්වීමේ පනත යටතේ චෝදනා එල්ල කළ යුතු නොවේද?\" ඔහු ඇසුවා.",
        "ත්‍රස්තවාදය වැළැක්වීමේ පනත යටතේ චෝදනා ගොනු කරන්නේ අහිංසක සිවිල් වැසියන්ට සහ දේශපාලකයන්ට අන්ත ප්‍රචණ්ඩත්වය සිදුකළ පුද්ගලයන්ට පමණක් බව අමාත්‍ය ගුණවර්ධන සහතික විය. සාමාන්‍ය නීතිය යටතේ එනම් සිවිල් ක්‍රියාපටිපාටි සංග්‍රහය හෝ අපරාධ ක්‍රියාපටිපාටි සංග්‍රහය යටතේ සුළු අපරාධ සිදු කර ඇති අයට චෝදනා කරනු ලැබේ. (සඳුන් ජයසේකර)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "PTA",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "මණ්ඩල",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "අපරාධ පරීක්ෂණ දෙපාර්තමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "CID",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "වසන්ත මුදලිගේ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ත්‍රස්තවාදය වැළැක්වීමේ පනත",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "PTA",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ත්‍රස්තවාදය වැළැක්වීමේ පනත",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "PTA",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලාංකික",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "බන්දුල ගුණවර්ධන",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "සතිපතා",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "දෙක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "අවිශිබම",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "හාමුදුරුවෝ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගල්වැව සිරිධම්ම හිමි",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "හෂාන්",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ත්‍රස්තවාදය වැළැක්වීමේ පනත",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "PTA",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "CID",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ත්‍රස්තවාදය වැළැක්වීමේ පනත",
            "label": "LAW"
          },
          {
            "text": "PTA",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජාතික ආරක්ෂක පනත",
            "label": "LAW"
          },
          {
            "text": "එන්එස්ඒ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "යුක්තිය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "විජයදාස රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ගුණවර්ධනය",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "මේ වසරේ මැයි 9",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "වසර 100 කට ආසන්න කාලයක්",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "මැයි 9 වැනිදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "දෙක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "සති කිහිපයක්",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලාංකික",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "PTA",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගුණවර්ධනය",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "මැයි 9 වැනිදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "72",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තු මන්ත්‍රීවරු",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "PTA",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ගුණවර්ධනය",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "PTA",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "සඳුන් ජයසේකර",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "பயங்கரவாதத்தை சமாளிக்க PTA அவசியம்: அமைச்சரவை செய்தி தொடர்பாளர்",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "பயங்கரவாதத் தடைச் சட்டத்தின் (PTA) விதிகளின் கீழ் தடுத்து வைக்கப்பட்டுள்ள IUSF இன் அழைப்பாளர் வசந்த முதலிகே உட்பட பல சந்தேக நபர்களை குற்றப் புலனாய்வுத் திணைக்களம் (CID) விசாரணை செய்து வருவதாக அரசாங்கம் இன்று தெரிவித்துள்ளது.",
        "பயங்கரவாதத் தடைச் சட்டம் (PTA) அண்மைய பயங்கரவாத அலையைச் சமாளிக்க அவசியமானது, எனவே போராட்டத்தின் போது வன்முறைச் செயலில் ஈடுபடாத எந்தவொரு இலங்கைப் பிரஜைக்கும் எதிராக எவரும் கைது செய்யப்படவோ அல்லது குற்றஞ்சாட்டப்படவோ மாட்டார்கள் என்று அமைச்சரவைப் பேச்சாளர் தெரிவித்தார். வாராந்த அமைச்சரவை முடிவுகளை அறிவிக்கும் ஊடகவியலாளர் சந்திப்பில் அமைச்சர் பந்துல குணவர்தன தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "IUSF இன் அழைப்பாளர் மற்றும் இரண்டு IUSF உறுப்பினர்களும் வண. கல்வெவ சிறிதம்ம தேரர் மற்றும் ஹஷான் ஜீவந்த ஆகியோரின் வாக்குமூலங்கள் பதிவு செய்யப்படும் வரை பயங்கரவாதத் தடைச் சட்டத்தின் (PTA) விதிகளின் கீழ் தடுத்து வைக்கப்படுவார்கள்.",
        "இந்த விடயம் தொடர்பான மேலதிக தகவல்களுக்காக சிஐடியினர் அவர்களிடம் விசாரணைகளை மேற்கொண்டு வருவதாகவும் அவர் மேலும் தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "பயங்கரவாதத் தடைச் சட்டத்தை (PTA) புதிய தேசிய பாதுகாப்புச் சட்டத்தை (NSA) கொண்டு வருவதற்கு அரசாங்கம் நடவடிக்கை எடுத்து வருவதாகவும், நீதி அமைச்சர் கலாநிதி விஜயதாச ராஜபக்ஷ அப்பணியில் கலந்துகொள்வதாகவும் அவர் கூறினார்.",
        "இந்த ஆண்டு மே மாதம் 9 ஆம் திகதி இடம்பெற்ற கொடூரமான வன்முறைகள் நாட்டிற்கு மட்டுமன்றி இலங்கையில் சுமார் 100 வருடங்களாக நடைமுறைப்படுத்தப்பட்ட பாராளுமன்ற ஜனநாயகத்திற்கும் களங்கம் என அமைச்சர் குணவர்தன தெரிவித்துள்ளார்.",
        "“எந்தவிதமான சட்ட மீறல், வன்முறை அல்லது பொருத்தமற்ற செயலிலும் நான் ஒருபோதும் ஈடுபடவில்லை. நான் அமைச்சர்களுக்கு வழங்கப்படும் வீட்டுக் கொடுப்பனவை பெற்றுக்கொள்ளவில்லை அல்லது உத்தியோகபூர்வ இல்லங்களில் வசிக்கவில்லை. எனது தனிப்பட்ட பயன்பாட்டிற்காக உத்தியோகபூர்வ ஆயுதத்தை (ரிவால்வர்) பெறவில்லை. நான் என் இரத்தம் மற்றும் வியர்வையில் சம்பாதித்த ஒரு வீட்டில் நான் வாழ்கிறேன். ஆனால் மே 9 அன்று நடந்தது. எனது வீட்டிற்கு தீ வைக்கப்பட்டது, எனது இரண்டு வாகனங்கள் முழுவதுமாக அழிக்கப்பட்டது. எனது குடும்பம் பல வாரங்கள் முழு அச்சத்துடன் வாழ்ந்தது. என்னைப் போன்ற சட்டத்தை மதிக்கும் அப்பாவி இலங்கையரை எனது சொந்த வீட்டில் என் குடும்பத்துடன் நிம்மதியாக வாழ இந்தப் போராட்டக்காரர்கள் விடவில்லை என்றால், அவர்கள் யார்? அவர்கள் மீது பயங்கரவாத தடைச் சட்டத்தைப் பயன்படுத்தவும், நாட்டின் சட்டத்தின் கீழ் அவர்கள் மீது தண்டனை நடவடிக்கை எடுக்கவும் கூடாதா? என அமைச்சர் குணவர்தன கேள்வி எழுப்பினார்.",
        "“மே 9 ஆம் திகதி பயங்கரவாத ஆட்சியின் போது, ​​72 பாராளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர்கள், அமைச்சர்கள், பிரதி மற்றும் இராஜாங்க அமைச்சர்களின் வீடுகள், வீடுகள் உள்ளிட்ட சொத்துக்கள் குண்டர்களால் தீக்குளிப்புக்கு உள்ளாக்கப்பட்டன. ஸ்ரீலங்கா பொதுஜன பெரமுனவின் பாராளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர் அமரகீர்த்தி அதுகோரளவும் அவரது மெய்ப்பாதுகாவலரும் மிருகத்தனமான முறையில் படுகொலை செய்யப்பட்டனர். இந்த கொலைகாரர்கள் மீது பயங்கரவாத தடை சட்டத்தின் கீழ் குற்றம் சாட்டப்பட வேண்டாமா?\" அவர் கேட்டார்.",
        "அப்பாவி பொதுமக்கள் மற்றும் அரசியல்வாதிகள் மீது அதீத வன்முறையில் ஈடுபட்டவர்கள் மீது மாத்திரம் பயங்கரவாத தடைச்சட்டத்தின் கீழ் குற்றச்சாட்டுக்கள் முன்வைக்கப்படும் என அமைச்சர் குணவர்தன உறுதியளித்துள்ளார். சிறிய குற்றங்களைச் செய்தவர்கள் மீது சாதாரண சட்டத்தின் கீழ், அதாவது சிவில் நடைமுறைச் சட்டம் அல்லது குற்றவியல் நடைமுறைச் சட்டத்தின் கீழ் குற்றம் சாட்டப்படும். (சந்துன் ஜயசேகர)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "PTA",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "மந்திரி சபை",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "குற்றப் புலனாய்வுத் திணைக்களம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "சி.ஐ.டி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "வசந்த முதலிகே",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "பயங்கரவாதத் தடுப்புச் சட்டம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "PTA",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பயங்கரவாதத் தடுப்புச் சட்டம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "PTA",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "பந்துல குணவர்தன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "வாரந்தோறும்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இரண்டு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "IUSF",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "வண",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "கல்வெவ சிறிதம்ம தேரர்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஹஷன்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "பயங்கரவாதத் தடுப்புச் சட்டம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "PTA",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "சி.ஐ.டி",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பயங்கரவாதத் தடைச் சட்டம்",
            "label": "LAW"
          },
          {
            "text": "PTA",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "தேசிய பாதுகாப்பு சட்டம்",
            "label": "LAW"
          },
          {
            "text": "NSA",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "நீதி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "விஜயதாச ராஜபக்ஷ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "குணவர்தன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்த ஆண்டு மே 9",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "கிட்டத்தட்ட 100 ஆண்டுகள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "மே 9 ஆம் தேதி",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இரண்டு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "பல வாரங்கள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "PTA",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "குணவர்தன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "மே 9 ஆம் தேதி",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "72",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர்கள்",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "PTA",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "குணவர்தன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "PTA",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "சந்துன் ஜயசேகர",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}