{
  "newspaper_id": "ada-lk",
  "url": "https://www.ada.lk/breaking_news/වස්කඩුවේ-ලී-මෝලක්-ගිනි-ගනී/11-395808",
  "time_ut": 1658984250,
  "original_lang": "si",
  "original_title": "වස්කඩුවේ ලී මෝලක් ගිනි ගනී",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "A sawmill catches fire in Waskadu",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "Kalutara North Police said that a large number of pallet boards prepared for import to foreign countries were destroyed in a fire that broke out in a wood mill in Waskaduwa last night (27th).",
        "The fire broke out in the section with the wood-seasoning boiler of the sawmill running behind a house in Vaskaduwa Gallupara.",
        "With the occurrence of the incident, a team consisting of six firemen of the Kalutara Municipal Council arrived and controlled the fire in about 45 minutes, but it was seen that all the pallets stored there were destroyed.",
        "The Kalutara Municipal Fire Fighting Unit states that the cause of the fire cannot be specified, and the damage has not yet been estimated."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Waskadu",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Kalutara North Police",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Waskaduwa",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "last night",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Vaskaduwa Gallupara",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "six",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Kalutara Municipal Council",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "about 45 minutes",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "The Kalutara Municipal Fire Fighting Unit",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "වස්කඩුවේ ලී මෝලක් ගිනි ගනී",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "වස්කඩුවේ ලී මෝලක ඊයේ (27දා) මධ්‍යම රාත්‍රියේ  හටගත් ගින්නකින් විදෙස් රටවලට ආනයනය කිරීමට සූදානම් කරන ලද පැලට් ලෑලි විශාල ප්‍රමාණයක්  විනාශ වී  ඇතැයි කළුතර උතුර පොලිසිය පවසයි.",
        "වස්කඩුව ගාලුපාරේ නිවසක් පිටුපස පවත්වාගෙන යන ලී මෝලේ ලී පදම් කරන බොයිලේරුව සහිත කොටසේ  ගින්න හටගෙන තිබේ.",
        "සිද්ධිය සැලවීමත් සමගින්  කළුතර නගර සභාවේ   ගිනි නිවන භටයින් හය දෙනෙකුගෙන් සමන්විත කණ්ඩායමක්  පැමිණ විනාඩි 45 ක් වැනි කාලයකදී ගින්න පාලනය කලද එහි ගබඩා කර තිබූ පැලට් ලෑලි සියල්ල විනාශවී ඇති අයුරු දැකගත හැකිවිය.",
        "ගින්නට හේතුව නිශ්චිත වශයෙන් සදහන් කල නොහැකි බව කළුතර නගර සභා ගිනි නිවන ඒකකය සදහන් කරන අතර , හානිය මෙතෙක් ගනන් බලා නොමැත."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "වස්කඩු",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "කළුතර උතුර පොලිසිය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "වස්කඩුව",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "අවසන් රාත්රිය",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "වස්කඩුව ගල්ලුපාර",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "හය",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "කළුතර මහ නගර සභාව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "විනාඩි 45 ක් පමණ",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "කළුතර නාගරික ගිනි නිවීමේ ඒකකය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "வாஸ்காடு பகுதியில் மரம் அறுக்கும் ஆலையில் தீப்பிடித்தது",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "வஸ்கடுவ மர ஆலையொன்றில் நேற்று (27) இரவு ஏற்பட்ட தீ விபத்தில் வெளிநாடுகளுக்கு இறக்குமதி செய்வதற்கு தயார் செய்யப்பட்டிருந்த பலகை பலகைகள் எரிந்து நாசமாகியுள்ளதாக களுத்துறை வடக்கு பொலிஸார் தெரிவித்தனர்.",
        "வஸ்கடுவ கல்லுபாறையில் உள்ள வீடொன்றின் பின்னால் ஓடும் மரத்தூள் ஆலையின் மரக்கறி கொதிகலன் கொண்ட பகுதியில் தீ பரவியுள்ளது.",
        "சம்பவம் இடம்பெற்ற உடன் களுத்துறை மாநகர சபையின் ஆறு தீயணைப்பு வீரர்கள் அடங்கிய குழுவொன்று வந்து சுமார் 45 நிமிடங்களில் தீயை கட்டுப்படுத்திய போதிலும் அங்கு சேமித்து வைக்கப்பட்டிருந்த பலகைகள் அனைத்தும் எரிந்து நாசமாகியிருந்தமை காணப்பட்டது.",
        "தீ விபத்திற்கான காரணத்தை கூறமுடியாது எனவும், சேத விபரம் இதுவரை மதிப்பிடப்படவில்லை எனவும் களுத்துறை மாநகர தீயணைப்பு பிரிவு தெரிவித்துள்ளது."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "வாஸ்காடு",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "களுத்துறை வடக்கு பொலிஸ்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "வஸ்கடுவ",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "நேற்று இரவு",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "வஸ்கடுவ கல்லுபர",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஆறு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "களுத்துறை மாநகர சபை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "சுமார் 45 நிமிடங்கள்",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "களுத்துறை மாநகரசபை தீ அணைப்பு பிரிவு",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}