{
  "newspaper_id": "island-lk",
  "url": "http://island.lk/to-dock-or-not-to-dock/",
  "time_ut": 1660498380,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "To dock or not to dock",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "To dock or not to dock",
      "author": "Thilina Walpola",
      "body_lines": [
        "Sri Lanka is like a storm-tossed bark struggling to remain afloat in an ocean of economic trouble; it is lucky to have avoided a head-on collision with a massive Chinese vessel, Yuan Wang 5 (YW-5), a ballistic missile and satellite-tracking ship, which is on its way to Hambantota. Colombo has finally stopped dillydallying and decided to allow the vessel to make a port call. India and the US have softened their collective stance on the Chinese ship’s visit. It was thought that the YW-5 issue would lead to a bitter diplomatic row with India, and if what was feared had come to pass with New Delhi cranking up pressure on Colombo to deny YW-5 permission to dock, it would have been a double whammy for Sri Lanka, which is dependent on the restructuring of Chinese debt to secure the much-needed IMF bailout package, and cannot afford to antagonise India, which is propping up its economy. All’s well that ends well.",
        "There are lessons to be learnt from the ship controversy. Colombo was initially all at sea. The Rajapaksa-Wickremesinghe government seemed divided on the issue with vital information one needed to figure out the provenance of the issue being suppressed. So, the arguments and counterarguments anent the issue were based on surmises, hunches, assumptions, hearsay, etc. Thankfully, the Foreign Ministry has put the record straight albeit belatedly.",
        "It behoves Sri Lanka to be mindful of India’s security concerns in handling maritime affairs. Perhaps, it is not the scheduled arrival of YW-5 as such that New Delhi was concerned about but the possibility of China continuing to use the Hambantota Port to berth more such vessels in the future. (China would not have secured a port in a strategic location in the Indian Ocean for nothing!) It is only natural that India and its QUAD allies think China is testing the water.",
        "It is the voice of the QUAD that one has heard through the critics of the YW-5 voyage. There is reason to believe that they are promoting a US-led drive to isolate China internationally. YW-5 embarked on its current voyage amidst a Chinese naval exercise near Taiwan in response to US Speaker Nancy Pelosi’s recent controversial visit to Taipei notwithstanding objections from Beijing.",
        "Colombo has acted tactfully by reportedly asking India and the US to specify the reasons for their misgivings about the Chinese vessel’s port call. However, it defies comprehension why Colombo requested Beijing to defer the arrival of YW-5 at Hambantota for replenishment, after granting permission.",
        "Meanwhile, the argument that China is sending its survey vessel all the way to Hambantota to spy on South India does not sound tenable. In fact, it reflects naivety on the part of those who make that claim, for China is equipped to spy on its rivals without taking the trouble of deploying its ships and drawing international attention to such missions unnecessarily. In this day and age, technology is so advanced that information about even what lies at the edge of the universe, as it were, could be gathered without any craft ever getting anywhere near it.",
        "Sri Lanka is already battered and bruised enough economically and certainly does not want any diplomatic rows to contend with. It has to get its foreign policy right. It had better take steps to avoid issues like the docking of YW-5 in the future lest it should become a victim of the big-power rivalry, which is intensifying; it ought to decide what types of ships will be allowed to berth at its ports, formulate a policy to that effect and make it known to the rest of the word so that unnecessary controversies could be averted, and hegemonic nations bent on projecting their power on a global scale will not be able to flex their naval muscles at the expense of Colombo.",
        "Leave a Reply Cancel replyYour email address will not be published. Required fields are marked *Comment Name *",
        "Save my name, email, and website in this browser for the next time I comment."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Chinese",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Yuan Wang",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "5",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "India",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "US",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Chinese",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "YW-5",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "India",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "New Delhi",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Colombo",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Chinese",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "India",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Rajapaksa-Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Foreign Ministry",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "India",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "New Delhi",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "China",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "China",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Indian Ocean",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "India",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "China",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "US",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "China",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Chinese",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Taiwan",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "US",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Nancy Pelosi’s",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Taipei",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Beijing",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "India",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "US",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Chinese",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Colombo",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Beijing",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "China",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "South India",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "China",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "this day",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Colombo",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [],
        []
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "ඩොක් කිරීමට හෝ නැව්ගත කිරීමට",
      "author": "තිළිණ වල්පොල",
      "body_lines": [
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකාව ආර්ථික කරදර සාගරයක පාවී සිටීමට අරගල කරන කුණාටුවකට හසු වූ පොත්තක් වැනි ය; හම්බන්තොට දෙසට ගමන් කරමින් තිබූ බැලස්ටික් මිසයිල සහ චන්ද්‍රිකා ලුහුබැඳීමේ නෞකාවක් වන යුවාන් වැන්ග් 5 (YW-5) නමැති දැවැන්ත චීන නෞකාවේ මුහුණට මුහුණ ගැටීම වළක්වා ගැනීමට හැකිවීම වාසනාවකි. කොළඹ අවසානයේ ඩිලිඩලි කිරීම නවතා නෞකාවට වරාය ඇමතුමක් ගැනීමට ඉඩ දීමට තීරණය කර ඇත. චීන නෞකාවේ සංචාරය සම්බන්ධයෙන් ඉන්දියාව සහ එක්සත් ජනපදය ඔවුන්ගේ සාමූහික ස්ථාවරය ලිහිල් කර ඇත. YW-5 ප්‍රශ්නය ඉන්දියාව සමඟ අමිහිරි රාජ්‍ය තාන්ත්‍රික ගැටුමකට තුඩු දෙනු ඇතැයි සිතූ අතර, YW-5 නැව් තටාකයට අවසර දීම ප්‍රතික්ෂේප කරන ලෙස නවදිල්ලිය කොළඹට බලපෑම් කිරීමත් සමඟ බිය වූ දෙය සිදු වූයේ නම්, එය අත්‍යවශ්‍ය ජාමූඅ ඇපදීමේ පැකේජය සුරක්ෂිත කර ගැනීම සඳහා චීන නය ප්‍රතිව්‍යුහගත කිරීම මත යැපෙන සහ එහි ආර්ථිකයට මුක්කු ගසන ඉන්දියාවට විරුද්ධ වීමට දරාගත නොහැකි ශ්‍රී ලංකාවට දෙගුණයක් වේ. සියල්ල හොඳයි, එය හොඳින් අවසන් වේ.",
        "නැව් මතභේදයෙන් උගත යුතු පාඩම් තිබේ. කොළඹ මුලදී තිබුණේ මුහුදේය. රාජපක්ෂ-වික‍්‍රමසිංහ ආන්ඩුව මෙම ප‍්‍රශ්නය සම්බන්ධයෙන් බෙදී සිටින බවක් පෙනෙන්නට තිබුනේ, යටපත් වෙමින් පවතින ප‍්‍රශ්නයේ ප‍්‍රභවය සොයා ගැනීමට අවශ්‍ය වැදගත් තොරතුරු සමගිනි. එබැවින්, ප්‍රශ්නයට ඉදිරිපත් වන තර්ක සහ ප්‍රතිතර්ක පදනම් වූයේ උපකල්පන, අනුමාන, උපකල්පන, කටකතා යනාදිය මත ය. ස්තුතිවන්ත විය යුත්තේ විදේශ අමාත්‍යාංශය ප්‍රමාද වී වුවද වාර්තාව කෙළින් කර තිබීමයි.",
        "සමුද්‍ර කටයුතු හැසිරවීමේදී ඉන්දියාවේ ආරක්‍ෂාව පිළිබඳ සැලකිලිමත් වීම ශ්‍රී ලංකාවට අවශ්‍ය වේ. සමහර විට, නව දිල්ලිය සැලකිලිමත් වූයේ YW-5 නියමිත පැමිණීම නොව අනාගතයේදී තවත් එවැනි යාත්‍රා නැංගුරම් ලෑම සඳහා චීනය හම්බන්තොට වරාය දිගටම භාවිතා කිරීමේ හැකියාව ගැන ය. (චීනය නිකරුණේ ඉන්දියන් සාගරයේ උපාය මාර්ගික ස්ථානයක වරායක් සුරක්ෂිත කර නොගනු ඇත!) ඉන්දියාව සහ එහි QUAD සහචරයින් චීනය ජලය පරීක්ෂා කරන බව සිතීම ස්වාභාවිකය.",
        "YW-5 මුහුදු ගමනේ විවේචකයින් හරහා යමෙකු අසා ඇත්තේ QUAD හි හඬයි. ඔවුන් චීනය ජාත්‍යන්තරව හුදකලා කිරීමේ එක්සත් ජනපදය ප්‍රමුඛ පෙළඹවීමක් ප්‍රවර්ධනය කරන බව විශ්වාස කිරීමට හේතුවක් තිබේ. බීජිං හි විරෝධතා නොතකා එක්සත් ජනපද කථානායක නැන්සි පෙලෝසිගේ මෑතකාලීන මතභේදාත්මක තායිපේ සංචාරයට ප්‍රතිචාර වශයෙන් YW-5 තායිවානය ආසන්නයේ චීන නාවික අභ්‍යාසයක් මධ්‍යයේ එහි වත්මන් ගමන ආරම්භ කළේය.",
        "වාර්තා වන අන්දමට චීන යාත්‍රාවේ වරාය ඇමතීම පිළිබඳව ඉන්දියාවෙන් සහ එක්සත් ජනපදයේ අවිශ්වාසයට හේතු සඳහන් කරන ලෙස කොළඹ උපක්‍රමශීලීව ක්‍රියා කර ඇත. කෙසේ වෙතත්, අවසර ලබා දීමෙන් පසු YW-5 නැවත පිරවීම සඳහා හම්බන්තොටට පැමිණීම කල් දමන ලෙස කොළඹ බීජිං වෙතින් ඉල්ලා සිටියේ මන්දැයි එය අවබෝධ කර නොගනී.",
        "මේ අතර, චීනය දකුණු ඉන්දියාව පිළිබඳ ඔත්තු බැලීම සඳහා සිය සමීක්ෂණ යාත්‍රාව හම්බන්තොටට යවන බවට ඇති තර්කය සාධාරණ නොවේ. ඇත්ත වශයෙන්ම, එය එම ප්‍රකාශය කරන අයගේ බොළඳ බව පිළිබිඹු කරයි, මන්ද චීනය තම නැව් යෙදවීමේ කරදරයක් නොගෙන තම ප්‍රතිවාදීන් ගැන ඔත්තු බැලීමට සහ එවැනි මෙහෙයුම් කෙරෙහි ජාත්‍යන්තර අවධානය අනවශ්‍ය ලෙස ආකර්ෂණය කර ගැනීමට සූදානම් බැවිනි. අද සහ යුගයේදී, තාක්‍ෂණය කෙතරම් දියුණු වී ඇත්ද යත්, විශ්වයේ කෙළවරේ ඇති දේ පිළිබඳ තොරතුරු පවා කිසිදු යාත්‍රාවක් ඒ අසලට නොපැමිණීමෙන් එක්රැස් කළ හැකිය.",
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකාව දැනටමත් ආර්ථික වශයෙන් බැටකෑමට හා තැලීම්වලට ලක්ව ඇති අතර නිසැකවම කිසිදු රාජ්‍ය තාන්ත්‍රික පේළියක් සමඟ ගැටීමට අවශ්‍ය නැත. එහි විදේශ ප්‍රතිපත්තිය නිවැරැදි විය යුතුයි. එය තීව්‍ර වෙමින් පවතින මහා බල එදිරිවාදිකමේ ගොදුරක් බවට පත් නොවන පරිදි අනාගතයේදී YW-5 ඩොකින් කිරීම වැනි ගැටළු මඟහරවා ගැනීමට පියවර ගැනීම වඩා හොඳය. එහි වරායේ නැංගුරම් ලෑමට ඉඩ දෙන්නේ කුමන වර්ගයේ නැව්ද යන්න තීරණය කළ යුතු අතර, ඒ සඳහා ප්‍රතිපත්තියක් සකස් කර අනවශ්‍ය මතභේද වළක්වා ගත හැකි වන පරිදි එය වචනයේ ඉතිරි කොටසට ප්‍රකාශ කළ යුතු අතර, අධිපතිවාදී ජාතීන් තම බලය ප්‍රක්ෂේපණය කිරීමට නැඹුරු විය ගෝලීය පරිමාණයකට කොළඹ වියදමින් ඔවුන්ගේ නාවික මාංශ පේශි නැමීමට නොහැකි වනු ඇත.",
        "පිළිතුරක් දෙන්න පිළිතුර අවලංගු කරන්න ඔබගේ විද්‍යුත් තැපැල් ලිපිනය ප්‍රකාශයට පත් නොකෙරේ. අවශ්‍ය ක්ෂේත්‍ර සලකුණු කර ඇත *අදහස් නම *",
        "මම ඊළඟ වතාවේ අදහස් දැක්වීම සඳහා මගේ නම, විද්‍යුත් තැපෑල සහ වෙබ් අඩවිය මෙම බ්‍රවුසරයේ සුරකින්න."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "චීන",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Yuan Wang",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "5",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "එක්සත් ජනපදය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "චීන",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "YW-5",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "නව දිල්ලි",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "කොළඹ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "චීන",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "රාජපක්ෂ-වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "විදේශ අමාත්‍යාංශය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "නව දිල්ලි",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "චීනය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "චීනය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දියන් සාගරය",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "චීනය",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "එක්සත් ජනපදය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "චීනය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "චීන",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "තායිවානය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "එක්සත් ජනපදය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "නැන්සි පෙලෝසිගේ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "තායිපේ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "බීජිං",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "එක්සත් ජනපදය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "චීන",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "කොළඹ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "බීජිං",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "චීනය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "දකුණු ඉන්දියාව",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "චීනය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "අද දවස",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "කොළඹ",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [],
        []
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "கப்பல்துறை அல்லது கப்பல்துறை",
      "author": "திலின வல்பொல",
      "body_lines": [
        "பொருளாதாரச் சிக்கலின் கடலில் மிதக்கப் போராடும் புயலால் வீசப்பட்ட பட்டை போன்றது இலங்கை; ஹம்பாந்தோட்டை நோக்கிச் சென்றுகொண்டிருக்கும் பாலிஸ்டிக் ஏவுகணை மற்றும் செயற்கைக்கோள் கண்காணிப்பு கப்பலான யுவான் வாங் 5 (YW-5) என்ற பாரிய சீனக் கப்பலுடன் நேருக்கு நேர் மோதுவதைத் தவிர்த்தது அதிர்ஷ்டம். கொழும்பு இறுதியாக தில்லுமுல்லு செய்வதை நிறுத்திவிட்டு, கப்பலை துறைமுக அழைப்பிற்கு அனுமதிக்க முடிவு செய்துள்ளது. சீனக் கப்பலின் பயணம் தொடர்பாக இந்தியாவும் அமெரிக்காவும் தங்கள் கூட்டு நிலைப்பாட்டை மென்மையாக்கியுள்ளன. YW-5 பிரச்சினை இந்தியாவுடனான கசப்பான இராஜதந்திர சண்டைக்கு வழிவகுக்கும் என்று கருதப்பட்டது, மேலும் YW-5 கப்பல்துறைக்கு அனுமதி மறுக்கும்படி கொழும்புக்கு அழுத்தம் கொடுப்பதன் மூலம் அஞ்சப்பட்டது என்னவாகும் என்று கருதப்பட்டது. மிகவும் தேவையான சர்வதேச நாணய நிதியத்தின் பிணை எடுப்புப் பொதியைப் பெறுவதற்கு சீனக் கடனின் மறுசீரமைப்பைச் சார்ந்து இருக்கும் இலங்கைக்கு இரட்டைச் சத்தம். எல்லாம் நன்றாக இருக்கிறது அது நன்றாகவே முடிகிறது.",
        "கப்பல் சர்ச்சையில் இருந்து கற்றுக்கொள்ள வேண்டிய பாடங்கள் உள்ளன. கொழும்பு முதலில் கடலில் இருந்தது. ராஜபக்சே-விக்கிரமசிங்கே அரசாங்கம் இந்த விவகாரத்தில் பிளவுபட்டதாகத் தோன்றியது, இந்த விவகாரத்தின் ஆதாரம் அடக்கப்படுவதைக் கண்டறிய தேவையான முக்கியமான தகவல் ஒன்று உள்ளது. எனவே, வாதங்கள் மற்றும் எதிர் வாதங்கள் யூகங்கள், ஊகங்கள், அனுமானங்கள், செவிவழிகள் போன்றவற்றின் அடிப்படையில் அமைந்தன. அதிர்ஷ்டவசமாக, வெளியுறவு அமைச்சகம் தாமதமாக இருந்தாலும் பதிவை நேராக வைத்துள்ளது.",
        "கடல் விவகாரங்களைக் கையாள்வதில் இந்தியாவின் பாதுகாப்புக் கவலைகள் குறித்து இலங்கை கவனத்தில் கொள்ள வேண்டும். ஒருவேளை, YW-5 இன் திட்டமிடப்பட்ட வருகையைப் பற்றி புது டெல்லி கவலைப்படவில்லை. (சும்மா இந்தியப் பெருங்கடலில் ஒரு மூலோபாய இடத்தில் ஒரு துறைமுகத்தை சீனா பாதுகாத்திருக்காது!) இந்தியாவும் அதன் குவாட் கூட்டாளிகளும் சீனா தண்ணீரை சோதிப்பதாக நினைப்பது இயற்கையானது.",
        "YW-5 பயணத்தின் விமர்சகர்கள் மூலம் ஒருவர் கேட்டது QUAD இன் குரல். சர்வதேச அளவில் சீனாவை தனிமைப்படுத்த அமெரிக்கா தலைமையிலான உந்துதலை அவர்கள் ஊக்குவிப்பதாக நம்புவதற்கு காரணம் உள்ளது. பெய்ஜிங்கின் ஆட்சேபனைகளை மீறி, அமெரிக்க சபாநாயகர் நான்சி பெலோசியின் சமீபத்திய சர்ச்சைக்குரிய தைபே விஜயத்திற்கு பதிலளிக்கும் விதமாக, YW-5 அதன் தற்போதைய பயணத்தை தைவான் அருகே சீன கடற்படை பயிற்சியின் மத்தியில் தொடங்கியது.",
        "சீனக் கப்பலின் துறைமுக அழைப்பு குறித்த சந்தேகத்திற்கான காரணங்களைக் குறிப்பிடுமாறு இந்தியா மற்றும் அமெரிக்காவிடம் கொழும்பு சாதுரியமாகச் செயற்பட்டதாகக் கூறப்படுகிறது. எவ்வாறாயினும், அனுமதி வழங்கிய பின்னர், YW-5 ஐ நிரப்புவதற்காக ஹம்பாந்தோட்டைக்கு வருவதை ஒத்திவைக்கும்படி கொழும்பு ஏன் பெய்ஜிங்கைக் கோரியது என்பது புரிந்துகொள்ள முடியாதது.",
        "இதற்கிடையில், தென்னிந்தியாவை உளவு பார்ப்பதற்காக சீனா தனது ஆய்வுக் கப்பலை ஹம்பாந்தோட்டை வரை அனுப்புகிறது என்ற வாதம் ஏற்புடையதாக இல்லை. உண்மையில், அந்த கூற்றை முன்வைப்பவர்களின் அப்பாவித்தனத்தை இது பிரதிபலிக்கிறது, ஏனெனில் சீனா தனது கப்பல்களை நிலைநிறுத்துவதில் சிரமத்தை எடுக்காமல், தேவையில்லாமல் சர்வதேச கவனத்தை அத்தகைய பணிகளுக்கு ஈர்க்காமல் அதன் போட்டியாளர்களை உளவு பார்க்க தயாராக உள்ளது. இக்காலத்தில், தொழில்நுட்பம் மிகவும் முன்னேறியதால், பிரபஞ்சத்தின் விளிம்பில் உள்ளதைப் பற்றிய தகவல்கள் கூட, எந்த கைவினைப்பொருளும் அதன் அருகில் எங்கும் செல்லாமல் சேகரிக்க முடியும்.",
        "இலங்கை ஏற்கனவே பொருளாதார ரீதியில் பாதிக்கப்பட்டுள்ளது மற்றும் நசுக்கப்பட்டுள்ளது. அது தனது வெளியுறவுக் கொள்கையை சரியாகப் பெற வேண்டும். வருங்காலத்தில் YW-5ஐ நறுக்குவது போன்ற சிக்கல்களைத் தவிர்க்க நடவடிக்கை எடுப்பது நல்லது, அது தீவிரமடைந்து வரும் பெரிய சக்திகளின் போட்டிக்கு பலியாகிவிடக்கூடாது; எந்த வகையான கப்பல்கள் அதன் துறைமுகங்களில் நிறுத்த அனுமதிக்கப்பட வேண்டும் என்பதை முடிவு செய்ய வேண்டும், அதற்கான கொள்கையை உருவாக்கி, தேவையற்ற சர்ச்சைகள் தவிர்க்கப்பட வேண்டும், மேலும் மேலாதிக்க நாடுகள் தங்கள் அதிகாரத்தை வெளிப்படுத்துவதில் முனைந்துள்ளன. உலக அளவில் கொழும்பின் இழப்பில் தங்கள் கடற்படை தசைகளை வளைக்க முடியாது.",
        "ஒரு பதிலை விடுங்கள் பதிலை ரத்துசெய் உங்கள் மின்னஞ்சல் முகவரி வெளியிடப்படாது. தேவையான புலங்கள் குறிக்கப்பட்டுள்ளன *கருத்து பெயர் *",
        "அடுத்த முறை நான் கருத்து தெரிவிக்க, எனது பெயர், மின்னஞ்சல் மற்றும் இணையதளத்தை இந்த உலாவியில் சேமிக்கவும்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சீன",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Yuan Wang",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "5",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்தியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "எங்களுக்கு",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சீன",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "YW-5",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்தியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "புது தில்லி",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "கொழும்பு",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சீன",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்தியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ராஜபக்சே-விக்ரமசிங்கே",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "வெளியுறவு அமைச்சகம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்தியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "புது தில்லி",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சீனா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சீனா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்தியப் பெருங்கடல்",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்தியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சீனா",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "எங்களுக்கு",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சீனா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சீன",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "தைவான்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "எங்களுக்கு",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "நான்சி பெலோசியின்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "தைபே",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "பெய்ஜிங்",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இந்தியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "எங்களுக்கு",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சீன",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "கொழும்பு",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "பெய்ஜிங்",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "சீனா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "தென் இந்தியா",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "சீனா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்த நாள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "கொழும்பு",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [],
        []
      ]
    }
  }
}