{
  "newspaper_id": "lankadeepa-lk",
  "url": "https://www.lankadeepa.lk/latest_news/සිරිල්-වසන්තට-ඇප/1-618947",
  "time_ut": 1661760005,
  "original_lang": "si",
  "original_title": "සිරිල් වසන්තට ඇප",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Bail for Cyril Vasant",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "Colombo Chief Magistrate Nandana Amarasinghe today (29) ordered the release of Cyril Wasantha, a social activist who was remanded in custody in connection with the alleged forced entry into the television corporation, on two sureties of Rs 25,000 cash and Rs 5 lakh each. .",
        "The Kurunduwatta Police also submitted to the court that the investigation regarding the first suspect in this incident, Mr. Dhanish Ali, has not yet been completed.",
        "Taking into consideration the facts presented, the Magistrate ordered the Kurunduwatta Police to report the progress regarding the incident on September 26."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Magistrate",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Nandana Amarasinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "29",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Cyril Wasantha",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "two",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "25,000",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "The Kurunduwatta Police",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "first",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Dhanish Ali",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Magistrate",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "September 26",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "සිරිල් වසන්තට ඇප",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "රූපවාහිනී සංස්ථාවට අයුතු ලෙස ඇතුළු වී බලහත්කාරයෙන් කටයුතු කලැයි කියන සිද්ධියට අදාළව රක්ෂිත බන්ධනාගාර ගත කර සිටි සමාජ ක්‍රියාකාරිකයෙකු වන සිරිල් වසන්ත නැමැත්තා රුපියල් 25000 මුදල් සහ රුපියල් ලක්ෂ 5 බැගින් වූ ශරීර ඇප දෙකක් මත මුදා හැරීමට කොළඹ ප්‍රධාන මහේස්ත්‍රාත් නන්දන අමරසිංහ මහතා අද (29) නියෝග කළේය.",
        "එමෙන් මෙම සිද්ධිය සම්බන්ධයෙන් පළමු සැකකරු වන  ධානිශ් අලී නැමැත්තා සම්බන්ධයෙන් විමර්ශන මෙතෙක් අවසන්ව නැතැයි ද කුරුඳුවත්ත පොලීසිය අධිකරණයට  කරුණු ඉදිරිපත් කළේය .",
        "ඉදිරිපත් වූ කරුණු සැලකිල්ලට ගත් මහේස්ත්‍රාත් වරයා සිද්ධිය සම්බන්ධයෙන් ප්‍රගතිය ලබන සැප්තැම්බර් මස 26 වන දිනට වාර්තා කරන ලෙසට කුරුඳුවත්ත පොලිසියට නියෝග කළේය."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "මහේස්ත්රාත්වරයා",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "නන්දන අමරසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "29",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "සිරිල් වසන්ත",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "දෙක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "25,000 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "කුරුඳුවත්ත පොලිසිය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "පළමුවන",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ධනිෂ් අලි",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "මහේස්ත්රාත්වරයා",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "සැප්තැම්බර් 26",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "சிரில் வசந்துக்கு ஜாமீன்",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "தொலைக்காட்சி கூட்டுத்தாபனத்திற்குள் பலவந்தமாக பிரவேசித்த குற்றச்சாட்டில் விளக்கமறியலில் வைக்கப்பட்டிருந்த சமூக ஆர்வலர் சிறில் வசந்தவை தலா 25,000 ரூபா ரொக்கம் மற்றும் 5 இலட்சம் ரூபா பெறுமதியான இரண்டு சரீரப் பிணைகளில் விடுவிக்க கொழும்பு பிரதான நீதவான் நந்தன அமரசிங்க இன்று (29) உத்தரவிட்டுள்ளார்.",
        "இந்த சம்பவத்தின் முதலாவது சந்தேகநபரான திரு.தனீஸ் அலி தொடர்பான விசாரணைகள் இன்னும் நிறைவடையவில்லை எனவும் குருந்துவத்தை பொலிஸார் நீதிமன்றில் சமர்பித்தனர்.",
        "முன்வைக்கப்பட்ட உண்மைகளை கருத்திற்கொண்ட நீதவான், சம்பவம் தொடர்பிலான முன்னேற்றத்தை செப்டம்பர் 26ஆம் திகதி அறிவிக்குமாறு குருந்துவத்தை பொலிஸாருக்கு உத்தரவிட்டார்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "மாஜிஸ்திரேட்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "நந்தன அமரசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "29",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "சிறில் வசந்த",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இரண்டு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "25,000",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "குருந்துவத்தை பொலிஸார்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "முதலில்",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "தனிஷ் அலி",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "மாஜிஸ்திரேட்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "செப்டம்பர் 26",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}