{
  "newspaper_id": "news-first-lk",
  "url": "https://www.newsfirst.lk/2022/07/06/navy-nets-kg-worth-rs-63-mn/",
  "time_ut": 1657099740,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Navy nets KG worth Rs. 63 Mn",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Navy nets KG worth Rs. 63 Mn",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); A special operation conducted by the Navy in Norochcholai, Puttalam this morning (06th July 2022), led to the seizure of about 212 kg of Kerala cannabis being transferred by a van. The Navy also nabbed a suspect in connection to this racket, during this operation.",
        "Accordingly, SLNS Thambapanni in the Northwestern Naval Command with the assistance of Norochcholai Police searched a suspicious van at the roadblock of Karamba, Norochcholai this morning. During the search, the raiding party managed to seize about 212kg of Kerala cannabis in 97 packages stuffed in 10 sacks, while being transferred by the vehicle. Meanwhile, a suspect in connection to the racket and the van used for smuggling narcotics were also held in this operation.",
        "The gross street value of Kerala cannabis seized in this operation is believed to be over Rs. 63 million.",
        "The apprehended suspect was identified as a 32-year-old resident of Colombo 14. The suspect along with the seized Kerala cannabis and the van was handed over to the Norochcholai Police for further legal proceedings.",
        "53 people arrested for illegal migration attempt; 2 smugglers also arrested",
        "Hirunika & several others arrested for protesting outside President’s House",
        "Nimal Siripala resigns as Minister of Ports, Shipping, and aviation",
        "Finance Minister Ranil Wickremesinghe must RESIGN – Min. Dhammika Perera"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Navy",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "63",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Navy",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Norochcholai",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Puttalam",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "this morning",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "06th July 2022",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "about 212 kg",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kerala",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Navy",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "SLNS Thambapanni",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Northwestern Naval Command",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Norochcholai Police",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "this morning",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "about 212kg",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kerala",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "97",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "10",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Kerala",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "63 million",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "32-year-old",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "14",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kerala",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Norochcholai Police",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "53",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "2",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Hirunika &",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "House",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Nimal Siripala",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ports",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Shipping",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Dhammika Perera",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "නාවික හමුදා දැල් කි.ග් රෑ. මිලියන 63",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); නාවික හමුදාව විසින් අද (2022 ජූලි 06) උදෑසන පුත්තලම, නොරොච්චෝලේ ප්‍රදේශයේ සිදුකළ විශේෂ මෙහෙයුමකදී වෑන් රථයකින් ප්‍රවාහනය කරමින් තිබූ කේරළ ගංජා කිලෝග්‍රෑම් 212ක් පමණ අත්අඩංගුවට ගෙන ඇත. මෙම මෙහෙයුමේදී මෙම ජාවාරමට සම්බන්ධ සැකකරුවෙකු ද නාවික හමුදාව විසින් අත්අඩංගුවට ගෙන ඇත.",
        "ඒ අනුව වයඹ නාවික විධානයට අයත් ශ්‍රී ලංකා නාවික නෞකා තම්බපන්නි නෞකාව නොරොච්චෝලේ පොලිසියේ සහය ඇතිව අද පෙරවරුවේ නොරොච්චෝලේ කරඹ මාර්ග බාධකයේදී සැකකටයුතු වෑන් රථයක් පරීක්ෂාවට ලක් කළේය. සෝදිසි කිරීමේදී ගෝනි 10ක පුරවන ලද පාර්සල් 97ක තිබූ කේරළ ගංජා කිලෝග්‍රෑම් 212ක් පමණ වාහනයකින් මාරුකර යවමින් තිබියදී අත්අඩංගුවට ගැනීමට වැටලීම් පාර්ශවය සමත්ව ඇත. මේ අතර ජාවාරමට සම්බන්ධ සැකකරුවෙකු සහ මත්කුඩු ප්‍රවාහනය කිරීමට යොදාගත් වෑන් රථයද මෙම මෙහෙයුමේදී අත්අඩංගුවට ගෙන තිබෙනවා.",
        "මෙම මෙහෙයුමේදී අත්අඩංගුවට ගත් කේරළ ගංජාවල වීදි වටිනාකම රුපියල් කෝටියකට අධික බව විශ්වාස කෙරේ. මිලියන 63 කි.",
        "අත්අඩංගුවට ගත් සැකකරු 32 හැවිරිදි කොළඹ 14 ප්‍රදේශයේ පදිංචිකරුවෙකු බවට හඳුනාගෙන ඇත. සැකකරු සහ අත්අඩංගුවට ගත් කේරළ ගංජා තොගය සහ වෑන් රථය ඉදිරි නීතිමය කටයුතු සඳහා නොරොච්චෝලේ පොලිසිය වෙත භාර දීමට කටයුතු කෙරිණි.",
        "නීතිවිරෝධී සංක්‍රමණයට උත්සාහ කළ 53ක් අත්අඩංගුවට; ජාවාරම්කරුවන් දෙදෙනෙකු ද අත්අඩංගුවට ගෙන ඇත",
        "ජනාධිපති මන්දිරය ඉදිරිපිට විරෝධතාවයේ නිරත වූ හිරුණිකා ඇතුළු පිරිසක් අත්අඩංගුවට",
        "නිමල් සිරිපාල වරාය, නාවික සහ ගුවන් සේවා අමාත්‍ය ධූරයෙන් ඉල්ලා අස්වෙයි",
        "මුදල් අමාත්‍ය රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ ඉල්ලා අස්විය යුතුයි – මිනි. ධම්මික පෙරේරා"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "නාවික",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "63",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "නාවික",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "නොරොච්චෝලේ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "පුත්තලම",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "මේ උදෑසන",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "2022 ජූලි 06",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "කිලෝ ග්රෑම් 212 ක් පමණ",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "කේරල",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "නාවික",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකා නාවික නෞකා තම්බපන්නි",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "වයඹ නාවික විධානය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "නොරොච්චෝලේ පොලිසිය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "මේ උදෑසන",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "212kg පමණ",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "කේරල",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "97",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "10",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "කේරල",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මිලියන 63 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "32 හැවිරිදිය",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "14",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "කේරල",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "නොරොච්චෝලේ පොලිසිය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "53",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "2",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Hirunika &",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "නිවස",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "නිමල් සිරිපාල",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "වරායන්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "නාවික",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ධම්මික පෙරේරා",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "கடற்படை வலைகள் கிலோ ரூ. 63 மில்லியன்",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); கடற்படையினரால் இன்று (ஜூலை 06, 2022) புத்தளம், நொரோச்சோலையில் மேற்கொள்ளப்பட்ட விசேட நடவடிக்கையின் மூலம் வேன் மூலம் கடத்தப்பட்ட சுமார் 212 கிலோகிராம் கேரள கஞ்சா கைப்பற்றப்பட்டது. இந்த நடவடிக்கையின் போது, ​​இந்த மோசடியுடன் தொடர்புடைய சந்தேக நபர் ஒருவரையும் கடற்படையினர் கைது செய்துள்ளனர்.",
        "அதன்படி இன்று காலை வடமேற்கு கடற்படை கட்டளைக்குட்பட்ட SLNS தம்பப்பண்ணி, நொரோச்சோலை பொலிஸாரின் உதவியுடன் சந்தேகத்திற்கிடமான வேன் ஒன்றை நொரோச்சோலை கரம்ப வீதித் தடுப்பில் சோதனையிட்டது. சோதனையின் போது, ​​வாகனம் மூலம் மாற்றப்பட்ட போது, ​​10 சாக்கு மூட்டைகளில் அடைக்கப்பட்ட 97 பொட்டலங்களில் சுமார் 212 கிலோ கேரள கஞ்சாவை பறிமுதல் செய்தனர். இதேவேளை, கடத்தல் தொடர்பில் சந்தேகநபர் ஒருவரும் போதைப்பொருள் கடத்தலுக்கு பயன்படுத்தப்பட்ட வேனும் இந்த நடவடிக்கையில் கைது செய்யப்பட்டுள்ளனர்.",
        "இந்த நடவடிக்கையில் கைப்பற்றப்பட்ட கேரளா கஞ்சாவின் மொத்த மதிப்பு ரூ. ரூ. 63 மில்லியன்.",
        "கைது செய்யப்பட்ட சந்தேகநபர் 32 வயதான கொழும்பு 14 பகுதியைச் சேர்ந்தவர் என அடையாளம் காணப்பட்டுள்ளார். கைப்பற்றப்பட்ட கேரள கஞ்சா மற்றும் வேனுடன் சந்தேகநபர் மேலதிக சட்ட நடவடிக்கைகளுக்காக நொரோச்சோலை பொலிஸாரிடம் ஒப்படைக்கப்பட்டார்.",
        "சட்டவிரோத குடியேற்ற முயற்சியில் 53 பேர் கைது; 2 கடத்தல்காரர்களும் கைது செய்யப்பட்டனர்",
        "ஜனாதிபதி மாளிகைக்கு வெளியே ஆர்ப்பாட்டத்தில் ஈடுபட்ட ஹிருணிகா மற்றும் பலர் கைது செய்யப்பட்டுள்ளனர்",
        "துறைமுகங்கள், கப்பல் போக்குவரத்து மற்றும் விமானப் போக்குவரத்து அமைச்சர் பதவியை நிமல் சிறிபால இராஜினாமா செய்துள்ளார்",
        "நிதியமைச்சர் ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க பதவி விலக வேண்டும் – குறைந்தபட்சம். தம்மிக்க பெரேரா"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "கடற்படை",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "63",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "கடற்படை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "நொரோச்சோலை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "புத்தளம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று காலை",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "06 ஜூலை 2022",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சுமார் 212 கி.கி",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "கேரளா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "கடற்படை",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "SLNS தம்பபன்னி",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "வடமேற்கு கடற்படை கட்டளை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "நொரோச்சோலை பொலிஸ்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று காலை",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "சுமார் 212 கிலோ",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "கேரளா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "97",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "10",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "கேரளா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "63 மில்லியன்",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "32 வயது",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "14",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "கேரளா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "நொரோச்சோலை பொலிஸ்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "53",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "2",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Hirunika &",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "வீடு",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "நிமல் சிறிபால",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "துறைமுகங்கள்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "கப்பல் போக்குவரத்து",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "தம்மிக்க பெரேரா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}