{
  "newspaper_id": "lankadeepa-lk",
  "url": "https://www.lankadeepa.lk/latest_news/එළවළු-පැළත්-ගණන්-උස්සයි/1-617013",
  "time_ut": 1658748344,
  "original_lang": "si",
  "original_title": "එළවළු පැළත් ගණන් උස්සයි",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Vegetables are high",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "It is reported that the prices of plants such as vegetables and chillies required for cultivation have also increased.",
        "Especially in Colombo and the suburbs, the price of chillies, kochi, tomatoes, cabbage, brinjal etc. has increased between 50 and 100 rupees per plant.",
        "In a place selling vegetable plants in Colombo city, the price of a plant like chili, fish chili, Varaniya chili is 100 rupees, the price of a tomato plant is 75 rupees and the price of a green cabbage plant is 80 rupees.",
        "Vegetable plants are also sold in Gampaha town at a price of 60 rupees per plant. A plant shop in Boralasgamuwa area sells a plant of chillies, tomatoes, eggplants etc. at the price of 50 rupees.",
        "A plant nursery in Piliyandala area sells a curry plant for 150 rupees, a plant of athugoa, cherry tomato etc. for 100 rupees, a Dubai pumpkin plant for 60 rupees, a gourd, a bitter gourd, a chilli plant, an eggplant plant for 45 rupees and a chilli plant for 40 rupees.",
        "When we asked a plant nursery in Kegalle, they said that this plant is sold at a price of 35 rupees.",
        "These days, plant nurseries say that this situation is due to the increase in the demand for plants due to the increase in the demand of plants due to the people living in the suburbs of their homes or resorting to cultivation activities.",
        "The price of vegetable plants in the areas where cultivation is done outside the city is quite low, and when we asked two plant nurseries in Kurunegala, Kobeigane and Wattala area, they said that they sell a plant at prices between 10 and 25 rupees.",
        "A vegetable plant is sold at prices between 12 and 22 rupees at the plant nursery in Kobeigan, while the price of 10 plants at the Wattala plant nursery is 150 rupees.",
        "People who buy plants for growing in gardens say that in the past, a collection of 10 or 15 chillies and vegetables could be bought at a price of 50 rupees, but now it costs 100 rupees to buy a plant.",
        "They mention that because some plants die after planting and the prices of fertilizers have also increased, it is not easy to grow them in the gardens."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "between 50 and 100",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Colombo",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Varaniya",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "100",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "75",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "80",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Gampaha",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "60",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Boralasgamuwa",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "50",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Piliyandala",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "150",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "athugoa",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "100",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Dubai",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "60",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "45",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "40",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Kegalle",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "35",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "These days",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "two",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kurunegala",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kobeigane",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Wattala",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "between 10 and 25",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "between 12 and 22",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kobeigan",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "10",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Wattala",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "150",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "10 or 15",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "50",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "100",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        []
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "එළවළු පැළත් ගණන් උස්සයි",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "වගා කිරීම සඳහා අවශ්‍ය එළවළු හා මිරිස් ආදී පැලවල මිල ගණන් ද මේ වන විට ඉහළ ගොස් ඇතැයි වාර්තා වේ.",
        "විශේෂයෙන් කොළඹ ඇතුළු නගරබද ප්‍රදේශයන්හි මිරිස්, කොච්චි, තක්කාලි, ගෝවා, බටු ආදී පැලයක් රුපියල් 50ත් 100ත් අතර මිලකට ඉහළ ගොස් ඇත.",
        "කොළඹ නගරයේ එළවළු පැල අලෙවි කරන ස්ථානයක මිරිස්, මාළු මිරිස්, වැරණිය මිරිස් වැනි පැලයක මිල රුපියල් 100ක් වන අතර, තක්කාලි පැලයක මිල රුපියල් 75ක් සහ කොල ගෝවා පැලයක මිල රුපියල් 80ක් විය.",
        "ගම්පහ නගරයේ ද එළවළු පැල අලෙවි වන්නේ පැලයක් රුපියල් 60ක පමණ මිලකටය. බොරලැස්ගමුව ප්‍රදේශයේ පැල අලෙවිසැලක මිරිස්, තක්කාලි, මෑ, වම්බටු ආදී පැලයක් අලෙවි කරන්නේ රුපියල් 50ක මිලටය.",
        "පිළියන්දල ප්‍රදේශයේ පැල තවානක කරපිංචා පැලයක් රුපියල් 150ක්, අතුගෝවා, චෙරි තක්කාලි ආදී පැලයක් රුපියල් 100ක්, ඩුබායි වට්ටක්කා පැලයක් රුපියල් 60ක්, කරවිල, මෑ, මාලුමිරිස්, දඹල, වම්බටු පැලයක් රුපියල් 45ක් සහ මිරිස් පැලයක් රුපියල් 40 ක් යන මිල ගණන්වලට අලෙවි කෙරේ.",
        "කෑගල්ලේ පැල තවානකින් අප කළ විමසීමකදී පැවසුවේ මෙම පැලයක් අලෙවි කරන්නේ රුපියල් 35ක මිලකට බවයි.",
        "මේ දිනවල නගරබද පදිංචි පිරිස් ද තම නිවෙස්වල පවතින ඉඩෙහි හෝ වගා කටයුතුවලට යොමුවීම හේතුවෙන් පැල වර්ගවල ඉල්ලුම ඉහළයාමෙන් මෙම තත්වය ඇතිව තිබෙන බව පැල තවාන්කරුවෝ පවසති.",
        "නගරයෙන් බැහැරව වගා කටයුතු බහුලව සිදුකෙරෙන ප්‍රදේශවල එළවළු පැල වර්ගවල මිල තරමක් අඩු වන අතර, කුරුණෑගල, කොබෙයිගනේ සහ වත්තල ප්‍රදේශයේ පැල තවාන් දෙකකින් අප කළ විමසීමේදී ඔවුන් පැවසුවේ තමන් පැලයක් රුපියල් 10ත් 25ත් අතර මිල ගණන්වලට අලෙවි කරන බවයි.",
        "කොබෙයිගනේ පිහිටි පැල තවානේ එළවළු පැලයක් රුපියල් 12ත් 22ත් අතර මිල ගණන්වලට අලෙවි කෙරෙන අතර, වත්තල පැල තවානේ පැල 10ක මිල රුපියල් 150කි.",
        "වෙනදා රුපියල් 50 ක පමණ මිලකට මිරිස්, එළවළු පැල 10ක, 15ක පමණ එකතුවක් මිලට ගත හැකි වූ අතර, මේ වන විට පැලයක් මිලදී ගැනීමට රුපියල් 100ක් පමණ අවශ්‍ය වී ඇති බව ගෙවතුවල වගාකරගැනීම සඳහා පැල මිලදී ගන්නා පිරිස් පවසති.",
        "ඇතැම් පැල සිටුවීමෙන් පසු මියයන නිසා හා පොහොර මිල ගණන් ද ඉහළ ගොස් ඇති නිසා මේ වන විට ගෙවතුවල වගා කිරීමද පහසු දෙයක් නොවන බව ඔවුහු සඳහන් කරති."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "50 සහ 100 අතර",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "කොළඹ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "වරණිය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "100",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "75",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "80",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ගම්පහ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "60",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "බොරලස්ගමුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "50",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "පිළියන්දල",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "150",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඇතුගෝවා",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "100",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඩුබායි",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "60",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "45",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "40",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "කෑගල්ල",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "35",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "මෙම දිනවල",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "දෙක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "කුරුණෑගල",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "කොබෙයිගනේ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "වත්තල",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "10 සහ 25 අතර",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "12 සහ 22 අතර",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kobeigan",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "10",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "වත්තල",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "150",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "10 හෝ 15",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "50",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "100",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        []
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "காய்கறிகள் அதிகம்",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "பயிர்ச்செய்கைக்குத் தேவையான மரக்கறி, மிளகாய் போன்ற செடிகளின் விலையும் அதிகரித்துள்ளதாகத் தெரிவிக்கப்படுகிறது.",
        "குறிப்பாக கொழும்பு மற்றும் புறநகர் பகுதிகளில் மிளகாய், கொச்சி, தக்காளி, முட்டைகோஸ், கத்தரி போன்றவற்றின் விலை ஒரு செடிக்கு 50 முதல் 100 ரூபாய் வரை அதிகரித்துள்ளது.",
        "கொழும்பு நகரில் மரக்கறிச் செடிகள் விற்பனை செய்யும் இடத்தில் மிளகாய், மீன் மிளகாய், வரணி மிளகாய் போன்ற ஒரு செடியின் விலை 100 ரூபாவாகவும், தக்காளிச் செடியின் விலை 75 ரூபாவாகவும், பச்சை முட்டைக்கோஸ் செடியின் விலை 80 ரூபாவாகவும் உள்ளது.",
        "கம்பஹா நகரிலும் ஒரு செடி 60 ரூபா என்ற விலையில் மரக்கறிச் செடிகள் விற்பனை செய்யப்படுகின்றன. பொரலஸ்கமுவ பிரதேசத்தில் உள்ள ஒரு செடி கடையில் மிளகாய், தக்காளி, கத்தரிக்காய் போன்ற ஒரு செடி 50 ரூபாவுக்கு விற்பனை செய்யப்படுகிறது.",
        "பிலியந்தலை பகுதியில் உள்ள ஒரு செடி நாற்றங்கால் கறிவேப்பிலை 150 ரூபாவிற்கும், அத்துகோவா, செர்ரி தக்காளி போன்றவை 100 ரூபாவிற்கும், துபாய் பூசணிக்காய் 60 ரூபாவிற்கும், பாக்கு, பாகற்காய், மிளகாய், கத்தரிக்காய் செடி ஒன்றுக்கு விற்பனை செய்யப்படுகிறது. 45 ரூபாய், மிளகாய் செடி 40 ரூபாய்.",
        "கேகாலையில் உள்ள செடி நாற்றங்காலிடம் கேட்டபோது, ​​இந்த செடி 35 ரூபாய்க்கு விற்கப்படுவதாக தெரிவித்தனர்.",
        "இந்நாட்களில், வீடுகளின் புறநகர்ப் பகுதிகளில் வசிப்பவர்கள் அல்லது பயிர்ச்செய்கை நடவடிக்கைகளில் ஈடுபடுவதனால், செடிகளின் தேவை அதிகரிப்பதன் காரணமாக, தாவரங்களின் தேவை அதிகரிப்பதன் காரணமாக, இந்நிலை ஏற்பட்டுள்ளதாக, தாவர நர்சரிகள் தெரிவிக்கின்றன.",
        "ஊருக்கு வெளியில் பயிர்ச்செய்கை மேற்கொள்ளப்படும் பிரதேசங்களில் மரக்கறிச் செடிகளின் விலை மிகவும் குறைவாகவே காணப்படுவதாகவும், குருநாகல், கொபேகனே, வத்தளை பிரதேசத்திலுள்ள இரண்டு செடி நாற்றங்காலங்களில் நாம் கேட்டபோது, ​​ஒரு செடியை 10 முதல் 25 ரூபா வரையில் விற்பனை செய்வதாகத் தெரிவித்தனர்.",
        "கொப்பெய்கனில் உள்ள தாவர நாற்று நிலையத்தில் ஒரு மரக்கறிச் செடி 12 ரூபா தொடக்கம் 22 ரூபாவிற்கும் இடைப்பட்ட விலையிலும், வத்தளை செடி நாற்றங்காலில் 10 செடிகளின் விலை 150 ரூபாவாகவும் விற்பனை செய்யப்படுகிறது.",
        "கடந்த காலங்களில் 10 அல்லது 15 மிளகாய், காய்கறிகள் சேகரமாக இருந்தால் 50 ரூபாய்க்கு வாங்கப்பட்ட நிலையில் தற்போது ஒரு செடி வாங்க 100 ரூபாய் செலவாகிறது என தோட்டங்களில் செடிகளை வாங்கும் மக்கள் கூறுகின்றனர்.",
        "நடவு செய்த பின் சில செடிகள் இறந்து விடுவதால், உரங்களின் விலையும் அதிகரித்துள்ளதால், அவற்றை தோட்டங்களில் வளர்ப்பது எளிதல்ல."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "50 மற்றும் 100 இடையே",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "கொழும்பு",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "வரணியா",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "100",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "75",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "80",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "கம்பஹா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "60",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "பொரலஸ்கமுவ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "50",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பிலியந்தலை",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "150",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "அதுகோவா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "100",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "துபாய்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "60",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "45",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "40",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "கேகாலை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "35",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இந்த நாட்களில்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இரண்டு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "குருநாகல்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "கோபேகனே",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "வத்தளை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "10 மற்றும் 25 இடையே",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "12 மற்றும் 22 க்கு இடையில்",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kobeigan",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "10",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "வத்தளை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "150",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "10 அல்லது 15",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "50",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "100",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        []
      ]
    }
  }
}