{
  "newspaper_id": "lankadeepa-lk",
  "url": "https://www.lankadeepa.lk/latest_news/රටේ-නායකත්වය-ලැබිය-යුත්තේ-සුජාතභාවය-හිමි-කණ්ඩායමකටයි/1-616834",
  "time_ut": 1658416601,
  "original_lang": "si",
  "original_title": "රටේ නායකත්වය ලැබිය යුත්තේ සුජාතභාවය හිමි කණ්ඩායමකටයි",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "The leadership of the country should be given to a group with integrity",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "Mr. Wimal Weerawansa, the leader of the National Freedom Front, said today (21) that even Ambamal Ronaka has no confidence that the new president and the people who appointed him will be able to rescue the country from the precipice it has fallen to, and that in the current state of the country, the leadership of the country should be given to a group of integrity.",
        "Mr. Weerawansa said that if Dallas Alahaperuma wins, Sajith Premadasa and the people who are with him will represent the government, then Mr. Weerawansa said that if a group with such integrity and confidence is formed, then the people will find it difficult to adapt to it. did",
        "Mr. Weerawansa said that even if the members of the Parliament won the presidency with the votes of 134, the integrity of the millions of people in the country is very little and it is not believed that such a regime will be allowed to manage the crisis.",
        "Mr. Weerawansa said that because Mr. Ranil Wickramasinghe successfully suppressed the struggle of 88, 89, the members who voted for him believe that he is their savior. It is not reasonable to think that a struggle can be suppressed with an 88, 89-style suppression in the current era of exchange of ideas.",
        "Mr. Weerawansa stated that President Ranil Wickramasinghe does not receive significant congratulations from an acceptable country, he does not have international recognition or local recognition and the economic crisis will continue to grow uncontrollably under such a regime.",
        "Mr. A said that in another month or two, the pressure of the people will intensify and explode again, and he also mentioned that it is likely to create the river of blood that the West is hoping for.",
        "If such a situation occurs, the intervention of the United Nations forces or India may lead the country to a terrible path and unfortunately the opportunity given to the Parliament to establish an all-party agreement to prevent such a situation from happening has been missed.",
        "Mr. Weerawansa said that the common reason for 134 MPs to vote for Mr. Ranil Wickramasinghe is the insecure mind of the MPs and that there is no security, houses are burnt, they cannot go to the village, they come to attack violently and they believe that only Ranil Wickramasinghe, who has a prestigious degree in this regard, can end the situation.",
        "At the end of the struggle, Mr. Ranil Wickramasinghe, who lost the election by sending Jayalaboo home with 69 lakh votes, was installed in the presidential chair. .",
        "Mr. Weerawansa further mentioned that the young activists did not have the sense, intelligence and thought to understand it and that the president who did not order to shoot when the activists raided the mansion, sent someone to the house and appointed someone to wait for the activists to feed them lentils.",
        "Member of Parliament Wimal Weerawansa said this at the press conference held today (21) at the National Freedom Front party headquarters in Pitakotta."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Wimal Weerawansa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the National Freedom Front",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "21",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ambamal Ronaka",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Weerawansa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Dallas",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Weerawansa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Weerawansa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "134",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "millions",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Weerawansa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickramasinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "88",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "89",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "88",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "89",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Weerawansa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickramasinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "A",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "another month",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "two",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "West",
            "label": "LOC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "United Nations",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "India",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Weerawansa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "134",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickramasinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickramasinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickramasinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Jayalaboo",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "69",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Weerawansa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Wimal Weerawansa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "21",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "the National Freedom Front",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Pitakotta",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "රටේ නායකත්වය ලැබිය යුත්තේ සුජාතභාවය හිමි කණ්ඩායමකටයි",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "නව ජනාධිපතිවරයා සහ ඔහුව පත්කිරීමට කටයුතු කළ පුද්ගලයන්ට රට වැටී තිබෙන ප්‍රපාතයෙන් ගොඩගැනීමට හැකිවේ යැයි අඹමල් රොනකවත් විශ්වාසයක් නොමැති බවත් රට වර්තමානයේ පවතින තත්වය තුළ රටේ නායකත්වය ලැබිය යුත්තේ සුජාතභාවය හිමි කණ්ඩායමකට බවත් ජාතික නිදහස් පෙරමුණේ නායක පාර්ලිමේන්තු මන්ත්‍රී විමල් වීරවංශ මහතා අද (21) පැවසීය.",
        "ඩලස් අලහපෙරුම ජයග්‍රහණය කළේ නම් සජිත් ප්‍රේමදාස සහ ඔහු සමඟ සිටින පිරිස ඇතුළුව සියලු දෙනා ඒ පාලනය නියෝජනය කිරීමෙන් මහජනයා තුළ විශ්වාස දිනාගැනීමට සමත් පිරිසකගේ පාලනයක් ඇති වන බව කී වීරවංශ මහතා එවැනි සුජාතභාවයක් සහ විශ්වාසයක් ඇති පිරිසක් පත්වූයේ නම් ජනතාව අමාරුවෙන් හෝ ඒ සමඟ අනුගත වන බව ද සඳහන් කළේය.",
        "පාර්ලිමේන්තුවේ මන්ත්‍රීවරු 134 ක ඡන්දය ලබා ජනාධිපති ධූරයට පත්වුවද රටේ කෝටි ගණනක ජනතාවගේ සුජාතභාවය ඉතා අල්ප මෙන්ම එවැනි පාලනයකට අර්බුදය කළමනාකරණය කිරීමට ඉඩ ලැබේ යැයි විශ්වාස කළ නොහැකි බවත් එවැනි පාලනයකින් නැවත පීඩනය පුපුරායාමේ හැකියාව වැඩි මෙන්ම එය මර්ධනයෙන් පාලනය කිරීමේ හැකියාව අඩු බවත් වීරවංශ මහතා කීය.",
        "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතා 88, 89 අරගලය සාර්ථකව මර්ධනය කරපු නිසා ඡන්දය දීපු මන්ත්‍රීවරු ඔවුන්ගේ ගැලවුම්කරු ඔහු යැයි විශ්වාස කරන බව කී වීරවංශ මහතා සඳහන් කළේ 88, 89 කාලයේ සාමාජ මාධ්‍ය, වට්ස්ඇප් නොතිබුණත් වර්තමානයේ එවැනි දේ තිබීම හේතුවෙන් ආතතියෙන් පෙළන තරුණ සහ මැදි වයසේ මහ සමාජයක් පාලනයකින් තොරව අදහස් හුවමාරු කරගන්නා වර්තමානයේ අරගලයක් 88, 89 පන්නයේ මර්ධනයකින් යටපත් කිරීමට හැකියැයි සිතීම සාධාරණ නොවන බවත්ය.",
        "ජනාධිපති රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහට පිළිගත හැකි රටකින් සැළකිය යුතු සුබපැතුම් නොලැබීම තුළ ඔහුට ජාත්‍යන්තර පිළිගැනීමක් හෝ දේශීය වශයෙන් පොදු පිළිගැනීමක් නොමැති බවත් එවැනි පාලනයක් තුළ ආර්ථික අර්බුදය අපාලිතව තවදුරටත් වැඩෙන බවත් වීරවංශ මහතා සඳහන් කළේය.",
        "තවත් මාසයකින් දෙදකින් හෝ තුනනික් නැවත ජනතා පීඩනය තිව්‍ර වී පුපුරා යන බව කී ඒ මහතා බටහිර බලාපොරොත්තු වන ලේ ගංගාව ඒ මගින් නිර්මාණ වීමට ඉඩ ඇති බව ද සඳහන් කළේය.",
        "එවැනි තත්වයක් ඇතිවුහොත් එක්සත් ජාතීන්ගේ හමුදා හෝ ඉන්දීය මැදිහත් වීමකට පොට පෑදී රට බිහිසුණු මාවකට ගෙන එන තැනකට පත්විහැකි බවත් එවැනි තත්වයක් ඇති නොවීමට සර්ව පාක්‍ෂික එකඟතා අන්තර් පාලනයක් ඇති කරගැනීම සඳහා පාර්ලිමේන්තුවට ලැබුණු අවස්ථාව අවාසනාවකට මඟ හැරුණු බවත්ය.",
        "මන්ත්‍රීවරු 134 ක් රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතාට ඡන්ද ප්‍රකාශ කිරීමේ පොදු හේතුව මන්ත්‍රීවරුන්ගේ අනාරක්‍ෂිත මනස බවත් ආරක්‍ෂාවක් නෑ, ගෙවල් ගිනිතිබ්බා, ගමට යන්න බෑ, ප්‍රචණ්ඩ ලෙස පහර දෙන්න එනවා ඒ තත්වය අවසන් කරන්න පුළුවන් ඒ සම්බන්ධව කීර්තිමත් උපාධියක් ලබාසිටින රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහට පමණක් බව විශ්වාසය බවත් වීරවංශ මහතා කීය.",
        "අරගලය අවසානයේ ඡන්ද 69 ලක්‍ෂයකින් ජයලැබූ ජනාධිපති ගෙදර යවලා ඡන්දෙන් පැරදුන රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතා ජනාධිපති පුටුවේ වාඩු කරවා ඇති බව කී වීරවිංශ මහතා සඳහන් කළේ  ජනාධිපති මන්දියර වටලන අවස්ථාවේදී හැර වෙනත් කිසිඳු අවස්ථාවක ජනාධිපතිවරයාට ඉවත් වන ලෙස ප්‍රකාශ නොළේ එවැනි දෙයක් වුවහොත් එය අරාජිකත්වයක් ඇති කිරීමත් බව ද සඳහන් කළේය.",
        "තරුණ අරගලකරුවන්ට එය තේරුම් ගැනීමට සිහියක් බුද්ධියක් සහ කල්පනාවක් නොතැබුණු බවත්  අරගලකරුවන් මන්දිරය වටලන විට වෙඩි තියන්න නියෝග නොකරපු ජනාධිපති ගෙදර යවා අරගලකරුවන් පරිප්පු කවන්න බලාගෙන ඉන්න කෙනෙක් පත්කර ඇති බව ද වීරවංශ මහතා වැඩි දුරටත් සඳහන කළේය.",
        "පාර්ලිමේන්තු මන්ත්‍රී විමල් වීරවංශ මහතා පිටකෝට්ටේ පිහිටි ජාතික නිදහස් පෙරමුණ පක්‍ෂ මූලස්ථානයේදී අද (21) පැවැති මාධ්‍ය හමුවේදී එසේ පැවසීය."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "විමල් වීරවංශ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජාතික නිදහස් පෙරමුණ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "21",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "අඹමල් රෝනක",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "වීරවංශ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඩලස්",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "වීරවංශ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "වීරවංශ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "134",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "මිලියන",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "වීරවංශ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "88",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "89",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "88",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "89",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "වීරවංශ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ඒ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "තවත් මාසයක්",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "දෙක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "බටහිර",
            "label": "LOC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "එක්සත් ජාතීන්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "වීරවංශ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "134",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජයලබූ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "69",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "වීරවංශ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "විමල් වීරවංශ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "21",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජාතික නිදහස් පෙරමුණ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "පිටකෝට්ට",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "நாட்டின் தலைமைத்துவம் நேர்மையுடன் கூடிய குழுவிற்கு வழங்கப்பட வேண்டும்",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "புதிய ஜனாதிபதியாலும் அவரை நியமித்தவர்களாலும் நாட்டை வீழ்ச்சியடைந்துள்ள அதலபாதாளத்திலிருந்து மீட்பார்கள் என்பதில் அம்பமல் றோனக்கவுக்குக் கூட நம்பிக்கை இல்லை என தேசிய சுதந்திர முன்னணியின் தலைவர் திரு.விமல் வீரவன்ச இன்று (21) தெரிவித்தார். நாட்டின் தற்போதைய நிலையில், நாட்டின் தலைமைத்துவம் ஒருமைப்பாட்டைக் கொண்ட குழுவிற்கு வழங்கப்பட வேண்டும்.",
        "டலஸ் அழகப்பெரும வெற்றி பெற்றால், சஜித் பிரேமதாசவும் அவருடன் இருப்பவர்களும் அரசாங்கத்தை பிரதிநிதித்துவப்படுத்துவார்கள் என தெரிவித்த திரு.வீரவன்ச, அவ்வாறான ஒருமைப்பாடும் நம்பிக்கையும் கொண்ட குழுவொன்றை உருவாக்கினால் மக்களை அனுசரித்துச் செல்வது கடினமாகும் எனவும் திரு. அதற்கு",
        "நாடாளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர்கள் 134 வாக்குகளைப் பெற்று ஜனாதிபதியாக பதவியேற்றாலும், நாட்டில் உள்ள கோடிக்கணக்கான மக்களின் நேர்மை மிகவும் குறைவாகவே காணப்படுவதாகவும், இவ்வாறானதொரு ஆட்சிக்கு நெருக்கடியை சமாளிக்க இடமளிக்கப்படும் என நம்ப முடியாது எனவும் திரு.வீரவன்ச தெரிவித்தார். .",
        "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க 88, 89 போராட்டத்தை வெற்றிகரமாக அடக்கியதால் வாக்களித்த உறுப்பினர்கள் அவரை மீட்பராக நம்புவதாகவும், 88, 89 மாதிரியான அடக்குமுறை மூலம் போராட்டத்தை அடக்கிவிடலாம் என்று நினைப்பது நியாயமில்லை என்றும் வீரவன்ச தெரிவித்தார். கருத்து பரிமாற்றத்தின் தற்போதைய காலகட்டத்தில்.",
        "ஜனாதிபதி ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க ஏற்றுக்கொள்ளக்கூடிய நாட்டிலிருந்து குறிப்பிடத்தக்க வாழ்த்துக்களைப் பெறவில்லை, அவருக்கு சர்வதேச அங்கீகாரம் அல்லது உள்ளூர் அங்கீகாரம் இல்லை, அத்தகைய ஆட்சியின் கீழ் பொருளாதார நெருக்கடி கட்டுப்பாடில்லாமல் வளரும் என்றும் வீரவன்ச கூறினார்.",
        "இன்னும் ஓரிரு மாதங்களில் மக்களின் அழுத்தம் உக்கிரமடைந்து மீண்டும் வெடிக்கும் எனத் தெரிவித்த திரு.ஏ, மேற்குலகம் எதிர்பார்க்கும் இரத்த ஆறு உருவாக வாய்ப்புள்ளதாகவும் குறிப்பிட்டுள்ளார்.",
        "அவ்வாறானதொரு நிலை ஏற்பட்டால், ஐக்கிய நாடுகள் சபையின் அல்லது இந்தியாவின் தலையீடு நாட்டைப் பயங்கரமான பாதைக்கு இட்டுச் செல்லக்கூடும் என்பதுடன், துரதிஷ்டவசமாக அவ்வாறானதொரு நிலை ஏற்படாமல் தடுப்பதற்கு அனைத்துக் கட்சி உடன்படிக்கையை ஏற்படுத்துவதற்கு பாராளுமன்றத்திற்கு வழங்கப்பட்ட சந்தர்ப்பம் தவறவிடப்பட்டுள்ளது.",
        "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்கவுக்கு 134 எம்.பி.க்கள் வாக்களிக்க பொதுக் காரணம் எம்.பி.க்களின் பாதுகாப்பற்ற மனப்பான்மை என்றும், பாதுகாப்பு இல்லை, வீடுகள் எரிக்கப்படுகின்றன, கிராமத்திற்குச் செல்ல முடியாது, வன்முறையில் தாக்க வருவார்கள், அவர்கள் என்றும் வீரவன்ச தெரிவித்தார். இந்த விடயத்தில் கௌரவமான பட்டம் பெற்ற ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்கவினால் மாத்திரமே இந்த நிலைமையை முடிவுக்கு கொண்டுவர முடியும் என நம்புகின்றேன்.",
        "போராட்டத்தின் இறுதியில் 69 இலட்சம் வாக்குகளைப் பெற்று ஜெயலாபுவை வீட்டுக்கு அனுப்பி தேர்தலில் தோல்வியடைந்த திரு.ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க ஜனாதிபதி கதிரையில் அமர வைக்கப்பட்டார்.",
        "அதனைப் புரிந்துகொள்ளும் உணர்வும், புத்திசாலித்தனமும், சிந்தனையும் இளம் செயற்பாட்டாளர்களுக்கு இல்லை என்றும், செயற்பாட்டாளர்கள் மாளிகையை முற்றுகையிட்ட போது சுட உத்தரவிடாத ஜனாதிபதி, வீட்டுக்கு ஒருவரை அனுப்பி, காத்திருக்க ஒருவரை நியமித்ததாகவும் திரு.வீரவன்ச மேலும் குறிப்பிட்டார். அவர்களுக்கு பருப்பு ஊட்ட ஆர்வலர்கள்.",
        "பிட்டகோட்டையில் உள்ள தேசிய சுதந்திர முன்னணியின் தலைமையகத்தில் இன்று (21) நடைபெற்ற ஊடகவியலாளர் சந்திப்பிலேயே நாடாளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர் விமல் வீரவன்ச மேற்கண்டவாறு தெரிவித்தார்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "விமல் வீரவன்ச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "தேசிய சுதந்திர முன்னணி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "21",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "அம்பமல் ரோனகா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "வீரவன்ச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "டல்லாஸ்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "வீரவன்ச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "வீரவன்ச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "134",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "மில்லியன்கள்",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "வீரவன்ச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "88",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "89",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "88",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "89",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "வீரவன்ச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஏ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "மற்றொரு மாதம்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இரண்டு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "மேற்கு",
            "label": "LOC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஐக்கிய நாடுகள்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்தியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "வீரவன்ச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "134",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜெயலாபூ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "69",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "வீரவன்ச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "விமல் வீரவன்ச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "21",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "தேசிய சுதந்திர முன்னணி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "பிடகோட்டா",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}