{
  "newspaper_id": "virakesari-lk",
  "url": "http://www.virakesari.lk/article/130405",
  "time_ut": 1656498460,
  "original_lang": "ta",
  "original_title": "ஜப்பான் தூதுவர் யாழ் மாநகர சபை முதல்வருடன் சமகால நிலைமைகள் தொடர்பில் கலந்துரையாடல்",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Ambassador of Japan discusses the current situation with the Mayor of Jaffna",
      "author": "Digital Desk 5",
      "body_lines": [
        "Japanese Ambassador to Sri Lanka Misukoshi Hidegi (29) called on Jaffna Chief Minister Vishwalingam Manivannan on Wednesday.",
        "Jaffna Municipal Commissioner ET Jayaseelan was also present at the meeting held at the Jaffna Municipal Council. The mayor also presented a memento to the Japanese ambassador.",
        "It is noteworthy that the Japanese Ambassador to Jaffna has been holding meetings with various parties regarding the current situation.",
        "Various issues were explored during this meeting. As the Mayor of Jaffna and on behalf of the people of Jaffna, I would like to thank Japan for the economic and development work that Japan has done in the past.",
        "Also during the period of peace in Sri Lanka, Japan made a significant contribution to the peace talks, especially with the Special Envoy to Sri Lanka Yasushi Akashi.",
        "Mayor Wiswalingam Manivannan also called on the Japanese Ambassador to the Government of Japan to present the Japanese Government's contribution to a permanent political settlement in Sri Lanka at present and to request the Government of Japan to use this opportunity to provide a comprehensive political settlement in Sri Lanka as a precondition for Japan's assistance to Sri Lanka in the current economic crisis."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Japan",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Japanese",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka Misukoshi Hidegi",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "29",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Jaffna",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Vishwalingam Manivannan",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Wednesday",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Jaffna Municipal",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ET Jayaseelan",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Jaffna Municipal Council",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Japanese",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Japanese",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Jaffna",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Jaffna",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Japan",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Japan",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Japan",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Yasushi Akashi",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Wiswalingam Manivannan",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Japanese",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Government of Japan",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Japanese Government's",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Japan",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "වත්මන් තත්ත්වය පිළිබඳව ජපාන තානාපතිවරයා යාපනය නගරාධිපතිවරයා සමඟ සාකච්ඡා කරයි",
      "author": "ඩිජිටල් මේසය 5",
      "body_lines": [
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ ජපාන තානාපති Misukoshi Hidegi (29) බදාදා යාපනය ප්‍රධාන අමාත්‍ය විශ්වලිංගම් මනිවන්නන් හමුවිය.",
        "යාපනය මහනගර සභාවේ පැවති මෙම රැස්වීමට යාපනය නාගරික කොමසාරිස් ඊ.ටී.ජයසීලන් ද එක්ව සිටියා. නගරාධිපතිවරයා විසින් ජපාන තානාපතිවරයා වෙත සමරු තිළිණයක් ද පිළිගැන්වීය.",
        "පවතින තත්ත්වය සම්බන්ධයෙන් යාපනයේ ජපාන තානාපතිවරයා විවිධ පාර්ශ්ව සමඟ සාකච්ඡා පවත්වමින් සිටීම විශේෂත්වයකි.",
        "මෙම හමුවේදී විවිධ ගැටලු පිළිබඳව සොයා බැලීය. යාපනයේ නගරාධිපතිවරයා ලෙසත් යාපනයේ ජනතාව වෙනුවෙන්ත් ජපානය පසුගිය කාලයේ සිදු කළ ආර්ථික හා සංවර්ධන කටයුතු පිළිබඳව ජපානයට ස්තුතිය පුද කරනවා.",
        "එසේම ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ සාම කාලය තුළ ජපානය සාම සාකච්ඡා සඳහා සුවිශේෂී දායකත්වයක් ලබා දුන්නේය, විශේෂයෙන් ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ විශේෂ නියෝජිත යසුෂි අකාෂි සමඟ.",
        "දැනට ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ ස්ථිර දේශපාලන විසඳුමක් සඳහා ජපන් රජයේ දායකත්වය ඉදිරිපත් කරන ලෙසත්, ශ්‍රී ලංකාව තුළ පුළුල් දේශපාලන විසඳුමක් ලබාදීමට මෙම අවස්ථාව ප්‍රයෝජනයට ගන්නා ලෙස ජපාන රජයෙන් ඉල්ලා සිටින ලෙසත් නගරාධිපති විශ්වලිංගම් මනිවන්නන් ජපාන රජයේ ජපාන තානාපතිවරයාගෙන් ඉල්ලා සිටියේය. වත්මන් ආර්ථික අර්බුදයේදී ජපානය ශ්‍රී ලංකාවට ලබා දෙන සහය සඳහා පූර්ව කොන්දේසියක් ලෙස."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ජපානය",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ජපන්",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka Misukoshi Hidegi",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "29",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "යාපනය",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "විශ්වලිංගම් මනිවන්නන්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "බදාදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "යාපනය මහ නගර සභාව",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඊ.ටී.ජයසීලන්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "යාපනය මහ නගර සභාව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජපන්",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ජපන්",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "යාපනය",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "යාපනය",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජපානය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජපානය",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජපානය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Yasushi Akashi",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "විශ්වලිංගම් මනිවන්නන්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජපන්",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජපාන රජය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජපන් රජයේ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජපානය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "ஜப்பான் தூதுவர் யாழ் மாநகர சபை முதல்வருடன் சமகால நிலைமைகள் தொடர்பில் கலந்துரையாடல்",
      "author": "Digital Desk 5",
      "body_lines": [
        "இலங்கைக்கான ஜப்பான் தூதுவர் மிசுகோஷி ஹிடேகி (29) புதன் கிழமை  யாழ் மாநகர முதல்வர் விஸ்வலிங்கம் மணிவண்ணனை சந்தித்து கலந்துரையாடினார்.",
        "யாழ் மாநகர சபையில் இடம்பெற்ற இந்த சந்திப்பில் யாழ் மாநகர ஆணையாளர் இ.த.ஜெயசீலனும் உடனிருந்தார். இதன்போது மாநகர முதல்வரால் ஜப்பான் தூதுவருக்கு நினைவுப்பரிசும் வழங்கப்பட்டது.",
        "யாழ்ப்பாணத்திற்கு விஜயம் செய்துள்ள ஜப்பான் தூதுவர் சமகால நிலைமைகள் தொடர்பில் பல்வேறுபட்ட தரப்புக்களுடனும் சந்திப்புக்களை மேற்கொண்டு வருகின்றமை குறிப்பிடத்தக்கது.",
        "இச் சந்திப்பின்போது பல்வேறு விடயங்கள் பற்றி ஆராயப்பட்டது. ஜப்பான் கடந்த காலங்களில் யாழ் மாநகர சபையின் எல்லைக்குள் செய்துவந்த பொருளாதார மற்றும் அபிவிருத்தி பணிகளுக்கு யாழ் மாநகர முதல்வர் என்ற வகையிலும் மாநகர மக்கள் சார்பிலும் நன்றி தெரிவிக்கப்பட்டது.",
        "அத்துடன் இலங்கையில் சமாதானம் நிலவிய காலத்தில் ஜப்பானால் சமாதான பேச்சுவார்த்தைக்கு காத்திரமான பங்களிப்பு செய்யப்பட்டது குறிப்பாக இலங்கைக்கான விசேட தூதுவர் யசுசி அகாஷி அந்த பணிகளிலே ஈடுபட்டிருந்தார்.",
        "அதேபோன்று தற்சமயமும் இலங்கையில் நிரந்தர அரசியல் தீர்வு ஒன்றுக்கு ஜப்பானிய அரசு பங்களிப்பு செய்ய வேண்டும் என்றும் தற்போதைய பொருளாதார நெருக்கடியில் இலங்கைக்கு ஜப்பான் உதவி வருகின்ற நிலையில் இச் சந்தர்ப்பத்தை பயன்படுத்தி முன்நிபந்தனையாக இலங்கையில் ஒரு சமஷ்டி அடிப்படையிலான அரசியல் தீர்வு வழங்கப்பட வேண்டும் என்ற கோரிக்கையை இலங்கை அரசுக்கு ஜப்பானிய அரசு விடுக்க வேண்டும் என்று மாநகர முதல்வர் விஸ்வலிங்கம் மணிவண்ணன் ஜப்பானிய தூதுவரிடம் கேட்டுக்கொண்டார்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ஜப்பான்",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ஜப்பானியர்",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka Misukoshi Hidegi",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "29",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "யாழ்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "விஸ்வலிங்கம் மணிவண்ணன்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "புதன்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "யாழ்ப்பாண மாநகரசபை",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஈ.டி.ஜெயசீலன்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "யாழ்ப்பாண மாநகர சபை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜப்பானியர்",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஜப்பானியர்",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "யாழ்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "யாழ்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜப்பான்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜப்பான்",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜப்பான்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Yasushi Akashi",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "விஸ்வலிங்கம் மணிவண்ணன்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜப்பானியர்",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜப்பான் அரசாங்கம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜப்பானிய அரசாங்கத்தின்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜப்பான்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}