{
  "newspaper_id": "lankadeepa-lk",
  "url": "https://www.lankadeepa.lk/latest_news/මෙරට-තත්ත්වය-ගැන-රුසියාවෙන්-ප්‍රකාශයක්/1-616349",
  "time_ut": 1657701380,
  "original_lang": "si",
  "original_title": "මෙරට තත්ත්වය ගැන රුසියාවෙන් ප්‍රකාශයක්",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "A statement from Russia about the situation in this country",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "The spokesperson of the Russian Ministry of Foreign Affairs Mrs. Maria Zakharova said that the current situation in Sri Lanka is an internal matter of Sri Lanka.",
        "Mrs. Maria Sakharova stated that Sri Lanka is a friendly state of Russia and that the political process of Sri Lanka will continue in accordance with the existing laws and constitution of the country and that Russia believes that the new administration will take the necessary measures to rescue Sri Lanka from the current economic crisis.",
        "Mrs. Sakharova said that she hopes that the current situation in Sri Lanka will return to normal soon."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Russia",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "the Russian Ministry of Foreign Affairs",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Maria Zakharova",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Maria Sakharova",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Russia",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Russia",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sakharova",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "මෙරට තත්ත්වය ගැන රුසියාවෙන් ප්‍රකාශයක්",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ ඇති වී තිබෙන වත්මන් තත්ත්වය ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ අභ්‍යන්තර කටයුත්තක් බව රුසියානු විදේශ කටයුතු අමාත්‍යංශයේ ප්‍රකාශිකා මරියා සකරෝවා මහත්මිය ප්‍රකාශ කළාය.",
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකාව රුසියාවේ මිත්‍ර රාජ්‍යයක් බවත් ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ දේශපාලන ක්‍රියාවලිය රටේ පවතින නීතියට මෙන්ම ආණ්ඩුක්‍රම ව්‍යවස්ථාවට අනුකූලව ඉදිරියට යනු ඇති බවත් පත්වන නව පාලනාධිකාරය වත්මන් ආර්ථික අර්බුදයෙන් ශ්‍රී ලංකාව මුදවා ගැනීම සඳහා අවශ්‍ය ක්‍රියාමාර්ග ගනු ඇතැයි රුසියාව විශ්වාස කරන බවත් මරියා සකරෝවා මහත්මිය සඳහන් කළාය.",
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ වත්මන් තත්ත්වය ඉතා ඉක්මණින් සාමාන්‍ය තත්ත්වය පත්වේ යැයි බලාපොරොත්තු වන බව සකරෝවා මහත්මිය පැවසුවාය."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "රුසියාව",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "රුසියානු විදේශ කටයුතු අමාත්යාංශය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "මාරියා සකාරෝවා",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "මාරියා සකාරෝවා",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "රුසියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "රුසියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "සකාරෝවා",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "இந்த நாட்டின் நிலைமை குறித்து ரஷ்யாவின் அறிக்கை",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "இலங்கையின் தற்போதைய நிலைமை இலங்கையின் உள்விவகாரம் என ரஷ்ய வெளிவிவகார அமைச்சின் பேச்சாளர் திருமதி மரியா சகரோவா தெரிவித்துள்ளார்.",
        "இலங்கை ரஷ்யாவின் நட்பு நாடு என்றும், இலங்கையின் அரசியல் செயல்முறை நாட்டின் தற்போதைய சட்டங்கள் மற்றும் அரசியலமைப்பின்படி தொடரும் என்றும், புதிய நிர்வாகம் மீட்க தேவையான நடவடிக்கைகளை எடுக்கும் என ரஷ்யா நம்புவதாகவும் திருமதி மரியா சகாரோவா தெரிவித்தார். தற்போதைய பொருளாதார நெருக்கடியில் இருந்து இலங்கை.",
        "இலங்கையின் தற்போதைய நிலைமை விரைவில் வழமைக்குத் திரும்பும் என நம்புவதாக திருமதி சாகரோவா தெரிவித்தார்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ரஷ்யா",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ரஷ்ய வெளியுறவு அமைச்சகம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "மரியா ஜகரோவா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "மரியா சகரோவா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரஷ்யா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரஷ்யா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "சகரோவா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}