{
  "newspaper_id": "daily-mirror-lk",
  "url": "https://www.dailymirror.lk/top_story/GR-to-return-to-SL-in-3-months-as-options-run-out/155-242850",
  "time_ut": 1660189760,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "GR to return to SL in 3 months as options run out",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "GR to return to SL in 3 months as options run out",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "- GR refrains from seeking asylum in Middle East after no positive response",
        "Former President Gotabaya Rajapaksa will return back to Sri Lanka in November after his 90 day Thai visa runs out, and as he runs out of options to receive temporary shelter in another country, the Daily Mirror learns.",
        "Political sources said that Rajapaksa will leave Singapore today and visit Thailand where he will stay for 90 days on a visit visa and he had not sought asylum in any country.",
        "Thai Prime Minister Prayut Chan O Cha yesterday confirmed to foreign media that Rajapaksa would be granted entry into Thailand on humanitarian grounds and they had been promised that it was only a temporary stay.",
        "The Sri Lankan government had directly made an appeal on behalf of the ousted President and sought permission to allow Rajapaksa to seek temporary shelter in Thailand.",
        "From the time Rajapaksa left Colombo last month for the Maldives, the Sri Lankan government has been in touch with the Maldives, Singapore and now the Thailand government, making arrangements for Rajapaksa to remain in those countries temporarily.",
        "However as the 90 day Thai visa runs out in November, political sources said that Rajapaksa will return back to Sri Lanka as he was a Sri Lankan citizen and had all the legal right to remain in the country.",
        "The Daily Mirror also learns that the multiple costs for the Rajapaksas to flee from the country was borne by himself and his son Manoj Rajapaksa and no state funds had been utilized thus far except for the Air Force flight that was used to transport him and his wife from Colombo to Male last month.",
        "The Rajapaksas, with their high connections overseas, also have rich businessmen who are funding the former President's accommodation. It is still unclear what accommodation arrangements have been made in Thailand for Gotabaya Rajapaksa and his wife.",
        "Although several attempts had been made for Rajapaksa to seek asylum in the Middle East, he had not received any favourable response which is why a decision has now been taken for him to return back to Sri Lanka in November. (JAMILA HUSAIN)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "3 months",
          "label": "DATE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Middle East",
            "label": "LOC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Gotabaya Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "November",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "90 day",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Thai",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Daily Mirror",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Rajapaksa",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Singapore",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Thailand",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "90 days",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Thai",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Prayut Chan",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "yesterday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Rajapaksa",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Thailand",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lankan",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Thailand",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Colombo",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "last month",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Maldives",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lankan",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Maldives",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Singapore",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Thailand",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the 90 day",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Thai",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "November",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Rajapaksa",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "The Daily Mirror",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Rajapaksas",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Manoj Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Air Force",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "last month",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Rajapaksas",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Thailand",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Gotabaya Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Rajapaksa",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Middle East",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "November",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "විකල්ප අවසන් වන බැවින් මාස 3 කින් නැවත ශ්‍රී ලංකාවට පැමිණීමට GR",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "- GR කිසිදු ධනාත්මක ප්‍රතිචාරයක් නොලැබීමෙන් පසු මැදපෙරදිග සරණාගතභාවය ලබා ගැනීමෙන් වැළකී සිටියි",
        "දින 90 ක තායි වීසා බලපත්‍රය අවසන් වීමෙන් පසු හිටපු ජනාධිපති ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ නොවැම්බර් මාසයේදී නැවත ශ්‍රී ලංකාවට පැමිණෙනු ඇති අතර ඔහුට වෙනත් රටක තාවකාලික නවාතැන් ගැනීමට විකල්ප නොමැති බැවින් ඩේලි මිරර් වෙත වාර්තා වේ.",
        "රාජපක්ෂ අද සිංගප්පූරුවෙන් පිටත්ව තායිලන්තයට පැමිණෙන බවත් එහිදී දින 90ක් සංචාරයක වීසා මත රැඳී සිටින බවත් ඔහු කිසිදු රටක සරණාගතභාවය පතා නොමැති බවත් දේශපාලන ආරංචි මාර්ග සඳහන් කළේය.",
        "මානුෂීය හේතූන් මත රාජපක්ෂට තායිලන්තයට ඇතුළු වීමට අවසර දෙන බව තායි අගමැති ප්‍රයුත් චාන් ඕ චා ඊයේ විදෙස් මාධ්‍ය වෙත තහවුරු කළ අතර එය තාවකාලික රැඳී සිටීමක් පමණක් බවට ඔවුන්ට පොරොන්දු වී තිබේ.",
        "බලයෙන් පහකළ ජනාධිපතිවරයා වෙනුවෙන් ශ්‍රී ලංකා රජය සෘජුවම අභියාචනයක් ඉදිරිපත් කර රාජපක්ෂට තායිලන්තයේ තාවකාලික නවාතැන් ගැනීමට අවසර දෙන ලෙස ඉල්ලා තිබුණි.",
        "පසුගිය මාසයේ රාජපක්ෂ කොළඹින් මාලදිවයිනට ගිය අවස්ථාවේ සිට ශ්‍රී ලංකා රජය මාලදිවයින, සිංගප්පූරුව සහ දැන් තායිලන්ත රජය සමඟ සම්බන්ධ වෙමින් රාජපක්ෂට තාවකාලිකව එම රටවල රැඳී සිටීමට කටයුතු සම්පාදනය කළේය.",
        "කෙසේ වෙතත් දින 90ක තායි වීසා බලපත්‍රය නොවැම්බර් මාසයේදී අවසන් වන බැවින්, දේශපාලන ආරංචි මාර්ග සඳහන් කළේ රාජපක්ෂ ශ්‍රී ලාංකික පුරවැසියෙකු බැවින් සහ රට තුළ රැඳී සිටීමට නීත්‍යානුකූල අයිතිය ඇති බැවින් ඔහු නැවත ශ්‍රී ලංකාවට පැමිණෙනු ඇති බවයි.",
        "රාජපක්ෂලාට රටින් පලායාමට බහුවිධ වියදම් දැරුවේ ඔහු සහ ඔහුගේ පුත් මනෝජ් රාජපක්ෂ බවත් ඔහු සහ ඔහුගේ බිරිඳ ප්‍රවාහනය කිරීමට යොදාගත් ගුවන් හමුදා ගුවන් යානය හැර මෙතෙක් රාජ්‍ය මුදල් යොදවා නොමැති බවත් ඩේලි මිරර් වෙත වාර්තා වේ. පසුගිය මාසයේ කොළඹ සිට මාලේ දක්වා.",
        "විදේශයන්හි ඉහළ සම්බන්ධතා ඇති රාජපක්ෂලාට හිටපු ජනාධිපතිවරයාගේ නවාතැනට මුදල් සපයන ධනවත් ව්‍යාපාරිකයන් ද සිටිති. ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ මහතාට සහ ඔහුගේ බිරිඳට තායිලන්තයේ නවාතැන් පහසුකම් සලසා ඇත්තේ කුමක් ද යන්න තවමත් පැහැදිලි නැත.",
        "රාජපක්ෂට මැදපෙරදිග රැකවරණ පතා යාමට කිහිප වතාවක්ම උත්සාහ කළද ඔහුට යහපත් ප්‍රතිචාරයක් නොලැබුණු නිසා නොවැම්බර් මාසයේදී නැවත ශ්‍රී ලංකාවට පැමිණීමට දැන් තීරණයක් ගෙන ඇත. (ජමිලා හුසේන්)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "මාස 3 යි",
          "label": "DATE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "මැද පෙරදිග",
            "label": "LOC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "නොවැම්බර්",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "දින 90 යි",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "තායි",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඩේලි මිරර්",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "සිංගප්පූරුව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "තායිලන්තය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "දින 90 යි",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "තායි",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ප්‍රයුත් චාන්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඊයේ",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "තායිලන්තය",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලාංකික",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "තායිලන්තය",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "කොළඹ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "පසුගිය මාසයේ",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මාලදිවයින",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලාංකික",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "මාලදිවයින",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "සිංගප්පූරුව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "තායිලන්තය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "දින 90",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "තායි",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "නොවැම්බර්",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ඩේලි මිරර්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "රාජපක්ෂලා",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මනෝජ් රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගුවන් හමුදාව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "පසුගිය මාසයේ",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "රාජපක්ෂලා",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "තායිලන්තය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මැද පෙරදිග",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "නොවැම්බර්",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "விருப்பத்தேர்வுகள் முடிந்துவிட்டதால் 3 மாதங்களில் SLக்குத் திரும்ப GR",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "- சாதகமான பதில் கிடைக்காததால் மத்திய கிழக்கில் தஞ்சம் கோருவதை ஜி.ஆர்",
        "முன்னாள் ஜனாதிபதி கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ச தனது 90 நாள் தாய்லாந்து விசா முடிந்து நவம்பர் மாதம் மீண்டும் இலங்கை திரும்புவார் என்றும், அவருக்கு வேறு நாட்டில் தற்காலிக தங்குமிடம் கிடைப்பதற்கான வாய்ப்புகள் இல்லாததால், டெய்லி மிரர் செய்தி வெளியிட்டுள்ளது.",
        "ராஜபக்சே இன்று சிங்கப்பூரில் இருந்து புறப்பட்டு தாய்லாந்து சென்று அங்கு விசிட் விசாவில் 90 நாட்கள் தங்குவார் என்றும் அவர் எந்த நாட்டிலும் தஞ்சம் கோரவில்லை என்றும் அரசியல் வட்டாரங்கள் தெரிவித்தன.",
        "தாய்லாந்து பிரதமர் பிரயுத் சான் ஓ சா, மனிதாபிமான அடிப்படையில் ராஜபக்ச தாய்லாந்திற்குள் நுழைய அனுமதிக்கப்படுவார் என்று வெளிநாட்டு ஊடகங்களுக்கு நேற்று உறுதிப்படுத்தினார், மேலும் அது தற்காலிக தங்குமிடம் மட்டுமே என்று அவர்களுக்கு உறுதியளிக்கப்பட்டது.",
        "பதவி நீக்கம் செய்யப்பட்ட அதிபர் சார்பில் இலங்கை அரசு நேரடியாக மேல்முறையீடு செய்து ராஜபக்சேவை தாய்லாந்தில் தற்காலிகமாக தங்கவைக்க அனுமதி கோரியது.",
        "கடந்த மாதம் ராஜபக்சே கொழும்பில் இருந்து மாலத்தீவுக்கு சென்றதில் இருந்து, இலங்கை அரசு மாலத்தீவு, சிங்கப்பூர் மற்றும் தற்போது தாய்லாந்து அரசுடன் தொடர்பு கொண்டு, ராஜபக்சேவை அந்த நாடுகளில் தற்காலிகமாக தங்க வைப்பதற்கான ஏற்பாடுகளை செய்து வருகிறது.",
        "எவ்வாறாயினும், நவம்பர் மாதம் 90 நாள் தாய்லாந்து விசா காலாவதியாகிவிட்டதால், ராஜபக்சே இலங்கைக்கு திரும்புவார் என்று அரசியல் வட்டாரங்கள் தெரிவித்தன, ஏனெனில் அவர் ஒரு இலங்கை குடிமகன் மற்றும் நாட்டில் தங்குவதற்கான அனைத்து சட்டப்பூர்வ உரிமையும் அவருக்கு உள்ளது.",
        "ராஜபக்சக்கள் நாட்டை விட்டு தப்பிச் செல்வதற்கான பல செலவுகளை அவரும் அவரது மகன் மனோஜ் ராஜபக்ஷவும் ஏற்றுக்கொண்டதாகவும், அவரையும் அவரது மனைவியையும் ஏற்றிச் செல்ல விமானப்படை விமானத்தை தவிர வேறு எந்த அரச நிதியும் இதுவரை பயன்படுத்தப்படவில்லை என்றும் டெய்லி மிரர் அறிகிறது. கடந்த மாதம் கொழும்பில் இருந்து மாலே.",
        "ராஜபக்சக்களுக்கு வெளிநாடுகளில் உயர் தொடர்புகள் உள்ளன, முன்னாள் ஜனாதிபதியின் தங்குமிடத்திற்கு நிதியளிக்கும் பணக்கார வர்த்தகர்களும் உள்ளனர். கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ச மற்றும் அவரது மனைவிக்கு தாய்லாந்தில் என்ன தங்குமிட ஏற்பாடுகள் செய்யப்பட்டுள்ளன என்பது இன்னும் தெளிவாகத் தெரியவில்லை.",
        "மத்திய கிழக்கில் ராஜபக்சே தஞ்சம் கோருவதற்கு பல முயற்சிகள் மேற்கொள்ளப்பட்ட போதிலும், அவருக்கு சாதகமான பதில் எதுவும் கிடைக்காததால், நவம்பரில் அவர் மீண்டும் இலங்கை திரும்புவதற்கான முடிவு எடுக்கப்பட்டுள்ளது. (ஜமிலா ஹுசைன்)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "3 மாதங்கள்",
          "label": "DATE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "மத்திய கிழக்கு",
            "label": "LOC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "நவம்பர்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "90 நாள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "தாய்",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "டெய்லி மிரர்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ராஜபக்சே",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "சிங்கப்பூர்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "தாய்லாந்து",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "90 நாட்கள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "தாய்",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "பிரயுத் சான்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "நேற்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ராஜபக்சே",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "தாய்லாந்து",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ராஜபக்சே",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "தாய்லாந்து",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ராஜபக்சே",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "கொழும்பு",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "கடந்த மாதம்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "மாலத்தீவுகள்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "மாலத்தீவுகள்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சிங்கப்பூர்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "தாய்லாந்து",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ராஜபக்சே",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "90 நாள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "தாய்",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "நவம்பர்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ராஜபக்சே",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "டெய்லி மிரர்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ராஜபக்சேக்கள்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "மனோஜ் ராஜபக்ஷ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "விமானப்படை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "கடந்த மாதம்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ராஜபக்சேக்கள்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "தாய்லாந்து",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ராஜபக்சே",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "மத்திய கிழக்கு",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "நவம்பர்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}