{
  "newspaper_id": "economy-next-com",
  "url": "https://economynext.com/sri-lanka-president-emails-resignation-from-singapore-97420/",
  "time_ut": 1657811760,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Sri Lanka President emails resignation from Singapore",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Sri Lanka President emails resignation from Singapore",
      "author": "",
      "body_lines": [
        "ECONOMYNEXT – Sri Lanka’s embattled president Gotabaya Rajapaksa, who has fled the country fearing for his life, has sent his resignation letter via email to Parliament Speaker Mahinda Yapa Abeywardena, the Speaker’s office said.",
        "However, an official announcement was delayed until the Speaker’s office re-checked the authenticity and legality.",
        "Rajapaksa, who fled the country and flew to Male in an Air Force flight on Wednesday early morning was expected to send the letter later on the same day. However, it was delayed as Rajapaksa, was not able to reach his “final destination”, his close allies have told Economy Next.",
        "The letter was sent via email to the Speaker and an official who is aware of the matter said they are checking the legality of the latter and if such letter could be sent via email.",
        "“The Speaker has received the resignation latter of President Gotabaya Rajapaksa via the office of Sri Lankan embassy in Singapore,” Speaker’s Media Secretary Indunil Abeywardena said in a tatement.",
        "“After clarifying the accuracy and finalising the legality of the letter, the speaker will officially announce with regard t this by tomoorow.”",
        "However, a government source said the original letter would be handed over to the Speaker through a key official of Rajapaksa staff.",
        "Rajapaksa sent the letter after he reached Singapore late on Thursday from Maldives, flying in a Saudi Arabian Airline. His stay in Maldives was facilitated by the Ibrahim Mohamed Solih’s administration in Maldives with its Parliament Speaker Mohamed Nasheed personally visiting to the Male airport to receive him amid many Sri Lankans living in Male protested against the move.",
        "“President GR has resigned. I hope Sri Lanka can now move forward,” Nasheed tweeted.",
        "“I believe the President would not have resigned if he were still in Sri Lanka, and fearful of losing his life. I commend the thoughtful actions of the Govt of Maldives. My best wishes to the people of Sri Lanka. ”",
        "🇱🇰 President GR has resigned. I hope Sri Lanka can now move forward. I believe the President would not have resigned if he were still in Sri Lanka, and fearful of losing his life. I commend the thoughtful actions of the Govt of Maldives. My best wishes to the people of Sri Lanka.",
        "Rajapaksa was forced to flee after tens of thousands of protesters stormed into his official residence on Saturday (09). The protesters had demanded his resignation for his policy failures after his government printed trillions of rupees which eventually caused Balance of payment crisis, dollars shortage and steep decline in foreign currency reserves.",
        "The lack of dollars later led to shortage of essentials like food, medicine, cooking gas, and essential foods including milk powder. His policy on overnight chemical fertilizer policy ban led to a food shortage and the island nation is facing a looming food shortage.",
        "It was not immediately clear if Rajapaksa would request for political asylum in any foreign country. Singapore government confirmed his entry into city nation.",
        "“In response to media queries, it is confirmed that Mr Rajapaksa has been allowed entry into Singapore on a private visit,” the Singapore’s Ministry of Foreign Affairs said in a statement.",
        "“He has not asked for asylum and neither has he been granted any asylum. Singapore generally does not grant requests for asylum.”",
        "Sources close to the president have said he was aiming for a country in the Middle East. (Colombo/July 14/2022)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Sri Lanka",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "Singapore",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka’s",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Gotabaya Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Mahinda Yapa Abeywardena",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "Rajapaksa",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Air Force",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Wednesday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "early morning",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "Rajapaksa",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Economy Next",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "Gotabaya Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lankan",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Singapore",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Indunil Abeywardena",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "Rajapaksa",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Rajapaksa",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Singapore",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Thursday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Maldives",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Saudi",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Maldives",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Ibrahim Mohamed Solih’s",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Maldives",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Mohamed Nasheed",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Male",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lankans",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "tens of thousands",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Saturday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "09",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "trillions",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "overnight",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Singapore",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Singapore",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Singapore",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ministry of Foreign Affairs",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Singapore",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the Middle East",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "Colombo",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "ශ්‍රී ලංකා ජනාධිපතිවරයා සිංගප්පූරුවෙන් ඉල්ලා අස්වීමේ ලිපිය ඊමේල් කරයි",
      "author": "",
      "body_lines": [
        "ECONOMYNEXT - ජීවිතය ගැන බියෙන් රටින් පැන ගොස් සිටින ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ ගැටී සිටින ජනාධිපති ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ මහතා සිය ඉල්ලා අස්වීමේ ලිපිය විද්‍යුත් තැපෑලෙන් පාර්ලිමේන්තු කථානායක මහින්ද යාපා අබේවර්ධන වෙත යවා ඇති බව කථානායක කාර්යාලය පවසයි.",
        "කෙසේ වෙතත්, කථානායක කාර්යාලය සත්‍යතාව සහ නීත්‍යානුකූලභාවය නැවත පරීක්ෂා කරන තෙක් නිල නිවේදනය ප්‍රමාද විය.",
        "බදාදා අලුයම ගුවන් හමුදාවේ ගුවන් යානයකින් රටින් පැන ගොස් මාලේ බලා ගිය රාජපක්‍ෂ මහතා එදිනම පසුව ලිපිය යැවීමට බලාපොරොත්තු විය. කෙසේ වෙතත්, එය ප්‍රමාද වූයේ රාජපක්ෂට ඔහුගේ “අවසාන ගමනාන්තයට” ළඟා වීමට නොහැකි වූ නිසා බව ඔහුගේ සමීප හිතවතුන් ඉකොනොමි නෙක්ස්ට් වෙත පවසා ඇත.",
        "කථානායකවරයා වෙත විද්‍යුත් තැපෑලෙන් ලිපිය යොමු කර ඇති අතර, එහි නීත්‍යානුකූලභාවය පිළිබඳව සොයා බලන බවත් එවැනි ලිපියක් විද්‍යුත් තැපෑලෙන් එවිය හැකි දැයි සොයා බලන බවත් ඒ පිළිබඳව දන්නා නිලධාරියෙක් පැවසීය.",
        "ජනාධිපති ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ මහතාගේ ඉල්ලා අස්වීම කථානායකවරයාට සිංගප්පූරුවේ ශ්‍රී ලංකා තානාපති කාර්යාලය හරහා ලැබී ඇති බව කථානායක මාධ්‍ය ලේකම් ඉඳුනිල් අබේවර්ධන මහතා නිවේදනයක් නිකුත් කරමින් කියා සිටියේය.",
        "\"ලිපියේ නිරවද්‍යතාවය පැහැදිලි කිරීමෙන් සහ නීත්‍යානුකූලභාවය අවසන් කිරීමෙන් පසු, කථානායකවරයා මේ සම්බන්ධයෙන් හෙට නිල වශයෙන් ප්‍රකාශ කරනු ඇත.\"",
        "කෙසේ වෙතත්, රජයේ ආරංචි මාර්ග පැවසුවේ රාජපක්ෂ කාර්ය මණ්ඩලයේ ප්‍රධාන නිලධාරියෙකු මාර්ගයෙන් මුල් ලිපිය කථානායකවරයා වෙත භාරදීමට නියමිත බවයි.",
        "මාලදිවයිනේ සිට බ්‍රහස්පතින්දා සවස සෞදි අරාබි ගුවන් සේවයකින් සිංගප්පූරුවට ළඟා වූ පසු රාජපක්ෂ මෙම ලිපිය යවා ඇත. ඔහුට මාලදිවයිනේ රැඳී සිටීමට මාලදිවයිනේ ඉබ්‍රාහිම් මොහොමඩ් සෝලිගේ පරිපාලනය පහසුකම් සලසන අතර එහි පාර්ලිමේන්තු කථානායක මොහොමඩ් නෂීඩ් ඔහු පිළිගැනීමට මාලේ ගුවන් තොටුපළට පෞද්ගලිකව පැමිණියේ මාලේ හි වෙසෙන බොහෝ ශ්‍රී ලාංකිකයන් මෙම පියවරට විරෝධය පළ කරමිනි.",
        "“ජනාධිපති ජී.ආර්. ශ්‍රී ලංකාවට දැන් ඉදිරියට යා හැකි යැයි මම බලාපොරොත්තු වෙමි,” නෂීඩ් ට්විටර් පණිවුඩයක් නිකුත් කළේය.",
        "“ජනාධිපතිවරයා තවමත් ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ සිටියා නම් සහ ජීවිතය නැති වේ යැයි බියෙන් ඉල්ලා අස් නොවනු ඇතැයි මම විශ්වාස කරමි. මාලදිවයින් රජයේ කල්පනාකාරී ක්‍රියා කලාපය මම අගය කරමි. ශ්‍රී ලංකාවාසී ජනතාවට මගේ සුභ පැතුම්. ”",
        "🇱🇰 ජනාධිපති ජී.ආර්. ශ්‍රී ලංකාවට දැන් ඉදිරියට යා හැකි යැයි මම බලාපොරොත්තු වෙමි. මම විශ්වාස කරනවා ජනාධිපතිතුමා තවමත් ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ සිටියා නම්, ජීවිතය නැති වේ යැයි බියෙන් ඉල්ලා අස් වන්නේ නැහැ. මාලදිවයින් රජයේ කල්පනාකාරී ක්‍රියා කලාපය මම අගය කරමි. ශ්‍රී ලංකාවාසී ජනතාවට මගේ සුභ පැතුම්.",
        "සෙනසුරාදා (09) දස දහස් සංඛ්‍යාත විරෝධතාකරුවන් ඔහුගේ නිල නිවසට කඩා වැදීමෙන් පසු රාජපක්ෂට පලා යාමට සිදුවිය. ඔහුගේ රජය රුපියල් ට්‍රිලියන ගනනක් මුද්‍රණය කිරීමෙන් පසුව ගෙවුම් ශේෂ අර්බුදය, ඩොලර් හිඟය සහ විදේශ මුදල් සංචිතවල දැඩි පහත වැටීමක් ඇති වූ පසු ඔහුගේ ප්‍රතිපත්තිමය අසාර්ථකත්වය වෙනුවෙන් ඔහු ඉල්ලා අස්වන ලෙස විරෝධතාකරුවන් ඉල්ලා තිබුණි.",
        "ඩොලර් හිඟය පසුකාලීනව ආහාර, ඖෂධ, ඉවුම් පිහුම් ගෑස් සහ කිරිපිටි ඇතුළු අත්‍යවශ්‍ය ආහාර වැනි අත්‍යවශ්‍ය ද්‍රව්‍ය හිඟයකට හේතු විය. එක රැයකින් රසායනික පොහොර ප්‍රතිපත්ති තහනම පිළිබඳ ඔහුගේ ප්‍රතිපත්තිය ආහාර හිඟයකට තුඩු දුන් අතර දිවයින ජාතිය ආහාර හිඟයකට මුහුණ දී සිටී.",
        "රාජපක්ෂ කිසියම් විදේශ රටක දේශපාලන රැකවරණ ඉල්ලා සිටින්නේද යන්න ක්ෂණිකව පැහැදිලි නොවීය. සිංගප්පූරු රජය ඔහු නගරයට ඇතුළු වීම තහවුරු කළේය.",
        "\"මාධ්‍ය ප්‍රශ්නවලට ප්‍රතිචාර වශයෙන්, රාජපක්ෂ මහතාට පෞද්ගලික සංචාරයක් සඳහා සිංගප්පූරුවට ඇතුළු වීමට අවසර දී ඇති බව තහවුරු වේ\" යනුවෙන් සිංගප්පූරු විදේශ කටයුතු අමාත්‍යාංශය නිවේදනයක් නිකුත් කරමින් කියා සිටියේය.",
        "“ඔහු සරණාගතභාවය ඉල්ලා නැත, ඔහුට සරණාගතභාවය ලබා දී නැත. සිංගප්පූරුව සාමාන්‍යයෙන් සරණාගත ඉල්ලීම් ලබා දෙන්නේ නැත.",
        "ජනාධිපතිවරයාට සමීප ආරංචි මාර්ග පවසා ඇත්තේ ඔහු මැදපෙරදිග රටක් ඉලක්ක කර ගනිමින් සිටින බවයි. (කොළඹ/ජූලි 14/2022)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "සිංගප්පූරුව",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "මහින්ද යාපා අබේවර්ධන",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගුවන් හමුදා",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "බදාදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "හිමිදිරි උදෑසන",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ආර්ථිකය ඊළඟ",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලාංකික",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "සිංගප්පූරුව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉඳුනිල් අබේවර්ධන",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "සිංගප්පූරුව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "බ්රහස්පතින්දා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මාලදිවයින",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "සෞදි",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "මාලදිවයින",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඊබ්‍රාහිම් මොහොමඩ් සෝලිගේ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "මාලදිවයින",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "මොහොමඩ් නෂීඩ්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "පිරිමි",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලාංකිකයන්",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "දස දහස් ගණනක්",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "සෙනසුරාදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "09",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ට්රිලියන",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "එක රැයකින්",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "සිංගප්පූරුව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "සිංගප්පූරුව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "සිංගප්පූරුව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "විදේශ කටයුතු අමාත්යංශය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "සිංගප්පූරුව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "මැද පෙරදිග",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "කොළඹ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "இலங்கை ஜனாதிபதி சிங்கப்பூரில் இருந்து இராஜினாமா கடிதம்",
      "author": "",
      "body_lines": [
        "பொருளாதாரம் – உயிருக்கு பயந்து நாட்டை விட்டு வெளியேறிய இலங்கையின் ஜனாதிபதி கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ச, தனது இராஜினாமா கடிதத்தை பாராளுமன்ற சபாநாயகர் மஹிந்த யாப்பா அபேவர்தனவுக்கு மின்னஞ்சல் மூலம் அனுப்பியுள்ளதாக சபாநாயகர் அலுவலகம் தெரிவித்துள்ளது.",
        "எவ்வாறாயினும், சபாநாயகர் அலுவலகம் நம்பகத்தன்மை மற்றும் சட்டபூர்வமான தன்மையை மீண்டும் சரிபார்க்கும் வரை அதிகாரப்பூர்வ அறிவிப்பு தாமதமானது.",
        "புதன்கிழமை அதிகாலை விமானப்படை விமானத்தில் நாட்டை விட்டு வெளியேறி மாலே சென்ற ராஜபக்சே, அன்றைய தினம் கடிதத்தை அனுப்புவார் என்று எதிர்பார்க்கப்பட்டது. இருப்பினும், ராஜபக்சே தனது \"இறுதி இலக்கை\" அடைய முடியாததால் அது தாமதமானது என்று அவரது நெருங்கிய கூட்டாளிகள் எகனாமி நெக்ஸ்ட் செய்தி நிறுவனத்திடம் கூறியுள்ளனர்.",
        "இந்த கடிதம் சபாநாயகருக்கு மின்னஞ்சல் மூலம் அனுப்பப்பட்டதுடன், இந்த விடயத்தை அறிந்த அதிகாரி ஒருவர், பிந்தையவற்றின் சட்டபூர்வமான தன்மையை சரிபார்த்து வருவதாகவும், அத்தகைய கடிதத்தை மின்னஞ்சல் மூலம் அனுப்ப முடியுமா என்றும் கூறினார்.",
        "ஜனாதிபதி கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்சவின் ராஜினாமா கடிதத்தை சிங்கப்பூரில் உள்ள இலங்கை தூதரகத்தின் ஊடாக சபாநாயகர் பெற்றுக்கொண்டார் என சபாநாயகரின் ஊடக செயலாளர் இந்துனில் அபேவர்தன தெரிவித்துள்ளார்.",
        "\"கடிதத்தின் துல்லியத்தை தெளிவுபடுத்தி, சட்டப்பூர்வமான தன்மையை இறுதி செய்த பிறகு, சபாநாயகர் இது தொடர்பாக நாளை அதிகாரப்பூர்வமாக அறிவிப்பார்.\"",
        "எவ்வாறாயினும், அசல் கடிதம் ராஜபக்சே ஊழியர்களின் முக்கிய அதிகாரி மூலம் சபாநாயகரிடம் ஒப்படைக்கப்படும் என்று அரசாங்க வட்டாரம் தெரிவித்துள்ளது.",
        "மாலத்தீவில் இருந்து வியாழன் தாமதமாக சவூதி அரேபிய ஏர்லைன்ஸில் சிங்கப்பூர் சென்றடைந்த பின்னர் ராஜபக்சே இந்தக் கடிதத்தை அனுப்பினார். இந்த நடவடிக்கைக்கு எதிராக மாலேயில் வசிக்கும் பல இலங்கையர்கள் எதிர்ப்பு தெரிவித்திருந்த நிலையில், மாலத்தீவில் உள்ள இப்ராஹிம் மொஹமட் சோலியின் நிர்வாகத்தால் மாலத்தீவில் அவர் தங்குவதற்கு அதன் பாராளுமன்ற சபாநாயகர் மொஹமட் நஷீத் தனிப்பட்ட முறையில் மாலே விமான நிலையத்திற்கு வருகை தந்தார்.",
        "“ஜனாதிபதி ஜி.ஆர். இலங்கை இப்போது முன்னேற முடியும் என்று நான் நம்புகிறேன்,” என்று நஷீட் ட்வீட் செய்துள்ளார்.",
        "“ஜனாதிபதி இலங்கையில் இருந்திருந்தால், தனது உயிரை இழக்க நேரிடும் என்ற அச்சத்தில் அவர் பதவி விலகியிருக்க மாட்டார் என்று நான் நம்புகிறேன். மாலத்தீவு அரசாங்கத்தின் சிந்தனைமிக்க நடவடிக்கைகளை நான் பாராட்டுகிறேன். இலங்கை மக்களுக்கு எனது வாழ்த்துகள். ”",
        "🇱🇰 தலைவர் ஜி.ஆர். இலங்கை இப்போது முன்னேற முடியும் என்று நம்புகிறேன். அவர் இன்னும் இலங்கையில் இருந்திருந்தால், தனது உயிரை இழக்க நேரிடும் என்ற அச்சத்தில் ஜனாதிபதி பதவி விலகியிருக்க மாட்டார் என்று நான் நம்புகிறேன். மாலத்தீவு அரசாங்கத்தின் சிந்தனைமிக்க நடவடிக்கைகளை நான் பாராட்டுகிறேன். இலங்கை மக்களுக்கு எனது வாழ்த்துகள்.",
        "பல்லாயிரக்கணக்கான எதிர்ப்பாளர்கள் சனிக்கிழமை (09) அவரது உத்தியோகபூர்வ இல்லத்திற்குள் நுழைந்ததைத் தொடர்ந்து ராஜபக்சே வெளியேற வேண்டிய கட்டாயம் ஏற்பட்டது. அவரது அரசாங்கம் டிரில்லியன் கணக்கான ரூபாய்களை அச்சடித்ததையடுத்து அவரது கொள்கை தோல்விகளுக்காக அவர் ராஜினாமா செய்யுமாறு போராட்டக்காரர்கள் கோரிக்கை விடுத்தனர், இது இறுதியில் பணம் செலுத்தும் நெருக்கடி, டாலர் பற்றாக்குறை மற்றும் வெளிநாட்டு நாணய கையிருப்பில் கடுமையான சரிவை ஏற்படுத்தியது.",
        "டாலர்கள் இல்லாததால் உணவு, மருந்து, சமையல் எரிவாயு, பால் பவுடர் உள்ளிட்ட அத்தியாவசிய உணவுகளுக்கு தட்டுப்பாடு ஏற்பட்டது. இரசாயன உரக் கொள்கை தடை குறித்த அவரது கொள்கை உணவுப் பற்றாக்குறைக்கு வழிவகுத்தது மற்றும் தீவு நாடு உணவுப் பற்றாக்குறையை எதிர்கொள்கிறது.",
        "ராஜபக்ச எந்த வெளிநாட்டிலும் அரசியல் தஞ்சம் கோருவாரா என்பது உடனடியாகத் தெரியவில்லை. சிங்கப்பூர் தேசத்திற்குள் அவர் நுழைவதை சிங்கப்பூர் அரசாங்கம் உறுதிப்படுத்தியது.",
        "\"ஊடகங்களின் கேள்விகளுக்கு பதிலளிக்கும் விதமாக, திரு ராஜபக்ச தனிப்பட்ட பயணமாக சிங்கப்பூருக்குள் நுழைய அனுமதிக்கப்பட்டார் என்பது உறுதிப்படுத்தப்பட்டுள்ளது\" என்று சிங்கப்பூர் வெளியுறவு அமைச்சகம் ஒரு அறிக்கையில் தெரிவித்துள்ளது.",
        "\"அவர் புகலிடம் கேட்கவில்லை, அவருக்கு எந்த புகலிடமும் வழங்கப்படவில்லை. சிங்கப்பூர் பொதுவாக புகலிடக் கோரிக்கைகளை வழங்குவதில்லை.",
        "அவர் மத்திய கிழக்கு நாடு ஒன்றை இலக்காகக் கொண்டுள்ளதாக ஜனாதிபதிக்கு நெருக்கமான வட்டாரங்கள் தெரிவித்துள்ளன. (கொழும்பு/ஜூலை 14/2022)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "இலங்கை",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "சிங்கப்பூர்",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கையின்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "மஹிந்த யாப்பா அபேவர்தன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "ராஜபக்சே",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "விமானப்படை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "புதன்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "அதிகாலை",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "ராஜபக்சே",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "பொருளாதாரம் அடுத்தது",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "சிங்கப்பூர்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்துனில் அபேவர்தன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "ராஜபக்சே",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ராஜபக்சே",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சிங்கப்பூர்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "வியாழன்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "மாலத்தீவுகள்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சவுதி",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "மாலத்தீவுகள்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இப்ராஹிம் முகமது சோலியின்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "மாலத்தீவுகள்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "முகமது நஷீத்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆண்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கையர்கள்",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ராஜபக்சே",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "பல்லாயிரக்கணக்கானவர்கள்",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "சனிக்கிழமை",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "09",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "டிரில்லியன்கள்",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஒரே இரவில்",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ராஜபக்சே",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "சிங்கப்பூர்",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ராஜபக்சே",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "சிங்கப்பூர்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சிங்கப்பூர்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "வெளிநாட்டு அலுவல்கள் அமைச்சு",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "சிங்கப்பூர்",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "மத்திய கிழக்கு",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "கொழும்பு",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}