{
  "newspaper_id": "tamil-mirror-lk",
  "url": "https://www.tamilmirror.lk/வன்னி/குருசபாடு-கடற்பரப்பில்-10-பேர்-கைது/72-302485",
  "time_ut": 1660713702,
  "original_lang": "ta",
  "original_title": "குருசபாடு கடற்பரப்பில் 10 பேர் கைது",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "10 people arrested in Kurusapadu beach",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "These ten people were arrested during a special search operation carried out by the Sri Lankan Navy yesterday (16) night in Thalaimannar Kurusapadu sea area.",
        "Navy. The Navy carries out routine patrolling and search operations covering the country's sea and coastline to prevent illegal activities carried out in sea lanes.",
        "In this case, a dinghy that was traveling in a suspicious manner was surrounded by a Sri Lankan P175 coastal patrol vessel.",
        "At that time, four (04) men above 18 years of age, two women (02) and four below 18 years of age who operated the dinghy were arrested.",
        "Those arrested by the navy have been identified as belonging to Besalai, Urumalai, Kilinochchi and Kandalai. Thalaimannar was handed over to the police for further legal action.",
        "The Sri Lankan Navy has issued a statement in this regard, asking the public to avoid being caught in human trafficking organized by traffickers using unsafe vessels to earn money, trying to migrate illegally from the country and risking their lives to avoid being punished before the law."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "10",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "Kurusapadu",
          "label": "LOC"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ten",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Sri Lankan Navy",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "yesterday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "16) night",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "Thalaimannar Kurusapadu",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Navy",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Navy",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "a Sri Lankan P175",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "four",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "18 years of age",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "02",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "four",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "18 years of age",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Besalai, Urumalai,",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kilinochchi",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kandalai",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Thalaimannar",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "The Sri Lankan Navy",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "කුරුසපාඩු මුහුදු තීරයේදී පුද්ගලයින් 10 දෙනෙකු අත්අඩංගුවට",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකා නාවික හමුදාව ඊයේ (16) රාත්‍රියේ තලෙයිමන්නාරම කුරුසපාඩු මුහුදු ප්‍රදේශයේදී සිදුකළ විශේෂ සෝදිසි මෙහෙයුමකදී මෙම පුද්ගලයන් දස දෙනා අත්අඩංගුවට ගෙන ඇත.",
        "නාවික. මුහුදු මංතීරුවල සිදුවන නීතිවිරෝධී ක්‍රියා වැළැක්වීම සඳහා නාවික හමුදාව රටේ මුහුද සහ වෙරළ තීරය ආවරණය වන පරිදි සාමාන්‍ය මුර සංචාර සහ සෝදිසි මෙහෙයුම් සිදු කරයි.",
        "මෙහිදී සැක කටයුතු ලෙස ගමන් කළ ඩිංගි යාත්‍රාවක් ශ්‍රී ලංකා පී 175 වෙරළාසන්න මුර යාත්‍රාවකින් වටකර ඇත.",
        "එම අවස්ථාවේදී ඩිංගි යාත්‍රාව ක්‍රියාත්මක කළ වයස අවුරුදු 18ට වැඩි පිරිමින් හතර දෙනෙකු (04) කාන්තාවන් දෙදෙනෙකු (02) සහ වයස අවුරුදු 18ට අඩු සිව් දෙනෙකු අත්අඩංගුවට ගෙන ඇත.",
        "නාවික හමුදාව විසින් අත්අඩංගුවට ගත් පිරිස බේසාලෙයි, ඌරුමලෙයි, කිලිනොච්චිය සහ කණ්ඩලෙයි යන ප්‍රදේශවලට අයත් අය බවට හඳුනාගෙන ඇත. ඉදිරි නීතිමය කටයුතු සඳහා තලෙයිමන්නාරම පොලිසියට භාර දීමට කටයුතු කෙරිණි.",
        "මේ සම්බන්ධයෙන් නිවේදනයක් නිකුත් කරමින් ශ්‍රී ලංකා නාවික හමුදාව මහජනතාවගෙන් ඉල්ලා සිටින්නේ අනාරක්ෂිත යාත්‍රා භාවිත කරමින් මුදල් ඉපයීම, නීතිවිරෝධී ලෙස රටින් සංක්‍රමණය වීමට උත්සාහ කිරීම සහ නීතිය ඉදිරියේ දඬුවම් නොලබා දිවි පරදුවට තබා ජාවාරම්කරුවන් සංවිධානය කරන මිනිස් ජාවාරම්වලට හසුවීමෙන් වළකින ලෙසයි. ."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "10",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "කුරුසපාඩු",
          "label": "LOC"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "දස",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකා නාවික හමුදාව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඊයේ",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "16) රාත්රිය",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "තලෙයිමන්නාරම කුරුසපාඩු",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "නාවික",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "නාවික",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලාංකික P175 එකක්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "හතර",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "වයස අවුරුදු 18 යි",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "02",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "හතර",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "වයස අවුරුදු 18 යි",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "බේසාලෙයි, ඌරුමලෙයි,",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "කිලිනොච්චි",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "කණ්ඩලෙයි",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "තලෙයිමන්නාරම",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකා නාවික හමුදාව",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "குருசபாடு கடற்பரப்பில் 10 பேர் கைது",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "தலைமன்னார் குருசபாடு கடற்பரப்பில் நேற்று (16)  இரவு இலங்கை கடற்படையினர் முன்னெடுத்த விசேட தேடுதல் நடவடிக்கையின் போதே இந்த பத்து பேரும் கைது செய்யப்பட்டனர்.",
        "கடற்படை. கடல் வழிகளில் மேற்கொள்ளப்படும் சட்டவிரோதச் செயற்பாடுகளைத் தடுப்பதற்காக கடற்படையினர் நாட்டின் கடல் மற்றும் கரையோரத்தை உள்ளடக்கி வழக்கமான ரோந்து மற்றும் தேடுதல் நடவடிக்கைகளை மேற்கொள்கின்றனர்.",
        "இந்நிலையில் சந்தேகத்துக்கு இடமானமுறையில் பயணித்த டிங்கி படகு ஒன்று இலங்கைக்கு சொந்தமான பி175 கரையோர ரோந்துக் கப்பலினால் சுற்றிவளைக்கப்பட்டது.",
        "அதன் போது, அந்த டிங்கி படகில்,     18 வயதுக்கு மேற்பட்ட நான்கு (04) ஆண்கள், இரண்டு பெண்கள் (02) மற்றும் 18 வயதுக்கு குறைவான நால்வரும்  டிங்கி படகுகளை இயக்கிய இருவரும் கைது செய்யப்பட்டுள்ளனர்.",
        "கடற்படையினரால் கைது செய்யப்பட்டவர்கள் பேசாலை, உறுமலை, கிளிநொச்சி மற்றும் கந்தளாய் ஆகிய பகுதிகளைச் சேர்ந்தவர்கள் என அடையாளம் காணப்பட்டுள்ளனர்.  மேலதிக சட்ட நடவடிக்கைகளுக்காக தலைமன்னார் பொலிஸாரிடம் ஒப்படைக்கப்பட்டனர்.",
        "இதுதொடர்பில் அறிக்கையொன்றை விடுத்துள்ள இலங்கை கடற்படை,  பணம் சம்பாதிப்பதற்காக பாதுகாப்பற்ற கப்பல்களை பயன்படுத்தி கடத்தல்காரர்கள் ஏற்பாடு செய்துள்ள மனித கடத்தலில் சிக்கி, நாட்டிலிருந்து சட்டவிரோதமாக இடம்பெயர முயற்சிப்பது மற்றும் உயிரை பணயம் வைத்து சட்டத்தின் முன் தண்டிக்கப்படுவதை தவிர்க்குமாறு கடற்படை பொதுமக்களிடம் கேட்டுக்கொண்டுள்ளது."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "10",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "குருசபாடு",
          "label": "LOC"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "பத்து",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை கடற்படை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "நேற்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "16) இரவு",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "தலைமன்னார் குருசபாடு",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "கடற்படை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "கடற்படை",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஒரு இலங்கை P175",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "நான்கு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "18 வயது",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "02",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "நான்கு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "18 வயது",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பேசாலை, உருமலை,",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "கிளிநொச்சி",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "கண்டலை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "தலைமன்னார்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை கடற்படை",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}