{
  "newspaper_id": "d-b-s-jeyaraj-com",
  "url": "https://dbsjeyaraj.com/dbsj/archives/78753",
  "time_ut": 1658862360,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "The International Monetary Fund (IMF) says  Sri Lanka should Commence debt restructuring talks with its bilateral lender China,",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "The International Monetary Fund (IMF) says  Sri Lanka should Commence debt restructuring talks with its bilateral lender China,",
      "author": "Administrator",
      "body_lines": [
        "The International Monetary Fund (IMF) said Sri Lanka should kick off debt restructuring talks with its bilateral lender China, while the island state’s government seeks a financing loan from the Washington-based fund.",
        "“China is a big creditor, and Sri Lanka has to engage proactively with it on a debt restructuring,” Krishna Srinivasan, director of the IMF’s Asia and Pacific Department, told Reuters in an interview on Tuesday.",
        "The island of 22 million is currently engulfed by its most severe economic and political crisis in recent history.",
        "Six-time prime minister Ranil Wickremesinghe was recently appointed as president after a popular uprising ousted his predecessor following months of severe shortages of fuel, food and medicines.",
        "The government recently decided to restrict fuel imports for 12 months.",
        "The country owes Beijing some $6.5 billion in financing including development bank loans and a central bank swap, according to data from the Institute of International Finance (IFF).",
        "The world’s second-largest economy has invested in projects such as highways, a port, an airport and a coal power plant. Japan and India are also bilateral creditors to Sri Lanka.",
        "“Sri Lanka has to engage with its creditors, both private and official bilateral, on a debt workout to ensure debt sustainability is restored,” Srinivasan said, as he pointed out that technical talks on a new IMF program are ongoing with both officials from the finance ministry and the central bank.",
        "Sri Lanka’s foreign ministry and central bank did not immediately respond to a request for comment. China’s embassy in Sri Lanka did not immediately respond.",
        "The South Asian nation has requested an IMF rescue plan to overcome its worst economic crisis since independence in 1948. The country defaulted on a bond payment debt earlier this year on its $12 billion overseas debt with private creditors, as it struggles to pay for imports of basic goods.",
        "“There are some areas where we need to make further progress,” Srinivasan added, but declined to specify the top reforms Sri Lanka should address in other to reach an agreement.",
        "An Extended Fund Facility (EFF) programme from the IMF, which would be the fund’s 17th plan for the nation, requires countries to make structural economic reforms.",
        "Maldives and Laos are other examples of countries in the region that are facing onerous debt situations.",
        "Srinivasan said the fund is advising countries to “spend more in alleviating the impact on the poor and vulnerable but keeping budget neutral by reducing expenditures elsewhere or raising revenues where feasible.”",
        "“It’s not just public debt, but also corporate debt and household debt – and that has implications for policymaking,” he said. “The debt issue is very significant.”"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "The International Monetary Fund",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "Sri Lanka",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "Commence",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "China",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "The International Monetary Fund",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "China",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Washington",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "China",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Krishna Srinivasan",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "IMF’s",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "Asia",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "Pacific Department",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Reuters",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Tuesday",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "22 million",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Six",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "months",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "12 months",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Beijing",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "some $6.5 billion",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Institute of International Finance",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "IFF",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "second",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Japan",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "India",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "Srinivasan",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "IMF",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka’s",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "foreign ministry and central bank",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "China",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "South Asian",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "1948",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "earlier this year",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "$12 billion",
            "label": "MONEY"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "EFF",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "IMF",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "17th",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Laos",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [],
        []
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "ජාත්‍යන්තර මූල්‍ය අරමුදල (IMF) පවසන්නේ ශ්‍රී ලංකාව සිය ද්විපාර්ශ්වික ණය දෙන්නා වන චීනය සමඟ ණය ප්‍රතිව්‍යුහගත කිරීමේ සාකච්ඡා ආරම්භ කළ යුතු බවයි.",
      "author": "පරිපාලක",
      "body_lines": [
        "ජාත්‍යන්තර මූල්‍ය අරමුදල (IMF) කියා සිටියේ ශ්‍රී ලංකාව සිය ද්විපාර්ශ්වික ණය දෙන්නා වන චීනය සමඟ ණය ප්‍රතිව්‍යුහගත කිරීමේ සාකච්ඡා ආරම්භ කළ යුතු බවත්, දිවයින ප්‍රාන්ත රජය වොෂින්ටනය පදනම් කරගත් අරමුදලෙන් මූල්‍ය ණයක් අපේක්ෂා කරන බවත්ය.",
        "\"චීනය විශාල ණය දෙන්නෙක් වන අතර, ශ්‍රී ලංකාව ණය ප්‍රතිව්‍යුහගත කිරීම සඳහා එය සමඟ ක්‍රියාකාරීව සම්බන්ධ විය යුතුය\" යනුවෙන් IMF හි ආසියා සහ පැසිෆික් දෙපාර්තමේන්තුවේ අධ්‍යක්ෂ ක්‍රිෂ්ණා ශ්‍රීනිවාසන් අඟහරුවාදා රොයිටර් පුවත් සේවයට පැවසීය.",
        "මිලියන 22 ක දූපත මේ වන විට මෑත ඉතිහාසයේ එහි දරුණුතම ආර්ථික හා දේශපාලන අර්බුදයෙන් ගිලී ඇත.",
        "සයවරක් අගමැති වූ රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ පසුගියදා ජනාධිපති ලෙස පත් කරනු ලැබුවේ මහජන නැගිටීමකින් පසු මාස ​​ගණනාවක් ඉන්ධන, ආහාර සහ ඖෂධ හිඟයෙන් පසු ඔහුගේ පූර්වගාමියා නෙරපා හැරීමෙන් පසුවය.",
        "ඉන්ධන ආනයනය මාස 12කට සීමා කිරීමට රජය පසුගියදා තීරණය කළා.",
        "ජාත්‍යන්තර මූල්‍ය ආයතනයේ (IFF) දත්තවලට අනුව සංවර්ධන බැංකු ණය සහ මහ බැංකු හුවමාරුව ඇතුළුව මූල්‍යකරණය සඳහා රට බීජිං වෙත ඩොලර් බිලියන 6.5 ක් ණයයි.",
        "ලෝකයේ දෙවන විශාලතම ආර්ථිකය මහාමාර්ග, වරාය, ගුවන් තොටුපළ සහ ගල් අඟුරු බලාගාරය වැනි ව්‍යාපෘති සඳහා ආයෝජනය කර ඇත. ජපානය සහ ඉන්දියාව ද ශ්‍රී ලංකාවට ද්විපාර්ශ්වික ණය දෙන්නන් ය.",
        "“ණය තිරසාරභාවය යථා තත්ත්වයට පත් කිරීම සහතික කිරීම සඳහා ශ්‍රී ලංකාව සිය ණයහිමියන් සමඟ පුද්ගලික සහ නිල ද්විපාර්ශ්වික ණය ව්‍යායාමයක නිරත විය යුතුය,” ශ්‍රීනිවාසන් පැවසුවේ නව ජාත්‍යන්තර මූල්‍ය අරමුදලේ වැඩසටහනක් පිළිබඳ තාක්‍ෂණික සාකච්ඡා ක්‍රියාත්මක වන බව ඔහු පෙන්වා දුන්නේය. මුදල් අමාත්‍යාංශය සහ මහ බැංකුව.",
        "අදහස් දැක්වීම සඳහා කරන ලද ඉල්ලීමකට ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ විදේශ අමාත්‍යාංශය සහ මහ බැංකුව වහාම ප්‍රතිචාර දැක්වූයේ නැත. ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ චීන තානාපති කාර්යාලය වහාම ප්‍රතිචාර දැක්වූයේ නැත.",
        "දකුණු ආසියාතික ජාතිය 1948 නිදහසෙන් පසු එහි දරුණුතම ආර්ථික අර්බුදයෙන් මිදීම සඳහා IMF ගලවා ගැනීමේ සැලැස්මක් ඉල්ලා ඇත. ආනයන සඳහා ගෙවීමට අරගල කරන බැවින්, රට මේ වසර මුලදී පුද්ගලික ණය හිමියන් සමඟ ඩොලර් බිලියන 12 ක විදේශ ණය මත බැඳුම්කර ගෙවීම පැහැර හැර ඇත. මූලික භාණ්ඩ.",
        "“අපට තවදුරටත් ප්‍රගතියක් ලබා ගත යුතු සමහර ක්ෂේත්‍ර තිබේ,” යනුවෙන් ශ්‍රීනිවාසන් වැඩිදුරටත් පැවසීය, නමුත් ගිවිසුමකට එළැඹීම සඳහා ශ්‍රී ලංකාව ආමන්ත්‍රණය කළ යුතු ඉහළම ප්‍රතිසංස්කරණ සඳහන් කිරීම ප්‍රතික්ෂේප කළේය.",
        "ජාතිය සඳහා වන අරමුදලේ 17 වැනි සැලැස්ම වන IMF වෙතින් විස්තීරණ අරමුදල් පහසුකම් (EFF) වැඩසටහනක් සඳහා රටවල් ව්‍යුහාත්මක ආර්ථික ප්‍රතිසංස්කරණ සිදු කිරීමට අවශ්‍ය වේ.",
        "මාලදිවයින සහ ලාඕසය කලාපයේ රටවලට දැඩි ණය තත්ත්වයන්ට මුහුණ දෙන අනෙකුත් උදාහරණ වේ.",
        "ශ්‍රීනිවාසන් පැවසුවේ “දුප්පත් සහ අවදානමට ලක්විය හැකි අයට වන බලපෑම අවම කිරීම සඳහා වැඩිපුර වියදම් කරන ලෙසත්, වෙනත් තැන්වල වියදම් අඩු කිරීමෙන් හෝ හැකි නම් ආදායම් ඉහළ නැංවීමෙන් අයවැය මධ්‍යස්ථව තබා ගැනීමටත්” අරමුදල රටවලට උපදෙස් දෙන බවයි.",
        "“එය හුදෙක් රාජ්‍ය ණය පමණක් නොව ආයතනික ණය සහ ගෘහ ණය ද වේ - එය ප්‍රතිපත්ති සම්පාදනය සඳහා ඇඟවුම් ඇත,” ඔහු පැවසීය. \"ණය ප්රශ්නය ඉතා වැදගත් වේ.\""
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ජාත්‍යන්තර මුල්‍ය අරමුදල",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "ආරම්භ කරන්න",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "චීනය",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ජාත්‍යන්තර මුල්‍ය අරමුදල",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "චීනය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "වොෂින්ටනය",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "චීනය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ක්‍රිෂ්ණ ශ්‍රීනිවාසන්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "IMF හි",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "ආසියාව",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "පැසිෆික් දෙපාර්තමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "රොයිටර්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "අඟහරුවාදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "මිලියන 22 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "හය",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "මාස",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "මාස 12 යි",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "බීජිං",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඩොලර් බිලියන 6.5ක් පමණ",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජාත්‍යන්තර මූල්‍ය ආයතනය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "IFF",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "දෙවැනි",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජපානය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රීනිවාසන්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "IMF",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "විදේශ අමාත්‍යාංශය සහ මහ බැංකුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "චීනය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "දකුණු ආසියානු",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "1948",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මීට පෙර මෙම වසරේ",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඩොලර් බිලියන 12 කි",
            "label": "MONEY"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "EFF",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "IMF",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "17 වැනි",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ලාඕසය",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [],
        []
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "இலங்கை தனது இருதரப்பு கடனாளியான சீனாவுடன் கடன் மறுசீரமைப்பு பேச்சுவார்த்தைகளை ஆரம்பிக்க வேண்டும் என சர்வதேச நாணய நிதியம் (IMF) தெரிவித்துள்ளது.",
      "author": "நிர்வாகி",
      "body_lines": [
        "சர்வதேச நாணய நிதியம் (IMF) இலங்கை தனது இருதரப்பு கடனாளியான சீனாவுடன் கடன் மறுசீரமைப்பு பேச்சுவார்த்தைகளை தொடங்க வேண்டும் என்று கூறியது, அதே நேரத்தில் தீவு மாநில அரசாங்கம் வாஷிங்டனை தளமாகக் கொண்ட நிதியத்தில் இருந்து நிதிக் கடனை நாடுகிறது.",
        "\"சீனா ஒரு பெரிய கடன் வழங்குநராக உள்ளது, மேலும் கடன் மறுசீரமைப்பில் இலங்கை அதனுடன் தீவிரமாக ஈடுபட வேண்டும்\" என்று IMF இன் ஆசிய மற்றும் பசிபிக் துறையின் இயக்குனர் கிருஷ்ணா சீனிவாசன் செவ்வாயன்று ராய்ட்டர்ஸுக்கு அளித்த பேட்டியில் கூறினார்.",
        "22 மில்லியன் மக்கள் வசிக்கும் தீவு தற்போது அதன் சமீபத்திய வரலாற்றில் மிகக் கடுமையான பொருளாதார மற்றும் அரசியல் நெருக்கடியால் சூழப்பட்டுள்ளது.",
        "6 முறை பிரதமராக இருந்த ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க, பல மாதங்களாக எரிபொருள், உணவு மற்றும் மருந்துகளுக்கு கடும் தட்டுப்பாடு ஏற்பட்டதைத் தொடர்ந்து, மக்கள் எழுச்சியால் அவரது முன்னோடி பதவியில் இருந்து அகற்றப்பட்டு, சமீபத்தில் ஜனாதிபதியாக நியமிக்கப்பட்டார்.",
        "எரிபொருள் இறக்குமதியை 12 மாதங்களுக்கு கட்டுப்படுத்த அரசாங்கம் அண்மையில் தீர்மானித்துள்ளது.",
        "இன்ஸ்டிடியூட் ஆஃப் இன்டர்நேஷனல் ஃபைனான்ஸ் (ஐஎஃப்எஃப்) தரவுகளின்படி, வளர்ச்சி வங்கிக் கடன்கள் மற்றும் மத்திய வங்கி இடமாற்றம் உட்பட பெய்ஜிங்கிற்கு நாடு சுமார் $6.5 பில்லியன் நிதியளிக்க வேண்டும்.",
        "உலகின் இரண்டாவது பெரிய பொருளாதாரம் நெடுஞ்சாலைகள், துறைமுகம், விமான நிலையம் மற்றும் நிலக்கரி மின் நிலையம் போன்ற திட்டங்களில் முதலீடு செய்துள்ளது. ஜப்பானும் இந்தியாவும் இலங்கைக்கு இருதரப்பு கடன் வழங்குபவர்கள்.",
        "\"கடன் நிலைத்தன்மையை மீட்டெடுப்பதை உறுதி செய்வதற்காக, இலங்கை தனது கடன் வழங்குநர்களுடன், தனியார் மற்றும் உத்தியோகபூர்வ இருதரப்பு, கடன் பயிற்சியில் ஈடுபட வேண்டும்\" என்று சீனிவாசன் கூறினார். நிதி அமைச்சகம் மற்றும் மத்திய வங்கி.",
        "இலங்கையின் வெளிவிவகார அமைச்சு மற்றும் மத்திய வங்கி கருத்துக்கான கோரிக்கைக்கு உடனடியாக பதிலளிக்கவில்லை. இலங்கையில் உள்ள சீன தூதரகம் உடனடியாக பதிலளிக்கவில்லை.",
        "தெற்காசிய நாடு 1948 இல் சுதந்திரத்திற்குப் பிறகு அதன் மோசமான பொருளாதார நெருக்கடியைச் சமாளிக்க IMF மீட்புத் திட்டத்தைக் கோரியுள்ளது. அந்த நாடு இந்த ஆண்டு தொடக்கத்தில் தனியார் கடனாளர்களிடம் $12 பில்லியன் வெளிநாட்டுக் கடனைப் பத்திரப்பதிவுக் கடனைத் திருப்பிச் செலுத்தத் தவறியது, ஏனெனில் அது இறக்குமதிகளுக்குச் செலுத்த போராடுகிறது. அடிப்படை பொருட்கள்.",
        "ஸ்ரீனிவாசன் மேலும் கூறுகையில், \"சில பகுதிகள் இன்னும் முன்னேற்றம் அடைய வேண்டும்,\" என்று சீனிவாசன் மேலும் கூறினார், ஆனால் ஒரு உடன்பாட்டை எட்டுவதற்கு மற்றவற்றில் இலங்கை கவனிக்க வேண்டிய முக்கிய சீர்திருத்தங்களைக் குறிப்பிட மறுத்துவிட்டார்.",
        "IMF இன் விரிவாக்கப்பட்ட நிதி வசதி (EFF) திட்டமானது, தேசத்திற்கான நிதியத்தின் 17வது திட்டமாக இருக்கும், கட்டமைப்பு பொருளாதார சீர்திருத்தங்களை நாடுகள் செய்ய வேண்டும்.",
        "மாலத்தீவுகள் மற்றும் லாவோஸ் ஆகியவை கடுமையான கடன் சூழ்நிலைகளை எதிர்கொள்ளும் பிராந்தியத்தில் உள்ள நாடுகளுக்கு மற்ற எடுத்துக்காட்டுகளாகும்.",
        "சீனிவாசன் கூறுகையில், \"ஏழைகள் மற்றும் பாதிக்கப்படக்கூடியவர்கள் மீதான பாதிப்பைத் தணிக்க அதிக செலவு செய்ய வேண்டும், ஆனால் வேறு இடங்களில் செலவினங்களைக் குறைப்பதன் மூலம் அல்லது சாத்தியமான இடங்களில் வருவாயை உயர்த்துவதன் மூலம் பட்ஜெட்டை நடுநிலையாக வைத்திருக்க வேண்டும்\" என்று நிதி நாடுகளுக்கு அறிவுறுத்துகிறது.",
        "\"இது பொதுக் கடன் மட்டுமல்ல, கார்ப்பரேட் கடன் மற்றும் வீட்டுக் கடன் - மேலும் இது கொள்கை வகுப்பதில் தாக்கங்களைக் கொண்டுள்ளது,\" என்று அவர் கூறினார். \"கடன் பிரச்சினை மிகவும் முக்கியமானது.\""
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "சர்வதேச நாணய நிதியம்",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "இலங்கை",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "தொடங்கு",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "சீனா",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "சர்வதேச நாணய நிதியம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சீனா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "வாஷிங்டன்",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "சீனா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "கிருஷ்ணா சீனிவாசன்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "IMF இன்",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆசியா",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "பசிபிக் துறை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ராய்ட்டர்ஸ்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "செவ்வாய்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "22 மில்லியன்",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஆறு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "மாதங்கள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "12 மாதங்கள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பெய்ஜிங்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சுமார் $6.5 பில்லியன்",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "சர்வதேச நிதி நிறுவனம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "IFF",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இரண்டாவது",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜப்பான்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்தியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "சீனிவாசன்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "IMF",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கையின்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "வெளியுறவு அமைச்சகம் மற்றும் மத்திய வங்கி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "சீனா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "தெற்காசிய",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "1948",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்த ஆண்டின் தொடக்கத்தில்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "$12 பில்லியன்",
            "label": "MONEY"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "EFF",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "IMF",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "17வது",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "லாவோஸ்",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [],
        []
      ]
    }
  }
}