{
  "newspaper_id": "lankadeepa-lk",
  "url": "https://www.lankadeepa.lk/latest_news/රුසියාව-සමඟ-හැප්පිලා-දිනන්න-කාටවත්-බෑ/1-616150",
  "time_ut": 1657417053,
  "original_lang": "si",
  "original_title": "රුසියාව සමඟ හැප්පිලා දිනන්න කාටවත් බෑ",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "No one can win against Russia",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "Russian President Vladimir Putin has said that no western country that boasts of being world powers can defeat Russia in the battlefield.",
        "Russian President Putin accuses that the Western countries, which claim to be world powers, are continuously taking various measures against Russia, and that they have forgotten the Russian-Ukraine peace talks.",
        "Responding to the statements made by Western countries including the United States at the recently concluded 'G7' summit, the Russian President has expressed the following comments.",
        "Russian President Vladimir Putin has further clarified that the Russian army is ready for war at any time with the army of any country that boasts of being world powers."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Russia",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Russian",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Vladimir Putin",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Russia",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Russian",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Putin",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Western",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Russia",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Russian",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the United States",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Russian",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Russian",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Vladimir Putin",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Russian",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "රුසියාව සමඟ හැප්පිලා දිනන්න කාටවත් බෑ",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "ලෝක බලවතුන් යැයි පුරසාරම් දොඩන කිසිදු බටහිර රටකට යුද පිහිටියේ දී රුසියාව පරාජය කළ නොහැකි බව රුසියානු ජනාධිපති ව්ලැදිමීර් පුටින් පවසා තිබේ.",
        "ලෝක බලවතුන් යැයි කියා ගන්නා බටහිර රාජ්‍යයන්, දිගින් දිගටම රුසියාවට එරෙහිව විවිධ පියවර ගනිමින් සිටින බවත්, රුසියන් යුක්රේන සාම කතා මේ වනවිට ඔවුන්ට අමතක වී ගොස් ඇති බවත් රුසියන් ජනාධිපති පුටින් චෝදනා කරයි.",
        "පසුගිය දා අවසන් වුණු ‘ජී 7’ සමුළුවේදී ඇමෙරිකාව ඇතුළු බටහිර රටවල් සිදු කළ ප්‍රකාශයන්ට ප්‍රතිචාර දක්වමින් රුසියානු ජනාධිපතිවරයා මෙසේ අදහස් පළ කර තිබේ.",
        "ලෝක බලවතුන් යැයි පුරසාරම් දොඩන ඕනෑම රටක හමුදාවක් සමඟ රුසියන් හමුදාව ඕනෑ වෙලාවක යුද්ධයකට සූදානම් බවත් රුසියන් ජනාධිපති ව්ලැදිමීර් පුටින් වැඩි දුරටත් පැහැදිලි කර තිබේ."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "රුසියාව",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "රුසියානු",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ව්ලැඩිමීර් පුටින්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "රුසියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "රුසියානු",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "පුටින්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "බටහිර",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "රුසියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "රුසියානු",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "එක්සත් ජනපදය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "රුසියානු",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "රුසියානු",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ව්ලැඩිමීර් පුටින්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "රුසියානු",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "ரஷ்யாவை எதிர்த்து யாராலும் வெல்ல முடியாது",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "உலக வல்லரசுகள் என்று தம்பட்டம் அடிக்கும் எந்த மேற்குலக நாடுகளாலும் ரஷ்யாவை போர்க்களத்தில் தோற்கடிக்க முடியாது என ரஷ்ய ஜனாதிபதி விளாடிமிர் புடின் தெரிவித்துள்ளார்.",
        "உலக வல்லரசுகள் என்று கூறிக்கொள்ளும் மேற்கத்திய நாடுகள் தொடர்ந்து ரஷ்யாவிற்கு எதிராக பல்வேறு நடவடிக்கைகளை மேற்கொண்டு வருவதாகவும், ரஷ்ய - உக்ரைன் அமைதிப் பேச்சுவார்த்தையை மறந்துவிட்டதாகவும் ரஷ்ய அதிபர் புதின் குற்றம்சாட்டியுள்ளார்.",
        "அண்மையில் நிறைவடைந்த 'ஜி7' மாநாட்டில் அமெரிக்கா உள்ளிட்ட மேற்கத்திய நாடுகள் வெளியிட்ட கருத்துக்களுக்கு பதிலளிக்கும் போதே ரஷ்ய ஜனாதிபதி மேற்கண்டவாறு கருத்து வெளியிட்டுள்ளார்.",
        "உலக வல்லரசுகள் என்று தம்பட்டம் அடிக்கும் எந்த நாட்டு ராணுவத்துடன் எந்த நேரத்திலும் போருக்கு ரஷ்ய ராணுவம் தயாராக உள்ளது என ரஷ்ய அதிபர் விளாடிமிர் புடின் மேலும் தெளிவுபடுத்தியுள்ளார்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ரஷ்யா",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ரஷ்யன்",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "விளாடிமிர் புடின்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரஷ்யா",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ரஷ்யன்",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "புடின்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "மேற்கு",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரஷ்யா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரஷ்யன்",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஐக்கிய நாடுகள்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரஷ்யன்",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ரஷ்யன்",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "விளாடிமிர் புடின்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரஷ்யன்",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}