{
  "newspaper_id": "lankadeepa-lk",
  "url": "https://www.lankadeepa.lk/news/දේශපාලන-ගෙම්බෝ-වෙන්න-ගියොත්-ජනතා-අධිකරණය-දඬුවම්-දේවි/101-617117",
  "time_ut": 1658906146,
  "original_lang": "si",
  "original_title": "දේශපාලන ගෙම්බෝ වෙන්න ගියොත් ජනතා අධිකරණය දඬුවම් දේවි",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "People's Court will punish if they become political gamblers",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "Opposition Leader Sajith Premadasa said today (27) in the Parliament that if they jump around like political Gembo, they will have to respond to them before the People's Court.",
        "The leader of the opposition said this while joining the debate on the adoption of the emergency law in the parliament.",
        "The opposition leader said that today the government is talking about \"emergency\" but the people have an emergency of living without any essential goods and the government has an emergency of spreading state terrorism.",
        "The Leader of the Opposition said that the dream of the President as well as the Leader of the Prime Minister came true, but the dreams of 220 lakh people have been crushed."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "People's Court",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Sajith Premadasa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "27",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Gembo",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the People's Court",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Opposition",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "220",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "දේශපාලන ගෙම්බෝ වෙන්න ගියොත් ජනතා අධිකරණය දඬුවම් දේවි",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "දේශපාලන ගෙම්බෝ වගේ එහාට මෙහාට පැන්නොත් ජනතා අධිකරණය හමුවේ ඒවාට ප්‍රතිචාර විදින්නට සිදු වනු ඇතැයි විපක්ෂ නායක සජිත් ප්‍රේමදාස මහතා පාර්ලිමේන්තුවේ දී අද (27)පැවසීය.",
        "පාර්ලිමේන්තුවේ හදිසි නීතිය සම්මත කර ගැනීමේ විවාදයට එක්වෙමින් විපක්ෂනායකවරයා මේ බව සඳහන් කළේය.",
        "අද ආණ්ඩුව \"හදිසිය\" ගැන කතා කරන නමුත් ජනතාවට ති⁣බෙන්නේ අත්‍යවශ්‍ය භාණ්ඩ කිසිවක් නැති  ජීවත් වීම පිළිබඳ හදිසියක් යැයිද ආණ්ඩුවට තිබෙන්නේ  තර්ජනය ගර්ජනය  රාජ්‍ය ත්‍රස්තවාදය ව්‍යාප්ත කරන හදිසි යැයිද විපක්ෂ නායකවරයා කීය.",
        "ජනපතිගේ මෙන්ම අගමැති සභානායක තුමන්ලාගේ සිහිනය සැබෑ වුණ නමුත් ලක්ෂ  220 ක් වන ජනතාවගේ සිහින කුඩුපට්ටම් වී තිබෙන බවද විපක්ෂනායකවරයා කීය."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "මහජන අධිකරණය",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "සජිත් ප්‍රේමදාස",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "27",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Gembo",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "මහජන අධිකරණය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "විපක්ෂ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "220",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "அரசியல் சூதாட்டக்காரர்களாக மாறினால் மக்கள் நீதிமன்றம் தண்டிக்கும்",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "அரசியல் கெம்போ போல் குதித்தால் மக்கள் நீதிமன்றில் பதில் சொல்ல வேண்டி வரும் என எதிர்க்கட்சித் தலைவர் சஜித் பிரேமதாச இன்று (27) பாராளுமன்றத்தில் தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "நாடாளுமன்றத்தில் அவசரகாலச் சட்டத்தை நிறைவேற்றுவது தொடர்பான விவாதத்தில் கலந்துகொண்டு உரையாற்றும் போதே எதிர்க்கட்சித் தலைவர் மேற்கண்டவாறு தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "இன்று அரசாங்கம் “அவசரகாலம்” பற்றி பேசுவதாகவும் ஆனால் மக்களுக்கு அத்தியாவசிய பொருட்கள் எதுவுமின்றி வாழும் அவசர நிலை ஏற்பட்டுள்ளதாகவும் அரச பயங்கரவாதத்தை பரப்பும் அவசர நிலை அரசாங்கத்திற்கு இருப்பதாகவும் எதிர்கட்சி தலைவர் தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "ஜனாதிபதியின் கனவும், பிரதமரின் கனவும் நனவாகியுள்ளதாகவும், ஆனால் 220 இலட்சம் மக்களின் கனவுகள் நசுக்கப்பட்டுள்ளதாகவும் எதிர்க்கட்சித் தலைவர் தெரிவித்துள்ளார்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "மக்கள் நீதிமன்றம்",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "சஜித் பிரேமதாச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "27",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜெம்போ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "மக்கள் நீதிமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "எதிர்ப்பு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "220",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}