{
  "newspaper_id": "lankadeepa-lk",
  "url": "https://www.lankadeepa.lk/latest_news/ඉන්දීය-ජනාධිපති-ධුරය-ද්‍රෞපදී-මුර්මු-ට/1-616833",
  "time_ut": 1658416018,
  "original_lang": "si",
  "original_title": "ඉන්දීය ජනාධිපති ධුරය ද්‍රෞපදී මුර්මු ට",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Draupadi Murmu became the President of India",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "Draupadi Murmu, who represented the National Democratic Alliance led by the Bharatiya Janata Party, was elected as the 15th President of India.",
        "After Pratibha Patil, this is the second time that a woman has won the post of President of India. Pratibha Patil was the 12th President of India and her tenure was from 2007 to 2012. Pratibha Patil is a member of the Indian Congress Party; A lawyer.",
        "Draupadi Murmu, 64, is a woman representing the tribal community of the Indian state of Odisha. Therefore, this is the first time in history that a woman representing the Indian tribal community has been elected to the presidency.",
        "Murmu is a politician as well as a teacher. She is a member of Bharatiya Janata Party. She also served as the Governor of Jharkhand from 2015 to 2021.",
        "The election of the President of India started on the last 18th. Counting of votes and release of results took place today (21).",
        "The two candidates who appeared in the Indian presidential election were Drupadi Murmu and 84-year-old Yashwant Sinha. Sinha represents the Trinamool Congress. Sinha, a former BJP leader. Yashwant Sinha contested the presidential election representing the opposition political groups led by the United Progressive Alliance.",
        "According to the Constitution of India, the President of the country is not elected by popular vote, but by the votes of the representatives of the Parliament. The term of office of the President of India is five years. Drupadi Murmu will be sworn in as President on the 25th."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Draupadi Murmu",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "India",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Draupadi Murmu",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the National Democratic Alliance",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Bharatiya Janata Party",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "15th",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "India",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "second",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "India",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "India",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "2012",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Indian Congress Party",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Draupadi Murmu",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "64",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Indian",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Odisha",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "first",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Indian",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Murmu",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Bharatiya Janata Party",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Jharkhand",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "from 2015 to 2021",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "India",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the last 18th",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "21",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "two",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Indian",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Drupadi Murmu",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "84-year-old",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Yashwant Sinha",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Trinamool Congress",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "BJP",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Yashwant Sinha",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the United Progressive Alliance",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the Constitution of India",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "India",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "five years",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Drupadi Murmu",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the 25th",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "ඉන්දීය ජනාධිපති ධුරය ද්‍රෞපදී මුර්මු ට",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "ඉන්දියාවේ 15 වැනි ජනාධිපති ලෙස භාරතීය ජනතා පක්ෂය ප්‍රමුඛ ජාතික ප්‍රජාතන්ත්‍රවාදී සන්ධානය නියෝජනය කරමින් එරට ජනාධිපතිවරණයට ඉදිරිපත් වුණු ද්‍රෞපදී මුර්මු තේරී පත් වූවාය.",
        "ප්‍රතිභා පාතිල්ගෙන් පසු ඉන්දීය ජනාධිපති ධුරය කාන්තාවකට හිමිවුණු දෙවැනි අවස්ථාව මෙයයි. ප්‍රතිභා පාතිල් ඉන්දියාවේ 12 වැනි ජනාධිපතිවරයා වූ අතර ඇගේ ධුර කාලය 2007 සිට 2012 දක්වාය. ප්‍රතිභා පාතිල් ඉන්දීය කොංග්‍රස් පක්ෂ සාමාජිකාවකි; නීතීඥවරියකි.",
        "64 හැවිරිදි ද්‍රෞපදී මුර්මු, ඉන්දියාවේ ඔඩිස්සා ප්‍රාන්තයේ ගෝත්‍රික ප්‍රජාව නියෝජනය කරන කාන්තාවකි. එබැවින් ඉන්දීය ගෝත්‍රික ප්‍රජාව නියෝජනය කරන කාන්තාවක ජනාධිපති ධුරය ට පත් වුණු පළමු ඓතිහාසික අවස්ථාව ලෙස මෙයයි.",
        "මුර්මු දේශපාලනඥයකු මෙන්ම ගුරුවරියක ද වෙයි. ඇය භාරතීය ජනතා පක්ෂ සාමාජිකාවකි. 2015 සිට 2021 තෙක් කාලයේ ජර්කාන්ද් ප්‍රාන්ත ආණ්ඩුකාරවරිය ලෙස කටයුතු කළේ ද ඇයයි.",
        "ඉන්දීය ජානාධිපතිවරණය ආරම්භ වූයේ පසුගිය 18 වැනිදාය. ඡන්ද ගණන් කිරීම සහ ප්‍රතිඵල නිකුත් කිරීම අද (21) සිදුවිය.",
        "ඉන්දීය ජනාධිපතිවරණයට ඉදිරිපත් වුණු අපේක්ෂයන් දෙදෙනා වූයේ ද්‍රෙෘපදී මුර්මු සහ 84 හැවිරිදි යෂ්වාන්ත් සිංහා ය. සිංහා නියෝජනය කරන්නේ ත්‍රිණමූල් කොංග්‍රසයයි. සිංහා, භාරතීය ජනතා පක්ෂයේ හිටපු නායකයෙකි. යෂ්වාන්ත් සිංහා ජනාධිපතිවරණයට ඉදිරිපත් වූයේ එක්සත් ප්‍රගතශීලී සන්ධානය ප්‍රමුඛ විපක්ෂ දේශපාලන කණ්ඩායම් නියෝජනය කරමිනි.",
        "ඉන්දියානු ආණ්ඩුක්‍රම ව්‍යවස්ථාව අනුව රටේ ජනාධිපතිවරයා තෝරා පත්කර ගනු ලබන්නේ මහජන ඡන්දයෙන් නොව, පාර්ලිමේන්තු නියෝජිතයන්ගේ ඡන්දයෙනි. ඉන්දීය ජනාධිපතිවරයාගේ ධුර කාලය වසර පහකි. ද්‍රෙෘපදී මුර්මු ලබන 25 වැනිදා ජනපති ධුරයේ දිවුරුම් දීමට නියමිතය."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ද්‍රෞපදී මුර්මු",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "ඉන්දියාව",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ද්‍රෞපදී මුර්මු",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජාතික ප්‍රජාතන්ත්‍රවාදී සන්ධානය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "භාරතීය ජනතා පක්ෂය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "15 වැනි",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "දෙවැනි",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "2012",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දීය කොංග්‍රස් පක්ෂය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ද්‍රෞපදී මුර්මු",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "64",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දීය",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඔඩිෂා",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "පළමුවන",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දීය",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "මුර්මු",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "භාරතීය ජනතා පක්ෂය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජාර්කන්ඩ්",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "2015 සිට 2021 දක්වා",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "පසුගිය 18 වැනිදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "21",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "දෙක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දීය",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Drupadi Murmu",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "84 හැවිරිදිය",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "යෂ්වන්ත් සිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ත්‍රිනාමුල් කොංග්‍රසය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "බී.ජේ.පී",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "යෂ්වන්ත් සිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "එක්සත් ප්‍රගතිශීලී සන්ධානය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දීය ආණ්ඩුක්රම ව්යවස්ථාව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "අවුරුදු පහක්",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Drupadi Murmu",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "25 වෙනිදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "திரௌபதி முர்மு இந்தியாவின் ஜனாதிபதியானார்",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "பாரதீய ஜனதா கட்சியின் தலைமையிலான தேசிய ஜனநாயகக் கூட்டணியின் சார்பில் திரௌபதி முர்மு இந்தியாவின் 15வது குடியரசுத் தலைவராகத் தேர்ந்தெடுக்கப்பட்டார்.",
        "பிரதீபா பாட்டீலுக்குப் பிறகு, இந்தியக் குடியரசுத் தலைவர் பதவிக்கு பெண் ஒருவர் வெற்றி பெறுவது இது இரண்டாவது முறையாகும். பிரதீபா பாட்டீல் இந்தியாவின் 12வது குடியரசுத் தலைவராக இருந்தார் மற்றும் அவரது பதவிக்காலம் 2007 முதல் 2012 வரை இருந்தது. பிரதிபா பாட்டீல் இந்திய காங்கிரஸ் கட்சியின் உறுப்பினர்; ஒரு வழக்கறிஞர்.",
        "திரௌபதி முர்மு, 64, இந்திய மாநிலமான ஒடிசாவின் பழங்குடி சமூகத்தை பிரதிநிதித்துவப்படுத்தும் பெண். எனவே, இந்திய பழங்குடியின சமூகத்தை பிரதிநிதித்துவப்படுத்தும் பெண் ஒருவர் குடியரசுத் தலைவர் பதவிக்கு தேர்ந்தெடுக்கப்படுவது வரலாற்றில் இதுவே முதல்முறை.",
        "முர்மு ஒரு அரசியல்வாதி மற்றும் ஆசிரியர். அவர் பாரதிய ஜனதா கட்சியின் உறுப்பினர். 2015 முதல் 2021 வரை ஜார்க்கண்ட் ஆளுநராகவும் பணியாற்றினார்.",
        "இந்திய குடியரசுத் தலைவர் தேர்தல் கடந்த 18ஆம் தேதி தொடங்கியது. வாக்கு எண்ணிக்கை மற்றும் முடிவுகள் வெளியீடு இன்று (21) நடைபெற்றது.",
        "இந்திய ஜனாதிபதி தேர்தலில் துருபதி முர்மு மற்றும் 84 வயதான யஷ்வந்த் சின்ஹா ​​ஆகிய இரு வேட்பாளர்கள் போட்டியிட்டனர். சின்ஹா ​​திரிணாமுல் காங்கிரஸை பிரதிநிதித்துவப்படுத்துகிறார். சின்ஹா, முன்னாள் பாஜக தலைவர். யஷ்வந்த் சின்ஹா, ஐக்கிய முற்போக்குக் கூட்டணி தலைமையிலான எதிர்க்கட்சிகள் சார்பில் குடியரசுத் தலைவர் தேர்தலில் போட்டியிட்டார்.",
        "இந்திய அரசியலமைப்புச் சட்டத்தின்படி, நாட்டின் குடியரசுத் தலைவர் மக்கள் வாக்குகளால் தேர்ந்தெடுக்கப்படுவதில்லை, மாறாக நாடாளுமன்றத்தின் பிரதிநிதிகளின் வாக்குகளால் தேர்ந்தெடுக்கப்படுகிறார். இந்திய ஜனாதிபதியின் பதவிக்காலம் ஐந்து ஆண்டுகள். துருபதி முர்மு வரும் 25ம் தேதி ஜனாதிபதியாக பதவியேற்கிறார்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "திரௌபதி முர்மு",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "இந்தியா",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "திரௌபதி முர்மு",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "தேசிய ஜனநாயகக் கூட்டணி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாரதிய ஜனதா கட்சி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "15வது",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்தியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இரண்டாவது",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்தியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்தியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "2012",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்திய காங்கிரஸ் கட்சி",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "திரௌபதி முர்மு",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "64",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்தியன்",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஒடிசா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "முதலில்",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்தியன்",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "முர்மு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாரதிய ஜனதா கட்சி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜார்கண்ட்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "2015 முதல் 2021 வரை",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இந்தியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "கடந்த 18ம் தேதி",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "21",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இரண்டு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்தியன்",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "துருபதி முர்மு",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "84 வயதானவர்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "யஷ்வந்த் சின்ஹா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "திரிணாமுல் காங்கிரஸ்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "பா.ஜ.க",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "யஷ்வந்த் சின்ஹா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஐக்கிய முற்போக்குக் கூட்டணி",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இந்திய அரசியலமைப்பு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்தியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஐந்து வருடம்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "துருபதி முர்மு",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "25 ஆம் தேதி",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}