{
  "newspaper_id": "lankadeepa-lk",
  "url": "https://www.lankadeepa.lk/latest_news/විද්‍යෝදය-සාහිත්‍ය-සම්මාන-සඳහා-නිර්දේශිත-කෘතීන්-ප්‍රකාශයට-පත්කෙරේ/1-618732",
  "time_ut": 1661415689,
  "original_lang": "si",
  "original_title": "විද්‍යෝදය සාහිත්‍ය සම්මාන සඳහා නිර්දේශිත කෘතීන් ප්‍රකාශයට පත්කෙරේ",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Recommended works for Vidyodaya Sahitya Awards will be announced",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "The Vidyodaya Sahitya Award Ceremony will be held at Sumangala Hall of Sri Jayawardenepura University on September 1st at 3:00 PM and the works recommended for the final round of awards have been announced by now.",
        "Awards will be presented for the best novel, short story collection, poetry collection, lyric collection, column collection and academic collection of the year.",
        "This year's best novel of the year is 'Hin Dos Male' written by Mrs. Sepali Mayadunne, 'Sandhyanandaya' written by Mr. Keerthi Welisarage, 'My Chicago Heart' written by Mrs. Shamel Jayakodi, 'Premanishansa' written by Mr. Chandraratne Bandara and 'Nakula' written by Mr. Eric Ilayaparachchi. Muni' novels have been recommended.",
        "Also for the award for the best short story collection of the year, 'International Confessions' by Mr. Eric Ilayapaarachchi, 'Because of being the daughter of a toilet washer' by Mr. Mahinda Ratnayake, 'Gini Some and other short stories' by Mr. Upali Ubayasekara, 'Memories of Man Mawathaka Miminilla' by Mr. Malindu Kavinda Kumarasinghe and Mr. Prince Senadheera's works 'Black Tall Man' have been recommended.",
        "Five works have been nominated for the best poetry anthology of the year award, Mr. Lakshantha Athukorala's 'Liyasav Lihi Gaya Ganasamadulu', Mrs. Sureka Samarasena's 'Vam Piyavura', Mrs. Anuradha Nilmini's 'Nari Sutra (Poetry), Mrs. Sandarasee Sudusingha's 'Fire-hit Wings', Eric Ilayaparachi's 'Prometheus Island' is one of those works.",
        "For the best lyric collection of the year, the three works 'Pramayai Manaram' written by Mrs. Yamuna Malini Perera, 'Pama Vee Pipunu Mal Mihanai' written by Mr. Wasantha Kumara Kobawaka, and 'Sandamadala Vee' by Pallegama Hemarathana Thero have been recommended, and the best columns of the year. Recommended works for the anthology are 'Vannige Kolama' by Mr. Nayanasena Vanninayake, 'Close Images' by Mr. Buddhadasa Galappatti and 'Ninnada' by Harshini Pushpamala Arachchi.",
        "For the best academic collection of the year award, Dr. Premasiri Nagasinghe's 'Sinhala Upasakapnalankaraya Edition and Critical Study', Mr. Saman Panapitiya's 'Sinhala Folk Singing Styles', Senior Professor Mahinda Somathilaka's 'Keulgama Dalada Chama Maligaya', Mahinda K. Five works have been recommended, Mr. Wimalasiri's 'Kadawara Adahima' and Mrs. Sandhya Kahandagama's 'Sankya Purana'.",
        "Organized by the faculty committee of the Faculty of Humanities and Social Sciences of the University of Sri Jayawardenepura, this literary award ceremony is being held for the 13th time this year.",
        "This time Mr. Ananda Tissa Kumara, Senior Professor of Sinhala Department of Sri Jayewardenepura University will be the chief guest."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Sumangala Hall of Sri Jayawardenepura University",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "September 1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "3:00 PM",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the year",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "year",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the year",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sepali Mayadunne",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sandhyanandaya",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Keerthi Welisarage",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Shamel Jayakodi",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Premanishansa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Chandraratne Bandara",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Nakula",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Eric Ilayaparachchi",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the year",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "'International Confessions'",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Eric Ilayapaarachchi",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Mahinda Ratnayake",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Upali Ubayasekara",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Mawathaka Miminilla'",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Malindu Kavinda Kumarasinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Prince Senadheera",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Black Tall Man'",
            "label": "WORK_OF_ART"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Five",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "the year award",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Lakshantha Athukorala's",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Liyasav Lihi",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Gaya Ganasamadulu'",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sureka Samarasena",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "'Vam Piyavura'",
            "label": "WORK_OF_ART"
          },
          {
            "text": "Anuradha Nilmini",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "'Nari Sutra (Poetry",
            "label": "WORK_OF_ART"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sandarasee Sudusingha's",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Wings'",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Eric Ilayaparachi's",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Prometheus Island",
            "label": "LOC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the year",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "three",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Pramayai Manaram'",
            "label": "WORK_OF_ART"
          },
          {
            "text": "Yamuna Malini Perera",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Wasantha",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kumara Kobawaka",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sandamadala Vee'",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Pallegama",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Hemarathana Thero",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the year",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Vannige Kolama'",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Nayanasena Vanninayake",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Buddhadasa Galappatti",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ninnada",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Harshini Pushpamala Arachchi",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the year award",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Premasiri Nagasinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sinhala Upasakapnalankaraya Edition and Critical Study'",
            "label": "WORK_OF_ART"
          },
          {
            "text": "Saman Panapitiya",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Mahinda Somathilaka's",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Keulgama Dalada",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Mahinda K. Five",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Wimalasiri",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kadawara Adahima'",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sandhya Kahandagama's",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sankya Purana'",
            "label": "WORK_OF_ART"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the faculty committee of the Faculty of Humanities and Social Sciences",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the University of Sri Jayawardenepura",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the 13th",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "this year",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Ananda Tissa Kumara",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sinhala Department of Sri Jayewardenepura University",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "විද්‍යෝදය සාහිත්‍ය සම්මාන සඳහා නිර්දේශිත කෘතීන් ප්‍රකාශයට පත්කෙරේ",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "විද්‍යෝදය සාහිත්‍ය සම්මාන උළෙල ශ්‍රී ජයවර්ධනපුර විශ්ව විද්‍යාලයීය සුමංගල ශාලාවේදී සැප්තැම්බර් මස 1 වැනිදා පස්වරු 3.00ට පැවැත්වෙන අතර එහි සම්මාන සඳහා අවසන් වටයට නිර්දේශිත කෘතීන් මේ වන විට ප්‍රකාශයට පත්කර ඇත.",
        "වසරේ විශිෂ්ටතම නවකතාව, කෙටිකතා සංග්‍රහය, පද්‍ය සංග්‍රහය, ගේය පද සංග්‍රහය, තීරු ලිපි සංග්‍රහය සහ ශාස්ත්‍රීය සංග්‍රහය සඳහා මෙහිදී සම්මාන පිරිනැමේ.",
        "මෙවර වසරේ විශිෂ්ටතම නවකතාව සඳහා සේපාලි මායාදුන්නේ මහත්මිය රචනා කළ ‘හින් දොස් මාලේ’, කීර්ති වැලිසරගේ මහතා රචනා කළ ‘සන්ධ්‍යානන්දය’, ශමෙල් ජයකොඩි මහත්මිය රචනා කළ ‘මගේ චිකාගෝ හදවත’, චන්ද්‍රරත්න බණ්ඩාර මහතා රචනා කළ ‘ප්‍රේමානිශංස’ සහ එරික් ඉලයප්ආරච්චි මහතාගේ ‘නකුල මුනි’ යන නවකතා නිර්දේශ වී ඇත.",
        "එමෙන්ම වසරේ විශිෂ්ටතම කෙටි කතා සංග්‍රහයට හිමි සම්මානය සඳහා එරික් ඉලයප්ආරච්චි මහතාගේ ‘ජාත්‍යන්තර පාපොච්චාරණය’, මහින්ද රත්නායක මහතාගේ ‘වැසිකිළි සෝදන්නාගේ දුව වීම නිසා’, උපාලි උබයසේකර මහතාගේ ‘ගිනි සෝමෙ සහ තවත් කෙටිකතා’, මලිඳු කාවින්ද කුමාරසිංහ මහතාගේ ‘මං මාවතක මතක මිමිණිල්ල’ සහ ප්‍රින්ස් සේනාධීර මහතාගේ ‘කළු උස මනුස්සයෙක්’ යන කෘතීන් නිර්දේශ වී තිබේ.",
        "වසරේ විශිෂ්ටතම පද්‍ය සංග්‍රහය සම්මානය සඳහා කෘති පහක් නිර්දේශ වී ඇති අතර, ලක්ශාන්ත අතුකෝරල මහතාගේ ‘ලියසැව් ලිහී ගිය ගනසාමඩුලු’, සුරේකා සමරසේන මහත්මියගේ ‘වම් පියවුර’, අනුරාධා නිල්මිණි මහත්මියගේ ‘නාරි සූත්‍රය (කාව්‍යාලේඛය), සඳරැසී සුදුසිංහ මහත්මියගේ ‘ගිනි වැදුණු පියාපත්’, එරික් ඉලයප්ආරච්චි මහතාගේ ‘ප්‍රොමිතියස් දූපත’ එම කෘතීන් වේ.",
        "වසරේ විශිෂ්ටතම ගේය පද සංග්‍රහය සඳහා යමුනා මාලිනී පෙරේරා මහත්මිය රචනා කළ ‘ප්‍රේමයයි මනරම්’, වසන්ත කුමාර කොබවක මහතා රචනා කළ ‘පමා වී පිපුණු මල් සුවඳයි’, පල්ලේගම හේමරතන හිමියන්ගේ ‘සඳමඩල වී’ යන කෘතීන් ත්‍රිත්වය නිර්දේශ වී ඇති අතර, වසරේ විශිෂ්ටතම තීරු ලිපි සංග්‍රහය සඳහා නයනසේන වන්නිනායක මහතාගේ ‘වන්නිගේ කොලම’, බුද්ධදාස ගලප්පත්ති මහතාගේ ‘සමීප රූප’ සහ හර්ෂිනී පුෂ්පමාලා ආරච්චිගේ ‘නින්නාද’ යන කෘතීන් නිර්දේශිතය.",
        "වසරේ විශිෂ්ටතම ශාස්ත්‍රීය සංග්‍රහය සම්මානය සඳහා ආචාර්ය ප්‍රේමසිරි නාගසිංහ මහතාගේ ‘සිංහල උපාසකප්නාලංකාරය සංස්කරණය සහ විචාරාත්මක අධ්‍යයනයක්’, සමන් පනාපිටිය මහතාගේ ‘සිංහල ජන ගායන ශෛලී’, ජ්‍යෙෂ්ඨ මහාචාර්ය මහින්ද සෝමතිලක මහතා රචනා කළ ‘කෙවුල්ගම දළදා ගමන් මාලිගය’, මහින්ද කේ. විමලසිරි මහතාගේ ‘කඩවර ඇදහීම’, සන්ධ්‍යා කහඳගම මහත්මියගේ ‘සංඛ්‍යා පුරාණය’ යන කෘතීන් පහ නිර්දේශ වී ඇත.",
        "ශ්‍රී ජයවර්ධනපුර විශ්ව විද්‍යාලයේ මානව ශාස්ත්‍ර හා සමාජීය විද්‍යා පීඨයෙහි පීඨ කමිටුව මගින් වාර්ෂිකව සංවිධානය කරන මෙම සාහිත්‍ය සම්මාන උළෙල මෙවර පැවැත්වෙන්නේ මෙවර 13 වැනි වරටය.",
        "මෙවර එහි ප්‍රධාන ආරාධිතයා ලෙස ශ්‍රී ජයවර්ධනපුර විශ්ව විද්‍යාලයේ සිංහල අධ්‍යයනාංශයේ ජ්‍යෙෂ්ඨ මහාචාර්ය ආනන්ද තිස්ස කුමාර මහතා සහභාගීවීමට නියමිතය."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ජයවර්ධනපුර විශ්වවිද්‍යාලයේ සුමංගල ශාලාව",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "සැප්තැම්බර් 1 වැනිදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "3:00 ප.ව",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "වසර",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "වර්ෂය",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "වසර",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "සේපාලි මායාදුන්නේ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "සන්ධ්යානන්දය",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "කීර්ති වැලිසරගේ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශමෙල් ජයකොඩි",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ප්‍රේමනිශංස",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "චන්ද්‍රරත්න බණ්ඩාර",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "නකුල",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "එරික් ඉලයප්ආරච්චි",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "වසර",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "'ජාත්‍යන්තර පාපොච්චාරණ'",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "එරික් ඉලයප්ආරච්චි",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "මහින්ද රත්නායක",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "උපාලි උබයසේකර",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "මාවතක මිමිනිල්ලා'",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "මලිඳු කාවින්ද කුමාරසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "සේනාධීර කුමාරයා",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "කළු උස මිනිසා'",
            "label": "WORK_OF_ART"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "පහ",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "වසරේ සම්මානය",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ලක්ෂාන්ත අතුකෝරලගේ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ලියසව් ලිහි",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගයා ගණසමාදුළු'",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sureka Samarasena",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "'වම් පියවුර'",
            "label": "WORK_OF_ART"
          },
          {
            "text": "අනුරාධා නිල්මිණි",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "'නාරි සූත්‍රය (කාව්‍ය",
            "label": "WORK_OF_ART"
          },
          {
            "text": "සඳරසී සුදුසිංහගේ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "පියාපත්'",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "එරික් ඉලයප්‍රච්චිගේ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Prometheus දිවයින",
            "label": "LOC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "වසර",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "තුන්",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ප්‍රමෛ මනරම්'",
            "label": "WORK_OF_ART"
          },
          {
            "text": "යමුනා මාලිනී පෙරේරා",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "වසන්ත",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kumara Kobawaka",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "සඳමඩල වී'",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "පල්ලේගම",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "හේමරතන හිමි",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "වසර",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "වන්නිගේ කෝලම'",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "නයනසේන වන්නිනායක",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "බුද්ධදාස ගලප්පත්ති",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "නින්නාද",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "හර්ෂිනී පුෂ්පමාලා ආරච්චි",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "වසරේ සම්මානය",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ප්‍රේමසිරි නාගසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "සිංහල උපාසකප්නාලංකාරය සංස්කරණය සහ විචාර අධ්‍යයනය'",
            "label": "WORK_OF_ART"
          },
          {
            "text": "සමන් පනාපිටිය",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "මහින්ද සෝමතිලකගේ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "කියුල්ගම දළදාව",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "මහින්ද කේ පහ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "විමලසිරි",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "කඩවර අඩහිම'",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "සන්ධ්‍යා කහඳගමගේ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "සංක්‍ය පුරාණය'",
            "label": "WORK_OF_ART"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "මානව ශාස්ත්‍ර හා සමාජ විද්‍යා පීඨයේ පීඨ කමිටුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ජයවර්ධනපුර විශ්වවිද්‍යාලය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "13 වැනි",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මේ වසරේ",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ආනන්ද තිස්ස කුමාර",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ජයවර්ධනපුර විශ්වවිද්‍යාලයේ සිංහල අංශය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "வித்யோதயா சாகித்ய விருதுகளுக்குப் பரிந்துரைக்கப்பட்ட படைப்புகள் அறிவிக்கப்படும்",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "வித்யோதயா சாகித்ய விருது வழங்கும் விழா ஸ்ரீ ஜயவர்தனபுர பல்கலைக்கழகத்தின் சுமங்கலா மண்டபத்தில் செப்டம்பர் 1 ஆம் தேதி பிற்பகல் 3:00 மணிக்கு நடைபெறவுள்ளதுடன், இறுதிச் சுற்று விருதுகளுக்கு பரிந்துரைக்கப்பட்ட படைப்புகள் தற்போது அறிவிக்கப்பட்டுள்ளன.",
        "ஆண்டின் சிறந்த நாவல், சிறுகதைத் தொகுப்பு, கவிதைத் தொகுப்பு, பாடல் தொகுப்பு, பத்தித் தொகுப்பு மற்றும் கல்வித் தொகுப்பு ஆகியவற்றுக்கான விருதுகள் வழங்கப்படும்.",
        "திருமதி செபாலி மாயாதுன்னே எழுதிய 'ஹின் டோஸ் மாலே', திரு. கீர்த்தி வெலிசரகே எழுதிய 'சந்தியாநந்தயா', திருமதி ஷமேல் ஜயகொடி எழுதிய 'மை சிகாகோ ஹார்ட்', திரு. சந்திரரத்ன எழுதிய 'பிரேமனிஷான்சா' இந்த ஆண்டின் சிறந்த நாவல். பண்டார மற்றும் திரு.எரிக் இளையப்பராச்சி.முனி எழுதிய 'நகுல' நாவல்கள் பரிந்துரைக்கப்பட்டுள்ளன.",
        "மேலும் இவ்வாண்டின் சிறந்த சிறுகதைத் தொகுப்பிற்கான விருது, திரு எரிக் இளையபாராச்சியின் 'சர்வதேச வாக்குமூலங்கள்', 'கழிவறை கழுவுபவரின் மகள் என்பதால்', திரு.மகிந்த ரத்நாயக்கவின், 'கினி சில மற்றும் பிற சிறுகதைகள்' திரு உபாலி உபயசேகர, திரு.மலிந்து கவிந்த குமாரசிங்கவின் 'மனிதன் மாவதக மிமினிலாவின் நினைவுகள்' மற்றும் திரு.பிரின்ஸ் சேனாதீரவின் 'கருப்பு உயரமான மனிதன்' ஆகிய படைப்புகள் பரிந்துரைக்கப்பட்டுள்ளன.",
        "திரு.லக்ஷாந்த அத்துகோரளவின் ‘லியாசவ் லிஹி கய கனசமடுலு’, திருமதி சுரேகா சமரசேனவின் ‘வம் பியவுர’, திருமதி அனுராதா நில்மினியின் ‘நாரி சூத்ரா (கவிதை), திருமதி.சந்தாரஸ், ​​திருமதி. எரிக் இளையபராச்சியின் 'புரோமிதியஸ் தீவு' அந்த படைப்புகளில் ஒன்று.",
        "இந்த வருடத்தின் சிறந்த பாடல் தொகுப்புக்காக திருமதி யமுனா மாலினி பெரேரா எழுதிய 'பிரமையை மணரம்', திரு.வசந்த குமார கோபவக எழுதிய 'பாம வீ பிபுனு மல் மிஹானை', பல்லேகம ஹேமரத்தன தேரரின் 'சந்தமடல வீ' ஆகிய மூன்று படைப்புகளும் இடம் பெற்றுள்ளன. பரிந்துரைக்கப்பட்ட, மற்றும் ஆண்டின் சிறந்த பத்திகள்.திரு. நயனசேன வன்னிநாயக்கவின் 'வன்னிகே கோலமா', திரு. புத்ததாச கலப்பட்டியின் 'நெருக்கமான படங்கள்' மற்றும் ஹர்ஷினி புஷ்பமாலா ஆராச்சியின் 'நின்னதா' ஆகியவை தொகுப்புக்கு பரிந்துரைக்கப்பட்ட படைப்புகள்.",
        "ஆண்டின் சிறந்த கல்வித் தொகுப்புக்கான விருது, கலாநிதி பிரேமசிறி நாகசிங்கவின் 'சிங்கள உபாசகப்னாலங்காரய பதிப்பும் விமர்சன ஆய்வும்', திரு.சமன் பனாபிட்டியவின் 'சிங்கள நாட்டுப்புற பாடும் பாங்குகள்', சிரேஷ்ட பேராசிரியர் மஹிந்த சோமதிலகயின் 'கெயுல்கம தலதா கமௌல்கயா', மகிந்த மழலிகய, சமாலிக. திரு.விமலசிறியின் 'கடவர அடஹிம' மற்றும் திருமதி சந்தியா கஹந்தகமவின் 'சங்கிய புராணம்' ஆகிய ஐந்து படைப்புகள் பரிந்துரைக்கப்பட்டுள்ளன.",
        "ஸ்ரீ ஜயவர்தனபுர பல்கலைக்கழகத்தின் மனிதநேய மற்றும் சமூக விஞ்ஞான பீடத்தின் ஆசிரிய குழுவினால் ஏற்பாடு செய்யப்பட்ட இந்த இலக்கிய விருது விழா இவ்வருடம் 13 ஆவது தடவையாக நடைபெறுகின்றது.",
        "இம்முறை பிரதம அதிதியாக ஸ்ரீ ஜயவர்தனபுர பல்கலைக்கழகத்தின் சிங்களப் பிரிவின் சிரேஷ்ட பேராசிரியர் திரு ஆனந்த திஸ்ஸ குமார கலந்து கொள்ளவுள்ளார்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ஸ்ரீ ஜயவர்தனபுர பல்கலைக்கழகத்தின் சுமங்கலா மண்டபம்",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "செப்டம்பர் 1",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "3:00 PM",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஆண்டு",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஆண்டு",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆண்டு",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "செபாலி மாயாதுன்னே",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஸந்த்யாநந்দாய",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "கீர்த்தி வெலிசரகே",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஷாமல் ஜெயக்கொடி",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "பிரேமனிஷான்சா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "சந்திரரத்ன பண்டார",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "நகுலன்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "எரிக் இளையபாராச்சி",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஆண்டு",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "'சர்வதேச ஒப்புதல்கள்'",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "எரிக் இளையபாராச்சி",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "மஹிந்த ரத்நாயக்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "உபாலி உபயசேகர",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "மாவதக மிமினிலா'",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "மலிந்து காவிந்த குமாரசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இளவரசர் சேனாதீர",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "கருப்பு உயரமான மனிதன்",
            "label": "WORK_OF_ART"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஐந்து",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆண்டு விருது",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "லக்ஷாந்த அத்துகோரலவின்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "லியாசவ் லிஹி",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "கயா கணசமடுலு'",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sureka Samarasena",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "'வம் பியவுர'",
            "label": "WORK_OF_ART"
          },
          {
            "text": "அனுராதா நில்மினி",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "'நாரி சூத்ரா (கவிதை",
            "label": "WORK_OF_ART"
          },
          {
            "text": "சந்தரசீ சுதுசிங்கவின்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இறக்கைகள்'",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "எரிக் இளையபராச்சியின்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ப்ரோமிதியஸ் தீவு",
            "label": "LOC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஆண்டு",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "மூன்று",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "பிரமயை மனரம்'",
            "label": "WORK_OF_ART"
          },
          {
            "text": "யமுனா மாலினி பெரேரா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "வசந்தா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kumara Kobawaka",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "சண்டமடல வீ'",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "பல்லேகம",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஹேமரத்தன தேரோ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆண்டு",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "வன்னிகே கோலமா'",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "நயனசேன வன்னிநாயக்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "புத்ததாச கலப்பட்டி",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "நின்னாடா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஹர்ஷினி புஷ்பமாலா ஆராச்சி",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஆண்டு விருது",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "பிரேமசிறி நாகசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "சிங்கள உபாசகப்நலங்கராய பதிப்பு மற்றும் விமர்சன ஆய்வு'",
            "label": "WORK_OF_ART"
          },
          {
            "text": "சமன் பனாபிட்டிய",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "மஹிந்த சோமதிலக்கவின்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "கெயுல்கம தலதா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "மஹிந்த கே. ஐந்து",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "விமலசிறி",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "கடவர அடஹிமா'",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "சந்தியா கஹந்தகமவின்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "சங்கிய புராணம்'",
            "label": "WORK_OF_ART"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "மனிதநேயம் மற்றும் சமூக அறிவியல் பீடத்தின் ஆசிரிய குழு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஸ்ரீ ஜெயவர்தனபுர பல்கலைக்கழகம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "13வது",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்த வருடம்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஆனந்த திஸ்ஸ குமார",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஸ்ரீ ஜயவர்தனபுர பல்கலைக்கழகத்தின் சிங்களத் துறை",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}