{
  "newspaper_id": "daily-mirror-lk",
  "url": "https://www.dailymirror.lk/breaking_news/Parliament-to-meet-tomorrow-new-Prez-to-be-elected-within-seven-days-Speaker/108-241134",
  "time_ut": 1657859664,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Parliament to meet tomorrow; new Prez to be elected within seven days: Speaker",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Parliament to meet tomorrow; new Prez to be elected within seven days: Speaker",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "Parliament will meet tomorrow as the official resignation of President Gotabaya Rajapaksa was made today, Speaker Mahinda Yapa Abeywardena said.",
        "He said he expected to elect a new President through Parliament within seven days in accordance with the provisions of the Constitution.",
        "The Speaker said in terms of the Constitution Prime Minister Ranil Wickremesinghe will function in the capacity of the President overseeing functions, duties, and powers of the office of the President until the constitutional procedure of electing the new President is over. (Ajith Siriwardana)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Parliament",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "tomorrow",
          "label": "DATE"
        },
        {
          "text": "Prez",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "seven days",
          "label": "DATE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "tomorrow",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Gotabaya Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Mahinda Yapa Abeywardena",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "seven days",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Constitution",
            "label": "LAW"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Constitution",
            "label": "LAW"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ajith Siriwardana",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව හෙට රැස්වෙයි; දින හතක් ඇතුළත නව ජනාධිපතිවරයා තෝරා පත් කර ගනී: කථානායක",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "ජනාධිපති ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ මහතා නිල වශයෙන් ඉල්ලා අස්වීම අද සිදු කළ බැවින් පාර්ලිමේන්තුව හෙට රැස්වන බව කථානායක මහින්ද යාපා අබේවර්ධන මහතා පවසයි.",
        "ආණ්ඩුක්‍රම ව්‍යවස්ථාවේ ප්‍රතිපාදනවලට අනුව දින හතක් ඇතුළත පාර්ලිමේන්තුව හරහා නව ජනාධිපතිවරයකු තෝරා පත් කර ගැනීමට අපේක්ෂා කරන බව ඔහු පැවසීය.",
        "නව ජනාධිපතිවරයා තෝරා පත් කර ගැනීමේ ව්‍යවස්ථාපිත ක්‍රියා පටිපාටිය අවසන් වන තුරු, ආණ්ඩුක්‍රම ව්‍යවස්ථාවට අනුව අගමැති රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතා ජනාධිපති කාර්යාලයේ කාර්යයන්, රාජකාරි සහ බලතල අධීක්‍ෂණය කරමින් ජනාධිපතිවරයාගේ තත්ත්වයෙන් කටයුතු කරන බව කථානායකවරයා පැවසීය. (අජිත් සිරිවර්ධන)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "හෙට",
          "label": "DATE"
        },
        {
          "text": "ජනාධිපති",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "දින හතක්",
          "label": "DATE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "හෙට",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මහින්ද යාපා අබේවර්ධන",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "දින හතක්",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ව්යවස්ථාව",
            "label": "LAW"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ව්යවස්ථාව",
            "label": "LAW"
          },
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "අජිත් සිරිවර්ධන",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "நாடாளுமன்றம் நாளை கூடுகிறது; ஏழு நாட்களுக்குள் புதிய ஜனாதிபதி தேர்தல்: சபாநாயகர்",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "ஜனாதிபதி கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ஷவின் உத்தியோகபூர்வ பதவி விலகல் இன்று அறிவிக்கப்பட்டுள்ள நிலையில் நாளை பாராளுமன்றம் கூடும் என சபாநாயகர் மஹிந்த யாப்பா அபேவர்தன தெரிவித்துள்ளார்.",
        "அரசியலமைப்பின் விதிகளின்படி ஏழு நாட்களுக்குள் புதிய ஜனாதிபதியை பாராளுமன்றத்தின் ஊடாக தெரிவு செய்ய எதிர்பார்ப்பதாக அவர் கூறினார்.",
        "அரசியலமைப்பின் பிரகாரம், புதிய ஜனாதிபதியை தெரிவு செய்வதற்கான அரசியலமைப்பு நடைமுறை முடியும் வரை ஜனாதிபதியின் பணி, கடமைகள் மற்றும் அதிகாரங்களை மேற்பார்வையிடும் ஜனாதிபதி என்ற தகுதியில் பிரதமர் ரணில் விக்ரமசிங்க செயற்படுவார் என சபாநாயகர் தெரிவித்தார். (அஜித் சிறிவர்தன)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "நாளை",
          "label": "DATE"
        },
        {
          "text": "Prez",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "ஏழு நாட்கள்",
          "label": "DATE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "நாளை",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "மஹிந்த யாப்பா அபேவர்தன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஏழு நாட்கள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "அரசியலமைப்பு",
            "label": "LAW"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "அரசியலமைப்பு",
            "label": "LAW"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "அஜித் சிறிவர்தன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}