{
  "newspaper_id": "news-first-lk",
  "url": "https://www.newsfirst.lk/2022/07/04/strong-winds-for-coastal-areas/",
  "time_ut": 1656911460,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Strong winds for coastal areas",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Strong winds for coastal areas",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); The Department of Meteorology announced that the prevailing windy condition in the western and southern sea areas and the southern half of the island due to the active Southwest Monsoon condition is expected today.",
        "Showers will occur at times in Sabaragamuwa provinces and Kandy and Nuwara-Eliya districts. Several spells of showers will occur in Western and North-Western provinces and Galle and Matara districts.",
        "Showers or thundershowers may occur at a few places in Uva and Eastern provinces during the afternoon or night.",
        "Strong winds of about (50-60) kmph can be expected at times in the western slopes of the Central hills, Western, Southern, and North-Western provinces.",
        "The general public is kindly requested to take adequate precautions to minimize damages caused by temporary localized strong winds and lightning during thundershowers.",
        "We didn’t ask to evict fort protesters, say Australian Test stars"
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "The Department of Meteorology",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "half",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Southwest Monsoon",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sabaragamuwa",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kandy",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Nuwara-Eliya",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Western",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "North-Western",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "Galle",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Matara",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Uva",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Eastern",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the afternoon or night",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "50-60",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Central",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "Western",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Southern",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "North-Western",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "Australian",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "වෙරළබඩ ප්‍රදේශවලට තද සුළං",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); සක්‍රීය නිරිතදිග මෝසම් තත්ත්වය හේතුවෙන් බස්නාහිර සහ දකුණු මුහුදු ප්‍රදේශවල සහ දිවයිනේ දකුණු අර්ධයේ පවතින සුළං තත්ත්වය අද දිනයේදී අපේක්ෂා කරන බව කාලගුණ විද්‍යා දෙපාර්තමේන්තුව නිවේදනය කරයි.",
        "සබරගමුව පළාත්වලත් මහනුවර සහ නුවරඑළිය දිස්ත්‍රික්කවලත් විටින් විට වැසි ඇති වේ. බස්නාහිර සහ වයඹ පළාත්වලත් ගාල්ල සහ මාතර දිස්ත්‍රික්කවලත් වැසි වාර කිහිපයක් ඇතිවේ.",
        "අපරභාගයේදී හෝ රාත්‍රී කාලයේදී ඌව සහ නැගෙනහිර පළාත්වල ස්ථාන ස්වල්පයක වැසි හෝ ගිගුරුම් සහිත වැසි ඇති විය හැක.",
        "මධ්‍යම කඳුකරයේ බටහිර බෑවුම් ප්‍රදේශවලත් බස්නාහිර, දකුණ සහ වයඹ පළාත්වලත් විටින් විට හමන පැ.කි.මී. (50-60) පමණ තද සුළං බලාපොරොත්තු විය හැක.",
        "ගිගුරුම් සහිත වැසි ඇති වන විට එම ප්‍රදේශවල තාවකාලික තද සුළං සහ අකුණු මඟින් සිදුවන අනතුරු අවම කර ගැනීමට ප්‍රමාණවත් පියවර ගන්නා ලෙස සාමාන්‍ය ජනතාවගෙන් කාරුණිකව ඉල්ලා සිටියි.",
        "බලකොටු විරෝධතාකරුවන් ඉවත් කරන ලෙස අපි ඉල්ලා නොසිටි බව ඕස්ට්‍රේලියානු ටෙස්ට් ක්‍රීඩකයෝ පවසති"
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "කාලගුණ විද්‍යා දෙපාර්තමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "අඩක්",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "නිරිතදිග මෝසම්",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "සබරගමුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "මහනුවර",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "නුවරඑළිය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "බටහිර",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "වයඹ",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගාල්ල",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මාතර",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ඌව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "නැගෙනහිර",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "දහවල් හෝ රාත්රිය",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "50-60",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "මධ්යම",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "බටහිර",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "දකුණු",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "වයඹ",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "ඕස්ට්රේලියානු",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "கடலோர பகுதிகளில் பலத்த காற்று வீசுகிறது",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); தென்மேற்கு பருவக்காற்று செயலில் உள்ள நிலையின் காரணமாக மேற்கு மற்றும் தெற்கு கடற்பரப்புகளிலும் தீவின் தென்பகுதியிலும் நிலவும் காற்றுடன் கூடிய நிலை இன்று எதிர்பார்க்கப்படுவதாக வளிமண்டலவியல் திணைக்களம் அறிவித்துள்ளது.",
        "சப்ரகமுவ மாகாணங்களிலும் கண்டி மற்றும் நுவரெலியா மாவட்டங்களிலும் அவ்வப்போது மழை பெய்யும். மேல் மற்றும் வடமேல் மாகாணங்களிலும் காலி மற்றும் மாத்தறை மாவட்டங்களிலும் பல தடவைகள் மழை பெய்யும்.",
        "ஊவா மற்றும் கிழக்கு மாகாணங்களில் சில இடங்களில் பிற்பகல் அல்லது இரவு வேளையில் மழை அல்லது இடியுடன் கூடிய மழை பெய்யக்கூடும்.",
        "மத்திய மலைநாட்டின் மேற்கு சரிவுகள், மேற்கு, தெற்கு மற்றும் வடமேற்கு மாகாணங்களில் அவ்வப்போது மணித்தியாலத்துக்கு (50-60) கிமீ வேகத்தில் பலத்த காற்று வீசக்கூடும்.",
        "இடியுடன் கூடிய மழையின் போது தற்காலிகமாக பலத்த காற்று மற்றும் மின்னல் தாக்கங்களினால் ஏற்படக்கூடிய பாதிப்புகளை குறைத்துக்கொள்ள போதிய முன்னெச்சரிக்கை நடவடிக்கைகளை எடுக்குமாறு பொதுமக்கள் அன்புடன் கேட்டுக்கொள்ளப்படுகிறார்கள்.",
        "கோட்டை எதிர்ப்பாளர்களை வெளியேற்ற நாங்கள் கேட்கவில்லை என ஆஸ்திரேலிய டெஸ்ட் நட்சத்திரங்கள் கூறுகின்றனர்"
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "வளிமண்டலவியல் திணைக்களம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாதி",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "தென்மேற்கு பருவக்காற்று",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "சப்ரகமுவ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "கண்டி",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "நுவரெலியா",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "மேற்கு",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "வடமேற்கு",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "காலி",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "மாத்தறை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஊவா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "கிழக்கு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "மதியம் அல்லது இரவு",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "50-60",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "மத்திய",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "மேற்கு",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "தெற்கு",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "வடமேற்கு",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஆஸ்திரேலிய",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}