{
  "newspaper_id": "lankadeepa-lk",
  "url": "https://www.lankadeepa.lk/latest_news/බයිඩ්න්ගෙන්--ගෝඨාභයට-පණිවිඩයක්/1-615495",
  "time_ut": 1656330092,
  "original_lang": "si",
  "original_title": "බයිඩ්න්ගෙන්  ගෝඨාභයට පණිවිඩයක්",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "A message from Biden to Gotabhaya",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "The US High Commissioner to Sri Lanka today (27) assured President Gotabhaya Rajapaksa that Sri Lanka will continue to support Sri Lanka's strong relationship with the International Monetary Fund at all levels.",
        "They also said that the US President had instructed them to provide maximum assistance to Sri Lanka.",
        "The delegation said this when they met President Gotabhaya Rajapaksa at the President's House in Colombo Fort this morning (27).",
        "The delegation includes representatives from the US State Department and the Treasury Department.",
        "President Rajapaksa commended the delegation and briefed them on the country's economic woes, social difficulties and the progress of discussions with the International Monetary Fund.",
        "US President Joe Biden is very concerned about the future of Sri Lanka and the US President has instructed him to do his utmost to help Sri Lanka during this difficult time. And Robert Kaproth, Deputy Treasurer of the U.S. Treasury Department for Asia.",
        "The delegation said that with the implementation of the program with the International Monetary Fund for the families at risk, relief would be provided and hoped that it would be positive for the future as well.",
        "The delegation commended the President on the free space available for anyone to express their views.",
        "The delegation said it had provided US $ 100 million in medium-term aid and $ 5.75 million in humanitarian assistance to the Commercial Bank for small business development, adding that it had supported polyester fiber and yarn processing projects from discarded plastics.",
        "Messrs. Kelly Kiederlin and Robert Caproth said they would seek the assistance of international banks in assisting Sri Lanka in issuing letters of credit to obtain medicines and essential commodities.",
        "Matthew Mohlenkamp, ​​Director, South and Southeast Asia, Treasury, US; John McDaniel, Head, Economic Unit, South and Central Asia, State Department; John McDaniel, Julie Chung, US Ambassador, Sri Lanka; Acting Chief of Political Staff Geoff Chanin and Secretary to the President Gamini Senarath, Chief Adviser to the President Lalith Weeratunga and Chief of Staff to the President Anura Dissanayake were also present."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Biden",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "Gotabhaya",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "US",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "27",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Gotabhaya Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka's",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the International Monetary Fund",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "US",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Gotabhaya Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "House",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Colombo Fort",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "this morning",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "27",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the US State Department",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Treasury Department",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the International Monetary Fund",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "US",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Joe Biden",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "US",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Robert Kaproth",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Treasurer",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the U.S. Treasury Department",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Asia",
            "label": "LOC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the International Monetary Fund",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "$ 100 million",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "$ 5.75 million",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Commercial Bank",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Kelly Kiederlin",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Robert Caproth",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Matthew Mohlenkamp",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "​​Director",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "South",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "Southeast Asia",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "Treasury",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "US",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "John McDaniel",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Economic Unit",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "South",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "Central Asia",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "State Department",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "John McDaniel",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Julie Chung",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "US",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Geoff Chanin",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Gamini Senarath",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Lalith Weeratunga",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Anura Dissanayake",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "බයිඩ්න්ගෙන්  ගෝඨාභයට පණිවිඩයක්",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "ජාත්‍යන්තර මූල්‍ය අරමුදල සමග ශ්‍රී ලංකාව ඇතිකරගෙන ඇති සබඳතාව  ශක්තිමත්ව පවත්වාගෙන යෑමට සෑම  මට්ටමකදීම අඛණ්ඩව  සහය දෙන බව මෙරටට පැමිණ සිටින ඇමරිකානු රාජ්‍ය තාන්ත්‍රික ඉහළ  පෙළේ දූත පිරිස ජනාධිපති ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ මහතාට අද (27)  පොරොන්දු වූහ.",
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවට හැකි උපරිමයෙන් උපකාර කරන ලෙස ඇමරිකානු ජනාධිපතිවරයා උපදෙස් දුන් බවද  ඔවුහු සඳහන් කළහ.",
        "මෙම දූත පිරිස මෙසේ පැවසුවේ ජනාධිපති ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ මහතා කොළඹ කොටුව ජනාධිපති මන්දිරයේදී අද (27) පෙරවරුවේ හමුවූ අවස්ථාවේදීය.",
        "මෙම දූත පිරිසට   අමෙරිකානු රාජ්‍ය දෙපාර්තමේන්තුවේ සහ භාණ්ඩාගාර දෙපාර්තමේන්තුවේ  නියෝජිතයෝ ඇතුළත් වෙති.",
        "දූත පිරිසේ සංචාරය  මෙහිදී  පැසසුමට ලක් කළ ජනාධිපතිවරයා  රටේ ආර්ථික අසිරුතාව, සමාජයීය අපහසුතාව සහ ජාත්‍යන්තර මූල්‍ය අරමුදල සමග පැවැත්වෙන සාකච්ඡාවන්හි ප්‍රගතිය පිළිබඳව  එම පිරිස  දැනුවත් කළේය.",
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ අනාගතය ගැන ඇමරිකානු ජනාධිපති ජෝ බයිඩ්න් මහතා ඉතා උනන්දුවෙන් පසුවන බවත්  මේ අසීරු කාල සීමාවේදී ශ්‍රී ලංකාවට  හැකි උපරිමයෙන් උපකාර කිරීමට කටයුතු කරන ලෙස ඇමරිකානු ජනාධිපතිවරයා උපදෙස් දුන් බවත්  එක්සත් ජනපද රාජ්‍ය දෙපාර්තමේන්තුවේ දකුණු සහ මධ්‍යම ආසියාව සඳහා  නියෝජ්‍ය රාජ්‍ය සහකාර ලේකම් කෙලී කීඩර්ලින් (Kelly Keiderling) සහ එක්සත් ජනපද භාණ්ඩාගාර දෙපාර්තමේන්තුවේ ආසියානු කලාපය බාර නියෝජ්‍ය ලේකම් රොබර්ට් කැප්‍රෝත් (Robert Kaproth) යන මහත්වරු මෙහිදී  සඳහන් කළහ.",
        "අවදානමට ලක්ව සිටින පවුල් සඳහා  ජාත්‍යන්තර මූල්‍ය අරමුදල සමග වන වැඩසටහන ක්‍රියාත්මක වීමත් සමග  සහන ලැබෙන  බව පැවසූ දූත පිරිස ඉදිරි කටයුතු සඳහාද එය ධනාත්මකව බල පැවැත්වෙනු ඇති බවට විශ්වාසය පළ කළහ.",
        "ඕනෑම අයකුට අදහස් ප්‍රකාශ කිරීම සඳහාදී ඇති නිදහස් අවකාශය පිළිබඳව දූත පිරිස ජනාධිපතිවරයාට  ප්‍රසාදය පළ කළහ.",
        "කුඩා පරිමාණ ව්‍යාපාර නගා සිටුවීමට කොමර්ෂල් බැංකුවට ඇමරිකානු ඩොලර් මිලියන 100ක මධ්‍ය කාලීන ආධාර මුදලක්ද  මානුෂීය ආධාර ලෙස ඩොලර් මිලියන 5.75ක හා ඩොලර් මිලියන 6ක ප්‍රදානයක්ද කර ඇතැයි  පැවසූ එම දූත පිරිස  ඉවතලන ප්ලාස්ටික් ද්‍රව්‍යවලින් පොලියෙස්ටර් කෙදි සහ නූල් සැකසීමේ ව්‍යාපෘති සඳහා සහායදී ඇති බවද  සිහිපත් කළහ.",
        "ඖෂධ සහ අත්‍යාවශ්‍ය ද්‍රව්‍ය ලබා ගැනීමට ණයවර ලිපි නිකුත් කිරීමේ දී ශ්‍රී ලංකාවට සහාය වන ලෙස ජාත්‍යන්තර බැංකු වෙතින් ඉල්ලා සිටීමට කටයුතු කරන බව කෙලී කීඩර්ලින් සහ රොබර්ට් කැප්‍රෝත් යන මහත්වරු කියා සිටියහ.",
        "මේ සාකච්ඡාවට එක්සත් ජනපද භාණ්ඩාගාර කාර්යාලයේ දකුණු සහ අග්නිදිග ආසියාවේ අධ්‍යක්ෂ මැතිව් මොහෙලෙන්කැම්ප් (Matthew Mohlenkamp), එක්සත් ජනපද රාජ්‍ය දෙපාර්තමේන්තුවේ දකුණු සහ මධ්‍යම ආසියාවේ ආර්ථික ඒකක ප්‍රධානි ජෝන් මැක්ඩැනියෙල් (John McDaniel), ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ ඇමරිකානු තානාපති ජූලි චන්ග් (Julie Chung), ඇමරිකානු තානාපති කාර්යාලයේ වැඩබලන දේශපාලන ප්‍රධානී ජෙෆ් චැනින් (Geoff Chanin) හා ජනාධිපති ලේකම් ගාමිණී සෙනරත්, ජනාධිපති ප්‍රධාන උපදේශක ලලිත් වීරතුංග සහ ජනාධිපති කාර්ය මණ්ඩල ප්‍රධානී අනුර දිසානායක යන මහත්ම මහත්මීන් ඇතුළු පිරිසක්ද සහභාගි වූහ."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "බයිඩෙන්",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "ගෝඨාභය",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "එක්සත් ජනපදය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "27",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජාත්‍යන්තර මුල්‍ය අරමුදල",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "එක්සත් ජනපදය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "නිවස",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "කොළඹ කොටුව",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "මේ උදෑසන",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "27",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "එක්සත් ජනපද රාජ්ය දෙපාර්තමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "භාණ්ඩාගාර දෙපාර්තමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජාත්‍යන්තර මුල්‍ය අරමුදල",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "එක්සත් ජනපදය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Joe Biden",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "එක්සත් ජනපදය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "රොබට් කප්රොත්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "භාණ්ඩාගාරික",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "එක්සත් ජනපද භාණ්ඩාගාර දෙපාර්තමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ආසියාව",
            "label": "LOC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ජාත්‍යන්තර මුල්‍ය අරමුදල",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "ඩොලර් මිලියන 100 කි",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඩොලර් මිලියන 5.75 කි",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "කොමර්ෂල් බැංකුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "කෙලී කීඩර්ලින්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "රොබට් කප්රොත්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "මැතිව් මොලෙන්කැම්ප්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "අධ්යක්ෂක",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "දකුණු",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගිනිකොනදිග ආසියාව",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "භාණ්ඩාගාර",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "එක්සත් ජනපදය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජෝන් මැක්ඩැනියෙල්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ආර්ථික ඒකකය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "දකුණු",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "මධ්යම ආසියාව",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "රාජ්ය දෙපාර්තමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජෝන් මැක්ඩැනියෙල්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජූලි චුන්ග්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "එක්සත් ජනපදය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජෙෆ් චැනින්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගාමිණී සෙනරත්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ලලිත් වීරතුංග",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "අනුර දිසානායක",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "கோத்தபாயவுக்கு பிடனிடமிருந்து ஒரு செய்தி",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "சர்வதேச நாணய நிதியத்துடனான இலங்கையின் வலுவான உறவுக்கு அனைத்து மட்டங்களிலும் இலங்கை தொடர்ந்து ஆதரவளிக்கும் என இலங்கைக்கான அமெரிக்க உயர்ஸ்தானிகர் இன்று (27) ஜனாதிபதி கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ஷவுக்கு உறுதியளித்துள்ளார்.",
        "இலங்கைக்கு அதிகபட்ச உதவிகளை வழங்குமாறு அமெரிக்க ஜனாதிபதி பணிப்புரை விடுத்துள்ளதாகவும் அவர்கள் தெரிவித்துள்ளனர்.",
        "இன்று (27) முற்பகல் கொழும்பு கோட்டையில் உள்ள ஜனாதிபதி மாளிகையில் ஜனாதிபதி கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ஷவை சந்தித்த போதே தூதுக்குழுவினர் இதனைத் தெரிவித்துள்ளனர்.",
        "தூதுக்குழுவில் அமெரிக்க வெளியுறவுத்துறை மற்றும் கருவூலத் துறையின் பிரதிநிதிகள் உள்ளனர்.",
        "ஜனாதிபதி ராஜபக்ஷ அவர்கள் தூதுக்குழுவினரைப் பாராட்டியதுடன், நாட்டின் பொருளாதார நெருக்கடிகள், சமூக நெருக்கடிகள் மற்றும் சர்வதேச நாணய நிதியத்துடனான கலந்துரையாடல்களின் முன்னேற்றம் குறித்து அவர்களுக்கு விளக்கமளித்தார்.",
        "இலங்கையின் எதிர்காலம் குறித்து அமெரிக்க ஜனாதிபதி ஜோ பிடன் மிகவும் கரிசனை கொண்டுள்ளதாகவும், இந்த இக்கட்டான நேரத்தில் இலங்கைக்கு தன்னால் இயன்ற உதவிகளை செய்யுமாறும் அமெரிக்க ஜனாதிபதி அவருக்கு பணிப்புரை விடுத்துள்ளார்.மற்றும் அமெரிக்க கருவூல திணைக்களத்தின் ஆசியாவிற்கான பிரதிப் பொருளாளர் ரொபேர்ட் கப்ரோத்.",
        "ஆபத்தில் உள்ள குடும்பங்களுக்கு சர்வதேச நாணய நிதியத்துடன் கூடிய வேலைத்திட்டம் அமுல்படுத்தப்படுவதன் மூலம் நிவாரணம் வழங்கப்படும் எனவும் அது எதிர்காலத்திற்கும் சாதகமாக அமையும் எனவும் தூதுக்குழுவினர் நம்பிக்கை வெளியிட்டுள்ளனர்.",
        "எவரும் தமது கருத்துக்களை வெளியிடுவதற்கான இலவச இடம் குறித்து ஜனாதிபதிக்கு தூதுக்குழுவினர் பாராட்டு தெரிவித்தனர்.",
        "சிறு வணிக மேம்பாட்டுக்காக கொமர்ஷல் வங்கிக்கு 100 மில்லியன் அமெரிக்க டாலர்கள் நடுத்தர கால உதவியும், மனிதாபிமான உதவியாக 5.75 மில்லியன் டாலர்களும் வழங்கியதாகக் கூறிய பிரதிநிதிகள், தூக்கி எறியப்பட்ட பிளாஸ்டிக்கிலிருந்து பாலியஸ்டர் ஃபைபர் மற்றும் நூல் செயலாக்கத் திட்டங்களை ஆதரிப்பதாகக் கூறினார்.",
        "மருந்துகள் மற்றும் அத்தியாவசியப் பொருட்களைப் பெறுவதற்கு கடன் கடிதங்களை வழங்குவதற்கு இலங்கைக்கு உதவுவதற்கு சர்வதேச வங்கிகளின் உதவியை நாடவுள்ளதாக கெல்லி கீடர்லின் மற்றும் ரொபர்ட் கப்ரோத் ஆகியோர் தெரிவித்தனர்.",
        "அமெரிக்காவின் தெற்கு மற்றும் தென்கிழக்கு ஆசியாவின் கருவூலத்தின் பணிப்பாளர் மேத்யூ மொஹ்லென்காம்ப், தெற்கு மற்றும் மத்திய ஆசியாவின் பொருளாதாரப் பிரிவின் தலைவர் ஜோன் மெக்டானியல், இலங்கையின் அமெரிக்கத் தூதுவர் ஜோன் மெக்டானியல், ஜூலி சுங், அரசியல் பணியாளர்களின் செயல் தலைவர் ஜெஃப் சானின் மற்றும் ஜனாதிபதியின் செயலாளர் காமினி செனரத், ஜனாதிபதியின் பிரதான ஆலோசகர் லலித் வீரதுங்க மற்றும் ஜனாதிபதியின் பணிமனைகளின் பிரதானி அனுர திஸாநாயக்க ஆகியோரும் கலந்துகொண்டனர்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "பிடன்",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "கோத்தபாய",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "எங்களுக்கு",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "27",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "கோத்தபாய ராஜபக்ச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கையின்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சர்வதேச நாணய நிதியம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "எங்களுக்கு",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "கோத்தபாய ராஜபக்ச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "வீடு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "கொழும்பு கோட்டை",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று காலை",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "27",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "அமெரிக்க வெளியுறவுத்துறை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "கருவூலத் துறை",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ராஜபக்சே",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "சர்வதேச நாணய நிதியம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "எங்களுக்கு",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Joe Biden",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "எங்களுக்கு",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ராபர்ட் கப்ரோத்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "பொருளாளர்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "அமெரிக்க கருவூலத் துறை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆசியா",
            "label": "LOC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "சர்வதேச நாணய நிதியம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "$ 100 மில்லியன்",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "$ 5.75 மில்லியன்",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "வணிக வங்கி",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "கெல்லி கீடர்லின்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ராபர்ட் கப்ரோத்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "மேத்யூ மோலென்காம்ப்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இயக்குனர்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "தெற்கு",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "தென்கிழக்கு ஆசியா",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "கருவூலம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "எங்களுக்கு",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜான் மெக்டேனியல்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "பொருளாதார பிரிவு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "தெற்கு",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "மைய ஆசியா",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "மாநில துறை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜான் மெக்டேனியல்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜூலி சுங்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "எங்களுக்கு",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜெஃப் சானின்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "காமினி செனரத்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "லலித் வீரதுங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "அனுர திஸாநாயக்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}