{
  "newspaper_id": "ada-derana-lk",
  "url": "http://www.adaderana.lk/news/84300/41-dead-in-egyptian-church-fire",
  "time_ut": 1660484880,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "41 dead in Egyptian church fire",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "41 dead in Egyptian church fire",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "A fire that broke out Sunday in a Coptic Christian church in Egypt’s capital Cairo killed 41 people and injured 14 others, church officials said.",
        "The blaze started for unknown reasons at the Abu Sifine church in the capital’s northwestern, working-class district of Imbaba, officials said.",
        "President Abdel Fattah al-Sisi declared on his Facebook page that “I have mobilised all state services to ensure that all measures are taken”.",
        "Fire services later said the blaze had been brought under control.",
        "Copts are the largest Christian community in the Middle East, making up at least 10 million of Egypt’s 103 million people.",
        "The minority has suffered attacks and complained of discrimination in the majority Muslim north African country, the Arab world’s most populous.",
        "Copts have suffered reprisals from Islamists, particularly after Sisi overthrew former Islamist president Mohamed Morsi in 2013, with churches, schools and homes burnt down.",
        "Sisi, the first Egyptian president to attend the Coptic Christmas mass every year, recently appointed a Coptic judge to head the Constitutional Court for the first time in history.",
        "In March 2021, at least 20 people died in a blaze in a textile factory in the eastern suburbs of Cairo.",
        "In 2020, two hospital fires claimed the lives of 14 Covid-19 patients."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "41",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "Egyptian",
          "label": "NORP"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Sunday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Coptic Christian",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Egypt",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Cairo",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "41",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "14",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Abu Sifine",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Imbaba",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Abdel Fattah al-Sisi",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "Copts",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Christian",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Middle East",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "at least 10 million",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Egypt",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "103 million",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Muslim",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "north African",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Arab",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Copts",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Islamists",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Islamist",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Mohamed Morsi",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "2013",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "first",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Egyptian",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "every year",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Coptic",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Constitutional Court",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "first",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "March 2021",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "at least 20",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Cairo",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "2020",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "two",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "14",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "ඊජිප්තු දේවස්ථානයක ගින්නකින් 41ක් මරුට",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "ඊජිප්තුවේ කයිරෝ අගනුවර කොප්ටික් ක්‍රිස්තියානි දේවස්ථානයක ඉරිදා හටගත් ගින්නකින් පුද්ගලයන් 41 දෙනෙකු මියගොස් තවත් 14 දෙනෙකු තුවාල ලබා ඇති බව පල්ලියේ බලධාරීහු පවසති.",
        "ඉම්බාබා හි වයඹදිග කම්කරු පන්තියේ දිස්ත්‍රික්කයේ අබු සිෆින් දේවස්ථානයේ නොදන්නා හේතූන් මත ගින්න ආරම්භ වූ බව නිලධාරීහු පවසති.",
        "ජනාධිපති අබ්දෙල් ෆටා අල්-සිසි සිය ෆේස්බුක් පිටුවේ ප්‍රකාශ කළේ “සියලු ක්‍රියාමාර්ග ගැනීම සහතික කිරීම සඳහා මම සියලුම රාජ්‍ය සේවාවන් බලමුලු ගන්වා ඇති” බවයි.",
        "පසුව ගිනි නිවීම් සේවා ප්‍රකාශ කළේ ගින්න පාලනය කර ඇති බවයි.",
        "කොප්ට්ස් යනු මැද පෙරදිග විශාලතම ක්‍රිස්තියානි ප්‍රජාව වන අතර, ඊජිප්තුවේ මිලියන 103 ක ජනගහනයෙන් අවම වශයෙන් මිලියන 10 ක් පමණ වේ.",
        "අරාබි ලෝකයේ වඩාත්ම ජනාකීර්ණ බහුතර මුස්ලිම් උතුරු අප්‍රිකානු රටෙහි සුළුතරය ප්‍රහාරවලට ලක්ව ඇති අතර වෙනස්කම් කිරීම් ගැන පැමිණිලි කර ඇත.",
        "පල්ලි, පාසල් සහ නිවාස ගිනිබත් කරමින් 2013 දී හිටපු ඉස්ලාමීය ජනාධිපති මොහොමඩ් මෝර්සි බලයෙන් පහකිරීමෙන් පසුව, විශේෂයෙන්ම සිසි විසින් ඉස්ලාම්වාදීන්ගෙන් පළිගැනීම්වලට ලක්ව ඇත.",
        "සෑම වසරකම කොප්ටික් නත්තල් උත්සවයට සහභාගී වන පළමු ඊජිප්තු ජනාධිපතිවරයා වන සිසි, ඉතිහාසයේ ප්‍රථම වතාවට ආණ්ඩුක්‍රම ව්‍යවස්ථා අධිකරණයේ ප්‍රධානියා ලෙස කොප්ටික් විනිසුරුවරයෙකු මෑතකදී පත් කළේය.",
        "2021 මාර්තු මාසයේදී කයිරෝවේ නැගෙනහිර තදාසන්න ප්‍රදේශයේ රෙදිපිළි කම්හලක ඇති වූ ගින්නකින් අවම වශයෙන් පුද්ගලයින් 20 දෙනෙකු මිය ගියහ.",
        "2020 දී රෝහල් ගිනිගැනීම් දෙකකින් Covid-19 රෝගීන් 14 දෙනෙකු ජීවිතක්ෂයට පත් විය."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "41",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "ඊජිප්තු",
          "label": "NORP"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ඉරිදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "කොප්ටික් ක්‍රිස්තියානි",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඊජිප්තුව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "කයිරෝ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "41",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "14",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "අබු සිෆින්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉම්බාබා",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "අබ්දෙල් ෆාටා අල්-සිසි",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "කොප්ට්ස්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ක්රිස්තියානි",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "මැද පෙරදිග",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "අවම වශයෙන් මිලියන 10 ක්",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඊජිප්තුව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මිලියන 103 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "මුස්ලිම්",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "උතුරු අප්රිකානු",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "අරාබි",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "කොප්ට්ස්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉස්ලාම්වාදීන්",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉස්ලාමීය",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "මොහොමඩ් මොර්සි",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "2013",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "පළමුවන",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඊජිප්තු",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "සෑම වසරකම",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "කොප්ටික්",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "ව්යවස්ථා අධිකරණය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "පළමුවන",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "2021 මාර්තු",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "අවම වශයෙන් 20",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "කයිරෝ",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "2020",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "දෙක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "14",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "எகிப்து தேவாலயத்தில் ஏற்பட்ட தீ விபத்தில் 41 பேர் பலியாகினர்",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "எகிப்து தலைநகர் கெய்ரோவில் உள்ள காப்டிக் கிறிஸ்தவ தேவாலயத்தில் ஞாயிற்றுக்கிழமை ஏற்பட்ட தீ விபத்தில் 41 பேர் உயிரிழந்ததுடன் 14 பேர் காயமடைந்துள்ளதாக தேவாலய அதிகாரிகள் தெரிவித்துள்ளனர்.",
        "தலைநகரின் வடமேற்கு, தொழிலாள வர்க்க மாவட்டமான இம்பாபாவில் உள்ள அபு சிஃபின் தேவாலயத்தில் அறியப்படாத காரணங்களுக்காக தீப்பிடித்ததாக அதிகாரிகள் தெரிவித்தனர்.",
        "ஜனாதிபதி அப்தெல் ஃபத்தா அல்-சிசி தனது முகநூல் பக்கத்தில், \"அனைத்து நடவடிக்கைகளும் எடுக்கப்படுவதை உறுதி செய்வதற்காக நான் அனைத்து அரசு சேவைகளையும் அணிதிரட்டியுள்ளேன்\" என்று அறிவித்தார்.",
        "பின்னர் தீ கட்டுக்குள் கொண்டு வரப்பட்டதாக தீயணைப்பு துறையினர் தெரிவித்தனர்.",
        "எகிப்தின் 103 மில்லியன் மக்களில் குறைந்தது 10 மில்லியனைக் கொண்ட மத்திய கிழக்கின் மிகப்பெரிய கிறிஸ்தவ சமூகம் காப்ட்ஸ் ஆகும்.",
        "சிறுபான்மையினர் தாக்குதலுக்கு ஆளாகியுள்ளனர் மற்றும் அரபு உலகில் அதிக மக்கள்தொகை கொண்ட வட ஆப்பிரிக்க நாடான பெரும்பான்மை முஸ்லிம்களில் பாகுபாடு காட்டப்படுவதாக புகார் அளித்துள்ளனர்.",
        "கோப்ட்ஸ் இஸ்லாமியர்களிடமிருந்து பழிவாங்கலுக்கு ஆளாகியுள்ளனர், குறிப்பாக 2013 இல் சிசி முன்னாள் இஸ்லாமிய அதிபர் முகமது மோர்சியை பதவியில் இருந்து அகற்றிய பின்னர், தேவாலயங்கள், பள்ளிகள் மற்றும் வீடுகள் எரிக்கப்பட்டன.",
        "ஒவ்வொரு ஆண்டும் காப்டிக் கிறிஸ்துமஸ் மாஸ்ஸில் கலந்து கொள்ளும் முதல் எகிப்திய ஜனாதிபதியான சிசி, வரலாற்றில் முதல்முறையாக அரசியலமைப்பு நீதிமன்றத்தின் தலைவராக காப்டிக் நீதிபதியை சமீபத்தில் நியமித்தார்.",
        "மார்ச் 2021 இல், கெய்ரோவின் கிழக்கு புறநகர்ப் பகுதியில் உள்ள ஜவுளித் தொழிற்சாலையில் ஏற்பட்ட தீ விபத்தில் குறைந்தது 20 பேர் இறந்தனர்.",
        "2020 ஆம் ஆண்டில், இரண்டு மருத்துவமனை தீ விபத்துகளில் 14 கோவிட்-19 நோயாளிகள் உயிரிழந்தனர்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "41",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "எகிப்தியன்",
          "label": "NORP"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ஞாயிற்றுக்கிழமை",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "காப்டிக் கிறிஸ்தவர்",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "எகிப்து",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "கெய்ரோ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "41",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "14",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "அபு சிஃபின்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இம்பாபா",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "அப்தெல் ஃபத்தா அல்-சிசி",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "காப்ட்ஸ்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "கிறிஸ்துவர்",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "மத்திய கிழக்கு",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "குறைந்தது 10 மில்லியன்",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "எகிப்து",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "103 மில்லியன்",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "முஸ்லிம்",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "வட ஆப்பிரிக்க",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "அரபு",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "காப்ட்ஸ்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இஸ்லாமியர்கள்",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "இஸ்லாமியர்",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "முகமது மோர்சி",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "2013",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "முதலில்",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "எகிப்தியன்",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஒவ்வொரு வருடமும்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "காப்டிக்",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "அரசியலமைப்பு நீதிமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "முதலில்",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "மார்ச் 2021",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "குறைந்தது 20",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "கெய்ரோ",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "2020",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இரண்டு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "14",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}