{
  "newspaper_id": "news-first-lk",
  "url": "https://www.newsfirst.lk/2022/09/04/digital-birth-certificates-for-babies-born-in-august/",
  "time_ut": 1662268740,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Digital birth certificates for babies born in August",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Digital birth certificates for babies born in August",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); The Department of Registration of Persons has started issuing a digital birth certificate, the National Birth Certificate in the digital format.",
        "Registrar General Prabhath Abeywardena said that the birth certificate will be issued for the children who were born from 1st of August 2022.",
        "The Registrar General said that the digital birth certificate program will be implemented across the island in the future.",
        "He pointed out that the number associated with the baby in the digital birth certificate will be their National Identity Card number when they are of 15 years of age.",
        "The program has been implemented across 6 Divisional Secretariat Divisions, and the Registrar General stated that the certificate will be issued in two languages, Sinhala-Tamil or English- Tamil, in order to enable translations.",
        "If IMF reforms not implemented, Sri Lanka goes back to square one – CBSL Chief"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Digital",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "August",
          "label": "DATE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "News 1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "The Department of Registration of Persons",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the National Birth Certificate",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Prabhath Abeywardena",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "1st of August 2022",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "The Registrar General",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Identity Card",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "15 years of age",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "6",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Registrar General",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "two",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sinhala-Tamil",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "Tamil",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "අගෝස්තු මාසයේ උපත ලද ළදරුවන් සඳහා ඩිජිටල් උප්පැන්න සහතික",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); පුද්ගලයන් ලියාපදිංචි කිරීමේ දෙපාර්තමේන්තුව විසින් ඩිජිටල් උප්පැන්න සහතිකය, ජාතික උප්පැන්න සහතිකය ඩිජිටල් ආකෘතියෙන් නිකුත් කිරීම ආරම්භ කර ඇත.",
        "උප්පැන්න සහතිකය 2022 අගෝස්තු 01 වැනිදා සිට උපත ලැබූ දරුවන් සඳහා නිකුත් කරන බව රෙජිස්ට්‍රාර් ජනරාල් ප්‍රභාත් අබේවර්ධන මහතා පැවසීය.",
        "ඩිජිටල් උප්පැන්න සහතික වැඩසටහන ඉදිරියේදී දිවයින පුරා ක්‍රියාත්මක කරන බව රෙජිස්ට්‍රාර් ජනරාල්වරයා පැවසීය.",
        "ඩිජිටල් උප්පැන්න සහතිකයේ බිළිඳා සම්බන්ධ අංකය වයස අවුරුදු 15 සම්පූර්ණ වූ විට ඔවුන්ගේ ජාතික හැඳුනුම්පත් අංකය වනු ඇතැයි ඔහු පෙන්වා දුන්නේය.",
        "මෙම වැඩසටහන ප්‍රාදේශීය ලේකම් කොට්ඨාශ 6ක් පුරා ක්‍රියාත්මක කර ඇති අතර, පරිවර්තන සක්‍රීය කිරීම සඳහා සහතිකය සිංහල-දෙමළ හෝ ඉංග්‍රීසි-දෙමළ යන භාෂා දෙකෙන් නිකුත් කරන බව රෙජිස්ට්‍රාර් ජනරාල්වරයා සඳහන් කළේය.",
        "ජාත්‍යන්තර මූල්‍ය අරමුදලේ ප්‍රතිසංස්කරණ ක්‍රියාත්මක නොකළහොත් ශ්‍රී ලංකාව පළමු තැනට යයි - මහ බැංකුවේ ප්‍රධානියා"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ඩිජිටල්",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "අගෝස්තු",
          "label": "DATE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "News 1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "පුද්ගලයන් ලියාපදිංචි කිරීමේ දෙපාර්තමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජාතික උප්පැන්න සහතිකය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ප්‍රභාත් අබේවර්ධන",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "2022 අගෝස්තු 1 වෙනිදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "රෙජිස්ට්රාර් ජනරාල්",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "හැඳුනුම්පත",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "වයස අවුරුදු 15 යි",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "6",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "රෙජිස්ට්රාර් ජනරාල්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "දෙක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "සිංහල-දෙමළ",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "දෙමළ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "ஆகஸ்ட் மாதத்தில் பிறந்த குழந்தைகளுக்கான டிஜிட்டல் பிறப்புச் சான்றிதழ்",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); ஆட்கள் பதிவுத் திணைக்களம் டிஜிட்டல் பிறப்புச் சான்றிதழை, தேசிய பிறப்புச் சான்றிதழை டிஜிட்டல் வடிவத்தில் வழங்கத் தொடங்கியுள்ளது.",
        "2022 ஓகஸ்ட் முதலாம் திகதி முதல் பிறந்த குழந்தைகளுக்கு பிறப்புச் சான்றிதழ் வழங்கப்படும் என பதிவாளர் நாயகம் பிரபாத் அபேவர்தன தெரிவித்துள்ளார்.",
        "டிஜிட்டல் பிறப்பு சான்றிதழ் திட்டம் எதிர்காலத்தில் நாடளாவிய ரீதியில் நடைமுறைப்படுத்தப்படும் என பதிவாளர் நாயகம் தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "டிஜிட்டல் பிறப்புச் சான்றிதழில் உள்ள குழந்தையுடன் தொடர்புடைய எண் 15 வயதை எட்டும்போது அவர்களின் தேசிய அடையாள அட்டை எண்ணாக இருக்கும் என்று அவர் சுட்டிக்காட்டினார்.",
        "இந்த வேலைத்திட்டம் 6 பிரதேச செயலகப் பிரிவுகளில் அமுல்படுத்தப்பட்டுள்ளதுடன், மொழிமாற்றங்களைச் செயல்படுத்தும் வகையில் சிங்களம்-தமிழ் அல்லது ஆங்கிலம்-தமிழ் ஆகிய இரு மொழிகளில் சான்றிதழ் வழங்கப்படும் என பதிவாளர் நாயகம் தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "சர்வதேச நாணய நிதியத்தின் சீர்திருத்தங்கள் நடைமுறைப்படுத்தப்படாவிட்டால், இலங்கை மீண்டும் முதல் நிலைக்குச் செல்லும் - CBSL தலைவர்"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "டிஜிட்டல்",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "ஆகஸ்ட்",
          "label": "DATE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "News 1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆட்கள் பதிவு துறை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "தேசிய பிறப்புச் சான்றிதழ்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பிரபாத் அபேவர்தன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆகஸ்ட் 1, 2022",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பதிவாளர் ஜெனரல்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "அடையாள அட்டை",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "15 வயது",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "6",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "பதிவாளர் ஜெனரல்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இரண்டு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "சிங்களம்-தமிழ்",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "தமிழ்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}