{
  "newspaper_id": "daily-mirror-lk",
  "url": "https://www.dailymirror.lk/breaking_news/Tension-prevails-at-railway-stations/108-240697",
  "time_ut": 1657341507,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Tension prevails at railway stations",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Tension prevails at railway stations",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "Tension has been reported at Galle, Matara and Kandy railway stations as stations were overcrowded and the angry commuters demanding station masters to operate trains despite the cancellation order.",
        "The station masters of the respective railway stations said the situation was gradually spilling out of control.",
        "The commuters were demanding them to allow the trains head towards Colombo.",
        "The Sri Lanka Station Masters' Union said although the trains have not started as per the normal schedule as yet, several trains are already on tracks heading towards Colombo Fort. (Chaturanga Samarawickrama)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Galle",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Matara",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kandy",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "The Sri Lanka Station Masters' Union",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Colombo Fort",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "Chaturanga Samarawickrama",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "දුම්රිය ස්ථානවල නොසන්සුන්තාවක් පවතී",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "ගාල්ල, මාතර සහ මහනුවර දුම්රිය ස්ථාන පිරී ඉතිරී යාමත් සමඟ කෝපයට පත් මගීන් දුම්රිය අවලංගු කිරීමේ නියෝගය නොතකා දුම්රිය ස්ථානාධිපතිවරුන්ගෙන් ඉල්ලා සිටින බව වාර්තා වේ.",
        "තත්ත්වය ක්‍රමයෙන් පාලනය කරගත නොහැකි වෙමින් පවතින බව අදාළ දුම්රිය ස්ථානවල ස්ථානාධිපතිවරු ප්‍රකාශ කළහ.",
        "මගීහු ඉල්ලා සිටියේ කොළඹ දෙසට යන දුම්රියට ඉඩ දෙන ලෙසයි.",
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකා දුම්රිය ස්ථානාධිපතිවරුන්ගේ සංගමය පැවසුවේ මෙතෙක් සාමාන්‍ය කාලසටහනට අනුව දුම්රිය ගමන් ආරම්භ කර නොමැති නමුත් මේ වන විටත් දුම්රිය කිහිපයක් කොළඹ කොටුව දෙසට ධාවනය වෙමින් පවතින බවයි. (චතුරංග සමරවික්‍රම)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ගාල්ල",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මාතර",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මහනුවර",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකා දුම්රිය ස්ථානාධිපති සංගමය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "කොළඹ කොටුව",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "චතුරංග සමරවික්‍රම",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "ரயில் நிலையங்களில் பதற்றம் நிலவுகிறது",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "காலி, மாத்தறை மற்றும் கண்டி புகையிரத நிலையங்களில் பயணிகள் கூட்டம் நிரம்பி வழிவதால் பதற்றம் ஏற்பட்டுள்ளதாகவும், இரத்துச் செய்யப்பட்ட உத்தரவை மீறி ரயில்களை இயக்குமாறு ரயில் நிலைய அதிபர்களிடம் கோபமடைந்த பயணிகள் கோரிக்கை விடுத்துள்ளனர்.",
        "நிலைமை படிப்படியாக கட்டுப்பாட்டை மீறுவதாக அந்தந்த ரயில் நிலையங்களின் ஸ்டேஷன் மாஸ்டர்கள் தெரிவித்தனர்.",
        "கொழும்பு நோக்கி செல்லும் ரயில்களை அனுமதிக்குமாறு பயணிகள் கோரிக்கை விடுத்துள்ளனர்.",
        "வழமையான கால அட்டவணையின் பிரகாரம் புகையிரத சேவைகள் ஆரம்பிக்கப்படாவிட்டாலும், பல புகையிரதங்கள் ஏற்கனவே கொழும்பு கோட்டை நோக்கிச் செல்லும் பாதையில் இயங்கி வருவதாக இலங்கை நிலைய அதிபர்கள் சங்கம் தெரிவித்துள்ளது. (சதுரங்க சமரவிக்ரம)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "காலி",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "மாத்தறை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "கண்டி",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை நிலைய அதிபர்கள் சங்கம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "கொழும்பு கோட்டை",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "சதுரங்க சமரவிக்ரம",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}