{
  "newspaper_id": "news-first-lk",
  "url": "https://www.newsfirst.lk/2022/07/10/protestors-in-sri-lanka-find-then-return-millions-of-rupees-in-cash/",
  "time_ut": 1657469580,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Protestors in Sri Lanka find, then return, millions of Rupees in Cash",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Protestors in Sri Lanka find, then return, millions of Rupees in Cash",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); Sri Lankans who engaged in a mass protest at the Fort area yesterday (09) took steps to inform the Central Colombo Police of a sum over Rs. 17 million being found, after which a group of Police officers attached to Fort Police station took steps to accept the funds.",
        "Accordingly, a sum of Rs. 17,850,000/- was handed over to the Police, after a group of protestors discovered the money at the President’s House, and informed a Special Task Force member at the premises.",
        "The relevant sum of money is currently being kept safely at the Fort Police station, and the Courts are due to be informed about the money tomorrow (11).",
        "Protestors in Sri Lanka find, then return, millions of Rupees in Cash",
        "Sri Lankans have right to peacefully raise their voices – Blinken"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Sri Lanka",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "millions",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lankans",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Fort",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "yesterday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "09",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Central Colombo Police",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "17 million",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Fort Police",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Police",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "House",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Special Task Force",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "premises",
            "label": "LOC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Fort Police",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "tomorrow",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "11",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "millions",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lankans",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ විරෝධතාකරුවන් රුපියල් මිලියන ගණනක මුදල් සොයා ගෙන ආපසු එයි",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); ඊයේ (09) කොටුව ප්‍රදේශයේ මහජන විරෝධතාවක නිරත වූ ශ්‍රී ලාංකිකයින් රුපියල් කෝටියකට අධික මුදලක් සම්බන්ධයෙන් මැද කොළඹ පොලිසියට දැනුම් දීමට පියවර ගත්තා. මිලියන 17 ක මුදලක් සොයා ගැනීමට හැකි වූ අතර, පසුව කොටුව පොලිස් ස්ථානයට අනුයුක්ත පොලිස් නිලධාරීන් පිරිසක් එම මුදල් භාර ගැනීමට පියවර ගෙන ඇත.",
        "ඒ අනුව රු. 17,850,000/- ක මුදලක් ජනාධිපති මන්දිරයේ දී විරෝධතාකරුවන් පිරිසක් විසින් සොයාගෙන එම පරිශ්‍රයේ සිටි විශේෂ කාර්ය බළකායේ සාමාජිකයකුට දැනුම් දීමෙන් පසු පොලිසියට භාර දෙන ලදී.",
        "අදාළ මුදල් මේ වන විට කොටුව පොලිස් ස්ථානයේ ආරක්ෂිතව තබා ඇති අතර, එම මුදල් සම්බන්ධයෙන් හෙට (11) අධිකරණයට දැනුම් දීමට නියමිතය.",
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ විරෝධතාකරුවන් රුපියල් මිලියන ගණනක මුදල් සොයා ගෙන ආපසු එයි",
        "සාමකාමීව හඬ නැගීමට ශ්‍රී ලාංකිකයන්ට අයිතියක් ඇත - Blinken"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "මිලියන",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලාංකිකයන්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "බලකොටුව",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඊයේ",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "09",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "මැද කොළඹ පොලිසිය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "මිලියන 17 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "කොටුව පොලිසිය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "පොලිසිය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "නිවස",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "විශේෂ කාර්ය බලකාය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "පරිශ්රය",
            "label": "LOC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "කොටුව පොලිසිය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "හෙට",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "11",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මිලියන",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලාංකිකයන්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "இலங்கையில் உள்ள எதிர்ப்பாளர்கள் மில்லியன் கணக்கான ரூபாயை ரொக்கமாகக் கண்டுபிடித்து, பின்னர் திருப்பி அனுப்புகிறார்கள்",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); நேற்று (09) கோட்டைப் பகுதியில் பாரிய ஆர்ப்பாட்டத்தில் ஈடுபட்ட இலங்கையர்கள் மத்திய கொழும்பு பொலிஸாருக்கு ரூ. 17 மில்லியன் கண்டுபிடிக்கப்பட்டது, அதன் பின்னர் கோட்டை பொலிஸ் நிலையத்தின் பொலிஸ் அதிகாரிகள் குழு நிதியை ஏற்றுக்கொள்ள நடவடிக்கை எடுத்தது.",
        "அதன்படி, ரூ. 17,850,000/- பொலிஸாரிடம் ஒப்படைக்கப்பட்டது, ஆர்ப்பாட்டக்காரர்கள் குழு ஜனாதிபதி மாளிகையில் பணத்தைக் கண்டுபிடித்து, வளாகத்தில் உள்ள சிறப்பு அதிரடிப்படை உறுப்பினருக்கு தகவல் கொடுத்தது.",
        "குறித்த பணம் தற்போது கோட்டை பொலிஸ் நிலையத்தில் பாதுகாப்பாக வைக்கப்பட்டுள்ளதுடன், குறித்த பணம் தொடர்பில் நீதிமன்றத்திற்கு நாளை (11) அறிவிக்கப்படவுள்ளது.",
        "இலங்கையில் உள்ள எதிர்ப்பாளர்கள் மில்லியன் கணக்கான ரூபாயை ரொக்கமாகக் கண்டுபிடித்து, பின்னர் திருப்பி அனுப்புகிறார்கள்",
        "அமைதியான முறையில் குரல் எழுப்ப இலங்கையர்களுக்கு உரிமை உண்டு – பிளிங்கன்"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "இலங்கை",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "மில்லியன்கள்",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கையர்கள்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "கோட்டை",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "நேற்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "09",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "மத்திய கொழும்பு காவல்துறை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "17 மில்லியன்",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "கோட்டை போலீஸ்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "காவல்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "வீடு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "சிறப்பு அதிரடிப்படை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "வளாகம்",
            "label": "LOC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "கோட்டை போலீஸ்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "நாளை",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "11",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "மில்லியன்கள்",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கையர்கள்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}