{
  "newspaper_id": "news-first-lk",
  "url": "https://www.newsfirst.lk/2022/07/09/sajith-calls-for-president-pm-to-resign/",
  "time_ut": 1657362180,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Sajith calls for President & PM to resign",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Sajith calls for President & PM to resign",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); The Opposition Leader Sajith Premadasa has called for both the Prime Minister and the President to resign, and had informed that the Samagi Jana Balawegaya will not participate in the discussions headed by the Prime Minister today (08).",
        "Issuing a statement, the Opposition Leader states that all people of the country are demanding that both President Gotabaya Rajapaksa and the current Prime Minister to resign, in addition to alleging that it was the current Prime Minister who secured the Rajapaksas amidst the protests by the people, and betrayed the struggle, thereby being a defendant of the cause for the current crisis.",
        "The end of the arbitrary, repressive, anti-democratic Government is now in sight and we will not participate in the empty discussions held in closed stables after the horse has run away, the statement reads.",
        "The Opposition Leader further states that at a time when all the people of this country are united in one goal for the rebuilding of the motherland, and at a time when the victory of that goal is visible, the futile negotiations called by the so-called prime minister will ensure the safety of the Rajapaksas for another round, and the whole Government will get rid of their past actions, without consequences.",
        "He emphasizes that the Samagi Jana Balawegaya does not want to discuss the future of the country with the guardians and gatekeepers of the Government led by Gotabaya Rajapaksa, and also mentions that the SJB will contribute to the rebuilding of this country by freeing it from anarchy together with all the parties that stood with the people’s struggle.",
        "Sri Lanka: Navy ships with unidentified persons left Colombo Port"
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Sajith Premadasa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Jana Balawegaya",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "08",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Gotabaya Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Rajapaksas",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "Opposition",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "one",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Rajapaksas",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Jana Balawegaya",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Gotabaya Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Navy",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Colombo Port",
            "label": "PRODUCT"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "සජිත් ජනපතිට සහ අගමැතිට ඉල්ලා අස්විය යුතු බව කියයි",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); අග්‍රාමාත්‍යවරයාට සහ ජනාධිපතිවරයාට ඉල්ලා අස්වන ලෙස විපක්ෂ නායක සජිත් ප්‍රේමදාස මහතා ඉල්ලා සිටින අතර, අද (08) අග්‍රාමාත්‍යවරයාගේ ප්‍රධානත්වයෙන් පැවැත්වෙන සාකච්ඡා සඳහා සමගි ජන බලවේගය සහභාගී නොවන බව දන්වා තිබේ.",
        "නිවේදනයක් නිකුත් කරමින් විපක්ෂ නායකවරයා පවසන්නේ ජනතාවගේ විරෝධය මධ්‍යයේ රාජපක්ෂවරුන් ආරක්ෂා කළේ වත්මන් අග්‍රාමාත්‍යවරයා බවට චෝදනා කිරීමට අමතරව ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ ජනාධිපතිවරයා සහ වත්මන් අග්‍රාමාත්‍යවරයා යන දෙදෙනාටම ඉල්ලා අස්විය යුතු බවට රටේ සියලු ජනතාව ඉල්ලා සිටින බවයි. , සහ අරගලය පාවා දුන් අතර, එමගින් වත්මන් අර්බුදයට හේතුව විත්තිකරුවෙකු විය.",
        "අත්තනෝමතික, මර්දනකාරී, ප්‍රජාතන්ත්‍රවිරෝධී ආණ්ඩුවේ අවසානය දැන් පෙනෙන්නට තිබෙන අතර අශ්වයා පැන ගිය පසු වසා දැමූ ඉස්තාලවල පැවැත්වෙන හිස් සාකච්ඡාවලට අපි සහභාගී නොවන බව එම නිවේදනයේ දැක්වේ.",
        "මාතෘභූමිය යළි ගොඩනැගීම සඳහා මේ රටේ සියලු ජනතාව එකම අරමුණක ඒකරාශී වී සිටින මොහොතක එම ඉලක්කයේ ජයග්‍රහණය පෙනෙන මොහොතක ඊනියා විසින් කැඳවන ලද නිෂ්ඵල සාකච්ඡා බව විපක්ෂ නායකවරයා වැඩිදුරටත් සඳහන් කරයි. අගමැතිවරයා තවත් වටයක් සඳහා රාජපක්ෂවරුන්ගේ ආරක්ෂාව සහතික කරනු ඇති අතර, ඔවුන්ගේ අතීත ක්‍රියාවන්ගෙන් ප්‍රතිවිපාක නොමැතිව මුළු රජයම මිදෙනු ඇත.",
        "ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ මහතා ප්‍රමුඛ ආණ්ඩුවේ මුරකරුවන් සහ ගේට්ටුකරුවන් සමඟ රටේ අනාගතය ගැන සාකච්ඡා කිරීමට සමගි ජන බලවේගයට අවශ්‍ය නොවන බව අවධාරණය කරන ඔහු, එක්ව මේ රට අරාජිකත්වයෙන් මුදවා යළි ගොඩනැගීමට SJB දායක වන බවද සඳහන් කරයි. ජන අරගලය සමඟ සිටි සියලුම පක්ෂ සමඟ.",
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකාව: නාඳුනන පුද්ගලයින් සමඟ නාවික හමුදාවේ නෞකා කොළඹ වරායෙන් පිටත් විය"
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "සජිත් ප්‍රේමදාස",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජන බලවේගය",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "08",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "රාජපක්ෂලා",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "විපක්ෂ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "එක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "රාජපක්ෂලා",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ජන බලවේගය",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "නාවික",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "කොළඹ වරාය",
            "label": "PRODUCT"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "ஜனாதிபதியும் பிரதமரும் பதவி விலக வேண்டும் என சஜித் அழைப்பு விடுத்துள்ளார்",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); பிரதமர் மற்றும் ஜனாதிபதி ஆகிய இருவரையும் பதவி விலகுமாறு அழைப்பு விடுத்துள்ள எதிர்க்கட்சித் தலைவர் சஜித் பிரேமதாச, இன்று (08) பிரதமர் தலைமையில் நடைபெறும் கலந்துரையாடலில் சமகி ஜன பலவேகய பங்கேற்காது என அறிவித்துள்ளார்.",
        "மக்களின் எதிர்ப்புக்கு மத்தியில் ராஜபக்சக்களை காப்பாற்றியவர் தற்போதைய பிரதமர் என குற்றஞ்சாட்டுவதுடன், ஜனாதிபதி கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ஷ மற்றும் தற்போதைய பிரதமர் இருவரும் பதவி விலக வேண்டும் என அனைத்து மக்களும் கோரிக்கை விடுக்கின்றனர் என எதிர்க்கட்சி தலைவர் அறிக்கை ஒன்றை வெளியிட்டுள்ளார். , மற்றும் போராட்டத்தை காட்டிக்கொடுத்து, அதன் மூலம் தற்போதைய நெருக்கடிக்கு காரணமான ஒரு பிரதிவாதி.",
        "எதேச்சதிகார, அடக்குமுறை, ஜனநாயக விரோத அரசாங்கத்தின் முடிவு தற்போது கண்கூடாகக் காணப்படுவதாகவும், குதிரை ஓட்டம் பிடித்த பிறகு மூடிய தொழுவத்தில் நடைபெறும் வெற்று விவாதங்களில் பங்கேற்க மாட்டோம் என்றும் அந்த அறிக்கையில் கூறப்பட்டுள்ளது.",
        "தாய்நாட்டை மீளக் கட்டியெழுப்புவதற்கு இந்நாட்டு மக்கள் அனைவரும் ஒரே இலக்கில் ஒன்றிணைந்துள்ள இவ்வேளையில், அந்த இலக்கின் வெற்றியை காணக்கூடிய வேளையில், வீண்பேச்சுவார்த்தைகள் என அழைக்கப்படுபவர்களால் அழைப்பு விடுக்கப்பட்டுள்ளதாக எதிர்க்கட்சித் தலைவர் மேலும் தெரிவிக்கிறார். பிரதமர் மற்றொரு சுற்றுக்கு ராஜபக்சக்களின் பாதுகாப்பை உறுதி செய்வார், மேலும் முழு அரசாங்கமும் அவர்களின் கடந்தகால செயல்களில் இருந்து விடுபடும்.",
        "கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ச தலைமையிலான அரசாங்கத்தின் பாதுகாவலர்கள் மற்றும் வாயில்காப்பாளர்களுடன் நாட்டின் எதிர்காலம் குறித்து கலந்துரையாடுவதற்கு சமகி ஜன பலவேகய விரும்பவில்லை என வலியுறுத்தும் அவர், இந்த நாட்டை அராஜகத்திலிருந்து விடுவித்து மீண்டும் கட்டியெழுப்புவதற்கு எஸ்.ஜே.பி பங்களிக்கும் எனவும் அவர் குறிப்பிட்டுள்ளார். மக்கள் போராட்டத்துடன் நின்ற அனைத்து கட்சிகளுடன்.",
        "இலங்கை: கொழும்பு துறைமுகத்தில் இருந்து அடையாளம் தெரியாத நபர்களுடன் கடற்படை கப்பல்கள் புறப்பட்டன"
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "சஜித் பிரேமதாச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜன பலவேகயா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "08",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ராஜபக்சேக்கள்",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "எதிர்ப்பு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஒன்று",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ராஜபக்சேக்கள்",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஜன பலவேகயா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "கடற்படை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "கொழும்பு துறைமுகம்",
            "label": "PRODUCT"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}