{
  "newspaper_id": "lankadeepa-lk",
  "url": "https://www.lankadeepa.lk/news/හිටපු-ජනාධිපති-ගෝඨාභයට-අගමැති-වෙන්න-පුළුවන්/101-618752",
  "time_ut": 1661432156,
  "original_lang": "si",
  "original_title": "හිටපු ජනාධිපති ගෝඨාභයට අගමැති වෙන්න පුළුවන්",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Former President Gotabaya can become Prime Minister",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "Parliamentarian Major Pradeep Udugoda said today (25) that he has no reluctance to appoint former President Gotabhaya Rajapaksa to the post of Prime Minister and would express his consent if such a proposal is presented.",
        "Mr. Pradeep Udugoda said that there is no obstacle for Gotabhaya Rajapaksa to come to the country as he was a president who won 69 lakh votes and was an officer who led the war to victory.",
        "Mr. Udugoda further said that the Human Rights Commission has also confirmed the right of Mr. Gotabhaya Rajapaksa to return to Sri Lanka and that he cannot make statements about the political decisions of the former president.",
        "Parliamentarian Major Pradeep Udugoda said at the press conference held today (25) at the Sri Lanka Lanka Podujana Peramuna party office at Battaramulla Nelum Mawatha.",
        "Colombo District Member of Parliament Mr. Madhura Vithanage, who participated in the press conference, said that there is no obstacle for former President Gotabhaya Rajapaksa to come to Sri Lanka."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Gotabaya",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Parliamentarian Major Pradeep Udugoda",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "25",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Gotabhaya Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Pradeep",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Gotabhaya Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "69",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Udugoda",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Human Rights Commission",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Gotabhaya Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Parliamentarian Major Pradeep Udugoda",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "25",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "Podujana Peramuna",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Battaramulla Nelum Mawatha",
            "label": "FAC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Madhura Vithanage",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Gotabhaya Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "හිටපු ජනාධිපති ගෝඨාභයට අගමැති වෙන්න පුළුවන්",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "හිටපු ජනාධිපති ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්‍ෂ මහතා අග්‍රාමාත්‍ය ධූරයට පත්කිරීමට කිසිඳු අකමැත්තක් නොමැති බවත් එවැනි යෝජනාවක් ඉදිරිපත් වුවහොත් කැමැත්ත පළකරන බවත් පාර්ලිමේන්තු මන්ත්‍රී මේජර් ප්‍රදීප් උදුගොඩ මහතා අද (25) පැවසීය.",
        "ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්‍ෂ ලක්‍ෂ 69 ක් ඡන්ද ලබාගෙන ජනාධිපතිවරයකු මෙන්ම යුද්දය ජය ලැබීමට නායකත්වය දුන් නිලධාරියකු වීම නිසා ඔහුට රටට පැමිණීමට කිසිඳු බාධවක් නොමැති බව කී ප්‍රදීප් උදුගොඩ මහතා ඇතැම් දේශපාලන අදිසි හස්තයන් මේ රටේ ජනතාව කුපිත කිරීම නිසා එතුමා ජනාධිපති ධූරයෙන් ඉල්ලා අස්වූ බව ද සඳහන් කළේය.",
        "ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්‍ෂ මහතාට නැවත මෙරටට පැමිණීමේ අයිතිවාසිකම මානව හිමිකම් කොමිසම ද තහවුරු කර ඇති බවත් හිටපු ජනාධිපතිවරයා ඉදිරියේදී එළඹෙන දේශපාලන තීන්දු පිළිබඳව තමන්ට ප්‍රකාශයන් කළ නොහැකි බවත් උදුගොඩ මහතා වැඩි දුරටත් කීය.",
        "බත්තරමුල්ල නෙළුම් මාවත පිහිටි ශ්‍රී ලංකා ලංකා පොදුජන පෙරමුණ පක්‍ෂ කාර්යාලයේදී අද (25) පැවැති මාධ්‍ය හමුවේදී පාර්ලිමේන්තු මන්ත්‍රී මේජර් ප්‍රදීප් උදුගොඩ මහතා පැවසීය.",
        "එම මාධ්‍ය හමුවට සහභාගි වූ කොළඹ දිස්ත්‍රික් පාර්ලිමේන්තු මන්ත්‍රී මධුර විතානගේ මහතා පැවසුවේ හිටපු ජනාධිපති ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්‍ෂ මහතාට ශ්‍රී ලංකාවට පැමිණීමට කිසිඳු බාධාවක් නොමැති බවත්ය."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ගෝඨාභය",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තු මන්ත්‍රී මේජර් ප්‍රදීප් උඩුගොඩ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "25",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ප්‍රදීප්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "69",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "උඩුගොඩ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "මානව හිමිකම් කොමිසම",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තු මන්ත්‍රී මේජර් ප්‍රදීප් උඩුගොඩ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "25",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "පොදුජන පෙරමුණ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "බත්තරමුල්ල නෙළුම් මාවත",
            "label": "FAC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "මධුර විතානගේ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "முன்னாள் ஜனாதிபதி கோட்டாபய பிரதமராகலாம்",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "முன்னாள் ஜனாதிபதி கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ஷவை பிரதமர் பதவிக்கு நியமிப்பதில் தனக்கு எந்த தயக்கமும் இல்லை எனவும் அவ்வாறு பிரேரணை முன்வைக்கப்பட்டால் அதற்கு சம்மதம் தெரிவிப்பதாகவும் நாடாளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர் மேஜர் பிரதீப் உடுகொட இன்று (25) தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "69 இலட்சம் வாக்குகளைப் பெற்ற ஜனாதிபதியாகவும், போரை வெற்றிப் பாதைக்கு அழைத்துச் சென்ற அதிகாரியாகவும் கோத்தபாய ராஜபக்ச நாட்டுக்கு வருவதற்கு எந்தத் தடையும் இல்லை என பிரதீப் உடுகொட தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "கோத்தபாய ராஜபக்சவுக்கு இலங்கை திரும்புவதற்கான உரிமையை மனித உரிமைகள் ஆணைக்குழுவும் உறுதிப்படுத்தியுள்ளதாகவும், முன்னாள் ஜனாதிபதியின் அரசியல் தீர்மானங்கள் குறித்து அவரால் அறிக்கை வெளியிட முடியாது எனவும் உடுகொட மேலும் தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "பத்தரமுல்லை நெலும் மாவத்தையில் அமைந்துள்ள ஸ்ரீலங்கா பொதுஜன பெரமுன கட்சியின் அலுவலகத்தில் இன்று (25) நடைபெற்ற ஊடகவியலாளர் சந்திப்பில் நாடாளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர் மேஜர் பிரதீப் உடுகொட தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "இந்த ஊடகவியலாளர் சந்திப்பில் கலந்து கொண்ட கொழும்பு மாவட்ட நாடாளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர் திரு.மதுர விதானகே, முன்னாள் ஜனாதிபதி கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ச இலங்கைக்கு வருவதற்கு எந்த தடையும் இல்லை."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "கோட்டாபய",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "நாடாளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர் மேஜர் பிரதீப் உடுகொட",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "25",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "கோத்தபாய ராஜபக்ச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பிரதீப்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "கோத்தபாய ராஜபக்ச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "69",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "உடுகொட",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "மனித உரிமைகள் ஆணையம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "கோத்தபாய ராஜபக்ச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "நாடாளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர் மேஜர் பிரதீப் உடுகொட",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "25",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "பொதுஜன பெரமுன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "பத்தரமுல்ல நெலும் மாவத்தை",
            "label": "FAC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "மதுர விதானகே",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "கோத்தபாய ராஜபக்ச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}