{
  "newspaper_id": "daily-mirror-lk",
  "url": "https://www.dailymirror.lk/breaking_news/No-money-to-buy-fuel/108-240690",
  "time_ut": 1657337608,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "No money to buy fuel",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "No money to buy fuel",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "The Central Bank has been compelled to print money in order to prevent a total breakdown of fuel supply in the country, as the Ceylon Petroleum Corporation (CPC), does not have sufficient rupees to buy dollars for fuel purchases, Central Bank Governor Dr. Nandalal Weerasinghe said.",
        "Addressing the media at the Central Bank on Thursday Dr. Weerasinghe said that the CPC had requested Rs. 217 billion from the Treasury for the purpose and the Treasury was unable to supply such a huge amount immediately.",
        "He stated that the Treasury in turn had made a request to the Central Bank and the only way for the Bank to fulfill that request is to print money.",
        "The Monetary Board of the Central Bank responded positively last week to another request by the CPC for Rs. 185 billion for fuel purchases, as there would be a grave situation in the country if that request was turned down, the Governor said.",
        "He added that the Central Bank was not in a position to turn down the latest request as well due to the dire situation the country is currently faced with. (Harshana Thushara Silva)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "The Central Bank",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Ceylon Petroleum Corporation",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "CPC",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Central Bank",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Nandalal Weerasinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the Central Bank",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Thursday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Weerasinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "CPC",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "217 billion",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Treasury",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Treasury",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Treasury",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Central Bank",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Bank",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "The Monetary Board of the Central Bank",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "last week",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "CPC",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "185 billion",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the Central Bank",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Harshana Thushara Silva",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "තෙල් ගන්න සල්ලි නෑ",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "ඉන්ධන මිලදී ගැනීම් සඳහා ඩොලර් මිලදී ගැනීමට ලංකා ඛනිජ තෙල් නීතිගත සංස්ථාවට (CPC) ප්‍රමාණවත් රුපියල් නොමැති බැවින් රට තුළ ඉන්ධන සැපයුම සම්පූර්ණයෙන් බිඳ වැටීම වැළැක්වීම සඳහා මුදල් මුද්‍රණය කිරීමට මහ බැංකුවට සිදුව ඇති බව මහ බැංකු අධිපති ආචාර්ය නන්දලාල් මහතා පවසයි. වීරසිංහ මහතා පැවසීය.",
        "බ‍්‍රහස්පතින්දා මහ බැංකුවේ මාධ්‍ය අමතමින් ආචාර්ය වීරසිංහ කියා සිටියේ තෙල් සංස්ථාව විසින් රු. ඒ සඳහා මහා භාණ්ඩාගාරයෙන් රුපියල් බිලියන 217ක් වූ අතර එවැනි විශාල මුදලක් ක්ෂණිකව සැපයීමට භාණ්ඩාගාරයට නොහැකි විය.",
        "මහා භාණ්ඩාගාරය විසින් මහ බැංකුවෙන් මේ සම්බන්ධයෙන් ඉල්ලීමක් කර ඇති බවත් එම ඉල්ලීම ඉටු කිරීමට බැංකුවට ඇති එකම මාර්ගය මුදල් මුද්‍රණය කිරීම බවත් ඔහු ප්‍රකාශ කළේය.",
        "CPC විසින් රු. එම ඉල්ලීම ප්‍රතික්‍ෂේප කළහොත් රට තුළ බරපතළ තත්ත්වයක්‌ ඇති වන බැවින් ඉන්ධන මිලදී ගැනීම් සඳහා රුපියල් බිලියන 185ක්‌ වැය වන බවද ආණ්ඩුකාරවරයා පැවසීය.",
        "මේ වන විට රට මුහුණ දී සිටින භයානක තත්ත්වය හේතුවෙන් නවතම ඉල්ලීම ද ප්‍රතික්ෂේප කිරීමට මහ බැංකුවට හැකියාවක් නොමැති බව ඔහු සඳහන් කළේය. (හර්ෂණ තුෂාර සිල්වා)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "මහ බැංකුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ලංකා ඛනිජ තෙල් නීතිගත සංස්ථාව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "CPC",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "මහ බැංකුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "නන්දලාල් වීරසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "මහ බැංකුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "බ්රහස්පතින්දා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "වීරසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "CPC",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "බිලියන 217 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "භාණ්ඩාගාර",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "භාණ්ඩාගාර",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "භාණ්ඩාගාර",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "මහ බැංකුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "බැංකුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "මහ බැංකුවේ මුදල් මණ්ඩලය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගිය සතිය",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "CPC",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "බිලියන 185 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "මහ බැංකුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "හර්ෂණ තුෂාර සිල්වා",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "எரிபொருள் வாங்க பணமில்லை",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "இலங்கை பெற்றோலியக் கூட்டுத்தாபனத்திடம் எரிபொருள் கொள்வனவுக்கான டொலர்களை கொள்வனவு செய்வதற்குப் போதிய ரூபா இல்லாததால், நாட்டில் எரிபொருள் விநியோகம் முற்றிலுமாகத் தடைபடுவதைத் தடுப்பதற்காக பணத்தை அச்சிடுவதற்கு மத்திய வங்கி நிர்ப்பந்திக்கப்பட்டுள்ளதாக மத்திய வங்கி ஆளுநர் கலாநிதி நந்தலால் தெரிவித்தார். வீரசிங்க தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "வியாழன் அன்று மத்திய வங்கியில் ஊடகங்களுக்கு கருத்து தெரிவிக்கும் போதே கலாநிதி வீரசிங்க தெரிவித்தார். இதற்காக திறைசேரியில் இருந்து 217 பில்லியன் ரூபா பெறப்பட்டது மற்றும் திறைசேரியால் இவ்வளவு பெரிய தொகையை உடனடியாக வழங்க முடியவில்லை.",
        "இதையொட்டி திறைசேரி மத்திய வங்கியிடம் கோரிக்கை விடுத்துள்ளதாகவும், அந்த கோரிக்கையை நிறைவேற்ற வங்கியின் ஒரே வழி பணத்தை அச்சிடுவதே என்றும் அவர் கூறினார்.",
        "மத்திய வங்கியின் நாணயச் சபை கடந்த வாரம் CPC இன் மற்றொரு கோரிக்கைக்கு சாதகமாக பதிலளித்தது. எரிபொருள் கொள்வனவுக்காக 185 பில்லியன் ரூபா ஒதுக்கப்பட்டுள்ளது, அந்த கோரிக்கை நிராகரிக்கப்பட்டால் நாட்டில் பாரதூரமான நிலைமை ஏற்படும் என ஆளுநர் தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "நாடு தற்போது எதிர்நோக்கி வரும் இக்கட்டான சூழ்நிலையின் காரணமாக சமீபத்திய கோரிக்கையையும் நிராகரிக்கும் நிலையில் மத்திய வங்கி இல்லை என்றும் அவர் கூறினார். (ஹர்ஷன துஷார சில்வா)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "மத்திய வங்கி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை பெற்றோலியக் கூட்டுத்தாபனம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "CPC",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "மத்திய வங்கி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "நந்தலால் வீரசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "மத்திய வங்கி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "வியாழன்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "வீரசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "CPC",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "217 பில்லியன்",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "கருவூலம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "கருவூலம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "கருவூலம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "மத்திய வங்கி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "வங்கி",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "மத்திய வங்கியின் நாணய வாரியம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "கடந்த வாரம்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "CPC",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "185 பில்லியன்",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "மத்திய வங்கி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஹர்ஷன துஷார சில்வா",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}