{
  "newspaper_id": "daily-ft-lk",
  "url": "https://www.ft.lk/business/Lanka-IOC-signs-agreement-with-Spectrum-Trading/34-739110",
  "time_ut": 1661469386,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Lanka IOC signs agreement with Spectrum Trading",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Lanka IOC signs agreement with Spectrum Trading",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "LIOC Managing Director Manoj Gupta (seated left) along with Spectrum Trading Co. Managing Director",
        "Dr. Kalinga Kaluperuma and senior officials during the agreement signing",
        "Lanka IOC, Sri Lanka’s No. 1 listed energy company has joined hands with the prestigious Stafford Group for the supply of co-branded SERVO ecoPLUS – a long life and eco-friendly lubricant to its dealers’ network for the first time in Sri Lanka.",
        "LIOC manufactures automotive, industrial and marine SERVO lubricants at its state-of-art plant in Trincomalee.",
        "In a statement LIOC affirmed its commitment to the development and economy of Sri Lanka. The entire range of SERVO Lubricants is locally manufactured, thus saving precious foreign exchange on imports.",
        "The company has always been at the forefront of offering the best quality lubricants at competitive prices. Besides this, LIOC will be the only company to set up a grease manufacturing plant in Sri Lanka.",
        "Spectrum Trading Co. Ltd., a leader in the marketing and distribution of automotive products is a member of the diversified Stafford Group.",
        "The first co-branded lubricant of LIOC has been launched as ‘SERVO ecoPLUS’ meeting API SN, the highest performance level specified by American Petroleum Institute. SERVO ecoPLUS is an eco-friendly, fuel-efficient, affordable long life lubricant which gives shield protection for the vehicle."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Spectrum Trading",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Manoj Gupta",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Spectrum Trading Co.",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Kalinga Kaluperuma",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Lanka IOC",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "1",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Stafford Group",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "first",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "SERVO",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Trincomalee",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "SERVO Lubricants",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Spectrum Trading Co. Ltd.",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Stafford Group",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "first",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "API SN",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "American Petroleum Institute",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "ලංකා IOC Spectrum Trading සමග ගිවිසුමක් අත්සන් කරයි",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "LIOC කළමනාකාර අධ්‍යක්ෂ මනෝජ් ගුප්තා (වමේ අසුන්ගෙන) සමග Spectrum Trading Co. කළමනාකාර අධ්‍යක්ෂ",
        "ගිවිසුමට අත්සන් තැබීමේදී වෛද්‍ය කාලිංග කළුපෙරුම මහතා සහ ජ්‍යෙෂ්ඨ නිලධාරීන්",
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ අංක 1 ලැයිස්තුගත බලශක්ති සමාගම වන Lanka IOC, ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ ප්‍රථම වරට සිය අලෙවි නියෝජිත ජාලයට දීර්ඝ ආයුෂ සහ පරිසර හිතකාමී ලිහිසි තෙල් වන සම සන්නාමය සහිත SERVO ecoPLUS සැපයීම සඳහා කීර්තිමත් ස්ටැෆර්ඩ් සමූහය සමඟ අත්වැල් බැඳගෙන ඇත.",
        "LIOC විසින් ත්‍රිකුණාමලයේ පිහිටි එහි අති නවීන කර්මාන්තශාලාවේ මෝටර් රථ, කාර්මික සහ සමුද්‍ර SERVO ලිහිසි තෙල් නිෂ්පාදනය කරයි.",
        "නිවේදනයක් නිකුත් කරමින් LIOC ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ සංවර්ධනයට සහ ආර්ථිකයට ඇති කැපවීම තහවුරු කළේය. SERVO ලිහිසි තෙල් මුළු පරාසයම දේශීයව නිෂ්පාදනය කර ඇති අතර එමඟින් ආනයනය කිරීමේදී වටිනා විදේශ විනිමය ඉතිරි වේ.",
        "තරඟකාරී මිල ගණන් යටතේ හොඳම තත්ත්වයේ ලිහිසි තෙල් පිරිනැමීමට සමාගම සැමවිටම ඉදිරියෙන් සිටී. මීට අමතරව ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ ග්‍රීස් නිෂ්පාදන කම්හලක් පිහිටුවන එකම සමාගම LIOC වේ.",
        "මෝටර් රථ නිෂ්පාදන අලෙවිකරණය සහ බෙදා හැරීමේ ප්‍රමුඛයා වන Spectrum Trading Co. Ltd, විවිධාංගීකරණය වූ ස්ටැෆර්ඩ් සමූහයේ සාමාජිකයෙකි.",
        "LIOC හි පළමු සම සන්නාමය සහිත ලිහිසි තෙල් ‘SERVO ecoPLUS’ රැස්වීම API SN ලෙස දියත් කර ඇත, එය ඇමරිකානු පෙට්‍රෝලියම් ආයතනය විසින් නිශ්චිතව දක්වා ඇති ඉහළම කාර්ය සාධන මට්ටම වේ. SERVO ecoPLUS යනු වාහනය සඳහා පලිහ ආරක්ෂාවක් ලබා දෙන පරිසර හිතකාමී, ඉන්ධන කාර්යක්ෂම, දැරිය හැකි දිගු ආයු කාලයක් සහිත ලිහිසි තෙල් වර්ගයකි."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "වර්ණාවලි වෙළඳාම",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "මනෝජ් ගුප්තා",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Spectrum Trading Co.",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "කාලිංග කළුපෙරුම",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ලංකා IOC",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "1",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ස්ටැෆර්ඩ් සමූහය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "පළමුවන",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "සර්වෝ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ත්රිකුණාමලය",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "SERVO ලිහිසි තෙල්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Spectrum Trading Co. Ltd.",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ස්ටැෆර්ඩ් සමූහය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "පළමුවන",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "API SN",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඇමරිකානු ඛනිජ තෙල් ආයතනය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "ஸ்பெக்ட்ரம் வர்த்தகத்துடன் லங்கா ஐஓசி ஒப்பந்தம் கைச்சாத்திடுகிறது",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "எல்ஐஓசி நிர்வாக இயக்குனர் மனோஜ் குப்தா (இடதுபுறம் அமர்ந்துள்ளார்) உடன் ஸ்பெக்ட்ரம் டிரேடிங் கோ. நிர்வாக இயக்குனர்",
        "உடன்படிக்கை கைச்சாத்திடலின் போது கலாநிதி கலிங்க களுபெரும மற்றும் சிரேஷ்ட அதிகாரிகள்",
        "இலங்கையின் நம்பர். 1 பட்டியலிடப்பட்ட எரிசக்தி நிறுவனமான Lanka IOC, இலங்கையில் முதல் முறையாக தனது டீலர்களின் வலையமைப்பிற்கு நீண்ட ஆயுளும் சுற்றுச்சூழலுக்கும் உகந்த லூப்ரிகண்டான இணை முத்திரையான SERVO ecoPLUS-ஐ வழங்குவதற்காக மதிப்புமிக்க Stafford குழுமத்துடன் கைகோர்த்துள்ளது.",
        "LIOC தனது திருகோணமலையில் உள்ள அதிநவீன தொழிற்சாலையில் வாகன, தொழில்துறை மற்றும் கடல்சார் SERVO லூப்ரிகண்டுகளை உற்பத்தி செய்கிறது.",
        "இலங்கையின் அபிவிருத்தி மற்றும் பொருளாதாரத்திற்கான தனது அர்ப்பணிப்பை LIOC உறுதிப்படுத்தியுள்ளது. SERVO லூப்ரிகண்டுகளின் முழு வரம்பும் உள்நாட்டில் உற்பத்தி செய்யப்படுகிறது, இதனால் இறக்குமதியில் விலைமதிப்பற்ற அந்நியச் செலாவணி சேமிக்கப்படுகிறது.",
        "போட்டி விலையில் சிறந்த தரமான லூப்ரிகண்டுகளை வழங்குவதில் நிறுவனம் எப்போதும் முன்னணியில் உள்ளது. இது தவிர, இலங்கையில் கிரீஸ் உற்பத்தி ஆலையை அமைக்கும் ஒரே நிறுவனமாக LIOC இருக்கும்.",
        "ஸ்பெக்ட்ரம் டிரேடிங் கோ. லிமிடெட், வாகன தயாரிப்புகளின் சந்தைப்படுத்தல் மற்றும் விநியோகத்தில் முன்னணியில் உள்ள பன்முகப்படுத்தப்பட்ட ஸ்டாஃபோர்ட் குழுமத்தில் உறுப்பினராக உள்ளது.",
        "LIOC இன் முதல் இணை-முத்திரை லூப்ரிகண்ட், அமெரிக்கன் பெட்ரோலியம் நிறுவனத்தால் குறிப்பிடப்பட்ட மிக உயர்ந்த செயல்திறன் மட்டமான 'SERVO ecoPLUS' மீட்டிங் API SN ஆக அறிமுகப்படுத்தப்பட்டது. SERVO ecoPLUS என்பது சுற்றுச்சூழலுக்கு உகந்த, எரிபொருள்-திறனுள்ள, மலிவு விலையில் நீண்ட ஆயுள் மசகு எண்ணெய், இது வாகனத்திற்கு கேடயப் பாதுகாப்பை வழங்குகிறது."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ஸ்பெக்ட்ரம் வர்த்தகம்",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "மனோஜ் குப்தா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஸ்பெக்ட்ரம் டிரேடிங் கோ.",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "கலிங்க களுபெரும",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "லங்கா ஐ.ஓ.சி",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "1",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஸ்டாஃபோர்ட் குழு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "முதலில்",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "சர்வோ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "திருகோணமலை",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "SERVO லூப்ரிகண்டுகள்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஸ்பெக்ட்ரம் டிரேடிங் கோ. லிமிடெட்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஸ்டாஃபோர்ட் குழு",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "முதலில்",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஏபிஐ எஸ்என்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "அமெரிக்க பெட்ரோலிய நிறுவனம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}