{
  "newspaper_id": "daily-mirror-lk",
  "url": "https://www.dailymirror.lk/breaking_news/SJB-ten-party-alliance-SLFP-SLPP-independents-moot-Dullas-Sajith-as-Prez-PM/108-240782",
  "time_ut": 1657509852,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "SJB, ten-party alliance, SLFP, SLPP independents moot Dullas, Sajith as Prez, PM",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "SJB, ten-party alliance, SLFP, SLPP independents moot Dullas, Sajith as Prez, PM",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "In the aftermath of the struggle, the political parties - the ten-party alliance, the Samagi Jana Balawegaya (SJB), Sri Lanka Freedom Party (SLFP) and the independent group of Sri Lanka Podujana Peramuna (SLPP)- met yesterday and decided to push for the nomination of MP Dullas Alahapperuma and Opposition Leader as the president and the prime minister of the proposed all-party government, Daily Mirror learns.",
        "The representatives of these parties met at the residence of SJB MP Thalata Athukorale in Colombo. The SJB, as the main opposition, was represented by its General Secretary Ranjith Madduma Bandara and Dr. Rajitha Senaratne. Representing the ten-party alliance, MPS Udaya Gammanpila, Wimal Weerawansa and Gevindu Cumaratunga attended it. The SLFP was represented by MPS Dayasiri Jayasekara and Duminda Dissanayake. The SLPP independent group sent MP Anura Priyadarshana Yapa for it.",
        "They reportedly discussed that Mr. Alahapperuma and Mr. Premadasa who is also the SJB leader should take over the leadership positions to steer the country out of the current mess.",
        "A faction of the ruling SLPP called for the resignation of President Gotabaya Rajapaksa on July 9. Besides, the leaders of the political parties represented in Parliament also requested him to do so. Speaker Mahinda Yapa Abeywardana said later that the president would step down on July 13.",
        "In the event of both the president and the prime minister resigning, the Speaker is appointed acting president for a temporary period till Parliament appoints one of its members to serve presidency for the rest of the term. In this instance,",
        "Mr. Alahapperuma is proposed to the post by one faction of the ruling party whereas the others promote newly appointed MP Dhammika Perera to it.",
        "A Cabinet comprising MPS from all the parties is proposed to be formed.the representatives of the struggle are to be included in the advisory council to instruct the Cabinet in governance. However, no final decision has been taken.(KELUM BANDARA)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ten",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "SLFP",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "Dullas, Sajith as",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "Prez",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ten",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Samagi Jana Balawegaya",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka Freedom Party",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "SLFP",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Podujana Peramuna",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "yesterday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Dullas Alahapperuma",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Daily Mirror",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Thalata Athukorale in Colombo",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ranjith Madduma Bandara",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Rajitha Senaratne",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ten",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "MPS Udaya Gammanpila",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Wimal Weerawansa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "SLFP",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "MPS Dayasiri Jayasekara",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Anura Priyadarshana",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Alahapperuma",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Premadasa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "SJB",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Gotabaya Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "July 9",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Mahinda Yapa Abeywardana",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "July 13",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "one",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Alahapperuma",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "one",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Dhammika Perera",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Cabinet",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "MPS",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Cabinet",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "taken.(KELUM BANDARA",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "SJB, දස පක්‍ෂ සන්ධානය, ශ්‍රීලනිප, ශ්‍රී ලංකා පොදුජන පෙරමුණ ස්වාධීන මන්ත්‍රීවරුන් ඩලස්, සජිත් ජනාධිපති, අගමැති",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "අරගලයෙන් පසුව දේශපාලන පක්ෂ - පක්ෂ දස සන්ධානය, සමගි ජන බලවේගය (SJB), ශ්‍රී ලංකා නිදහස් පක්ෂය (SLFP) සහ ශ්‍රී ලංකා පොදුජන පෙරමුණේ (SLPP) ස්වාධීන කණ්ඩායම ඊයේ රැස්වී තීරණය කළේය. යෝජිත සර්ව පාක්ෂික ආණ්ඩුවේ ජනාධිපතිවරයා සහ අගමැති ලෙස ඩලස් අලහප්පෙරුම මන්ත්‍රීවරයා සහ විපක්ෂ නායකවරයා නම් කිරීම සඳහා තල්ලුවක්, ඩේලි මිරර් වෙත වාර්තා වේ.",
        "මෙම පක්ෂ නියෝජිතයින් රැස්වුණේ SJB පාර්ලිමේන්තු මන්ත්‍රී තලතා අතුකෝරළ මහත්මියගේ කොළඹ පිහිටි නිවසේදීය. ප්‍රධාන විපක්ෂය ලෙස SJB පක්ෂය නියෝජනය කරමින් එහි ප්‍රධාන ලේකම් රංජිත් මද්දුම බණ්ඩාර සහ වෛද්‍ය රාජිත සේනාරත්න එක්ව සිටියා. පක්ෂ දහයකින් සමන්විත සන්ධානය නියෝජනය කරමින් පාර්ලිමේන්තු මන්ත්‍රී උදය ගම්මන්පිල, විමල් වීරවංශ සහ ගෙවිඳු කුමාරතුංග ඊට එක්ව සිටියා. ශ්‍රීලනිපය නියෝජනය කළේ පාර්ලිමේන්තු මන්ත්‍රී දයාසිරි ජයසේකර සහ දුමින්ද දිසානායකයි. ශ්‍රී ලංකා පොදුජන පෙරමුණේ ස්වාධීන කණ්ඩායම ඒ සඳහා අනුර ප්‍රියදර්ශන යාපා මන්ත්‍රීවරයා යැව්වා.",
        "අලහප්පෙරුම මහතා සහ SJB නායකයා ද වන ප්‍රේමදාස මහතා වත්මන් අවුලෙන් රට ගොඩ ගැනීමට නායකත්ව තනතුරු භාරගත යුතු බවට ඔවුන් සාකච්ඡා කළ බව වාර්තා වේ.",
        "ජනාධිපති ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ මහතාට ඉල්ලා අස්විය යුතු බවට පාලක ශ්‍රී ලංකා පොදුජන පෙරමුණේ කණ්ඩායමක් ජූලි 9 වැනිදා ඉල්ලා සිටියේය. ඊට අමතරව පාර්ලිමේන්තුව නියෝජනය කරන දේශපාලන පක්ෂ නායකයන් ද ඔහුගෙන් ඉල්ලා සිටියේය. කථානායක මහින්ද යාපා අබේවර්ධන පසුව ප්‍රකාශ කළේ ජනාධිපතිවරයා ජූලි 13 වැනිදා ඉල්ලා අස්වන බවයි.",
        "ජනාධිපතිවරයා සහ අග්‍රාමාත්‍යවරයා යන දෙදෙනාම ඉල්ලා අස් වුවහොත්, ඉතිරි කාලය සඳහා ජනාධිපති ධුරයේ කටයුතු කිරීම සඳහා පාර්ලිමේන්තුව සිය මන්ත්‍රීවරයෙකු පත් කරන තෙක් තාවකාලික කාලසීමාවකට කථානායකවරයා වැඩබලන ජනාධිපති ලෙස පත් කරනු ලැබේ. මෙම අවස්ථාවේ දී,",
        "අලහප්පෙරුම මහතා එම තනතුරට යෝජනා කරන්නේ ආණ්ඩු පක්ෂයේ එක් පාර්ශවයක් වන අතර අනෙක් පිරිස අලුතින් පත් වූ පාර්ලිමේන්තු මන්ත්‍රී ධම්මික පෙරේරා මහතා එම තනතුරට උසස් කරති.",
        "සියලුම පක්ෂවල මන්ත්‍රීවරුන්ගෙන් සැදුම්ලත් අමාත්‍ය මණ්ඩලයක් පිහිටුවීමට යෝජිතය. පාලනය සම්බන්ධයෙන් කැබිනට් මණ්ඩලයට උපදෙස් දීම සඳහා අරගලයේ නියෝජිතයන් උපදේශක සභාවට ඇතුළත් කිරීමට නියමිතය. කෙසේ වෙතත් අවසන් තීරණයක් ගෙන නොමැත.(කැලුම් බණ්ඩාර)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "දස",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "ශ්‍රීලනිප",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "ඩලස්, සජිත් ලෙස",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "ජනාධිපති",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "දස",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "සමගි ජන බලවේගය",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකා නිදහස් පක්ෂය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රීලනිප",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "පොදුජන පෙරමුණ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඊයේ",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඩලස් අලහප්පෙරුම",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඩේලි මිරර්",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "තලතා අතුකෝරළ කොළඹ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "රංජිත් මද්දුම බණ්ඩාර",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "රාජිත සේනාරත්න",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "දස",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තු මන්ත්‍රී උදය ගම්මන්පිල",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "විමල් වීරවංශ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රීලනිප",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තු මන්ත්‍රී දයාසිරි ජයසේකර",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "අනුර ප්‍රියදර්ශන",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Alahapperuma",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ප්‍රේමදාස ය",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "එස්.ජේ.බී",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජූලි 9",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "මහින්ද යාපා අබේවර්ධන",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජූලි 13",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "එක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Alahapperuma",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "එක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ධම්මික පෙරේරා",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "මණ්ඩල",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "එම්.පී.එස්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "මණ්ඩල",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගන්නා ලදී.(කැලුම් බණ්ඩාර",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "SJB, பத்து கட்சிகள் கொண்ட கூட்டணி, SLFP, SLPP சுயேட்சைகள் டல்லாஸ், சஜித், ஜனாதிபதி, பிரதமர்",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "போராட்டத்தை அடுத்து, பத்து கட்சிகள் கொண்ட கூட்டணி, சமகி ஜன பலவேகய, ஸ்ரீலங்கா சுதந்திரக் கட்சி (SLFP) மற்றும் ஸ்ரீலங்கா பொதுஜன பெரமுனவின் (SLPP) சுயேச்சைக் குழு ஆகிய அரசியல் கட்சிகள் நேற்று கூடி தீர்மானித்தன. பாராளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர் டலஸ் அழகப்பெரும மற்றும் எதிர்க்கட்சித் தலைவர் ஆகியோரை ஜனாதிபதியாகவும், பிரதம மந்திரியாகவும் நியமிப்பதற்கு அழுத்தம் கொடுப்பதாக டெய்லி மிரர் செய்தி வெளியிட்டுள்ளது.",
        "இந்த கட்சிகளின் பிரதிநிதிகள் கொழும்பில் உள்ள SJB பாராளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர் தலதா அத்துகோரளவின் இல்லத்தில் சந்தித்தனர். SJB, பிரதான எதிர்க்கட்சியாக, அதன் பொதுச் செயலாளர் ரஞ்சித் மத்தும பண்டார மற்றும் டொக்டர் ராஜித சேனாரத்ன ஆகியோர் பிரதிநிதித்துவப்படுத்தினர். பத்து கட்சிகளை கொண்ட கூட்டணியை பிரதிநிதித்துவப்படுத்தி, எம்.பி.எஸ் உதய கம்மன்பில, விமல் வீரவன்ச மற்றும் கெவிந்து குமாரதுங்க ஆகியோர் இதில் கலந்து கொண்டனர். ஸ்ரீலங்கா சுதந்திரக் கட்சி சார்பில் தயாசிறி ஜயசேகர மற்றும் துமிந்த திஸாநாயக்க ஆகியோர் கலந்துகொண்டனர். ஸ்ரீலங்கா பொதுஜன பெரமுனவின் சுயேட்சைக் குழு பாராளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர் அனுர பிரியதர்ஷன யாப்பாவை அதற்காக அனுப்பியது.",
        "தற்போதைய குழப்பத்தில் இருந்து நாட்டை வெளியேற்றுவதற்கு திரு.அழப்பெரும மற்றும் SJB தலைவரான திரு. பிரேமதாச ஆகியோர் தலைமைப் பதவிகளை ஏற்க வேண்டும் என அவர்கள் கலந்துரையாடியதாக கூறப்படுகிறது.",
        "ஆளும் SLPP யின் ஒரு பிரிவினர் ஜனாதிபதி கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ஷவை ஜூலை 9 ஆம் திகதி பதவி விலகுமாறு அழைப்பு விடுத்தனர். அதுமட்டுமல்லாமல், பாராளுமன்றத்தில் அங்கம் வகிக்கும் அரசியல் கட்சிகளின் தலைவர்களும் அவ்வாறு செய்யுமாறு அவரிடம் கோரிக்கை விடுத்துள்ளனர். ஜூலை 13 ஆம் திகதி ஜனாதிபதி பதவி விலகுவார் என சபாநாயகர் மஹிந்த யாப்பா அபேவர்தன பின்னர் தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "ஜனாதிபதி மற்றும் பிரதமர் இருவரும் ராஜினாமா செய்யும் பட்சத்தில், சபாநாயகர் தற்காலிக காலத்திற்கு தற்காலிக தலைவராக நியமிக்கப்படுவார், அதன் உறுப்பினர்களில் ஒருவரை எஞ்சிய காலத்திற்கு ஜனாதிபதியாக பணியாற்ற பாராளுமன்றம் நியமிக்கும். இந்த நிகழ்வில்,",
        "திரு. அழகப்பெருமவை ஆளும் கட்சியின் ஒரு பிரிவினர் அந்தப் பதவிக்கு முன்மொழிந்துள்ளனர், மற்றவர்கள் புதிதாக நியமிக்கப்பட்ட பாராளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர் தம்மிக பெரேராவை பதவிக்கு உயர்த்துகிறார்கள்.",
        "அனைத்துக் கட்சிகளைச் சேர்ந்த எம்.பி.எஸ்.களை உள்ளடக்கிய அமைச்சரவை அமைக்க உத்தேசிக்கப்பட்டுள்ளது.அமைச்சரவைக்கு ஆட்சி அமைக்க அறிவுறுத்தும் ஆலோசனைக் குழுவில் போராட்டத்தின் பிரதிநிதிகள் சேர்க்கப்பட உள்ளனர். எனினும் இறுதி முடிவு எதுவும் எடுக்கப்படவில்லை.(கெலும் பண்டார)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "பத்து",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "ஸ்ரீ.ல.சு.க",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "டல்லாஸ், சஜித் என",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "Prez",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "பத்து",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "சமகி ஜன பலவேகயா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜனாதிபதி தேர்தல்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஸ்ரீ.ல.சு.க",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "பொதுஜன பெரமுன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "நேற்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "டலஸ் அழகப்பெரும",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "டெய்லி மிரர்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "கொழும்பில் தலதா அத்துகோரள",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரஞ்சித் மத்தும பண்டார",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ராஜித சேனாரத்ன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "பத்து",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "எம்.பி.எஸ் உதய கம்மன்பில",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "விமல் வீரவன்ச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஸ்ரீ.ல.சு.க",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "எம்.பி.எஸ்.தயாசிறி ஜயசேகர",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "அனுர பிரியதர்ஷன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Alahapperuma",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "பிரேமதாச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "எஸ்.ஜே.பி",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜூலை 9",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "மஹிந்த யாப்பா அபேவர்தன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜூலை 13",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஒன்று",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Alahapperuma",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஒன்று",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "தம்மிக்க பெரேரா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "மந்திரி சபை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "எம்.பி.எஸ்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "மந்திரி சபை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "எடுக்கப்பட்டது.(கெலும் பண்டார",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}