{
  "newspaper_id": "d-b-s-jeyaraj-com",
  "url": "https://dbsjeyaraj.com/dbsj/archives/78269",
  "time_ut": 1656357840,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "The 22nd Amendment to the Constitution will be published in the Gazette of June 29 and  presented to Parliament after seven days, Says Justice Minister Wijeyadasa Rajapakshe; Cabinet Approved Draft Bill on June 27",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "The 22nd Amendment to the Constitution will be published in the Gazette of June 29 and  presented to Parliament after seven days, Says Justice Minister Wijeyadasa Rajapakshe; Cabinet Approved Draft Bill on June 27",
      "author": "Administrator",
      "body_lines": [
        "The 22nd Amendment to the Constitution will be published in the Gazette today (June 29), following which it will be presented to Parliament after seven days, Justice Minister Wijeyadasa Rajapakshe said yesterday (June 28).",
        "He said that on Monday (June 27), the Cabinet had given approval to publish the Bill in the Gazette after the draft Bill prepared by the Legal Draftsman was cleared by the Attorney General, who informed that the Bill is in accordance with the Constitution.",
        "He said while the Bill will be gazetted as the 22nd Amendment to the Constitution, it will be enacted as the 21st Amendment.",
        "“The SJB presented a Private Member’s Bill titled 21st Amendment to the Constitution and the Supreme Court ruled all its clauses will need approval at referendum hence it will not be possible to enact their Bill. The Government Bill will be enacted as the 21st Amendment,” Rajapakshe said.",
        "The Minister said the Bill will reinstate the independent commissions and strengthen the role of Parliament.",
        "“The international community too is keen to see that we bring legislation that strengthens democracy. Along with this we will also enact legislation on the lines of the United Nations Convention against Corruption as well as amend the laws dealing with declaration of assets and liabilities,” the Justice Minister said.",
        "He also said that President Gotabaya Rajapaksa has entrusted him with the work related to drafting a new Constitution.",
        "“I have been given a copy of the report of the expert committee led by Romesh de Silva PC which prepared the draft of a new Constitution. Once the work relating to the 21st Amendment is completed, a parliamentary select committee will be set up to study the report,” he said.",
        "Rajapakshe added that a new Constitution will be enacted after the approval of the people at a referendum."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "22nd",
          "label": "ORDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "Constitution",
          "label": "LAW"
        },
        {
          "text": "Gazette",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "June 29",
          "label": "DATE"
        },
        {
          "text": "Parliament",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "seven days",
          "label": "DATE"
        },
        {
          "text": "Justice",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "Wijeyadasa Rajapakshe",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "Cabinet",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "Bill",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "June 27",
          "label": "DATE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "22nd",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Constitution",
            "label": "LAW"
          },
          {
            "text": "Gazette",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "June 29",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "seven days",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Justice",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Wijeyadasa Rajapakshe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "yesterday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "June 28",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Monday (June 27",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Cabinet",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Bill",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Gazette",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Bill",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Legal Draftsman",
            "label": "LAW"
          },
          {
            "text": "Bill",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Constitution",
            "label": "LAW"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Bill",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "22nd",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Constitution",
            "label": "LAW"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "SJB",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Bill",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "21st",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Constitution",
            "label": "LAW"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Supreme Court",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Rajapakshe",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the United Nations Convention against Corruption",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Gotabaya Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Constitution",
            "label": "LAW"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Romesh de Silva",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Constitution",
            "label": "LAW"
          },
          {
            "text": "21st",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Constitution",
            "label": "LAW"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "ආණ්ඩුක්‍රම ව්‍යවස්ථාවේ 22 වැනි සංශෝධනය ජූනි 29 වැනිදා ගැසට් මගින් ප්‍රකාශයට පත් කර දින හතකට පසු පාර්ලිමේන්තුවට ඉදිරිපත් කරන බව අධිකරණ අමාත්‍ය විජයදාස රාජපක්ෂ මහතා පවසයි. ජූනි 27 වැනි දින අමාත්‍ය මණ්ඩල අනුමැතිය හිමි විය",
      "author": "පරිපාලක",
      "body_lines": [
        "ආණ්ඩුක්‍රම ව්‍යවස්ථාවේ 22 වැනි සංශෝධනය අද (ජුනි 29) ගැසට් පත්‍රයේ ප්‍රකාශයට පත් කරන අතර ඉන් අනතුරුව දින හතකට පසු එය පාර්ලිමේන්තුවට ඉදිරිපත් කරන බව අධිකරණ අමාත්‍ය විජයදාස රාජපක්ෂ මහතා ඊයේ (ජුනි 28) පැවසීය.",
        "නීති කෙටුම්පත් සම්පාදකයා විසින් සකස් කරන ලද පනත් කෙටුම්පත ආණ්ඩුක්‍රම ව්‍යවස්ථාවට අනුකූල බව නීතිපතිවරයා විසින් නිෂ්කාශනය කිරීමෙන් පසු පනත් කෙටුම්පත ගැසට් පත්‍රයේ ප්‍රකාශයට පත් කිරීමට සඳුදා (ජුනි 27) අමාත්‍ය මණ්ඩලය අනුමැතිය ලබා දුන් බව ඔහු පැවසීය.",
        "මෙම පනත් කෙටුම්පත 22 වැනි ආණ්ඩුක්‍රම ව්‍යවස්ථා සංශෝධනය ලෙස ගැසට් කරන අතරම එය 21 වැනි සංශෝධනය ලෙස බලාත්මක කරන බවද ඔහු පැවසීය.",
        "“SJB විසින් 21 වන ආණ්ඩුක්‍රම ව්‍යවස්ථා සංශෝධනය නමින් පුද්ගලික මන්ත්‍රී පනතක් ඉදිරිපත් කළ අතර ශ්‍රේෂ්ඨාධිකරණය තීන්දු කළේ එහි සියලුම වගන්ති සඳහා ජනමත විචාරණයේදී අනුමැතිය අවශ්‍ය වන බැවින් ඒවායේ පනත් කෙටුම්පත බලාත්මක කිරීමට නොහැකි වනු ඇති බවයි. රජයේ පනත් කෙටුම්පත 21 වැනි සංශෝධනය ලෙස බලාත්මක කරනවා” යැයිද රාජපක්ෂ මහතා පැවසීය.",
        "මෙම පනත් කෙටුම්පත ස්වාධීන කොමිෂන් සභා යළි ස්ථාපිත කර පාර්ලිමේන්තුවේ කාර්යභාරය ශක්තිමත් කරන බව අමාත්‍යවරයා පැවසීය.",
        "“ජාත්‍යන්තර ප්‍රජාවත් උනන්දුයි අපි ප්‍රජාතන්ත්‍රවාදය ශක්තිමත් කරන නීති සම්පාදනය කරනවා දකින්න. මේ සමඟම දූෂණයට එරෙහි එක්සත් ජාතීන්ගේ ප්‍රඥප්තියට අනුව නීති සම්පාදනය කිරීම මෙන්ම වත්කම් බැරකම් ප්‍රකාශ කිරීම සම්බන්ධ නීති සංශෝධන ද සිදු කරනවා,” අධිකරණ අමාත්‍යවරයා පැවසීය.",
        "නව ආණ්ඩුක්‍රම ව්‍යවස්ථාවක් සම්පාදනය කිරීමේ වැඩකටයුතු ජනාධිපති ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ මහතා තමන්ට භාර දී ඇති බවද ඔහු කියා සිටියා.",
        "“නව ආණ්ඩුක්‍රම ව්‍යවස්ථා කෙටුම්පත සකස් කළ ජනාධිපති නීතිඥ රොමේෂ් ද සිල්වා ප්‍රමුඛ විද්වත් කමිටු වාර්තාවේ පිටපතක් මා වෙත ලබාදී තිබෙනවා. 21 වැනි සංශෝධනයට අදාළ කටයුතු අවසන් වූ පසු එම වාර්තාව අධ්‍යයනය කිරීමට පාර්ලිමේන්තු තේරීම් කාරක සභාවක් පත් කරනවා.”",
        "ජනමත විචාරණයකින් ජනතා අනුමැතිය ලැබීමෙන් පසු නව ආණ්ඩුක්‍රම ව්‍යවස්ථාවක් සම්පාදනය කරන බව ද රාජපක්ෂ මහතා පැවසීය."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "22 වැනි",
          "label": "ORDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "ව්යවස්ථාව",
          "label": "LAW"
        },
        {
          "text": "ගැසට්",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "ජූනි 29",
          "label": "DATE"
        },
        {
          "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "දින හතක්",
          "label": "DATE"
        },
        {
          "text": "යුක්තිය",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "විජයදාස රාජපක්ෂ",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "මණ්ඩල",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "බිල්පත්",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "ජූනි 27",
          "label": "DATE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "22 වැනි",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ව්යවස්ථාව",
            "label": "LAW"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගැසට්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජූනි 29",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "දින හතක්",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "යුක්තිය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "විජයදාස රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඊයේ",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජූනි 28",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "සඳුදා (ජුනි 27",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මණ්ඩල",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "බිල්පත්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගැසට්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "බිල්පත්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "නීති කෙටුම්පත්කරු",
            "label": "LAW"
          },
          {
            "text": "බිල්පත්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ව්යවස්ථාව",
            "label": "LAW"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "බිල්පත්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "22 වැනි",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ව්යවස්ථාව",
            "label": "LAW"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "එස්.ජේ.බී",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "බිල්පත්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "21 වැනි",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ව්යවස්ථාව",
            "label": "LAW"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රේෂ්ඨාධිකරණය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "දූෂණයට එරෙහි එක්සත් ජාතීන්ගේ සම්මුතිය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ව්යවස්ථාව",
            "label": "LAW"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "රොමේෂ් ද සිල්වා",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ව්යවස්ථාව",
            "label": "LAW"
          },
          {
            "text": "21 වැනි",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ව්යවස්ථාව",
            "label": "LAW"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "அரசியலமைப்பின் 22ஆவது திருத்தம் ஜூன் 29ஆம் திகதி வர்த்தமானியில் வெளியிடப்பட்டு ஏழு நாட்களுக்குப் பின்னர் நாடாளுமன்றத்தில் சமர்ப்பிக்கப்படும் என நீதியமைச்சர் விஜயதாச ராஜபக்ஷ தெரிவித்துள்ளார். ஜூன் 27 அன்று வரைவு மசோதாவுக்கு அமைச்சரவை ஒப்புதல் அளித்தது",
      "author": "நிர்வாகி",
      "body_lines": [
        "அரசியலமைப்பின் 22 ஆவது திருத்தம் இன்று (ஜூன் 29) வர்த்தமானியில் வெளியிடப்படும் என்றும், ஏழு நாட்களுக்குப் பின்னர் அது பாராளுமன்றத்தில் சமர்ப்பிக்கப்படும் என்றும் நீதி அமைச்சர் விஜயதாச ராஜபக்ஷ நேற்று (ஜூன் 28) தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "திங்கட்கிழமை (ஜூன் 27) சட்ட வரைவாளரால் தயாரிக்கப்பட்ட வரைவு சட்டமூலத்திற்கு சட்டமா அதிபரினால் அனுமதி கிடைத்ததையடுத்து சட்டமூலத்தை அரசிதழில் வெளியிடுவதற்கு அமைச்சரவை அங்கீகாரம் வழங்கியுள்ளதாகவும், இந்த சட்டமூலம் அரசியலமைப்பிற்கு உட்பட்டது எனவும் அவர் தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "இந்த சட்டமூலம் அரசியலமைப்பின் 22 ஆவது திருத்தமாக வர்த்தமானியில் வெளியிடப்படும் அதேவேளை, 21 ஆவது திருத்தமாக இது அமுல்படுத்தப்படும் என அவர் தெரிவித்துள்ளார்.",
        "\"SJB அரசியலமைப்பின் 21 வது திருத்தம் என்ற தலைப்பில் ஒரு தனியார் உறுப்பினர் மசோதாவை சமர்ப்பித்தது மற்றும் உச்ச நீதிமன்றம் அதன் அனைத்து உட்பிரிவுகளுக்கும் வாக்கெடுப்பில் ஒப்புதல் தேவை என்று தீர்ப்பளித்தது, எனவே அவர்களின் மசோதாவை நிறைவேற்ற முடியாது. அரசாங்க சட்டமூலம் 21வது திருத்தமாக அமுல்படுத்தப்படும்” என ராஜபக்ஷ தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "இந்த சட்டமூலம் சுயாதீன ஆணைக்குழுக்களை மீள ஸ்தாபிதம் செய்து பாராளுமன்றத்தின் பங்கை பலப்படுத்தும் என அமைச்சர் தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "“சர்வதேச சமூகமும் ஜனநாயகத்தை வலுப்படுத்தும் சட்டத்தை கொண்டு வர வேண்டும் என்று ஆர்வமாக உள்ளது. இதனுடன், ஊழலுக்கு எதிரான ஐக்கிய நாடுகளின் மாநாட்டின் அடிப்படையில் நாங்கள் சட்டத்தை இயற்றுவோம், அத்துடன் சொத்துக்கள் மற்றும் கடன்களை அறிவிப்பது தொடர்பான சட்டங்களைத் திருத்துவோம், ”என்று நீதி அமைச்சர் கூறினார்.",
        "புதிய அரசியலமைப்பை உருவாக்குவது தொடர்பான பணிகளை ஜனாதிபதி கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ஷ தன்னிடம் ஒப்படைத்துள்ளதாகவும் அவர் கூறினார்.",
        "“புதிய அரசியலமைப்பு வரைவைத் தயாரித்த பிசி ரொமேஷ் டி சில்வா தலைமையிலான நிபுணர் குழுவின் அறிக்கையின் நகல் என்னிடம் வழங்கப்பட்டுள்ளது. 21வது திருத்தம் தொடர்பான பணிகள் நிறைவடைந்தவுடன், அந்த அறிக்கையை ஆய்வு செய்ய நாடாளுமன்றத் தெரிவுக்குழு அமைக்கப்படும்” என்றார்.",
        "பொது வாக்கெடுப்பின் மூலம் மக்களின் ஒப்புதலுக்குப் பிறகு புதிய அரசியலமைப்பு உருவாக்கப்படும் என்றும் ராஜபக்ஷ மேலும் தெரிவித்தார்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "22வது",
          "label": "ORDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "அரசியலமைப்பு",
          "label": "LAW"
        },
        {
          "text": "அரசிதழ்",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "ஜூன் 29",
          "label": "DATE"
        },
        {
          "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "ஏழு நாட்கள்",
          "label": "DATE"
        },
        {
          "text": "நீதி",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "விஜயதாச ராஜபக்ஷ",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "மந்திரி சபை",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "ர சி து",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "ஜூன் 27",
          "label": "DATE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "22வது",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "அரசியலமைப்பு",
            "label": "LAW"
          },
          {
            "text": "அரசிதழ்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜூன் 29",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஏழு நாட்கள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "நீதி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "விஜயதாச ராஜபக்ஷ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "நேற்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜூன் 28",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "திங்கட்கிழமை (ஜூன் 27",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "மந்திரி சபை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ர சி து",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "அரசிதழ்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ர சி து",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "சட்ட வரைவாளர்",
            "label": "LAW"
          },
          {
            "text": "ர சி து",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "அரசியலமைப்பு",
            "label": "LAW"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ர சி து",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "22வது",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "அரசியலமைப்பு",
            "label": "LAW"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "எஸ்.ஜே.பி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ர சி து",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "21 ஆம் தேதி",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "அரசியலமைப்பு",
            "label": "LAW"
          },
          {
            "text": "உச்ச நீதிமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ராஜபக்சே",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஊழலுக்கு எதிரான ஐக்கிய நாடுகளின் மாநாடு",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "அரசியலமைப்பு",
            "label": "LAW"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ரொமேஷ் டி சில்வா",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "அரசியலமைப்பு",
            "label": "LAW"
          },
          {
            "text": "21 ஆம் தேதி",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "அரசியலமைப்பு",
            "label": "LAW"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}