{
  "newspaper_id": "daily-mirror-lk",
  "url": "https://www.dailymirror.lk/breaking_news/12-5Kg-LITRO-gas-cylinder-price-down-by-Rs-113/108-244324",
  "time_ut": 1662359131,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "12.5Kg LITRO gas cylinder price down by Rs.113",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "12.5Kg LITRO gas cylinder price down by Rs.113",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "The price of 12.5kg domestic LITRO gas cylinder has been reduced by Rs. 113 from midnight today, LITRO Lanka Chairman Muditha Peiris said.",
        "Accordingly, the new retail price of the 12.5kg gas cylinder will be Rs. 4,551.",
        "The 5 kg gas cylinder will be reduced by Rs.45 and the 2.3 kg cylinder will be reduced by Rs.21 from tonight.",
        "The price reduction is mainly due to the fluctuation in global gas prices, the chairman said.",
        "The price revision took place by collective efforts taken by the Finance Ministry, Consumer Affairs Authority (CAA), the Presidential Secretariat and with LITRO Lanka Ltd., following new added features to the existing gas price formula. Earlier, price of domestic LITRO gas cylinders was reduced on August 9. (Chaturanga Samarawickrama)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "12.5Kg",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "12.5kg",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "113",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "midnight today",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "LITRO Lanka",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Muditha Peiris",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "12.5kg",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "4,551",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "5 kg",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "2.3 kg",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "tonight",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "the Finance Ministry",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Consumer Affairs Authority",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Presidential Secretariat",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "LITRO Lanka Ltd.",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "August 9",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Chaturanga Samarawickrama",
            "label": "LOC"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "12.5Kg LITRO ගෑස් සිලින්ඩරයක මිල රුපියල් 113 කින් පහතට",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "12.5kg ගෘහස්ථ LITRO ගෑස් සිලින්ඩරයක මිල රු. අද මධ්‍යම රාත්‍රියේ සිට 113 දක්වා ඉහළ ගොස් ඇති බව ලිට්‍රෝ ලංකා සභාපති මුදිත පීරිස් මහතා පැවසීය.",
        "ඒ අනුව කිලෝග්‍රෑම් 12.5 ගෑස් සිලින්ඩරයේ නව සිල්ලර මිල රු. 4,551 කි.",
        "අද රාත්‍රියේ සිට කිලෝ ග්‍රෑම් 5 ගෑස් සිලින්ඩරය රුපියල් 45කින් සහ කිලෝග්‍රෑම් 2.3ක සිලින්ඩරය රුපියල් 21කින් අඩු කෙරේ.",
        "ගෝලීය ගෑස් මිලෙහි උච්චාවචනය ප්‍රධාන වශයෙන් මිල අඩු කිරීමට හේතු වී ඇති බව සභාපතිවරයා පැවසීය.",
        "පවතින ගෑස් මිල සූත්‍රයට නව එකතු කළ විශේෂාංග අනුව මුදල් අමාත්‍යාංශය, පාරිභෝගික කටයුතු අධිකාරිය (CAA), ජනාධිපති ලේකම් කාර්යාලය සහ LITRO Lanka Ltd සමඟ එක්ව ගත් සාමූහික ප්‍රයත්නයන් මත මෙම මිල සංශෝධනය සිදු විය. මීට පෙර අගෝස්තු 9 වැනිදා ගෘහස්ථ ලිට්‍රෝ ගෑස් සිලින්ඩරවල මිල අඩු කරන ලදී. (චතුරංග සමරවික්‍රම)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "12.5Kg",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "12.5kg",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "113",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "අද මධ්‍යම රාත්‍රිය",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "ලිට්රෝ ලංකා",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "මුදිත පීරිස්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "12.5kg",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "4,551 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "කිලෝ ග්රෑම් 5 කි",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "කිලෝ ග්රෑම් 2.3 කි",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "අද රෑ",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "මුදල් අමාත්යාංශය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාරිභෝගික කටයුතු අධිකාරිය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජනාධිපති ලේකම් කාර්යාලය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "LITRO Lanka Ltd.",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "අගෝස්තු 9",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "චතුරංග සමරවික්‍රම",
            "label": "LOC"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "12.5கிலோ லிட்ரோ கேஸ் சிலிண்டர் விலை ரூ.113 குறைந்துள்ளது",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "12.5 கிலோகிராம் உள்நாட்டு லிட்ரோ எரிவாயு சிலிண்டரின் விலை ரூ. இன்று நள்ளிரவு முதல் 113 என லிட்ரோ லங்கா தலைவர் முதித பீரிஸ் தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "அதன்படி, 12.5 கிலோ எடையுள்ள எரிவாயு சிலிண்டரின் புதிய சில்லறை விலை ரூ. 4,551.",
        "இன்று இரவு முதல் 5 கிலோ காஸ் சிலிண்டர் ரூ.45ம், 2.3 கிலோ சிலிண்டர் ரூ.21ம் குறைக்கப்படுகிறது.",
        "சர்வதேச எரிவாயு விலையில் ஏற்பட்டுள்ள ஏற்ற இறக்கம் காரணமாகவே இந்த விலைக் குறைவு ஏற்பட்டுள்ளதாக தலைவர் தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "நிதி அமைச்சு, நுகர்வோர் விவகார அதிகார சபை (CAA), ஜனாதிபதி செயலகம் மற்றும் LITRO லங்கா லிமிடெட் ஆகியவற்றுடன் இணைந்து, தற்போதுள்ள எரிவாயு விலை சூத்திரத்தில் புதிய சேர்க்கப்பட்ட அம்சங்களைத் தொடர்ந்து இந்த விலை திருத்தம் மேற்கொள்ளப்பட்டது. முன்னதாக, உள்நாட்டு லிட்ரோ எரிவாயு சிலிண்டர்களின் விலை ஆகஸ்ட் 9 ஆம் தேதி குறைக்கப்பட்டது. (சதுரங்க சமரவிக்ரம)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "12.5 கிலோ",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "12.5 கிலோ",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "113",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று நள்ளிரவு",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "லிட்ரோ லங்கா",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "முதித பீரிஸ்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "12.5 கிலோ",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "4,551",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "5 கிலோ",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "2.3 கிலோ",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்றிரவு",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "நிதி அமைச்சகம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "நுகர்வோர் விவகார ஆணையம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜனாதிபதி செயலகம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "லிட்ரோ லங்கா லிமிடெட்.",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆகஸ்ட் 9",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சதுரங்க சமரவிக்ரம",
            "label": "LOC"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}