{
  "newspaper_id": "lankadeepa-lk",
  "url": "https://www.lankadeepa.lk/news/අගමැති-නිවසේ-සිද්ධිය-සී-අයි-ඩීයට-බාරදෙයි/101-616175",
  "time_ut": 1657451519,
  "original_lang": "si",
  "original_title": "අගමැති නිවසේ සිද්ධිය සී.අයි.ඩීයට බාරදෙයි",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "The incident at the Prime Minister's house is handed over to the CID",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "The Criminal Investigation Department has handed over the investigation into the incident of breaking into and setting fire to the private residence of Prime Minister Ranil Wickremesinghe.",
        "Inspector General of Police Mr. CD Wickramaratne assigned these investigations to the investigation department today (10).",
        "Police sources say that a team of the Criminal Investigation Department has already visited the Prime Minister's private residence and started investigations."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "CID",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "The Criminal Investigation Department",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Wickramaratne",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "10",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the Criminal Investigation Department",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "අගමැති නිවසේ සිද්ධිය සී.අයි.ඩීයට බාරදෙයි",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "අග්‍රාමාත්‍ය රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතාගේ පෞද්ගලික නිවසට ඇතුළු වී එයට ගිනි තබා විනාශ කිරීමේ සිද්ධියේ පරීක්ෂණ අපරාධ පරීක්ෂණ දෙපාර්තමේන්තුව බාර දීඇත.",
        "පොලිස්පති සී.ඩී වික්‍රමරත්න මහතා විසින් මෙම පරීක්ෂණ කටයුතු අද (10) අද පරීක්ෂණ දෙපාර්තමේන්තුවට පවරා තිබිණි.",
        "අපරාධ පරීක්ෂණ දෙපාර්තමේන්තුවේ කණ්ඩායමක් මේ වන විට අග්‍රාමාත්‍යවරයාගේ පුද්ගලික නිවස වෙත ගොස් විමර්ශන ආරම්භ කර ඇති බව පොලිස් ආරංචි මාර්ග කියයි."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "CID",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "අපරාධ පරීක්ෂණ දෙපාර්තමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "වික්‍රමරත්න",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "10",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "අපරාධ පරීක්ෂණ දෙපාර්තමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "பிரதமர் வீட்டில் நடந்த சம்பவம் சிஐடியிடம் ஒப்படைக்கப்படுகிறது",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "பிரதமர் ரணில் விக்ரமசிங்கவின் தனிப்பட்ட இல்லத்தை உடைத்து தீ வைத்த சம்பவம் தொடர்பிலான விசாரணைகளை குற்றப் புலனாய்வு திணைக்களம் ஒப்படைத்துள்ளது.",
        "பொலிஸ் மா அதிபர் திரு. சி.டி.விக்ரமரத்ன இந்த விசாரணைகளை இன்று (10) புலனாய்வுத் திணைக்களத்திற்கு பணித்தார்.",
        "குற்றப் புலனாய்வுத் திணைக்களத்தின் குழுவொன்று ஏற்கனவே பிரதமரின் தனிப்பட்ட இல்லத்திற்குச் சென்று விசாரணைகளை ஆரம்பித்துள்ளதாக பொலிஸ் வட்டாரங்கள் தெரிவிக்கின்றன."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "சி.ஐ.டி",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "குற்றப் புலனாய்வுத் துறை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "விக்கிரமரத்ன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "10",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "குற்றப் புலனாய்வுத் துறை",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}