{
  "newspaper_id": "news-first-lk",
  "url": "https://www.newsfirst.lk/2022/08/23/non-parliament-parties-to-meet-ec-today-23/",
  "time_ut": 1661228280,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Non-Parliament parties to meet EC today (23)",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Non-Parliament parties to meet EC today (23)",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); The National Election Commission (NEC) says that a special discussion will be held today (23) between members of political parties who are NOT represented in Parliament and Election Monitors.",
        "The Chairman of the National Election Commission Attorney-at-law Nimal G. Punchihewa said that representatives of 55 political parties have been invited to the meeting.",
        "Previously, the NEC held discussions with all political parties represented in Parliament on the proposals of the Select Committee of Parliament to identify appropriate reforms of the election laws and the electoral system.",
        "During the meeting with the political parties that are not represented in Parliament and Election Monitors, the implementation of the proposals on election reforms will be taken up for discussion.",
        "Sri Lanka Govt must permit the safe return of Gotabaya & Family – HRCSL"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Non-Parliament",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "EC",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "today",
          "label": "DATE"
        },
        {
          "text": "23",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "News 1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "The National Election Commission",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "NEC",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "23",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Election Monitors",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the National Election Commission",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Nimal G. Punchihewa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "55",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "NEC",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Select Committee of Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Election Monitors",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Gotabaya & Family",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "පාර්ලිමේන්තු නොවන පක්ෂ අද (23) EC රැස්වීමට",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); පාර්ලිමේන්තුව නියෝජනය නොකරන දේශපාලන පක්ෂවල සාමාජිකයින් සහ මැතිවරණ නිරීක්ෂකයින් අතර විශේෂ සාකච්ඡාවක් අද (23) පැවැත්වෙන බව ජාතික මැතිවරණ කොමිෂන් සභාව පවසයි.",
        "ජාතික මැතිවරණ කොමිසමේ සභාපති නීතිඥ නිමල් ජී.පුංචිහේවා මහතා පැවසුවේ, දේශපාලන පක්ෂ 55ක නියෝජිතයින්ට රැස්වීමට ආරාධනා කර ඇති බවයි.",
        "මැතිවරණ නීති සහ මැතිවරණ ක්‍රමයේ යෝග්‍ය ප්‍රතිසංස්කරණ හඳුනා ගැනීම සඳහා පාර්ලිමේන්තු තේරීම් කාරක සභාවේ යෝජනා පිළිබඳව NEC විසින් මීට පෙර පාර්ලිමේන්තුව නියෝජනය කරන සියලුම දේශපාලන පක්ෂ සමඟ සාකච්ඡා පැවැත්වීය.",
        "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව නියෝජනය නොකරන දේශපාලන පක්ෂ සහ මැතිවරණ නිරීක්ෂකයින් සමඟ පැවැත්වෙන මෙම සාකච්ඡාවේදී මැතිවරණ ප්‍රතිසංස්කරණ පිළිබඳ යෝජනා ක්‍රියාත්මක කිරීම සම්බන්ධයෙන් සාකච්ඡා කිරීමට නියමිතයි.",
        "ගෝඨාභය සහ පවුලේ අය ආරක්ෂිතව නැවත පැමිණීමට ශ්‍රී ලංකා රජය අවසර දිය යුතුය - HRCSL"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තු නොවන",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "EC",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "අද",
          "label": "DATE"
        },
        {
          "text": "23",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "News 1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජාතික මැතිවරණ කොමිසම",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "NEC",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "23",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "මැතිවරණ නිරීක්ෂකයින්",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ජාතික මැතිවරණ කොමිසම",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "නිමල් ජී පුංචිහේවා",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "55",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "NEC",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තු තේරීම් කාරක සභාව",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "මැතිවරණ නිරීක්ෂකයින්",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ගෝඨාභය සහ පවුල",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "நாடாளுமன்றம் அல்லாத கட்சிகள் இன்று (23) தேர்தல் ஆணையத்தை சந்திக்க உள்ளன.",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); பாராளுமன்றத்தில் பிரதிநிதித்துவம் இல்லாத அரசியல் கட்சிகளின் உறுப்பினர்களுக்கும் தேர்தல் கண்காணிப்பாளர்களுக்கும் இடையில் இன்று (23) விசேட கலந்துரையாடல் ஒன்று இடம்பெறவுள்ளதாக தேசிய தேர்தல்கள் ஆணைக்குழு தெரிவித்துள்ளது.",
        "இந்தக் கூட்டத்திற்கு 55 அரசியல் கட்சிகளின் பிரதிநிதிகளுக்கு அழைப்பு விடுக்கப்பட்டுள்ளதாக தேசிய தேர்தல்கள் ஆணைக்குழுவின் தலைவர் சட்டத்தரணி நிமல் ஜி.புஞ்சிஹேவா தெரிவித்துள்ளார்.",
        "முன்னதாக, தேர்தல் சட்டங்கள் மற்றும் தேர்தல் முறைகளில் பொருத்தமான சீர்திருத்தங்களை அடையாளம் காண்பதற்கான பாராளுமன்றத் தெரிவுக்குழுவின் முன்மொழிவுகள் குறித்து பாராளுமன்றத்தில் பிரதிநிதித்துவப்படுத்தும் அனைத்து அரசியல் கட்சிகளுடனும் NEC கலந்துரையாடல்களை நடத்தியது.",
        "பாராளுமன்றத்தில் பிரதிநிதித்துவம் இல்லாத அரசியல் கட்சிகள் மற்றும் தேர்தல் கண்காணிப்பாளர்களுடனான சந்திப்பின் போது, ​​தேர்தல் சீர்திருத்தங்கள் தொடர்பான முன்மொழிவுகளை அமுல்படுத்துவது தொடர்பில் கலந்துரையாடப்படவுள்ளது.",
        "கோட்டாபய மற்றும் குடும்பத்தினர் பாதுகாப்பாக திரும்புவதற்கு இலங்கை அரசாங்கம் அனுமதிக்க வேண்டும் - HRCSL"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "பாராளுமன்றம் அல்லாதது",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "EC",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "இன்று",
          "label": "DATE"
        },
        {
          "text": "23",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "News 1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "தேசிய தேர்தல் ஆணையம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "NEC",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "23",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "தேர்தல் கண்காணிப்பாளர்கள்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "தேசிய தேர்தல் ஆணையம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "நிமல் ஜி புஞ்சிஹேவா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "55",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "NEC",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றத்தின் தெரிவுக்குழு",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "தேர்தல் கண்காணிப்பாளர்கள்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "கோட்டாபய & குடும்பம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}