{
  "newspaper_id": "news-first-lk",
  "url": "https://www.newsfirst.lk/2022/07/25/slcgs-jayesagara-joins-coast-guard-fleet/",
  "time_ut": 1658719800,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "SLCGS Jayesagara joins Coast Guard fleet",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "SLCGS Jayesagara joins Coast Guard fleet",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); An Offshore Patrol Vessel (OPV) of the Sri Lanka Coast Guard received her commission from the Secretary, Ministry of Defence General Kamal Gunaratne (Retd) WWV RWP RSP USP ndc psc MPhil during the Commissioning Ceremony held at the Naval Dockyard, Trincomalee 23rd July 2022.",
        "Sri Lanka Navy handed over this OPV to Sri Lanka Coast Guard on 03rd January 2022 at Galle harbour and she was commissioned today as ‘SLCGS Jayesagara’.",
        "The Commander of the Navy Vice Admiral Nishantha Ulugetenne, RSP*, VSV, USP, ndc, psc and Commander Eastern Naval Area Rear Admiral Jayantha Kularatne RSP*, USP, psc were also present at the occasion.",
        "The Secretary, Ministry of Defence was received by the Director General Sri Lanka Coast Guard and the Deputy Chief of Staff, Sri Lanka Navy Rear Admiral Anura Ekanayake RSP**, USP, psc upon the arrival of the Chief Guest at the Naval Dockyard, Trincomalee and was accorded a Guard of Honour by Coastguardsmen.",
        "The Secretary, Ministry of Defence accompanied by the Commander of the Navy and the Director General Sri Lanka Coast Guard made an inspection visit of the ship, “SLCGS Jayesagara”. The Navigation Officer briefed the Secretary, Ministry of Defence on the features of the ship and operational aspects of the ship.",
        "The Director General Sri Lanka Coast Guard and the Deputy Chief of Staff, Sri Lanka Navy also presented a memento to the Secretary, Ministry of Defence to mark the occasion.",
        "The SLCGS Jayesagara, with a displacement of 313 tons, is 39.8m in length and 7.0m in breadth. Manned by a crew of 10 officers and 68 sailors, the vessel can cover 3,200 nautical miles maintaining a cruising speed of 7 knots. The vessel served in the Sri Lanka Navy for nearly four decades and made a significant contribution during the Humanitarian Operation and countering illegal activities in Sri Lankan Waters.",
        "Members of the Maha Sangha and other religious denominations, members of the diplomatic corps, senior officers of the Sri Lanka Navy and Sri Lanka Coast Guard, distinguished invitees and a large number of Naval and Coastguard personnel were also present at the Commissioning Ceremony."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "SLCGS Jayesagara",
          "label": "LOC"
        },
        {
          "text": "Coast Guard",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "News 1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "An Offshore Patrol Vessel",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Sri Lanka Coast Guard",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ministry of Defence General",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kamal Gunaratne",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "USP",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Commissioning Ceremony",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Naval Dockyard",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "Trincomalee",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "23rd July 2022",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka Navy",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka Coast Guard",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "03rd January 2022",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Galle harbour",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "‘SLCGS Jayesagara’",
            "label": "FAC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Navy",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Nishantha Ulugetenne",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "RSP*",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "VSV",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "USP",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Eastern Naval Area",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "Jayantha Kularatne",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "RSP*",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "USP",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Ministry of Defence",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka Coast Guard",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Anura Ekanayake",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "USP",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Naval Dockyard",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "Trincomalee",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Ministry of Defence",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Navy",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka Coast Guard",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "SLCGS Jayesagara",
            "label": "WORK_OF_ART"
          },
          {
            "text": "Navigation Officer",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ministry of Defence",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka Coast Guard",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka Navy",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ministry of Defence",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "The SLCGS Jayesagara",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "313 tons",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "39.8",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "7.0",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "10",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "68",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "3,200 nautical miles",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "7",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Sri Lanka Navy",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "nearly four decades",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Humanitarian Operation",
            "label": "EVENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lankan Waters",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the diplomatic corps",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Sri Lanka Navy",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka Coast Guard",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Coastguard",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Commissioning Ceremony",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "SLCGS ජයේසාගර වෙරළාරක්ෂක බලඇණියට එක්වෙයි",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); 2022 ජුලි 23 දින ත්‍රිකුණාමලය, නාවික තටාකාංගනයේ පැවති කොමිස් කිරීමේ උත්සවයේදී ශ්‍රී ලංකා වෙරළාරක්ෂක බලකායේ අක්වෙරළ මුර යාත්‍රාවක් (OPV) ආරක්ෂක අමාත්‍යාංශයේ ලේකම් ජෙනරාල් කමල් ගුණරත්න (විශ්‍රාමික) WWV RWP RSP USP ndc psc MPhil ගෙන් කොමිස් ලබා ගත්තාය. .",
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකා නාවික හමුදාව විසින් 2022 ජනවාරි 03 වන දින ගාල්ල වරායේදී මෙම OPV නෞකාව ශ්‍රී ලංකා වෙරළාරක්ෂක බලකාය වෙත භාර දුන් අතර, ඇය අද දින ‘SLCGS ජයසාගර’ ලෙස පත් කරන ලදී.",
        "මෙම අවස්ථාවට නාවික හමුදාපති වයිස් අද්මිරාල් නිශාන්ත උළුගේතැන්න, RSP*, VSV, USP, ndc, psc සහ නැගෙනහිර නාවික ප්‍රදේශයේ ආඥාපති රියර් අද්මිරාල් ජයන්ත කුලරත්න RSP*, USP, psc යන මහත්වරු ද සහභාගි වූහ.",
        "ත්‍රිකුණාමලය, නාවික තටාකාංගනය වෙත ප්‍රධාන ආරාධිත අමුත්තා පැමිණි අවස්ථාවේදී, ආරක්ෂක අමාත්‍යාංශයේ ලේකම්වරයා, ශ්‍රී ලංකා වෙරළාරක්ෂක දෙපාර්තමේන්තුවේ අධ්‍යක්ෂ ජනරාල් සහ ශ්‍රී ලංකා නාවික හමුදාවේ නියෝජ්‍ය මාණ්ඩලික ප්‍රධානී, රියර් අද්මිරාල් අනුර ඒකනායක RSP**, USP, psc විසින් පිළිගන්නා ලදී. සහ වෙරළාරක්ෂක භටයින් විසින් ගෞරව සම්මාන මුරයක් පිරිනමන ලදී.",
        "ආරක්ෂක අමාත්‍යාංශයේ ලේකම්, නාවික හමුදාධිපති සහ ශ්‍රී ලංකා වෙරළාරක්ෂක දෙපාර්තමේන්තුවේ අධ්‍යක්ෂ ජනරාල්වරයා සමඟින් “SLCGS ජයසාගර” නෞකාවේ නිරීක්ෂණ චාරිකාවක නිරත විය. නාවික නිලධාරියා විසින් නෞකාවේ විශේෂාංග සහ නෞකාවේ මෙහෙයුම් කටයුතු පිළිබඳව ආරක්ෂක අමාත්‍යාංශයේ ලේකම්වරයා දැනුවත් කරන ලදී.",
        "මෙම අවස්ථාව සනිටුහන් කරමින් ශ්‍රී ලංකා වෙරළාරක්ෂක දෙපාර්තමේන්තුවේ අධ්‍යක්ෂ ජනරාල්වරයා සහ ශ්‍රී ලංකා නාවික හමුදාවේ නියෝජ්‍ය මාණ්ඩලික ප්‍රධානී විසින් ආරක්ෂක අමාත්‍යාංශයේ ලේකම්වරයා වෙත සමරු තිළිණයක් ද ප්‍රදානය කරන ලදී.",
        "ටොන් 313 ක විස්ථාපනයක් සහිත SLCGS ජයසාගර, දිග මීටර් 39.8 ක් සහ පළල මීටර් 7.0 කි. නිලධාරීන් 10 දෙනෙකුගෙන් සහ නැවියන් 68 දෙනෙකුගෙන් යුත් කාර්ය මණ්ඩලයකින් සමන්විත මෙම යාත්‍රාවට නාවික සැතපුම් 3,200ක් යාත්‍රා කළ හැකි අතර ගැට 7ක යාත්‍රා කිරීමේ වේගයක් පවතී. මෙම යාත්‍රාව දශක හතරකට ආසන්න කාලයක් ශ්‍රී ලංකා නාවික හමුදාවේ සේවය කර ඇති අතර මානුෂීය මෙහෙයුමේදී සහ ශ්‍රී ලංකා මුහුදු සීමාවේ නීති විරෝධී ක්‍රියාකාරකම් මැඩපැවැත්වීමේදී සැලකිය යුතු දායකත්වයක් ලබා දුන්නේය.",
        "මහා සංඝරත්නය ප්‍රමුඛ සෙසු ආගමික නිකායන්, රාජ්‍ය තාන්ත්‍රික සාමාජිකයින්, ශ්‍රී ලංකා නාවික හමුදාවේ සහ ශ්‍රී ලංකා වෙරළාරක්ෂක දෙපාර්තමේන්තුවේ ජ්‍යෙෂ්ඨ නිලධාරීන්, සම්භාවනීය ආරාධිතයින් සහ නාවික සහ වෙරළාරක්ෂක නිලධාරීන් විශාල පිරිසක් ද මෙම පත්කිරීමේ උත්සවයට එක්ව සිටියහ."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "SLCGS ජයසාගර",
          "label": "LOC"
        },
        {
          "text": "වෙරළාරක්ෂක",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "News 1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "අක්වෙරළ මුර යාත්‍රාවක්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකා වෙරළාරක්ෂක බලකාය",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "ආරක්ෂක අමාත්යාංශය ජෙනරාල්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "කමල් ගුණරත්න",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "යූඑස්පී",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "කොමිස් කිරීමේ උත්සවය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "නාවික තටාකාංගනය",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "ත්රිකුණාමලය",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "2022 ජූලි 23",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකා නාවික හමුදාව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකා වෙරළාරක්ෂක බලකාය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "2022 ජනවාරි 03",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගාලු වරාය",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "‘SLCGS ජයසාගර’",
            "label": "FAC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "නාවික",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "නිශාන්ත උළුගේතැන්න",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "RSP*",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "වී.එස්.වී",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "යූඑස්පී",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "නැගෙනහිර නාවික කලාපය",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජයන්ත කුලරත්න",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "RSP*",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "යූඑස්පී",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ආරක්ෂක අමාත්යාංශය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකා වෙරළාරක්ෂක බලකාය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "අනුර ඒකනායක",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "යූඑස්පී",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "නාවික තටාකාංගනය",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "ත්රිකුණාමලය",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ආරක්ෂක අමාත්යාංශය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "නාවික",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකා වෙරළාරක්ෂක බලකාය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "SLCGS ජයසාගර",
            "label": "WORK_OF_ART"
          },
          {
            "text": "නාවික නිලධාරියා",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ආරක්ෂක අමාත්යාංශය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකා වෙරළාරක්ෂක බලකාය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකා නාවික හමුදාව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ආරක්ෂක අමාත්යාංශය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ජයසාගර SLCGS",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "ටොන් 313 කි",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "39.8",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "7.0",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "10",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "68",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "නාවික සැතපුම් 3,200 කි",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "7",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකා නාවික හමුදාව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "දශක හතරකට ආසන්න කාලයක්",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මානුෂීය මෙහෙයුම",
            "label": "EVENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකා ජලය",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "රාජ්යතාන්ත්රික බලකාය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකා නාවික හමුදාව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකා වෙරළාරක්ෂක බලකාය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "වෙරළාරක්ෂක",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "කොමිස් කිරීමේ උත්සවය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "SLCGS ஜெய்சாகரா கடலோர காவல்படையில் இணைகிறது",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); 2022 ஆம் ஆண்டு ஜூலை 23 ஆம் திகதி திருகோணமலை கடற்படை கப்பற்படையில் நடைபெற்ற ஆணையிடும் விழாவின் போது இலங்கை கடலோரக் காவல்படையின் ஒரு கடல் ரோந்துக் கப்பல் (OPV) பாதுகாப்பு அமைச்சின் செயலாளர் ஜெனரல் கமல் குணரத்ன (ஓய்வு) WWV RWP RSP USP ndc psc MPhil அவர்களிடமிருந்து தனது கமிஷனைப் பெற்றது. .",
        "இலங்கை கடற்படை இந்த OPV ஐ 03 ஜனவரி 2022 அன்று காலி துறைமுகத்தில் இலங்கை கடலோரக் காவல்படையிடம் கையளித்தது, மேலும் அவர் இன்று ‘SLCGS ஜெயேசாகரா’ ஆக பணியமர்த்தப்பட்டார்.",
        "இந்நிகழ்வில் கடற்படைத் தளபதி வைஸ் அட்மிரல் நிஷாந்த உலுகெதென்ன, RSP*, VSV, USP, ndc, psc மற்றும் கிழக்கு கடற்படைத் தளபதி ரியர் அட்மிரல் ஜயந்த குலரத்ன RSP*, USP, psc ஆகியோரும் கலந்துகொண்டனர்.",
        "திருகோணமலை கடற்படை கப்பல்துறையில் பிரதம அதிதியாக வருகை தந்த பாதுகாப்பு அமைச்சின் செயலாளரை இலங்கை கடலோரக் காவல்படையின் பணிப்பாளர் நாயகம் மற்றும் பிரதிப் பணிப்பாளர் இலங்கை கடற்படை ரியர் அட்மிரல் அனுர ஏகநாயக்க RSP**, USP, psc ஆகியோர் வரவேற்றனர். மற்றும் கடலோர காவல்படையினரால் அவருக்கு மரியாதை செலுத்தப்பட்டது.",
        "பாதுகாப்பு அமைச்சின் செயலாளர், கடற்படைத் தளபதி மற்றும் இலங்கை கடலோரக் காவல்படையின் பணிப்பாளர் நாயகம் ஆகியோருடன் “SLCGS ஜயசகர” கப்பலின் ஆய்வு விஜயமொன்றை மேற்கொண்டார். கப்பலின் அம்சங்கள் மற்றும் கப்பலின் செயல்பாட்டு அம்சங்கள் குறித்து பாதுகாப்பு அமைச்சின் செயலாளருக்கு கடற்படை அதிகாரி விளக்கினார்.",
        "இலங்கை கடலோரக் காவல்படையின் பணிப்பாளர் நாயகம் மற்றும் சிறிலங்கா கடற்படையின் பிரதிப் பிரதானி அவர்களும் இந்த நிகழ்வைக் குறிக்கும் வகையில் பாதுகாப்பு அமைச்சின் செயலாளருக்கு நினைவுச் சின்னம் ஒன்றையும் வழங்கி வைத்தனர்.",
        "SLCGS ஜெய்சாகரா, 313 டன்கள் இடப்பெயர்ச்சியுடன், 39.8 மீ நீளமும் 7.0 மீ அகலமும் கொண்டது. 10 அதிகாரிகள் மற்றும் 68 மாலுமிகள் கொண்ட குழுவால் நிர்வகிக்கப்படும் இந்த கப்பல் 3,200 கடல் மைல்களை கடக்கும், 7 முடிச்சுகள் வேகத்தில் பயணிக்கும். இந்த கப்பல் சுமார் நான்கு தசாப்தங்களாக இலங்கை கடற்படையில் சேவையாற்றியது மற்றும் மனிதாபிமான நடவடிக்கையின் போது குறிப்பிடத்தக்க பங்களிப்பை வழங்கியது மற்றும் இலங்கை கடற்பரப்பில் சட்டவிரோத நடவடிக்கைகளை எதிர்த்தது.",
        "மகா சங்கத்தினர் மற்றும் ஏனைய சமய ஸ்தாபனங்களைச் சேர்ந்தவர்கள், இராஜதந்திரப் பிரிவைச் சேர்ந்தவர்கள், இலங்கை கடற்படை மற்றும் இலங்கை கடலோரக் காவல்படையின் சிரேஷ்ட அதிகாரிகள், கௌரவ அழைப்பாளர்கள் மற்றும் பெருந்தொகையான கடற்படை மற்றும் கரையோரப் படையினரும் ஆணையிடும் நிகழ்வில் கலந்துகொண்டனர்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "SLCGS ஜயசகர",
          "label": "LOC"
        },
        {
          "text": "கடலோர காவல்படை",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "News 1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஒரு கடல் ரோந்து கப்பல்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை கடலோர காவல்படை",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாதுகாப்பு அமைச்சகம் ஜெனரல்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "கமல் குணரத்ன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "யுஎஸ்பி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆணையிடும் விழா",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "கடற்படை கப்பல்துறை",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "திருகோணமலை",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "23 ஜூலை 2022",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை கடற்படை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை கடலோர காவல்படை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜனவரி 03, 2022",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "காலி துறைமுகம்",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "‘எஸ்எல்சிஜிஎஸ் ஜயசாகர’",
            "label": "FAC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "கடற்படை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "நிஷாந்த உலுகெதென்ன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆர்எஸ்பி*",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "வி.எஸ்.வி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "யுஎஸ்பி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "கிழக்கு கடற்படை பகுதி",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜயந்த குலரத்ன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆர்எஸ்பி*",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "யுஎஸ்பி",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பாதுகாப்பு அமைச்சகம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை கடலோர காவல்படை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "அனுர ஏக்கநாயக்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "யுஎஸ்பி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "கடற்படை கப்பல்துறை",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "திருகோணமலை",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பாதுகாப்பு அமைச்சகம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "கடற்படை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை கடலோர காவல்படை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "SLCGS ஜயசகர",
            "label": "WORK_OF_ART"
          },
          {
            "text": "வழிசெலுத்தல் அதிகாரி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாதுகாப்பு அமைச்சகம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை கடலோர காவல்படை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை கடற்படை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாதுகாப்பு அமைச்சகம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "எஸ்.எல்.சி.ஜி.எஸ்.ஜெயசாகரா",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "313 டன்",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "39.8",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "7.0",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "10",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "68",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "3,200 கடல் மைல்கள்",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "7",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை கடற்படை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "கிட்டத்தட்ட நான்கு தசாப்தங்கள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "மனிதாபிமான நடவடிக்கை",
            "label": "EVENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை கடல்",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "தூதரகப் படை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை கடற்படை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை கடலோர காவல்படை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "கடலோர காவல்படை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆணையிடும் விழா",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}