{
  "newspaper_id": "virakesari-lk",
  "url": "http://www.virakesari.lk/article/130348",
  "time_ut": 1656417095,
  "original_lang": "ta",
  "original_title": "ராதிகா குமாரசுவாமி எத்தியோப்பியா தொடர்பான சர்வதேச மனித உரிமைகள் நிபுணர் குழுவின் உறுப்பினராக நியமனம்",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Radhika Kumaraswamy appointed member of the International Committee on Human Rights Experts on Ethiopia",
      "author": "Digital Desk 5",
      "body_lines": [
        "Radhika Kumaraswamy, a Sri Lankan national, has been appointed a member of the International Committee of the Red Cross (ICRC) on Ethiopia, UN Human Rights Council President Federico Willegas (28) announced on Tuesday.",
        "Radhika Kumaraswamy from Sri Lanka has been appointed as the third member of the panel, following the appointment of Kari Perry Murungi from Kenya and Steven Rurner from the United States last March (2).",
        "The appointment follows the resignation of Ferro Benzuda, a member of the committee, last (8) years.",
        "An international panel of human rights experts was set up by the UN Human Rights Council on December 17, 2021 to investigate international human rights abuses, humanitarian and refugee abuses in Ethiopia since November 2020.",
        "Radhika Kumaraswamy has many years of experience as a human rights lawyer and has held various important positions in Sri Lanka and internationally."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Radhika Kumaraswamy",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "the International Committee on Human Rights Experts",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "Ethiopia",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Radhika Kumaraswamy",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lankan",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the International Committee of the Red Cross",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ethiopia",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "UN Human Rights Council",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Federico Willegas",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "28",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Tuesday",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Radhika Kumaraswamy",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "third",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kari Perry Murungi",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kenya",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Steven Rurner",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the United States",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "last March",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "2",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Ferro Benzuda",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "8) years",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the UN Human Rights Council",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "December 17, 2021",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ethiopia",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "November 2020",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Radhika Kumaraswamy",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "many years",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "ඉතියෝපියාව පිළිබඳ මානව හිමිකම් පිළිබඳ විශේෂඥයින්ගේ ජාත්‍යන්තර කමිටුවේ සාමාජිකාවක් ලෙස රාධිකා කුමාරස්වාමි පත් කර තිබේ",
      "author": "ඩිජිටල් මේසය 5",
      "body_lines": [
        "ශ්‍රී ලාංකිකයෙකු වන රාධිකා කුමාරස්වාමි ඉතියෝපියාවේ ජාත්‍යන්තර රතු කුරුස සංවිධානයේ (ICRC) සාමාජිකාවක් ලෙස පත් කර ඇති බව එක්සත් ජාතීන්ගේ මානව හිමිකම් කවුන්සිලයේ සභාපති ෆෙඩරිකෝ විලෙගාස් (28) අඟහරුවාදා නිවේදනය කළේය.",
        "පසුගිය මාර්තු (2) දින කෙන්යාවේ Kari Perry Murungi සහ එක්සත් ජනපදයේ Steven Rurner පත්කිරීමෙන් අනතුරුව එහි තුන්වන සාමාජිකාව ලෙස ශ්‍රී ලංකාවෙන් Radhika Kumaraswamy පත් කර ඇත.",
        "පසුගිය (8) වසර තුළ කමිටුවේ සාමාජිකයෙකු වූ ෆෙරෝ බෙන්සුඩා ඉල්ලා අස්වීමෙන් පසුව මෙම පත් කිරීම සිදු කෙරේ.",
        "2020 නොවැම්බර් මාසයේ සිට ඉතියෝපියාවේ සිදු වූ ජාත්‍යන්තර මානව හිමිකම් උල්ලංඝනය කිරීම්, මානුෂීය සහ සරණාගත අපයෝජනයන් පිළිබඳව විමර්ශනය කිරීම සඳහා 2021 දෙසැම්බර් 17 වන දින එක්සත් ජාතීන්ගේ මානව හිමිකම් කවුන්සිලය විසින් මානව හිමිකම් විශේෂඥයින්ගේ ජාත්‍යන්තර මණ්ඩලයක් පිහිටුවන ලදී.",
        "මානව හිමිකම් නීතිඥවරියක් ලෙස වසර ගණනාවක පළපුරුද්දක් ඇති රාධිකා කුමාරස්වාමි ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ සහ ජාත්‍යන්තර වශයෙන් විවිධ වැදගත් තනතුරු හොබවා ඇත."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "රාධිකා කුමාරස්වාමි",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "මානව හිමිකම් පිළිබඳ විශේෂඥයින් පිළිබඳ ජාත්‍යන්තර කමිටුව",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "ඉතියෝපියාව",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "රාධිකා කුමාරස්වාමි",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලාංකික",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජාත්‍යන්තර රතු කුරුස කමිටුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉතියෝපියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "එක්සත් ජාතීන්ගේ මානව හිමිකම් කවුන්සිලය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Federico Willegas",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "28",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "අඟහරුවාදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "රාධිකා කුමාරස්වාමි",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "තෙවන",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "කරි පෙරී මුරුංගි",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "කෙන්යාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ස්ටීවන් රනර්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "එක්සත් ජනපදය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "පසුගිය මාර්තු",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "2",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ෆෙරෝ බෙන්සුඩා",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "8) වසර",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "එක්සත් ජාතීන්ගේ මානව හිමිකම් කවුන්සිලය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "දෙසැම්බර් 17, 2021",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉතියෝපියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "2020 නොවැම්බර්",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "රාධිකා කුමාරස්වාමි",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "වර්ෂ බොහෝ ගණනක්",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "ராதிகா குமாரசுவாமி எத்தியோப்பியா தொடர்பான சர்வதேச மனித உரிமைகள் நிபுணர் குழுவின் உறுப்பினராக நியமனம்",
      "author": "Digital Desk 5",
      "body_lines": [
        "எதியோப்பியா தொடர்பான சர்வதேச மனித உரிமைகள் நிபுணர் குழுவின் உறுப்பினராக இலங்கையைச்சேர்ந்த ராதிகா குமாரசுவாமி நியமிக்கப்பட்டிருப்பதாக ஐக்கிய நாடுகள் மனித உரிமைகள் பேரவையின் தலைவர் ஃபெட்ரிகோ விலெகஸ் (28) செவ்வாய்கிழமை அறிவித்துள்ளார்.",
        "ஏற்கனவே மேற்குறிப்பிட்ட குழுவின் உறுப்பினர்களாக கென்யாவைச்சேர்ந்த காரி பெற்றி முருங்கி மற்றும் அமெரிக்காவைச்சேர்ந்த ஸ்டீவென் ரற்னர் ஆகியோர் கடந்த மார்ச் மாதம் (2) நியமிக்கப்பட்ட நிலையிலேயே மூன்றாவதாக இலங்கையைச் சேர்ந்த ராதிகா குமாரசுவாமி நியமிக்கப்பட்டிருக்கின்றார்.",
        "இக்குழுவின் உறுப்பினராகக் கடமையாற்றிய ஃபற்றோ பென்சூடா கடந்த (8) பதவி விலகியதையடுத்தே இந்த நியமனம் இடம்பெற்றிருக்கின்றது.",
        "எதியோப்பியாவில் கடந்த 2020 நவம்பர் மாதத்திலிருந்து இடம்பெற்ற சர்வதேச மனித உரிமை மீறல்கள், மனிதாபிமான மற்றும் அகதிகள் சட்டமீறல்கள் தொடர்பில் விசாரணைகளை மேற்கொள்வதற்காக கடந்த 2021 டிசம்பர் 17 ஆம் திகதி ஐ.நா மனித உரிமைகள் பேரவையினால் சர்வதேச மனித உரிமைகள் நிபுணர்கள் குழு உருவாக்கப்பட்டது.",
        "ராதிகா குமாரசுவாமி மனித உரிமைகள் சட்டத்தரணி என்ற ரீதியில் பலவருடகால அனுபவத்தைக் கொண்டிருப்பதுடன், அவர் இலங்கையிலும் சர்வதேச ரீதியிலும் பல்வேறு முக்கிய பதவிகளை வகித்துள்ளமை குறிப்பிடத்தக்கது."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ராதிகா குமாரசாமி",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "மனித உரிமைகள் நிபுணர்களுக்கான சர்வதேச குழு",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "எத்தியோப்பியா",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ராதிகா குமாரசாமி",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சர்வதேச செஞ்சிலுவைச் சங்கம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "எத்தியோப்பியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஐ.நா மனித உரிமைகள் பேரவை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Federico Willegas",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "28",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "செவ்வாய்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ராதிகா குமாரசாமி",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "மூன்றாவது",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "காரி பேரி முருங்கை",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "கென்யா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஸ்டீவன் ரன்னர்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஐக்கிய நாடுகள்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "கடந்த மார்ச்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "2",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஃபெரோ பென்சுடா",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "8) ஆண்டுகள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஐ.நா மனித உரிமைகள் பேரவை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "டிசம்பர் 17, 2021",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "எத்தியோப்பியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "நவம்பர் 2020",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ராதிகா குமாரசாமி",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "பல ஆண்டுகள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}