{
  "newspaper_id": "lankadeepa-lk",
  "url": "https://www.lankadeepa.lk/news/සාපෙළ-ප්‍රායෝගික-පරික්ෂණ-දින-පහකින්-පස්සට/101-619349",
  "time_ut": 1662383193,
  "original_lang": "si",
  "original_title": "සාපෙළ ප්‍රායෝගික පරික්ෂණ දින පහකින් පස්සට",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "SAPELA Practical Tests back in five days",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "Examination Commissioner General L. M. D. Dharmasena says that the practical tests related to the aesthetic subjects of the General Certificate of Education 2021 examination will begin on the 20th of this month.",
        "Mr. Dharmasena also says that the practical tests were scheduled to start on the 15th of this month, but due to unavoidable reasons, it had to be postponed.",
        "The examination commissioner also says that the evaluation work of the examination is at the final stage.",
        "Mr. Dharmasena also said that it will take another two months to release the results of the general examination."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "five days",
          "label": "DATE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "L. M. D. Dharmasena",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the General Certificate of Education",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "2021",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "the 20th of this month",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Dharmasena",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the 15th of this month",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "Dharmasena",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "another two months",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "සාපෙළ ප්‍රායෝගික පරික්ෂණ දින පහකින් පස්සට",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "අධ්‍යාපන පොදු සහතික පත්‍ර සාමාන්‍ය පෙළ 2021 විභාගයේ සෞන්දර්ය විෂයන්ට අදාල ප්‍රායෝගික පරීක්ෂණ මෙම මස 20 වැනි දා ආරම්භ කෙරෙන බව විභාග කොමසාරිස්  ජනරාල් එල්.එම්.ඩී ධර්මසේන මහතා පවසයි.",
        "එම ප්‍රායෝගික පරික්ෂණ මෙම මස 15 වැනි දින  ආරම්භ කිරීමට නියමිතව තිබුණද නොවැළැක්විය හැකි හේතුවක් නිසා එය කල්දැමීමට සිදු වූ බව ද ධර්මසේන මහතා කියයි.",
        "එම විභාගයේ ඇගයීම් කටයුතු මේ වන විට අවසන් අදියරේ තිබෙන බව ද විභාග කොමසාරිස්වරයා කියයි.",
        "සාමාන්‍ය පෙළ විභාගයේ ප්‍රතිඵල නිකුත් කිරීමට තවත් මාස දෙකක් පමණ කාලයක් ගත වුනු ඇතැයි ද ධර්මසේන මහතා කීවේය."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "දින පහක්",
          "label": "DATE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "L. M. D. ධර්මසේන",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "අධ්යාපන පොදු සහතිකය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "2021",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "මේ මස 20 වැනිදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ධර්මසේන",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "මේ මස 15 වැනිදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "ධර්මසේන",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "තවත් මාස දෙකක්",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "ஐந்து நாட்களில் மீண்டும் SAPELA நடைமுறை சோதனைகள்",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "கல்விப் பொதுச் சான்றிதழ் 2021 பரீட்சையின் அழகியல் பாடங்கள் தொடர்பான நடைமுறைப் பரீட்சைகள் இம்மாதம் 20ஆம் திகதி ஆரம்பமாகவுள்ளதாக பரீட்சை ஆணையாளர் நாயகம் எல்.எம்.டி.தர்மசேன தெரிவித்துள்ளார்.",
        "நடைமுறைப் பரீட்சைகள் இம்மாதம் 15ஆம் திகதி ஆரம்பமாகவிருந்த போதிலும், தவிர்க்க முடியாத காரணங்களால் அது பிற்போடப்பட்டதாகவும் திரு தர்மசேன கூறுகிறார்.",
        "பரீட்சைக்கான மதிப்பீட்டுப் பணிகள் இறுதிக்கட்டத்தில் இருப்பதாகவும் பரீட்சை ஆணையாளர் கூறுகிறார்.",
        "பொதுப் பரீட்சை பெறுபேறுகள் வெளிவர இன்னும் இரண்டு மாதங்கள் ஆகும் என்றும் தர்மசேன தெரிவித்தார்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ஐந்து நாட்கள்",
          "label": "DATE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "எல்.எம்.டி.தர்மசேன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "கல்விக்கான பொதுச் சான்றிதழ்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "2021",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்த மாதம் 20 ஆம் தேதி",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "தர்மசேனா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்த மாதம் 15 ஆம் தேதி",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "தர்மசேனா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்னும் இரண்டு மாதங்கள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}