{
  "newspaper_id": "ada-lk",
  "url": "https://www.ada.lk/breaking_news/කෝටියකට-අධික-වටිනාකමින්-යුත්-කේරළ-ගංජා-තොගයක්-සමග-අයෙක්-කොටුවෙයි/11-395586",
  "time_ut": 1658302899,
  "original_lang": "si",
  "original_title": "කෝටියකට අධික වටිනාකමින් යුත් කේරළ ගංජා තොගයක් සමග අයෙක් කොටුවෙයි",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "A person is arrested with a stock of Kerala ganja worth over one crore",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "A person was arrested today (20th) with 54 kilos and 710 grams of Kerala ganja worth over ten million rupees, says the Colombo South Division Criminal Investigation Unit.",
        "Police say that the arrested person is a (24)-year-old resident of Sedawatta area of ​​Wellampitiya.",
        "During this raid, the Senior Superintendent of Police in charge of Colombo South Division Mr. Sisira Pettathantri was informed about a person who was selling Kerala cannabis in bulk to many areas around Colombo. It is said that a person was arrested with the stock of Kerala ganja.",
        "While raiding and inspecting a house in Kurunduwatta Hatte Watta area, the police found three suspicious parcels hidden in that house.",
        "Later, the three parcels were taken into police custody and during inspection, they found Kerala ganja in them, and when they were weighed, the police said that there were 54 kilos of Kerala ganja and 710 grams in them.",
        "It is said that the value of the stock of Kerala ganja seized by the police is over ten million.",
        "The police said that this Kerala ganja had been smuggled in order to be sold in bulk to many areas around Colombo and earlier the Mattakkuliya police arrested the suspect along with 20 kilos of Kerala ganja and took him to jail.",
        "Investigations are on whether other people involved in the Kerala ganja trafficking of the suspect are involved.",
        "The arrested suspect was to be handed over to the Kuruduwatta police to be presented to the Maligakanda court."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Kerala",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "20th",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "54",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "710 grams",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kerala",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Colombo South Division Criminal Investigation Unit",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "24)-year-old",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sedawatta",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the Senior Superintendent of Police",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Colombo South Division",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sisira Pettathantri",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kerala",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Colombo",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kerala",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Kurunduwatta Hatte Watta",
            "label": "FAC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "three",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kerala",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "54",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kerala",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "710 grams",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Kerala",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Kerala",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Colombo",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "20",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kerala",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Kerala",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Kuruduwatta",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Maligakanda",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "කෝටියකට අධික වටිනාකමින් යුත් කේරළ ගංජා තොගයක් සමග අයෙක් කොටුවෙයි",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "රුපියල් මිලියන දහයකට අධික වටිනාකමින් යුත් කේරළ ගංජා කිලෝ පනස් හතරයි ග්‍රෑම් හත්සිය දහයක් සමග පුද්ගලයෙකු අද  (20දා)  දා අත්අඩංගුවට ගත් බව කොළඹ දකුණ කොට්ඨාශ අපරාධ විමර්ශන ඒකකය පවසයි .",
        "මෙසේ අත්අඩංගුවට ගෙන ඇත්තේ වැල්ලම්පිටිය සේදවත්ත ප්‍රදේශයේ පදිංචි (24) හැවිරිදි පුද්ගලයෙකු බව පොලිසිය කියයි .",
        "කොළඹ අවට ප්‍රදේශ රැසකට කේරල ගංජා තොග වශයෙන්  අලෙවි කරන පුද්ගලයෙකු පිළිබඳ , කොළඹ දකුණ කොට්ඨාස  විෂ මත්ද්‍රව්‍ය ඒකකයේ ස්ථානාධිපති උප පොලිස් පරීක්ෂක ෂෙහාන් ආනන්ද මහතාට ලැබී තිබූ තොරතුරක්  පිළිබඳව කොළඹ දකුණ  කොට්ඨාශ භාර ජේෂ්ඨ පොලිස් අධිකාරී  සිසිර පෙත්තතන්ත්‍රි   මහතා  දැනුවත් කොට එතුමාගෙන් ලද උපදෙස් අනුව සිදු කළ වැටලීමේදී මෙම කේරල ගංජා තොගය සමග පුද්ගලයෙකු මෙසේ අත්අඩංගුවට ගත්  බව පැවසේ .",
        "එහිදී  කුරුඳුවත්ත හැටේ වත්ත ප්‍රදේශයේ නිවසක් වටලා පරීක්ෂා කිරීමේදී එම නිවසේ  සගවා තිබූ සැකකටයුතු පාර්සල් තුනක් පොලිසිය සොයාගෙන තිබුණි .",
        "පසුව එම පාර්සල් තුන පොලිස් භාරයට ගෙන පරික්ෂා කිරීමේ දී  ඒ තුළ කේරළ ගංජා  තිබූ බවත් පසුව ඒවා කිරා මැන බැලීමේදී ඒ තුළ කේරළ ගංජා කිලෝ 54  ග්‍රෑම් 710  තිබූ බවත් පොලිසිය කියයි .",
        "පොලිස් භාරයට ගත්  කේරළ ගංජා තොගයේ වටිනාකම  මිලියන  දහයකට අධික බවද පැවසේ .",
        "මෙම කේරල ගංජා  කොළඹ අවට ප්‍රදේශ රැසකට තොග වශයෙන් අලෙවි කිරීම සඳහා මෙසේ සගවා තිබී ඇති බවත් මීට පෙර මට්ටක්කුලිය පොලිසිය මගින් කේරළ ගංජා කිලෝ 20 සමග සැකකරු අත්අඩංගුවට ගෙන බන්ධනාගාර ගත කිරීමෙන් පසුව ඇප මත නිදහස්ව ආ පුද්ගලයකු බවට තොරතුරු අනාවරණය වූ බවත් පොලිසිය පවසයි .",
        "සැකකරුගේ කේරල ගංජා ජාවාරමට සම්බන්ධ තවත් පුද්ගලයින්   සම්බන්ධ දැයි විමර්ශන ක්‍රියාත්මක ය.",
        "අත්අඩංගුවට ගත් සැකකරු මාලිගාකන්ද අධිකරණයට ඉදිරිපත් කිරීම සඳහා කුරුදුවත්ත පොලිසියට භාරදීමට නියමිතව තිබුණි ."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "කේරල",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "20 වැනි",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "54",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ග්රෑම් 710 යි",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "කේරල",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "කොළඹ දකුණ කොට්ඨාශ අපරාධ විමර්ශන ඒකකය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "24)-වයස",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "සේදවත්ත",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ජ්‍යෙෂ්ඨ පොලිස් අධිකාරි",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "කොළඹ දකුණ කොට්ඨාසය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "සිසිර පෙත්තතන්ත්‍රී",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "කේරල",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "කොළඹ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "කේරල",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Kurunduwatta Hatte Watta",
            "label": "FAC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "තුන්",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "කේරල",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "54",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "කේරල",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ග්රෑම් 710 යි",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "කේරල",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "කේරල",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "කොළඹ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "20",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "කේරල",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "කේරල",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Kuruduwatta",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මාලිගාකන්ද",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "ஒரு கோடி மதிப்பிலான கேரள கஞ்சாவுடன் ஒருவர் கைது செய்யப்பட்டுள்ளார்",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "பத்து மில்லியன் ரூபாவுக்கும் அதிகமான பெறுமதியான 54 கிலோ 710 கிராம் கேரள கஞ்சாவுடன் ஒருவர் இன்று (20) கைது செய்யப்பட்டதாக கொழும்பு தெற்கு குற்றப் புலனாய்வுப் பிரிவு தெரிவித்துள்ளது.",
        "கைது செய்யப்பட்டவர் வெல்லம்பிட்டிய சேடவத்த பகுதியைச் சேர்ந்த (24) வயதுடையவர் என பொலிஸார் தெரிவிக்கின்றனர்.",
        "இச்சோதனையின் போது கொழும்பை சுற்றியுள்ள பல பகுதிகளுக்கு கேரளா கஞ்சாவை மொத்தமாக விற்பனை செய்யும் நபர் ஒருவர் தொடர்பில் கொழும்பு தெற்கு பிரிவுக்கு பொறுப்பான சிரேஷ்ட பொலிஸ் அத்தியட்சகர் திரு.சிசிர பேட்டதந்திரிக்கு தகவல் கிடைத்தது.கேரள கையிருப்புடன் ஒருவர் கைது செய்யப்பட்டதாக கூறப்படுகிறது. கஞ்சா.",
        "குருந்துவத்தை ஹட்டே வத்த பிரதேசத்தில் உள்ள வீடொன்றை சுற்றிவளைத்து சோதனையிட்ட போது, ​​குறித்த வீட்டில் சந்தேகத்திற்கிடமான மூன்று பொதிகள் மறைத்து வைக்கப்பட்டிருந்ததை பொலிஸார் கண்டுபிடித்துள்ளனர்.",
        "பின்னர், அந்த மூன்று பார்சல்களையும் போலீஸார் கஸ்டடியில் எடுத்து சோதனையிட்டபோது, ​​அதில் கேரள கஞ்சா இருப்பது தெரியவந்தது, அவற்றை எடைபோட்டுப் பார்த்தபோது, ​​அதில் 54 கிலோ கேரள கஞ்சா, 710 கிராம் இருந்ததாக போலீஸார் தெரிவித்தனர்.",
        "பொலிஸாரால் கைப்பற்றப்பட்ட கேரள கஞ்சாவின் பெறுமதி பத்து இலட்சத்துக்கும் அதிகம் என தெரிவிக்கப்படுகிறது.",
        "இந்த கேரள கஞ்சா கொழும்பை சுற்றியுள்ள பல பகுதிகளுக்கு மொத்தமாக விற்பனை செய்வதற்காக கடத்தப்பட்டதாக தெரிவித்த பொலிஸார், முன்னதாக மட்டக்குளிய பொலிஸார் சந்தேக நபரை 20 கிலோ கேரளா கஞ்சாவுடன் கைது செய்து சிறையில் அடைத்துள்ளனர்.",
        "சந்தேக நபரின் கேரள கஞ்சா கடத்தலுடன் தொடர்புடைய வேறு நபர்களுக்கு தொடர்பு உள்ளதா என்பது குறித்து விசாரணை நடத்தப்பட்டு வருகிறது.",
        "கைது செய்யப்பட்ட சந்தேக நபரை மாளிகாகந்த நீதிமன்றில் ஆஜர்படுத்துவதற்காக குருதுவத்த பொலிஸாரிடம் ஒப்படைக்கப்படவுள்ளார்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "கேரளா",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "20வது",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "54",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "710 கிராம்",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "கேரளா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "கொழும்பு தெற்கு பிரிவு குற்றப் புலனாய்வுப் பிரிவு",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "24) வயது",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சேடவத்த",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "மூத்த காவல்துறை கண்காணிப்பாளர்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "கொழும்பு தெற்கு பிரிவு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "சிசிர பேட்டதந்திரி",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "கேரளா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "கொழும்பு",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "கேரளா",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Kurunduwatta Hatte Watta",
            "label": "FAC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "மூன்று",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "கேரளா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "54",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "கேரளா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "710 கிராம்",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "கேரளா",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "கேரளா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "கொழும்பு",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "20",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "கேரளா",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "கேரளா",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Kuruduwatta",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "மாளிகாகந்த",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}