{
  "newspaper_id": "lankadeepa-lk",
  "url": "https://www.lankadeepa.lk/news/අගරු-චෙක්-පතක්-දුන්-ව්‍යාපාරිකයා-මාට්ටු/101-618876",
  "time_ut": 1661680686,
  "original_lang": "si",
  "original_title": "අගරු චෙක් පතක් දුන් ව්‍යාපාරිකයා මාට්ටු",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "The businessman who gave a valuable check was caught",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "The Panadura Special Crime Investigation Division says that a businessman who allegedly bought paint worth 14 lakhs 2065 rupees from a factory in Panadura North area and gave a valuable check was arrested.",
        "Police say that the suspect businessman residing in Dambulla area had obtained this ink in 2021.",
        "A police officer said that investigations were conducted based on a complaint made to the police by the manager of the Panadura factory that the bank informed him that there was no money in the account when he banked the check he had given.",
        "The police say that the suspected businessman was informed to come to the police on several occasions, but he avoided, so they went to the Dambulla area and arrested the suspect."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "The Panadura Special Crime Investigation Division",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "14",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Panadura North",
            "label": "LOC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Dambulla",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "2021",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Panadura",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Dambulla",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "අගරු චෙක් පතක් දුන් ව්‍යාපාරිකයා මාට්ටු",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "පානදුර උතුර ප්‍රදේශයේ කර්මාන්ත ශාලාවකින් රුපියල් 14 ලක්ෂ 2065 වටිනා තීන්ත මිලදී ගෙන අගරු චෙක්පතක් ලබා දුන් බව කියන ව්‍යාපාරිකයකු  අත්අඩංගුවට ගත් බව පානදුර විශේෂ අපරාධ විමර්ශන අංශය කියයි.",
        "දඹුල්ල ප්‍රදේශයේ පදිංචි සැකකාර ව්‍යාපාරිකයා 2021 වසරේ දී මෙම තීන්ත ලබා ගෙන තිබූ බව පොලිසිය කියයි.",
        "ඔහු ලබාදුන් චෙක් පත බැංකු ගත කිරීමේදී එම ගිණුමේ මුදල් නොමැති බව බැංකු විසින් දැනුම් දුන් බව පානදුර කර්මාන්තශාලාවේ කළමනාකරු පොලිසියට කරන ලද පැමිණිල්ලක් අනුව විමර්ශන පැවැත්වූ බව පොලිස් නිලධාරියෙක් පැවැසීය.",
        "සැකකාර ව්‍යාපාරිකයාට අවස්ථා කිහිපයකදීම පොලිසියට පැමිණෙන ලෙස දැනුම් දුන්නද ඔහු මගහැර සිටි බැවින් දඹුල්ල ප්‍රදේශයට ගොස් සැකකරු අත්අඩංගුවට ගත් බව පොලිසිය කියයි."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ඒ පානදුර විශේෂ අපරාධ විමර්ශන කොට්ඨාසය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "14",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "පානදුර උතුර",
            "label": "LOC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "දඹුල්ල",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "2021",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "පානදුර",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "දඹුල්ල",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "பெறுமதியான காசோலை கொடுத்த தொழிலதிபர் சிக்கினார்",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "பாணந்துறை வடக்கு பிரதேசத்திலுள்ள தொழிற்சாலையொன்றில் இருந்து 14 இலட்சத்து 2065 ரூபா பெறுமதியான பெயின்ட் கொள்வனவு செய்து பெறுமதியான காசோலையை வழங்கிய வர்த்தகர் ஒருவர் கைது செய்யப்பட்டதாக பாணந்துறை விசேட குற்றப் புலனாய்வுப் பிரிவு தெரிவித்துள்ளது.",
        "தம்புள்ளை பிரதேசத்தில் வசிக்கும் சந்தேக நபரான வர்த்தகர் 2021 ஆம் ஆண்டு இந்த வர்ணத்தை பெற்றுள்ளதாக பொலிஸார் தெரிவிக்கின்றனர்.",
        "பாணந்துறை தொழிற்சாலையின் முகாமையாளர் பொலிஸாருக்கு வழங்கிய முறைப்பாட்டின் அடிப்படையில், தான் வழங்கிய காசோலையை வங்கியில் செலுத்திய போது கணக்கில் பணம் இல்லை என வங்கி தெரிவித்ததாக பொலிஸ் அதிகாரி ஒருவர் தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "சந்தேகத்திற்குரிய வர்த்தகரை பொலிஸாருக்கு வருமாறு பல தடவைகள் அறிவித்த போதும் அவர் தவிர்த்ததால் தம்புள்ளை பகுதிக்கு சென்று சந்தேக நபரை கைது செய்துள்ளதாக பொலிஸார் தெரிவிக்கின்றனர்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "பாணந்துறை விசேட குற்றப் புலனாய்வுப் பிரிவினர்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "14",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாணந்துறை வடக்கு",
            "label": "LOC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "தம்புள்ளை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "2021",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பாணந்துறை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "தம்புள்ளை",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}