{
  "newspaper_id": "news-first-lk",
  "url": "https://www.newsfirst.lk/2022/07/19/national-fuel-pass-qr-program-island-wide-implementation-from-25th-july/",
  "time_ut": 1658229000,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "National Fuel Pass QR program island-wide implementation from 25th July",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "National Fuel Pass QR program island-wide implementation from 25th July",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); The National Fuel Pass QR program will be implemented across the Island from Monday, the 25th of July, tweeted Minister Kanchana Wijesekera.",
        "He said that a Pilot Project will be conducted in multiple locations in Colombo from the 21st July along with the last digit of the number plate for QR Quota.",
        "The Minister said that the QR Code will be tested at multiple locations in Colombo 21-24th July.",
        "Changes to the last Digit of Number Plate for Fueling – Will be effective from 21st July, Island wide.",
        "National Fuel Pass QR program island-wide implementation from 25th July",
        "Sri Lanka crisis: India calls all-party meet on Tuesday (19)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "25th July",
          "label": "DATE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "News 1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "The National Fuel Pass QR",
            "label": "LAW"
          },
          {
            "text": "Monday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the 25th of July",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kanchana Wijesekera",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Colombo",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the 21st July",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Colombo",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "July",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "from 21st July",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Island",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "25th July",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "India",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Tuesday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "19",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "ජාතික ඉන්ධන අවසර පත්‍ර QR වැඩසටහන ජූලි 25 සිට දිවයින පුරා ක්‍රියාත්මක කෙරේ",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); ජාතික Fuel Pass QR වැඩසටහන ජූලි 25 සඳුදා සිට දිවයින පුරා ක්‍රියාත්මක කරන බව අමාත්‍ය කාංචන විජේසේකර ට්විටර් පණිවුඩයක් නිකුත් කරමින් කියා සිටියේය.",
        "QR කෝටාව සඳහා අංක තහඩුවේ අවසාන අංකය සමඟ නියමු ව්‍යාපෘතියක් ජූලි 21 වැනිදා සිට කොළඹ ස්ථාන කිහිපයක පවත්වන බව ඔහු පැවසීය.",
        "QR කේතය ජූලි 21 සිට 24 දක්වා කොළඹ ස්ථාන කිහිපයකදී පරීක්ෂා කරන බව අමාත්‍යවරයා පැවසීය.",
        "ඉන්ධන සැපයීම සඳහා අංක තහඩුවේ අවසාන ඉලක්කම් වෙනස් කිරීම - ජූලි 21 දින සිට දිවයින පුරා ක්‍රියාත්මක වේ.",
        "ජාතික ඉන්ධන අවසර පත්‍ර QR වැඩසටහන ජූලි 25 සිට දිවයින පුරා ක්‍රියාත්මක කෙරේ",
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ අර්බුදය: ඉන්දියාව අඟහරුවාදා (19) සර්ව පාක්ෂික රැස්වීමක් කැඳවයි"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ජූලි 25",
          "label": "DATE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "News 1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජාතික ඉන්ධන අවසර පත්‍රය QR",
            "label": "LAW"
          },
          {
            "text": "සඳුදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජූලි 25 වෙනිදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "කාංචන විජේසේකර",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "කොළඹ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජූලි 21",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "කොළඹ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජුලි",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ජූලි 21 සිට",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "දිවයින",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ජූලි 25",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "අඟහරුවාදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "19",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "தேசிய எரிபொருள் பாஸ் QR திட்டம் ஜூலை 25 முதல் நாடு முழுவதும் செயல்படுத்தப்படுகிறது",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); தேசிய எரிபொருள் பாஸ் QR திட்டம் ஜூலை 25 ஆம் திகதி திங்கட்கிழமை முதல் நாடளாவிய ரீதியில் அமுல்படுத்தப்படும் என அமைச்சர் காஞ்சன விஜேசேகர ட்வீட் செய்துள்ளார்.",
        "QR கோட்டாவுக்கான இலக்கத் தகட்டின் கடைசி இலக்கத்துடன் ஜூலை 21 முதல் கொழும்பில் பல இடங்களில் முன்னோடித் திட்டம் நடத்தப்படும் என்று அவர் கூறினார்.",
        "ஜூலை 21 முதல் 24 வரை கொழும்பில் பல இடங்களில் QR குறியீடு சோதனை செய்யப்படும் என்று அமைச்சர் கூறினார்.",
        "எரிபொருள் நிரப்புவதற்கான எண் தகட்டின் கடைசி இலக்கத்தில் மாற்றங்கள் - தீவு முழுவதும் ஜூலை 21 முதல் நடைமுறைக்கு வரும்.",
        "தேசிய எரிபொருள் பாஸ் QR திட்டம் ஜூலை 25 முதல் நாடு முழுவதும் செயல்படுத்தப்படுகிறது",
        "இலங்கை நெருக்கடி: செவ்வாய்க்கிழமை (19) அனைத்துக் கட்சிக் கூட்டத்திற்கு இந்தியா அழைப்பு"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ஜூலை 25",
          "label": "DATE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "News 1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "தேசிய எரிபொருள் பாஸ் QR",
            "label": "LAW"
          },
          {
            "text": "திங்கட்கிழமை",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜூலை 25 ஆம் தேதி",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "காஞ்சனா விஜேசேகர",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "கொழும்பு",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜூலை 21",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "கொழும்பு",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜூலை",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஜூலை 21 முதல்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "தீவு",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஜூலை 25",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்தியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "செவ்வாய்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "19",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}