{
  "newspaper_id": "news-first-lk",
  "url": "https://www.newsfirst.lk/2022/06/25/prof-rangita-de-alwis-elected-as-sl-representative-for-cedaw/",
  "time_ut": 1656142920,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Prof. Rangita De Alwis elected as SL representative for CEDAW",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Prof. Rangita De Alwis elected as SL representative for CEDAW",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); Professor Rangita De Silva De Alwis was elected to the UN Committee on the Elimination of All Forms of Discrimination Against Women (CEDAW) for the term 2023-2026 representing Sri Lanka.",
        "Prof. De Silva-De Alwis was elected during the 22nd Meeting of the State Parties to the CEDAW Convention at the United Nations in New York on 23rd June.",
        "At this election, State Parties to the Convention elected 12 members out of 23 candidates, to the Committee of the Convention. Sri Lanka obtained 124 votes obtaining the 5th highest number of votes. Other countries elected are Cuba, Uganda, Nigeria, Egypt, Israel, Spain, Estonia, Azerbaijan, Bulgaria, Trinidad and Tobago and Japan.",
        "Sri Lanka became a State Party to the Convention on the Elimination of All Forms of Discrimination against Women in 1981.",
        "The Committee on the Elimination of Discrimination against Women (CEDAW) is the body of independent experts that monitors implementation of the Convention, which consists of 23 experts on women’s rights from around the globe.",
        "Professor Rangita De Silva De Alwis is currently serving as the Associate Dean of International Affairs and the Academic Director of the Global Institute for Human Rights at the University of Pennsylvania Law School, in the USA. She earned her Bachelor of Law Degree from the University of Colombo and her LL.M and Ph.D from Harvard Law School.",
        "She is an expert on matters coming under the purview of the CEDAW, with over 25 years of experience globally, advocating for equal representation of women.",
        "Prof. Rangita De Alwis elected as SL representative for CEDAW",
        "Six people get addicted to heroin daily: National Authority on Tobacco and Alcohol"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Rangita De Alwis",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "SL",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "CEDAW",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Rangita De Silva De Alwis",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the UN Committee",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Elimination of All Forms of Discrimination Against Women",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "2023-2026",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "De Silva-De Alwis",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "22nd",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "the United Nations",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "New York",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "23rd June",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "State",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Convention",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "12",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "23",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Committee of the Convention",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "124",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "5th",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Cuba",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Uganda",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Nigeria",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Egypt",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Israel",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Spain",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Estonia",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Azerbaijan",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Bulgaria",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Trinidad",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Tobago",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Japan",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "a State Party",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "1981",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "The Committee on the Elimination of Discrimination",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Convention",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "23",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Rangita De Silva De Alwis",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Associate Dean of International Affairs",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Global Institute for Human Rights",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the University of Pennsylvania Law School",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "USA",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the University of Colombo",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Harvard Law School",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "CEDAW",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "25 years",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Rangita De Alwis",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "SL",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "CEDAW",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Six",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "daily",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "National Authority on Tobacco and Alcohol",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "CEDAW හි ශ්‍රී ලංකා නියෝජිතයා ලෙස මහාචාර්ය රංගිත ද අල්විස් තේරී පත් විය",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); ශ්‍රී ලංකාව නියෝජනය කරමින් 2023-2026 කාලසීමාව සඳහා කාන්තාවන්ට එරෙහි සියලු ආකාරයේ වෙනස්කම් කිරීම් ඉවත් කිරීම පිළිබඳ එක්සත් ජාතීන්ගේ කමිටුවට (CEDAW) මහාචාර්ය රංගිත ද සිල්වා ද අල්විස් තේරී පත් විය.",
        "ජූනි 23 වැනි දින නිව් යෝර්ක් නුවර එක්සත් ජාතීන්ගේ CEDAW සම්මුතියේ රාජ්‍ය පාර්ශවයන්ගේ 22 වැනි රැස්වීමේදී මහාචාර්ය ද සිල්වා-ද අල්විස් තේරී පත් විය.",
        "මෙම මැතිවරණයේදී, සම්මුතියේ කාරක සභාවට අපේක්ෂකයින් 23 දෙනෙකුගෙන් සාමාජිකයින් 12 දෙනෙකු සම්මුතියේ රාජ්‍ය පක්ෂ විසින් තේරී පත් විය. ශ්‍රී ලංකාව ඡන්ද 124ක් ලබා ගත්තේ 5 වැනි ඉහළම ඡන්ද සංඛ්‍යාව ලබා ගනිමින්. තේරී පත් වූ අනෙකුත් රටවල් වන්නේ කියුබාව, උගන්ඩාව, නයිජීරියාව, ඊජිප්තුව, ඊශ්‍රායලය, ස්පාඤ්ඤය, එස්තෝනියාව, අසර්බයිජානය, බල්ගේරියාව, ට්‍රිනිඩෑඩ් සහ ටොබැගෝ සහ ජපානයයි.",
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකාව 1981 දී කාන්තාවන්ට එරෙහි සියලු ආකාරයේ වෙනස්කම් කිරීම් තුරන් කිරීමේ සම්මුතියේ රාජ්‍ය පාර්ශවයක් බවට පත් විය.",
        "කාන්තාවන්ට එරෙහි වෙනස් කොට සැලකීම තුරන් කිරීම පිළිබඳ කමිටුව (CEDAW) යනු ලොව පුරා සිටින කාන්තා අයිතිවාසිකම් පිළිබඳ විශේෂඥයින් 23 දෙනෙකුගෙන් සමන්විත සම්මුතිය ක්‍රියාත්මක කිරීම අධීක්ෂණය කරන ස්වාධීන විශේෂඥයින්ගේ ආයතනයයි.",
        "මහාචාර්ය රංගිත ද සිල්වා ද අල්විස් මේ වන විට ඇමරිකා එක්සත් ජනපදයේ පෙන්සිල්වේනියා විශ්වවිද්‍යාලයේ නීති විද්‍යාලයේ මානව හිමිකම් පිළිබඳ ගෝලීය ආයතනයේ ජාත්‍යන්තර කටයුතු පිළිබඳ සහකාර පීඨාධිපති ලෙස ද කටයුතු කරයි. ඇය කොළඹ විශ්වවිද්‍යාලයෙන් නීතිවේදී උපාධිය සහ හාවර්ඩ් නීති විද්‍යාලයෙන් LL.M සහ Ph.D ලබා ගත්තාය.",
        "ඇය CEDAW හි විෂය පථය යටතේ එන කරුණු පිළිබඳ විශේෂඥවරියක් වන අතර, ගෝලීය වශයෙන් වසර 25 කට වැඩි පළපුරුද්දක් ඇති, කාන්තා සමාන නියෝජනයක් වෙනුවෙන් පෙනී සිටින්නීය.",
        "CEDAW හි ශ්‍රී ලංකා නියෝජිතයා ලෙස මහාචාර්ය රංගිත ද අල්විස් තේරී පත් විය",
        "දිනකට හය දෙනෙක් හෙරොයින් වලට ඇබ්බැහි වෙති: දුම්කොළ සහ මධ්‍යසාර පිළිබඳ ජාතික අධිකාරිය"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "රංගිත ද අල්විස්",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "එස්.එල්",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "CEDAW",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "රංගිත ද සිල්වා ද අල්විස්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "එක්සත් ජාතීන්ගේ කමිටුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "කාන්තාවන්ට එරෙහි සියලු ආකාරයේ වෙනස්කම් කිරීම් තුරන් කිරීම",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "2023-2026",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ද සිල්වා-ද අල්විස්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "22 වැනි",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "එක්සත් ජාතීන්ගේ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "නිව්යෝක්",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජුනි 23",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "රජයේ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "සම්මුතිය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "12",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "23",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "සම්මුතියේ කමිටුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "124",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "5 වැනි",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "කියුබාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "උගන්ඩාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "නයිජීරියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඊජිප්තුව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඊශ්රායෙල්",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ස්පාඤ්ඤය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "එස්තෝනියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "අසර්බයිජානය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "බල්ගේරියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ට්‍රිනිඩෑඩ්",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ටොබැගෝ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජපානය",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "රාජ්ය පක්ෂයක්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "1981",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "වෙනස් කොට සැලකීම තුරන් කිරීමේ කමිටුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "සම්මුතිය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "23",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "රංගිත ද සිල්වා ද අල්විස්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජාත්‍යන්තර කටයුතු පිළිබඳ සහකාර පීඨාධිපති",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "මානව හිමිකම් පිළිබඳ ගෝලීය ආයතනය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "පෙන්සිල්වේනියා විශ්ව විද්‍යාලයේ නීති විද්‍යාලය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඇඑජ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "කොළඹ විශ්වවිද්‍යාලය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "හාවඩ් නීති විද්‍යාලය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "CEDAW",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "අවුරුදු 25 යි",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "රංගිත ද අල්විස්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "එස්.එල්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "CEDAW",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "හය",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "දිනපතා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "දුම්කොළ සහ මධ්‍යසාර පිළිබඳ ජාතික අධිකාරිය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "CEDAW இன் இலங்கைப் பிரதிநிதியாக பேராசிரியர் ரங்கிதா டி அல்விஸ் தேர்ந்தெடுக்கப்பட்டார்",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); பேராசிரியர் ரங்கிதா டி சில்வா டி அல்விஸ், இலங்கையைப் பிரதிநிதித்துவப்படுத்தும் 2023-2026 காலப்பகுதிக்கு பெண்களுக்கு எதிரான அனைத்து வகையான பாகுபாடுகளையும் நீக்குவதற்கான ஐ.நா குழுவிற்கு (CEDAW) தெரிவு செய்யப்பட்டார்.",
        "ஜூன் 23 ஆம் திகதி நியூயோர்க்கில் ஐக்கிய நாடுகள் சபையில் நடைபெற்ற CEDAW மாநாட்டிற்கான அரச கட்சிகளின் 22வது கூட்டத்தின் போது பேராசிரியர் டி சில்வா-டி அல்விஸ் தெரிவு செய்யப்பட்டார்.",
        "இந்தத் தேர்தலில், மாநாட்டின் மாநிலக் கட்சிகள் 23 வேட்பாளர்களில் 12 உறுப்பினர்களை மாநாட்டின் குழுவிற்குத் தேர்ந்தெடுத்தன. இலங்கை 124 வாக்குகளைப் பெற்று 5ஆவது அதிக வாக்குகளைப் பெற்றுள்ளது. தேர்ந்தெடுக்கப்பட்ட மற்ற நாடுகள் கியூபா, உகாண்டா, நைஜீரியா, எகிப்து, இஸ்ரேல், ஸ்பெயின், எஸ்டோனியா, அஜர்பைஜான், பல்கேரியா, டிரினிடாட் மற்றும் டொபாகோ மற்றும் ஜப்பான்.",
        "1981 இல் பெண்களுக்கு எதிரான அனைத்து வகையான பாகுபாடுகளையும் நீக்குவதற்கான மாநாட்டில் இலங்கை ஒரு அரச கட்சியாக ஆனது.",
        "பெண்களுக்கு எதிரான பாகுபாடுகளை நீக்குவதற்கான குழு (CEDAW) என்பது உலகெங்கிலும் உள்ள பெண்களின் உரிமைகள் குறித்த 23 நிபுணர்களைக் கொண்ட மாநாட்டை செயல்படுத்துவதைக் கண்காணிக்கும் சுயாதீன நிபுணர்களின் அமைப்பாகும்.",
        "பேராசிரியர் ரங்கிதா டி சில்வா டி அல்விஸ் தற்போது அமெரிக்காவில் உள்ள பென்சில்வேனியா பல்கலைக்கழக சட்டப் பள்ளியில் சர்வதேச விவகாரங்களுக்கான அசோசியேட் டீனாகவும், மனித உரிமைகளுக்கான உலகளாவிய நிறுவனத்தின் கல்வி இயக்குநராகவும் பணியாற்றுகிறார். அவர் கொழும்பு பல்கலைக்கழகத்தில் சட்ட இளங்கலைப் பட்டமும், ஹார்வர்ட் சட்டப் பள்ளியில் தனது LL.M மற்றும் Ph.D பட்டமும் பெற்றார்.",
        "அவர் CEDAW இன் கீழ் வரும் விஷயங்களில் நிபுணராக உள்ளார், உலகளவில் 25 ஆண்டுகளுக்கும் மேலான அனுபவத்துடன், பெண்களுக்கு சமமான பிரதிநிதித்துவத்திற்காக வாதிடுகிறார்.",
        "CEDAW இன் இலங்கைப் பிரதிநிதியாக பேராசிரியர் ரங்கிதா டி அல்விஸ் தேர்ந்தெடுக்கப்பட்டார்",
        "தினமும் ஆறு பேர் ஹெராயினுக்கு அடிமையாகிறார்கள்: புகையிலை மற்றும் மதுபானம் மீதான தேசிய ஆணையம்"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ரங்கிதா டி அல்விஸ்",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "எஸ்.எல்",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "CEDAW",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ரங்கிதா டி சில்வா டி அல்விஸ்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஐநா குழு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "பெண்களுக்கு எதிரான அனைத்து வகையான பாகுபாடுகளையும் நீக்குதல்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "2023-2026",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "டி சில்வா-டி அல்விஸ்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "22வது",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஐக்கிய நாடுகள்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "நியூயார்க்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "23 ஜூன்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "நிலை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "மாநாடு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "12",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "23",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "மாநாட்டின் குழு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "124",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "5வது",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "கியூபா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "உகாண்டா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "நைஜீரியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "எகிப்து",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இஸ்ரேல்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஸ்பெயின்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "எஸ்டோனியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "அஜர்பைஜான்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "பல்கேரியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "டிரினிடாட்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "டொபாகோ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜப்பான்",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஒரு மாநில கட்சி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "1981",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பாகுபாடுகளை நீக்குவதற்கான குழு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "மாநாடு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "23",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ரங்கிதா டி சில்வா டி அல்விஸ்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "சர்வதேச விவகாரங்களின் அசோசியேட் டீன்",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "மனித உரிமைகளுக்கான உலகளாவிய நிறுவனம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "பென்சில்வேனியா பல்கலைக்கழக சட்டப் பள்ளி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "அமெரிக்கா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "கொழும்பு பல்கலைக்கழகம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஹார்வர்ட் சட்டப் பள்ளி",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "CEDAW",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "25 ஆண்டுகள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ரங்கிதா டி அல்விஸ்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "எஸ்.எல்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "CEDAW",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஆறு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "தினசரி",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "புகையிலை மற்றும் மதுபானம் மீதான தேசிய ஆணையம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}