{
  "newspaper_id": "economy-next-com",
  "url": "https://economynext.com/up-to-6-3-million-people-face-food-insecurity-in-cash-strapped-sri-lanka-wfp-99373/",
  "time_ut": 1662114600,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Up to 6.3 million people face food insecurity in cash-strapped Sri Lanka: WFP",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Up to 6.3 million people face food insecurity in cash-strapped Sri Lanka: WFP",
      "author": "Neshella Perera",
      "body_lines": [
        "ECONOMYNEXT – As Sri Lanka goes through its worst economic crisis since independence, 6.3 million people are food insecure and 6.7 million people are not consuming adequate diets, a Situation Report for August by the World Food Programme (WFP) said.",
        "“Up to 6.3 million people are food-insecure, based on WFP and FAO’s Crop and Food Security Assessment Mission. These numbers could mount even further without urgent intervention,” the statement said.",
        "WFP’s economic crisis response aims to reach a total of 3.4 million people across three main activities:  unconditional food assistance through cash or in-kind, school meals and nutritional support.",
        "Sri Lanka’s inflation for the month of August accelerated to 64.3 percent and food prices have risen by 93.7 percent after excess money printing that led to exceeding inflation.",
        "WFP has secured 1,475 metric tons of rice and 755 metric tons of iron-fortified rice to support 1 million children with school meals for a span of three months.",
        "In August and for November 2022 WFP has 24,440 metric tons of food currently in the pipeline, with 79 metric tons of vegetable oil already in storage and 2,075 metric tons in transit, including rice, iron fortified rice, vegetable oil, and yellow split peas.",
        "As per the statement, WFP has received 21.35 million US dollars from the governments of Australia, Italy, Japan, New Zealand, Norway, and Switzerland, as well as from the UN Central Emergency Response Fund, private sector partners, and multilateral donors, which represents 34 percent of its emergency appeal for 63 million dollars.",
        "Monthly telephone surveys are conducted covering all nine provinces across estate, urban, and rural settings. The surveys gather data on household food security, nutrition, access to food, markets, livelihoods, and debt, the statement said.",
        "Meanwhile, Agriculture Minister Mahinda Amaraweera told reporters this week that Sri Lanka might see a minor rice shortage in December which will be contained.",
        "However, the WFP statement said food and nutrition security is expected to deteriorate further during the upcoming lean season, between October 2022 and February 2023, if the country is unable to import adequate amounts of rice and other food products to cover its food deficit. (Colombo/Sep02/2022)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Up to",
          "label": "QUANTITY"
        },
        {
          "text": "6.3 million",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "Sri Lanka",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "WFP",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "6.3 million",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "6.7 million",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "August",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the World Food Programme",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "WFP",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Up to 6.3 million",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "WFP",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "FAO",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Crop and Food Security Assessment Mission",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "WFP",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "3.4 million",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "three",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the month of August",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "64.3 percent",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "93.7 percent",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "WFP",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "1,475 metric tons",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "755 metric tons",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "1 million",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "a span of three months",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "August",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "November 2022",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "WFP",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "24,440 metric tons",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "79 metric tons",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "2,075 metric tons",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "WFP",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "21.35 million US dollars",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "Australia",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Italy",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Japan",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "New Zealand",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Norway",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Switzerland",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the UN Central Emergency Response Fund",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "34 percent",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "63 million dollars",
            "label": "MONEY"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Monthly",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "nine",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Agriculture",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Mahinda Amaraweera",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "this week",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "December",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "WFP",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the upcoming lean season",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "between October 2022",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "February 2023",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Colombo/Sep02/2022",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "මුදල් හිඟ ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ මිලියන 6.3 ක් දක්වා ජනතාව ආහාර අනාරක්ෂිතභාවයට මුහුණ දෙති: WFP",
      "author": "නෙෂෙල්ලා පෙරේරා",
      "body_lines": [
        "ECONOMYNEXT - නිදහසින් පසු ශ්‍රී ලංකාව එහි දරුණුතම ආර්ථික අර්බුදය හරහා ගමන් කරන විට, මිලියන 6.3 ක ජනතාවක් ආහාර අනාරක්‍ෂිතව සිටින අතර මිලියන 6.7 ක ජනතාවක් ප්‍රමාණවත් ආහාර අනුභව නොකරන බව ලෝක ආහාර වැඩසටහන (WFP) විසින් අගෝස්තු සඳහා වන තත්ව වාර්තාවක් පවසයි.",
        "“WFP සහ FAO හි භෝග සහ ආහාර සුරක්ෂිතතා තක්සේරු මෙහෙයුම මත පදනම්ව මිලියන 6.3 ක් දක්වා ජනතාව ආහාර අනාරක්ෂිත ය. හදිසි මැදිහත්වීමකින් තොරව මෙම සංඛ්‍යා තව දුරටත් ඉහළ යා හැකිය, ”ප්‍රකාශයේ සඳහන් වේ.",
        "WFP හි ආර්ථික අර්බුද ප්‍රතිචාරය ප්‍රධාන ක්‍රියාකාරකම් තුනක් හරහා මුළු මිලියන 3.4 ක ජනතාවක් වෙත ළඟා වීමට ඉලක්ක කරයි:  මුදල් හෝ ද්‍රව්‍ය හරහා කොන්දේසි විරහිත ආහාර ආධාර, පාසල් ආහාර සහ පෝෂණ සහාය.",
        "අගෝස්තු මාසය සඳහා ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ උද්ධමනය සියයට 64.3 දක්වා වේගවත් වූ අතර උද්ධමනය ඉක්මවීමට තුඩු දුන් අතිරික්ත මුදල් මුද්‍රණයෙන් පසු ආහාර මිල ගණන් සියයට 93.7 කින් ඉහළ ගොස් ඇත.",
        "මාස තුනක කාලයක් සඳහා ළමුන් මිලියනයකට පාසල් ආහාර වේල සඳහා සහල් මෙට්‍රික් ටොන් 1,475 ක් සහ යකඩ සවි කළ සහල් මෙට්‍රික් ටොන් 755 ක් WFP විසින් සුරක්ෂිත කර ඇත.",
        "අගෝස්තු සහ 2022 නොවැම්බර් සඳහා WFP සතුව දැනට නල මාර්ගයේ ආහාර මෙට්‍රික් ටොන් 24,440 ක් ඇති අතර, දැනටමත් එළවළු තෙල් මෙට්‍රික් ටොන් 79 ක් ගබඩා කර ඇති අතර සහල්, යකඩ ශක්තිමත් කළ සහල්, එළවළු තෙල් සහ කහ බෙදුණු කඩල ඇතුළු මෙට්‍රික් ටොන් 2,075 ක් ප්‍රවාහනයේ පවතී.",
        "ප්‍රකාශයට අනුව, WFP ඔස්ට්‍රේලියාව, ඉතාලිය, ජපානය, නවසීලන්තය, නෝර්වේ සහ ස්විට්සර්ලන්තය යන රජයන්ගෙන් මෙන්ම එක්සත් ජාතීන්ගේ මධ්‍යම හදිසි ප්‍රතිචාර අරමුදල, පුද්ගලික අංශයේ හවුල්කරුවන් සහ බහුපාර්ශ්වික ආධාරකරුවන්ගෙන් ඇමරිකානු ඩොලර් මිලියන 21.35ක් ලබාගෙන ඇත. ඩොලර් මිලියන 63 ක් සඳහා එහි හදිසි අභියාචනයෙන් සියයට 34 ක් නියෝජනය කරයි.",
        "වතු, නාගරික සහ ග්‍රාමීය පසුබිම් හරහා පළාත් නවයම ආවරණය වන පරිදි මාසික දුරකථන සමීක්ෂණ පවත්වනු ලැබේ. සමීක්ෂණ මගින් ගෘහස්ථ ආහාර සුරක්ෂිතතාව, පෝෂණය, ආහාර සඳහා ප්‍රවේශය, වෙළඳපල, ජීවනෝපාය සහ ණය පිළිබඳ දත්ත රැස් කරන බව එම ප්‍රකාශයේ සඳහන් වේ.",
        "මේ අතර, කෘෂිකර්ම අමාත්‍ය මහින්ද අමරවීර මේ සතියේ මාධ්‍යවේදීන් අමතමින් කියා සිටියේ දෙසැම්බර් මාසයේදී ශ්‍රී ලංකාවට සුළු සහල් හිඟයක් ඇති විය හැකි බවත් එය පාලනය වනු ඇති බවයි.",
        "කෙසේ වෙතත්, WFP ප්‍රකාශය පවසන්නේ, 2022 ඔක්තෝම්බර් සහ 2023 පෙබරවාරි අතර, රටේ ආහාර හිඟය පියවා ගැනීම සඳහා ප්‍රමාණවත් තරම් සහල් සහ අනෙකුත් ආහාර නිෂ්පාදන ආනයනය කිරීමට නොහැකි වුවහොත්, එළඹෙන සිහින් සමය තුළ ආහාර සහ පෝෂණ සුරක්ෂිතතාව තවදුරටත් පිරිහීමට අපේක්ෂා කරන බවයි. (කොළඹ/සැප්.02/2022)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "දක්වා",
          "label": "QUANTITY"
        },
        {
          "text": "මිලියන 6.3 කි",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "WFP",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මිලියන 6.3 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "මිලියන 6.7 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "අගෝස්තු",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ලෝක ආහාර වැඩසටහන",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "WFP",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "මිලියන 6.3 දක්වා",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "WFP",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "FAO",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "බෝග සහ ආහාර සුරක්ෂිතතා තක්සේරු මෙහෙයුම",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "WFP",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "මිලියන 3.4 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "තුන්",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "අගෝස්තු මාසය",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "සියයට 64.3 කි",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "සියයට 93.7 කි",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "WFP",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "මෙට්‍රික් ටොන් 1,475 කි",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "මෙට්‍රික් ටොන් 755 කි",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "මිලියන 1 ක්",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "මාස තුනක කාලයක්",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "අගෝස්තු",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "2022 නොවැම්බර්",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "WFP",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "මෙට්‍රික් ටොන් 24,440 කි",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "මෙට්‍රික් ටොන් 79 කි",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "මෙට්‍රික් ටොන් 2,075 කි",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "WFP",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඩොලර් මිලියන 21.35 කි",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඕස්ට්රේලියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉතාලිය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජපානය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "නවසීලන්තය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "නෝර්වේ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ස්විට්සර්ලන්තය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "එක්සත් ජාතීන්ගේ මධ්‍යම හදිසි ප්‍රතිචාර අරමුදල",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "සියයට 34 කි",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඩොලර් මිලියන 63 කි",
            "label": "MONEY"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "මාසික",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "නවය",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "කෘෂිකර්ම",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "මහින්ද අමරවීර",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "මෙම සතිය",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "දෙසැම්බර්",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "WFP",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "එළඹෙන සිහින් සමය",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "2022 ඔක්තෝබර් අතර",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "2023 පෙබරවාරි",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "කොළඹ/සැප්.02/2022",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "பணப்பற்றாக்குறை உள்ள இலங்கையில் 6.3 மில்லியன் மக்கள் உணவுப் பாதுகாப்பின்மையை எதிர்கொள்கின்றனர்: WFP",
      "author": "நெஷெல்லா பெரேரா",
      "body_lines": [
        "ECONOMYNEXT - இலங்கை சுதந்திரத்திற்குப் பின்னர் மிக மோசமான பொருளாதார நெருக்கடியை எதிர்கொண்டுள்ள நிலையில், 6.3 மில்லியன் மக்கள் உணவுப் பாதுகாப்பின்றி உள்ளனர் மற்றும் 6.7 மில்லியன் மக்கள் போதுமான உணவுகளை உட்கொள்வதில்லை என உலக உணவுத் திட்டத்தின் (WFP) ஆகஸ்ட் மாதத்திற்கான சூழ்நிலை அறிக்கை தெரிவித்துள்ளது.",
        "“WFP மற்றும் FAO இன் பயிர் மற்றும் உணவுப் பாதுகாப்பு மதிப்பீட்டுத் திட்டத்தின் அடிப்படையில் 6.3 மில்லியன் மக்கள் உணவுப் பாதுகாப்பற்ற நிலையில் உள்ளனர். இந்த எண்கள் அவசரத் தலையீடு இல்லாமல் இன்னும் கூடும்,” என்று அந்த அறிக்கை கூறியது.",
        "WFP இன் பொருளாதார நெருக்கடிக்கான பதில் மூன்று முக்கிய நடவடிக்கைகளில் மொத்தம் 3.4 மில்லியன் மக்களைச் சென்றடைவதை நோக்கமாகக் கொண்டுள்ளது:  நிபந்தனையற்ற உணவு உதவி பணம் அல்லது பொருள், பள்ளி உணவு மற்றும் ஊட்டச்சத்து ஆதரவு.",
        "ஆகஸ்ட் மாதத்திற்கான இலங்கையின் பணவீக்கம் 64.3 சதவீதமாக அதிகரித்தது மற்றும் பணவீக்கத்தை மீறுவதற்கு வழிவகுத்த அதிகப்படியான பணத்தை அச்சடித்ததன் பின்னர் உணவுப் பொருட்களின் விலைகள் 93.7 சதவீதத்தால் அதிகரித்துள்ளன.",
        "WFP ஆனது 1,475 மெட்ரிக் டன் அரிசி மற்றும் 755 மெட்ரிக் டன் இரும்புச் செறிவூட்டப்பட்ட அரிசியை 1 மில்லியன் குழந்தைகளுக்கு மூன்று மாத காலத்திற்கு பள்ளி உணவுடன் வழங்குவதற்குப் பாதுகாத்துள்ளது.",
        "ஆகஸ்ட் மற்றும் நவம்பர் 2022 இல் WFP ஆனது தற்போது 24,440 மெட்ரிக் டன் உணவுகள் பைப்லைனில் உள்ளது, 79 மெட்ரிக் டன் தாவர எண்ணெய் ஏற்கனவே சேமிப்பில் உள்ளது மற்றும் 2,075 மெட்ரிக் டன்கள் போக்குவரத்தில் உள்ளது, இதில் அரிசி, இரும்புச் செறிவூட்டப்பட்ட அரிசி, தாவர எண்ணெய் மற்றும் மஞ்சள் பிளவு பட்டாணி ஆகியவை அடங்கும்.",
        "அறிக்கையின்படி, WFP ஆஸ்திரேலியா, இத்தாலி, ஜப்பான், நியூசிலாந்து, நார்வே மற்றும் சுவிட்சர்லாந்து அரசாங்கங்களிடமிருந்து 21.35 மில்லியன் அமெரிக்க டாலர்களைப் பெற்றுள்ளது. 63 மில்லியன் டாலர்களுக்கான அதன் அவசர முறையீட்டில் 34 சதவீதத்தை பிரதிபலிக்கிறது.",
        "எஸ்டேட், நகர்ப்புற மற்றும் கிராமப்புற அமைப்புகளில் ஒன்பது மாகாணங்களையும் உள்ளடக்கிய மாதாந்திர தொலைபேசி ஆய்வுகள் நடத்தப்படுகின்றன. வீட்டு உணவு பாதுகாப்பு, ஊட்டச்சத்து, உணவுக்கான அணுகல், சந்தைகள், வாழ்வாதாரம் மற்றும் கடன் பற்றிய தரவுகளை இந்த ஆய்வுகள் சேகரிக்கின்றன என்று அந்த அறிக்கையில் கூறப்பட்டுள்ளது.",
        "இதற்கிடையில், விவசாய அமைச்சர் மஹிந்த அமரவீர இந்த வாரம் செய்தியாளர்களிடம் கூறுகையில், டிசம்பரில் இலங்கையில் ஒரு சிறிய அரிசி தட்டுப்பாடு ஏற்படக்கூடும், அது கட்டுப்படுத்தப்படும்.",
        "எவ்வாறாயினும், அக்டோபர் 2022 மற்றும் பிப்ரவரி 2023 க்கு இடையில், நாட்டின் உணவுப் பற்றாக்குறையை ஈடுகட்ட போதுமான அளவு அரிசி மற்றும் பிற உணவுப் பொருட்களை இறக்குமதி செய்ய முடியாவிட்டால், உணவு மற்றும் ஊட்டச்சத்து பாதுகாப்பு வரவிருக்கும் மெலிந்த பருவத்தில் மேலும் மோசமடையும் என்று WFP அறிக்கை கூறியது. (கொழும்பு/செப்02/2022)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "அது வரை",
          "label": "QUANTITY"
        },
        {
          "text": "6.3 மில்லியன்",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "இலங்கை",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "WFP",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "6.3 மில்லியன்",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "6.7 மில்லியன்",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆகஸ்ட்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "உலக உணவு திட்டம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "WFP",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "6.3 மில்லியன் வரை",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "WFP",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "FAO",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "பயிர் மற்றும் உணவு பாதுகாப்பு மதிப்பீட்டு பணி",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "WFP",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "3.4 மில்லியன்",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "மூன்று",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆகஸ்ட் மாதம்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "64.3 சதவீதம்",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "93.7 சதவீதம்",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "WFP",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "1,475 மெட்ரிக் டன்",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "755 மெட்ரிக் டன்",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "1 மில்லியன்",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "மூன்று மாத இடைவெளி",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஆகஸ்ட்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "நவம்பர் 2022",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "WFP",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "24,440 மெட்ரிக் டன்",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "79 மெட்ரிக் டன்",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "2,075 மெட்ரிக் டன்",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "WFP",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "21.35 மில்லியன் அமெரிக்க டாலர்கள்",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆஸ்திரேலியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இத்தாலி",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜப்பான்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "நியூசிலாந்து",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "நார்வே",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சுவிட்சர்லாந்து",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "UN மத்திய அவசரகால பதில் நிதியம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "34 சதவீதம்",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "63 மில்லியன் டாலர்கள்",
            "label": "MONEY"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "மாதாந்திர",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஒன்பது",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "வேளாண்மை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "மஹிந்த அமரவீர",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்த வாரம்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "டிசம்பர்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "WFP",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "வரவிருக்கும் ஒல்லியான பருவம்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "அக்டோபர் 2022 க்கு இடையில்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "பிப்ரவரி 2023",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "கொழும்பு/செப்02/2022",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}