{
  "newspaper_id": "ada-lk",
  "url": "https://www.ada.lk/breaking_news/අපි-ඩලස්ව-ඉදිරිපත්-කළා/11-395596",
  "time_ut": 1658322303,
  "original_lang": "si",
  "original_title": "අපි ඩලස්ව ඉදිරිපත් කළා",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "We presented Dallas",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "Former Prime Minister Mahinda Rajapaksa said that Mr. Dallas Alahapperuma also submitted for the election of a President from the Parliament and that the goal face struggle should end now. He said this while speaking to the media after the parliamentary session.",
        "\"We are waiting to see how it will turn out. No matter what government comes, we will serve the people of the country. (Regarding the replacement of the government) the party has not yet taken a decision.",
        "I work according to the decisions taken by our party. We presented Dallas. We voted. So lost. Someone wins. Winners win. Losers lost. (Golfface Struggle) Now it's enough.\""
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Dallas",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Mahinda Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Dallas Alahapperuma",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "Dallas",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Golfface Struggle",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "අපි ඩලස්ව ඉදිරිපත් කළා",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "පාර්ලිමේන්තුවෙන් ජනපතිවරයෙක් තෝරා පත්කර ගැනීම වෙනුවෙන් වූ ඡන්ද විමසීම සඳහා ඩලස් අලහප්පෙරුම මහතාද ඉදිරිපත් කළ බවත් ගෝල් ෆේස් අරගලය දැන් නිමාවිය යුතු බවත් හිටපු අගමැති මහින්ද රාජපක්ෂ මහතා පැවැසීය. පාර්ලිමේන්තු සැසිවාරයෙන් අනතුරුව මාධ්‍ය වෙත අදහස් දක්වමින් ඔහු මේ බව පැවැසිය.",
        "\"අපි බලාගෙන ඉන්නවා කොහොමද වෙන්නේ කියලා. මොන ආණ්ඩුව ආවත් රටේ ජනතාවට එපැයි සේවය කරන්න. (ආණ්ඩුව  පිහටුවීම සම්බන්ධයෙන්) තවමත් පක්ෂයෙන් තීරණයක් අරගෙන නෑ.",
        "අපේ පක්ෂය ගන්න තීන්දු අනුව තමයි මම වැඩ කරන්නේ. අපි ඩලස්ව ඉදිරිපත් කළා. අපි ඡන්දේ දුන්නා. පැරදුණා ඉතින්. කවුරු හරි දිනන් ඒපැයි. දිනන අය දින්නා. පැරදුන අය පැරදුනා. (ගෝල්ෆේස් අරගලය) දැන් ඉතින් ඒ්ක ඇති කියලයි කියන්නේ.\""
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ඩලස්",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "මහින්ද රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඩලස් අලහප්පෙරුම",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "ඩලස්",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගෝල්ෆේස් අරගලය",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "நாங்கள் டல்லாஸை வழங்கினோம்",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "திரு டலஸ் அழகப்பெரும அவர்களும் பாராளுமன்றத்தில் இருந்து ஜனாதிபதியை தெரிவு செய்வதற்கு சமர்ப்பணம் செய்ததாகவும் இலக்குப் போராட்டம் இப்போதே முடிவுக்கு வர வேண்டும் எனவும் முன்னாள் பிரதமர் மஹிந்த ராஜபக்ஷ தெரிவித்தார். நாடாளுமன்ற அமர்வின் பின்னர் ஊடகங்களுக்கு கருத்து தெரிவிக்கும் போதே அவர் இதனை கூறியுள்ளார்.",
        "“எப்படி அமையும் என்று காத்திருக்கிறோம்.எந்த அரசாங்கம் வந்தாலும் நாட்டு மக்களுக்கு சேவை செய்வோம்.(அரசாங்கத்தை மாற்றுவது தொடர்பாக) கட்சி இன்னும் முடிவு எடுக்கவில்லை.",
        "கட்சி எடுக்கும் முடிவுகளின்படி செயல்படுகிறேன். நாங்கள் டல்லாஸை வழங்கினோம். வாக்களித்தோம். அதனால் இழந்தேன். யாரோ வெற்றி பெறுகிறார்கள். வெற்றியாளர்கள் வெற்றி. தோற்றவர்கள் இழந்தனர். (Golfface Struggle) இப்போது அது போதும்.\""
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "டல்லாஸ்",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "மஹிந்த ராஜபக்ஷ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "டலஸ் அழகப்பெரும",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "டல்லாஸ்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "கோல்ஃபேஸ் போராட்டம்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}