{
  "newspaper_id": "lankadeepa-lk",
  "url": "https://www.lankadeepa.lk/latest_news/අගමැති-රනිල්-ඉල්ලා-අස්විය-යුතුයි:-පක්ෂ-නායකයෝ-කියති/1-616373",
  "time_ut": 1657722420,
  "original_lang": "si",
  "original_title": "අගමැති රනිල් ඉල්ලා අස්විය යුතුයි: පක්ෂ නායකයෝ කියති",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "PM Ranil should resign: Party leaders say",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "It is said from parliamentary sources that the majority of party leaders have indicated to the speaker at the parliamentary affairs committee meeting that Mr. Ranil Wickramasinghe should resign from his position immediately in order to resolve the crisis in the country.",
        "The party leaders have also stated that the Speaker should be appointed as the Acting President after handing over the letter of resignation of the President.",
        "The Committee on Parliamentary Affairs met today (13) afternoon at the Parliament complex under the chairmanship of Speaker Mahinda Yapa Abeywardena.",
        "The Speaker, Mr. Mahinda Yapa Abeywardena, who has commented here, has stated that after the President has submitted his resignation letter, Parliament will be convened and necessary measures will be taken to appoint a new President.",
        "The Chief of Defense Staff General Shavendra Silva, the three armed forces commanders and the Inspector General of Police also participated in this meeting.",
        "It was also discussed about the strugglers entering different places. It has been learned that the commanders of the three armed forces have been asked about how to control the militants and the party leaders have requested the commanders of the three armed forces to never use live ammunition for that purpose.",
        "No specific decisions were taken in this meeting and the Committee on Parliamentary Affairs has decided to meet again tomorrow (14) to further discuss the current situation."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Ranil",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickramasinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "The Committee on Parliamentary Affairs",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "13) afternoon",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Mahinda Yapa Abeywardena",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Mahinda Yapa Abeywardena",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Shavendra Silva",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "three",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Inspector General of Police",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "three",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "three",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the Committee on Parliamentary Affairs",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "tomorrow",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "අගමැති රනිල් ඉල්ලා අස්විය යුතුයි: පක්ෂ නායකයෝ කියති",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "රටේ මතුවී අර්බුදය විසඳා ගැනීමට නම් රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතා සිය ධූරයෙන් වහාම  ඉල්ලා අස්විය යුතු බව පක්ෂ නායකයන් බහුතරයක් පාර්ලිමේන්තු කටයුතු පිළිබඳ කාරක සභා රැස්වීමේදී කතානායකවරයාට පෙන්වාදී ඇතැයි පාර්ලිමේන්තු ආරංචි මාර්ග වලින් පැවසේ.",
        "ජනාධිපතිවරයා ඉල්ලා අස්වීමේ අස්වීමේ ලිපිය බාර දීමෙන් පසු  කතානායකවරයා  වැඩබලන ජනාධිපතිවරයා ලෙස පත් විය යුතු බවද   පක්ෂ නායකයන් ප්‍රකාශ කර ඇත.",
        "පාර්ලිමේන්තු කටයුතු පිළිබඳ කාරක සභාව කතානායක මහින්ද යාපා අබේවර්ධන මහතාගේ ප්‍රධානත්වයෙන් පාර්ලිමේන්තු සංකීර්ණයේදී අද (13) පස්වරුවේ රැස් විය.",
        "මෙහිදී අදහස් දක්වා ඇති කතානායක මහින්ද යාපා අබේවර්ධන මහතා ප්‍රකාශ කර ඇත්තේ ජනාධිපතිවරයා සිය ඉල්ලා අස්වීමේ ලිපිය බාර දුන් පසුව  පාර්ලිමේන්තුව කැඳවා අභිනව ජනාධිපතිවරයෙකු පත්කරගැනීම සඳහා අවශ්‍ය ක්‍රියාමාර්ග ගන්නා බවයි.",
        "මෙම රැස්වීමට  ආරක්ෂක මාණ්ඩලික ප්‍රධානී ජෙනරාල් ශවේන්ද්‍ර සිල්වා මහතා අද ත්‍රිවිධ හමුදාපතිවරු සහ පොලිස්පතිවරයාද සහභාගි වූහ.",
        "අරගලකරුවන් විවිධ ස්ථානවලට ඇතුළු වීම සම්බන්ධයෙන්ද මෙහිදී සාකච්ඡා කෙරිණ. අරගලකරුවන් පාලනය කළ යුතු ආකාරය සම්බන්ධයෙන් ත්‍රිවිධ හමුදාපතිවරුන් මෙහිදී විමසා ඇති අතර ඒ සඳහා   කිසි විටෙකත් ජීව උණ්ඩ යොදා නොගන්නා ලෙස මෙහිදී පක්ෂ නායකයන් ත්‍රිවිධ හමුදාපතිවරුන්ගෙන් ඉල්ලීමක් කර ඇතැයි  දැනගන්නට ඇත.",
        "මෙම රැස්වීමේදී විශේෂිත තීන්දු කිසිවක් ගෙන නොතිබූ අතර  පවතින තත්වය   සම්බන්ධයෙන් තවදුරටත් සාකච්ඡා කිරීම සඳහා පාර්ලිමේන්තු කටයුතු පිළිබඳ කාරක සභාව හෙට (14) දිනයේ නැවත රැස්වීමටද එහිදී තීරණය කර ඇත."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "රනිල්",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තු කටයුතු පිළිබඳ කාරක සභාව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "13) සවස",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "මහින්ද යාපා අබේවර්ධන",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "මහින්ද යාපා අබේවර්ධන",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශවේන්ද්‍ර සිල්වා",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "තුන්",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "පොලිස්පති",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "තුන්",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "තුන්",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තු කටයුතු පිළිබඳ කාරක සභාව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "හෙට",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "பிரதமர் ரணில் பதவி விலக வேண்டும்: கட்சித் தலைவர்கள் கருத்து",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "நாட்டில் ஏற்பட்டுள்ள நெருக்கடிக்கு தீர்வாக ரணில் விக்ரமசிங்க உடனடியாக தனது பதவியை இராஜினாமா செய்ய வேண்டும் என பெரும்பான்மை கட்சித் தலைவர்கள் நாடாளுமன்ற விவகாரக் குழுக் கூட்டத்தில் சபாநாயகரிடம் சுட்டிக்காட்டியுள்ளதாக நாடாளுமன்றத் தகவல்கள் தெரிவிக்கின்றன.",
        "ஜனாதிபதியின் இராஜினாமா கடிதத்தை கையளித்ததன் பின்னர் சபாநாயகரை பதில் ஜனாதிபதியாக நியமிக்க வேண்டும் எனவும் கட்சித் தலைவர்கள் குறிப்பிட்டுள்ளனர்.",
        "பாராளுமன்ற விவகாரங்களுக்கான குழு இன்று (13) பிற்பகல் சபாநாயகர் மஹிந்த யாப்பா அபேவர்தன தலைமையில் பாராளுமன்ற கட்டடத்தொகுதியில் கூடியது.",
        "இங்கு கருத்து தெரிவித்த சபாநாயகர் மஹிந்த யாப்பா அபேவர்தன, ஜனாதிபதி தனது இராஜினாமா கடிதத்தை சமர்ப்பித்த பின்னர் பாராளுமன்றத்தை கூட்டி புதிய ஜனாதிபதியை நியமிப்பதற்கு தேவையான நடவடிக்கைகள் எடுக்கப்படும் என குறிப்பிட்டுள்ளார்.",
        "இந்த சந்திப்பில் பாதுகாப்பு படைகளின் பிரதானி ஜெனரல் சவேந்திர சில்வா, முப்படை தளபதிகள் மற்றும் பொலிஸ் மா அதிபர் ஆகியோர் கலந்துகொண்டனர்.",
        "பல்வேறு இடங்களில் போராட்டக்காரர்கள் நுழைவது குறித்தும் விவாதிக்கப்பட்டது. தீவிரவாதிகளை எவ்வாறு கட்டுப்படுத்துவது என்பது குறித்து முப்படைகளின் தளபதிகளிடம் கேட்கப்பட்டதாகவும், அதற்காக உயிருள்ள வெடிமருந்துகளை ஒருபோதும் பயன்படுத்த வேண்டாம் என்றும் கட்சித் தலைவர்கள் முப்படைகளின் தளபதிகளிடம் கோரிக்கை விடுத்துள்ளதாகவும் தெரியவந்துள்ளது.",
        "இந்தக் கூட்டத்தில் குறிப்பிட்ட முடிவுகள் எதுவும் எடுக்கப்படவில்லை என்பதுடன், தற்போதைய நிலவரங்கள் குறித்து விவாதிக்க நாடாளுமன்ற விவகாரங்களுக்கான குழு நாளை (14) மீண்டும் கூடுவதற்குத் தீர்மானித்துள்ளது."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ரணில்",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "நாடாளுமன்ற விவகாரங்களுக்கான குழு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "13) பிற்பகல்",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "மஹிந்த யாப்பா அபேவர்தன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "மஹிந்த யாப்பா அபேவர்தன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "சவேந்திர சில்வா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "மூன்று",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்ஸ்பெக்டர் ஜெனரல் ஆஃப் போலீஸ்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "மூன்று",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "மூன்று",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்ற விவகாரங்களுக்கான குழு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "நாளை",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}