{
  "newspaper_id": "news-first-lk",
  "url": "https://www.newsfirst.lk/2022/09/05/gotabaya-has-no-place-in-politics-again-says-welgama/",
  "time_ut": 1662390360,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Gotabaya has no place in politics again, says Welgama",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Gotabaya has no place in politics again, says Welgama",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); MP Kumara Welgama, the Leader of the Nawa Lanka Freedom Party has cautioned Former President Gotabaya Rajapaksa not to re-enter Sri Lankan Politics.",
        "\"Some claim he will return as the Prime Minister or an MP,\" said Welgama adding that the wise thing for Rajapaksa to do is to stay at home, and engage in meritorious deeds with his wife.",
        "Kumara Welgama said that he warned Gotabaya Rajapaksa that many from his own camp were not pleased with him becoming the President with a mandate of 6.9 million people.",
        "UNHRC: Sri Lanka will not accept any external mechanism – Foreign Minister",
        "(VIDEO) School boy trapped in storm drain in Kurunegala, dies"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Gotabaya",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "Welgama",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "News 1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kumara Welgama",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Nawa Lanka Freedom Party",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Gotabaya Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lankan Politics",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Welgama",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Kumara Welgama",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Gotabaya Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "6.9 million",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Kurunegala",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "ගෝඨාභයට යළි දේශපාලනයේ ඉඩක් නොමැති බව වෙල්ගම පවසයි",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); හිටපු ජනාධිපති ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ මහතාට යළි ශ්‍රී ලංකා දේශපාලනයට නොපැමිණෙන ලෙස නව ලංකා නිදහස් පක්ෂයේ නායක පාර්ලිමේන්තු මන්ත්‍රී කුමාර වෙල්ගම මහතා අවවාද කරයි.",
        "“සමහරු කියනවා එතුමා ආයෙත් අගමැති හෝ මන්ත්‍රී කෙනෙක් වෙයි කියලා,” වෙල්ගම කීවේ රාජපක්‍ෂ කළ යුතු නැණවත්ම දේ ගෙදරට වී බිරිඳ සමඟ පින්කම් කිරීම බවයි.",
        "ලක්ෂ 69ක ජනවරමකින් ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ මහතා ජනාධිපති වීම ගැන ඔහුගේම කඳවුරේම බොහෝ දෙනෙක් සතුටු නොවන බවට තමන් ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ මහතාට අවවාද කළ බවද කුමාර වෙල්ගම මහතා පැවසීය.",
        "UNHRC: ශ්‍රී ලංකාව කිසිදු බාහිර යාන්ත්‍රණයක් පිළිගන්නේ නැහැ - විදේශ ඇමති",
        "(VIDEO) කුරුණෑගලදී වැසි කාණුවේ සිරවී පාසල් සිසුවා මරුට"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ගෝඨාභය",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "වෙල්ගම",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "News 1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "කුමාර වෙල්ගම",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "නව ලංකා නිදහස් පක්ෂය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකා දේශපාලනය",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "වෙල්ගම",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "කුමාර වෙල්ගම",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "මිලියන 6.9 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "කුරුණෑගල",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "கோட்டாபயவுக்கு மீண்டும் அரசியலில் இடமில்லை என வெல்கம தெரிவித்துள்ளார்",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); முன்னாள் ஜனாதிபதி கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ச மீண்டும் இலங்கை அரசியலுக்கு வர வேண்டாம் என நவ லங்கா சுதந்திரக் கட்சியின் தலைவர் குமார வெல்கம எச்சரித்துள்ளார்.",
        "\"அவர் மீண்டும் பிரதமராகவோ அல்லது எம்.பி.யாகவோ வருவார் என்று சிலர் கூறுகின்றனர்,\" என்று கூறிய வெல்கம, ராஜபக்ச செய்ய வேண்டியது புத்திசாலித்தனமான விஷயம், வீட்டில் தங்கி மனைவியுடன் புண்ணிய செயல்களில் ஈடுபடுவதுதான்.",
        "6.9 மில்லியன் மக்களின் ஆணையைப் பெற்று ஜனாதிபதியாக பதவியேற்பதில் அவரது சொந்த முகாமைச் சேர்ந்த பலர் மகிழ்ச்சியடையவில்லை என கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்சவை எச்சரித்ததாக குமார வெல்கம தெரிவித்துள்ளார்.",
        "UNHRC: இலங்கை எந்தவொரு வெளிப்புற பொறிமுறையையும் ஏற்றுக்கொள்ளாது – வெளிவிவகார அமைச்சர்",
        "(வீடியோ) குருநாகலில் புயல் வடிகாலில் சிக்கிய பாடசாலை மாணவன் மரணம்"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "கோட்டாபய",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "வெல்கம",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "News 1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "குமார வெல்கம",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "நவ லங்கா சுதந்திரக் கட்சி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை அரசியல்",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "வெல்கம",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ராஜபக்சே",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "குமார வெல்கம",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "6.9 மில்லியன்",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "குருநாகல்",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}