{
  "newspaper_id": "ada-lk",
  "url": "https://www.ada.lk/breaking_news/ජී-එල්-ඉවත්කරන්නැයි-බැසිල්ට-බලපෑම්/11-396295",
  "time_ut": 1660539336,
  "original_lang": "si",
  "original_title": "ජී.එල් ඉවත්කරන්නැයි බැසිල්ට බලපෑම්",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Pressure on Basil to remove G.L",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "Chairman of Sri Lanka Podujana Peramuna, Professor G.L. It is reported that a group of non-members of parliament are putting pressure on the national organizer of the party, Mr. Basil Rajapaksa, to remove Mr. Peiris from that position.",
        "Accordingly, it is stated that it includes a secretary of the party, a chairman of a major government institution related to the environment and a governor.",
        "In addition, it is also said that these three persons are recently 'engaged in a race' to get the vacant position of MP if Mr. Dhammika Perera resigns.",
        "In the meantime, a spokesperson of the Sri Lanka Podujana Peramuna mentioned that Prof. G.L. It can be believed that the removal of Mr. Peiris from the party presidency will happen in the future. However, he said that it is not possible to say whether the removal will be done at the upcoming party convention or on another date.",
        "The General Secretary of the Sri Lanka Podujana Peramuna, Member of Parliament Mr. Sagara Kariyawasam emphasized in a press conference of the party that the future decision regarding the positions of the Sri Lanka Podujana Peramuna will be taken by the party's executive members.",
        "He emphasized this by the chairman of the party, Prof. G.L. During the questioning by the journalists whether Mr. Peiris intends to take disciplinary action as a party for holding a press conference separately with Mr. Dallas Alahapperuma and the group."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "G.L",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Podujana Peramuna",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "G.L.",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Basil Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Peiris",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "three",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Dhammika Perera",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "Podujana Peramuna",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "G.L.",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Peiris",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the upcoming party convention or on",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "Podujana Peramuna",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sagara Kariyawasam",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "Podujana Peramuna",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "G.L.",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Peiris",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Dallas Alahapperuma",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "ජී.එල් ඉවත්කරන්නැයි බැසිල්ට බලපෑම්",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකා පොදුජන පෙරමුණෙහි සභාපති, මහාචාර්ය ජී.එල්. පීරිස් මහතා එම තනතුරෙන් ඉවත් කරන ලෙසට පාර්ලිමේන්තු මන්ත්‍රීවරුන් නොවන පරිසක් මූලික වෙමින් එම පක්ෂයේ ජාතික සංවිධායක බැසිල් රාජපක්ෂ මහතාට බලපෑම් කරමින් සිටින බවට වාර්තා වේ.",
        "ඒ අනුව ඊට පක්ෂයේ ලේකම්වරයෙකු, පරිසරය හා සම්බන්ධ ප්‍රධාන රාජ්‍ය ආයතනයක සභාපතිවරයෙකු හා ආණ්ඩුකාරවරයෙකුද ඇතුළත් බව සඳහන්ය.",
        "මීට අමතරව මෙම පුද්ගලයන් තිදෙනා ධම්මික පෙරේරා මහතා පාර්ලිමේන්තු මන්ත්‍රී ධුරයෙන් ඉල්ලා අස්වුවහොත් ඉන් පුරප්පාඩු වන මන්ත්‍රී ධුරය ලබාගැනීමට පසුගියදා ‘තරගයක නිරතවූවන්’ වන බවද සඳහන් වේ.",
        "මේ අතර මේ පිළිබඳ ‘අද’ කළ විමසීමේදී ශ්‍රී ලංකා පොදුජන පෙරමුණෙහි ප්‍රකාශකයෙකු සඳහන් කර සිටියේ මහාචාර්ය ජී.එල්. පීරිස් මහතා පක්ෂ සභාපතිත්වයෙන් ඉවත් කිරීම ඉදිරියේදී සිදුවනු ඇති බවට විශ්වාස කළ හැකි බවයි. කෙසේ වුවද එම ඉවත් කිරීම එළඹෙන පක්ෂ සම්මේලනයේදී සිදු කරන්නේද නොඑසේනම් වෙනත් දිනයකද යන්න නිශ්චිතව ප්‍රකාශ කළ නොහැකි බව ඔහු පවසා සිටියේය.",
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකා පොදුජන පෙරමුණෙහි තනතුරු සම්බන්ධයෙන් වූ ඉදිරි තීරණය පක්ෂයේ විධායක සභිකයන් විසින් ගනු ඇතැයි එම පෙරමුණෙහි ප්‍රධාන ලේකම්, පාර්ලිමේන්තු මන්ත්‍රී සාගර කාරියවසම් මහතා පසුගියදා පැවැති පක්ෂයේ මාධ්‍ය හමුවකදී අවධාරණය කර සිටියේය.",
        "හෙතෙම මේ බව අවධාරණය කර සිටියේ පක්ෂයෙහි සභාපති, මහාචාර්ය ජී.එල්. පීරිස් මහතා ඩලස් අලහප්පෙරුම මහතා ඇතුළු කණ්ඩායම සමග වෙන්ව මාධ්‍ය හමුවක් පැවැත්වීම සම්බන්ධයෙන් පක්ෂයක් ලෙස විනය ක්‍රියාමාර්ග ගැනීමට අදහස් කරන්නේද යන්න පිළිබඳ මාධ්‍යවේදීන් විසින් එහිදී සිදු කරන ලද ප්‍රශ්න කිරීමේදීය."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ජී.එල්",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "පොදුජන පෙරමුණ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජී.එල්.",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "බැසිල් රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "පීරිස්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "තුන්",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ධම්මික පෙරේරා",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "පොදුජන පෙරමුණ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජී.එල්.",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "පීරිස්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "එළඹෙන පක්ෂ සම්මේලනය හෝ",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "පොදුජන පෙරමුණ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "සාගර කාරියවසම්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "පොදුජන පෙරමුණ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ජී.එල්.",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "පීරිස්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඩලස් අලහප්පෙරුම",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "ஜி.எல்.யை நீக்குமாறு பசிலுக்கு அழுத்தம்",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "ஸ்ரீலங்கா பொதுஜன பெரமுனவின் தலைவர் பேராசிரியர் ஜி.எல். பீரிஸை அந்தப் பதவியில் இருந்து நீக்குமாறு கட்சியின் தேசிய அமைப்பாளர் பசில் ராஜபக்ஷவுக்கு நாடாளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர்கள் அல்லாதவர்கள் குழுவொன்று அழுத்தம் கொடுத்து வருவதாகத் தெரிவிக்கப்படுகிறது.",
        "இதன்படி, கட்சியின் செயலாளர் ஒருவரும், சுற்றாடல் தொடர்பான பிரதான அரச நிறுவனமொன்றின் தலைவர் மற்றும் ஆளுநர் ஒருவரும் அடங்குவதாக தெரிவிக்கப்படுகிறது.",
        "மேலும், திரு.தம்மிக்க பெரேரா இராஜினாமா செய்தால் வெற்றிடமான எம்.பி. பதவியைப் பெறுவதற்காக இந்த மூவரும் அண்மையில் 'பந்தயத்தில்' ஈடுபட்டுள்ளதாகவும் கூறப்படுகிறது.",
        "இதேவேளை, ஸ்ரீலங்கா பொதுஜன பெரமுனவின் பேச்சாளர் ஒருவர், பேராசிரியர் ஜி.எல். கட்சித் தலைவர் பதவியில் இருந்து திரு.பீரிஸ் நீக்கப்படுவது எதிர்காலத்தில் நடக்கும் என நம்பலாம். எவ்வாறாயினும், எதிர்வரும் கட்சி மாநாட்டிலா அல்லது வேறு திகதியிலா இந்த நீக்கம் செய்யப்படுமா என்பதை கூற முடியாது எனவும் அவர் தெரிவித்துள்ளார்.",
        "ஸ்ரீலங்கா பொதுஜன பெரமுனவின் பதவிகள் தொடர்பில் கட்சியின் செயற்குழு உறுப்பினர்களே எதிர்கால தீர்மானம் எடுப்பார்கள் என ஸ்ரீலங்கா பொதுஜன பெரமுனவின் பொதுச் செயலாளர், நாடாளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர் திரு.சாகர காரியவசம் கட்சியின் செய்தியாளர் சந்திப்பில் வலியுறுத்தினார்.",
        "இதனை அவர் வலியுறுத்திய கட்சியின் தலைவர் பேராசிரியர் ஜீ.எல். டலஸ் அழகப்பெரும மற்றும் குழுவினருடன் தனித்தனியாக ஊடகவியலாளர் மாநாட்டை நடத்தியதற்காக கட்சி என்ற ரீதியில் ஒழுக்காற்று நடவடிக்கை எடுக்க திரு. பீரிஸ் உத்தேசித்துள்ளாரா என ஊடகவியலாளர்கள் வினவிய போது."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ஜி.எல்",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "பொதுஜன பெரமுன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜி.எல்.",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "பசில் ராஜபக்ஷ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "பீரிஸ்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "மூன்று",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "தம்மிக்க பெரேரா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "பொதுஜன பெரமுன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜி.எல்.",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "பீரிஸ்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "வரவிருக்கும் கட்சி மாநாடு அல்லது அன்று",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "பொதுஜன பெரமுன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "சாகர காரியவசம்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "பொதுஜன பெரமுன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஜி.எல்.",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "பீரிஸ்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "டலஸ் அழகப்பெரும",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}