{
  "newspaper_id": "news-first-lk",
  "url": "https://www.newsfirst.lk/2022/07/10/pm-will-not-violate-constitution-vajira/",
  "time_ut": 1657467360,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "PM will NOT violate constitution – Vajira",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "PM will NOT violate constitution – Vajira",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); The Chairman of the United National Party (UNP), Vajira Abeywardena says that there is no clause in the constitution that the Prime Minister should resign because the President does.",
        "The UNP Chairman Abeywardena reminded that there is a need for law in the country, and all actions should abide by the constitution.",
        "Stating that the Prime Minister cannot immediately resign because the President resigned, he added that there is no such clause in the constitution.",
        "Pointing out that breaking the law mentioned in the constitution is not possible, Abeywardena stated that the Prime Minister’s previous statement about his willingness to leave was misinterpreted by the media.",
        "The UNP Chairman also said that the Article 37 of the Constitution is written to create stability when there is instability in a country, it is further strengthened by articles 37/1 and 37/2.",
        "“Such clauses are used by Pakistan. They are used by Russia. Therefore it should be used in Sri Lanka too,” he mentioned.",
        "Abeywardena added that due to the above two sub-clauses, there is no impediment to continuing the Government despite the President’s pending resignation on 13th July.",
        "Sri Lankans have right to peacefully raise their voices – Blinken"
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "the United National Party",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "UNP",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Vajira Abeywardena",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "UNP",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Abeywardena",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "Abeywardena",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "UNP",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Article 37 of the Constitution",
            "label": "LAW"
          },
          {
            "text": "37/1",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "37/2",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Pakistan",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Russia",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Abeywardena",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "two",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "13th July",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lankans",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "අගමැති ව්‍යවස්ථාව කඩ කරන්නේ නැහැ - වජිර",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); ජනාධිපතිවරයා ඉල්ලා අස්වන නිසා අගමැතිවරයා ඉල්ලා අස්විය යුතු බවට ව්‍යවස්ථාවේ වගන්තියක් නොමැති බව එක්සත් ජාතික පක්ෂයේ (එජාප) සභාපති වජිර අබේවර්ධන මහතා පවසයි.",
        "රටට නීතියක් අවශ්‍ය බවත්, සියලු ක්‍රියාමාර්ග ආණ්ඩුක්‍රම ව්‍යවස්ථාවට අනුව සිදු විය යුතු බවත් එක්සත් ජාතික පක්ෂ සභාපති අබේවර්ධන මහතා සිහිපත් කළේය.",
        "ජනාධිපතිවරයා ඉල්ලා අස් වූ නිසා අගමැතිවරයාට වහාම ඉල්ලා අස්විය නොහැකි බව ප්‍රකාශ කළ ඔහු වැඩිදුරටත් කියා සිටියේ ව්‍යවස්ථාවේ එවැනි වගන්තියක් නොමැති බවයි.",
        "ආණ්ඩුක්‍රම ව්‍යවස්ථාවේ සඳහන් නීතිය කඩ කිරීම කිසිසේත්ම කළ නොහැකි බව පෙන්වා දුන් අබේවර්ධන කියා සිටියේ තමන් ඉවත්ව යාමට කැමැත්ත පළ කරන බවට අග්‍රාමාත්‍යවරයා කළ ප්‍රකාශය මාධ්‍ය විසින් වැරදි ලෙස අර්ථකථනය කර ඇති බවයි.",
        "ආණ්ඩුක්‍රම ව්‍යවස්ථාවේ 37 වැනි වගන්තිය ලියා ඇත්තේ රටක අස්ථාවර භාවයක් ඇති වූ විට ස්ථාවරත්වයක් ඇති කිරීමට බවත් එය 37/1 සහ 37/2 වගන්තිවලින් තවත් ශක්තිමත් වන බවත් එජාප සභාපතිවරයා පැවසීය.",
        "“එවැනි වගන්ති පාකිස්ථානය භාවිතා කරනවා. ඔවුන් රුසියාව විසින් භාවිතා කරනු ලැබේ. ඒ නිසා එය ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේත් භාවිත කළ යුතුයි.” ඔහු සඳහන් කළේය.",
        "ජුලි 13 වැනිදා ජනාධිපතිවරයා ඉල්ලා අස්වීමට නියමිතව තිබියදී ඉහත උප වගන්ති දෙක නිසා රජය පවත්වාගෙන යාමට බාධාවක් නොමැති බවද අබේවර්ධන මහතා පැවසීය.",
        "සාමකාමීව හඬ නැගීමට ශ්‍රී ලාංකිකයන්ට අයිතියක් ඇත - Blinken"
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "එක්සත් ජාතික පක්ෂය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "එජාප",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "වජිර අබේවර්ධන",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "එජාප",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "අබේවර්ධන ය",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "අබේවර්ධන ය",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "එජාප",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ආණ්ඩුක්‍රම ව්‍යවස්ථාවේ 37 වැනි වගන්තිය",
            "label": "LAW"
          },
          {
            "text": "37/1",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "37/2",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "පකිස්ථානය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "රුසියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "අබේවර්ධන ය",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "දෙක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජූලි 13",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලාංකිකයන්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "பிரதமர் அரசியலமைப்பை மீறமாட்டார் – வஜிர",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); ஜனாதிபதி பதவி விலகுவதால் பிரதமர் பதவி விலக வேண்டும் என அரசியலமைப்பில் கூறப்படவில்லை என ஐக்கிய தேசியக் கட்சியின் தலைவர் வஜிர அபேவர்தன தெரிவித்துள்ளார்.",
        "நாட்டில் சட்டத்தின் தேவை இருப்பதாகவும், அனைத்து நடவடிக்கைகளும் அரசியலமைப்பிற்கு உட்பட்டு நடக்க வேண்டும் என்றும் ஐக்கிய தேசியக் கட்சியின் தலைவர் அபேவர்தன நினைவுபடுத்தினார்.",
        "ஜனாதிபதி இராஜினாமா செய்ததால் பிரதமர் உடனடியாக பதவி விலக முடியாது என தெரிவித்த அவர், அரசியலமைப்பில் அவ்வாறான எந்த சரத்தும் இல்லை எனவும் குறிப்பிட்டுள்ளார்.",
        "அரசியலமைப்பில் குறிப்பிடப்பட்டுள்ள சட்டத்தை மீறுவது சாத்தியமில்லை என சுட்டிக்காட்டிய அபேவர்தன, பிரதமர் தாம் வெளியேறத் தயாராக இருப்பதாக முன்னர் தெரிவித்திருந்த கருத்து ஊடகங்களால் தவறாகப் புரிந்துகொள்ளப்பட்டதாகக் குறிப்பிட்டார்.",
        "அரசியலமைப்பின் 37வது சரத்து ஒரு நாட்டில் ஸ்திரத்தன்மை இல்லாத போது ஸ்திரத்தன்மையை உருவாக்குவதற்காக எழுதப்பட்டதாகவும், அது 37/1 மற்றும் 37/2 ஆகிய சரத்துக்களால் மேலும் வலுப்படுத்தப்படுவதாகவும் ஐக்கிய தேசியக் கட்சியின் தலைவர் தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "“அத்தகைய விதிகளை பாகிஸ்தான் பயன்படுத்துகிறது. அவை ரஷ்யாவால் பயன்படுத்தப்படுகின்றன. எனவே இது இலங்கையிலும் பயன்படுத்தப்பட வேண்டும்” என அவர் குறிப்பிட்டுள்ளார்.",
        "மேற்கூறிய இரண்டு உப சரத்துக்கள் காரணமாக, ஜூலை 13 ஆம் திகதி ஜனாதிபதி பதவி விலகுவதற்கு நிலுவையில் உள்ள போதிலும், அரசாங்கத்தை தொடர்வதில் எந்தத் தடையும் இல்லை என்றும் அபேவர்தன மேலும் தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "அமைதியான முறையில் குரல் எழுப்ப இலங்கையர்களுக்கு உரிமை உண்டு – பிளிங்கன்"
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ஐக்கிய தேசிய கட்சி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஐ.தே.க",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "வஜிர அபேவர்தன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஐ.தே.க",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "அபேவர்தன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "அபேவர்தன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஐ.தே.க",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "அரசியலமைப்பின் பிரிவு 37",
            "label": "LAW"
          },
          {
            "text": "37/1",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "37/2",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பாகிஸ்தான்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரஷ்யா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "அபேவர்தன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இரண்டு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜூலை 13",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கையர்கள்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}