{
  "newspaper_id": "lankadeepa-lk",
  "url": "https://www.lankadeepa.lk/news/මහින්දට-බැසිල්ට-28තෙක්-විදෙස්-ගමන්-තහනම්/101-616474",
  "time_ut": 1657885120,
  "original_lang": "si",
  "original_title": "මහින්දට-බැසිල්ට 28තෙක් විදෙස් ගමන් තහනම්",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Mahinda-Basil banned from traveling abroad until 28",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "The Supreme Court issued an interim order today (15) prohibiting former Prime Minister Mahinda Rajapaksa and former Finance Minister Basil Rajapaksa from traveling abroad until the 28th of this month without the permission of the Supreme Court.",
        "This interim order was issued when the petitions filed by social activist Chandra Jayaratne and other petitioners were called before a five-judge bench of the Supreme Court today (15).",
        "This motion was filed by Chief Justice Jayantha Jayasuriya, Bhuvaneka Aluvihare, Priyantha Jayawardena, Vijith Malalgoda and L. D. B. Dehideniya was considered before a panel of five judges.",
        "Former Central Bank Governor Professor W. D. Lakshman and former Secretary of the Ministry of Finance S. R. Mr. Atigala also promised before the court that they will not go abroad until the 27th of this month.",
        "Another respondent here, former Central Bank Governor Mr. Ajith Nivard Kabral also promised in the court that he will not go abroad without the permission of the Supreme Court.",
        "This motion has been filed by social activist Chandra Jayaratne and famous Sri Lankan swimmer Julian Bowling.",
        "The petitioners have filed these petitions before the Supreme Court asking for an investigation and action against those responsible for the country's economic crisis."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Mahinda-Basil",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "28",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "The Supreme Court",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "15",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Mahinda Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Finance",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Basil Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the 28th of this month",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Supreme Court",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Chandra Jayaratne",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "five",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Supreme Court",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "15",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Jayantha Jayasuriya",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Aluvihare",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Priyantha Jayawardena",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Malalgoda",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "L. D. B. Dehideniya",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "five",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Central Bank",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "W. D. Lakshman",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Ministry of Finance S. R.",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Atigala",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the 27th of this month",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Central Bank",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ajith Nivard Kabral",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Supreme Court",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Chandra Jayaratne",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lankan",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "Julian Bowling",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the Supreme Court",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "මහින්දට-බැසිල්ට 28තෙක් විදෙස් ගමන් තහනම්",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "හිටපු අග්‍රාමාත්‍ය මහින්ද රාජපක්ෂ, හිටපු මුදල් අමාත්‍ය බැසිල් රාජපක්ෂ යන මහත්වරු දෙදෙනාට ශ්‍රේෂ්ඨාධිකරණයේ අවසරයකින් තොරව මේ මස 28 වැනි දින තෙක් විදෙස් ගතවීම තහනම් කරමින් ශ්‍රේෂ්ඨාධිකරණය අතුරු නියෝගයක්  අද (15) නිකුත් කළේය.",
        "මෙම අතුරු නියෝගය නිකුත් කෙරුණේ සමාජ ක්‍රියාකාරිකයෙකු වන චන්ද්‍රා ජයරත්න ඇතුළු පෙත්සම්කරුවන් විසින් ගොනුකරනු ලැබ තිබූ පෙත්සම් ශේෂ්ඨාධිකරණ පංච පුද්ගල විනිසුරු මඩුල්ලක් හමුවේ අද  (15) කැඳවනු ලැබූ අවස්ථාවේදී ය.",
        "මෙම මෝසම අගවිනිසුරු ජයන්ත ජයසූරිය, බුවනෙක අලුවිහාරේ, ප්‍රියන්ත ජයවර්ධන, විජිත් මළල්ගොඩ සහ එල්. ඩී. බී. දෙහිදෙණිය යන මහත්වරුන්ගෙන් සමන්විත පංච පුද්ගල විනිසුරු මඩුල්ලක් හමුවේ සලකා බැලිණ.",
        "පෙත්සමේ වගඋත්තරකරුවන් වශයෙන් නම් කර සිටින හිටපු මහ බැංකු අධිපති මහාචාර්ය ඩබ්ලිව්. ඩී. ලක්ෂ්මන් සහ මුදල් අමාත්‍යාංශයේ හිටපු ලේකම් එස්. ආර්. ආටිගල යන මහත්වරුන් මෙම මස 27 වන දින තෙක් විදේශගත නොවන බවට ද අධිකරණය හමුවේ පොරොන්දු වූහ.",
        "මෙහි තවත් වගඋත්තරකරුවකු වන හිටපු මහ බැංකු අධිපති අජිත් නිවාඩ් කබ්රාල් මහතා ද ශ්‍රේෂ්ඨාධිකරණයේ අවසරයකින් තොරව විදෙස්ගත නොවන බවට අධිකරණයේ දී පොරොන්දු විය.",
        "මෙම මෝසම ගොනු කරනු ලැබ ඇත්තේ සමාජ ක්‍රියාකාරිකයකු වන චන්ද්‍රා ජයරත්න, ප්‍රසිද්ධ ශ්‍රී ලංකා පිහිනුම් ක්‍රීඩක ජුලියන් බෝලිං ඇතුළු තිදෙනකු විසිනි.",
        "රටේ ආර්ථික අර්බුදයට සම්බන්ධ වගකිවයුත්තන් සම්බන්ධයෙන් විමර්ශනයක් පවත්වා පියවර ගන්නා ලෙසට ඉල්ලා පෙත්සම්කරුවන් ශ්‍රේෂ්ඨාධිකරණය හමුවේ මෙම පෙත්සම් ගොනු කරනු ලැබ තිබේ."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "මහින්ද-බැසිල්",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "28",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රේෂ්ඨාධිකරණය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "15",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "මහින්ද රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "මූල්ය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "බැසිල් රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "මේ මස 28 වැනිදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රේෂ්ඨාධිකරණය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "චන්ද්‍රා ජයරත්න",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "පහ",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රේෂ්ඨාධිකරණය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "15",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ජයන්ත ජයසූරිය",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "අලුවිහාරේ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ප්‍රියන්ත ජයවර්ධන",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "මලල්ගොඩ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "එල්.ඩී.බී.දෙහිදෙණිය",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "පහ",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "මහ බැංකුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඩබ්ලිව් ඩී ලක්ෂ්මන්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "මුදල් අමාත්‍යාංශයේ එස්.ආර්.",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ආටිගල",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "මේ මස 27 වැනිදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "මහ බැංකුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "අජිත් නිවාඩ් කබ්රාල්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රේෂ්ඨාධිකරණය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "චන්ද්‍රා ජයරත්න",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලාංකික",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජූලියන් පන්දු යැවීම",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රේෂ්ඨාධිකරණය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "மஹிந்த-பசிலுக்கு எதிர்வரும் 28ஆம் திகதி வரை வெளிநாடு செல்ல தடை விதிக்கப்பட்டுள்ளது",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "முன்னாள் பிரதமர் மஹிந்த ராஜபக்ஷ மற்றும் முன்னாள் நிதியமைச்சர் பசில் ராஜபக்ஷ ஆகியோர் உச்ச நீதிமன்றத்தின் அனுமதியின்றி எதிர்வரும் 28 ஆம் திகதி வரை வெளிநாடு செல்வதற்கு தடை விதித்து உச்ச நீதிமன்றம் இன்று (15) இடைக்கால உத்தரவு பிறப்பித்துள்ளது.",
        "சமூக ஆர்வலர் சந்திரா ஜயரத்ன மற்றும் ஏனைய மனுதாரர்களால் தாக்கல் செய்யப்பட்ட மனுக்கள் இன்று (15) உச்ச நீதிமன்றத்தின் ஐவர் அடங்கிய நீதிபதிகள் குழாம் முன்னிலையில் விசாரணைக்கு எடுத்துக் கொள்ளப்பட்ட போதே இந்த இடைக்கால உத்தரவு பிறப்பிக்கப்பட்டுள்ளது.",
        "பிரதம நீதியரசர் ஜயந்த ஜயசூரிய, புவனேகா அலுவிஹாரே, பிரியந்த ஜயவர்தன, விஜித் மலல்கொட மற்றும் எல். டி. பி. ஐவர் அடங்கிய நீதிபதிகள் குழாம் முன்னிலையில் தெஹிதெனிய பரிசீலிக்கப்பட்டது.",
        "மத்திய வங்கியின் முன்னாள் ஆளுநர் பேராசிரியர் டபிள்யூ. டி. லக்ஷ்மன் மற்றும் நிதி அமைச்சின் முன்னாள் செயலாளர் எஸ். ஆர். இம்மாதம் 27ஆம் திகதி வரை வெளிநாடு செல்ல மாட்டோம் எனவும் திரு அடிகல நீதிமன்றில் உறுதியளித்துள்ளார்.",
        "இங்கு மற்றொரு பிரதிவாதியான முன்னாள் மத்திய வங்கி ஆளுநர் திரு.அஜித் நிவார்ட் கப்ரால், உச்ச நீதிமன்றத்தின் அனுமதியின்றி வெளிநாடு செல்லமாட்டேன் என நீதிமன்றத்தில் உறுதியளித்தார்.",
        "சமூக ஆர்வலர் சந்திரா ஜெயரத்ன மற்றும் பிரபல இலங்கை நீச்சல் வீரர் ஜூலியன் பவுலிங் ஆகியோர் இந்த மனுவை தாக்கல் செய்துள்ளனர்.",
        "நாட்டின் பொருளாதார நெருக்கடிக்கு காரணமானவர்கள் மீது விசாரணை நடத்தி நடவடிக்கை எடுக்க வேண்டும் என உச்சநீதிமன்றத்தில் மனுதாரர்கள் இந்த மனுக்களை தாக்கல் செய்துள்ளனர்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "மஹிந்த-பசில்",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "28",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "உச்ச நீதிமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "15",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "மஹிந்த ராஜபக்ஷ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "நிதி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "பசில் ராஜபக்ஷ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்த மாதம் 28 ஆம் தேதி",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "உச்ச நீதிமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "சந்திரா ஜயரத்ன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஐந்து",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "உச்ச நீதிமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "15",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஜயந்த ஜயசூரிய",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "அலுவிஹாரே",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "பிரியந்த ஜயவர்தன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "மலல்கொட",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "எல்.டி.பி.தெஹிதெனிய",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஐந்து",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "மத்திய வங்கி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "டபிள்யூ.டி.லக்ஷ்மன்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "நிதி அமைச்சகம் எஸ்.ஆர்.",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "அடிகல",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்த மாதம் 27 ஆம் தேதி",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "மத்திய வங்கி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "அஜித் நிவர்ட் கப்ரால்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "உச்ச நீதிமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "சந்திரா ஜயரத்ன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜூலியன் பந்துவீச்சு",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "உச்ச நீதிமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}