{
  "newspaper_id": "economy-next-com",
  "url": "https://economynext.com/chinas-jinping-offers-help-to-sri-lankas-wickremesinghe-government-97822/",
  "time_ut": 1658504520,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "China’s Jinping offers help to Sri Lanka’s Wickremesinghe government",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "China’s Jinping offers help to Sri Lanka’s Wickremesinghe government",
      "author": "",
      "body_lines": [
        "ECONOMYNEXT – Chinese President Xi Jinping expressed his willingness to the government of Sri Lanka’s new president Ranil Wickremesinghe to the best of his ability for the island nation’s leader and its people.",
        "Jinping’s congratulatory message, the first from a foreign country, came as the new president was widely condemned for his ordering the island nation’s military to attack and remove the protesters from the main protest site near the presidential secretariat.",
        "“I attach great importance to the development of China-Sri Lanka relations, and am willing to provide support and assistance to the best of my ability for you and the Sri Lankan people in your efforts,” Jinping said in a statement.",
        "“I believe that under your leadership, Sri Lanka will be able to overcome temporary difficulties and advance the process of economic and social recovery.”",
        "“It is hoped that the two sides will carry forward the traditional friendship, consolidate political mutual trust, and push forward the strategic cooperative partnership of sincere mutual assistance and ever-lasting friendship between two countries.”",
        "Wickremesinghe has been elected as the president by the parliament for the rest of the tenure of former leader Gotabaya Rajapaksa who fled the country and resigned from Singapore. Rajapaksa fled after three months of the protests for his failure to address economic crisis, which later turned into a political crisis.",
        "The same protesters who forced Rajapaksa to flee were attacked by the military under the state of emergency declared by Rajapaksa.",
        "China has invested billions of dollars, but pressure from India and the West has been a deterrent for successive Sri Lankan government deal with China, which is accused of dragging Sri Lanka into a debt trap.",
        "India and the United Stated have raised concerns over increasing Chinese presence in Sri Lanka which they say could be a security threat for Indian Ocean. China has said its interest in Sri Lanka is only commercial. (Colombo/July 23/2022)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "China",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "Sri Lanka’s",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "Wickremesinghe",
          "label": "NORP"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Chinese",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Xi Jinping",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "first",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "China",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "two",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "between two",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Gotabaya Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Singapore",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Rajapaksa",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "three months",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Rajapaksa",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Rajapaksa",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "China",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "billions of dollars",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "India",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "West",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lankan",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "China",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "India",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the United Stated",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Chinese",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Indian Ocean",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "China",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Colombo/July 23/2022",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "චීනයේ ජින්පින් ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ වික්‍රමසිංහ රජයට උදව් කරයි",
      "author": "",
      "body_lines": [
        "ECONOMYNEXT - චීන ජනාධිපති ෂී ජින් පිං මහතා ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ නව ජනාධිපති රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතාගේ රජයට සිය උපරිමයෙන් දිවයිනේ ජාතියේ නායකයා සහ එහි ජනතාව වෙනුවෙන් සිය කැමැත්ත ප්‍රකාශ කළේය.",
        "ජින්පිං ගේ සුබපැතුම් පණිවිඩය, විදේශ රටකින් පැමිණි ප්‍රථම සුබපැතුම් පණිවිඩය, ජනාධිපති ලේකම් කාර්යාලය අසල ප්‍රධාන විරෝධතා භූමියෙන් විරෝධතාකරුවන්ට පහර දී ඉවත් කරන ලෙස දිවයිනේ හමුදාවට නියෝග කිරීම සම්බන්ධයෙන් නව ජනාධිපතිවරයා පුළුල් ලෙස හෙළා දකින ලදී.",
        "\"චීන-ශ්‍රී ලංකා සබඳතා වර්ධනයට මම විශාල වැදගත්කමක් ලබා දෙන අතර, ඔබ සහ ශ්‍රී ලාංකීය ජනතාව වෙනුවෙන් මගේ උපරිමයෙන් සහයෝගය සහ සහාය ලබා දීමට මම කැමැත්තෙමි\" යනුවෙන් ජින් පිං නිවේදනයක් නිකුත් කරමින් කියා සිටියේය.",
        "\"ඔබගේ නායකත්වය යටතේ ශ්‍රී ලංකාවට තාවකාලික දුෂ්කරතා මඟහරවා ගැනීමටත් ආර්ථික හා සමාජීය ප්‍රකෘතිමත් වීමේ ක්‍රියාවලිය ඉදිරියට ගෙන යාමටත් හැකි වනු ඇතැයි මම විශ්වාස කරමි.\"",
        "\"දෙපාර්ශ්වය සාම්ප්‍රදායික මිත්‍රත්වය, දේශපාලන අන්‍යෝන්‍ය විශ්වාසය තහවුරු කර, අවංක අන්‍යෝන්‍ය සහයෝගීතාවයේ සහ දෙරට අතර සදාකාලික මිත්‍රත්වයේ උපායමාර්ගික සහයෝගිතා හවුල්කාරිත්වය ඉදිරියට ගෙන යනු ඇතැයි අපේක්ෂා කෙරේ.\"",
        "රටින් පැන ගොස් සිංගප්පූරුවෙන් ඉල්ලා අස්වූ හිටපු නායක ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ මහතාගේ ඉතිරි කාලය සඳහා පාර්ලිමේන්තුව විසින් වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතා ජනාධිපතිවරයා ලෙස තේරී පත්වී ඇත. ආර්ථික අර්බුදයට පිළියම් යෙදීමට අපොහොසත් වීම නිසා මාස තුනක විරෝධතාවලින් පසු රාජපක්ෂ පලා ගිය අතර එය පසුව දේශපාලන අර්බුදයක් බවට පත්විය.",
        "රාජපක්ෂට පලා යාමට බල කළ විරෝධතාකරුවන්ටම රාජපක්ෂ විසින් ප්‍රකාශයට පත් කරන ලද හදිසි නීතිය යටතේ හමුදාව විසින් පහර දෙන ලදී.",
        "චීනය ඩොලර් බිලියන ගණනින් ආයෝජනය කර ඇතත්, ඉන්දියාව සහ බටහිර රටවල පීඩනය ශ්‍රී ලංකාව ණය උගුලකට ඇද දැමූ බවට චෝදනා කරන චීනය සමඟ ශ්‍රී ලංකා රජය අනුප්‍රාප්තික ගනුදෙනු සඳහා බාධාවක් වී ඇත.",
        "ඉන්දියන් සාගරයේ ආරක්‍ෂාවට තර්ජනයක් විය හැකි බව පවසමින් ශ‍්‍රී ලංකාවේ චීන පැවැත්ම වැඩි වීම පිළිබඳව ඉන්දියාව සහ එක්සත් ජනපදය කනස්සල්ල පළ කර ඇත. චීනය පවසන්නේ ශ්‍රී ලංකාව සම්බන්ධයෙන් ඇති උනන්දුව වාණිජමය පමණක් බවයි. (කොළඹ/ජූලි 23/2022)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "චීනය",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "වික්‍රමසිංහ",
          "label": "NORP"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "චීන",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Xi Jinping",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "පළමුවන",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "චීනය",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "දෙක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "දෙකක් අතර",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "සිංගප්පූරුව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මාස තුනක්",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "චීනය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඩොලර් බිලියන ගණනක්",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "බටහිර",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලාංකික",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "චීනය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "එක්සත් ජනපදය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "චීන",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දියන් සාගරය",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "චීනය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "කොළඹ/ජූලි 23/2022",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "இலங்கையின் விக்ரமசிங்கே அரசாங்கத்திற்கு சீனாவின் ஜின்பிங் உதவி வழங்குகிறார்",
      "author": "",
      "body_lines": [
        "பொருளாதாரம் - சீன ஜனாதிபதி ஷி ஜின்பிங், இலங்கையின் புதிய ஜனாதிபதி ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்கவின் அரசாங்கத்திடம், தீவு தேசத்தின் தலைவருக்கும் அதன் மக்களுக்கும் தன்னால் இயன்றவரை தனது விருப்பத்தை வெளிப்படுத்தினார்.",
        "ஜின்பிங்கின் வாழ்த்துச் செய்தி, வெளிநாட்டிலிருந்து வந்த முதல், புதிய ஜனாதிபதி, ஜனாதிபதி செயலகத்திற்கு அருகிலுள்ள பிரதான போராட்டத் தளத்திலிருந்து போராட்டக்காரர்களைத் தாக்கி அகற்றுமாறு தீவு நாட்டின் இராணுவத்திற்கு உத்தரவிட்டதற்காக பரவலாகக் கண்டனம் செய்யப்பட்டார்.",
        "\"சீனா-இலங்கை உறவுகளின் வளர்ச்சிக்கு நான் அதிக முக்கியத்துவம் கொடுக்கிறேன், மேலும் உங்களது முயற்சிகளில் உங்களுக்கும் இலங்கை மக்களுக்கும் என்னால் இயன்றளவு ஆதரவையும் உதவியையும் வழங்க தயாராக இருக்கிறேன்\" என்று ஜின்பிங் தனது அறிக்கையில் தெரிவித்துள்ளார்.",
        "\"உங்கள் தலைமையின் கீழ், இலங்கை தற்காலிக சிரமங்களை சமாளிக்க முடியும் என்று நான் நம்புகிறேன் மற்றும் பொருளாதார மற்றும் சமூக மீட்சியின் செயல்முறையை முன்னெடுக்க முடியும்.\"",
        "\"இரு தரப்பும் பாரம்பரிய நட்பை முன்னெடுத்துச் செல்லும் என்றும், அரசியல் பரஸ்பர நம்பிக்கையை ஒருங்கிணைத்து, நேர்மையான பரஸ்பர உதவி மற்றும் இரு நாடுகளுக்கு இடையே என்றும் நிலைத்திருக்கும் நட்புறவு ஆகியவற்றின் மூலோபாய கூட்டுறவு கூட்டாண்மையை முன்னோக்கித் தள்ளும் என்று நம்பப்படுகிறது.\"",
        "முன்னாள் தலைவர் கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ச நாட்டை விட்டு வெளியேறி சிங்கப்பூரில் இருந்து ராஜினாமா செய்ததன் எஞ்சிய காலப்பகுதிக்கு விக்ரமசிங்கே ஜனாதிபதியாக நாடாளுமன்றத்தால் தெரிவு செய்யப்பட்டுள்ளார். பொருளாதார நெருக்கடிக்கு தீர்வுகாணத் தவறியதற்காக மூன்று மாத போராட்டங்களுக்குப் பிறகு ராஜபக்சே தப்பியோடினார், அது பின்னர் அரசியல் நெருக்கடியாக மாறியது.",
        "ராஜபக்சேவைத் தப்பி ஓடச் செய்த அதே போராட்டக்காரர்கள், ராஜபக்சே அறிவித்த அவசரகாலச் சட்டத்தின் கீழ் இராணுவத்தால் தாக்கப்பட்டனர்.",
        "சீனா பில்லியன் கணக்கான டாலர்களை முதலீடு செய்துள்ளது, ஆனால் இந்தியா மற்றும் மேற்கு நாடுகளின் அழுத்தம், இலங்கையை கடன் பொறிக்குள் இழுத்ததாக குற்றம் சாட்டப்படும் சீனாவுடனான இலங்கை அரசாங்கத்தின் தொடர்ச்சியான ஒப்பந்தத்திற்கு தடையாக உள்ளது.",
        "இலங்கையில் சீனாவின் பிரசன்னம் அதிகரிப்பது குறித்து இந்தியாவும் அமெரிக்காவும் கவலைகளை எழுப்பியுள்ளன, இது இந்து சமுத்திரத்திற்கு பாதுகாப்பு அச்சுறுத்தலாக இருக்கலாம் என்று அவர்கள் கூறுகின்றனர். இலங்கை மீதான தனது ஆர்வம் வர்த்தகம் மட்டுமே என சீனா தெரிவித்துள்ளது. (கொழும்பு/ஜூலை 23/2022)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "சீனா",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "இலங்கையின்",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "விக்கிரமசிங்க",
          "label": "NORP"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "சீன",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Xi Jinping",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "முதலில்",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "சீனா",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இரண்டு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "இரண்டு இடையே",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "சிங்கப்பூர்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ராஜபக்சே",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "மூன்று மாதங்கள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ராஜபக்சே",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ராஜபக்சே",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "சீனா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "பில்லியன் டாலர்கள்",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்தியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "மேற்கு",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "சீனா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இந்தியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "அமெரிக்கா",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "சீன",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்திய பெருங்கடல்",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "சீனா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "கொழும்பு/ஜூலை 23/2022",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}