{
  "newspaper_id": "daily-ft-lk",
  "url": "https://www.ft.lk/news/CBK-to-open-Nawa-Lanka-Nidahas-Pakshaya-HQ-today/56-739487",
  "time_ut": 1662327328,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "CBK to open Nawa Lanka Nidahas Pakshaya HQ today",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "CBK to open Nawa Lanka Nidahas Pakshaya HQ today",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "Former President Chandrika Bandaranaike Kumaratunga will declare open the new party head office of the Nawa Lanka Nidahas Pakshaya (New Lanka Freedom Party) in Battaramulla today morning.",
        "The new political party is led by Parliamentarian Kumara Welgama.",
        "He said the party is set to implement programs to train youth under the age of 40 and take steps to establish a corruption-free youth-led political movement in the future.",
        "Welgama formed the Nawa Lanka Nidahas Pakshaya on 6 March 2020, claiming it is seeking to uphold the now forgotten Bandaranaike policies. At the time Welgama claimed he was forming the new party because the Sri Lanka Freedom Party (SLFP) created by the late S.W.R.D Bandaranaike of which he had been a member has become a sell-out in recent times.",
        "The party was registered and officially listed in the Election Commission’s list of registered political parties on 10 January."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Nawa Lanka",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "Nidahas Pakshaya",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "today",
          "label": "DATE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Chandrika Bandaranaike",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kumaratunga",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Nidahas Pakshaya",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "New Lanka Freedom Party",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Battaramulla",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "morning",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Parliamentarian Kumara Welgama",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the age of 40",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Nidahas Pakshaya",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "6 March 2020",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Bandaranaike",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Welgama",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Sri Lanka Freedom Party",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Bandaranaike",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the Election Commission’s",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "10 January",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "නව ලංකා නිදහස් පක්ෂය මූලස්ථානය අද විවෘත කිරීමට සී.බී.කේ",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "නව ලංකා නිදහස් පක්ෂයේ (නව ලංකා නිදහස් පක්ෂයේ) නව පක්ෂ ප්‍රධාන කාර්යාලය හිටපු ජනාධිපතිනි චන්ද්‍රිකා බණ්ඩාරනායක කුමාරතුංග මහත්මිය විසින් අද පෙරවරුවේ බත්තරමුල්ලේ දී විවෘත කිරීමට නියමිතය.",
        "නව දේශපාලන පක්ෂය පාර්ලිමේන්තු මන්ත්‍රී කුමාර වෙල්ගම මහතාගේ ප්‍රධානත්වයෙන්.",
        "වයස අවුරුදු 40 ට අඩු තරුණ තරුණියන් පුහුණු කිරීමේ වැඩසටහන් ක්‍රියාත්මක කිරීමටත්, දූෂණයෙන් තොර තරුණ ප්‍රමුඛ දේශපාලන ව්‍යාපාරයක් අනාගතයේදී ස්ථාපිත කිරීමටත් පක්ෂය කටයුතු කිරීමට නියමිත බව ඔහු පැවසීය.",
        "වෙල්ගම විසින් 2020 මාර්තු 6 වන දින නව ලංකා නිදහස් පක්ෂය පිහිටුවනු ලැබුවේ එය දැන් අමතක වී ඇති බණ්ඩාරනායක ප්‍රතිපත්ති ආරක්ෂා කිරීමට උත්සාහ කරන බව පවසමිනි. වෙල්ගම එම අවස්ථාවේදී ප්‍රකාශ කළේ තමන් නව පක්ෂය පිහිටුවන්නේ තමන් සාමාජිකත්වය දැරූ දිවංගත එස්.ඩබ්ලිව්.ආර්.ඩී බණ්ඩාරනායක මහතා විසින් නිර්මාණය කරන ලද ශ්‍රී ලංකා නිදහස් පක්ෂය (ශ්‍රීලනිප) මෑත කාලයේ විකුණා දැමූ පක්ෂයක් බවට පත්ව ඇති බැවිනි.",
        "පක්ෂය ජනවාරි 10 වන දින මැතිවරණ කොමිසමේ ලියාපදිංචි දේශපාලන පක්ෂ ලැයිස්තුවේ ලියාපදිංචි කර නිල වශයෙන් ලැයිස්තුගත කරන ලදී."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "නව ලංකා",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "නිදහස් පක්ෂය",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "අද",
          "label": "DATE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "චන්ද්‍රිකා බණ්ඩාරනායක",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "කුමාරතුංග ය",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "නිදහස් පක්ෂය",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "නව ලංකා නිදහස් පක්ෂය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "බත්තරමුල්ල",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "උදෑසන",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තු මන්ත්‍රී කුමාර වෙල්ගම",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "වයස අවුරුදු 40 යි",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "නිදහස් පක්ෂය",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "6 මාර්තු 2020",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "බණ්ඩාරනායක",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "වෙල්ගම",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකා නිදහස් පක්ෂය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "බණ්ඩාරනායක",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "මැතිවරණ කොමිසමේ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "10 ජනවාරි",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "நவ லங்கா நிதாஹஸ் பக்ஷய தலைமையகத்தை இன்று திறக்கும் சி.பி.கே",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "நவ லங்கா நிதாஹஸ் பக்ஷய (புதிய லங்கா சுதந்திரக் கட்சியின்) கட்சியின் புதிய தலைமை அலுவலகத்தை முன்னாள் ஜனாதிபதி சந்திரிக்கா பண்டாரநாயக்க குமாரதுங்க இன்று காலை பத்தரமுல்லையில் திறந்து வைக்கவுள்ளார்.",
        "பாராளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர் குமார வெல்கம தலைமையில் புதிய அரசியல் கட்சி ஆரம்பிக்கப்பட்டுள்ளது.",
        "40 வயதுக்குட்பட்ட இளைஞர்களுக்கு பயிற்சி அளிக்கும் திட்டங்களை செயல்படுத்தவும், எதிர்காலத்தில் ஊழலற்ற இளைஞர்கள் தலைமையிலான அரசியல் இயக்கத்தை ஏற்படுத்தவும் கட்சி நடவடிக்கை எடுக்க உள்ளது என்றார்.",
        "வெல்கம 2020 மார்ச் 6 அன்று நவ லங்கா நிதாஹஸ் பக்ஷயவை உருவாக்கினார், அது இப்போது மறந்துவிட்ட பண்டாரநாயக்க கொள்கைகளை நிலைநிறுத்த முயல்வதாகக் கூறினார். மறைந்த எஸ்.டபிள்யூ.ஆர்.டி. பண்டாரநாயக்கவினால் உருவாக்கப்பட்ட ஸ்ரீலங்கா சுதந்திரக் கட்சி (SLFP) அண்மைக் காலமாக விற்பனையாகிவிட்டதால் தான் புதிய கட்சியை உருவாக்குவதாக வெல்கம கூறியிருந்தார்.",
        "ஜனவரி 10 அன்று தேர்தல் ஆணையத்தின் பதிவு செய்யப்பட்ட அரசியல் கட்சிகளின் பட்டியலில் கட்சி பதிவு செய்யப்பட்டு அதிகாரப்பூர்வமாக பட்டியலிடப்பட்டது."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "நவ லங்கா",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "நிதாஹஸ் பக்ஷயா",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "இன்று",
          "label": "DATE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "சந்திரிகா பண்டாரநாயக்கா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "குமாரதுங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "நிதாஹஸ் பக்ஷயா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "புதிய லங்கா சுதந்திரக் கட்சி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "பத்தரமுல்ல",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "காலை",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர் குமார வெல்கம",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "வயது 40",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "நிதாஹஸ் பக்ஷயா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "6 மார்ச் 2020",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "பண்டாரநாயக்கா",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "வெல்கம",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஸ்ரீலங்கா சுதந்திரக் கட்சி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "பண்டாரநாயக்கா",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "தேர்தல் ஆணையத்தின்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "10 ஜனவரி",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}