{
  "newspaper_id": "ada-derana-lk",
  "url": "http://www.adaderana.lk/news/83680/parliament-to-meet-today-two-entry-roads-temporarily-closed-for-traffic",
  "time_ut": 1657943640,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Parliament to meet today, two entry roads temporarily closed for traffic",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Parliament to meet today, two entry roads temporarily closed for traffic",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "The two main entry roads to the Parliament have been temporarily closed for traffic, the police said, urging motorists to use alternate routes for the time being.",
        "Road closure comes ahead of today’s parliamentary session, chaired by Speaker Mahinda Yapa Abeywardena, scheduled to commence at 10.00 a.m.",
        "The parliament is meeting pursuant to the provisions of the Presidential Elections (Special Provisions) Act, No. 02 of 1981 after former President Gotabaya Rajapaksa vacated the office effective from the 14th of July.",
        "Accordingly, the Secretary-General of Parliament, under Section 5 of this Act, will announce the vacancy in the office of President.",
        "He will also announce the date and time for the receipt of nominations for the presidency.",
        "A new Head of State will be elected in a parliamentary vote on the 20th of July (Wednesday) and the nominations are expected to be accepted on the day before.",
        "Ranil Wickremesinghe, who was became the Prime Minister for the sixth time in May, will serve the Acting President to exercise and perform the powers, functions and duties of the Head of State in the meantime."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Parliament",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "today",
          "label": "DATE"
        },
        {
          "text": "two",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "two",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Mahinda Yapa Abeywardena",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "10.00 a.m.",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the Presidential Elections (Special Provisions) Act",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "02",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "1981",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Gotabaya Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the 14th of July",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Section 5 of this Act",
            "label": "LAW"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "State",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the 20th of July",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Wednesday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the day before",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "sixth",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "May",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව අද රැස්වීමට නියමිත අතර පිවිසුම් මාර්ග දෙකක් ගමනාගමනය සඳහා තාවකාලිකව වසා දැමේ",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "පාර්ලිමේන්තුවට පිවිසෙන ප්‍රධාන මාර්ග දෙක ගමනාගමනය සඳහා තාවකාලිකව වසා දමා ඇති අතර, දැනට විකල්ප මාර්ග භාවිත කරන ලෙස පොලීසිය රියදුරන්ගෙන් ඉල්ලා සිටියි.",
        "කථානායක මහින්ද යාපා අබේවර්ධන මහතාගේ ප්‍රධානත්වයෙන් අද පෙරවරු 10.00 ට ආරම්භ වීමට නියමිත පාර්ලිමේන්තු සැසිවාරයට පෙර මාර්ගය වසා දැමීම සිදු කෙරේ.",
        "1981 අංක 02 දරන ජනාධිපතිවරණ (විශේෂ විධිවිධාන) පනතේ විධිවිධාන අනුව පාර්ලිමේන්තුව රැස්වන්නේ හිටපු ජනාධිපති ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ මහතා ජූලි 14 වැනිදා සිට එම ධුරයෙන් ඉවත්වීමෙන් පසුවය.",
        "ඒ අනුව, මෙම පනතේ 5 වැනි වගන්තිය යටතේ පාර්ලිමේන්තු මහලේකම්වරයා විසින් ජනාධිපති ධුරයේ පුරප්පාඩුව ප්‍රකාශයට පත් කරනු ඇත.",
        "ජනාධිපති ධුර අපේක්ෂකත්වය සඳහා නාමයෝජනා භාර ගන්නා දිනය සහ වේලාව ද ඔහු විසින් ප්‍රකාශයට පත් කරනු ඇති.",
        "ජුලි 20 (බදාදා) පාර්ලිමේන්තු ඡන්ද විමසීමකින් නව රාජ්‍ය නායකයෙකු තෝරා පත් කර ගැනීමට නියමිත අතර ඊට පෙර දින නාමයෝජනා භාර ගැනීමට අපේක්ෂා කෙරේ.",
        "මැයි මාසයේදී හයවැනි වරටත් අගමැති ධුරයට පත් වූ රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතා වැඩබලන ජනාධිපතිවරයාට සේවය කරන්නේ ඒ අතරතුර රාජ්‍ය නායකයාගේ බලතල, කාර්යයන් සහ යුතුකම් ක්‍රියාත්මක කිරීමට සහ ඉටු කිරීමට ය."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "අද",
          "label": "DATE"
        },
        {
          "text": "දෙක",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "දෙක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මහින්ද යාපා අබේවර්ධන",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "10.00 පෙ.ව.",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ජනාධිපති මැතිවරණ (විශේෂ විධිවිධාන) පනත",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "02",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "1981",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජූලි 14 වෙනිදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "මෙම පනතේ 5 වන වගන්තිය",
            "label": "LAW"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "රජයේ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජූලි 20 වැනිදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "බදාදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "පෙර දින",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "හය වන",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "මැයි",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "பாராளுமன்றம் இன்று கூடவுள்ள நிலையில் இரண்டு நுழைவு வீதிகள் போக்குவரத்துக்காக தற்காலிகமாக மூடப்பட்டது",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "பாராளுமன்றத்திற்கான இரண்டு பிரதான நுழைவு வீதிகளும் போக்குவரத்துக்காக தற்காலிகமாக மூடப்பட்டுள்ளதாக தெரிவித்த பொலிஸார், தற்போதைக்கு மாற்று வீதிகளை பயன்படுத்துமாறு வாகன சாரதிகளை கேட்டுக்கொண்டுள்ளனர்.",
        "சபாநாயகர் மஹிந்த யாப்பா அபேவர்தன தலைமையில் இன்று காலை 10.00 மணிக்கு ஆரம்பிக்கப்படவுள்ள பாராளுமன்ற அமர்வுக்கு முன்னதாகவே வீதி மூடல் மேற்கொள்ளப்பட்டுள்ளது.",
        "முன்னாள் ஜனாதிபதி கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ஷ ஜூலை 14 ஆம் திகதி முதல் பதவியை விட்டு வெளியேறியதன் பின்னர், 1981 ஆம் ஆண்டின் 02 ஆம் இலக்க ஜனாதிபதித் தேர்தல்கள் (விசேட ஏற்பாடுகள்) சட்டத்தின் விதிகளுக்கு இணங்க பாராளுமன்றம் கூடுகிறது.",
        "அதன்படி, இந்தச் சட்டத்தின் 5வது பிரிவின் கீழ், நாடாளுமன்றத்தின் பொதுச் செயலாளர், குடியரசுத் தலைவர் பதவியில் உள்ள வெற்றிடத்தை அறிவிப்பார்.",
        "ஜனாதிபதி பதவிக்கான வேட்புமனுக்கள் பெறப்படும் தேதி மற்றும் நேரத்தையும் அவர் அறிவிப்பார்.",
        "ஜூலை 20 ஆம் தேதி (புதன்கிழமை) பாராளுமன்ற வாக்கெடுப்பில் புதிய அரச தலைவர் தேர்ந்தெடுக்கப்படுவார் மற்றும் வேட்புமனுக்கள் முந்தைய நாளில் ஏற்றுக்கொள்ளப்படும் என்று எதிர்பார்க்கப்படுகிறது.",
        "மே மாதம் ஆறாவது தடவையாக பிரதமராக பதவியேற்ற ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க, இடைக்கால ஜனாதிபதியின் அதிகாரங்கள், செயல்பாடுகள் மற்றும் கடமைகளை நிறைவேற்றுவதற்கும், நிறைவேற்றுவதற்கும் பதில் ஜனாதிபதியாக பணியாற்றுவார்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "இன்று",
          "label": "DATE"
        },
        {
          "text": "இரண்டு",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "இரண்டு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "மஹிந்த யாப்பா அபேவர்தன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "காலை 10.00 மணி",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஜனாதிபதி தேர்தல்கள் (சிறப்பு ஏற்பாடுகள்) சட்டம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "02",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "1981",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜூலை 14 ஆம் தேதி",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்த சட்டத்தின் பிரிவு 5",
            "label": "LAW"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "நிலை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜூலை 20 ஆம் தேதி",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "புதன்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "முந்தைய நாள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆறாவது",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "மே",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}