{
  "newspaper_id": "ada-derana-lk",
  "url": "http://www.adaderana.lk/news/83736/sri-lankan-students-in-india-asked-to-register-for-a-census",
  "time_ut": 1658214600,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Sri Lankan students in India asked to register for a census",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Sri Lankan students in India asked to register for a census",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "Deputy High Commission of Sri Lanka in Chennai and the Consulate General of Sri Lanka in Mumbai are planning to collect details of the Sri Lankan students who are currently studying in India, in order to update the relevant databases.",
        "This would enable the Sri Lankan Missions/Posts to reach out to Sri Lankan students and provide assistance whenever necessary, the Sri Lankan High Commission in India said in a statement.",
        "The Sri Lankan Missions/Posts in India accordingly request the Sri Lankan students to register themselves using the web links available at the High Commission of Sri Lanka, Consulate General in Mumbai, or the Deputy High Commission of Sri Lanka in Chennai as per the state/union territory where they are currently studying or residing.",
        "Sri Lankan High Commission in New Delhi and Consulate General of Sri Lanka in Mumbai - https://www.slhcindia.org/",
        "Registration for the Deputy High Commission of Sri Lanka in Chennai - https://www.sldhcchennai.org/"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Sri Lankan",
          "label": "NORP"
        },
        {
          "text": "India",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "the Consulate General of Sri Lanka",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Mumbai",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Sri Lankan",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "India",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the Sri Lankan Missions/Posts",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lankan",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Sri Lankan High Commission",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "India",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "The Sri Lankan Missions/Posts",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "India",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the High Commission of Sri Lanka",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Mumbai",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lankan High Commission",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "New Delhi",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Consulate General of Sri Lanka",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Mumbai",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Chennai - https://www.sldhcchennai.org/",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "ඉන්දියාවේ සිටින ශ්‍රී ලාංකික සිසුන් සංගණනයකට ලියාපදිංචි වන ලෙස ඉල්ලා සිටියේය",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "අදාළ දත්ත සමුදායන් යාවත්කාලීන කිරීම සඳහා දැනට ඉන්දියාවේ අධ්‍යාපනය ලබන ශ්‍රී ලාංකික සිසුන්ගේ තොරතුරු රැස් කිරීමට චෙන්නායි හි ශ්‍රී ලංකා නියෝජ්‍ය මහ කොමසාරිස්වරයා සහ මුම්බායි හි ශ්‍රී ලංකා කොන්සල් ජනරාල් කාර්යාලය සැලසුම් කරයි.",
        "මෙමගින් ශ්‍රී ලංකා දූත මණ්ඩල/තැපැල්වලට ශ්‍රී ලාංකික සිසුන් වෙත ළඟා වීමට සහ අවශ්‍ය විටෙක ආධාර සැපයීමට හැකි වනු ඇති බව ඉන්දියාවේ ශ්‍රී ලංකා මහ කොමසාරිස් කාර්යාලය නිවේදනයක් නිකුත් කරමින් කියා සිටී.",
        "ඒ අනුව ශ්‍රී ලංකා මහ කොමසාරිස් කාර්යාලය, මුම්බායි හි කොන්සල් ජනරාල් කාර්යාලය හෝ චෙන්නායි හි ශ්‍රී ලංකා නියෝජ්‍ය මහ කොමසාරිස් කාර්යාලයේ ඇති වෙබ් සබැඳි භාවිතා කර ලියාපදිංචි වන ලෙස ඉන්දියාවේ ශ්‍රී ලංකා දූත මණ්ඩල/තැපැල් ශ්‍රී ලාංකික සිසුන්ගෙන් ඉල්ලා සිටියි. ඔවුන් දැනට ඉගෙනුම ලබන හෝ පදිංචිව සිටින යුනියන් ප්‍රදේශය.",
        "නවදිල්ලියේ ශ්‍රී ලංකා මහ කොමසාරිස් කාර්යාලය සහ මුම්බායි හි ශ්‍රී ලංකා කොන්සල් ජනරාල් කාර්යාලය - https://www.slhcindia.org/",
        "චෙන්නායි හි ශ්‍රී ලංකා නියෝජ්‍ය මහ කොමසාරිස් කාර්යාලය සඳහා ලියාපදිංචිය - https://www.sldhcchennai.org/"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ශ්‍රී ලාංකික",
          "label": "NORP"
        },
        {
          "text": "ඉන්දියාව",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකා කොන්සල් ජනරාල් කාර්යාලය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "මුම්බායි",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලාංකිකයා",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකා දූත මණ්ඩල/තැපැල්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලාංකික",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකා මහ කොමසාරිස් කාර්යාලය",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකා දූත මණ්ඩල/තැපැල්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකා මහ කොමසාරිස් කාර්යාලය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "මුම්බායි",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකා මහ කොමසාරිස්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "නව දිල්ලි",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකා කොන්සල් ජනරාල් කාර්යාලය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "මුම්බායි",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "චෙන්නායි - https://www.sldhcchennai.org/",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "இந்தியாவில் உள்ள இலங்கை மாணவர்கள் மக்கள்தொகை கணக்கெடுப்பிற்கு பதிவு செய்யுமாறு கேட்டுக் கொண்டனர்",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "சென்னையில் உள்ள இலங்கையின் துணை உயர் ஸ்தானிகராலயமும், மும்பையில் உள்ள இலங்கை தூதரகமும் தற்போது இந்தியாவில் கல்வி கற்கும் இலங்கை மாணவர்களின் விபரங்களைச் சேகரித்து, தொடர்புடைய தரவுத்தளங்களைப் புதுப்பிக்கத் திட்டமிட்டுள்ளன.",
        "இதன் மூலம் இலங்கை தூதரகங்கள்/பதவிகள் இலங்கை மாணவர்களைச் சென்றடையவும், தேவைப்படும்போது உதவிகளை வழங்கவும் உதவும் என்று இந்தியாவிலுள்ள இலங்கை உயர்ஸ்தானிகராலயம் அறிக்கை ஒன்றில் தெரிவித்துள்ளது.",
        "அதன்படி, இலங்கை உயர்ஸ்தானிகராலயம், மும்பையில் உள்ள துணைத் தூதரகம் அல்லது சென்னையில் உள்ள இலங்கையின் துணை உயர் ஸ்தானிகராலயத்தில் உள்ள இணைய இணைப்புகளைப் பயன்படுத்தி தங்களைப் பதிவு செய்யுமாறு இலங்கை மாணவர்களை இந்தியாவிலுள்ள இலங்கை தூதரகங்கள்/பதவிகள் கேட்டுக்கொள்கின்றன/ அவர்கள் தற்போது படிக்கும் அல்லது வசிக்கும் யூனியன் பிரதேசம்.",
        "புது தில்லியில் உள்ள இலங்கை உயர்ஸ்தானிகராலயம் மற்றும் மும்பையில் உள்ள இலங்கையின் துணைத் தூதரகம் - https://www.slhcindia.org/",
        "சென்னையில் உள்ள இலங்கையின் துணை உயர் ஸ்தானிகராலயத்திற்கான பதிவு - https://www.sldhcchennai.org/"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "இலங்கை",
          "label": "NORP"
        },
        {
          "text": "இந்தியா",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கையின் துணைத் தூதரகம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "மும்பை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்தியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை தூதரகங்கள்/பதவிகள்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை உயர்ஸ்தானிகராலயம்",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்தியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை தூதரகங்கள்/பதவிகள்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்தியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை உயர் ஸ்தானிகராலயம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "மும்பை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை உயர்ஸ்தானிகராலயம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "புது தில்லி",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை துணைத் தூதரகம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "மும்பை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "சென்னை - https://www.sldhcchennai.org/",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}