{
  "newspaper_id": "news-first-lk",
  "url": "https://www.newsfirst.lk/2022/08/26/unicef-regional-director-for-south-asia-meets-foreign-minister/",
  "time_ut": 1661515560,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "UNICEF Regional Director for South Asia meets Foreign Minister",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "UNICEF Regional Director for South Asia meets Foreign Minister",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); The UNICEF Regional Director for South Asia, George Laryea-Adjei, who is currently on a visit to Sri Lanka, paid a courtesy call on the Minister of Foreign Affairs, Ali Sabry on Wednesday.",
        "Foreign Minister Sabry appreciated the cooperation and assistance extended by UNICEF to Sri Lanka.",
        "Particular attention was paid to projects related to early childhood development, health and nutrition, immunization, safe water and sanitization, education and skills building, social welfare policies, and COVID-19 response.",
        "The Regional Director apprised Foreign Minister Sabry of  UNICEF programs in the country, particularly efforts undertaken to assist Sri Lanka during the current challenges.",
        "The Minister welcomed the new UNICEF country program to be implemented in 2023.",
        "He further stated that Sri Lanka has been a benchmark in its efforts in providing free healthcare, education as well as other social security measures due to which the Human Development Index for Sri Lanka is well above the regional average.",
        "The Regional Director appreciated the efforts taken by the Government of Sri Lanka for the protection and well-being of children in Sri Lanka and assured the continued cooperation and assistance of UNICEF to Sri Lanka.",
        "“I’d love to speak like I used to, but I cannot,” – Ranjan talks to the press after released from prison",
        "SJB wants full Presidential Pardon for Ranjan Ramanayake with Political Rights"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "South Asia",
          "label": "LOC"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "News 1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "South Asia",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "George Laryea-Adjei",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ali Sabry",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Wednesday",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sabry",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "Regional",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sabry",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "2023",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Regional",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Government of Sri Lanka",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Ranjan",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "SJB",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Presidential Pardon for Ranjan Ramanayake",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "යුනිසෙෆ් දකුණු ආසියාවේ කලාපීය අධ්‍යක්ෂ විදේශ ඇමති හමුවෙයි",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); මේ දිනවල ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ සංචාරයක නිරතව සිටින යුනිසෙෆ් සංවිධානයේ දකුණු ආසියාවේ කලාපීය අධ්‍යක්ෂ ජෝර්ජ් ලැරියා-ඇඩ්ජේ බදාදා විදේශ කටයුතු අමාත්‍ය අලි සබ්රි මහතා හමුවිය.",
        "යුනිසෙෆ් සංවිධානය ශ්‍රී ලංකාව වෙත ලබා දෙන සහයෝගිතාව සහ සහාය විදේශ අමාත්‍ය සබ්රි අගය කළේය.",
        "මුල් ළමාවිය සංවර්ධනය, සෞඛ්‍ය සහ පෝෂණය, ප්‍රතිශක්තිකරණය, ආරක්ෂිත ජලය සහ සනීපාරක්ෂාව, අධ්‍යාපනය සහ කුසලතා ගොඩනැගීම, සමාජ සුබසාධන ප්‍රතිපත්ති සහ COVID-19 ප්‍රතිචාරය සම්බන්ධ ව්‍යාපෘති කෙරෙහි විශේෂ අවධානය යොමු විය.",
        "ප්‍රාදේශීය අධ්‍යක්ෂවරයා විදේශ අමාත්‍ය සබ්රි වෙත  යුනිසෙෆ් හි රට තුළ වැඩසටහන්, විශේෂයෙන්ම වත්මන් අභියෝග වලදී ශ්‍රී ලංකාවට සහය වීමට ගෙන ඇති ප්‍රයත්නයන් පිළිබඳව දැනුවත් කළේය.",
        "2023 වසරේ ක්‍රියාත්මක කිරීමට නියමිත යුනිසෙෆ් නව රට වැඩසටහන අමාත්‍යවරයා විසින් පිළිගනු ලැබීය.",
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකාව නිදහස් සෞඛ්‍ය සේවා, අධ්‍යාපනය මෙන්ම අනෙකුත් සමාජ ආරක්ෂණ ක්‍රියාමාර්ග ලබාදීමේ ප්‍රයත්නයන්හිදී ශ්‍රී ලංකාව මිණුම් ලකුණක් වී ඇති බවත්, එම නිසා ශ්‍රී ලංකාව සඳහා මානව සංවර්ධන දර්ශකය කලාපීය සාමාන්‍යයට වඩා බෙහෙවින් ඉහළින් පවතින බවත් ඔහු වැඩිදුරටත් සඳහන් කළේය.",
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ දරුවන්ගේ ආරක්ෂාව සහ යහපැවැත්ම සඳහා ශ්‍රී ලංකා රජය ගෙන ඇති ප්‍රයත්නයන් ප්‍රාදේශීය අධ්‍යක්ෂවරයා අගය කළ අතර යුනිසෙෆ් සංවිධානයේ අඛණ්ඩ සහයෝගය සහ සහාය ශ්‍රී ලංකාවට ලබා දෙන බවට සහතික විය.",
        "\"මම ඉස්සර වගේ කතා කරන්න කැමතියි, නමුත් මට බැහැ\" - රංජන් බන්ධනාගාරයෙන් නිදහස් වූ පසු මාධ්‍ය වෙත කතා කරයි",
        "SJB දේශපාලන අයිතිවාසිකම් ඇති රන්ජන් රාමනායකට පූර්ණ ජනාධිපති සමාව අවශ්‍යයි"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "දකුණු ආසියාව",
          "label": "LOC"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "News 1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "දකුණු ආසියාව",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජෝර්ජ් ලැරියා-ඇඩ්ජේ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "අලි සබ්රි",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "බදාදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "සබ්රි",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "කලාපීය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "සබ්රි",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "2023",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "කලාපීය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකා රජය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "රන්ජන්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "එස්.ජේ.බී",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "රන්ජන් රාමනායකට ජනාධිපති සමාව",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "யுனிசெஃப் தெற்காசியாவிற்கான பிராந்திய இயக்குனர் வெளியுறவு அமைச்சரை சந்தித்தார்",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); தற்போது இலங்கைக்கு விஜயம் செய்துள்ள யுனிசெஃப் தெற்காசியாவிற்கான பிராந்திய பணிப்பாளர் ஜோர்ஜ் லரியா-அட்ஜே, வெளிவிவகார அமைச்சர் அலி சப்ரியை புதன்கிழமை சந்தித்து கலந்துரையாடினார்.",
        "இலங்கைக்கு யுனிசெப் வழங்கிய ஒத்துழைப்பு மற்றும் உதவிகளை வெளிவிவகார அமைச்சர் சப்ரி பாராட்டினார்.",
        "குழந்தைப் பருவ வளர்ச்சி, உடல்நலம் மற்றும் ஊட்டச்சத்து, நோய்த்தடுப்பு, பாதுகாப்பான நீர் மற்றும் சுத்திகரிப்பு, கல்வி மற்றும் திறன்களை மேம்படுத்துதல், சமூக நலக் கொள்கைகள் மற்றும் கோவிட்-19 பதிலளிப்பது தொடர்பான திட்டங்களுக்கு குறிப்பாக கவனம் செலுத்தப்பட்டது.",
        "நாட்டின்  UNICEF திட்டங்கள், குறிப்பாக தற்போதைய சவால்களின் போது இலங்கைக்கு உதவ மேற்கொள்ளப்படும் முயற்சிகள் குறித்து பிராந்திய இயக்குனர் வெளியுறவு அமைச்சர் சப்ரியிடம் தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "2023ஆம் ஆண்டு நடைமுறைப்படுத்தப்படவுள்ள புதிய யுனிசெஃப் நாட்டுத் திட்டத்தை அமைச்சர் வரவேற்றார்.",
        "இலவச சுகாதாரம், கல்வி மற்றும் ஏனைய சமூகப் பாதுகாப்பு நடவடிக்கைகளை வழங்குவதில் இலங்கை தனது முயற்சிகளில் ஒரு அளவுகோலாக இருப்பதாக அவர் மேலும் கூறினார்.",
        "இலங்கையில் உள்ள சிறுவர்களின் பாதுகாப்பு மற்றும் நல்வாழ்வுக்காக இலங்கை அரசாங்கம் எடுத்துள்ள முயற்சிகளைப் பாராட்டிய பிராந்திய பணிப்பாளர், இலங்கைக்கு யுனிசெப்பின் தொடர்ச்சியான ஒத்துழைப்பையும் உதவியையும் உறுதியளித்தார்.",
        "\"நான் முன்பு போல் பேச விரும்புகிறேன், ஆனால் என்னால் முடியாது,\" - சிறையில் இருந்து வெளிவந்த பிறகு ரஞ்சன் செய்தியாளர்களிடம் பேசுகிறார்",
        "அரசியல் உரிமைகளுடன் கூடிய ரஞ்சன் ராமநாயக்கவிற்கு ஜனாதிபதியின் முழுமையான மன்னிப்பை SJB விரும்புகிறது"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "தெற்காசியா",
          "label": "LOC"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "News 1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "தெற்காசியா",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜார்ஜ் லாரியா-அட்ஜீ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "அலி சப்ரி",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "புதன்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "சப்ரி",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "பிராந்தியமானது",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "சப்ரி",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "2023",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பிராந்தியமானது",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை அரசாங்கம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ரஞ்சன்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "எஸ்.ஜே.பி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரஞ்சன் ராமநாயக்கவுக்கு ஜனாதிபதி மன்னிப்பு",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}