{
  "newspaper_id": "news-first-lk",
  "url": "https://www.newsfirst.lk/2022/07/21/imf-would-need-commitment-from-administration-cbsl-chief/",
  "time_ut": 1658402340,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "IMF would need commitment from administration – CBSL Chief",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "IMF would need commitment from administration – CBSL Chief",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); Governor of the Central Bank of Sri Lanka (CBSL) Dr. Nandalal Weerasinghe says he is confident that Sri Lanka can come out of the prevalent crisis within a period of 04 – 05 months.",
        "“We have a clear program and a clear path,” he said, adding “if we follow this path… I am confident that we can come out of this crisis… say for example in about 04 – 05 months… Until then we will have a difficult time.” Dr. Weerasinghe added he is hopeful that people would be patient until Sri Lanka can ride out the crisis situation over the next couple of months.",
        "In an interview with CNN, Dr. Weerasinghe was of the view that the country will certainly benefit from the economic reforms being implemented and the reforms that are to be implemented in the future.",
        "He also said that if there was continued stable administration Sri Lanka could have reached the IMF staff-level agreement within this month (July).",
        "“But if there is a delay in forming an administration, then, of course, IMF needs a commitment from the new administration of the policies that we have presented to the IMF at the technical level. So the time of that process will depend on the new administration approach,” he said.",
        "Sri Lanka: Police hunt for three heroin peddlers after Rs. 380 Mn heroin bust in Embilipitiya"
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "News 1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Central Bank of Sri Lanka",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Nandalal Weerasinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "04 – 05 months",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "about 04 –",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Weerasinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the next couple of months",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "CNN",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Weerasinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "IMF",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "this month (July",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "IMF",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "three",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Mn",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Embilipitiya",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "ජාත්‍යන්තර මූල්‍ය අරමුදලට පරිපාලනයෙන් කැපවීමක් අවශ්‍යයි - මහ බැංකුවේ ප්‍රධානියා",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); ශ්‍රී ලංකා මහ බැංකුවේ (CBSL) අධිපති ආචාර්ය නන්දලාල් වීරසිංහ මහතා පවසන්නේ මාස 04 ත් 05 ත් අතර කාලසීමාවක් තුළ ශ්‍රී ලංකාවට පවතින අර්බුදයෙන් ගොඩ ඒමට හැකි බව තමාට විශ්වාස බවයි.",
        "\"අපට පැහැදිලි වැඩපිළිවෙලක් සහ පැහැදිලි මාවතක් ඇත,\" ඔහු තවදුරටත් පැවසීය, \"අපි මෙම මාර්ගය අනුගමනය කරන්නේ නම් ... අපට මෙම අර්බුදයෙන් ගොඩ ඒමට හැකි බව මට විශ්වාසයි ... උදාහරණයක් ලෙස මාස 04 - 05 කින් පමණ කියන්න ... එතෙක් අපට පවතිනු ඇත. දුෂ්කර කාලයක්.\" ඉදිරි මාස දෙක තුළ ශ්‍රී ලංකාවට අර්බුදකාරී තත්ත්වයෙන් මිදීමට හැකි වන තෙක් ජනතාව ඉවසිලිවන්තව සිටිනු ඇතැයි තමා බලාපොරොත්තු වන බව වෛද්‍ය වීරසිංහ මහතා පැවසීය.",
        "CNN නාලිකාව සමඟ සම්මුඛ සාකච්ඡාවකට එක්වෙමින් ආචාර්ය වීරසිංහගේ අදහස වූයේ ක්‍රියාත්මක වන ආර්ථික ප්‍රතිසංස්කරණ සහ ඉදිරියේදී ක්‍රියාත්මක කිරීමට නියමිත ප්‍රතිසංස්කරණවලින් රටට නිසැක ප්‍රතිලාභ ලැබෙන බවයි.",
        "ස්ථාවර පරිපාලනයක් අඛණ්ඩව පැවතියේ නම් ශ්‍රී ලංකාවට මේ මස (ජූලි) ඇතුළත ජාත්‍යන්තර මූල්‍ය අරමුදලේ කාර්ය මණ්ඩල මට්ටමේ එකඟතාවයකට පැමිණීමට හැකිව තිබූ බවද ඔහු පැවසීය.",
        "“නමුත් පරිපාලනයක් පිහිටුවීමේ ප්‍රමාදයක් තිබේ නම්, ඇත්ත වශයෙන්ම, IMF වෙත තාක්ෂණික මට්ටමින් IMF වෙත ඉදිරිපත් කර ඇති ප්‍රතිපත්තිවල නව පරිපාලනයෙන් කැපවීමක් අවශ්‍ය වේ. එබැවින් එම ක්‍රියාවලියේ කාලය නව පරිපාලන ප්‍රවේශය මත රඳා පවතිනු ඇත,” ඔහු පැවසීය.",
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකාව: රුපියල් කෝටි 100 කට පසු හෙරොයින් ජාවාරම්කරුවන් තිදෙනෙකු සොයා පොලිසිය සොයයි. ඇඹිලිපිටියෙන් මිලියන 380ක හෙරොයින් තොගයක්"
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "News 1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකා මහ බැංකුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "නන්දලාල් වීරසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මාස 04 - 05",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "04 ක් පමණ -",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "වීරසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉදිරි මාස කිහිපය",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "සීඑන්එන්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "වීරසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "IMF",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "මෙම මාසයේ (ජූලි",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "IMF",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "තුන්",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Mn",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඇඹිලිපිටිය",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "சர்வதேச நாணய நிதியத்திற்கு நிர்வாகத்தின் அர்ப்பணிப்பு தேவை - CBSL தலைவர்",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); இலங்கை மத்திய வங்கியின் (CBSL) ஆளுநர் கலாநிதி நந்தலால் வீரசிங்க 04 - 05 மாத காலப்பகுதிக்குள் இலங்கையானது நிலவும் நெருக்கடியிலிருந்து மீள முடியும் என நம்பிக்கை கொண்டுள்ளதாக தெரிவித்துள்ளார்.",
        "\"எங்களிடம் தெளிவான திட்டமும் தெளிவான பாதையும் உள்ளது,\" என்று அவர் மேலும் கூறினார், \"நாம் இந்த பாதையை பின்பற்றினால்... இந்த நெருக்கடியிலிருந்து நாம் வெளியே வர முடியும் என்று நான் நம்புகிறேன்... உதாரணத்திற்கு சுமார் 04 - 05 மாதங்களில் சொல்லுங்கள்... அதுவரை நாங்கள் ஒரு கடினமான நேரம்.\" அடுத்த இரண்டு மாதங்களில் இலங்கை நெருக்கடி நிலையிலிருந்து விடுபடும் வரை மக்கள் பொறுமையாக இருப்பார்கள் என்று நம்புவதாக டாக்டர் வீரசிங்க மேலும் கூறினார்.",
        "அமுல்படுத்தப்படும் பொருளாதார சீர்திருத்தங்கள் மற்றும் எதிர்காலத்தில் அமுல்படுத்தப்படவுள்ள சீர்திருத்தங்களினால் நாடு நிச்சயமாக பலனடையும் என கலாநிதி வீரசிங்க CNNக்கு வழங்கிய நேர்காணலில் கருத்து தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "நிலையான நிர்வாகம் தொடர்ந்திருந்தால், இந்த மாதத்திற்குள் (ஜூலை) இலங்கை சர்வதேச நாணய நிதியத்தின் பணியாளர் மட்ட ஒப்பந்தத்தை எட்டியிருக்க முடியும் என்றும் அவர் கூறினார்.",
        "\"ஆனால் நிர்வாகத்தை உருவாக்குவதில் தாமதம் ஏற்பட்டால், நிச்சயமாக, IMF க்கு தொழில்நுட்ப மட்டத்தில் IMF க்கு வழங்கிய கொள்கைகளின் புதிய நிர்வாகத்தின் அர்ப்பணிப்பு அவசியம். எனவே அந்த செயல்முறையின் நேரம் புதிய நிர்வாக அணுகுமுறையைப் பொறுத்தது, ”என்று அவர் கூறினார்.",
        "இலங்கை: ஹெராயின் போதைப் பொருள் கடத்தல்காரர்களை போலீசார் தேடி வருகின்றனர். எம்பிலிப்பிட்டியவில் 380 மில்லியன் ஹெரோயின் கடத்தல்!"
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "News 1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை மத்திய வங்கி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "நந்தலால் வீரசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "04 - 05 மாதங்கள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "சுமார் 04 –",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "வீரசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "அடுத்த இரண்டு மாதங்கள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "சிஎன்என்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "வீரசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "IMF",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்த மாதம் (ஜூலை",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "IMF",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "மூன்று",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Mn",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "எம்பிலிபிட்டிய",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}