{
  "newspaper_id": "island-lk",
  "url": "http://island.lk/state-owned-kalubowitiyana-tea-soars-to-new-heights/",
  "time_ut": 1661088180,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "State owned Kalubowitiyana Tea soars to new heights",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "State owned Kalubowitiyana Tea soars to new heights",
      "author": "Thilina Walpola",
      "body_lines": [
        "Incorporated on the 30th of September in 1992 as a public company fully owned by the government of Sri Lanka, Kalubowitiyana Tea Factory Ltd (KTFL) operates four tea factories which directly contribute to the national grid. The main factory located in Kalubowitiyana produces the record setting low grown CTC tea while the other three factories produce Orthodox tea. The four factories located in Kalubowitiyana and Derangala in the Matara District, Hiniduma Hills in the Galle District and Menikdiwela in the Kandy District are committed to enriching the lives of over 4,000 tea smallholders, while supporting the livelihoods of over 350 employees. This economic benefit and stability that KTFL provides to 10,000+ people, is no small feat given the severe economic difficulties facing the country today.",
        "Steeped in the concerns of recent operational challenges, Kalubowitiyana Tea has steered masterfully through the volatility to achieve the remarkable feat of closing their first quarter of 2022 with a revenue of Rs. 583 million and a net profit of Rs. 222 million. Mr. Aminda Rodrigo, Chairman of Kalubowitiyana Tea, confirmed that the company has recorded the all time highest price for low grown CTC tea at more than a staggering 50% of the twelve auctions held so far, peaking at a selling price of Rs. 3250 in the current financial year, which is a testament to the hard work of the management and employees operating KTFL, the flagship factory of the organization, and the premium quality of the tea, proudly produced in Sri Lanka. Furthermore, in July of 2022, the company was proud to offer the tea small holders that supply the award winning grades of low grown CTC tea, with a record breaking compensation of Rs. 434.82 per kilo.",
        "Plantation Minister, Dr. Ramesh Pathirana stated that profits are often an indication of strong leadership and Kalubowitiyana Tea has the privilege of operating under a transparent process of governing which aims to build a legacy appointed through ethical business practices that encourage growth and sustained stability. As a representative of a proud tea nation, Kalubowitiyana tea is committed to maintaining the gold standards of their business to honour the symbol of quality that is pure Ceylon Tea.",
        "Ranil, Sajith 2nd round of talks couldn’t come at a better time",
        "Leave a Reply Cancel replyYour email address will not be published. Required fields are marked *Comment Name *",
        "Save my name, email, and website in this browser for the next time I comment."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "State",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "Kalubowitiyana Tea",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "the 30th of September in 1992",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kalubowitiyana Tea Factory Ltd",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "KTFL",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "four",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kalubowitiyana",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "CTC",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "three",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Orthodox",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "four",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kalubowitiyana",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Derangala",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Matara District",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "Hiniduma Hills",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Galle District",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "Menikdiwela",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Kandy District",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "over 4,000",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "over 350",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "KTFL",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "10,000",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Kalubowitiyana Tea",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "their first quarter of 2022",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "583 million",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Rs",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "222 million",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Aminda Rodrigo",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kalubowitiyana Tea",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "CTC",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "50%",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "the current financial year",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "KTFL",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "July of 2022",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "CTC",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "434.82",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Ramesh Pathirana",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kalubowitiyana Tea",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kalubowitiyana",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ceylon Tea",
            "label": "PRODUCT"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [],
        []
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "රජය සතු කළුබෝවිටියන තේ නව තලයකට නගී",
      "author": "තිළිණ වල්පොල",
      "body_lines": [
        "1992 සැප්තැම්බර් 30 වැනි දින ශ්‍රී ලංකා රජයට පූර්ණ හිමිකාරීත්වය දරන පොදු සමාගමක් ලෙස සංස්ථාපිත වූ කළුබෝවිටියන තේ කර්මාන්ත ශාලාව (KTFL) ජාතික විදුලිබල පද්ධතියට සෘජුවම දායක වන තේ කර්මාන්ත ශාලා හතරක් ක්‍රියාත්මක කරයි. කළුබෝවිටියන ප්‍රදේශයේ පිහිටි ප්‍රධාන කර්මාන්ත ශාලාව අඩු වගා කළ CTC තේ නිෂ්පාදනය කරන අතර අනෙක් කර්මාන්තශාලා තුන ඕතඩොක්ස් තේ නිෂ්පාදනය කරයි. මාතර දිස්ත්‍රික්කයේ කළුබෝවිටියන සහ දෙරංගල, ගාල්ල දිස්ත්‍රික්කයේ හිනිදුම කඳුකරය සහ මහනුවර දිස්ත්‍රික්කයේ මැණික්දිවෙල යන ප්‍රදේශවල පිහිටි කර්මාන්තශාලා 4, 4000කට අධික කුඩා තේ වතු හිමියන්ගේ ජීවිත සරු කිරීමට කැපවී සිටින අතර, සේවක සේවිකාවන් 350කට අධික පිරිසකගේ ජීවනෝපාය සඳහා සහය වේ. KTFL විසින් 10,000+ පුද්ගලයින්ට ලබා දෙන මෙම ආර්ථික ප්‍රතිලාභය සහ ස්ථාවරත්වය අද රට මුහුණ දෙන දැඩි ආර්ථික දුෂ්කරතා හමුවේ සුළු දෙයක් නොවේ.",
        "මෑත කාලීන මෙහෙයුම් අභියෝග පිළිබඳ උත්සුකයන් තුළ ගිලී සිටින කළුබෝවිටියන තේ 2022 වසරේ පළමු කාර්තුවේදී රු. මිලියන 583 ක් සහ ශුද්ධ ලාභය රු. මිලියන 222 කි. කළුබෝවිටියන තේ සමාගමේ සභාපති අමින්ද රුද්‍රිගු මහතා තහවුරු කළේ මෙතෙක් පැවති වෙන්දේසි දොළහෙන් 50%කට වඩා වැඩි ප්‍රමාණයකින් අඩු වගා කළ CTC තේ සඳහා මෙතෙක් පැවති ඉහළම මිල සමාගම විසින් වාර්තා කර ඇති අතර විකුණුම් මිල රු. ආයතනයේ ප්‍රමුඛතම කර්මාන්ත ශාලාව වන KTFL පවත්වාගෙන යන කළමනාකාරීත්වයේ සහ සේවකයන්ගේ වෙහෙස මහන්සිය සහ ශ්‍රී ලංකාව තුළ අභිමානවත් ලෙස නිෂ්පාදනය කරන තේවල උසස් තත්ත්වය පිළිබඳ සාක්‍ෂියක් වන මෙම මූල්‍ය වර්ෂයේ දී රුපියල් 3250 ක් රු. තවද, 2022 ජූලි මාසයේදී, අඩු වගා කළ CTC තේවල සම්මානලාභී ශ්‍රේණි සපයන කුඩා තේ වතු හිමියන්ට රුපියල් මිලියනයක වාර්තාගත වන්දියක් පිරිනැමීමට සමාගම ආඩම්බර විය. කිලෝවක් 434.82 කි.",
        "ලාභය බොහෝ විට ශක්තිමත් නායකත්වයක සලකුණක් වන අතර, වර්ධනය සහ තිරසාර ස්ථාවරත්වය දිරිගන්වන සදාචාරාත්මක ව්‍යාපාරික භාවිතයන් තුළින් පත් කරන ලද උරුමයක් ගොඩනැගීමේ අරමුණින් විනිවිද පෙනෙන පාලන ක්‍රියාවලියක් යටතේ ක්‍රියාත්මක වීමේ වරප්‍රසාදය කළුබෝවිටියන තේවලට හිමිවන බව වැවිලි අමාත්‍ය ආචාර්ය රමේෂ් පතිරණ ප්‍රකාශ කළේය. අභිමානවත් තේ ජාතියක නියෝජිතයෙකු ලෙස කළුබෝවිටියන තේ පිරිසිදු ලංකා තේ වන ගුණාත්මක සංකේතයට ගෞරව කිරීම සඳහා තම ව්‍යාපාරයේ රන් ප්‍රමිතිය පවත්වා ගැනීමට කැපවී සිටී.",
        "රනිල්, සජිත් දෙවෙනි වටයේ සාකච්ඡා මීට වඩා හොඳ වෙලාවක එන්න බෑ",
        "පිළිතුරක් දෙන්න පිළිතුර අවලංගු කරන්න ඔබගේ විද්‍යුත් තැපැල් ලිපිනය ප්‍රකාශයට පත් නොකෙරේ. අවශ්‍ය ක්ෂේත්‍ර සලකුණු කර ඇත *අදහස් නම *",
        "මම ඊළඟ වතාවේ අදහස් දැක්වීම සඳහා මගේ නම, විද්‍යුත් තැපෑල සහ වෙබ් අඩවිය මෙම බ්‍රවුසරයේ සුරකින්න."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "රජයේ",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "කළුබෝවිටියාන තේ",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "1992 සැප්තැම්බර් 30 වැනිදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "සීමාසහිත කළුබෝවිටියන තේ කර්මාන්ත ශාලාව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "KTFL",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "හතර",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "කළුබෝවිටියාන",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "CTC",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "තුන්",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඕතඩොක්ස්",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "හතර",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "කළුබෝවිටියාන",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "දෙරංගල",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "මාතර දිස්ත්‍රික්කය",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "හිනිදුම කඳුකරය",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගාල්ල දිස්ත්‍රික්කය",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "මැණික්දිවෙල",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මහනුවර දිස්ත්‍රික්කය",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "4,000 ට වැඩි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "350 ට වැඩි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "KTFL",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "10,000 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "කළුබෝවිටියාන තේ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඔවුන්ගේ 2022 පළමු කාර්තුව",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මිලියන 583 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "රුපියල්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "මිලියන 222 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "අමින්ද රුද්‍රිගු",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "කළුබෝවිටියාන තේ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "CTC",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "50%",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "වත්මන් මූල්ය වර්ෂය",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "KTFL",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "2022 ජූලි",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "CTC",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "434.82 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "රමේෂ් පතිරණ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "කළුබෝවිටියාන තේ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "කළුබෝවිටියාන",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ලංකා තේ",
            "label": "PRODUCT"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [],
        []
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "அரசுக்கு சொந்தமான களுபோவிட்டியன தேயிலை புதிய உயரத்திற்கு உயர்ந்துள்ளது",
      "author": "திலின வல்பொல",
      "body_lines": [
        "1992 ஆம் ஆண்டு செப்டெம்பர் மாதம் 30 ஆம் திகதி இலங்கை அரசாங்கத்திற்கு முழுமையாக சொந்தமான பொது நிறுவனமாக இணைக்கப்பட்ட களுபோவிட்டியன தேயிலை தொழிற்சாலை லிமிடெட் (KTFL) தேசிய கட்டத்திற்கு நேரடியாக பங்களிக்கும் நான்கு தேயிலை தொழிற்சாலைகளை நடத்துகிறது. களுபோவிட்டியனவில் அமைந்துள்ள பிரதான தொழிற்சாலையானது குறைந்த பயிரிடப்பட்ட CTC தேயிலையை உற்பத்தி செய்து சாதனை படைக்கும் அதேவேளை ஏனைய மூன்று தொழிற்சாலைகள் ஆர்த்தடாக்ஸ் தேயிலையை உற்பத்தி செய்கின்றன. மாத்தறை மாவட்டத்தில் களுபோவிட்டியன மற்றும் தேரங்கல, காலி மாவட்டத்தில் ஹினிதும மலை மற்றும் கண்டி மாவட்டத்தில் மெனிக்திவெல ஆகிய இடங்களில் அமைந்துள்ள நான்கு தொழிற்சாலைகள் 4,000 இற்கும் மேற்பட்ட சிறு தேயிலை உடமையாளர்களின் வாழ்வாதாரத்தை செழுமைப்படுத்த அர்ப்பணிப்புடன் உள்ளன. KTFL 10,000+ பேருக்கு வழங்கும் இந்த பொருளாதார நன்மை மற்றும் ஸ்திரத்தன்மை, இன்று நாடு எதிர்கொள்ளும் கடுமையான பொருளாதார சிரமங்களை கருத்தில் கொண்டு சிறிய சாதனை அல்ல.",
        "சமீபத்திய செயல்பாட்டு சவால்களின் கவலைகளில் மூழ்கியிருக்கும் களுபோவிட்டியன தேயிலை, 2022 இன் முதல் காலாண்டில் ரூ. வருவாயுடன் முடிவடையும் குறிப்பிடத்தக்க சாதனையை அடைவதற்கு ஏற்ற இறக்கத்தின் மூலம் சிறந்த முறையில் வழிநடத்தியுள்ளது. 583 மில்லியன் மற்றும் நிகர லாபம் ரூ. 222 மில்லியன். களுபோவிட்டியன தேயிலையின் தலைவர் திரு. அமிந்த ரொட்ரிகோ, இதுவரை நடைபெற்ற பன்னிரெண்டு ஏலங்களில் 50%க்கும் அதிகமாக குறைந்த பயிரிடப்பட்ட CTC தேயிலைக்கான அதிகூடிய விலையை நிறுவனம் பதிவு செய்துள்ளதாக உறுதிப்படுத்தினார். நடப்பு நிதியாண்டில் 3250, இது நிறுவனத்தின் முதன்மை தொழிற்சாலையான KTFL ஐ இயக்கும் நிர்வாகம் மற்றும் ஊழியர்களின் கடின உழைப்பிற்கும், இலங்கையில் பெருமையுடன் உற்பத்தி செய்யப்படும் தேயிலையின் பிரீமியம் தரத்திற்கும் சான்றாகும். மேலும், 2022 ஆம் ஆண்டு ஜூலை மாதம், குறைந்த அளவு வளர்ந்த CTC தேயிலையின் விருது பெற்ற கிரேடுகளை வழங்கும் சிறு தேயிலை உரிமையாளர்களுக்கு, சாதனை முறியடிப்பு இழப்பீடாக ரூ. ஒரு கிலோவுக்கு 434.82.",
        "பெருந்தோட்ட அமைச்சர் கலாநிதி ரமேஷ் பத்திரன கூறுகையில், இலாபங்கள் பலம் வாய்ந்த தலைமைத்துவத்தின் அறிகுறியாகும், மேலும் களுபோவிட்டியன தேயிலைக்கு வெளிப்படையான ஆட்சியின் கீழ் இயங்கும் பாக்கியம் உள்ளது, இது வளர்ச்சி மற்றும் நிலையான ஸ்திரத்தன்மையை ஊக்குவிக்கும் நெறிமுறை வணிக நடைமுறைகள் மூலம் நியமிக்கப்பட்ட மரபுவழியை கட்டியெழுப்புவதை நோக்கமாகக் கொண்டுள்ளது. ஒரு பெருமைமிக்க தேயிலை தேசத்தின் பிரதிநிதியாக, களுபோவிட்டியன தேயிலை, தூய சிலோன் தேயிலையின் தரத்தின் அடையாளத்தை கௌரவிக்கும் வகையில் தங்களுடைய வணிகத்தின் தங்கத் தரத்தைப் பேணுவதற்கு அர்ப்பணிப்புடன் உள்ளது.",
        "ரணில், சஜித் 2வது சுற்று பேச்சுவார்த்தை நல்ல நேரத்தில் வரவில்லை",
        "ஒரு பதிலை விடுங்கள் பதிலை ரத்துசெய் உங்கள் மின்னஞ்சல் முகவரி வெளியிடப்படாது. தேவையான புலங்கள் குறிக்கப்பட்டுள்ளன *கருத்து பெயர் *",
        "அடுத்த முறை நான் கருத்து தெரிவிக்க, எனது பெயர், மின்னஞ்சல் மற்றும் இணையதளத்தை இந்த உலாவியில் சேமிக்கவும்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "நிலை",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "களுபோவிட்டியன தேநீர்",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "1992 ஆம் ஆண்டு செப்டம்பர் 30 ஆம் தேதி",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "களுபோவிட்டியன தேயிலை தொழிற்சாலை லிமிடெட்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "KTFL",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "நான்கு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "களுபோவிட்டியன",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "CTC",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "மூன்று",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆர்த்தடாக்ஸ்",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "நான்கு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "களுபோவிட்டியன",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "தேரங்கலா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "மாத்தறை மாவட்டம்",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஹினிடும மலைகள்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "காலி மாவட்டம்",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "மெனிக்திவெல",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "கண்டி மாவட்டம்",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "4,000க்கு மேல்",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "350க்கு மேல்",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "KTFL",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "10,000",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "களுபோவிட்டியன தேநீர்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "2022 இன் முதல் காலாண்டு",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "583 மில்லியன்",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரூ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "222 மில்லியன்",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "அமிண்டா ரோட்ரிகோ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "களுபோவிட்டியன தேநீர்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "CTC",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "50%",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "நடப்பு நிதியாண்டு",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "KTFL",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜூலை 2022",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "CTC",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "434.82",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ரமேஷ் பத்திரன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "களுபோவிட்டியன தேநீர்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "களுபோவிட்டியன",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சிலோன் டீ",
            "label": "PRODUCT"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [],
        []
      ]
    }
  }
}