{
  "newspaper_id": "ada-derana-lk",
  "url": "http://www.adaderana.lk/news/83236/four-anti-govt-activists-under-arrest-granted-bail",
  "time_ut": 1656067140,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Four anti-govt activists under arrest granted bail",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Four anti-govt activists under arrest granted bail",
      "body_lines": [
        "Four out of the seven youth activists from the ‘GotaGoGama’ anti-government protest site at the Galle Face Green who were under remand custody have been granted bail.",
        "Jagath Manuwarna, Jehan Appuhamy, Dhammika Munasinghe and Eranga Gunasekara are among the four activists who were released on bail by the Colombo Fort Magistrate’s Court.",
        "Meanwhile, the remaining three activists, namely YouTuber Rathindu Senaratne alias ‘Ratta’, Lahiru Weerasekara and Ven. Rathkarawwe Jinarathana Thero were remanded further.",
        "On June 17, the Colombo Fort Magistrate ordered the police to arrest 09 suspects for their unruly and violent behaviour during protests at Colombo Fort and Thalangama on the 9th and 10th of June and to produce them before the court.",
        "Several charges including criminal coercion, obstruction of duties of police officers, unlawful assembly, causing injuries and causing damages to public property have been levelled against them.",
        "Later, seven activists were taken into custody and placed under remand custody until the case is called today."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Four",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Four",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "seven",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Galle Face Green",
            "label": "FAC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Jagath Manuwarna",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Jehan Appuhamy",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Dhammika Munasinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Eranga Gunasekara",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "four",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Colombo Fort Magistrate’s Court",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "three",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "YouTuber Rathindu Senaratne",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Lahiru Weerasekara",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ven",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Jinarathana Thero",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "June 17",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Colombo Fort Magistrate",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "09",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Colombo Fort",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "Thalangama",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the 9th and 10th of June",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "seven",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "අත්අඩංගුවට ගෙන සිටි රාජ්‍ය විරෝධීන් 4 දෙනෙකුට ඇප",
      "body_lines": [
        "රිමාන්ඩ් භාරයේ සිටි ගාලුමුවදොර ‘ගොටගොගම’ රාජ්‍ය විරෝධී උද්ඝෝෂණ භූමියේ තරුණ ක්‍රියාකාරීන් හත් දෙනාගෙන් 4 දෙනෙකුට ඇප නියම වී තිබේ.",
        "ජගත් මනුවර්ණ, ජෙහාන් අප්පුහාමි, ධම්මික මුණසිංහ සහ එරංග ගුණසේකර යන ක්‍රියාකාරීන් සිව්දෙනා කොළඹ කොටුව මහේස්ත්‍රාත් අධිකරණය විසින් ඇප මත මුදා හැර තිබේ.",
        "මේ අතර, ඉතිරි ක්‍රියාකාරීන් තිදෙනා වන යූ ටියුබර් රතිඳු සේනාරත්න හෙවත් ‘රට්ටා’, ලහිරු වීරසේකර සහ පූජ්‍ය හිමි රත්කරව්වේ ජිනරතන හිමියන් තවදුරටත් රක්ෂිත බන්ධනාගාර ගත කෙරුණා.",
        "ජුනි මස 9 සහ 10 යන දිනවල කොළඹ කොටුවේ සහ තලංගම ප්‍රදේශවල පැවති විරෝධතා අතරතුර කලහකාරී සහ ප්‍රචණ්ඩකාරී ලෙස හැසිරීම සම්බන්ධයෙන් සැකකරුවන් 09 දෙනෙකු අත්අඩංගුවට ගෙන අධිකරණයට ඉදිරිපත් කරන ලෙස කොළඹ කොටුව මහේස්ත්‍රාත්වරයා ජුනි 17 වනදා පොලිසියට නියෝග කළේය.",
        "සාපරාධී බලහත්කාරය, පොලිස් නිලධාරීන්ගේ රාජකාරියට බාධා කිරීම, නීතිවිරෝධී රැස්වීම්, තුවාල සිදුකිරීම, පොදු දේපළවලට හානි කිරීම ඇතුළු චෝදනා කිහිපයක් ඔවුන්ට එල්ල වී තිබේ.",
        "පසුව, ක්‍රියාකාරීන් හත් දෙනෙකු අත්අඩංගුවට ගෙන අද නඩුව කැඳවන තෙක් රිමාන්ඩ් භාරයට පත් කෙරිණි."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "හතර",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "හතර",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "හත",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගාලු මුවදොර පිටිය",
            "label": "FAC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ජගත් මනුවර්ණ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජෙහාන් අප්පුහාමි",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ධම්මික මුණසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Eranga Gunasekara",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "හතර",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "කොළඹ කොටුව මහේස්ත්‍රාත් අධිකරණයේදී",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "තුන්",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "YouTuber රතිඳු සේනාරත්න",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ලහිරු වීරසේකර",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "හාමුදුරුවෝ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජිනරතන හිමි",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ජූනි 17",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "කොළඹ කොටුව මහේස්ත්‍රාත්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "09",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "කොළඹ කොටුව",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "තලංගම",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජුනි 9 සහ 10",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "හත",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "கைது செய்யப்பட்ட 4 அரசு எதிர்ப்பாளர்களுக்கு ஜாமீன் வழங்கப்பட்டது",
      "body_lines": [
        "விளக்கமறியலில் வைக்கப்பட்டிருந்த காலிமுகத்திடலில் உள்ள ‘கொட்டகோகம’ அரசாங்க எதிர்ப்புப் போராட்டத் தளத்தைச் சேர்ந்த ஏழு இளைஞர் செயற்பாட்டாளர்களில் நால்வருக்கு பிணை வழங்கப்பட்டுள்ளது.",
        "ஜகத் மனுவர்ண, ஜெஹான் அப்புஹாமி, தம்மிக்க முனசிங்க மற்றும் எரங்க குணசேகர ஆகிய நான்கு செயற்பாட்டாளர்கள் கொழும்பு கோட்டை நீதவான் நீதிமன்றினால் பிணையில் விடுவிக்கப்பட்டுள்ளனர்.",
        "இதேவேளை, எஞ்சிய மூன்று செயற்பாட்டாளர்களான யூடியூபர் ரதிந்து சேனாரத்ன என்ற ‘ரட்டா’, லஹிரு வீரசேகர மற்றும் வண. ரத்கரவ்வே ஜினரதன தேரர் மேலும் விளக்கமறியலில் வைக்கப்பட்டுள்ளார்.",
        "ஜூன் 9 மற்றும் 10 ஆம் திகதிகளில் கொழும்பு கோட்டை மற்றும் தலங்கமவில் இடம்பெற்ற ஆர்ப்பாட்டங்களின் போது கட்டுக்கடங்காத மற்றும் வன்முறையில் ஈடுபட்ட 09 சந்தேக நபர்களை கைது செய்து நீதிமன்றத்தில் ஆஜர்படுத்துமாறு கடந்த ஜூன் 17 ஆம் திகதி கொழும்பு கோட்டை நீதவான் பொலிஸாருக்கு உத்தரவிட்டார்.",
        "குற்றவியல் நிர்ப்பந்தம், காவல்துறை அதிகாரிகளின் பணியைத் தடுத்தல், சட்டவிரோதமாக ஒன்றுகூடல், காயங்களை ஏற்படுத்துதல், பொதுச் சொத்துக்களுக்கு சேதம் விளைவித்தல் உள்ளிட்ட பல குற்றச்சாட்டுகள் அவர்கள் மீது சுமத்தப்பட்டுள்ளன.",
        "பின்னர், ஏழு ஆர்வலர்கள் காவலில் வைக்கப்பட்டு, வழக்கு இன்று அழைக்கப்படும் வரை விளக்கமறியலில் வைக்கப்பட்டனர்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "நான்கு",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "நான்கு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஏழு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Galle Face Green",
            "label": "FAC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஜகத் மனுவர்ண",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜெஹான் அப்புஹாமி",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "தம்மிக்க முனசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Eranga Gunasekara",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "நான்கு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "கொழும்பு கோட்டை நீதவான் நீதிமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "மூன்று",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "யூடியூபர் ரதிந்து சேனாரத்ன",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "லஹிரு வீரசேகர",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "வண",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜினரதன தேரோ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஜூன் 17",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "கொழும்பு கோட்டை நீதவான்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "09",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "கொழும்பு கோட்டை",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "தலங்கம",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜூன் 9 மற்றும் 10",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஏழு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  },
  "title": "Four anti-govt activists under arrest granted bail",
  "body_lines": [
    "Four out of the seven youth activists from the ‘GotaGoGama’ anti-government protest site at the Galle Face Green who were under remand custody have been granted bail.",
    "Jagath Manuwarna, Jehan Appuhamy, Dhammika Munasinghe and Eranga Gunasekara are among the four activists who were released on bail by the Colombo Fort Magistrate’s Court.",
    "Meanwhile, the remaining three activists, namely YouTuber Rathindu Senaratne alias ‘Ratta’, Lahiru Weerasekara and Ven. Rathkarawwe Jinarathana Thero were remanded further.",
    "On June 17, the Colombo Fort Magistrate ordered the police to arrest 09 suspects for their unruly and violent behaviour during protests at Colombo Fort and Thalangama on the 9th and 10th of June and to produce them before the court.",
    "Several charges including criminal coercion, obstruction of duties of police officers, unlawful assembly, causing injuries and causing damages to public property have been levelled against them.",
    "Later, seven activists were taken into custody and placed under remand custody until the case is called today."
  ],
  "translate": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Four anti-govt activists under arrest granted bail",
      "body_lines": [
        "Four out of the seven youth activists from the ‘GotaGoGama’ anti-government protest site at the Galle Face Green who were under remand custody have been granted bail.",
        "Jagath Manuwarna, Jehan Appuhamy, Dhammika Munasinghe and Eranga Gunasekara are among the four activists who were released on bail by the Colombo Fort Magistrate’s Court.",
        "Meanwhile, the remaining three activists, namely YouTuber Rathindu Senaratne alias ‘Ratta’, Lahiru Weerasekara and Ven. Rathkarawwe Jinarathana Thero were remanded further.",
        "On June 17, the Colombo Fort Magistrate ordered the police to arrest 09 suspects for their unruly and violent behaviour during protests at Colombo Fort and Thalangama on the 9th and 10th of June and to produce them before the court.",
        "Several charges including criminal coercion, obstruction of duties of police officers, unlawful assembly, causing injuries and causing damages to public property have been levelled against them.",
        "Later, seven activists were taken into custody and placed under remand custody until the case is called today."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Four",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Four",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "seven",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Galle Face Green",
            "label": "FAC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Jagath Manuwarna",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Jehan Appuhamy",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Dhammika Munasinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Eranga Gunasekara",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "four",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Colombo Fort Magistrate’s Court",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "three",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "YouTuber Rathindu Senaratne",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Lahiru Weerasekara",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ven",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Jinarathana Thero",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "June 17",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Colombo Fort Magistrate",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "09",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Colombo Fort",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "Thalangama",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the 9th and 10th of June",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "seven",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "අත්අඩංගුවට ගෙන සිටි රාජ්‍ය විරෝධීන් 4 දෙනෙකුට ඇප",
      "body_lines": [
        "රිමාන්ඩ් භාරයේ සිටි ගාලුමුවදොර ‘ගොටගොගම’ රාජ්‍ය විරෝධී උද්ඝෝෂණ භූමියේ තරුණ ක්‍රියාකාරීන් හත් දෙනාගෙන් 4 දෙනෙකුට ඇප නියම වී තිබේ.",
        "ජගත් මනුවර්ණ, ජෙහාන් අප්පුහාමි, ධම්මික මුණසිංහ සහ එරංග ගුණසේකර යන ක්‍රියාකාරීන් සිව්දෙනා කොළඹ කොටුව මහේස්ත්‍රාත් අධිකරණය විසින් ඇප මත මුදා හැර තිබේ.",
        "මේ අතර, ඉතිරි ක්‍රියාකාරීන් තිදෙනා වන යූ ටියුබර් රතිඳු සේනාරත්න හෙවත් ‘රට්ටා’, ලහිරු වීරසේකර සහ පූජ්‍ය හිමි රත්කරව්වේ ජිනරතන හිමියන් තවදුරටත් රක්ෂිත බන්ධනාගාර ගත කෙරුණා.",
        "ජුනි මස 9 සහ 10 යන දිනවල කොළඹ කොටුවේ සහ තලංගම ප්‍රදේශවල පැවති විරෝධතා අතරතුර කලහකාරී සහ ප්‍රචණ්ඩකාරී ලෙස හැසිරීම සම්බන්ධයෙන් සැකකරුවන් 09 දෙනෙකු අත්අඩංගුවට ගෙන අධිකරණයට ඉදිරිපත් කරන ලෙස කොළඹ කොටුව මහේස්ත්‍රාත්වරයා ජුනි 17 වනදා පොලිසියට නියෝග කළේය.",
        "සාපරාධී බලහත්කාරය, පොලිස් නිලධාරීන්ගේ රාජකාරියට බාධා කිරීම, නීතිවිරෝධී රැස්වීම්, තුවාල සිදුකිරීම, පොදු දේපළවලට හානි කිරීම ඇතුළු චෝදනා කිහිපයක් ඔවුන්ට එල්ල වී තිබේ.",
        "පසුව, ක්‍රියාකාරීන් හත් දෙනෙකු අත්අඩංගුවට ගෙන අද නඩුව කැඳවන තෙක් රිමාන්ඩ් භාරයට පත් කෙරිණි."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "හතර",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "හතර",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "හත",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගාලු මුවදොර පිටිය",
            "label": "FAC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ජගත් මනුවර්ණ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජෙහාන් අප්පුහාමි",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ධම්මික මුණසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Eranga Gunasekara",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "හතර",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "කොළඹ කොටුව මහේස්ත්‍රාත් අධිකරණයේදී",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "තුන්",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "YouTuber රතිඳු සේනාරත්න",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ලහිරු වීරසේකර",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "හාමුදුරුවෝ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජිනරතන හිමි",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ජූනි 17",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "කොළඹ කොටුව මහේස්ත්‍රාත්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "09",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "කොළඹ කොටුව",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "තලංගම",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජුනි 9 සහ 10",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "හත",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "கைது செய்யப்பட்ட 4 அரசு எதிர்ப்பாளர்களுக்கு ஜாமீன் வழங்கப்பட்டது",
      "body_lines": [
        "விளக்கமறியலில் வைக்கப்பட்டிருந்த காலிமுகத்திடலில் உள்ள ‘கொட்டகோகம’ அரசாங்க எதிர்ப்புப் போராட்டத் தளத்தைச் சேர்ந்த ஏழு இளைஞர் செயற்பாட்டாளர்களில் நால்வருக்கு பிணை வழங்கப்பட்டுள்ளது.",
        "ஜகத் மனுவர்ண, ஜெஹான் அப்புஹாமி, தம்மிக்க முனசிங்க மற்றும் எரங்க குணசேகர ஆகிய நான்கு செயற்பாட்டாளர்கள் கொழும்பு கோட்டை நீதவான் நீதிமன்றினால் பிணையில் விடுவிக்கப்பட்டுள்ளனர்.",
        "இதேவேளை, எஞ்சிய மூன்று செயற்பாட்டாளர்களான யூடியூபர் ரதிந்து சேனாரத்ன என்ற ‘ரட்டா’, லஹிரு வீரசேகர மற்றும் வண. ரத்கரவ்வே ஜினரதன தேரர் மேலும் விளக்கமறியலில் வைக்கப்பட்டுள்ளார்.",
        "ஜூன் 9 மற்றும் 10 ஆம் திகதிகளில் கொழும்பு கோட்டை மற்றும் தலங்கமவில் இடம்பெற்ற ஆர்ப்பாட்டங்களின் போது கட்டுக்கடங்காத மற்றும் வன்முறையில் ஈடுபட்ட 09 சந்தேக நபர்களை கைது செய்து நீதிமன்றத்தில் ஆஜர்படுத்துமாறு கடந்த ஜூன் 17 ஆம் திகதி கொழும்பு கோட்டை நீதவான் பொலிஸாருக்கு உத்தரவிட்டார்.",
        "குற்றவியல் நிர்ப்பந்தம், காவல்துறை அதிகாரிகளின் பணியைத் தடுத்தல், சட்டவிரோதமாக ஒன்றுகூடல், காயங்களை ஏற்படுத்துதல், பொதுச் சொத்துக்களுக்கு சேதம் விளைவித்தல் உள்ளிட்ட பல குற்றச்சாட்டுகள் அவர்கள் மீது சுமத்தப்பட்டுள்ளன.",
        "பின்னர், ஏழு ஆர்வலர்கள் காவலில் வைக்கப்பட்டு, வழக்கு இன்று அழைக்கப்படும் வரை விளக்கமறியலில் வைக்கப்பட்டனர்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "நான்கு",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "நான்கு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஏழு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Galle Face Green",
            "label": "FAC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஜகத் மனுவர்ண",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜெஹான் அப்புஹாமி",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "தம்மிக்க முனசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Eranga Gunasekara",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "நான்கு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "கொழும்பு கோட்டை நீதவான் நீதிமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "மூன்று",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "யூடியூபர் ரதிந்து சேனாரத்ன",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "லஹிரு வீரசேகர",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "வண",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜினரதன தேரோ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஜூன் 17",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "கொழும்பு கோட்டை நீதவான்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "09",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "கொழும்பு கோட்டை",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "தலங்கம",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜூன் 9 மற்றும் 10",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஏழு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}