{
  "newspaper_id": "news-first-lk",
  "url": "https://www.newsfirst.lk/2022/08/15/indian-navy-vice-admiral-in-colombo-15/",
  "time_ut": 1660534980,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Indian Navy Vice Admiral in Colombo (15)",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Indian Navy Vice Admiral in Colombo (15)",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); The Defence Officials in India said Navy Vice Chief Vice Admiral Satish N Ghormade arrived in Sri Lanka on Sunday (14) to hand over the Dornier maritime patrol aircraft to the island country’s military.",
        "According to the Defence official both sides to discussed other bilateral issues to enhance defence cooperation.",
        "Furthermore, the aircraft would be operated by the Sri Lankan Air Force crew who have been trained in India.",
        "According to an earlier report, the Government of India may provide one Dornier 228 Maritime Patrol Aircraft from the Indian Naval Fleet on a gratis basis for two years. The aircraft is being provided for an interim period of two years till a plane being manufactured in India for Sri Lanka is ready.",
        "The aircraft comes as a sequel to the dialogue between India and Sri Lanka that took place on January 9, 2018, in New Delhi, when the Sri Lankan government sought the possibility of obtaining two Dornier Reconnaissance Aircraft from India.",
        "The Indian Naval Dornier (INDO – 228) is basically a Short Take-Off and Landing (STOL), multirole light transport aircraft used by the Indian Navy for electronic warfare missions, maritime surveillance, disaster relief and other work with a turboprop twin-engine, produced since 1981.",
        "The first ever Dornier will be inducted to SLAF Fleet on August 15, 2022, in a ceremonial procession under the patronage by the Sri Lanka President, Ranil Wickremesinghe and High Commissioner of India, India’s High Commissioner in Colombo, Gopal Baglay.",
        "The aircraft will be flown and maintained only by 15 SLAF crew who were specifically trained in India for a period of four months.",
        "The crew who received training consisted of pilots, observers, engineering officers and technicians along with the supervision by the GOI technical team attached to SLAF comprising of engineering officers and technicians.",
        "India continues to assist Sri Lanka in its economic development to overcome its economic challenges under its ‘Neighbourhood First’ policy. In line with this policy, India continues to assist Sri Lanka in its economic development and also supports it in overcoming its economic challenges. India is becoming a stronger and more mutually beneficial partner to Sri Lanka. Apart from assistance during the pandemic and fertilizer chaos, India is also donating basic products to the island nation.",
        "Sri Lanka has been suffering a diesel shortage since February, which led to hours of daily power cuts. Presently, Sri Lanka is struggling with acute food and electricity shortages, forcing the country to seek help from its neighbours.",
        "India under its ‘Neighbourhood First’ policy, has always come forward to help the debt-ridden island country. Recently, India has extended 8 Lines of Credit (LOCs) to Sri Lanka amounting to USD 1,850.64 million in the past 10 years.(ANI)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Indian Navy",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "Colombo",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "15",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "News 1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "The Defence Officials",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "India",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Navy",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Satish N Ghormade",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sunday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Dornier",
            "label": "LOC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Defence",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the Sri Lankan Air Force",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "India",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the Government of India",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "one",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Indian Naval Fleet",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "two years",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "two years",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "India",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "India",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "January 9, 2018",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "New Delhi",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lankan",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "two",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Dornier Reconnaissance Aircraft",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "India",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Indian",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "228",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "STOL",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Indian Navy",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "1981",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "first",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Dornier",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "SLAF Fleet",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "August 15, 2022",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "India",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "India",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Colombo",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Gopal Baglay",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "15",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "India",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "a period of four months",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "GOI",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "India",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "India",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "India",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "India",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "February",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "India",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "India",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "8",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "USD 1,850.64 million",
            "label": "LAW"
          },
          {
            "text": "the past 10",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "ඉන්දීය නාවික හමුදාවේ වයිස් අද්මිරාල් කොළඹ (15)",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); ඩෝනියර් සමුද්‍ර මුර සංචාර ගුවන් යානය දිවයිනේ හමුදාවට භාරදීම සඳහා නාවික හමුදා උප ප්‍රධානී වයිස් අද්මිරාල් සතිෂ් එන් ගෝර්මඩේ ඉරිදා (14) ශ්‍රී ලංකාවට පැමිණි බව ඉන්දියාවේ ආරක්ෂක නිලධාරීහු පැවසූහ.",
        "ආරක්ෂක සහයෝගීතාව වැඩි දියුණු කිරීම සඳහා දෙපාර්ශ්වයම අනෙකුත් ද්විපාර්ශ්වික කරුණු පිළිබඳව සාකච්ඡා කිරීමට ආරක්ෂක නිලධාරියාට අනුව.",
        "තවද, මෙම ගුවන් යානය මෙහෙයවනු ලබන්නේ ඉන්දියාවේ පුහුණුව ලැබූ ශ්‍රී ලංකා ගුවන් හමුදා කාර්ය මණ්ඩලය විසිනි.",
        "පෙර වාර්තාවකට අනුව, ඉන්දියානු රජය විසින් වසර දෙකක කාලයක් සඳහා ඉන්දියානු නාවික බලඇණියෙන් එක් ඩෝනියර් 228 සමුද්‍ර මුර සංචාර ගුවන් යානයක් නොමිලේ ලබා දිය හැකිය. ශ්‍රී ලංකාව සඳහා ඉන්දියාවේ නිෂ්පාදනය කෙරෙන ගුවන් යානයක් සූදානම් වන තෙක් වසර දෙකක අන්තර් කාලසීමාවක් සඳහා මෙම ගුවන් යානය ලබාදීමට නියමිතය.",
        "මෙම ගුවන් යානය පැමිණෙන්නේ 2018 ජනවාරි 9 වන දින නවදිල්ලියේ දී ශ්‍රී ලංකා රජය ඉන්දියාවෙන් ඩෝනියර් ඔත්තු බැලීමේ ගුවන් යානා දෙකක් ලබා ගැනීමේ හැකියාව සොයන විට ඉන්දියාව සහ ශ්‍රී ලංකාව අතර ඇති වූ සංවාදයේ අනුප්‍රාප්තිකයක් ලෙස ය.",
        "ඉන්දියානු නාවික හමුදා ඩෝනියර් (INDO - 228) යනු මූලික වශයෙන් කෙටි ගුවන්ගත කිරීම් සහ ගොඩබෑම (STOL), බහුකාර්ය සැහැල්ලු ප්‍රවාහන ගුවන් යානයක් වන අතර එය ඉලෙක්ට්‍රොනික යුධ මෙහෙයුම්, සමුද්‍ර නිරීක්ෂණ, ආපදා සහන සහ ටර්බෝප්‍රොප් ද්විත්ව එන්ජිමක් සහිත වෙනත් වැඩ සඳහා ඉන්දියානු නාවික හමුදාව භාවිතා කරයි. 1981 සිට නිෂ්පාදනය කරන ලදී.",
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකා ජනාධිපති රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ සහ ඉන්දීය මහ කොමසාරිස්, කොළඹ ඉන්දීය මහ කොමසාරිස් ගෝපාල් බග්ලේ යන මහත්වරුන්ගේ ප්‍රධානත්වයෙන් 2022 අගෝස්තු 15 වන දින චාරිත්‍රානුකූල පෙරහැරකින් ප්‍රථම ඩෝනියර් යානය ශ්‍රී ලංකා ගුවන් හමුදා බලඇණියට ඇතුළත් කරනු ලැබේ.",
        "මෙම ගුවන් යානය පියාසර කර නඩත්තු කරනු ලබන්නේ මාස හතරක කාලයක් සඳහා ඉන්දියාවේ විශේෂ පුහුණුවක් ලැබූ ගුවන් හමුදා කාර්ය මණ්ඩලය 15 දෙනෙකු විසින් පමණි.",
        "පුහුණුව ලැබූ කාර්ය මණ්ඩලය ගුවන් නියමුවන්, නිරීක්ෂකයින්, ඉංජිනේරු නිලධාරීන් සහ කාර්මික ශිල්පීන්ගෙන් සමන්විත වූ අතර ඉංජිනේරු නිලධාරීන් සහ කාර්මික ශිල්පීන්ගෙන් සමන්විත ගුවන් හමුදාවට අනුයුක්ත GOI තාක්ෂණික කණ්ඩායම විසින් අධීක්ෂණය කරන ලදී.",
        "ඉන්දියාව සිය ‘අසල්වැසි ප්‍රථම’ ප්‍රතිපත්තිය යටතේ ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ ආර්ථික අභියෝග ජය ගැනීම සඳහා ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ ආර්ථික සංවර්ධනය සඳහා අඛණ්ඩව සහාය වේ. මෙම ප්‍රතිපත්තියට අනුකූලව ඉන්දියාව ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ ආර්ථික සංවර්ධනය සඳහා අඛණ්ඩව සහය වන අතර එහි ආර්ථික අභියෝග ජය ගැනීම සඳහා ද සහාය දක්වයි. ඉන්දියාව ශ්‍රී ලංකාවට වඩාත් ශක්තිමත් සහ අන්‍යෝන්‍ය වශයෙන් වාසිදායක හවුල්කරුවෙකු බවට පත්වෙමින් තිබේ. වසංගතය සහ පොහොර අවුල් සහගත කාලය තුළ ආධාර හැරුණු විට, ඉන්දියාව දිවයිනේ ජාතියට මූලික නිෂ්පාදන ද පරිත්‍යාග කරයි.",
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකාව පෙබරවාරි මාසයේ සිට ඩීසල් හිඟයකින් පෙළෙන අතර එය දිනපතා පැය ගණනක් විදුලිය විසන්ධි කිරීමට හේතු විය. වර්තමානයේදී, ශ්‍රී ලංකාව උග්‍ර ආහාර සහ විදුලි හිඟයකින් පොරබදමින් සිටින අතර, අසල්වැසියන්ගෙන් උපකාර පැතීමට රටට බල කෙරෙයි.",
        "ඉන්දියාව සිය 'අසල්වැසි ප්‍රථම' ප්‍රතිපත්තිය යටතේ, ණය බරින් පෙළෙන දූපත් රටට උපකාර කිරීමට සැමවිටම ඉදිරිපත් වී ඇත. මෑතදී, ඉන්දියාව පසුගිය වසර 10 තුළ ශ්‍රී ලංකාවට ණය රේඛා 8ක් (LOC) ලබා දී ඇති අතර එය ඩොලර් මිලියන 1,850.64 කි. (ANI)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ඉන්දීය නාවික හමුදාව",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "කොළඹ",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "15",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "News 1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ආරක්ෂක නිලධාරීන්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "නාවික",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "සතිෂ් එන් ගෝර්මඩේ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉරිදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඩෝනියර්",
            "label": "LOC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ආරක්ෂක",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකා ගුවන් හමුදාව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දීය රජය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "එක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දියානු නාවික බලඇණිය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "අවුරුදු දෙකක්",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "අවුරුදු දෙකක්",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "2018 ජනවාරි 9",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "නව දිල්ලි",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලාංකික",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "දෙක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඩෝනියර් ඔත්තු බැලීමේ ගුවන් යානය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දීය",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "228",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "STOL",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දියානු නාවික හමුදාව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "1981",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "පළමුවන",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඩෝනියර්",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගුවන් හමුදා බලඇණිය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "2022 අගෝස්තු 15",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "කොළඹ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගෝපාල් බග්ලේ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "15",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මාස හතරක කාලයක්",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "GOI",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "පෙබරවාරි",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "8",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඩොලර් මිලියන 1,850.64 කි",
            "label": "LAW"
          },
          {
            "text": "පසුගිය 10",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "கொழும்பில் இந்திய கடற்படை வைஸ் அட்மிரல் (15)",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); டோர்னியர் கடல் ரோந்து விமானத்தை தீவு நாட்டு இராணுவத்திடம் கையளிப்பதற்காக கடற்படையின் துணைத் தலைமை அதிகாரி வைஸ் அட்மிரல் சதீஷ் என் கோர்மேட் ஞாயிற்றுக்கிழமை (14) இலங்கை வந்தடைந்ததாக இந்தியாவிலுள்ள பாதுகாப்பு அதிகாரிகள் தெரிவித்தனர்.",
        "பாதுகாப்பு அதிகாரிகளின் கூற்றுப்படி, இருதரப்பு பாதுகாப்பு ஒத்துழைப்பை மேம்படுத்துவதற்கு மற்ற இருதரப்பு விவகாரங்கள் குறித்து விவாதிக்கப்பட்டது.",
        "மேலும், இந்த விமானம் இந்தியாவில் பயிற்சி பெற்ற இலங்கை விமானப்படை பணியாளர்களால் இயக்கப்படும்.",
        "முந்தைய அறிக்கையின்படி, இந்திய அரசு ஒரு டோர்னியர் 228 கடல்சார் ரோந்து விமானத்தை இந்திய கடற்படைக் கடற்படையிலிருந்து இரண்டு ஆண்டுகளுக்கு இலவசமாக வழங்கலாம். இலங்கைக்காக இந்தியாவில் தயாரிக்கப்படும் விமானம் தயாராகும் வரை இரண்டு ஆண்டுகளுக்கு இடைக்காலமாக இந்த விமானம் வழங்கப்படும்.",
        "ஜனவரி 9, 2018 அன்று புதுடெல்லியில் இந்தியாவிற்கும் இலங்கைக்கும் இடையிலான உரையாடலின் தொடர்ச்சியாக இந்த விமானம் வருகிறது, அப்போது இலங்கை அரசாங்கம் இரண்டு டோர்னியர் உளவு விமானங்களை இந்தியாவிடமிருந்து பெறுவதற்கான வாய்ப்பை நாடியது.",
        "இந்திய கடற்படை டோர்னியர் (INDO - 228) அடிப்படையில் ஒரு குறுகிய டேக்-ஆஃப் மற்றும் லேண்டிங் (STOL), மின்னணு போர்ப் பணிகள், கடல்சார் கண்காணிப்பு, பேரிடர் நிவாரணம் மற்றும் டர்போபிராப் இரட்டை இயந்திரத்துடன் கூடிய பிற வேலைகளுக்காக இந்திய கடற்படையால் பயன்படுத்தப்படும் மல்டிரோல் இலகுரக போக்குவரத்து விமானமாகும். , 1981 முதல் தயாரிக்கப்பட்டது.",
        "இலங்கை ஜனாதிபதி ரணில் விக்ரமசிங்கே மற்றும் இந்திய உயர் ஸ்தானிகர், கொழும்பில் உள்ள இந்திய உயர் ஸ்தானிகர் கோபால் பாக்லே ஆகியோரின் அனுசரணையின் கீழ் சம்பிரதாய அணிவகுப்பில் ஆகஸ்ட் 15, 2022 அன்று முதல் டோர்னியர் SLAF கடற்படையில் இணைக்கப்படும்.",
        "நான்கு மாத காலத்திற்கு இந்தியாவில் குறிப்பாக பயிற்சி பெற்ற 15 SLAF குழுவினரால் மட்டுமே இந்த விமானம் பறந்து பராமரிக்கப்படும்.",
        "பயிற்சி பெற்ற குழுவினர் விமானிகள், பார்வையாளர்கள், பொறியியல் அதிகாரிகள் மற்றும் தொழில்நுட்ப வல்லுநர்கள் மற்றும் பொறியியல் அதிகாரிகள் மற்றும் தொழில்நுட்ப வல்லுநர்கள் அடங்கிய SLAF உடன் இணைக்கப்பட்ட GOI தொழில்நுட்பக் குழுவின் மேற்பார்வையுடன் இருந்தனர்.",
        "இந்தியா தனது ‘அண்டை நாடுகளுக்கு முதலில்’ கொள்கையின் கீழ் அதன் பொருளாதார சவால்களை வெற்றிகொள்வதற்கு இலங்கைக்கு அதன் பொருளாதார வளர்ச்சியில் தொடர்ந்து உதவி வருகிறது. இந்தக் கொள்கைக்கு இணங்க, இலங்கையின் பொருளாதார வளர்ச்சியில் இந்தியா தொடர்ந்து உதவி வருவதுடன், அதன் பொருளாதார சவால்களை முறியடிப்பதற்கும் ஆதரவளிக்கிறது. இலங்கைக்கு இந்தியா பலமான மற்றும் பரஸ்பர நன்மை பயக்கும் பங்காளியாக மாறி வருகிறது. தொற்றுநோய் மற்றும் உரக் குழப்பத்தின் போது உதவியைத் தவிர, இந்தியா தீவு நாட்டிற்கு அடிப்படை தயாரிப்புகளையும் நன்கொடையாக வழங்குகிறது.",
        "இலங்கையில் பெப்ரவரி மாதம் முதல் டீசல் தட்டுப்பாடு ஏற்பட்டுள்ளதால், தினசரி பல மணிநேர மின்வெட்டு ஏற்பட்டது. தற்போது, ​​இலங்கை கடுமையான உணவு மற்றும் மின்சார தட்டுப்பாட்டுடன் போராடி வருவதால், அண்டை நாடுகளின் உதவியை நாட வேண்டிய கட்டாயத்தில் உள்ளது.",
        "இந்தியா தனது ‘அண்டை நாடுகளுக்கு முதலில்’ கொள்கையின் கீழ், கடனில் சிக்கித் தவிக்கும் தீவு நாட்டிற்கு எப்போதும் உதவ முன்வந்துள்ளது. சமீபத்தில், இந்தியா கடந்த 10 ஆண்டுகளில் 1,850.64 மில்லியன் அமெரிக்க டாலர்களை இலங்கைக்கு 8 கடன் வரிகளை (LOCs) நீட்டித்துள்ளது.(ANI)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "இந்திய கடற்படை",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "கொழும்பு",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "15",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "News 1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாதுகாப்பு அதிகாரிகள்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்தியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "கடற்படை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "சதீஷ் என் கோர்மேட்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஞாயிற்றுக்கிழமை",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "டோர்னியர்",
            "label": "LOC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பாதுகாப்பு",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை விமானப்படை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்தியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இந்திய அரசு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஒன்று",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்திய கடற்படை கடற்படை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இரண்டு ஆண்டுகளுக்கு",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இரண்டு ஆண்டுகளுக்கு",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்தியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இந்தியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜனவரி 9, 2018",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "புது தில்லி",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "இரண்டு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "டோர்னியர் உளவு விமானம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்தியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இந்தியன்",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "228",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "STOL",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்திய கடற்படை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "1981",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "முதலில்",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "டோர்னியர்",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "SLAF கடற்படை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆகஸ்ட் 15, 2022",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்தியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்தியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "கொழும்பு",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "கோபால் பாக்லே",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "15",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்தியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "நான்கு மாத காலம்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "GOI",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இந்தியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்தியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்தியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்தியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "பிப்ரவரி",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இந்தியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்தியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "8",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "USD 1,850.64 மில்லியன்",
            "label": "LAW"
          },
          {
            "text": "கடந்த 10",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}