{
  "newspaper_id": "ada-derana-lk",
  "url": "http://www.adaderana.lk/news/83640/president-rajapaksa-leaves-maldives-on-saudi-plane-report",
  "time_ut": 1657783560,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "President Rajapaksa leaves Maldives on Saudi plane - report",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "President Rajapaksa leaves Maldives on Saudi plane - report",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "Sri Lanka’s embattled President Gotabaya Rajapaksa has left Maldives after fleeing his own country amid an economic collapse, foreign media reported today.",
        "He boarded a Saudi Airlines plane that will take him to Singapore and then to Jeddah, Saudi Arabia, a Maldives government official said Thursday. The official spoke on condition of anonymity because of the sensitivity of the matter, AP reported.",
        "Rajapaksa fled Sri Lanka early Wednesday as protesters were taking over government buildings to demand he resign.",
        "With the country sinking into political chaos, President Gotabaya Rajapaksa and his wife fled to the Maldives on Wednesday aboard a military aircraft. He made the prime minister acting president in his absence — a move that further roiled passions among a public that blames Rajapaksa for an economic crisis that has caused severe shortages of food and fuel.",
        "Rajapaksa had promised to resign by Wednesday night, and since Sri Lankan presidents are protected from arrest while in power it’s likely he planned his departure while he still had constitutional immunity and access to a military jet. It was unclear exactly where he was in the Maldives, an archipelago of hundreds of islands dotted with luxury tourist resorts, and where he planned to travel next.",
        "Troops in green military uniforms and camouflage vests arrived by armored personnel carriers at the parliament building, anticipating more protests after a group attempted to storm the entrance the previous day, clashing with police who fended them off with tear gas and batons.",
        "Some protesters posted videos on social media pleading with others not to storm the Parliament, fearing an escalation of violence.",
        "Wickremesinghe’s office has imposed a state of emergency giving broader powers to the military and police. Defense leaders have called for calm and cooperation with security forces — comments that have rankled some lawmakers who insist civilian leaders would be the ones to find a solution.",
        "The protesters blame Rajapaksa and his powerful, dynastic family for leading the country into an economic abyss, but they are also furious with Wickremesinghe, whom they accuse of protecting the president. Many believe that his appointment in May alleviated pressure on Rajapaksa to resign.",
        "Both leaders said after the protests escalated over the weekend that they would resign, but Wickremesinghe said he will not leave until a new government is in place. He has urged the speaker of Parliament to find a new prime minister agreeable to both the ruling and opposition parties.",
        "It’s unclear when that might happen since the opposition is deeply fractured. But assuming that Rajapaksa resigns as promised, Sri Lankan lawmakers have agreed to elect a new president on July 20 who will serve the remainder of Rajapaksa’s term, which ends in 2024. That person could potentially appoint a new prime minister, who would then have to be approved by Parliament.",
        "The political impasse threatens to worsen the bankrupt nation’s economic collapse since the absence of an alternative government could delay a hoped-for bailout from the International Monetary Fund. In the meantime, the country is relying on aid from India and China.",
        "The shortages of basic necessities have sown despair among Sri Lanka’s 22 million people. The country’s rapid decline was all the more shocking because, before the recent crisis, the economy had been expanding, with a growing, comfortable middle class."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Rajapaksa",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "Maldives",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "Saudi",
          "label": "NORP"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka’s",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Gotabaya Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Maldives",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Saudi Airlines",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Singapore",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Jeddah",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Saudi Arabia",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Maldives",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Thursday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "AP",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Rajapaksa",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "early Wednesday",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Gotabaya Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Maldives",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Wednesday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Rajapaksa",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Wednesday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "night",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lankan",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "Maldives",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "hundreds",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the previous day",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "May",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Rajapaksa",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the weekend",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Rajapaksa",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lankan",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "July 20",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Rajapaksa",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "2024",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the International Monetary Fund",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "India",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "China",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "22 million",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "ජනපති මාලදිවයිනේ සෞදි ගුවන් යානයකින් පිටත් වෙයි - වාර්තාව",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "ආර්ථික කඩාවැටීම මධ්‍යයේ තම රටින් පලාගොස් මාලදිවයිනෙන් පිටව ගිය ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ ජනාධිපති ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ මහතා මාලදිවයිනෙන් පිටව ගොස් ඇති බව විදෙස් මාධ්‍ය අද වාර්තා කළේය.",
        "ඔහු සෞදි එයාර්ලයින්ස් ගුවන් යානයකට ගොඩ වූ අතර එය ඔහුව සිංගප්පූරුවට ගෙන ගොස් සෞදි අරාබියේ ජෙඩා වෙත ගෙන යන බව මාලදිවයිනේ රජයේ නිලධාරියෙක් බ්‍රහස්පතින්දා පැවසීය. කාරණයේ සංවේදීතාව නිසා නිලධාරියා නිර්නාමිකභාවය පිළිබඳ කොන්දේසියක් මත කතා කළ බව AP වාර්තා කළේය.",
        "ඔහුට ඉල්ලා අස්වීමට බලකරමින් විරෝධතාකරුවන් රජයේ ගොඩනැගිලි අත්පත් කර ගනිමින් සිටියදී රාජපක්ෂ බදාදා අලුයම ශ්‍රී ලංකාවෙන් පලා ගියේය.",
        "රට දේශපාලන අවුල් ජාලයක ගිලී යාමත් සමඟ ජනාධිපති ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ සහ ඔහුගේ බිරිඳ බදාදා හමුදා ගුවන් යානයකින් මාලදිවයිනට පලා ගියහ. ඔහු නොමැති විට ඔහු අගමැති වැඩබලන ජනාධිපති බවට පත් කළේය - දැඩි ආහාර හා ඉන්ධන හිඟයක් ඇති කළ ආර්ථික අර්බුදයකට රාජපක්ෂට දොස් කියන මහජනතාව අතර ආශාවන් තව තවත් අවුල් කළ පියවරකි.",
        "රාජපක්ෂ බදාදා රාත්‍රිය වන විට ඉල්ලා අස්වන බවට පොරොන්දු වී ඇති අතර, බලයේ සිටියදී ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ ජනාධිපතිවරුන් අත්අඩංගුවට ගැනීමෙන් ආරක්ෂා වී ඇති බැවින්, ව්‍යවස්ථාපිත මුක්තිය සහ හමුදා ජෙට් යානයකට ප්‍රවේශය තිබියදී ඔහු ඉවත්ව යාමට සැලසුම් කර ඇත. සුඛෝපභෝගී සංචාරක නිකේතනවලින් සමන්විත දූපත් සිය ගණනකින් යුත් දූපත් සමූහයක් වන මාලදිවයිනේ ඔහු සිටින්නේ කොතැනද යන්න සහ ඔහු ඊළඟට යාමට සැලසුම් කළේ කොතැනද යන්න නිශ්චිතවම අපැහැදිලි විය.",
        "කොළ පැහැති හමුදා නිල ඇඳුමින් සැරසුණු භට පිරිස් සන්නාහ සන්නද්ධ පිරිස් වාහකයන් මගින් පාර්ලිමේන්තු ගොඩනැගිල්ල වෙත පැමිණියේ පෙරේදා දිනයේදී කිසියම් පිරිසක් ඇතුල්වීමට කඩා වැදීමට උත්සාහ කිරීමෙන් පසු තවත් විරෝධතාවන් අපේක්ෂාවෙන්, කඳුළු ගෑස් සහ බැටන් පොලුවලින් ඔවුන්ව වැළැක්වූ පොලිසිය සමඟ ගැටී ඇත.",
        "ඇතැම් විරෝධතාකරුවන් ප්‍රචණ්ඩත්වය උත්සන්න වේ යැයි බියෙන් පාර්ලිමේන්තුවට කඩා නොවැටෙන ලෙස තවත් අයගෙන් අයැද සිටින වීඩියෝ සමාජ මාධ්‍යවල පළ කළහ.",
        "වික්‍රමසිංහගේ කාර්යාලය හමුදාවට සහ පොලිසියට පුලුල් බලතල දෙමින් හදිසි තත්වයක් පනවා ඇත. ආරක්‍ෂක නායකයින් ආරක්‍ෂක අංශ සමග සන්සුන්ව සහ සහයෝගීතාවෙන් කටයුතු කරන ලෙස ඉල්ලා ඇත - සිවිල් නායකයින් විසින් විසඳුමක් සොයා ගත යුතු බව අවධාරනය කරන සමහර නීති සම්පාදකයින් ශ්‍රේණිගත කර ඇති අදහස්.",
        "රට ආර්ථික අගාධයකට ඇද දැමීම සම්බන්ධයෙන් විරෝධතාකරුවන් රාජපක්ෂ සහ ඔහුගේ බලගතු, රාජවංශික පවුලට දොස් පවරන නමුත්, ඔවුන් ජනාධිපතිවරයා ආරක්ෂා කරන බවට චෝදනා කරන වික්‍රමසිංහ කෙරෙහි ද කෝපයෙන් සිටිති. බොහෝ දෙනා විශ්වාස කරන්නේ මැයි මාසයේදී ඔහු පත් කිරීම රාජපක්ෂට ඉල්ලා අස්වන ලෙසට එල්ල වූ පීඩනය සමනය කළ බවයි.",
        "සති අන්තයේ විරෝධතා උත්සන්න වීමෙන් පසු තමන් ඉල්ලා අස්වන බව නායකයින් දෙදෙනාම ප්‍රකාශ කළ නමුත් වික්‍රමසිංහ පැවසුවේ නව රජයක් පිහිටුවන තුරු තමන් ඉවත් නොවන බවයි. ආණ්ඩු පක්‍ෂයට මෙන්ම විරුද්ධ පක්‍ෂ දෙකටම එකඟ වන නව අගමැතිවරයකු සොයා දෙන ලෙස ඔහු කතානායකවරයාගෙන් ඉල්ලා තිබේ.",
        "විපක්ෂය දැඩි ලෙස බිඳී ඇති බැවින් එය කවදා සිදු විය හැකිද යන්න පැහැදිලි නැත. එහෙත් පොරොන්දු වූ පරිදි රාජපක්ෂ ඉල්ලා අස්වන බව උපකල්පනය කරමින්, 2024 දී අවසන් වන රාජපක්ෂගේ ඉතිරි ධුර කාලය සඳහා නව ජනාධිපතිවරයකු ජූලි 20 දින තෝරා ගැනීමට ශ්‍රී ලංකා නීති සම්පාදකයින් එකඟ වී ඇත. පාර්ලිමේන්තුව විසින් අනුමත කරනු ලැබේ.",
        "විකල්ප ආන්ඩුවක් නොමැතිකම ජාත්‍යන්තර මුල්‍ය අරමුදලෙන් බලාපොරොත්තු වන ඇපදීම ප්‍රමාද කළ හැකි බැවින් දේශපාලන අවුල් ජාලය බංකොලොත් ජාතියේ ආර්ථික කඩාවැටීම නරක අතට හැරීමට තර්ජනය කරයි. මේ අතර, රට ඉන්දියාවේ සහ චීනයේ ආධාර මත විශ්වාසය තබයි.",
        "මූලික අවශ්‍යතා හිඟය ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ මිලියන 22 ක ජනතාව අතර බලාපොරොත්තු සුන්වීමක් වපුරා ඇත. රටේ ශීඝ්‍ර පරිහානිය වඩාත් කම්පනයට පත් වූයේ, මෑත අර්බුදයට පෙර, වර්ධනය වන, සුවපහසු මධ්‍යම පන්තියක් සමඟ ආර්ථිකය ප්‍රසාරණය වෙමින් තිබූ බැවිනි."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "රාජපක්ෂ",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "මාලදිවයින",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "සෞදි",
          "label": "NORP"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "මාලදිවයින",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "සෞදි ගුවන් සේවය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "සිංගප්පූරුව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජෙඩා",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "සවුදි අරාබිය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මාලදිවයින",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "බ්රහස්පතින්දා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "AP",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "බදාදා මුල",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "මාලදිවයින",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "බදාදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "බදාදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "රෑ",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලාංකික",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "මාලදිවයින",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "සිය ගණනක්",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "පෙර දින",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "මැයි",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "සති අන්තය",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලාංකික",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජූලි 20",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "2024",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ජාත්‍යන්තර මුල්‍ය අරමුදල",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "චීනය",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මිලියන 22 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "சவூதி விமானத்தில் மாலத்தீவில் இருந்து அதிபர் ராஜபக்சே புறப்பட்டார் - அறிக்கை",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "இலங்கையின் ஜனாதிபதி கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ச, பொருளாதார வீழ்ச்சிக்கு மத்தியில் தனது சொந்த நாட்டை விட்டு வெளியேறிய பின்னர் மாலைதீவை விட்டு வெளியேறியதாக வெளிநாட்டு ஊடகங்கள் இன்று செய்தி வெளியிட்டுள்ளன.",
        "அவர் சவூதி ஏர்லைன்ஸ் விமானத்தில் ஏறினார், அது அவரை சிங்கப்பூருக்கும் பின்னர் சவுதி அரேபியாவின் ஜெட்டாவுக்கும் அழைத்துச் செல்லும் என்று மாலத்தீவு அரசாங்க அதிகாரி வியாழக்கிழமை தெரிவித்தார். இந்த விஷயத்தின் உணர்திறன் காரணமாக அந்த அதிகாரி பெயர் தெரியாத நிலையில் பேசினார் என்று AP தெரிவித்துள்ளது.",
        "ராஜபக்சே பதவி விலகக் கோரி அரசு கட்டிடங்களை போராட்டக்காரர்கள் கைப்பற்றியதால், புதன்கிழமை அதிகாலை இலங்கையிலிருந்து ராஜபக்சே வெளியேறினார்.",
        "நாடு அரசியல் குழப்பத்தில் மூழ்கியுள்ள நிலையில், ஜனாதிபதி கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்சவும் அவரது மனைவியும் புதன்கிழமை இராணுவ விமானத்தில் மாலைதீவுக்கு தப்பிச் சென்றனர். அவர் இல்லாத நேரத்தில் அவர் பிரதமரை செயல் ஜனாதிபதியாக ஆக்கினார் - இது உணவு மற்றும் எரிபொருளின் கடுமையான பற்றாக்குறையை ஏற்படுத்திய பொருளாதார நெருக்கடிக்கு ராஜபக்சேவைக் குற்றம் சாட்டும் பொதுமக்களிடையே ஆர்வத்தை மேலும் தூண்டியது.",
        "புதன் இரவுக்குள் ராஜபக்சே ராஜினாமா செய்வதாக உறுதியளித்திருந்தார், மேலும் இலங்கை அதிபர்கள் ஆட்சியில் இருக்கும் போது கைது செய்யப்படாமல் பாதுகாக்கப்படுவதால், அரசியலமைப்பு ரீதியிலான விலக்கு மற்றும் இராணுவ ஜெட் விமானத்தை அணுகும் போது அவர் வெளியேற திட்டமிட்டார். ஆடம்பர சுற்றுலா விடுதிகள் நிறைந்த நூற்றுக்கணக்கான தீவுகளின் தீவுக்கூட்டமான மாலத்தீவில் அவர் எங்கு இருந்தார், அடுத்து அவர் எங்கு பயணிக்கத் திட்டமிட்டார் என்பது தெளிவாகத் தெரியவில்லை.",
        "பச்சை நிற இராணுவ சீருடைகள் மற்றும் உருமறைப்பு உள்ளாடைகள் அணிந்த துருப்புக்கள் பாராளுமன்ற கட்டிடத்திற்கு கவச பணியாளர்கள் கேரியர்களால் வந்தனர், முந்தைய நாள் ஒரு குழு நுழைவாயிலில் நுழைய முயன்றதை அடுத்து மேலும் எதிர்ப்புகளை எதிர்பார்த்து, அவர்களை கண்ணீர் புகை குண்டுகள் மற்றும் தடியடிகளால் தடுத்த பொலிஸாருடன் மோதினர்.",
        "சில போராட்டக்காரர்கள், வன்முறை அதிகரிக்கும் என்ற அச்சத்தில், நாடாளுமன்றத்தை முற்றுகையிட வேண்டாம் என்று மற்றவர்களிடம் கெஞ்சும் வீடியோக்களை சமூக ஊடகங்களில் வெளியிட்டனர்.",
        "விக்கிரமசிங்கவின் அலுவலகம் இராணுவம் மற்றும் பொலிஸுக்கு பரந்த அதிகாரங்களை வழங்கும் அவசரகாலச் சட்டத்தை விதித்துள்ளது. பாதுகாப்புத் தலைவர்கள் அமைதி மற்றும் பாதுகாப்புப் படைகளுடன் ஒத்துழைக்க அழைப்பு விடுத்துள்ளனர் - சிவிலியன் தலைவர்கள் ஒரு தீர்வைக் கண்டுபிடிக்க வேண்டும் என்று வலியுறுத்தும் சில சட்டமியற்றுபவர்களை தரவரிசைப்படுத்திய கருத்துக்கள்.",
        "நாட்டைப் பொருளாதாரப் படுகுழியில் இட்டுச் சென்றதற்காக ராஜபக்சே மற்றும் அவரது சக்திவாய்ந்த, வம்ச குடும்பத்தை எதிர்ப்பாளர்கள் குற்றம் சாட்டுகிறார்கள், ஆனால் அவர்கள் ஜனாதிபதியைப் பாதுகாப்பதாக அவர்கள் குற்றம் சாட்டும் விக்கிரமசிங்க மீதும் கடும் கோபத்தில் உள்ளனர். மே மாதம் அவரது நியமனம் ராஜபக்சேவை ராஜினாமா செய்ய வேண்டிய அழுத்தத்தைத் தணித்ததாக பலர் நம்புகிறார்கள்.",
        "வார இறுதியில் போராட்டங்கள் தீவிரமடைந்ததையடுத்து இரு தலைவர்களும் தாங்கள் ராஜினாமா செய்வதாகக் கூறினர், ஆனால் புதிய அரசாங்கம் அமையும் வரை தாம் வெளியேறப் போவதில்லை என்று விக்கிரமசிங்க கூறினார். ஆளும் கட்சிக்கும் எதிர்க்கட்சிகளுக்கும் இணங்கக்கூடிய புதிய பிரதமரைக் கண்டுபிடிக்க வேண்டும் என்று அவர் நாடாளுமன்ற சபாநாயகரிடம் வலியுறுத்தியுள்ளார்.",
        "எதிர்க்கட்சி ஆழமாக உடைந்திருப்பதால் அது எப்போது நடக்கும் என்பது தெளிவாகத் தெரியவில்லை. ஆனால் ராஜபக்சே வாக்குறுதி அளித்தபடி ராஜினாமா செய்தார் என்று கருதி, 2024 இல் முடிவடையும் ராஜபக்சவின் எஞ்சிய பதவிக் காலத்திற்குப் பணியாற்றும் புதிய அதிபரை ஜூலை 20 அன்று தேர்ந்தெடுக்க இலங்கை நாடாளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர்கள் ஒப்புக்கொண்டனர். அந்த நபர் ஒரு புதிய பிரதமரை நியமிக்கலாம். பாராளுமன்றத்தால் அங்கீகரிக்கப்படும்.",
        "அரசியல் முட்டுக்கட்டையானது திவாலாகிவிட்ட நாட்டின் பொருளாதார சரிவை மோசமாக்க அச்சுறுத்துகிறது, ஏனெனில் மாற்று அரசாங்கம் இல்லாததால் சர்வதேச நாணய நிதியத்தில் இருந்து எதிர்பார்க்கப்படும் பிணை எடுப்பு தாமதமாகும். இதற்கிடையில், அந்த நாடு இந்தியா மற்றும் சீனாவின் உதவியை நம்பியுள்ளது.",
        "அடிப்படைத் தேவைகளின் பற்றாக்குறை இலங்கையின் 22 மில்லியன் மக்களிடையே விரக்தியை விதைத்துள்ளது. நாட்டின் விரைவான சரிவு மிகவும் அதிர்ச்சியூட்டுவதாக இருந்தது, ஏனெனில், சமீபத்திய நெருக்கடிக்கு முன்னர், பொருளாதாரம் வளர்ந்து, வசதியான நடுத்தர வர்க்கத்துடன் விரிவடைந்து வந்தது."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ராஜபக்சே",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "மாலத்தீவுகள்",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "சவுதி",
          "label": "NORP"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கையின்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "மாலத்தீவுகள்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "சவுதி ஏர்லைன்ஸ்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "சிங்கப்பூர்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜித்தா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சவூதி அரேபியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "மாலத்தீவுகள்",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "வியாழன்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "AP",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ராஜபக்சே",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "புதன் ஆரம்பத்தில்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "மாலத்தீவுகள்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "புதன்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ராஜபக்சே",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ராஜபக்சே",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "புதன்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இரவு",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "மாலத்தீவுகள்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "நூற்றுக்கணக்கான",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "முந்தைய நாள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ராஜபக்சே",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "மே",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ராஜபக்சே",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "வார இறுதி",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ராஜபக்சே",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜூலை 20",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ராஜபக்சே",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "2024",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "சர்வதேச நாணய நிதியம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்தியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சீனா",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "22 மில்லியன்",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}