{
  "newspaper_id": "island-lk",
  "url": "http://island.lk/peoples-bank-organises-blood-donation-camp-to-mark-61st-anniversary/",
  "time_ut": 1659028260,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "People’s Bank organises blood donation camp to mark 61st Anniversary",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "People’s Bank organises blood donation camp to mark 61st Anniversary",
      "author": "Sahan Weerasooriya",
      "body_lines": [
        "To commemorate the Bank’s 61st anniversary, People’s Bank Welfare Department recently organized a blood donation camp at the Head Office in Colombo 2.",
        "The event was also attended by Ranjith Kodituwakku – Chief Executive Officer/General Manager of People’s Bank, Mahinda Premanath – Deputy General Manager (Channel Management), Nipunika Wijayarathne – Deputy General Manager (Banking Support Services), K.A Nihal – Acting Deputy General Manager (Human Resources) and Ajith Rathnayake – Senior Manager (Welfare and Staff Loans).",
        "Following the health checkup, the blood was collected from the donors under the strict supervision of the doctors of the Blood Bank. Through this annual programme People’s Bank donates a significant amount of blood every year to the Blood Bank.",
        "Leave a Reply Cancel replyYour email address will not be published. Required fields are marked *Comment Name *",
        "Save my name, email, and website in this browser for the next time I comment."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "People’s Bank",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "61st",
          "label": "ORDINAL"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "61st",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "People’s Bank Welfare Department",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Head Office",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "2",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Ranjith Kodituwakku",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "People’s Bank",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Mahinda Premanath",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Channel Management",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Nipunika Wijayarathne",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "K.A Nihal",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ajith Rathnayake",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the Blood Bank",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "annual",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "People’s Bank",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "every year",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Blood Bank",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [],
        []
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "මහජන බැංකුව 61 වැනි සංවත්සරය වෙනුවෙන් ලේ දන්දීමේ කඳවුරක් සංවිධානය කරයි",
      "author": "සහන් වීරසූරිය",
      "body_lines": [
        "බැංකුවේ 61 වැනි සංවත්සරය සැමරීම සඳහා මහජන බැංකු සුබසාධන දෙපාර්තමේන්තුව විසින් පසුගියදා කොළඹ 2 ප්‍රධාන කාර්යාලයේදී ලේ දන්දීමේ කඳවුරක් සංවිධානය කරන ලදී.",
        "මෙම අවස්ථාවට මහජන බැංකුවේ ප්‍රධාන විධායක නිලධාරී/සාමාන්‍යාධිකාරී රංජිත් කොඩිතුවක්කු, නියෝජ්‍ය සාමාන්‍යාධිකාරී (නාලිකා කළමනාකරණය), නිපුනිකා විජයරත්න - නියෝජ්‍ය සාමාන්‍යාධිකාරී (බැංකු සහාය සේවා), K.A නිහාල් - වැඩ බලන නියෝජ්‍ය සාමාන්‍යාධිකාරී ( මානව සම්පත්) සහ අජිත් රත්නායක - ජ්‍යෙෂ්ඨ කළමනාකරු (සුබසාධන සහ කාර්ය මණ්ඩල ණය).",
        "සෞඛ්‍ය පරීක්‍ෂාවෙන් අනතුරුව රුධිර බැංකුවේ වෛද්‍යවරුන්ගේ දැඩි අධීක්‍ෂණය යටතේ පරිත්‍යාගශීලීන්ගෙන් රුධිරය ලබා ගන්නා ලදී. මෙම වාර්ෂික වැඩසටහන හරහා මහජන බැංකුව සෑම වසරකම සැලකිය යුතු රුධිර ප්‍රමාණයක් ලේ බැංකුවට පරිත්‍යාග කරයි.",
        "පිළිතුරක් දෙන්න පිළිතුර අවලංගු කරන්න ඔබගේ විද්‍යුත් තැපැල් ලිපිනය ප්‍රකාශයට පත් නොකෙරේ. අවශ්‍ය ක්ෂේත්‍ර සලකුණු කර ඇත *අදහස් නම *",
        "මම ඊළඟ වතාවේ අදහස් දැක්වීම සඳහා මගේ නම, විද්‍යුත් තැපෑල සහ වෙබ් අඩවිය මෙම බ්‍රවුසරයේ සුරකින්න."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "මහජන බැංකුව",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "61 වැනි",
          "label": "ORDINAL"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "61 වැනි",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "මහජන බැංකු සුබසාධන දෙපාර්තමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ප්රධාන කාර්යාලය",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "2",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Ranjith Kodituwakku",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "මහජන බැංකුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "මහින්ද ප්‍රේමනාත්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "නාලිකා කළමනාකරණය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "නිපුනිකා විජයරත්න",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "K.A නිහාල්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "අජිත් රත්නායක",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ලේ බැංකුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "වාර්ෂික",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මහජන බැංකුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "සෑම වසරකම",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ලේ බැංකුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [],
        []
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "61வது ஆண்டு நிறைவை முன்னிட்டு மக்கள் வங்கி இரத்த தான முகாமை ஏற்பாடு செய்துள்ளது",
      "author": "சஹான் வீரசூரிய",
      "body_lines": [
        "வங்கியின் 61வது ஆண்டு நிறைவை நினைவுகூரும் வகையில், மக்கள் வங்கி நலன்புரி திணைக்களம் அண்மையில் கொழும்பு 2 இல் உள்ள தலைமை அலுவலகத்தில் இரத்த தான முகாமை ஏற்பாடு செய்திருந்தது.",
        "இந்த நிகழ்வில் ரஞ்சித் கொடிதுவாக்கு – மக்கள் வங்கியின் பிரதம நிறைவேற்று அதிகாரி/பொது முகாமையாளர், மஹிந்த பிரேமநாத் – பிரதிப் பொது முகாமையாளர் (சேனல் முகாமைத்துவம்), நிபுனிகா விஜயரத்ன – பிரதிப் பொது முகாமையாளர் (வங்கி ஆதரவு சேவைகள்), கே.ஏ.நிஹால் – பதில் பிரதிப் பொது முகாமையாளர் ( மனித வளங்கள்) மற்றும் அஜித் ரத்நாயக்க - சிரேஷ்ட முகாமையாளர் (நலன்புரி மற்றும் பணியாளர் கடன்கள்).",
        "சுகாதாரப் பரிசோதனையைத் தொடர்ந்து, ரத்த வங்கி மருத்துவர்களின் தீவிரக் கண்காணிப்பில், கொடையாளர்களிடம் இருந்து ரத்தம் சேகரிக்கப்பட்டது. இந்த வருடாந்த வேலைத்திட்டத்தின் மூலம் மக்கள் வங்கி ஒவ்வொரு வருடமும் இரத்த வங்கிக்கு கணிசமான அளவு இரத்தத்தை தானமாக வழங்குகிறது.",
        "ஒரு பதிலை விடுங்கள் பதிலை ரத்துசெய் உங்கள் மின்னஞ்சல் முகவரி வெளியிடப்படாது. தேவையான புலங்கள் குறிக்கப்பட்டுள்ளன *கருத்து பெயர் *",
        "அடுத்த முறை நான் கருத்து தெரிவிக்க, எனது பெயர், மின்னஞ்சல் மற்றும் இணையதளத்தை இந்த உலாவியில் சேமிக்கவும்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "மக்கள் வங்கி",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "61வது",
          "label": "ORDINAL"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "61வது",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "மக்கள் வங்கி நலத்துறை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "தலைமை அலுவலகம்",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "2",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Ranjith Kodituwakku",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "மக்கள் வங்கி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "மஹிந்த பிரேமநாத்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "சேனல் மேலாண்மை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "நிபுனிகா விஜயரத்ன",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "கே.ஏ.நிஹால்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "அஜித் ரத்நாயக்க",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இரத்த வங்கி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆண்டு",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "மக்கள் வங்கி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஒவ்வொரு வருடமும்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இரத்த வங்கி",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [],
        []
      ]
    }
  }
}