{
  "newspaper_id": "lankadeepa-lk",
  "url": "https://www.lankadeepa.lk/news/පැරිසියෙන්-ගෙනා-කෝටි-තුනහමාරක-රත්‍රං-රේගුවේ-හිර-වෙයි/101-618837",
  "time_ut": 1661585127,
  "original_lang": "si",
  "original_title": "පැරිසියෙන් ගෙනා කෝටි තුනහමාරක රත්‍රං රේගුවේ හිර වෙයි",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Three and a half million worth of gold brought from Paris gets stuck in customs",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "Mr. Sudatta Silva, Director of Customs, said that the customs officers of the airport seized a consignment of gold worth more than three and a half million rupees, which was illegally brought by a Sri Lankan passenger who arrived early today (27) on a flight belonging to SriLankan Airlines from Paris.",
        "The customs spokesman said that they tried to carry 2414.6 grams of gold on the green route for passengers who had nothing to declare to the customs, hidden very carefully in the luggage, pretending to be personal belongings and the amount of gold seized was estimated at 36,219,000 rupees.",
        "Mr. Sudatta Silva further mentioned that the Customs will conduct further investigations regarding this stock of gold, confiscate the stock of gold and impose fines on the airport duty officers of Sri Lanka Customs."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Three and a half million",
          "label": "DATE"
        },
        {
          "text": "Paris",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Sudatta Silva",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Customs",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "more than three and a half million",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lankan",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "27",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "SriLankan Airlines",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Paris",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "2414.6 grams",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "36,219,000",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sudatta Silva",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Customs",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka Customs",
            "label": "LOC"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "පැරිසියෙන් ගෙනා කෝටි තුනහමාරක රත්‍රං රේගුවේ හිර වෙයි",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "පැරීසියේ සිට ශ්‍රී ලංකන් ගුවන් සේවයට අයත් ගුවන් යානයකින් අද (27) අළුයම පැමිණි ශ්‍රී ලාංකික ගුවන් මඟියෙක් නීති විරෝධීව රැගෙන ආ රුපියල් කෝටි තුනහමාරකට අධික වටිනාකමින් යුත් රත්තරන් තොගයක් ගුවන්තොටුපල රේගු නිලධාරීන් අත්අඩංගුවට ගත් බව රේගු මාධ්‍ය ප්‍රකාශක රේගු අධ්‍යක්ෂ සුදත්ත සිල්වා මහතා පැවසීය.",
        "ගමන්මළු තුළ ඉතා සුක්ෂම ලෙස සඟවා, පුද්ගලික බඩු ලෙස හඟවමින් රේගුවට ප්‍රකාශ කිරීමට කිසිවක් නොමැති මඟීන් සඳහා වන හරිත මාර්ගයේ රත්තරන් ග්‍රෑම් 2414.6 ක ප්‍රමාණයක් රැගෙන යාමට උත්සාහ කළ බවත් අත්අඩංගුවට රත්තරන් තොගය රුපියල් 36,219,000  ලෙස තක්සේරු කර ඇති බවත් රේගු මාධ්‍ය ප්‍රකාශකවරයා කීය.",
        "මෙම රත්තරන් තොගය සම්බන්ධයෙන් රේගුව වැඩිදුර විමර්ශන පවත්වා රත්තරන් තොගය රාජසන්තක කර දඩ පැනවීමට ශ්‍රී ලංකා රේගුවේ ගුවන් තොටුපල රාජකාරියේ නියුතු නිලධාරීන් කටයුතු කිරීමට නියමිත බවද සුදත්ත සිල්වා මහතා වැඩිදුරටත් සඳහන් කළේය."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "මිලියන තුනහමාරක්",
          "label": "DATE"
        },
        {
          "text": "පැරිස්",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "සුදත්ත සිල්වා",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "රේගුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "මිලියන තුනහමාරකට වැඩිය",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලාංකික",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "27",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකන් ගුවන් සේවය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "පැරිස්",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ග්රෑම් 2414.6 කි",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "36,219,000 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "සුදත්ත සිල්වා",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "රේගුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකා රේගුව",
            "label": "LOC"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "பாரிஸில் இருந்து கொண்டு வரப்பட்ட மூன்றரை மில்லியன் மதிப்புள்ள தங்கம் சுங்கச்சாவடியில் சிக்குகிறது",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "இன்று (27) அதிகாலை வந்த இலங்கை பயணி ஒருவரால் சட்டவிரோதமான முறையில் கொண்டுவரப்பட்ட மூன்றரை மில்லியன் ரூபாவுக்கும் அதிகமான பெறுமதியான தங்கத் தொகுதியை விமான நிலைய சுங்க அதிகாரிகள் கைப்பற்றியதாக சுங்கப் பணிப்பாளர் திரு.சுதத்த சில்வா தெரிவித்தார். பாரிஸில் இருந்து ஸ்ரீலங்கன் ஏர்லைன்ஸ் நிறுவனத்திற்கு சொந்தமான விமானம்.",
        "சுங்கத்திற்கு அறிவிக்க எதுவுமில்லாத, பயணப் பொதிகளில் மிகவும் கவனமாக மறைத்து, தனிப்பட்ட உடமைகளாகக் காட்டி, 2414.6 கிராம் தங்கத்தை பச்சைப் பாதையில் கொண்டு செல்ல முயன்றதாகவும், கைப்பற்றப்பட்ட தங்கத்தின் அளவு 36,219,000 என மதிப்பிடப்பட்டுள்ளதாகவும் சுங்கப் பேச்சாளர் தெரிவித்தார். ரூபாய்.",
        "இந்த தங்கம் தொடர்பான மேலதிக விசாரணைகளை சுங்கப் பிரிவினர் மேற்கொண்டு, தங்கத்தை பறிமுதல் செய்து, இலங்கை சுங்கத்தின் விமான நிலைய கடமை அதிகாரிகளுக்கு அபராதம் விதிக்கப்படும் என திரு.சுதத்த சில்வா மேலும் குறிப்பிட்டார்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "மூன்றரை மில்லியன்",
          "label": "DATE"
        },
        {
          "text": "பாரிஸ்",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "சுதத்த சில்வா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "சுங்கம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "மூன்றரை மில்லியனுக்கும் அதிகமானவை",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "27",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஸ்ரீலங்கன் ஏர்லைன்ஸ்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாரிஸ்",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "2414.6 கிராம்",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "36,219,000",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "சுதத்த சில்வா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "சுங்கம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை சுங்கம்",
            "label": "LOC"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}