{
  "newspaper_id": "virakesari-lk",
  "url": "http://www.virakesari.lk/article/130606",
  "time_ut": 1656737158,
  "original_lang": "ta",
  "original_title": "மண்டபம் அகதிகள் முகாமில் இருந்த இலங்கை தமிழ் இளைஞர் தற்கொலை",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Sri Lankan Tamil youth committed suicide in Mandapam refugee camp",
      "author": "T. Saranya",
      "body_lines": [
        "A Sri Lankan Tamil youth committed suicide in the Mandapam refugee camp in Tamil Nadu.",
        "In the year 2006, a woman named Rani went to Tamil Nadu as refugees from Sri Lanka with one son and three daughters and is staying at Mandapam Refugee Rehabilitation Camp.",
        "In this case, 22-year-old Niroshan, the son of a woman named Rani, a Sri Lankan refugee, has been playing games on his cell phone with his friends for the past few days without going to work.",
        "The enraged Rani then scolded her son to stop playing games and go to work.",
        "After this, the Eelam Tamil youth Niroshan, who was heartbroken due to his mother's reprimand, was lying drunk two days ago.",
        "After that, Niroshan, who was in a coma, was admitted to the hospital by his friends, where he succumbed to his injuries.",
        "Subsequently, the police are engaged in the process of taking the body of the deceased Eelam Tamil youth to the Mandapam Refugee Rehabilitation Camp after conducting an autopsy.",
        "Also, based on the complaint filed by Priya, the sister of the deceased Eelam Tamil youth, the police have registered a case and are investigating.",
        "The people of the area are deeply saddened by the young man who took the tragic decision after his mother reprimanded him for playing games on his cell phone instead of going to work."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Sri Lankan Tamil",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "Mandapam",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lankan Tamil",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Mandapam",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Tamil Nadu",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the year 2006",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Rani",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Tamil Nadu",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "one",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "three",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Mandapam Refugee Rehabilitation Camp",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "22-year-old",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Niroshan",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Rani",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lankan",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the past few days",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Rani",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Eelam Tamil",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Niroshan",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "two days ago",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Niroshan",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Eelam Tamil",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Mandapam Refugee Rehabilitation Camp",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Priya",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Eelam Tamil",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        []
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "මණ්ඩපම් සරණාගත කඳවුරේදී ශ්‍රී ලාංකික දෙමළ තරුණයෙක් සියදිවි නසා ගත්තේය",
      "author": "T. Saranya",
      "body_lines": [
        "තමිල්නාඩුවේ මණ්ඩපම් සරණාගත කඳවුරේදී ශ්‍රී ලාංකික දෙමළ තරුණයෙකු සියදිවි හානිකරගෙන තිබේ.",
        "2006 වසරේදී රාණි නමැති කාන්තාවක් එක් පුතෙකු සහ දියණියන් තිදෙනෙකු සමඟ ශ්‍රී ලංකාවෙන් සරණාගතයින් ලෙස තමිල්නාඩුවට ගොස් මණ්ඩපම් සරණාගත පුනරුත්ථාපන කඳවුරේ රැඳී සිටියි.",
        "මෙම නඩුවේදී ශ්‍රී ලාංකික සරණාගත රාණි නමැති කාන්තාවගේ පුත් 22 හැවිරිදි නිරෝෂන් පසුගිය දින කිහිපයේ රැකියාවට නොගොස් තම මිතුරන් සමඟ ජංගම දුරකථනයෙන් ගේම් ගසමින් සිට ඇත.",
        "එවිට කෝපයට පත් රාණි තම පුතාට ගේම් ගහන එක නවත්තලා වැඩට යන්න කියලා බැනලා.",
        "මෙයින් පසු මවගේ බැන වැදීමෙන් සිත් තැවුලට පත් නිරෝෂන් නමැති ඊළාම් දෙමළ තරුණයා මීට දින දෙකකට පෙර බීමතින් වැතිර සිටියේය.",
        "ඉන් පසු සිහිසුන්ව සිටි නිරෝෂන් මිතුරන් විසින් රෝහලට ඇතුළත් කර ඇති අතර එහිදී ඔහු ජීවිතක්ෂයට පත් විය.",
        "අනතුරුව මරණ පරීක්ෂණයක් පවත්වා මියගිය ඊළාම් දෙමළ තරුණයාගේ දේහය මණ්ඩපම් සරණාගත පුනරුත්ථාපන කඳවුර වෙත රැගෙන යාමට පොලිසිය කටයුතු කරමින් සිටිනවා.",
        "එමෙන්ම මියගිය ඊළාම් දෙමළ තරුණයාගේ සොහොයුරිය වන ප්‍රියා විසින් කරන ලද පැමිණිල්ලකට අනුව පොලිසිය මේ සම්බන්ධයෙන් නඩුවක් ලියාපදිංචි කර විමර්ශන ආරම්භ කර තිබේ.",
        "රැකියාවට නොගොස් ජංගම දුරකථනයෙන් ගේම් ගහන බවට මව තරවටු කිරීමත් සමඟ තරුණයා මෙම ඛේදනීය තීරණය ගැනීම සම්බන්ධයෙන් ප්‍රදේශවාසීන් දැඩි ශෝකයට පත්ව සිටිනවා."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ශ්‍රී ලාංකික දෙමළ",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "මණ්ඩපය",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලාංකික දෙමළ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "මණ්ඩපය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "තමිල්නාඩුව",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "2006 වර්ෂය",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "රාණි",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "තමිල්නාඩුව",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "එක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "තුන්",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "මණ්ඩපම් සරණාගත පුනරුත්ථාපන කඳවුර",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "22 හැවිරිදිය",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "නිරෝෂන්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "රාණි",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලාංකික",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "පසුගිය දින කිහිපය",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "රාණි",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ඊළාම් දෙමළ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "නිරෝෂන්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "දින දෙකකට කලින්",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "නිරෝෂන්",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ඊළාම් දෙමළ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "මණ්ඩපම් සරණාගත පුනරුත්ථාපන කඳවුර",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ප්‍රියා",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඊළාම් දෙමළ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        []
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "மண்டபம் அகதிகள் முகாமில் இருந்த இலங்கை தமிழ் இளைஞர் தற்கொலை",
      "author": "T. Saranya",
      "body_lines": [
        "தமிழகத்தில் மண்டபம் அகதிகள் முகாமில் இருந்த இலங்கை தமிழ் இளைஞர் தற்கொலை செய்து கொண்டுள்ளார்.",
        "கடந்த 2006 ஆம் ஆண்டு ராணி என்ற பெண் ஒரு மகன், மூன்று பெண் பிள்ளைகளுடன் இலங்கையில் இருந்து அகதிகளாக தமிழகத்திற்கு சென்று மண்டபம் அகதிகள்  மறுவாழ்வு  முகாமில் தங்கி வசித்து வருகின்றார்.",
        "இந்நிலையில் இலங்கை அகதியான ராணி என்ற பெண்ணின் மகனான 22 வயதுடைய இளைஞர் நிரோஷன் கடந்த சில நாட்களாக வேலைக்கு செல்லாமல் நண்பர்களுடன் சேர்ந்து கொண்டு செல்போனில் கேம் விளையாடி சுற்றித் திரிந்துள்ளார்.",
        "இதையடுத்து ஆத்திரமடைந்த ராணி தனது மகனை கேம் விளையாடுவதை விட்டுவிட்டு வேலைக்கு செல்லுமாறு கண்டித்ததுள்ளார்.",
        "இதையடுத்து தாயின் கண்டிப்பால் மனம் உடைந்த ஈழத் தமிழர் இளைஞர் நிரோஷன் தஞ்சை அறுந்தி கடந்த இரண்டு நாட்களுக்கு முன்பு  குடித்து விட்டு படுத்து கிடந்துள்ளார்.",
        "இதையடுத்து மயக்க நிலையில் இருந்த  நிரோஷனை அவரது நண்பர்கள்  வைத்தியசாலையில் அனுமதித்து அளிக்கப்பட்டு வந்த நிலையில் சிகிச்சை பலனின்றி உயிரிழந்துள்ளார்.",
        "இதையடுத்து உயிரிழந்த ஈழத் தமிழர் இளைஞரின் உடலை  உடற்கூறு ஆய்வு செய்யப்பட்டு மண்டபம் அகதிகள் மறுவாழ்வு முகாமிற்கு கொண்டு வரும் பணியில் பொலிஸார் ஈடுபட்டு வருகின்றனர்.",
        "மேலும் இது குறித்து உயிரிழந்த ஈழத் தமிழர் இளைஞரின் சகோதரி பிரியா கொடுத்த புகாரின் அடிப்படையில் காவல்துறையினர் வழக்குப்பதிவு செய்து விசாரணை நடத்தி வருகின்றனர்.",
        "வேலைக்கு செல்லாமல் தனது செல்போனில் கேம் விளையாடுவதை தாய் கண்டித்ததால் விபரீத முடிவு எடுத்த இளைஞரால் பகுதியில் உள்ள மக்கள் மிகுந்த  சோகத்தில் ஆழ்ந்துள்ளனர்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "இலங்கைத் தமிழர்",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "மண்டபம்",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கைத் தமிழர்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "மண்டபம்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "தமிழ்நாடு",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "2006 ஆம் ஆண்டு",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ராணி",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "தமிழ்நாடு",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஒன்று",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "மூன்று",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "மண்டபம் அகதிகள் மறுவாழ்வு முகாம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "22 வயது",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "நிரோஷன்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ராணி",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "கடந்த சில நாட்களாக",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ராணி",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஈழத் தமிழர்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "நிரோஷன்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இரண்டு நாட்களுக்கு முன்பு",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "நிரோஷன்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஈழத் தமிழர்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "மண்டபம் அகதிகள் மறுவாழ்வு முகாம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பிரியா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஈழத் தமிழர்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        []
      ]
    }
  }
}