{
  "newspaper_id": "lankadeepa-lk",
  "url": "https://www.lankadeepa.lk/news/පක්ෂ-නායක-රැස්වීමෙි-දී-තීරණ-හතරක්-ගනියි/101-616137",
  "time_ut": 1657374448,
  "original_lang": "si",
  "original_title": "පක්ෂ නායක රැස්වීමෙි දී තීරණ හතරක් ගනියි",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Party leaders take four decisions at the meeting",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "Dr. Harsha De Silva, Member of Parliament of the United People's Party, said in a tweet that four major decisions were reached at the party leaders' meeting.",
        "Mr. Harsha de Silva stated in his twitter message that the four decisions are the resignation of the President and the Prime Minister, the appointment of the Speaker as Acting President for thirty days, the appointment of a member representing the Parliament as the President and the formation of an all-party government until an election is held."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "four",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Harsha De Silva",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the United People's Party",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "four",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Harsha de Silva",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "four",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "thirty days",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "පක්ෂ නායක රැස්වීමෙි දී තීරණ හතරක් ගනියි",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "පක්ෂ නායක රැස්වීමේදී ප්‍රධාන තීරණ හතරකට එළඹි බව සමගි ජනබලවේගයේ පාලිමේන්තු මන්ත්‍රී ආචාර්ය හර්ෂ ද සිල්වා මහතා ට්විටර් පණිවිඩයක් නිකුත් කරමින් සඳහන් කරයි.",
        "ජනාධිපති සහ අගමැති ඉවත් වීම,කතානායක වැඩබලන ජනාධිපති ලෙස දින තිහක් සඳහා පත්වීම,පාර්ලිමේන්තුව නියෝජනය කරන මන්ත්‍රීවරයෙකු ජනාධිපති ලෙස පත් කිරීම සහ මැතිවරණයක් පවත්වන තුරු සර්ව පාක්ෂික ආණ්ඩුවක් පිහිටුවීම එම තීරණ හතර බව හර්ෂ ද සිල්වා මහතා සිය ට්විටර් පණිවිඩයේ සඳහන් කරයි."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "හතර",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "හර්ෂ ද සිල්වා",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "එක්සත් ජනතා පක්ෂය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "හතර",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "හර්ෂ ද සිල්වා",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "හතර",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "දින තිහක්",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "கட்சித் தலைவர்கள் கூட்டத்தில் நான்கு முடிவுகள் எடுக்கப்படுகின்றன",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "கட்சித் தலைவர்கள் கூட்டத்தில் நான்கு முக்கிய தீர்மானங்கள் எட்டப்பட்டதாக ஐக்கிய மக்கள் கட்சியின் நாடாளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர் கலாநிதி ஹர்ஷ டி சில்வா டுவிட்டரில் தெரிவித்துள்ளார்.",
        "ஜனாதிபதி மற்றும் பிரதமர் பதவி விலகல், முப்பது நாட்களுக்கு சபாநாயகரை பதில் ஜனாதிபதியாக நியமித்தல், பாராளுமன்றத்தை பிரதிநிதித்துவப்படுத்தும் உறுப்பினர் ஒருவரை ஜனாதிபதியாக நியமித்தல் ஆகிய நான்கு தீர்மானங்களாகும் என ஹர்ஷ டி சில்வா தனது டுவிட்டர் செய்தியில் குறிப்பிட்டுள்ளார். தேர்தல் நடைபெறும் வரை அனைத்துக் கட்சி ஆட்சி அமைக்க வேண்டும்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "நான்கு",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ஹர்ஷ டி சில்வா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஐக்கிய மக்கள் கட்சி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "நான்கு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஹர்ஷ டி சில்வா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "நான்கு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "முப்பது நாட்கள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}