{
  "newspaper_id": "economy-next-com",
  "url": "https://economynext.com/vietnam-rises-strongly-from-covid-keeps-inflation-down-as-77-national-day-celebrated-99360/",
  "time_ut": 1662104280,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Vietnam rises strongly from Covid, keeps inflation down as 77 national day celebrated",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Vietnam rises strongly from Covid, keeps inflation down as 77 national day celebrated",
      "author": "",
      "body_lines": [
        "ECONOMYNEXT – Vietnam has recovered strongly as the country emerged from a Coronavirus pandemic and the country celebrates its national day on September 02, a statement said as exports foreign investment grew and tourists started to return.",
        "“Production and business activities have returned to the normal state as before the Covid-19 epidemic appeared,” a Foreign Ministry statement said.",
        "“However, our country’s economy is facing challenges such as high prices of input materials, especially gasoline prices.”",
        "Vietnam is celebrating its national day on September 02. Vietnam leader declared independence from French rule 77 years ago.",
        "The country adopted a market economy in 1983, started reforming its central bank from 1989 and is now admired as a stable high growth country drawing foreign direct investment and growing exports and imports.",
        "Foreign direct investment realized in the first seven months was 11.57 billion US dollars up 10.2 percent from a year ago.",
        "Processing and manufacturing industry drew 8.87 billion dollars and real estate business 1004.8 million dollars.",
        "Exports in the first seven month of the year were 216.35 billion US dollars, with the domestic sector contributing 56.9 billion US dollars and foreign investment sector 159.3 billion US dollars.",
        "Import turnover was 215.59 billion US dollars, with the FDI sector accounting for 139.5 billion US dollars and domestic sector 76.06 billion US dollars.",
        "The US was Vietnam’s largest export market accounting for 72.6 billion US dollars and China was the largest import market with an estimated turnover of 72.6 billion US dollars.",
        "There was a trade deficit of 42.2 billion dollars with China, 23.5 billion deficit with Korea, a deficit of 7.9 billion US dollars with ASEAN, a deficit of 23.5 billion US dollars with Korea, a deficit of 769 million with Japan.",
        "There was a trade surplus of 18.7 billion US dollar with the EU.",
        "Bilateral trade between Sri Lanka and Vietnam grew to 460 million US dollars in 2021 from 287 million US dollars in 2020.",
        "Exports from Vietnam in 2021 was 397.8 million US dollars up from 250.2 million dollars. Imports from Sri Lanka was 62.22 million up from 37.19 million dollars a year earlier.",
        "Vietnam drew 954,000 foreign visitors in the first seven months of 2022, 10 times higher than a year earlier amid Covid crisis but 90 percent lower than 2019. (Colombo/Sep02/2022)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Vietnam",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "Covid",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "77 national day",
          "label": "DATE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Vietnam",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Coronavirus",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "September 02",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Foreign Ministry",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "Vietnam",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "September 02",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Vietnam",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "French",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "77 years ago",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "1983",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "1989",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the first seven months",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "11.57 billion US dollars",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "10.2 percent",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "a year ago",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "8.87 billion dollars",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "1004.8 million dollars",
            "label": "MONEY"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the first seven month of the year",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "216.35 billion US dollars",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "56.9 billion US dollars",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "159.3 billion US dollars",
            "label": "MONEY"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "215.59 billion US dollars",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "FDI",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "139.5 billion US dollars",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "76.06 billion US dollars",
            "label": "MONEY"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "US",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Vietnam",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "72.6 billion US dollars",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "China",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "72.6 billion US dollars",
            "label": "MONEY"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "42.2 billion dollars",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "China",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "23.5 billion",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Korea",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "7.9 billion US dollars",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "ASEAN",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "23.5 billion US dollars",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "Korea",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "769 million",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Japan",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "18.7 billion US dollar",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "EU",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Vietnam",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "460 million US dollars",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "2021",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "287 million US dollars",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "2020",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Vietnam",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "2021",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "397.8 million US dollars",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "250.2 million dollars",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "62.22 million",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "37.19 million dollars",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "a year earlier",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Vietnam",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "954,000",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "the first seven months of 2022",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "10",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "a year earlier",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "90 percent",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "2019",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Colombo/Sep02/2022",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "වියට්නාමය කොවිඩ් වලින් දැඩි ලෙස ඉහල යයි, 77 ජාතික දිනය සමරන විට උද්ධමනය අඩු කරයි",
      "author": "",
      "body_lines": [
        "ECONOMYNEXT - රට කොරොන වයිරස් වසංගතයෙන් මිදීමත් සමඟ වියට්නාමය ශක්තිමත් ලෙස යථා තත්ත්වයට පත් වී ඇති අතර රට සැප්තැම්බර් 02 වන දින එහි ජාතික දිනය සමරන බව නිවේදනයක් නිකුත් කරමින් කියා සිටියේ අපනයන විදේශ ආයෝජන වර්ධනය වී සංචාරකයින් නැවත පැමිණීමට පටන් ගත් බැවිනි.",
        "“COVID-19 වසංගතය ඇතිවීමට පෙර නිෂ්පාදන සහ ව්‍යාපාරික කටයුතු සාමාන්‍ය තත්ත්වයට පත්ව ඇත,” විදේශ අමාත්‍යාංශයේ ප්‍රකාශයක් පවසයි.",
        "\"කෙසේ වෙතත්, අපේ රටේ ආර්ථිකය ආදාන ද්‍රව්‍යවල ඉහළ මිල, විශේෂයෙන් පෙට්‍රල් මිල වැනි අභියෝගවලට මුහුණ දී සිටී.\"",
        "වියට්නාමය සැප්තැම්බර් 02 වන දින සිය ජාතික දිනය සමරයි. වියට්නාම නායකයා මීට වසර 77 කට පෙර ප්‍රංශ පාලනයෙන් නිදහස ප්‍රකාශ කළේය.",
        "රට 1983 දී වෙළඳපොල ආර්ථිකයක් සම්මත කර ගත් අතර, 1989 සිට එහි මහ බැංකුව ප්‍රතිසංස්කරණය කිරීමට පටන් ගත් අතර, සෘජු විදේශ ආයෝජන ලබා ගනිමින් සහ අපනයන හා ආනයන වර්ධනය වෙමින් ස්ථාවර ඉහළ වර්ධන රටක් ලෙස දැන් අගය කරනු ලැබේ.",
        "පළමු මාස ​​හත තුළ සාක්ෂාත් කර ගත් සෘජු විදේශ ආයෝජනය වසරකට පෙර සිට සියයට 10.2 කින් ඩොලර් බිලියන 11.57 කින් වැඩි විය.",
        "සැකසුම් සහ නිෂ්පාදන කර්මාන්තය ඩොලර් බිලියන 8.87 ක් සහ දේපල වෙළඳාම් ව්‍යාපාරය ඩොලර් මිලියන 1004.8 ක් ලබා ගෙන ඇත.",
        "වසරේ මුල් මාස හත තුළ අපනයන ඩොලර් බිලියන 216.35 ක් වූ අතර දේශීය අංශයෙන් ඩොලර් බිලියන 56.9 ක් සහ විදේශ ආයෝජන අංශයෙන් ඩොලර් බිලියන 159.3 ක දායකත්වයක් ලබා දී ඇත.",
        "ආනයන පිරිවැටුම ඇමෙරිකානු ඩොලර් බිලියන 215.59ක් වූ අතර, එෆ්ඩීඅයි අංශය ඩොලර් බිලියන 139.5ක් සහ දේශීය අංශයෙන් ඩොලර් බිලියන 76.06ක් විය.",
        "එක්සත් ජනපදය වියට්නාමයේ විශාලතම අපනයන වෙළඳපොල වන අතර එය ඩොලර් බිලියන 72.6 ක් වන අතර චීනය එක්සත් ජනපද ඩොලර් බිලියන 72.6 ක ඇස්තමේන්තුගත පිරිවැටුමක් සහිත විශාලතම ආනයන වෙළඳපොල විය.",
        "චීනය සමඟ ඩොලර් බිලියන 42.2 ක වෙළඳ හිඟයක්, කොරියාව සමඟ ඩොලර් බිලියන 23.5 ක හිඟයක්, ආසියාන් සමඟ ඩොලර් බිලියන 7.9 ක හිඟයක්, කොරියාව සමඟ ඩොලර් බිලියන 23.5 ක හිඟයක්, ජපානය සමඟ ඩොලර් මිලියන 769 ක හිඟයක් තිබුණා.",
        "යුරෝපා සංගමය සමඟ ඇමෙරිකානු ඩොලර් බිලියන 18.7ක වෙළෙඳ අතිරික්තයක් තිබුණා.",
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකාව සහ වියට්නාමය අතර ද්විපාර්ශ්වික වෙළඳාම 2020 දී ඩොලර් මිලියන 287 සිට 2021 දී ඩොලර් මිලියන 460 දක්වා වර්ධනය විය.",
        "2021 දී වියට්නාමයෙන් අපනයනය ඩොලර් මිලියන 250.2 සිට ඩොලර් මිලියන 397.8 ක් විය. ශ්‍රී ලංකාවෙන් ආනයනය මීට පෙර වසරකට ඩොලර් මිලියන 37.19 සිට මිලියන 62.22 ක් විය.",
        "වියට්නාමය 2022 පළමු මාස ​​හත තුළ විදේශීය අමුත්තන් 954,000 ක් ඇදී ඇති අතර, කොවිඩ් අර්බුදය මධ්‍යයේ වසරකට පෙරට වඩා 10 ගුණයකින් වැඩි නමුත් 2019 ට වඩා සියයට 90 කින් අඩු විය. (කොළඹ/සැප්.02/2022)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "වියට්නාමය",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "කොවිඩ්",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "77 ජාතික දිනය",
          "label": "DATE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "වියට්නාමය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "කොරෝනාවයිරසය",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "සැප්තැම්බර් 02",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "විදේශ අමාත්‍යාංශය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "වියට්නාමය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "සැප්තැම්බර් 02",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "වියට්නාමය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ප්රංශ",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "අවුරුදු 77කට කලින්",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "1983",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "1989",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "පළමු මාස ​​හත",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඩොලර් බිලියන 11.57 කි",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "සියයට 10.2 කි",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "වසරකට පෙර",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ඩොලර් බිලියන 8.87 කි",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඩොලර් මිලියන 1004.8 කි",
            "label": "MONEY"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "වසරේ පළමු මාස ​​හත",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඩොලර් බිලියන 216.35 කි",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඩොලර් බිලියන 56.9 කි",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඩොලර් බිලියන 159.3 කි",
            "label": "MONEY"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ඩොලර් බිලියන 215.59 කි",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "එෆ්ඩීඅයි",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඩොලර් බිලියන 139.5 කි",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඩොලර් බිලියන 76.06 කි",
            "label": "MONEY"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "එක්සත් ජනපදය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "වියට්නාමය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඩොලර් බිලියන 72.6 කි",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "චීනය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඩොලර් බිලියන 72.6 කි",
            "label": "MONEY"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ඩොලර් බිලියන 42.2 කි",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "චීනය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "බිලියන 23.5 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "කොරියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඩොලර් බිලියන 7.9 කි",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "ආසියාන්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඩොලර් බිලියන 23.5 කි",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "කොරියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මිලියන 769 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජපානය",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ඩොලර් බිලියන 18.7 කි",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "EU",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "වියට්නාමය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඩොලර් මිලියන 460 කි",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "2021",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඩොලර් මිලියන 287 කි",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "2020",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "වියට්නාමය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "2021",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඩොලර් මිලියන 397.8 කි",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඩොලර් මිලියන 250.2 කි",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මිලියන 62.22 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඩොලර් මිලියන 37.19 කි",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "වසරකට පෙර",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "වියට්නාමය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "954,000 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "2022 පළමු මාස ​​හත",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "10",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "වසරකට පෙර",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "සියයට 90ක්",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "2019",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "කොළඹ/සැප්.02/2022",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "வியட்நாம் கோவிட் நோயிலிருந்து வலுவாக உயர்ந்து, 77 வது தேசிய தினம் கொண்டாடப்படும்போது பணவீக்கத்தைக் குறைக்கிறது",
      "author": "",
      "body_lines": [
        "பொருளாதாரம் - வியட்நாம் ஒரு கொரோனா வைரஸ் தொற்றுநோயிலிருந்து மீண்டு வருவதால், வியட்நாம் வலுவாக மீண்டுள்ளது மற்றும் நாடு செப்டம்பர் 02 அன்று தனது தேசிய தினத்தை கொண்டாடுகிறது, ஏற்றுமதி வெளிநாட்டு முதலீடுகள் அதிகரித்து சுற்றுலாப் பயணிகள் திரும்பத் தொடங்கியதால் ஒரு அறிக்கை கூறுகிறது.",
        "\"உற்பத்தி மற்றும் வணிக நடவடிக்கைகள் கோவிட் -19 தொற்றுநோய் தோன்றுவதற்கு முன்பு இயல்பு நிலைக்குத் திரும்பியுள்ளன\" என்று வெளியுறவு அமைச்சக அறிக்கை தெரிவித்துள்ளது.",
        "\"இருப்பினும், நமது நாட்டின் பொருளாதாரம் உள்ளீட்டு பொருட்களின் அதிக விலைகள், குறிப்பாக பெட்ரோல் விலை போன்ற சவால்களை எதிர்கொள்கிறது.\"",
        "வியட்நாம் தனது தேசிய தினத்தை செப்டம்பர் 02 அன்று கொண்டாடுகிறது. வியட்நாம் தலைவர் 77 ஆண்டுகளுக்கு முன்பு பிரெஞ்சு ஆட்சியில் இருந்து சுதந்திரம் அறிவித்தார்.",
        "நாடு 1983 இல் சந்தைப் பொருளாதாரத்தை ஏற்றுக்கொண்டது, 1989 இல் இருந்து அதன் மத்திய வங்கியை சீர்திருத்தத் தொடங்கியது மற்றும் வெளிநாட்டு நேரடி முதலீட்டை ஈர்க்கும் மற்றும் ஏற்றுமதி மற்றும் இறக்குமதிகளை அதிகரித்து ஒரு நிலையான உயர் வளர்ச்சி நாடாக இப்போது போற்றப்படுகிறது.",
        "முதல் ஏழு மாதங்களில் அந்நிய நேரடி முதலீடு 11.57 பில்லியன் அமெரிக்க டாலர்கள் கடந்த ஆண்டை விட 10.2 சதவீதம் அதிகமாகும்.",
        "செயலாக்கம் மற்றும் உற்பத்தித் துறை 8.87 பில்லியன் டாலர்களையும், ரியல் எஸ்டேட் வணிகம் 1004.8 மில்லியன் டாலர்களையும் ஈட்டியது.",
        "ஆண்டின் முதல் ஏழு மாதங்களில் ஏற்றுமதி 216.35 பில்லியன் அமெரிக்க டாலர்கள், உள்நாட்டுத் துறை 56.9 பில்லியன் அமெரிக்க டாலர்கள் மற்றும் வெளிநாட்டு முதலீட்டுத் துறை 159.3 பில்லியன் அமெரிக்க டாலர்கள்.",
        "இறக்குமதி விற்றுமுதல் 215.59 பில்லியன் அமெரிக்க டாலர்கள், FDI துறை 139.5 பில்லியன் அமெரிக்க டாலர்கள் மற்றும் உள்நாட்டுத் துறை 76.06 பில்லியன் அமெரிக்க டாலர்கள்.",
        "வியட்நாமின் மிகப்பெரிய ஏற்றுமதிச் சந்தையாக அமெரிக்கா 72.6 பில்லியன் அமெரிக்க டாலர்களைக் கொண்டுள்ளது மற்றும் சீனா 72.6 பில்லியன் அமெரிக்க டாலர் மதிப்பீட்டைக் கொண்டு மிகப்பெரிய இறக்குமதிச் சந்தையாக இருந்தது.",
        "சீனாவுடன் வர்த்தகப் பற்றாக்குறை 42.2 பில்லியன் டாலர்கள், கொரியாவுடன் 23.5 பில்லியன் பற்றாக்குறை, ஆசியானுடன் 7.9 பில்லியன் அமெரிக்க டாலர்கள் பற்றாக்குறை, கொரியாவுடன் 23.5 பில்லியன் அமெரிக்க டாலர்கள் பற்றாக்குறை, ஜப்பானுடன் 769 மில்லியன் டாலர் பற்றாக்குறை.",
        "ஐரோப்பிய ஒன்றியத்துடன் 18.7 பில்லியன் அமெரிக்க டாலர் வர்த்தக உபரி இருந்தது.",
        "இலங்கைக்கும் வியட்நாமுக்கும் இடையிலான இருதரப்பு வர்த்தகம் 2020 இல் 287 மில்லியன் அமெரிக்க டொலர்களில் இருந்து 2021 இல் 460 மில்லியன் அமெரிக்க டொலர்களாக அதிகரித்துள்ளது.",
        "2021 இல் வியட்நாமில் இருந்து ஏற்றுமதி 250.2 மில்லியன் டாலர்களில் இருந்து 397.8 மில்லியன் அமெரிக்க டாலர்கள். இலங்கையில் இருந்து இறக்குமதி 62.22 மில்லியனாக இருந்தது, இது முந்தைய வருடத்தில் 37.19 மில்லியன் டாலர்களாக இருந்தது.",
        "வியட்நாம் 2022 ஆம் ஆண்டின் முதல் ஏழு மாதங்களில் 954,000 வெளிநாட்டுப் பார்வையாளர்களை ஈர்த்தது, இது கோவிட் நெருக்கடிக்கு மத்தியில் ஒரு வருடத்திற்கு முந்தைய ஆண்டை விட 10 மடங்கு அதிகம் ஆனால் 2019 ஐ விட 90 சதவீதம் குறைவு. (கொழும்பு/செப்02/2022)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "வியட்நாம்",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "கோவிட்",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "77 தேசிய நாள்",
          "label": "DATE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "வியட்நாம்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "கொரோனா வைரஸ்",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "செப்டம்பர் 02",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "வெளியுறவு அமைச்சகம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "வியட்நாம்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "செப்டம்பர் 02",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "வியட்நாம்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "பிரெஞ்சு",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "77 ஆண்டுகளுக்கு முன்பு",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "1983",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "1989",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "முதல் ஏழு மாதங்கள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "11.57 பில்லியன் அமெரிக்க டாலர்கள்",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "10.2 சதவீதம்",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஒரு வருடம் முன்பு",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "8.87 பில்லியன் டாலர்கள்",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "1004.8 மில்லியன் டாலர்கள்",
            "label": "MONEY"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஆண்டின் முதல் ஏழு மாதம்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "216.35 பில்லியன் அமெரிக்க டாலர்கள்",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "56.9 பில்லியன் அமெரிக்க டாலர்கள்",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "159.3 பில்லியன் அமெரிக்க டாலர்கள்",
            "label": "MONEY"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "215.59 பில்லியன் அமெரிக்க டாலர்கள்",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "FDI",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "139.5 பில்லியன் அமெரிக்க டாலர்கள்",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "76.06 பில்லியன் அமெரிக்க டாலர்கள்",
            "label": "MONEY"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "எங்களுக்கு",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "வியட்நாம்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "72.6 பில்லியன் அமெரிக்க டாலர்கள்",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "சீனா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "72.6 பில்லியன் அமெரிக்க டாலர்கள்",
            "label": "MONEY"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "42.2 பில்லியன் டாலர்கள்",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "சீனா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "23.5 பில்லியன்",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "கொரியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "7.9 பில்லியன் அமெரிக்க டாலர்கள்",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆசியான்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "23.5 பில்லியன் அமெரிக்க டாலர்கள்",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "கொரியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "769 மில்லியன்",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜப்பான்",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "18.7 பில்லியன் அமெரிக்க டாலர்",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "EU",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "வியட்நாம்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "460 மில்லியன் அமெரிக்க டாலர்கள்",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "2021",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "287 மில்லியன் அமெரிக்க டாலர்கள்",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "2020",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "வியட்நாம்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "2021",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "397.8 மில்லியன் அமெரிக்க டாலர்கள்",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "250.2 மில்லியன் டாலர்கள்",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "62.22 மில்லியன்",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "37.19 மில்லியன் டாலர்கள்",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஒரு வருடம் முன்பு",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "வியட்நாம்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "954,000",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "2022 இன் முதல் ஏழு மாதங்கள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "10",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஒரு வருடம் முன்பு",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "90 சதவீதம்",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "2019",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "கொழும்பு/செப்02/2022",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}