{
  "newspaper_id": "lankadeepa-lk",
  "url": "https://www.lankadeepa.lk/news/නිව්මෝනියාවෙන්-වෛද්‍යවරයා-මරුට/101-616421",
  "time_ut": 1657803369,
  "original_lang": "si",
  "original_title": "නිව්මෝනියාවෙන් වෛද්‍යවරයා මරුට",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "The doctor died of pneumonia",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "A doctor from the Sirimavo Bandaranaike Children's Hospital in Peradeniya died while receiving treatment at the Karapitiya Teaching Hospital, the health department said.",
        "The deceased was a 30-year-old doctor named Deepal Amarasuriya, a thinker of Thennakoon Mudiansela, a resident of Halyela.",
        "A post-mortem examination revealed that he had died of shock caused by a bacterial infection with pneumonia. The inquest into this death was conducted today (14) at the Galle Karapitiya Teaching Hospital by Additional Municipal Coroner Mr. Chandrasena Lokuge.",
        "The deceased doctor was a father of one. It was revealed during the autopsy that he had been treated for corona virus and had also contracted influenza a few weeks ago. Relatives have also said that the doctor, who has been waiting in petrol queues for several days, used a tube to take petrol from his car to the motorcycle.",
        "After that, he fell ill and developed pneumonia and was admitted to Peradeniya Hospital. He was later admitted to Kandy Hospital and Ekmo was transferred to Karapitiya Hospital on the 11th for treatment. He died this morning (14).",
        "The post-mortem examination of the dead doctor's body was conducted by expert forensic doctor Mrs. Janaki Warusahannadi."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "the Sirimavo Bandaranaike Children's Hospital",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Peradeniya",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Karapitiya Teaching Hospital",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "30-year-old",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Deepal Amarasuriya",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Thennakoon Mudiansela",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Halyela",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "14",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Galle Karapitiya Teaching Hospital",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "Chandrasena Lokuge",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "a few weeks ago",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "several days",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Peradeniya Hospital",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kandy Hospital",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ekmo",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Karapitiya Hospital",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "11th",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "this morning",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "14",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Janaki Warusahannadi",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "නිව්මෝනියාවෙන් වෛද්‍යවරයා මරුට",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "පේරාදෙණිය සිරිමාවෝ බණ්ඩාරනායක ළමා රෝහලේ වෛද්‍යවයකු කරාපිටිය ශික්ෂණ රෝහලේ එක්මෝ ප්‍රතිකාර ලබමින් සිටිය දී මියගොස් ඇතැයි සෞඛ්‍ය අංශ පවසයි.",
        "මෙලෙස මියගොස් ඇත්තේ හාලිඇල පදිංචි තෙන්නකෝන් මුදියන්සේලාගේ චින්තක දීපාල් අමරසූරිය නැමති 30 හැවිරිදි වියේ පසු වූ වෛද්‍යවරයෙකි.",
        "නිව්මෝනියා තත්ත්වයක් සමඟ රුධිරයට විෂබීජයක් යාමෙන් ඇති වූ කම්පන තත්වයෙන් ඔහු මියගොස් ඇති බව පශ්චාත් මරණ පරීක්ෂණයේ දී අනාවරණය විය. මෙම මරණය සම්බන්ධ හදිසි මරණ පරීක්ෂණය අද (14) ගාල්ල කරාපිටිය ශික්ෂණ රෝහලේ දී අතිරේක නාගරික හදිසි මරණ පරීක්ෂක චන්ද්‍රසේන ලොකුගේ මහතා විසින් පවත්වන ලදී.",
        "මියගිය වෛද්‍යවරයා එක්දරු පියෙකි. ඔහු කොරෝනා ආසාදිතව ප්‍රතිකාර ලබා ඇති අතර සති කිහිපයකට පෙර ඉන්‍ෆ්ලුවන්සා රෝගය ද වැළඳී සිටි බව මරණ පරීක්ෂණයේදී අනාවරණය වී තිබිණි. දින කිහිපයක් පෙට්‍රල් පෝළිම්වල ද රැඳී සිට ඇති වෛද්‍යවරයා තම කාරයේ තිබූ පෙට්‍රල් යතුරුපැදියට ගැනීම සඳහා බටයක් යොදා කටින් පෙට්‍රල් ඇද ඇති බව ද ඥාතීන් පවසා ඇත.",
        "ඉන් පසු රෝගී ව නිව්මෝනියා තත්වයට පත්වූ ඔහු පේරාදෙණිය රෝහලට ඇතුලත්කර ඇත. පසුව මහනුවර රෝහලට ඇතුළත් කර ඇති අතර එක්මෝ ප්‍රතිකාර සඳහා පසුගිය 11 වැනි දා කරාපිටිය රෝහලට මාරුකර එවා තිබිණි. අද (14) උදෑසන ඔහු මියගියේය.",
        "මියගිය වෛද්‍යවරයාගේ සිරුර සම්බන්ධ පශ්චාත් මරණ පරික්ෂණය විශේෂඥ අධිකරණ වෛද්‍ය ජානකී වරුසාහැන්නදි මහත්මිය විසින් පවත්වන ලදී."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "සිරිමාවෝ බණ්ඩාරනායක ළමා රෝහල",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "පේරාදෙණිය",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "කරාපිටිය ශික්ෂණ රෝහල",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "30 හැවිරිදිය",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "දීපාල් අමරසූරිය",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "තෙන්නකෝන් මුදියන්සේලා",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "හාලිඇල",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "14",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගාල්ල කරාපිටිය ශික්ෂණ රෝහල",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "චන්ද්‍රසේන ලොකුගේ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "සති කිහිපයකට පෙර",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "දින කිහිපයක්",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "පේරාදෙණිය රෝහල",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "මහනුවර රෝහල",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "එක්මෝ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "කරාපිටිය රෝහල",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "11 වැනි",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "මේ උදෑසන",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "14",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ජානකී වරුසහන්නදී",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "மருத்துவர் நிமோனியாவால் இறந்தார்",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "பேராதனை சிறிமாவோ பண்டாரநாயக்க சிறுவர் வைத்தியசாலையின் வைத்தியர் ஒருவர் கராப்பிட்டிய போதனா வைத்தியசாலையில் சிகிச்சை பெற்று வந்த நிலையில் உயிரிழந்துள்ளதாக சுகாதார திணைக்களம் தெரிவித்துள்ளது.",
        "ஹாலிஎல பகுதியைச் சேர்ந்த தென்னகோன் முடிஞ்சேலாவின் சிந்தனையாளரான தீபால் அமரசூரிய என்ற 30 வயதுடைய வைத்தியரே இவ்வாறு உயிரிழந்துள்ளார்.",
        "பிரேதப் பரிசோதனையில் அவர் நிமோனியாவால் பாக்டீரியா தொற்று காரணமாக அதிர்ச்சியில் இறந்தது தெரியவந்தது. இந்த மரணம் தொடர்பான விசாரணைகள் இன்று (14) காலி கராபிட்டிய போதனா வைத்தியசாலையில் மேலதிக மாநகர மரண விசாரணை அதிகாரி திரு.சந்திரசேன லொக்குகேவினால் மேற்கொள்ளப்பட்டது.",
        "உயிரிழந்த மருத்துவர் ஒரு பிள்ளையின் தந்தையாவார். பிரேதப் பரிசோதனையின் போது, ​​அவர் கொரோனா வைரஸுக்கு சிகிச்சை பெற்று வந்ததும், சில வாரங்களுக்கு முன் காய்ச்சலால் பாதிக்கப்பட்டிருப்பதும் தெரியவந்தது. பல நாட்களாக பெற்றோல் வரிசையில் காத்திருந்த வைத்தியர் தனது காரில் இருந்து மோட்டார் சைக்கிளுக்கு பெட்ரோலை ட்யூப் மூலம் எடுத்துச் சென்றதாகவும் உறவினர்கள் தெரிவித்துள்ளனர்.",
        "அதன் பின்னர் அவர் நோய்வாய்ப்பட்டு நிமோனியா நோயினால் பாதிக்கப்பட்டு பேராதனை வைத்தியசாலையில் அனுமதிக்கப்பட்டுள்ளார். பின்னர் அவர் கண்டி வைத்தியசாலையில் அனுமதிக்கப்பட்டு சிகிச்சைக்காக எக்மோ கடந்த 11ஆம் திகதி கராப்பிட்டிய வைத்தியசாலைக்கு மாற்றப்பட்டார். இன்று (14) காலை மரணமடைந்தார்.",
        "உயிரிழந்த வைத்தியரின் சடலத்தின் பிரேதப் பரிசோதனையை நிபுணர் சட்ட வைத்தியர் திருமதி ஜானகி வருசஹன்னதி மேற்கொண்டார்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "சிறிமாவோ பண்டாரநாயக்க சிறுவர் வைத்தியசாலை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "பேராதனை",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "கராப்பிட்டிய போதனா வைத்தியசாலை",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "30 வயது",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "தீபால் அமரசூரிய",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "தென்னகோன் முடியசெல",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஹாலியேலா",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "14",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "காலி கராபிட்டிய போதனா வைத்தியசாலை",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "சந்திரசேன லொகுகே",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "சில வாரங்களுக்கு முன்பு",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "பல நாட்கள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பேராதனை வைத்தியசாலை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "கண்டி வைத்தியசாலை",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "எக்மோ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "கராபிட்டிய வைத்தியசாலை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "11வது",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று காலை",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "14",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஜானகி வருசஹன்னடி",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}