{
  "newspaper_id": "ada-lk",
  "url": "https://www.ada.lk/breaking_news/වෙරළබඩ-වෙඩි-තැබීමකින්-පුද්ගලයෙක්-මරුට/11-395890",
  "time_ut": 1659248499,
  "original_lang": "si",
  "original_title": "වෙරළබඩ වෙඩි තැබීමකින් පුද්ගලයෙක් මරුට",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "One killed in coastal shooting",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "Mr. Nihal Talduwa, Police Media Spokesman, said that a person was killed in a shooting by two unknown persons who came on a motorcycle at the Vivekananda Kanda Road area of ​​Koorah Bada last night (30th).",
        "The dead are Sundaram Antony Bernard, 51, a broker and moneylender who lived in the same area.",
        "He was shot in the head and chest area by a 9 mm firearm. The spokesperson added that he died while being taken to the hospital.",
        "The reason for the shooting has not yet been revealed. Coastal Police are investigating."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Nihal Talduwa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "two",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Vivekananda Kanda Road",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Bada",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "last night",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "30th",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sundaram Antony Bernard",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "51",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "9 mm",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Coastal Police",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "වෙරළබඩ වෙඩි තැබීමකින් පුද්ගලයෙක් මරුට",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "යතුරුපැදියකින් පැමිණි නාඳුනන පුද්ගලයන් දෙදෙනකු  වෙරළ බඩ  විවේකානන්ද කන්ද පාර ප්‍රදේශයේදී ඊයේ (30දා) රාත්‍රි සිදු කළ වෙඩි තැබීමකින් පුද්ගලයෙක් මිය ගොස් ඇතැයි පොලිස් මාධ්‍ය ප්‍රකාශක ජ්‍යෙෂ්ඨ පොලිස් අධිකාරී නීතිඥ නිහාල් තල්දූව මහතා පැවසීය.",
        "මියගොස් ඇත්තේ එම ප්‍රදේශයේම පදිංචිව සිටි  බ්‍රෝකර්වරයකු සහ පොලියට මුදල් ලබා දෙන්නකු ලෙස කටයුතු කළ සුන්දරම් ඇන්ටනී බර්නාඩ් 51 යන අයයි.",
        "මිලි මීටර් 9 වර්ගයේ ගිනි අවියකින් වෙඩි තබා ඇති අතර ඔහුගේ හිසට සහ පපු  ප්‍රදේශයට වෙඩි ප්‍රහාරය එල්ල වී ඇත. රෝහල් ගත කිරීමේදී ඔහු මියගොස් ඇතැයි මාධ්‍ය ප්‍රකාශකවරයා වැඩිදුරටත් පැවසීය.",
        "වෙඩි තැබීමට හේතුව මෙතෙක් අනාවරණය වී නැත. වෙරළබඩ පොලිසිය  පරීක්ෂණ පවත්වයි."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "නිහාල් තල්දූව",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "දෙක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "විවේකානන්ද කන්ද පාර",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "බඩා",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "අවසන් රාත්රිය",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "30 වැනි",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "සුන්දරම් ඇන්ටනි බර්නාඩ්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "51",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "9 මි.මී",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "වෙරළබඩ පොලිසිය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "கடலோர துப்பாக்கிச்சூட்டில் ஒருவர் பலியானார்",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "நேற்று (30) இரவு கூரா படாவின் விவேகானந்த கந்த வீதிப் பகுதியில் மோட்டார் சைக்கிளில் வந்த இனந்தெரியாத இருவரால் மேற்கொள்ளப்பட்ட துப்பாக்கிச் சூட்டில் ஒருவர் உயிரிழந்துள்ளதாக பொலிஸ் ஊடகப் பேச்சாளர் திரு. நிஹால் தல்துவ தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "இறந்தவர்கள் அதே பகுதியில் வசித்து வந்த தரகர் மற்றும் பணம் கொடுக்கும் சுந்தரம் ஆண்டனி பெர்னார்ட் (51) ஆவார்.",
        "அவர் தலை மற்றும் மார்பு பகுதியில் 9 மி.மீ துப்பாக்கியால் சுடப்பட்டார். வைத்தியசாலைக்கு கொண்டு செல்லும் போது அவர் உயிரிழந்துள்ளதாக பேச்சாளர் மேலும் தெரிவித்துள்ளார்.",
        "துப்பாக்கிச் சூடு நடத்தப்பட்டதற்கான காரணம் இதுவரை வெளியாகவில்லை. கடலுார் போலீசார் விசாரிக்கின்றனர்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "நிஹால் தல்துவா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இரண்டு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "விவேகானந்தா கண்ட சாலை",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "படா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "நேற்று இரவு",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "30வது",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "சுந்தரம் ஆண்டனி பெர்னார்ட்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "51",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "9 மி.மீ",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "கடலோர போலீஸ்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}