{
  "newspaper_id": "ada-derana-lk",
  "url": "http://www.adaderana.lk/news/84650/sri-lanka-has-made-good-progress-in-negotiations-with-imf-cbsl-chief",
  "time_ut": 1661868060,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Sri Lanka has made good progress in negotiations with IMF - CBSL chief",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Sri Lanka has made good progress in negotiations with IMF - CBSL chief",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "The Governor of the Central Bank of Sri Lanka (CBSL) Dr. Nandalal Weerasinghe says that Sri Lanka has made “good progress” in the negotiations with the International Monetary Fund (IMF), which are aimed at clinching a bailout package.",
        "“I can announce that we have made good progress in the negotiations with the IMF. Hopefully, we will be able to reach the first milestone, a staff-level agreement with the IMF soon,” the central bank chief told reporters in Colombo.",
        "Delivering the interim budget speech for 2022 earlier today, President Ranil Wickremesinghe had also said that talks with the IMF had reached the “final stage”.",
        "Negotiations with the IMF, which has a team of officials visiting Sri Lanka, had made headway, said Wickremesinghe.",
        "“Negotiations with the International Monetary Fund (IMF) have successfully reached its final stage. Discussions on debt restructuring will be held with the main countries that provide loan assistance to our country,” the President had said.",
        "Unveiling the measures in parliament, President Ranil Wickremesinghe added that the government would aim to rein in inflation and introduce legislation to bolster central bank independence.",
        "Sri Lankan officials hope the budget will be followed by a preliminary, staff-level agreement with the IMF for a loan package worth between $2 billion and $3 billion.",
        "The revised budget estimates project revenues of 2 trillion Sri Lankan rupees ($5.6 billion) in 2022, down from an initial figure of 2.23 trillion.",
        "Total expenditure is set to rise to 4.4 trillion rupees, exceeding the earlier estimate of 3.9 trillion."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Sri Lanka",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "the Central Bank of Sri Lanka",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Nandalal Weerasinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the International Monetary Fund",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "first",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "IMF",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Colombo",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "2022",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "IMF",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "IMF",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the International Monetary Fund",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lankan",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "IMF",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "between $2 billion and $3 billion",
            "label": "MONEY"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "2 trillion",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lankan",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "$5.6 billion",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "2022",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "2.23 trillion",
            "label": "MONEY"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "4.4 trillion",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "3.9 trillion",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "ශ්‍රී ලංකාව IMF - CBSL ප්‍රධානියා සමඟ සාකච්ඡා වලදී හොඳ ප්‍රගතියක් ලබා ඇත",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකා මහ බැංකුවේ (CBSL) අධිපති ආචාර්ය නන්දලාල් වීරසිංහ මහතා පවසන්නේ ඇපදීමේ පැකේජයක් ලබා ගැනීමේ අරමුණින් ජාත්‍යන්තර මූල්‍ය අරමුදල (IMF) සමඟ පැවැත්වූ සාකච්ඡාවලදී ශ්‍රී ලංකාව “හොඳ ප්‍රගතියක්” ලබා ඇති බවයි.",
        "“ජාත්‍යන්තර මූල්‍ය අරමුදල සමඟ පැවති සාකච්ඡාවලදී අපි හොඳ ප්‍රගතියක් ලබා ඇති බව මට ප්‍රකාශ කළ හැකියි. IMF සමඟ කාර්ය මණ්ඩල මට්ටමේ ගිවිසුමක් වන පළමු සන්ධිස්ථානයට ලඟා වීමට අපට හැකි වනු ඇතැයි බලාපොරොත්තු වෙමු,” මහ බැංකු ප්‍රධානියා කොළඹදී වාර්තාකරුවන්ට පැවසීය.",
        "2022 වසර සඳහා වන අතුරු අයවැය කතාව අද පෙරේදා ඉදිරිපත් කරමින් ජනාධිපති රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ ද කියා සිටියේ ජාත්‍යන්තර මූල්‍ය අරමුදල සමඟ සාකච්ඡා “අවසන් අදියරට” පැමිණ ඇති බවයි.",
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවට පැමිණෙන නිලධාරීන් කණ්ඩායමක් සිටින IMF සමඟ සාකච්ඡා ප්‍රගතියක් ලබා ඇති බව වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතා පැවසීය.",
        "“ජාත්‍යන්තර මූල්‍ය අරමුදල (IMF) සමඟ සාකච්ඡා සාර්ථකව අවසන් අදියරට පැමිණ තිබෙනවා. අපේ රටට ණය ආධාර ලබාදෙන ප්‍රධාන රටවල් සමඟ ණය ප්‍රතිව්‍යුහගත කිරීම පිළිබඳ සාකච්ඡා කරනවා” යැයි ජනාධිපතිවරයා එහිදී පවසා තිබේ.",
        "උද්ධමනය පාලනය කිරීම සහ මහ බැංකුවේ ස්වාධීනත්වය තහවුරු කිරීම සඳහා නීති සම්පාදනය කිරීම රජයේ අරමුණ බව පාර්ලිමේන්තුවේදී ජනාධිපති රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතා ප්‍රකාශ කළේය.",
        "ඩොලර් බිලියන 2 ත් 3 ත් අතර ණය පැකේජයක් සඳහා IMF සමඟ මූලික, කාර්ය මණ්ඩල මට්ටමේ ගිවිසුමක් මගින් අයවැය අනුගමනය කරනු ඇතැයි ශ්‍රී ලංකා නිලධාරීන් බලාපොරොත්තු වේ.",
        "සංශෝධිත අයවැය මඟින් 2022 දී ශ්‍රී ලංකා රුපියල් ට්‍රිලියන 2 (ඩොලර් බිලියන 5.6) ක ව්‍යාපෘති ආදායමක් ඇස්තමේන්තු කර ඇති අතර එය මූලික අගය වූ ට්‍රිලියන 2.23 ට වඩා පහත වැටී ඇත.",
        "මුළු වියදම රුපියල් ට්‍රිලියන 4.4 දක්වා ඉහළ යාමට නියමිත අතර එය කලින් ඇස්තමේන්තු කළ ටි‍්‍රලියන 3.9 ඉක්මවයි."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකා මහ බැංකුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "නන්දලාල් වීරසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජාත්‍යන්තර මුල්‍ය අරමුදල",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "පළමුවන",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "IMF",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "කොළඹ",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "2022",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "IMF",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "IMF",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ජාත්‍යන්තර මුල්‍ය අරමුදල",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලාංකික",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "IMF",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඩොලර් බිලියන 2 සිට ඩොලර් බිලියන 3 දක්වා",
            "label": "MONEY"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ට්‍රිලියන 2 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලාංකික",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඩොලර් බිලියන 5.6 කි",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "2022",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ට්‍රිලියන 2.23 කි",
            "label": "MONEY"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ට්‍රිලියන 4.4 කි",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "ට්‍රිලියන 3.9 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "IMF - CBSL தலைவர் உடனான பேச்சுவார்த்தைகளில் இலங்கை நல்ல முன்னேற்றம் கண்டுள்ளது",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "இலங்கை மத்திய வங்கியின் (CBSL) ஆளுநர் கலாநிதி நந்தலால் வீரசிங்க, பிணை எடுப்புப் பொதியை இலக்காகக் கொண்ட சர்வதேச நாணய நிதியத்துடனான (IMF) பேச்சுவார்த்தைகளில் இலங்கை \"நல்ல முன்னேற்றம்\" அடைந்துள்ளது என்று கூறுகிறார்.",
        "“IMF உடனான பேச்சுவார்த்தையில் நாங்கள் நல்ல முன்னேற்றம் அடைந்துள்ளோம் என்பதை என்னால் அறிவிக்க முடியும். IMF உடனான ஊழியர் அளவிலான உடன்படிக்கையான முதல் மைல்கல்லை நாம் விரைவில் அடைய முடியும் என நம்புகிறோம்” என மத்திய வங்கியின் தலைவர் கொழும்பில் செய்தியாளர்களிடம் தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "2022ஆம் ஆண்டுக்கான இடைக்கால வரவு செலவுத் திட்டத்தை இன்று முன்வைத்த ஜனாதிபதி ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க, சர்வதேச நாணய நிதியத்துடனான பேச்சுவார்த்தை “இறுதிக் கட்டத்தை” எட்டியுள்ளதாகவும் தெரிவித்திருந்தார்.",
        "இலங்கைக்கு விஜயம் செய்யும் அதிகாரிகள் குழுவைக் கொண்ட சர்வதேச நாணய நிதியத்துடனான பேச்சுவார்த்தைகள் முன்னேறியுள்ளதாக விக்கிரமசிங்க கூறினார்.",
        "“சர்வதேச நாணய நிதியத்துடனான (IMF) பேச்சுவார்த்தைகள் வெற்றிகரமாக இறுதிக் கட்டத்தை எட்டியுள்ளன. எமது நாட்டிற்கு கடன் உதவி வழங்கும் பிரதான நாடுகளுடன் கடன் மறுசீரமைப்பு தொடர்பில் கலந்துரையாடப்படும்” என ஜனாதிபதி தெரிவித்திருந்தார்.",
        "இந்த நடவடிக்கைகளை நாடாளுமன்றத்தில் வெளியிட்ட ஜனாதிபதி ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க, பணவீக்கத்தை கட்டுப்படுத்துவது மற்றும் மத்திய வங்கியின் சுதந்திரத்தை வலுப்படுத்தும் சட்டத்தை அறிமுகப்படுத்துவது அரசாங்கத்தின் இலக்காக இருக்கும் என்று கூறினார்.",
        "வரவு செலவுத் திட்டத்தைத் தொடர்ந்து IMF உடன் 2 பில்லியன் டாலர் முதல் 3 பில்லியன் டாலர் வரையிலான கடன் பொதிக்கான பூர்வாங்க, பணியாளர்கள் அளவிலான ஒப்பந்தம் மேற்கொள்ளப்படும் என இலங்கை அதிகாரிகள் நம்புகின்றனர்.",
        "திருத்தப்பட்ட வரவுசெலவுத் திட்டம் 2022 இல் 2 டிரில்லியன் இலங்கை ரூபாய் ($5.6 பில்லியன்) திட்ட வருமானத்தை மதிப்பிடுகிறது, இது ஆரம்ப எண்ணிக்கையான 2.23 டிரில்லியனில் இருந்து குறைகிறது.",
        "மொத்தச் செலவு 4.4 டிரில்லியன் ரூபாயாக உயரும், இது முந்தைய மதிப்பீட்டான 3.9 டிரில்லியனைத் தாண்டியது."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "இலங்கை",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை மத்திய வங்கி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "நந்தலால் வீரசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சர்வதேச நாணய நிதியம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "முதலில்",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "IMF",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "கொழும்பு",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "2022",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "IMF",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "IMF",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "சர்வதேச நாணய நிதியம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "IMF",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "$2 பில்லியன் மற்றும் $3 பில்லியன் இடையே",
            "label": "MONEY"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "2 டிரில்லியன்",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "$5.6 பில்லியன்",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "2022",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "2.23 டிரில்லியன்",
            "label": "MONEY"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "4.4 டிரில்லியன்",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "3.9 டிரில்லியன்",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}