{
  "newspaper_id": "daily-mirror-lk",
  "url": "https://www.dailymirror.lk/latest_news/Two-Sri-Lankan-origin-Canadians-among-Top-25-Canadian-Immigrants-of-2022/342-243505",
  "time_ut": 1661177737,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Two Sri Lankan origin Canadians among Top 25 Canadian Immigrants of 2022",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Two Sri Lankan origin Canadians among Top 25 Canadian Immigrants of 2022",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "Two Sri Lankan origin Canadians, Professor Janaka Ruwanpura and Dr. Sivakumar Gulasingam were among the Top 25 Canadian Immigrants of 2022, the High Commission of Sri Lanka to Canada said.",
        "Professor Ruwanpura is a scholar in construction engineering and an award-winning academic.",
        "He is the Vice-provost and Associate Vice-President (Research/international) and Professor of Engineering at the University of Calgary.",
        "Professor Ruwanpura has won international, national, provincial, and municipal awards for his academic accomplishments, research and innovation.",
        "A few recent awards received by him include the Distinguished Alumni Award (Arizona State University), Life Time Achievement Award from Sri Lanka Foundation (Los Angeles) and City of Calgary’s International Achievement.",
        "Dr. Sivakumar Gulasingam is an award-winning physical medicine and rehabilitation physician attached to University Health Network’s Toronto Rehabilitation Institute and an Assistant Professor of the University of Toronto.",
        "Before migrating to Canada, Dr. Gulasingam had worked as the lead physician at the National Rehabilitation Hospital in Sri Lanka.",
        "He is a national trainer and para-athletics classifier with Athletics Canada, International Paralympic Committee classifier, international trainer for World Para-Athletics and World Para-Dance Sports.",
        "Dr. Gulasingam is a recipient of many prestigious awards including Michael Gordon Award for Humanism in Medicine from University of Toronto and The Most Outstanding Young Persons of the Year - Humanitarian and Voluntary Services, Junior Chambers International (JCI), Sri Lanka (2004).",
        "The High Commissioner of Sri Lanka to Canada Harsha Kumara Navaratne graced the Annual Award Ceremony of the Canadian Immigrant Magazine in Toronto where the two Sri Lankans were rewarded.",
        "The Minister of Immigration, Refugees and Citizenship of Canada, Sean Fraser, High Commissioner Navaratne and a cross section of academics, professionals and members of the business community in Canada, attended the event."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Two",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "Sri Lankan",
          "label": "NORP"
        },
        {
          "text": "Canadians",
          "label": "NORP"
        },
        {
          "text": "25",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "Canadian",
          "label": "NORP"
        },
        {
          "text": "Immigrants",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "2022",
          "label": "DATE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Two",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lankan",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Canadians",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Janaka Ruwanpura",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sivakumar Gulasingam",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "25",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Canadian",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Immigrants",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "2022",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the High Commission of Sri Lanka",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Canada",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Ruwanpura",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the University of Calgary",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Ruwanpura",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Arizona State University",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Life Time Achievement Award",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka Foundation",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Los Angeles",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Calgary",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sivakumar Gulasingam",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "University Health Network’s",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Toronto Rehabilitation Institute",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the University of Toronto",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Canada",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Gulasingam",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the National Rehabilitation Hospital",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Athletics Canada",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "International Paralympic Committee",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "World Para-Athletics",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "World Para-Dance Sports",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Gulasingam",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Michael Gordon Award",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "University of Toronto",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Voluntary Services",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Junior Chambers International",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "2004",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Canada",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kumara Navaratne",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Canadian Immigrant Magazine",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Toronto",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "two",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lankans",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Canada",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sean Fraser",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Canada",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "2022 හොඳම කැනේඩියානු සංක්‍රමණිකයන් 25 දෙනා අතරට ශ්‍රී ලාංකික සම්භවයක් ඇති කැනේඩියානුවන් දෙදෙනෙක්",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "ශ්‍රී ලාංකික සම්භවයක් ඇති කැනේඩියානුවන් දෙදෙනෙකු වන මහාචාර්ය ජනක රුවන්පුර සහ ආචාර්ය සිවකුමාර් ගුලසිංහම් 2022 වසරේ හොඳම කැනේඩියානු සංක්‍රමණිකයන් 25 දෙනා අතරට පැමිණි බව කැනඩාවේ ශ්‍රී ලංකා මහ කොමසාරිස් කාර්යාලය පවසයි.",
        "මහාචාර්ය රුවන්පුර ඉදිකිරීම් ඉංජිනේරු විද්‍යාව පිළිබඳ විශාරදයෙකු වන අතර සම්මානලාභී ශාස්ත්‍රපතියෙකි.",
        "ඔහු කැල්ගරි විශ්වවිද්‍යාලයේ උප ප්‍රොවෝස්ට් සහ සහකාර උප සභාපති (පර්යේෂණ/ජාත්‍යන්තර) සහ ඉංජිනේරු විද්‍යාව පිළිබඳ මහාචාර්යවරයා වේ.",
        "මහාචාර්ය රුවන්පුර ඔහුගේ ශාස්ත්‍රීය ජයග්‍රහණ, පර්යේෂණ සහ නවෝත්පාදන සඳහා ජාත්‍යන්තර, ජාතික, පළාත් සහ නාගරික සම්මාන දිනා ඇත.",
        "ඔහුට මෑතකාලීනව ලැබුණු සම්මාන කිහිපයක් අතර විශිෂ්ට ආදි ශිෂ්‍ය සම්මානය (ඇරිසෝනා ප්‍රාන්ත විශ්ව විද්‍යාලය), ශ්‍රී ලංකා පදනම (ලොස් ඇන්ජලීස්) වෙතින් ජීවිත කාලය ජයග්‍රහණ සම්මානය සහ කැල්ගරි නගරයේ ජාත්‍යන්තර ජයග්‍රහණ ඇතුළත් වේ.",
        "වෛද්‍ය සිවකුමාර් ගුලසිංහම් යනු විශ්ව විද්‍යාල සෞඛ්‍ය ජාලයේ ටොරොන්ටෝ පුනරුත්ථාපන ආයතනයට අනුබද්ධ සම්මානලාභී ශාරීරික වෛද්‍ය සහ පුනරුත්ථාපන වෛද්‍යවරයෙකි සහ ටොරොන්ටෝ විශ්ව විද්‍යාලයේ සහකාර මහාචාර්යවරයෙකි.",
        "කැනඩාවට සංක්‍රමණය වීමට පෙර වෛද්‍ය ගුලසිංහම් ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ ජාතික පුනරුත්ථාපන රෝහලේ ප්‍රධාන වෛද්‍යවරයා ලෙස සේවය කර ඇත.",
        "ඔහු මලල ක්‍රීඩා කැනඩාව, ජාත්‍යන්තර පැරාලිම්පික් කමිටු වර්ගීකාරකය, ලෝක පැරා මලල ක්‍රීඩා සහ ලෝක පැරා-නැටුම් ක්‍රීඩා සඳහා ජාත්‍යන්තර පුහුණුකරුවා සමඟ ජාතික පුහුණුකරුවෙකු සහ පැරා මලල ක්‍රීඩා වර්ගීකාරකයෙකි.",
        "වෛද්‍ය ගුලසිංහම් ටොරොන්ටෝ විශ්ව විද්‍යාලයෙන් වෛද්‍ය විද්‍යාව පිළිබඳ මානවවාදය සඳහා වන මයිකල් ගෝර්ඩන් සම්මානය සහ වසරේ විශිෂ්ටතම තරුණ පුද්ගලයින් - මානුෂීය හා ස්වේච්ඡා සේවා, ජූනියර් චේම්බර්ස් ඉන්ටර්නැෂනල් (JCI), ශ්‍රී ලංකාව (2004) ඇතුළු කීර්තිමත් සම්මාන රැසකින් පිදුම් ලැබූවෙකි.",
        "කැනඩාවේ ශ්‍රී ලංකා මහ කොමසාරිස් හර්ෂ කුමාර නවරත්න මහතා විසින් ටොරොන්ටෝ හි පැවති කැනේඩියානු සංක්‍රමණික සඟරාවේ වාර්ෂික සම්මාන ප්‍රදානෝත්සවයට සහභාගී වූ අතර එහිදී ශ්‍රී ලාංකිකයන් දෙදෙනාට ත්‍යාග පිරිනමන ලදී.",
        "කැනඩාවේ ආගමන, සරණාගතයින් සහ පුරවැසිභාවය පිළිබඳ අමාත්‍ය ෂෝන් ෆ්‍රේසර්, මහ කොමසාරිස් නවරත්න සහ කැනඩාවේ විද්වතුන්, වෘත්තිකයන් සහ ව්‍යාපාරික ප්‍රජාවේ සාමාජිකයින්ගේ හරස්කඩක් මෙම අවස්ථාවට සහභාගී විය."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "දෙක",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "ශ්‍රී ලාංකික",
          "label": "NORP"
        },
        {
          "text": "කැනේඩියානුවන්",
          "label": "NORP"
        },
        {
          "text": "25",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "කැනේඩියානු",
          "label": "NORP"
        },
        {
          "text": "සංක්‍රමණිකයන්",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "2022",
          "label": "DATE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "දෙක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලාංකික",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "කැනේඩියානුවන්",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Janaka Ruwanpura",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "සිවකුමාර් ගුලසිංහම්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "25",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "කැනේඩියානු",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "සංක්‍රමණිකයන්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "2022",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකා මහ කොමසාරිස් කාර්යාලය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "කැනඩාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Ruwanpura",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "කැල්ගරි විශ්ව විද්‍යාලය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Ruwanpura",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ඇරිසෝනා රාජ්ය විශ්ව විද්යාලය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Life Time Achievement Award",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකා පදනම",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ලොස් ඇන්ජලීස්",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "කැල්ගරි",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "සිවකුමාර් ගුලසිංහම්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "විශ්ව විද්‍යාල සෞඛ්‍ය ජාලය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ටොරොන්ටෝ පුනරුත්ථාපන ආයතනය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ටොරොන්ටෝ විශ්ව විද්‍යාලය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "කැනඩාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගුලසිංහම් ය",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජාතික පුනරුත්ථාපන රෝහල",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "මලල ක්රීඩා කැනඩාව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජාත්‍යන්තර පැරාලිම්පික් කමිටුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ලෝක පැරා මලල ක්‍රීඩා",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ලෝක පැරා-නැටුම් ක්රීඩා",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ගුලසිංහම් ය",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "මයිකල් ගෝර්ඩන් සම්මානය",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ටොරොන්ටෝ විශ්ව විද්‍යාලය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ස්වේච්ඡා සේවා",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජූනියර් චැම්බර්ස් ඉන්ටර්නැෂනල්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "2004",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "කැනඩාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "කුමාර නවරත්න",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "කැනේඩියානු සංක්‍රමණ සඟරාව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Toronto",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "දෙක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලාංකිකයන්",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "කැනඩාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ෂෝන් ෆ්රේසර්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "කැනඩාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "2022 ஆம் ஆண்டின் முதல் 25 கனேடிய குடியேறியவர்களில் இரண்டு இலங்கை வம்சாவளி கனேடியர்கள்",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "இரண்டு இலங்கை வம்சாவளி கனேடியர்கள், பேராசிரியர் ஜானக ருவன்புர மற்றும் கலாநிதி சிவகுமார் குலசிங்கம் ஆகியோர் 2022 ஆம் ஆண்டின் முதல் 25 கனேடிய குடியேற்றக்காரர்களில் ஒருவர் என்று கனடாவுக்கான இலங்கை உயர்ஸ்தானிகராலயம் தெரிவித்துள்ளது.",
        "பேராசிரியர் ருவன்புரா கட்டுமானப் பொறியியலில் அறிஞரும் விருது பெற்ற கல்வியாளரும் ஆவார்.",
        "அவர் கால்கேரி பல்கலைக்கழகத்தில் துணை-ஆய்வாளர் மற்றும் இணை துணைத் தலைவர் (ஆராய்ச்சி/சர்வதேசம்) மற்றும் பொறியியல் பேராசிரியராக உள்ளார்.",
        "பேராசிரியர் ருவன்புரா தனது கல்விசார் சாதனைகள், ஆராய்ச்சி மற்றும் கண்டுபிடிப்புகளுக்காக சர்வதேச, தேசிய, மாகாண மற்றும் நகராட்சி விருதுகளை வென்றுள்ளார்.",
        "அவர் சமீபத்தில் பெற்ற சில விருதுகளில் புகழ்பெற்ற முன்னாள் மாணவர் விருது (அரிசோனா மாநில பல்கலைக்கழகம்), இலங்கை அறக்கட்டளையின் (லாஸ் ஏஞ்சல்ஸ்) வாழ்நாள் சாதனை விருது மற்றும் கால்கரியின் சர்வதேச சாதனைகள் ஆகியவை அடங்கும்.",
        "டாக்டர். சிவகுமார் குலசிங்கம், பல்கலைக்கழக சுகாதார வலையமைப்பின் ரொறொன்ரோ புனர்வாழ்வு நிறுவனத்தில் இணைந்த ஒரு விருது பெற்ற உடல் மருத்துவம் மற்றும் மறுவாழ்வு மருத்துவர் மற்றும் டொராண்டோ பல்கலைக்கழகத்தின் உதவி பேராசிரியரும் ஆவார்.",
        "கனடாவிற்கு குடிபெயர்வதற்கு முன்னர், இலங்கையில் உள்ள தேசிய புனர்வாழ்வு மருத்துவமனையில் முன்னணி மருத்துவராக டாக்டர் குலசிங்கம் பணியாற்றினார்.",
        "அவர் தேசிய பயிற்சியாளர் மற்றும் தடகள கனடா, சர்வதேச பாராலிம்பிக் கமிட்டி வகைப்படுத்தி, உலக பாரா தடகளம் மற்றும் உலக பாரா-டான்ஸ் விளையாட்டுகளுக்கான சர்வதேச பயிற்சியாளர்.",
        "டொராண்டோ பல்கலைக்கழகத்தின் மருத்துவத்தில் மனிதநேயத்திற்கான மைக்கேல் கார்டன் விருது மற்றும் இந்த ஆண்டின் மிகச் சிறந்த இளைஞர்கள் - மனிதநேய மற்றும் தன்னார்வ சேவைகள், ஜூனியர் சேம்பர்ஸ் இன்டர்நேஷனல் (JCI), இலங்கை (2004) உட்பட பல மதிப்புமிக்க விருதுகளை டாக்டர் குலசிங்கம் பெற்றுள்ளார்.",
        "கனடாவுக்கான இலங்கை உயர்ஸ்தானிகர் ஹர்ஷ குமார நவரத்ன அவர்கள் ரொறன்ரோவில் நடைபெற்ற கனேடிய புலம்பெயர்ந்தோர் சஞ்சிகையின் வருடாந்த விருது வழங்கும் நிகழ்வில் கலந்துகொண்டு இரண்டு இலங்கையர்களுக்கு வெகுமதி வழங்கப்பட்டது.",
        "கனடாவின் குடிவரவு, அகதிகள் மற்றும் குடியுரிமை அமைச்சர், சீன் பிரேசர், உயர் ஸ்தானிகர் நவரத்ன மற்றும் கனடாவிலுள்ள கல்வியாளர்கள், தொழில் வல்லுனர்கள் மற்றும் வர்த்தக சமூகத்தின் ஒரு பிரிவினர் இந்த நிகழ்வில் கலந்து கொண்டனர்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "இரண்டு",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "இலங்கை",
          "label": "NORP"
        },
        {
          "text": "கனடியர்கள்",
          "label": "NORP"
        },
        {
          "text": "25",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "கனடியன்",
          "label": "NORP"
        },
        {
          "text": "குடியேறியவர்கள்",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "2022",
          "label": "DATE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "இரண்டு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "கனடியர்கள்",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Janaka Ruwanpura",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "சிவகுமார் குலசிங்கம்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "25",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "கனடியன்",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "குடியேறியவர்கள்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "2022",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை உயர் ஸ்தானிகராலயம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "கனடா",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Ruwanpura",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "கல்கரி பல்கலைக்கழகம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Ruwanpura",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "அரிசோனா மாநில பல்கலைக்கழகம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "வாழ்நாள் சாதனையாளர் விருது",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை அறக்கட்டளை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "லாஸ் ஏஞ்சல்ஸ்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "கல்கரி",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "சிவகுமார் குலசிங்கம்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "பல்கலைக்கழக சுகாதார வலையமைப்பு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "டொராண்டோ மறுவாழ்வு நிறுவனம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "டொராண்டோ பல்கலைக்கழகம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "கனடா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "குலசிங்கம்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "தேசிய மறுவாழ்வு மருத்துவமனை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "தடகள கனடா",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "சர்வதேச பாராலிம்பிக் குழு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "உலக பாரா தடகளம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "உலக பாரா-டான்ஸ் விளையாட்டு",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "குலசிங்கம்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "மைக்கேல் கார்டன் விருது",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "டொராண்டோ பல்கலைக்கழகம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "தன்னார்வ சேவைகள்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜூனியர் சேம்பர்ஸ் இன்டர்நேஷனல்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "2004",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "கனடா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "குமார நவரத்ன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "கனடியன் இமிக்ரண்ட் இதழ்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Toronto",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இரண்டு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கையர்கள்",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "கனடா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சீன் ஃப்ரேசர்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "கனடா",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}