{
  "newspaper_id": "economy-next-com",
  "url": "https://economynext.com/sri-lankas-prestige-battle-ananda-passes-the-baton-of-blame-97856/",
  "time_ut": 1658640900,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Sri Lanka’s prestige battle: Ananda passes the baton of blame",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Sri Lanka’s prestige battle: Ananda passes the baton of blame",
      "author": "Namal Suvendra",
      "body_lines": [
        "ECONOMYNEXT – The ascension to power of President Ranil Wickremesinghe and school-time buddy Dinesh Gunawardena is cheered and widely celebrated by an unlikely group, the distinguished old boys of Ananda College, one of the top public schools in the island.",
        "After being at the receiving end of popular public scorn over old boy Gotabaya Rajapaksa’s efficient mismanagement of the economy, old Anandians were jubilant when the honour now passes to two alumni of Royal.",
        "“We have hereby handed the opportunity to receive public insults to Royalists – sent by Anandians,” read a post widely shared among former students of the Colombo 10 (Maria Kade) school that was also attended by Gotabaya and disgraced treasury secretary Sajith Attygalle.",
        "A Facebook page entitled: Anandians for Gotabaya” changed its name to “Anandians for nation” when Gotabaya escaped through a backdoor and fled when tens of thousands overran his palace on July 9. A spokesman for an old Anandian WhatsApp group said the traffic on their smart phones had declined sharply and members were already seeing considerable savings on their internet data bills.",
        "They were also relieved when Dullas Alahapperuma, an Ananda alumnus, lost to old Royalist Ranil in the parliamentary election on July 19. “It was a good battle to loose,” a senior Ananda OBA spokesman said adding that he was fed up explaining to friends that he cannot recall a Rajapaksa in his class.",
        "It is reliably learnt that there was no maroon-and-gold tie wearing old boys at the Changi Terminal 3 when Rajapaksa arrived in Singapore on July 14 aboard a Saudia Boeing 787 Dreamliner ending the nightmare of many Sri Lankans.",
        "In less that 24 hours at the job, Wickremesinghe received more international traction than Gotabaya in his entire 32-month presidency for his Yankee-style shock-and-awe crackdown on the Galle Face protestors. The US, EU, UN and the core group on Sri Lanka at the Human Rights Council also issued statements regarding the South Asian nation.",
        "US ambassador Julie Chung led the pack with: “This is not the time to crack down on citizens, but instead to look ahead at the immediate and tangible steps the Government can take to regain the trust of the people, restore stability, and rebuild the economy.”",
        "A remarkable achievement considering it took Gotabaya one full week to receive similar missives from  foreign governments. That was after the abduction of a Swiss embassy local employee.",
        "The Ranil-Dinesh combo has been close friends since 1952 when they were both 3 years old. They are from what is known as the “Group of 60,” the Form 1 batch of Royal College Colombo. Two other politicians from the same batch are the late Anura Bandaranaike and former minister Malik Samarawickrema.",
        "Prime minister Sirima Bandaranaike had her son Anura’s classmate, Jayantha Jayasinghe, as her PSO, Personal Security Officer.",
        "But, the most honourable in the Group of 60 is possibly brigadier Vipul Boteju who quit the army after refusing to take orders from then state minister of defence Ranjan Wijeratne to bump off JVP suspects in his custody. Vipul quit his post as a commanding officer in the deep south after explaining to Wijeratne in unprintable language that he would not carry out illegal orders."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Sri Lanka",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "Ananda",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Dinesh Gunawardena",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ananda College",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "one",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Gotabaya Rajapaksa’s",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Anandians",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "two",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Royal",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Royalists",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Maria Kade",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Gotabaya",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "treasury",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sajith Attygalle",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Gotabaya",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Gotabaya",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "tens of thousands",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "July 9",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Anandian WhatsApp",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Dullas Alahapperuma",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ananda",
            "label": "PRODUCT"
          },
          {
            "text": "Royalist Ranil",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "July 19",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ananda OBA",
            "label": "PRODUCT"
          },
          {
            "text": "Rajapaksa",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the Changi Terminal 3",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "Rajapaksa",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Singapore",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "July 14",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Saudia Boeing",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lankans",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "less that",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "24 hours",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Gotabaya",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "32-month",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Yankee",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Galle Face",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "US",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "EU",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "UN",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Human Rights Council",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "South Asian",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "US",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Julie Chung",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Gotabaya",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Swiss",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "1952",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "3 years old",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the “Group of 60",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Royal College Colombo",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Two",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Anura Bandaranaike",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Malik Samarawickrema",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sirima Bandaranaike",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Anura",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Jayantha Jayasinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "PSO",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "60",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Vipul Boteju",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ranjan Wijeratne",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "JVP",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Wijeratne",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ කීර්තිමත් සටන: ආනන්ද දොස් පවරයි",
      "author": "නාමල් සුවේන්ද්‍ර",
      "body_lines": [
        "ECONOMYNEXT – ජනාධිපති රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ සහ පාසල් කාලයේ මිතුරෙකු වූ දිනේෂ් ගුණවර්ධන බලයට පත්වීම දිවයිනේ ප්‍රමුඛ පෙළේ රජයේ පාසලක් වන ආනන්ද විද්‍යාලයේ කීර්තිමත් ආදි ශිෂ්‍යයින් පිරිසක් විසින් ඔල්වරසන් හා පුළුල් ලෙස සමරනු ලබයි.",
        "ආදි ශිෂ්‍ය ගෝඨාබය රාජපක්ෂගේ කාර්යක්ෂම ආර්ථිකය කළමනාකරණය කිරීම සම්බන්ධයෙන් මහජනතාවගේ අප්‍රසාදයට ලක්වීමෙන් පසුව, රාජකීය ආදි සිසුන් දෙදෙනකුට එම ගෞරවය හිමිවන විට ආදි ආනන්දීයයෝ ප්‍රීතියෙන් පිනා ගියහ.",
        "කොළඹ 10 (මරියා කඩේ) පාසලේ ආදි සිසුන් අතර බහුලව හුවමාරු වූ සටහනක් කියවුනේ, \"ආනන්දිකයන් විසින් එවන ලද රාජකීයයන්ට ප්‍රසිද්ධියේ අපහාස ලැබීමට අපි මෙයින් අවස්ථාව ලබා දී ඇත්තෙමු\" යනුවෙන් ගෝඨාභය සහ අපකීර්තියට පත් භාණ්ඩාගාර ලේකම් සජිත් ආටිගල ද සහභාගි විය.",
        "ජුලි 9 වැනිදා දස දහස් ගණනක් ඔහුගේ මාලිගාවට කඩා වදින විට ගෝඨාභය පිටුපස දොරකින් පැන පලා ගිය විට: Anandians for Gotabaya” නමින් Facebook පිටුවක් එහි නම “Anandians for nation” ලෙස වෙනස් කර ඇත. පැරණි Anandian WhatsApp group එකක ප්‍රකාශකයෙකු පැවසුවේ ඔවුන්ගේ ගමනාගමනය ස්මාර්ට් ජංගම දුරකථන තියුනු ලෙස පහත වැටී ඇති අතර සාමාජිකයින් දැනටමත් ඔවුන්ගේ අන්තර්ජාල දත්ත බිල්පත්වල සැලකිය යුතු ඉතිරියක් දැක ඇත.",
        "ජුලි 19 වැනිදා පැවති පාර්ලිමේන්තු මැතිවරණයේදී ආනන්ද ආදි ශිෂ්‍යයෙකු වූ ඩලස් අලහප්පෙරුම පරණ රාජකීය රනිල්ට පරාජය වීමත් සමඟ ඔවුන්ද සහනයට පත් විය. \"එය පැරදවීමට හොඳ සටනක් විය\" යනුවෙන් ආනන්ද ආදි ශිෂ්‍ය සංගමයේ ජ්‍යෙෂ්ඨ ප්‍රකාශකයෙකු පැවසුවේ මිතුරන්ට කරුණු පැහැදිලි කිරීම ඔහුට එපා වූ බවයි. තමන්ගේ පන්තියේ රාජපක්ෂ කෙනෙක්ව මතක් කරන්න බෑ කියලා.",
        "බොහෝ ශ්‍රී ලාංකිකයන්ගේ බියකරු සිහිනය නිමා කරමින් සෞදියා බෝයිං 787 ඩ්‍රීම්ලයිනර් යානයකින් රාජපක්ෂ ජූලි 14 වැනිදා සිංගප්පූරුවට පැමිණෙන විට චාන්ගි ටර්මිනල් 3 හි මෙරූන් සහ රන් ටයි පටියක් නොතිබූ බව විශ්වාසදායක ලෙස දැනගන්නට ඇත.",
        "රැකියාවේ පැය 24කටත් අඩු කාලයකදී, ගාලු මුවදොර විරෝධතාකරුවන්ට එරෙහිව යැංකි පන්නයේ කම්පන සහ විස්මිත මර්ධනය සඳහා වික්‍රමසිංහට ඔහුගේ මුළු මාස ​​32 ජනාධිපති ධුර කාලය තුළ ගෝඨාභයට වඩා ජාත්‍යන්තර ආකර්ෂණයක් ලැබුණි. මානව හිමිකම් කවුන්සිලයේදී එක්සත් ජනපදය, යුරෝපා සංගමය, එක්සත් ජාතීන්ගේ සංවිධානය සහ ශ්‍රී ලංකාව පිළිබඳ මූලික කණ්ඩායම ද දකුණු ආසියානු ජාතිය සම්බන්ධයෙන් ප්‍රකාශ නිකුත් කළේය.",
        "එක්සත් ජනපද තානාපතිනි ජුලී චුන්ග් මෙම පැකේජයට නායකත්වය දුන්නේ: “මෙය පුරවැසියන් මර්දනය කිරීමට කාලය නොවේ, ඒ වෙනුවට ජනතාවගේ විශ්වාසය නැවත ලබා ගැනීමට, ස්ථාවරත්වය යථා තත්ත්වයට පත් කිරීමට සහ නැවත ගොඩනැගීමට රජයට ගත හැකි ක්ෂණික හා ප්‍රත්‍යක්ෂ පියවර දෙස බලා සිටීමටයි. ආර්ථිකය.\"",
        "විදේශීය ආන්ඩුවලින් එවැනිම මිසයිල ලබා ගැනීමට ගෝඨාභයට සතියක් ගතවීම කැපී පෙනෙන ජයග්‍රහණයක් ලෙස සැලකේ. ඒ ස්විට්සර්ලන්ත තානාපති කාර්යාලයේ දේශීය සේවකයෙකු පැහැරගෙන යාමෙන් අනතුරුවයි.",
        "රනිල් - දිනේෂ් කොම්බෝ 1952 සිට ඔවුන් දෙදෙනාට වයස අවුරුදු 3 සිට සමීප මිතුරන් වේ. ඔවුන් කොළඹ රාජකීය විද්‍යාලයේ 1 වැනි කාණ්ඩයේ “60 කණ්ඩායම” ලෙස හඳුන්වනු ලබන අයයි. එම කණ්ඩායමේම තවත් දේශපාලනඥයන් දෙදෙනකු වන්නේ දිවංගත අනුර බණ්ඩාරනායක සහ හිටපු අමාත්‍ය මලික් සමරවික්‍රම ය.",
        "අගමැතිනි සිරිමා බණ්ඩාරනායක මහත්මියගේ පුතු අනුරගේ පන්තියේ මිතුරෙකු වූ ජයන්ත ජයසිංහ ඇයගේ PSO, පුද්ගලික ආරක්ෂක නිලධාරියා ලෙස කටයුතු කළාය.",
        "එහෙත් 60 කණ්ඩායමේ ගෞරවනීයම පුද්ගලයා විය හැක්කේ තමන් අත්අඩංගුවේ සිටි ජවිපෙ සැකකරුවන්ට පහර දෙන ලෙස එවකට ආරක්ෂක රාජ්‍ය අමාත්‍ය රන්ජන් විජේරත්නගෙන් කළ අණ ප්‍රතික්ෂේප කර හමුදාවෙන් ඉවත් වූ බ්‍රිගේඩියර් විපුල් බොතේජු විය හැකිය. නීතිවිරෝධී නියෝග ක්‍රියාත්මක නොකරන බව විජේරත්නට මුද්‍රණය කළ නොහැකි භාෂාවෙන් පැහැදිලි කිරීමෙන් පසු විපුල් දකුණේ ගැඹුරු අණදෙන නිලධාරි තනතුරෙන් ඉවත් විය."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "ආනන්ද",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "දිනේෂ් ගුණවර්ධන",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ආනන්ද විද්‍යාලය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "එක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂගේ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ආනන්දියන්",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "දෙක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "රාජකීය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "රාජකීයයන්",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Maria Kade",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගෝඨාභය",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "භාණ්ඩාගාර",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "සජිත් ආටිගල",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ගෝඨාභය",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගෝඨාභය",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "දස දහස් ගණනක්",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජූලි 9",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ආනන්දියන් වට්ස්ඇප්",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ඩලස් අලහප්පෙරුම",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ආනන්ද",
            "label": "PRODUCT"
          },
          {
            "text": "රාජකීය රනිල්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජූලි 19",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ආනන්ද OBA",
            "label": "PRODUCT"
          },
          {
            "text": "රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "චැංගි පර්යන්තය 3",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "සිංගප්පූරුව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජූලි 14",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "සෞදි බෝයිං",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලාංකිකයන්",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ඊට අඩුවෙන්",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "පැය 24",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගෝඨාභය",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "32-මාස",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "යැංකි",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගාලු මුවදොර",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "එක්සත් ජනපදය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "EU",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "එ.ජා",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මානව හිමිකම් කවුන්සිලය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "දකුණු ආසියානු",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "එක්සත් ජනපදය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජූලි චුන්ග්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ගෝඨාභය",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ස්විස්",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "1952",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "වයස අවුරුදු 3 යි",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "\"60 කණ්ඩායම",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "කොළඹ රාජකීය විද්‍යාලය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "දෙක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "අනුර බණ්ඩාරනායක",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "මලික් සමරවික්‍රම",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "සිරිමා බණ්ඩාරනායක",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "අනුර",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජයන්ත ජයසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "PSO",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "60",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "විපුල් බොතේජු",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "රන්ජන් විජේරත්න",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජ.වි.පෙ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "විජේරත්න ය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "இலங்கையின் கெளரவப் போர்: ஆனந்தா பழியின் தடியடியை கடந்து செல்கிறார்",
      "author": "நாமல் சுவேந்திரா",
      "body_lines": [
        "பொருளாதாரம் - ஜனாதிபதி ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க மற்றும் பள்ளி கால நண்பர் தினேஷ் குணவர்தன ஆகியோர் ஆட்சிக்கு வந்ததை, தீவின் உயர்மட்ட பொதுப் பள்ளிகளில் ஒன்றான ஆனந்தா கல்லூரியின் புகழ்பெற்ற பழைய மாணவர்களால் ஆரவாரம் செய்து, பரவலாக கொண்டாடப்பட்டது.",
        "பழைய சிறுவன் கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்சவின் திறமையான பொருளாதார நிர்வாகத்தின் மீது பொதுமக்களின் அதிருப்திக்கு ஆளாகியிருந்த நிலையில், தற்போது றோயலின் பழைய மாணவர்கள் இருவருக்கு இந்த கௌரவம் கிடைத்தபோது, ​​வயதான ஆனந்திகள் மகிழ்ச்சியடைந்தனர்.",
        "\"ஆனந்தியர்களால் அனுப்பப்பட்ட அரசகுடியினருக்கு பகிரங்க அவமானங்களைப் பெறுவதற்கான வாய்ப்பை நாங்கள் இதன் மூலம் வழங்கியுள்ளோம்,\" என கொழும்பு 10 (மரியா காடே) பாடசாலையின் முன்னாள் மாணவர்கள் மத்தியில் பரவலாக பகிரப்பட்ட ஒரு இடுகையை வாசிக்கவும், அதில் கோட்டாபய மற்றும் அவமானப்படுத்தப்பட்ட திறைசேரி செயலாளர் சஜித் ஆட்டிகல ஆகியோர் கலந்து கொண்டனர்.",
        "ஜூலை 9 அன்று பல்லாயிரக்கணக்கானோர் அவரது அரண்மனையைக் கைப்பற்றியபோது கோத்தபய பின்கதவு வழியாக தப்பி ஓடியபோது, ​​கோட்டாபயவிற்காக ஆனந்திகள்” என்ற முகநூல் பக்கம் அதன் பெயரை “தேசத்திற்கான ஆனந்தியன்” என்று மாற்றியது. பழைய ஆனந்தியன் வாட்ஸ்அப் குழுவின் செய்தித் தொடர்பாளர் ஒருவர் கூறினார். ஸ்மார்ட் போன்கள் கடுமையாக குறைந்துவிட்டன மற்றும் உறுப்பினர்கள் ஏற்கனவே தங்கள் இணைய டேட்டா பில்களில் கணிசமான சேமிப்பைக் கண்டனர்.",
        "ஜூலை 19 அன்று நடைபெற்ற நாடாளுமன்றத் தேர்தலில், ஆனந்த பழைய மாணவரான டலஸ் அழகப்பெரும, பழைய அரச தலைவர் ரணிலிடம் தோல்வியடைந்ததால், அவர்களும் நிம்மதியடைந்தனர். \"தோல்வி அடைய இது ஒரு நல்ல போராக இருந்தது,\" என்று ஆனந்த ஓபிஏவின் மூத்த பேச்சாளர் ஒருவர் கூறினார். அவர் தனது வகுப்பில் ஒரு ராஜபக்சேவை நினைவுபடுத்த முடியாது.",
        "சவுதியா போயிங் 787 ட்ரீம்லைனர் கப்பலில் ராஜபக்சே சிங்கப்பூர் வந்தபோது, ​​பல இலங்கையர்களின் கனவுக்கு முடிவுகட்ட ராஜபக்ஷ ஜூலை 14 அன்று சாங்கி டெர்மினல் 3 இல் பழைய சிறுவர்கள் அணிந்த மெரூன் மற்றும் தங்க டை இல்லை என்பது நம்பத்தகுந்த தகவல்.",
        "வேலையில் இருந்த 24 மணி நேரத்திற்குள், விக்ரமசிங்க தனது 32 மாத ஜனாதிபதி பதவியில் கோட்டாபயவை விட அதிக சர்வதேச ஈர்ப்பைப் பெற்றார். மனித உரிமைகள் பேரவையில் அமெரிக்கா, ஐரோப்பிய ஒன்றியம், ஐநா மற்றும் இலங்கை தொடர்பான முக்கிய குழுவும் தெற்காசிய நாடு தொடர்பாக அறிக்கைகளை வெளியிட்டன.",
        "அமெரிக்க தூதர் ஜூலி சுங், \"குடிமக்கள் மீது நடவடிக்கை எடுப்பதற்கான நேரம் இதுவல்ல, மாறாக மக்களின் நம்பிக்கையை மீட்டெடுக்கவும், ஸ்திரத்தன்மையை மீட்டெடுக்கவும், மீண்டும் கட்டியெழுப்பவும் அரசாங்கம் எடுக்கக்கூடிய உடனடி மற்றும் உறுதியான நடவடிக்கைகளை எதிர்நோக்க வேண்டும். பொருளாதாரம்.\"",
        "வெளிநாட்டு அரசாங்கங்களிடமிருந்து இதேபோன்ற தகவல்களைப் பெறுவதற்கு கோட்டாபயவுக்கு ஒரு முழு வாரம் தேவைப்பட்டது என்பது குறிப்பிடத்தக்க சாதனையாகும். அது சுவிஸ் தூதரக உள்ளூர் ஊழியர் கடத்தப்பட்டதை அடுத்து.",
        "ரணில்-தினேஷ் கூட்டணி 1952 ஆம் ஆண்டு முதல் அவர்கள் இருவரும் 3 வயதில் நெருங்கிய நண்பர்கள். அவர்கள் கொழும்பு ரோயல் கல்லூரியின் படிவம் 1 குழுவான \"60 பேர் கொண்ட குழு\" என்று அழைக்கப்படுபவர்கள். இதே தொகுதியைச் சேர்ந்த மேலும் இரு அரசியல்வாதிகள் மறைந்த அனுர பண்டாரநாயக்க மற்றும் முன்னாள் அமைச்சர் மலிக் சமரவிக்ரம ஆகியோர் ஆவர்.",
        "பிரதமர் சிறிமா பண்டாரநாயக்க தனது மகன் அனுரவின் வகுப்புத் தோழரான ஜயந்த ஜயசிங்கவை தனது PSO, தனிப்பட்ட பாதுகாப்பு அதிகாரியாகக் கொண்டிருந்தார்.",
        "ஆனால், 60 பேர் கொண்ட குழுவில் மிகவும் கெளரவமானவர் பிரிகேடியர் விபுல் பொதேஜு, அவர் காவலில் உள்ள ஜே.வி.பி சந்தேக நபர்களை முறியடிக்க அப்போதைய பாதுகாப்பு இராஜாங்க அமைச்சர் ரஞ்சன் விஜேரத்னவின் உத்தரவை ஏற்க மறுத்து இராணுவத்திலிருந்து விலகினார். சட்ட விரோதமான உத்தரவுகளை நிறைவேற்ற மாட்டோம் என அச்சிட முடியாத மொழியில் விஜேரத்னவிடம் விளக்கியதையடுத்து, ஆழமான தெற்கில் கட்டளை அதிகாரியாக இருந்த விபுல் தனது பதவியை ராஜினாமா செய்தார்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "இலங்கை",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "ஆனந்த",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "தினேஷ் குணவர்தன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆனந்தா கல்லூரி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஒன்று",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்சவின்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆனந்தியர்கள்",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "இரண்டு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ராயல்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ராயல்ஸ்டுகள்",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Maria Kade",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "கோட்டாபய",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "கருவூலம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "சஜித் ஆட்டிகல",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "கோட்டாபய",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "கோட்டாபய",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "பல்லாயிரக்கணக்கானவர்கள்",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜூலை 9",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆனந்தியன் வாட்ஸ் அப்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "டலஸ் அழகப்பெரும",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆனந்த",
            "label": "PRODUCT"
          },
          {
            "text": "அரச தலைவர் ரணில்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜூலை 19",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆனந்த ஓபிஏ",
            "label": "PRODUCT"
          },
          {
            "text": "ராஜபக்சே",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "சாங்கி டெர்மினல் 3",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "ராஜபக்சே",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சிங்கப்பூர்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜூலை 14",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சவுதியா போயிங்",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கையர்கள்",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "குறைவாக",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "24 மணி நேரம்",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "கோட்டாபய",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "32-மாதம்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "யாங்கி",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "காலி முகம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "எங்களுக்கு",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "EU",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஐ.நா",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "மனித உரிமைகள் பேரவை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "தெற்காசிய",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "எங்களுக்கு",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜூலி சுங்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "கோட்டாபய",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "சுவிஸ்",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "1952",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "3 வயது",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "\"60 பேர் கொண்ட குழு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "கொழும்பு ரோயல் கல்லூரி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இரண்டு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "அனுர பண்டாரநாயக்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "மலிக் சமரவிக்ரம",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "சிறிமா பண்டாரநாயக்கா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "அனுர",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜயந்த ஜயசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "PSO",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "60",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "விபுல் பொடேஜு",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரஞ்சன் விஜேரத்ன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜே.வி.பி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "விஜேரத்ன",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}