{
  "newspaper_id": "lankadeepa-lk",
  "url": "https://www.lankadeepa.lk/news/ආර්ථික-අර්බුදයට-කතානායකවරයාත්-වගකිව-යුතුයි/101-618139",
  "time_ut": 1660555644,
  "original_lang": "si",
  "original_title": "ආර්ථික අර්බුදයට කතානායකවරයාත් වගකිව යුතුයි",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "The Speaker is also responsible for the economic crisis",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "The Chief Organizer of the Opposition, Member of Parliament Mr. Lakshman Kiriella said in Colombo today (15) that the speaker and the leader of the house who suspended the standing orders and gave the chairmanship of the finance committee to the government are complicit in the destruction that has befallen the country.",
        "Mr. Kiriella mentioned that after the general election of 2020, according to the standing orders, the chairmanship of the finance committee should be given to the opposition, but by violating the standing orders and giving the chairmanship of the committee to the government, Mr. Kiriella mentioned that the country has become so old.",
        "He said this while attending a press conference called at the office of the opposition leader in Colombo that if the position of chairman of the Finance Committee was given to the Member of Parliament, Dr. Harsha De Silva, the people would have known the real facts about the economic crisis the country was facing two years ago.",
        "The MP also mentioned that he would have gone to the International Monetary Fund and taken many important decisions regarding the country.",
        "He further said that today the people have to enjoy the consequences of arbitrary government actions by misleading the people by saying that the government has enough money."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Opposition",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Lakshman Kiriella",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Colombo",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "15",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Kiriella",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "2020",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kiriella",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Colombo",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Finance Committee",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Harsha De Silva",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "two years ago",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the International Monetary Fund",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "ආර්ථික අර්බුදයට කතානායකවරයාත් වගකිව යුතුයි",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "මහමැතිවරණයෙන් පසු ස්ථාවර නියෝග අත්හිටුවා මුදල් කමිටුවේ සභාපති ධුරය ආණ්ඩුවට ලබාදීමට කටයුතු කළ කතානායකවරයා සහ සභානායකවරයා රටට සිදුවූ විනාශයේ හවුල්කරුවන් බව විපක්ෂයේ ප්‍රධාන සංවිධායක පාර්ලිමේන්තු මන්ත්‍රී ලක්ෂ්මන් කිරිඇල්ල මහතා කොළඹ දී අද (15)පැවසීය.",
        "2020 වසරේ මහ මැතිවරණයෙන් පසු ස්ථාවර නියෝග අනුව මුදල් කමිටුවේ සභාපති ධුරය විපක්ෂ සඳහා ලබා දිය යුතු වුවත් ස්ථාවර නියෝග කඩ කරමින් එම කමිටුවේ සභාපති ධුරය ආණ්ඩුව ට ලබා දීමෙන් රට මෙතරම් වයසනයකට පත්වීමට හේතු වූ බවත් කිරිඇල්ල මහතා සඳහන් කළේය.",
        "එවක මුදල් කමිටුවේ සභාපති ධුරය පාර්ලිමේන්තු මන්ත්‍රී ආචාර්ය හර්ෂ ද සිල්වා මහතාට ලබා දුන්නේ නම් රට පත්ව ඇති ආර්ථික අර්බුදය පිළිබඳ සැබෑ තතු ජනතාවට මීට වසර දෙකකට පෙර දැන ගැනීමට ඉඩ තිබූ බවත් කොළඹ විපක්ෂනායක කාර්යාලයේ කැඳවූ මාධ්‍ය හමුවකට එක්වෙමින් ඔහු මේ බව පැවසීය.",
        "එසේනම් කල් ඇතුව ජාත්‍යන්තර මූල්‍ය අරමුදලට ගොස් රට සම්බන්ධයෙන් වැදගත් තීන්දු තීරණ රැසක් ගැනීමට ඉඩ තිබූ බවත් මන්ත්‍රීවරයා සඳහන් කළේය.",
        "රජයට අවශ්‍ය තරම් මුදල් ඇති බව පවසමින් ජනතාව නොමග යවමින් අත්තනෝමතික ලෙස රජයේ කටයුතු කිරීමේ ප්‍රතිවිපාක අද ජනතාවට භුක්ති විඳීමට සිදුව ඇති බවත් හෙතෙම තවදුරටත් කීවේය."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "විපක්ෂ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ලක්ෂ්මන් කිරිඇල්ල",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "කොළඹ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "15",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "කිරිඇල්ල",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "2020",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "කිරිඇල්ල",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "කොළඹ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "මූල්ය කමිටුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "හර්ෂ ද සිල්වා",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "අවුරුදු දෙකකට පෙර",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ජාත්‍යන්තර මුල්‍ය අරමුදල",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "பொருளாதார நெருக்கடிக்கு சபாநாயகரும் பொறுப்பு",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "நிலையியற் கட்டளையை இடைநிறுத்தி, நிதிக்குழுவின் தலைவர் பதவியை அரசாங்கத்திற்கு வழங்கிய சபாநாயகரும், அவைத் தலைவருமே இதற்கு உடந்தையாக இருப்பதாக எதிர்க்கட்சியின் பிரதான அமைப்பாளரும், நாடாளுமன்ற உறுப்பினருமான திரு.லக்ஷ்மன் கிரியெல்ல இன்று (15) கொழும்பில் தெரிவித்தார். நாட்டிற்கு ஏற்பட்ட அழிவு.",
        "2020ஆம் ஆண்டு பொதுத் தேர்தலுக்குப் பின்னர் நிலையியற் கட்டளைகளின் பிரகாரம் நிதிக்குழுவின் தலைவர் பதவி எதிர்க்கட்சிக்கு வழங்கப்பட வேண்டும் எனவும், ஆனால் நிலையியற் கட்டளைகளை மீறி குழுவின் தலைவர் பதவியை அரசாங்கத்திற்கு வழங்குவதாகவும் திரு.கிரியெல்ல குறிப்பிட்டார். நாடு மிகவும் பழமையானதாகிவிட்டது என கிரியெல்ல குறிப்பிட்டுள்ளார்.",
        "நாடாளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர் கலாநிதி ஹர்ஷ டி சில்வாவுக்கு நிதிக்குழுவின் தலைவர் பதவி வழங்கப்படுமாயின் மக்கள் உண்மையான உண்மைகளை அறிந்திருப்பார்கள் என கொழும்பில் உள்ள எதிர்க்கட்சித் தலைவரின் அலுவலகத்தில் அழைக்கப்பட்ட ஊடகவியலாளர் சந்திப்பில் கலந்துகொண்டு கருத்து தெரிவிக்கையிலேயே அவர் மேற்கண்டவாறு தெரிவித்தார். இரண்டு வருடங்களுக்கு முன்னர் நாடு எதிர்கொண்ட பொருளாதார நெருக்கடி பற்றி.",
        "சர்வதேச நாணய நிதியத்திற்கு சென்று நாடு தொடர்பான பல முக்கிய தீர்மானங்களை எடுத்திருப்பார் எனவும் பாராளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர் குறிப்பிட்டுள்ளார்.",
        "அவர் மேலும் தெரிவிக்கையில், அரசாங்கத்திடம் பணம் போதுமானது என்று கூறி மக்களை ஏமாற்றி தன்னிச்சையான அரசாங்க நடவடிக்கைகளின் விளைவுகளை இன்று மக்கள் அனுபவிக்க வேண்டியுள்ளது."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "எதிர்ப்பு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "லக்ஷ்மன் கிரியெல்ல",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "கொழும்பு",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "15",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "கிரியெல்ல",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "2020",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "கிரியெல்ல",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "கொழும்பு",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "நிதிக் குழு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஹர்ஷ டி சில்வா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இரண்டு ஆண்டுகளுக்கு முன்பு",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "சர்வதேச நாணய நிதியம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}