{
  "newspaper_id": "news-first-lk",
  "url": "https://www.newsfirst.lk/2022/07/30/chinese-ambassador-assures-necessary-support-for-sl-imf-discussions/",
  "time_ut": 1659183540,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Chinese Ambassador assures necessary support for SL-IMF discussions",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Chinese Ambassador assures necessary support for SL-IMF discussions",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); China expects that Sri Lanka’s discussions with the International Monetary Fund will be successful, as China too is a member of the IMF, the Ambassador of China, Qi Zhenhong assured adding that the necessary support will be provided in the meeting of the IMF Board of Directors.",
        "The Ambassador stated this during a meeting between Prime Minister Dinesh Gunawardena and Chinese Ambassador to Sri Lanka Qi Zhenhong at the Prime Minister's Office yesterday (29).",
        "The Ambassador also officially handed over the congratulatory message sent by the Chinese Prime Minister Li Keqiang to the Prime Minister.",
        "During the meeting, the importance of strengthening the existing economic, agricultural and cultural relations between China and Sri Lanka in the face of the current economic crisis was emphasized.",
        "Appreciating the assistance provided by China to alleviate the current economic crisis in Sri Lanka, the Prime Minister said Sri Lanka would welcome direct private investments as well as investments in agriculture, renewable energy, irrigation and water supply sectors to provide long term solutions to economic issues.",
        "He also emphasized the importance of increasing Chinese tourism to Sri Lanka once again.",
        "Chinese investment opportunities related to industries and the agriculture sector in the Hambantota Economic Zone centered in the Southern Province were also discussed during the meeting."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Chinese",
          "label": "NORP"
        },
        {
          "text": "SL-IMF",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "News 1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "China",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka’s",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the International Monetary Fund",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "China",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "IMF",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "China",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Qi Zhenhong",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the IMF Board of Directors",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Dinesh Gunawardena",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Chinese",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "yesterday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "29",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Chinese",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Li Keqiang",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "China",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "China",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Chinese",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Chinese",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Hambantota Economic Zone",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Southern Province",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "ශ්‍රී ලංකා ජාත්‍යන්තර මූල්‍ය අරමුදලේ සාකච්ඡා සඳහා අවශ්‍ය සහය ලබාදෙන බවට චීන තානාපතිවරයා සහතික වෙයි",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); චීනය ද ජාත්‍යන්තර මූල්‍ය අරමුදලේ සාමාජිකයෙකු වන බැවින් ජාත්‍යන්තර මූල්‍ය අරමුදල සමඟ ශ්‍රී ලංකාව සිදුකරන සාකච්ඡා සාර්ථක වනු ඇතැයි චීනය අපේක්ෂා කරන බව චීන තානාපති Qi Zhenhong සහතික වූයේ ජාත්‍යන්තර මූල්‍ය අරමුදලේ අධ්‍යක්ෂ මණ්ඩල රැස්වීමේදී අවශ්‍ය සහයෝගය ලබා දෙන බවයි. .",
        "තානාපතිවරයා මේ බව ප්‍රකාශ කළේ අග්‍රාමාත්‍ය දිනේෂ් ගුණවර්ධන මහතා සහ ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ චීන තානාපති Qi Zhenhong මහතා අතර ඊයේ (29) අග්‍රාමාත්‍ය කාර්යාලයේදී පැවති හමුවකදීය.",
        "චීන අග්‍රාමාත්‍ය Li Keqiang මහතා විසින් එවන ලද සුබපැතුම් පණිවිඩය ද තානාපතිවරයා විසින් නිල වශයෙන් අග්‍රාමාත්‍යවරයා වෙත භාර දෙනු ලැබීය.",
        "පවතින ආර්ථික අර්බුදය හමුවේ චීනය සහ ශ්‍රී ලංකාව අතර පවතින ආර්ථික, කෘෂිකාර්මික සහ සංස්කෘතික සබඳතා ශක්තිමත් කර ගැනීමේ වැදගත්කම මෙම හමුවේදී අවධාරණය කෙරිණි.",
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ වත්මන් ආර්ථික අර්බුදය සමනය කිරීම සඳහා චීනය ලබා දෙන සහය අගය කළ අග්‍රාමාත්‍යවරයා, ආර්ථික ප්‍රශ්නවලට දීර්ඝ කාලීන විසඳුම් ලබාදීම සඳහා සෘජු පෞද්ගලික ආයෝජන මෙන්ම කෘෂිකර්මාන්තය, පුනර්ජනනීය බලශක්තිය, වාරිමාර්ග සහ ජල සම්පාදන ක්ෂේත්‍රවල ආයෝජන ශ්‍රී ලංකාව සාදරයෙන් පිළිගන්නා බව පැවසීය. .",
        "නැවත වරක් ශ්‍රී ලංකාවට චීන සංචාරක ව්‍යාපාරය වැඩි කිරීමේ වැදගත්කම ද ඔහු අවධාරණය කළේය.",
        "දකුණු පළාත කේන්ද්‍ර කර ගනිමින් හම්බන්තොට ආර්ථික කලාපයේ කර්මාන්ත හා කෘෂිකර්ම ක්ෂේත්‍රයට අදාළ චීන ආයෝජන අවස්ථා පිළිබඳව ද මෙහිදී සාකච්ඡා කෙරිණි."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "චීන",
          "label": "NORP"
        },
        {
          "text": "SL-IMF",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "News 1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "චීනය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජාත්‍යන්තර මුල්‍ය අරමුදල",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "චීනය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "IMF",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "චීනය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Qi Zhenhong",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "IMF අධ්‍යක්ෂ මණ්ඩලය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "දිනේෂ් ගුණවර්ධන",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "චීන",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඊයේ",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "29",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "චීන",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Li Keqiang",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "චීනය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "චීනය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "චීන",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "චීන",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "හම්බන්තොට ආර්ථික කලාපය",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "දකුණු පළාත",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "SL-IMF விவாதங்களுக்கு தேவையான ஆதரவை சீன தூதுவர் உறுதியளிக்கிறார்",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); சர்வதேச நாணய நிதியத்துடனான இலங்கையின் கலந்துரையாடல் வெற்றியடையும் என சீனா எதிர்பார்ப்பதாகவும், சீனாவும் சர்வதேச நாணய நிதியத்தில் அங்கம் வகிக்கும் நாடாக இருப்பதால், சர்வதேச நாணய நிதியத்தின் பணிப்பாளர் சபையின் கூட்டத்தில் தேவையான உதவிகள் வழங்கப்படும் என சீனத் தூதுவர் Qi Zhenhong உறுதியளித்துள்ளார். .",
        "பிரதமர் தினேஷ் குணவர்தனவுக்கும் இலங்கைக்கான சீனத் தூதுவர் Qi Zhenhong அவர்களுக்கும் இடையில் நேற்று (29) பிரதமர் அலுவலகத்தில் இடம்பெற்ற சந்திப்பின் போதே தூதுவர் இதனைத் தெரிவித்துள்ளார்.",
        "சீனப் பிரதமர் லீ கெகியாங் அனுப்பிய வாழ்த்துச் செய்தியையும் தூதுவர் உத்தியோகபூர்வமாக பிரதமரிடம் கையளித்தார்.",
        "இச்சந்திப்பின் போது, ​​தற்போதைய பொருளாதார நெருக்கடிக்கு முகங்கொடுக்கும் வகையில் சீனாவுக்கும் இலங்கைக்கும் இடையில் நிலவும் பொருளாதார, விவசாய மற்றும் கலாசார உறவுகளை வலுப்படுத்த வேண்டியதன் முக்கியத்துவம் குறித்து வலியுறுத்தப்பட்டது.",
        "இலங்கையின் தற்போதைய பொருளாதார நெருக்கடியைத் தணிக்க சீனா வழங்கிய உதவிகளைப் பாராட்டிய பிரதமர், பொருளாதாரப் பிரச்சினைகளுக்கு நீண்டகாலத் தீர்வுகளை வழங்குவதற்காக விவசாயம், புதுப்பிக்கத்தக்க எரிசக்தி, நீர்ப்பாசனம் மற்றும் நீர் வழங்கல் துறைகளில் நேரடி தனியார் முதலீடுகளையும், முதலீடுகளையும் இலங்கை வரவேற்கும் என்றார். .",
        "இலங்கைக்கான சீன சுற்றுலாவை மீண்டும் ஒருமுறை அதிகரிப்பதன் முக்கியத்துவத்தையும் அவர் வலியுறுத்தினார்.",
        "தென் மாகாணத்தை மையமாகக் கொண்ட ஹம்பாந்தோட்டை பொருளாதார வலயத்தில் கைத்தொழில்கள் மற்றும் விவசாயத் துறை தொடர்பான சீன முதலீட்டு வாய்ப்புகள் குறித்தும் இந்த சந்திப்பின் போது கலந்துரையாடப்பட்டது."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "சீன",
          "label": "NORP"
        },
        {
          "text": "SL-IMF",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "News 1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சீனா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கையின்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சர்வதேச நாணய நிதியம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "சீனா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "IMF",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "சீனா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Qi Zhenhong",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "IMF இயக்குநர்கள் குழு",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "தினேஷ் குணவர்தன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "சீன",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "நேற்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "29",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "சீன",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Li Keqiang",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "சீனா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "சீனா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "சீன",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "சீன",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஹம்பாந்தோட்டை பொருளாதார வலயம்",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "தென் மாகாணம்",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}