{
  "newspaper_id": "news-first-lk",
  "url": "https://www.newsfirst.lk/2022/08/14/pakistan-stands-with-sri-lanka-high-commissioner/",
  "time_ut": 1660481880,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Pakistan stands with Sri Lanka : High Commissioner",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Pakistan stands with Sri Lanka : High Commissioner",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); The Pakistani community in Sri Lanka celebrated The Diamond Jubilee of independence of Pakistan today (14).",
        "The event was held at the Pakistan High Commission in Colombo.",
        "Pakistan High Commissioner to Sri Lanka, Retired Maj. Gen Umar Farooq Burki hoisted the national flag of Pakistan in a vibrant ceremony at the Pakistan High Commission in Colombo.",
        "Maj. Gen (Retd) Umar Farooq Burki, the Pakistan High Commissioner to Sri Lanka welcomed the Pakistani vessel PNS Taimur which has been docked about two to three days.",
        "He emphasized that the foreign policy of Pakistan is based on the vision of their founding fathers.Which is friendship towards all and animosity towards none.",
        "\"We believe in whoever having social, cordial relations with all countries and especially with the countries in our neighbourhood,\" the High Commissioner stated.",
        "High Commissioner Maj. Gen (Retd) Umar Farooq Burki pointed out that both Pakistan and Sri Lanka are key members of SAARC and both countries strong bonds of friendship and brotherhood came into being.",
        "\"We have stood with our Sri Lankan brothers and sisters through thick and thin and so have they. and we will continue to do so in the future as well,\" he added.",
        "The event was attended by diplomats, members of the Pakistan community, local dignitarian and officers of PNS Taimur which is port calling Colombo these days.",
        "Will support from Opposition until Tamil people are satisfied: C.V. Wigneswaran"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Pakistan",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "Sri Lanka",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "News 1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Pakistani",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Pakistan",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "14",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the Pakistan High Commission",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Colombo",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Pakistan",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Pakistan",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Pakistan High Commission",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Colombo",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Umar Farooq Burki",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Pakistan",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Pakistani",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "PNS Taimur",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "about two to three days",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Pakistan",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "Umar Farooq Burki",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Pakistan",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lankan",
            "label": "LOC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Pakistan",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "dignitarian",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "PNS Taimur",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Colombo",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "these days",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "C.V. Wigneswaran",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "පකිස්ථානය ශ්‍රී ලංකාව සමගයි : මහ කොමසාරිස්",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ පාකිස්ථානු ප්‍රජාව අද (14) පාකිස්ථානයේ නිදහසේ දියමන්ති ජුබිලිය සමරනු ලැබුවා.",
        "මෙම උත්සවය කොළඹ පිහිටි පකිස්ථාන මහ කොමසාරිස් කාර්යාලයේදී පැවැත්විණි.",
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ පකිස්ථාන මහ කොමසාරිස් විශ්‍රාමික මේජර් ජෙනරාල් උමාර් ෆාරුක් බුර්කි විසින් පාකිස්ථානයේ ජාතික ධජය එසවීමේ උත්සවයක් පාකිස්ථානු මහ කොමසාරිස් කාර්යාලයේදී පැවැත්විණි.",
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ පකිස්ථාන මහ කොමසාරිස් මේජර් ජෙනරාල් (විශ්‍රාමික) උමාර් ෆාරුක් බුර්කි විසින් දින දෙක තුනක් පමණ නැංගුරම් ලා ඇති PNS Taimur පකිස්ථාන නෞකාව පිළිගනු ලැබීය.",
        "පාකිස්තානයේ විදේශ ප්‍රතිපත්තිය පදනම් වී ඇත්තේ ඔවුන්ගේ ආරම්භක පියවරුන්ගේ දැක්ම මත බව ඔහු අවධාරණය කළේය.එය සියල්ලන්ටම මිත්‍රත්වය සහ කිසිවෙකු කෙරෙහි වෛරයක් නොවන බව.",
        "“සියලු රටවල් සමඟ සහ විශේෂයෙන් අපගේ අසල්වැසි රටවල් සමඟ සමාජීය, සුහද සබඳතා පවත්වන ඕනෑම අයෙකු කෙරෙහි අපි විශ්වාස කරමු,” මහ කොමසාරිස්වරයා ප්‍රකාශ කළේය.",
        "මහ කොමසාරිස් මේජර් ජෙනරාල් (විශ්‍රාමික) උමාර් ෆාරුක් බුර්කි පෙන්වා දුන්නේ පාකිස්තානය සහ ශ්‍රී ලංකාව යන රටවල් දෙකම සාර්ක් සංවිධානයේ ප්‍රධාන සාමාජිකයන් වන අතර දෙරටේම මිත්‍රත්වයේ සහ සහෝදරත්වයේ ශක්තිමත් බැඳීම් ඇති වූ බවයි.",
        "\"අපි අපේ ශ්‍රී ලාංකීය සහෝදර සහෝදරියන් සමඟ ඝණ සහ කෙට්ටු හරහා සිට තිබෙනවා. ඔවුන් එසේ කරනවා. අනාගතයේදීත් අපි එය කරගෙන යනවා,\" ඔහු වැඩිදුරටත් පැවසීය.",
        "මෙම අවස්ථාවට රාජ්‍ය තාන්ත්‍රිකයින්, පකිස්ථාන ප්‍රජාවේ සාමාජිකයින්, ප්‍රාදේශීය සම්භාවනීය අමුත්තන් සහ මේ දිනවල කොළඹ වරාය ලෙස හඳුන්වන PNS Taimur හි නිලධාරීන් සහභාගී විය.",
        "දෙමළ ජනතාව තෘප්තිමත් වන තුරු විපක්ෂයේ සහය දෙනවා: සී.වී. විග්නේෂ්වරන්"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "පකිස්ථානය",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "News 1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "පකිස්ථානු",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "පකිස්ථානය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "14",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "පකිස්ථාන මහ කොමසාරිස් කාර්යාලය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "කොළඹ",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "පකිස්ථානය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "පකිස්ථානය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "පකිස්ථාන මහ කොමසාරිස් කාර්යාලය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "කොළඹ",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "උමාර් ෆාරුක් බුර්කි",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "පකිස්ථානය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "පකිස්ථානු",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "පීඑන්එස් තයිමූර්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "දින දෙක තුනක් පමණ",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "පකිස්ථානය",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "උමාර් ෆාරුක් බුර්කි",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "පකිස්ථානය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලාංකික",
            "label": "LOC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "පකිස්ථානය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "සම්භාවනීය",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "පීඑන්එස් තයිමූර්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "කොළඹ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "මෙම දිනවල",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "CV. විග්නේෂ්වරන්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "பாகிஸ்தான் இலங்கையுடன் நிற்கிறது: உயர்ஸ்தானிகர்",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); பாகிஸ்தானின் சுதந்திர வைரவிழாவை இலங்கையில் உள்ள பாகிஸ்தான் சமூகத்தினர் இன்று (14) கொண்டாடினர்.",
        "கொழும்பில் உள்ள பாகிஸ்தான் உயர்ஸ்தானிகராலயத்தில் இந்த நிகழ்வு இடம்பெற்றது.",
        "இலங்கைக்கான பாகிஸ்தான் உயர்ஸ்தானிகர் ஓய்வுபெற்ற மேஜர் ஜெனரல் உமர் ஃபாரூக் புர்கி, கொழும்பில் உள்ள பாகிஸ்தான் உயர்ஸ்தானிகராலயத்தில் நடைபெற்ற அதிரவைக்கும் நிகழ்வில் பாகிஸ்தானின் தேசியக் கொடியை ஏற்றி வைத்தார்.",
        "இலங்கைக்கான பாகிஸ்தான் உயர்ஸ்தானிகர் மேஜர் ஜெனரல் (ஓய்வு) உமர் ஃபாரூக் புர்கி, இரண்டு மூன்று நாட்களாக நிறுத்தி வைக்கப்பட்டுள்ள PNS தைமூர் என்ற பாகிஸ்தான் கப்பலை வரவேற்றார்.",
        "பாகிஸ்தானின் வெளியுறவுக் கொள்கையானது அவர்களின் ஸ்தாபக தந்தைகளின் தொலைநோக்குப் பார்வையை அடிப்படையாகக் கொண்டது என்று அவர் வலியுறுத்தினார்.",
        "\"எல்லா நாடுகளுடனும், குறிப்பாக நமது அண்டை நாடுகளில் உள்ள நாடுகளுடனும் சமூக, சுமூகமான உறவுகளை வைத்திருப்பவர்கள் மீது நாங்கள் நம்பிக்கை கொண்டுள்ளோம்\" என்று உயர்ஸ்தானிகர் கூறினார்.",
        "உயர் ஸ்தானிகர் மேஜர் ஜெனரல் (ஓய்வு) உமர் ஃபரூக் புர்கி, பாகிஸ்தான் மற்றும் இலங்கை ஆகிய இரண்டும் சார்க் அமைப்பின் முக்கிய அங்கத்தினர்கள் என்றும், இரு நாடுகளும் நட்பு மற்றும் சகோதரத்துவத்தின் வலுவான பிணைப்புகள் உருவாகியுள்ளன என்றும் சுட்டிக்காட்டினார்.",
        "\"நாங்கள் எங்கள் இலங்கை சகோதர சகோதரிகளுடன் தடிமனாகவும் மெலிந்தவர்களாகவும் இருந்தோம், அவர்களும் இருக்கிறார்கள். எதிர்காலத்திலும் நாங்கள் அதைத் தொடருவோம்,\" என்று அவர் மேலும் கூறினார்.",
        "இந்நிகழ்வில் இராஜதந்திரிகள், பாகிஸ்தான் சமூகத்தைச் சேர்ந்தவர்கள், உள்ளூர் உயரதிகாரிகள் மற்றும் கொழும்பு துறைமுகத்தை அழைக்கும் PNS தைமூர் அதிகாரிகள் ஆகியோர் கலந்துகொண்டனர்.",
        "தமிழ் மக்கள் திருப்தி அடையும் வரை எதிர்க்கட்சிகளின் ஆதரவு: சி.வி. விக்னேஸ்வரன்"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "பாகிஸ்தான்",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "இலங்கை",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "News 1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாகிஸ்தானியர்",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாகிஸ்தான்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "14",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பாகிஸ்தான் உயர் ஸ்தானிகராலயம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "கொழும்பு",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பாகிஸ்தான்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாகிஸ்தான்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாகிஸ்தான் உயர் ஸ்தானிகராலயம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "கொழும்பு",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "உமர் பாரூக் புர்கி",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாகிஸ்தான்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாகிஸ்தானியர்",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "பிஎன்எஸ் தைமூர்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "சுமார் இரண்டு மூன்று நாட்கள்",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பாகிஸ்தான்",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "உமர் பாரூக் புர்கி",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாகிஸ்தான்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "LOC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பாகிஸ்தான்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "கௌரவர்",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "பிஎன்எஸ் தைமூர்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "கொழும்பு",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்த நாட்களில்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "சுயவிவரம். விக்னேஸ்வரன்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}