{
  "newspaper_id": "virakesari-lk",
  "url": "http://www.virakesari.lk/article/132613",
  "time_ut": 1659284015,
  "original_lang": "ta",
  "original_title": "யாழ். குருநகரிலுள்ள கத்தோலிக்க ஆலயத்தில் மின்னல் தாக்கம்",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Jaffna. Catholic Church in Gurunagar struck by lightning",
      "author": "Vishnu",
      "body_lines": [
        "While the Sunday Mass was being held at the Catholic Church in Gurunagar, Jaffna, there was a brief commotion due to a lightning strike.",
        "According to local residents, the incident took place at Gurunagar's St. Arogyanatha Temple at around 6.30 am on Sunday morning.",
        "The accident took place in several parts of Jaffna in the morning when rain accompanied by thunder and lightning was reported.",
        "Due to the lightning strike in the temple, roof parts and electrical connections were slightly damaged. However, the public reports that no one was harmed."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Jaffna",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "Catholic Church",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "Gurunagar",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Sunday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Catholic Church",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Gurunagar",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Jaffna",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Gurunagar's",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "6.30 am",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sunday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "morning",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Jaffna",
            "label": "FAC"
          }
        ],
        []
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "යාපනය. ගුරුනගර්හි කතෝලික පල්ලියට අකුණු සැර වැදී ඇත",
      "author": "විෂ්ණු",
      "body_lines": [
        "යාපනයේ ගුරුනගර් ප්‍රදේශයේ පිහිටි කතෝලික දේවස්ථානයේ ඉරිදා දිව්‍ය පූජාව පැවැත්වෙන අතරතුර අකුණු සැර වැදීමක් හේතුවෙන් සුළු නොසන්සුන්තාවක් ඇති විය.",
        "ප්‍රදේශවාසීන් පවසන පරිදි ඉරිදා උදෑසන 6.30 ට පමණ ගුරුනගර්හි ශාන්ත ආරෝග්‍යනාථ විහාරස්ථානයේ දී මෙම සිදුවීම සිදුව ඇත.",
        "ගිගුරුම් සහිත අකුණු සමඟ වර්ෂාව ඇද හැලෙන විට යාපනයේ ප්‍රදේශ කිහිපයකට අලුයම මෙම අනතුර සිදුව තිබේ.",
        "අකුණු සැර වැදීමෙන් විහාරස්ථානයේ වහල කොටස්වලට සහ විදුලි සම්බන්ධතාවලට සුළු හානි සිදුවී ඇත. කෙසේ වෙතත් කිසිවෙකුටත් හානියක් සිදුවී නොමැති බවයි මහජනතාව පවසන්නේ."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "යාපනය",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "කතෝලික පල්ලිය",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "ගුරුනගර්",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ඉරිදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "කතෝලික පල්ලිය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගුරුනගර්",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "යාපනය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ගුරුනගර්ගේ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "6.30 පෙ.ව",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉරිදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "උදෑසන",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "යාපනය",
            "label": "FAC"
          }
        ],
        []
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "யாழ். குருநகரிலுள்ள கத்தோலிக்க ஆலயத்தில் மின்னல் தாக்கம்",
      "author": "Vishnu",
      "body_lines": [
        "யாழ்ப்பாணம் குருநகரிலுள்ள கத்தோலிக்க ஆலயத்தில் ஞாயிறு திருப்பலி இடம்பெற்றுக் கொண்டிருந்த போது,  மின்னல் தாக்கியதால் சிறிது நேரம் பரபரப்பு ஏற்பட்டது.",
        "குருநகர், புனித ஆரோக்கியநாதர் ஆலயத்தில் ஞாயிற்று காலை 6.30 மணியளவில் திருப்பலி இடம்பெற்றபோதே இந்த சம்பவம் நடந்ததாக அப்பகுதி பொதுமக்கள் தெரிவிக்கின்றனர்.",
        "காலை யாழ்ப்பாணத்தின் பல பகுதிகளில் இடி மின்னலுடன் மழை வீழ்ச்சி பதிவான நிலையில் இந்த அனர்த்தம் இடம்பெற்றது.",
        "ஆலயத்தில் நடந்த மின்னல் தாக்கத்தால் மேற்கூரைப் பகுதிகளும், மின் இணைப்புக்களும் சிறிது சேதமடைந்தன. எனினும், யாருக்கும் பாதிப்பு ஏற்படவில்லை என பொதுமக்கள் தெரிவிக்கின்றனர்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "யாழ்",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "கத்தோலிக்க திருச்சபை",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "குருநகர்",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ஞாயிற்றுக்கிழமை",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "கத்தோலிக்க திருச்சபை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "குருநகர்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "யாழ்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "குருநகரின்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "காலை 6.30 மணி",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஞாயிற்றுக்கிழமை",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "காலை",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "யாழ்",
            "label": "FAC"
          }
        ],
        []
      ]
    }
  }
}