{
  "newspaper_id": "island-lk",
  "url": "http://island.lk/cse-driven-by-expectations-of-debt-restructuring-with-china/",
  "time_ut": 1659028020,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "CSE driven by expectations of debt restructuring with China",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "CSE driven by expectations of debt restructuring with China",
      "author": "Sahan Weerasooriya",
      "body_lines": [
        "Trading activities at the CSE was positive yesterday after the announcement of President Ranil Wickremesinghe’s visit to China soon. One of the main reasons for his visit  was that  The International Monetary Fund (IMF) has said that Sri Lanka should kick off debt restructuring talks with its bilateral lender China, while the  government seeks a financing loan from the Washington-based fund, market analysts said.",
        "“China is a big creditor, and Sri Lanka has to engage proactively with it on a debt restructuring,” Krishna Srinivasan, director of the IMF’s Asia and Pacific Department, told the International Media recently.",
        "Amid these developments, the main All Share Price Index rose by 52.9 points and the most liquid index moved up  31.0 points. Turnover stood at Rs one billion without a single crossing. In the retail market top seven companies that mainly contributed to the turnover were Lanka IOC Rs 140 million (1.7 million shares traded), Expolanka Holdings Rs 113 million (655,000 shares traded), TJ Lanka Rs 63 million (1.4 million shares traded), Kotagala Plantations Rs 55.7 million (9.1 million shares traded), Browns Investments Rs 52.8 million (7.3 million shares traded), Balangoda Plantations  Rs 49.3 million (943,000 shares traded) and Printcare Rs 34.8 million (1.2 million shares traded), During the day 56 million share volume changed hands in 16000 share transactions.",
        "According to the stock brokers, there was considerable participation in plantation sector counters. The reason being that the rupee depreciation has benefited especially tea exporters despite a yield drop in the sector due to fertilizer issues in the country. Further, in the month of July upto now net foreing inflows have touched Rs 754 million. On the previous day  itself  foreing outflows were reported at Rs 283 million.",
        "People’s Bank organises blood donation camp to mark 61st Anniversary",
        "SLT-Mobitel to offer its underutilised properties to corporate sector on long term lease",
        "Leave a Reply Cancel replyYour email address will not be published. Required fields are marked *Comment Name *",
        "Save my name, email, and website in this browser for the next time I comment."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "CSE",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "China",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "CSE",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "yesterday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "China",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "One",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "The International Monetary Fund",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "China",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Washington",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "China",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Krishna Srinivasan",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "IMF’s",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "Asia",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "Pacific Department",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the International Media",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "52.9",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "31.0",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "seven",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Lanka IOC Rs 140 million",
            "label": "PRODUCT"
          },
          {
            "text": "1.7 million",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "113 million",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "655,000",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Rs 63 million",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "1.4 million",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kotagala Plantations Rs",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "55.7 million",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "9.1 million",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Browns Investments",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "52.8 million",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "7.3 million",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Balangoda Plantations",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "49.3 million",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "943,000",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "34.8 million",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "1.2 million",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "56 million",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "16000",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the month of July",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "754 million",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "the previous day",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "283 million",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "People’s Bank",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "61st",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "SLT-Mobitel",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [],
        []
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "CSE මෙහෙයවනු ලබන්නේ චීනය සමඟ ණය ප්‍රතිව්‍යුහගත කිරීමේ අපේක්ෂාවෙනි",
      "author": "සහන් වීරසූරිය",
      "body_lines": [
        "ජනාධිපති රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතාගේ චීන සංචාරය නුදුරේදීම ප්‍රකාශයට පත් කිරීමෙන් පසු කොළඹ කොටස් වෙළෙඳපොළේ වෙළෙඳ කටයුතු ඊයේ ධනාත්මක විය. ඔහුගේ සංචාරයට එක් ප්‍රධාන හේතුවක් වූයේ  ජාත්‍යන්තර මූල්‍ය අරමුදල (IMF) ශ්‍රී ලංකාව සිය ද්විපාර්ශ්වික ණය දෙන්නා වන චීනය සමඟ ණය ප්‍රතිව්‍යුහගත කිරීමේ සාකච්ඡා ආරම්භ කළ යුතු බව ප්‍රකාශ කර ඇති අතර  රජය වොෂින්ටනය පදනම් කරගත් අරමුදලෙන් මූල්‍ය ණයක් අපේක්ෂා කරන අතර වෙළඳපල විශ්ලේෂකයින් කිව්වා.",
        "\"චීනය විශාල ණයහිමියෙකු වන අතර, ශ්‍රී ලංකාව ණය ප්‍රතිව්‍යුහගත කිරීම සඳහා ක්‍රියාශීලීව සම්බන්ධ විය යුතුය,\" IMF හි ආසියා සහ පැසිෆික් දෙපාර්තමේන්තුවේ අධ්‍යක්ෂ ක්‍රිෂ්ණා ශ්‍රීනිවාසන් මෑතකදී ජාත්‍යන්තර මාධ්‍ය වෙත පැවසීය.",
        "මෙම වර්ධනයන් මධ්‍යයේ ප්‍රධාන සියලු කොටස් මිල දර්ශකය ඒකක 52.9කින් ඉහළ ගිය අතර වඩාත්ම ද්‍රවශීල දර්ශකය ඒකක 31.0කින් ඉහළ ගියේය. එක හරස් මාර්ගයක් නොමැතිව පිරිවැටුම රුපියල් බිලියනයක් විය. සිල්ලර වෙළඳපොලේ පිරිවැටුම සඳහා ප්‍රධාන වශයෙන් දායක වූ සමාගම් හත වන්නේ Lanka IOC රුපියල් මිලියන 140 (කොටස් මිලියන 1.7 ක්), එක්ස්පෝලංකා හෝල්ඩිංග්ස් රුපියල් මිලියන 113 (කොටස් 655,000 ක් ගනුදෙනු), TJ Lanka රුපියල් මිලියන 63 (කොටස් මිලියන 1.4 ක් ගනුදෙනු), කොටගල. වැවිලි රුපියල් මිලියන 55.7 (කොටස් මිලියන 9.1ක් ගනුදෙනු), Browns Investments රුපියල් මිලියන 52.8 (කොටස් මිලියන 7.3ක් ගනුදෙනු), බළන්ගොඩ වැවිලි  රුපියල් මිලියන 49.3 (කොටස් 943,000ක් ගනුදෙනු) සහ Printcare රුපියල් මිලියන 34.8 (කොටස් මිලියන 1.2ක් ගනුදෙනු), දින තුළ කොටස් ගනුදෙනු 16000 කදී කොටස් පරිමාව වෙනස් විය.",
        "කොටස් තැරැව්කරුවන්ට අනුව, වතුකරයේ කවුන්ටරවල සැලකිය යුතු සහභාගීත්වයක් තිබුණි. රටේ පොහොර ප්‍රශ්නය හේතුවෙන් තේ ක්ෂේත්‍රයේ අස්වැන්න අඩු වුවද රුපියල අවප්‍රමාණය වීම විශේෂයෙන් තේ අපනයනකරුවන්ට වාසිදායක වී තිබීම ඊට හේතුවයි. තවද, ජූලි මාසය තුළ මේ දක්වා ශුද්ධ ඉදිරි ගලා ඒම රුපියල් මිලියන 754 දක්වා ළඟා වී තිබේ. පෙර දිනයේදීම  ඉදිරි පිටවීම් රුපියල් මිලියන 283ක් ලෙස වාර්තා විය.",
        "මහජන බැංකුව 61 වැනි සංවත්සරය වෙනුවෙන් ලේ දන්දීමේ කඳවුරක් සංවිධානය කරයි",
        "SLT-Mobitel විසින් සිය ඌන උපයෝගි කරගත් දේපළ දිගුකාලීන බදු පදනම මත ආයතනික අංශයට පිරිනැමීමට නියමිතය",
        "පිළිතුරක් දෙන්න පිළිතුර අවලංගු කරන්න ඔබගේ විද්‍යුත් තැපැල් ලිපිනය ප්‍රකාශයට පත් නොකෙරේ. අවශ්‍ය ක්ෂේත්‍ර සලකුණු කර ඇත *අදහස් නම *",
        "මම ඊළඟ වතාවේ අදහස් දැක්වීම සඳහා මගේ නම, විද්‍යුත් තැපෑල සහ වෙබ් අඩවිය මෙම බ්‍රවුසරයේ සුරකින්න."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "CSE",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "චීනය",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "CSE",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඊයේ",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "චීනය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "එක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජාත්‍යන්තර මුල්‍ය අරමුදල",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "චීනය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "වොෂින්ටනය",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "චීනය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ක්‍රිෂ්ණ ශ්‍රීනිවාසන්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "IMF හි",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "ආසියාව",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "පැසිෆික් දෙපාර්තමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජාත්‍යන්තර මාධ්‍ය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "52.9",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "31.0",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "හත",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ලංකා IOC රුපියල් මිලියන 140 යි",
            "label": "PRODUCT"
          },
          {
            "text": "මිලියන 1.7 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "මිලියන 113 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "655,000 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "රුපියල් මිලියන 63 කි",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "මිලියන 1.4 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "කොටගල වැවිලි රු",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "මිලියන 55.7 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "මිලියන 9.1 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "බ්රවුන්ස් ආයෝජන",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "මිලියන 52.8 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "මිලියන 7.3 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "බලංගොඩ වැවිලි",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "මිලියන 49.3 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "943,000 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "මිලියන 34.8 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "මිලියන 1.2 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "මිලියන 56 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "16000",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ජූලි මාසය",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මිලියන 754 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "පෙර දින",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මිලියන 283 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "මහජන බැංකුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "61 වැනි",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "SLT-Mobitel",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [],
        []
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "CSE சீனாவுடனான கடன் மறுசீரமைப்பு எதிர்பார்ப்புகளால் இயக்கப்படுகிறது",
      "author": "சஹான் வீரசூரிய",
      "body_lines": [
        "ஜனாதிபதி ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்கவின் சீன விஜயம் விரைவில் அறிவிக்கப்பட்டதை அடுத்து, CSE இல் வர்த்தக நடவடிக்கைகள் நேற்றைய தினம் சாதகமாக இருந்தன. அவரது வருகைக்கான முக்கிய காரணங்களில் ஒன்று   சர்வதேச நாணய நிதியம் (IMF) இலங்கை அதன் இருதரப்பு கடனாளியான சீனாவுடனான கடன் மறுசீரமைப்பு பேச்சுக்களை தொடங்க வேண்டும் என்று கூறியுள்ளது, அதே நேரத்தில்  அரசாங்கம் வாஷிங்டனை தளமாகக் கொண்ட நிதியத்திடம் இருந்து நிதிக் கடனை நாடுகிறது, சந்தை ஆய்வாளர்கள் கூறினார்.",
        "\"சீனா ஒரு பெரிய கடன் வழங்குநராக உள்ளது, மேலும் கடன் மறுசீரமைப்பில் இலங்கை உடனுக்குடன் ஈடுபட வேண்டும்\" என்று சர்வதேச நாணய நிதியத்தின் ஆசியா மற்றும் பசிபிக் துறையின் இயக்குனர் கிருஷ்ணா சீனிவாசன் சமீபத்தில் சர்வதேச ஊடகத்திற்கு தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "இந்த முன்னேற்றங்களுக்கு மத்தியில், முக்கிய அனைத்து பங்கு விலைக் குறியீடு 52.9 புள்ளிகள் உயர்ந்தது மற்றும் அதிக திரவக் குறியீடு  31.0 புள்ளிகள் உயர்ந்தது. விற்றுமுதல் ஒரு பில்லியனாக இருந்தது. சில்லறை விற்பனை சந்தையில் லங்கா ஐஓசி ரூ.140 மில்லியன் (1.7 மில்லியன் பங்குகள் வர்த்தகம்), எக்ஸ்போலங்கா ஹோல்டிங்ஸ் ரூ.113 மில்லியன் (655,000 பங்குகள் வர்த்தகம்), டிஜே லங்கா ரூ.63 மில்லியன் (1.4 மில்லியன் பங்குகள் வர்த்தகம்), கொட்டகலை ஆகியவை வருவாயில் பங்களித்த முதல் ஏழு நிறுவனங்களாகும். பெருந்தோட்டங்கள் ரூ 55.7 மில்லியன் (9.1 மில்லியன் பங்குகள் வர்த்தகம்), பிரவுன்ஸ் இன்வெஸ்ட்மென்ட் ரூ 52.8 மில்லியன் (7.3 மில்லியன் பங்குகள் வர்த்தகம்), பலாங்கொட தோட்டங்கள்  ரூ 49.3 மில்லியன் (943,000 பங்குகள் வர்த்தகம்) மற்றும் பிரிண்ட்கேர் ரூ 34.8 மில்லியன் (1.2 மில்லியன் பங்குகள் வர்த்தகம்), 56 மில்லியன் 16000 பங்கு பரிவர்த்தனைகளில் பங்கு அளவு கை மாறியது.",
        "பங்கு தரகர்களின் கூற்றுப்படி, பெருந்தோட்டத் துறை கவுண்டர்களில் கணிசமான பங்கேற்பு இருந்தது. காரணம், நாட்டில் உரப் பிரச்சனைகள் காரணமாக இத்துறையில் விளைச்சல் குறைந்துள்ள போதிலும், ரூபாய் மதிப்பு சரிவு குறிப்பாக தேயிலை ஏற்றுமதியாளர்களுக்குப் பயனளித்தது. மேலும், ஜூலை மாதத்தில் தற்போது வரையிலான நிகர வரவுகள் ரூ.754 மில்லியனைத் தொட்டுள்ளன. முந்தைய நாளில்  283 மில்லியன் ரூ.",
        "61வது ஆண்டு நிறைவை முன்னிட்டு மக்கள் வங்கி இரத்த தான முகாமை ஏற்பாடு செய்துள்ளது",
        "SLT-Mobitel அதன் பயன்படுத்தப்படாத சொத்துக்களை கார்ப்பரேட் துறைக்கு நீண்ட கால குத்தகைக்கு வழங்க உள்ளது",
        "ஒரு பதிலை விடுங்கள் பதிலை ரத்துசெய் உங்கள் மின்னஞ்சல் முகவரி வெளியிடப்படாது. தேவையான புலங்கள் குறிக்கப்பட்டுள்ளன *கருத்து பெயர் *",
        "அடுத்த முறை நான் கருத்து தெரிவிக்க, எனது பெயர், மின்னஞ்சல் மற்றும் இணையதளத்தை இந்த உலாவியில் சேமிக்கவும்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "CSE",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "சீனா",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "CSE",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "நேற்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "சீனா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஒன்று",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "சர்வதேச நாணய நிதியம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சீனா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "வாஷிங்டன்",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "சீனா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "கிருஷ்ணா சீனிவாசன்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "IMF இன்",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆசியா",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "பசிபிக் துறை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "சர்வதேச ஊடகங்கள்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "52.9",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "31.0",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஏழு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "லங்கா ஐஓசி 140 மில்லியன்",
            "label": "PRODUCT"
          },
          {
            "text": "1.7 மில்லியன்",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "113 மில்லியன்",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "655,000",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரூ 63 மில்லியன்",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "1.4 மில்லியன்",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "கொட்டகலை தோட்டங்கள் ரூ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "55.7 மில்லியன்",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "9.1 மில்லியன்",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "பிரவுன்ஸ் முதலீடுகள்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "52.8 மில்லியன்",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "7.3 மில்லியன்",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "பலாங்கொடை தோட்டங்கள்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "49.3 மில்லியன்",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "943,000",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "34.8 மில்லியன்",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "1.2 மில்லியன்",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "56 மில்லியன்",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "16000",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஜூலை மாதம்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "754 மில்லியன்",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "முந்தைய நாள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "283 மில்லியன்",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "மக்கள் வங்கி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "61வது",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "SLT-Mobitel",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [],
        []
      ]
    }
  }
}