{
  "newspaper_id": "ada-derana-lk",
  "url": "http://www.adaderana.lk/news/84520/amendment-to-the-penal-code-on-lgbtq-rights-handed-over-to-president",
  "time_ut": 1661360220,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Amendment to the Penal Code on LGBTQ+ rights handed over to President",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Amendment to the Penal Code on LGBTQ+ rights handed over to President",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "A bill to amend the Penal Code with the aim of protecting the rights of the LGBTQ+ communities in Sri Lanka was handed over to President Ranil Wickremesinghe today (Aug 24) by Attorney-at-Law MP Premanath C. Dolawatta.",
        "This bill to amend the Penal Code was submitted to the Parliament yesterday (Aug 23) by MP Dolawatta as a Private Member’s Bill.",
        "The society of Sri Lanka has an extremely backward notion regarding the LGBTQ + community and as a result, not only in daily life, but even in government and law enforcement agencies, this community has been subjected to various forms of violence, oppression and harassment, the President’s Media Division (PMD) said in a press release.",
        "At times, even their democratic basic rights have been violated, the PMD added.",
        "“Punishment of individuals based on sexual orientation and sexual identification was spread throughout the world by colonial legal systems in the Victorian era. But in modern psychiatry, this is not considered a crime or a perversion. Also, developed countries have worked to amend the laws that penalize this community and limit their rights,” the statement read further.",
        "Having taken these factors into consideration, MP Dolawatte submitted this Private Member’s Bill."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "the Penal Code",
          "label": "LAW"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "the Penal Code",
            "label": "LAW"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "24",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the Penal Code",
            "label": "LAW"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "yesterday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "23",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Dolawatta",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "daily",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Media Division",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "PMD",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "PMD",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Victorian",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Dolawatte",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "LGBTQ+ අයිතිවාසිකම් පිළිබඳ දණ්ඩ නීති සංග්‍රහයේ සංශෝධන ජනපතිට භාර දෙයි",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ LGBTQ+ ප්‍රජාවන්ගේ අයිතීන් සුරැකීමේ අරමුණින් දණ්ඩ නීති සංග්‍රහය සංශෝධනය කිරීම සඳහා වූ පනත් කෙටුම්පතක් අද (අගෝස්තු 24) නීතීඥ පාර්ලිමේන්තු මන්ත්‍රී ප්‍රේමනාත් සී දොලවත්ත මහතා විසින් ජනාධිපති රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතා වෙත භාර දෙන ලදී.",
        "දණ්ඩ නීති සංග්‍රහය සංශෝධනය කිරීම සඳහා වූ මෙම පනත් කෙටුම්පත පෞද්ගලික මන්ත්‍රී පනත් කෙටුම්පතක් ලෙස පාර්ලිමේන්තු මන්ත්‍රී දොළවත්ත මහතා විසින් ඊයේ (අගෝස්තු 23) පාර්ලිමේන්තුවට ඉදිරිපත් කරන ලදී.",
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකා සමාජය LGBTQ + ප්‍රජාව සම්බන්ධයෙන් අතිශයින් පසුගාමී මතයක් දරන අතර එහි ප්‍රතිඵලයක් ලෙස එදිනෙදා ජීවිතයේදී පමණක් නොව රජයේ සහ නීතිය ක්‍රියාත්මක කරන ආයතනවල පවා මෙම ප්‍රජාව විවිධ ප්‍රචණ්ඩත්වයන්ට, පීඩාවන්ට සහ හිරිහැරවලට ලක්ව ඇත. ජනාධිපති මාධ්‍ය අංශය (PMD) මාධ්‍ය නිවේදනයක් නිකුත් කරමින් කියා සිටියේය.",
        "ඇතැම් අවස්ථාවලදී ඔවුන්ගේ ප්‍රජාතන්ත්‍රවාදී මූලික අයිතිවාසිකම් පවා උල්ලංඝනය වී ඇති බව පීඑම්ඩී වැඩිදුරටත් සඳහන් කළේය.",
        "“ලිංගික දිශානතිය සහ ලිංගික අනන්‍යතාවය මත පදනම්ව පුද්ගලයන්ට දඬුවම් කිරීම වික්ටෝරියානු යුගයේ යටත් විජිත නීති පද්ධති මගින් ලොව පුරා ව්‍යාප්ත විය. නමුත් නූතන මනෝ වෛද්‍ය විද්‍යාව තුළ මෙය අපරාධයක් හෝ විකෘතියක් ලෙස නොසැලකේ. එසේම මෙම ප්‍රජාවට දඬුවම් කරන සහ ඔවුන්ගේ අයිතිවාසිකම් සීමා කරන නීති සංශෝධනය කිරීමට සංවර්ධිත රටවල් කටයුතු කර ඇත.",
        "මෙම කරුණු සැලකිල්ලට ගනිමින් දොලවත්ත මන්ත්‍රීවරයා මෙම පෞද්ගලික මන්ත්‍රී පනත් කෙටුම්පත ඉදිරිපත් කළේය."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "දණ්ඩ නීති සංග්‍රහය",
          "label": "LAW"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "දණ්ඩ නීති සංග්‍රහය",
            "label": "LAW"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "24",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "දණ්ඩ නීති සංග්‍රහය",
            "label": "LAW"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඊයේ",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "23",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "දොලවත්ත",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "දිනපතා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මාධ්ය අංශය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "පීඑම්ඩී",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "පීඑම්ඩී",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "වික්ටෝරියානු",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "දොලවත්ත",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "LGBTQ+ உரிமைகள் மீதான தண்டனைச் சட்டத்தில் திருத்தம் ஜனாதிபதியிடம் ஒப்படைக்கப்பட்டது",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "இலங்கையில் உள்ள LGBTQ+ சமூகங்களின் உரிமைகளைப் பாதுகாக்கும் நோக்கில் தண்டனைச் சட்டத்தை திருத்துவதற்கான சட்டமூலம் இன்று (ஆகஸ்ட் 24) ஜனாதிபதி ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்கவிடம் சட்டத்தரணி பாராளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர் பிரேமநாத் சி.தொலவத்தவினால் கையளிக்கப்பட்டது.",
        "குற்றவியல் சட்டத்தை திருத்துவதற்கான இந்த சட்டமூலம் பாராளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர் டோலவத்தவினால் தனியார் சட்டமூலமாக நேற்று (ஆகஸ்ட் 23) பாராளுமன்றத்தில் சமர்ப்பிக்கப்பட்டது.",
        "இலங்கையின் சமூகம் LGBTQ + சமூகம் தொடர்பாக மிகவும் பின்தங்கிய கருத்தைக் கொண்டுள்ளது, இதன் விளைவாக, அன்றாட வாழ்க்கையில் மட்டுமல்ல, அரசாங்க மற்றும் சட்ட அமலாக்க நிறுவனங்களிலும் கூட, இந்த சமூகம் பல்வேறு வகையான வன்முறை, அடக்குமுறை மற்றும் துன்புறுத்தலுக்கு உள்ளாகியுள்ளது. ஜனாதிபதி ஊடகப் பிரிவு (PMD) விடுத்துள்ள ஊடக அறிக்கையில் தெரிவிக்கப்பட்டுள்ளது.",
        "சில நேரங்களில், அவர்களின் ஜனநாயக அடிப்படை உரிமைகள் கூட மீறப்பட்டுள்ளன, PMD மேலும் கூறியது.",
        "\"பாலியல் நோக்குநிலை மற்றும் பாலின அடையாளத்தின் அடிப்படையில் தனிநபர்களின் தண்டனை விக்டோரியா காலத்தில் காலனித்துவ சட்ட அமைப்புகளால் உலகம் முழுவதும் பரவியது. ஆனால் நவீன மனநல மருத்துவத்தில், இது ஒரு குற்றமாகவோ அல்லது வக்கிரமாகவோ கருதப்படவில்லை. மேலும், வளர்ந்த நாடுகள் இந்த சமூகத்தை தண்டிக்கும் மற்றும் அவர்களின் உரிமைகளை மட்டுப்படுத்தும் சட்டங்களை திருத்துவதற்கு உழைத்துள்ளன, ”என்று அறிக்கை மேலும் வாசிக்கிறது.",
        "இந்தக் காரணிகளை கருத்திற் கொண்டு பாராளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர் டோலவத்த இந்த தனியார் சட்டமூலத்தை சமர்ப்பித்தார்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "தண்டனைச் சட்டம்",
          "label": "LAW"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "தண்டனைச் சட்டம்",
            "label": "LAW"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "24",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "தண்டனைச் சட்டம்",
            "label": "LAW"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "நேற்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "23",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "டோலவத்த",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "தினசரி",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஊடகப் பிரிவு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "பிஎம்டி",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பிஎம்டி",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "விக்டோரியன்",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "டோலவத்தே",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}