{
  "newspaper_id": "news-first-lk",
  "url": "https://www.newsfirst.lk/2022/07/27/shots-fired-in-gampaha-four-criminals-including-pas-podda-injured/",
  "time_ut": 1658911920,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Shots fired in Gampaha; Four criminals including Pas Podda injured",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Shots fired in Gampaha; Four criminals including Pas Podda injured",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); Four people including notorious criminal 'Pas Podda' were injured in a drive-by shooting close to the Gampaha Court Complex on Wednesday (27) afternoon.",
        "olice Spokesperson SSP Nihal Thalduwa told News 1st that all four men were admitted to the Gampaha Hospital.",
        "Six suspects were being transported to the Gampaha Court for trial, and the shooting took place targeting them.",
        "Four of them were injured in the shooting, and Police said shots were fired from a car.",
        "Shots fired in Gampaha; Four criminals including Pas Podda injured",
        "Aragalaya activist Dhaniz Ali faces three charges including forcing to suspend SLRC transmission – Police"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Gampaha",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "Four",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "Pas Podda",
          "label": "PRODUCT"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "News 1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Four",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Gampaha Court",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Wednesday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "27) afternoon",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Spokesperson SSP Nihal Thalduwa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "News 1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "four",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Gampaha Hospital",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Six",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Gampaha Court",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Four",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Gampaha",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Four",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Pas Podda",
            "label": "PRODUCT"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Dhaniz Ali",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "three",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "ගම්පහ වෙඩි තැබීමක්; පස් පොඩ්ඩා ඇතුළු අපරාධකරුවන් හතර දෙනෙකුට තුවාල",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); බදාදා (27) පස්වරුවේ ගම්පහ අධිකරණ සංකීර්ණය ආසන්නයේදී රිය පදවාගෙන ගිය වෙඩි තැබීමකින් නමගිය අපරාධකරු ‘පස් පොඩ්ඩා’ ඇතුළු සිව් දෙනෙකු තුවාල ලබා තිබේ.",
        "ඔලිස් මාධ්‍ය ප්‍රකාශක ජ්‍යෙෂ්ඨ පොලිස් අධිකාරී නිහාල් තල්දූව News 1st වෙත කියා සිටියේ ඔවුන් සිව්දෙනාම ගම්පහ රෝහලට ඇතුළත් කළ බවයි.",
        "සැකකරුවන් හය දෙනෙකු නඩු විභාගය සඳහා ගම්පහ අධිකරණය වෙත ප්‍රවාහනය කරමින් සිටියදී ඔවුන් ඉලක්ක කර මෙම වෙඩි තැබීම සිදුව තිබේ.",
        "වෙඩි තැබීමෙන් ඔවුන්ගෙන් 4 දෙනෙකු තුවාල ලබා ඇති අතර පොලිසිය පැවසුවේ මෝටර් රථයකින් වෙඩි ප්‍රහාරයක් එල්ල වී ඇති බවයි.",
        "ගම්පහ වෙඩි තැබීමක්; පස් පොඩ්ඩා ඇතුළු අපරාධකරුවන් හතර දෙනෙකුට තුවාල",
        "SLRC විකාශනය අත්හිටුවීමට බල කිරීම ඇතුළු චෝදනා තුනකට අරගල ක්‍රියාකාරිකයෙකු වන ධනීස් අලිට - පොලිසිය"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ගම්පහ",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "හතර",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "පාස් පොඩ්ඩා",
          "label": "PRODUCT"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "News 1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "හතර",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගම්පහ අධිකරණය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "බදාදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "27) සවස",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "මාධ්‍ය ප්‍රකාශක ජ්‍යෙෂ්ඨ පොලිස් අධිකාරී නිහාල් තල්දූව",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "News 1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "හතර",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගම්පහ රෝහල",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "හය",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගම්පහ අධිකරණය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "හතර",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ගම්පහ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "හතර",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාස් පොඩ්ඩා",
            "label": "PRODUCT"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ධනීස් අලි",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "තුන්",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "கம்பஹாவில் துப்பாக்கிச் சூடு; பாஸ் போடா உட்பட நான்கு குற்றவாளிகள் காயமடைந்தனர்",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); கம்பஹா நீதிமன்ற வளாகத்திற்கு அருகில் நேற்று புதன்கிழமை (27) பிற்பகல் இடம்பெற்ற துப்பாக்கிச் சூட்டில் பிரபல குற்றவாளி 'பாஸ் போட்டா' உட்பட நால்வர் காயமடைந்துள்ளனர்.",
        "நான்கு பேரும் கம்பஹா வைத்தியசாலையில் அனுமதிக்கப்பட்டுள்ளதாக பொலிஸ் ஊடகப் பேச்சாளர் சிரேஷ்ட பொலிஸ் அத்தியட்சகர் நிஹால் தல்துவா நியூஸ் 1ஸ்டுக்கு தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "ஆறு சந்தேக நபர்கள் விசாரணைக்காக கம்பஹா நீதிமன்றத்திற்கு கொண்டு செல்லப்பட்ட நிலையில், அவர்களை இலக்கு வைத்து துப்பாக்கிச் சூடு நடத்தப்பட்டுள்ளது.",
        "துப்பாக்கிச் சூட்டில் நான்கு பேர் காயமடைந்தனர், மேலும் காரில் இருந்து துப்பாக்கிச் சூடு நடத்தப்பட்டதாக போலீசார் தெரிவித்தனர்.",
        "கம்பஹாவில் துப்பாக்கிச் சூடு; பாஸ் போடா உட்பட நான்கு குற்றவாளிகள் காயமடைந்தனர்",
        "அரகலயா செயற்பாட்டாளர் தனிஸ் அலி SLRC ஒலிபரப்பை இடைநிறுத்த வற்புறுத்தியது உட்பட மூன்று குற்றச்சாட்டுகளை எதிர்கொள்கிறார் – காவல்துறை"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "கம்பஹா",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "நான்கு",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "பாஸ் போட்டா",
          "label": "PRODUCT"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "News 1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "நான்கு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "கம்பஹா நீதிமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "புதன்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "27) பிற்பகல்",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "செய்தி தொடர்பாளர் SSP நிஹால் தல்துவா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "News 1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "நான்கு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "கம்பஹா வைத்தியசாலை",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஆறு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "கம்பஹா நீதிமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "நான்கு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "கம்பஹா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "நான்கு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாஸ் போட்டா",
            "label": "PRODUCT"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "தனிஸ் அலி",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "மூன்று",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}