{
  "newspaper_id": "daily-mirror-lk",
  "url": "https://www.dailymirror.lk/breaking_news/Police-release-photographs-of-main-suspects-wanted-over-setting-fire-to-Ranils-private-residence/108-241897",
  "time_ut": 1658916738,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Police release photographs of main suspects wanted over setting fire to Ranil’s private residence",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Police release photographs of main suspects wanted over setting fire to Ranil’s private residence",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "The Police released a set of photographs of a group of suspects wanted over the incident of setting fire to President Ranil Wickremesinghe's private residence in Colombo on July 9.",
        "Police said the investigations into the arson attack on the President's private residence was being carried out by the Criminal Investigations Department.",
        "They said the investigators were looking to identify a group of persons identified as the main suspects involved in causing damage and setting fire to the house based on the CCTV footage and the video footage.",
        "Accordingly, the police released 14 photographs of suspects in order to identify them and take the necessary legal action.",
        "The police requested the public to inform the CID to the following phone numbers 071-8594950, 071-8594929 or 011-2422176 through WhatsApp or calls if they have any information about the people in those photographs.",
        "Earlier, the police arrested four suspects arrested over the incident and were remanded till August 10 by Colombo Fort Magistrate's Court.",
        "President Wickremesinghe's private residence on 5th Lane in Colombo has been set on fire by the protestors after a tense situation erupted between the protestors and security forces on July 9.(DSB)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Ranil",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Colombo",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "July 9",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the Criminal Investigations Department",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "CCTV",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "14",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "CID",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "071-8594950",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "071-8594929",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "011-2422176",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "WhatsApp",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "four",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "August 10",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Colombo Fort Magistrate's",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "5th Lane",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "Colombo",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "July 9.(DSB",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "රනිල්ගේ පෞද්ගලික නිවසට ගිනි තැබීමට අවශ්‍ය ප්‍රධාන සැකකරුවන්ගේ ඡායාරූප පොලිසිය නිකුත් කරයි",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "ජුලි 9 වැනිදා ජනාධිපති රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතාගේ කොළඹ පිහිටි පෞද්ගලික නිවසට ගිනි තැබීමේ සිද්ධිය සම්බන්ධයෙන් අවශ්‍ය සැකකරුවන් පිරිසකගේ ඡායාරූප පෙළක් පොලිසිය විසින් නිකුත් කර තිබේ.",
        "ජනාධිපතිවරයාගේ පෞද්ගලික නිවසට ගිනි තැබීමේ සිද්ධිය සම්බන්ධයෙන් විමර්ශන අපරාධ පරීක්ෂණ දෙපාර්තමේන්තුව විසින් සිදුකරන බව පොලිසිය පවසයි.",
        "CCTV දර්ශන සහ වීඩියෝ දර්ශන පදනම් කරගනිමින් නිවසට අලාභහානි සිදුකිරීමට සහ ගිනි තැබීමට සම්බන්ධ ප්‍රධාන සැකකරුවන් ලෙස හඳුනාගෙන ඇති පුද්ගලයින් පිරිසක් හඳුනා ගැනීමට විමර්ශන නිලධාරීන් බලාපොරොත්තු වන බව ඔවුන් පැවසීය.",
        "ඒ අනුව සැකකරුවන් හඳුනාගෙන අවශ්‍ය නීතිමය ක්‍රියාමාර්ග ගැනීම සඳහා පොලිසිය ඔවුන්ගේ ඡායාරූප 14ක් නිකුත් කළා.",
        "එම ඡායාරූපවල සිටින පුද්ගලයන් පිළිබඳ තොරතුරක් ඇත්නම් පහත සඳහන් දුරකථන අංක 071-8594950, 071-8594929 හෝ 011-2422176 යන දුරකථන අංකවලට වට්ස්ඇප් හෝ ඇමතුම් මගින් දැනුම් දෙන ලෙස පොලිසිය මහජනතාවගෙන් ඉල්ලා සිටියේය.",
        "මීට පෙර සිද්ධිය සම්බන්ධයෙන් අත්අඩංගුවට ගත් සැකකරුවන් සිව් දෙනෙකු අත්අඩංගුවට ගත් පොලිසිය අගෝස්තු 10 වැනිදා දක්වා රක්ෂිත බන්ධනාගාර ගත කිරීමට කොළඹ කොටුව මහේස්ත්‍රාත් අධිකරණය නියෝග කළා.",
        "ජුලි 9 වැනිදා විරෝධතාකරුවන් සහ ආරක්ෂක අංශ අතර ඇතිවූ නොසන්සුන්කාරී තත්ත්වයක් හේතුවෙන් කොළඹ 5 වැනි පටුමගේ ජනාධිපති වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතාගේ පෞද්ගලික නිවසට විරෝධතාකරුවන් විසින් ගිනි තබා ඇත.(DSB)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "රනිල්",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "කොළඹ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජූලි 9",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "අපරාධ පරීක්ෂණ දෙපාර්තමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "සීසීටීවී",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "14",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "CID",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "071-8594950",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "071-8594929",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "011-2422176",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "WhatsApp",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "හතර",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "අගෝස්තු 10",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "කොළඹ කොටුව මහේස්ත්‍රාත්",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "5 වන පටුමග",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "කොළඹ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජූලි 9. (DSB",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "ரணிலின் இல்லத்திற்கு தீ வைத்த முக்கிய சந்தேக நபர்களின் புகைப்படங்களை பொலிஸார் வெளியிட்டுள்ளனர்",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "ஜனாதிபதி ரணில் விக்ரமசிங்கவின் கொழும்பில் கடந்த ஜூலை மாதம் 9ஆம் திகதியன்று அவரது இல்லத்திற்கு தீ வைத்த சம்பவம் தொடர்பில் தேடப்பட்டு வரும் சந்தேக நபர்களின் புகைப்படத் தொகுப்பை பொலிஸார் வெளியிட்டுள்ளனர்.",
        "ஜனாதிபதியின் தனிப்பட்ட இல்லத்திற்கு தீ வைப்புத் தாக்குதல் சம்பவம் தொடர்பில் குற்றப் புலனாய்வுப் பிரிவினர் விசாரணைகளை மேற்கொண்டு வருவதாக பொலிஸார் தெரிவித்துள்ளனர்.",
        "சிசிடிவி காட்சிகள் மற்றும் வீடியோ காட்சிகளின் அடிப்படையில் வீட்டிற்கு சேதம் விளைவித்த மற்றும் தீ வைப்பதில் தொடர்புடைய முக்கிய சந்தேக நபர்களாக அடையாளம் காணப்பட்ட நபர்களின் குழுவை புலனாய்வாளர்கள் தேடுகின்றனர் என்று அவர்கள் தெரிவித்தனர்.",
        "அதன்படி, சந்தேக நபர்களை அடையாளம் கண்டு தேவையான சட்ட நடவடிக்கை எடுப்பதற்காக 14 புகைப்படங்களை போலீசார் வெளியிட்டனர்.",
        "அந்தப் புகைப்படங்களில் உள்ளவர்கள் குறித்து ஏதேனும் தகவல் தெரிந்தால், பின்வரும் தொலைபேசி எண்களான 071-8594950, 071-8594929 அல்லது 011-2422176 ஆகிய தொலைபேசி எண்களுக்கு வாட்ஸ்அப் அல்லது அழைப்புகள் மூலம் தெரிவிக்குமாறு பொதுமக்கள் பொதுமக்களிடம் கேட்டுக்கொண்டுள்ளனர்.",
        "முன்னதாக, சம்பவம் தொடர்பில் கைது செய்யப்பட்ட நான்கு சந்தேக நபர்களை பொலிஸார் கைது செய்து கொழும்பு கோட்டை நீதவான் நீதிமன்றத்தினால் ஆகஸ்ட் 10 ஆம் திகதி வரை விளக்கமறியலில் வைக்கப்பட்டுள்ளனர்.",
        "ஜூலை 9 ஆம் தேதி ஆர்ப்பாட்டக்காரர்களுக்கும் பாதுகாப்புப் படையினருக்கும் இடையில் பதற்றமான சூழ்நிலை ஏற்பட்டதை அடுத்து, கொழும்பில் 5வது லேனில் உள்ள ஜனாதிபதி விக்கிரமசிங்கவின் தனிப்பட்ட இல்லம் போராட்டக்காரர்களால் தீக்கிரையாக்கப்பட்டது.(DSB)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ரணில்",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "கொழும்பு",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜூலை 9",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "குற்றப் புலனாய்வுத் திணைக்களம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "மறைகாணி",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "14",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "சி.ஐ.டி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "071-8594950",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "071-8594929",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "011-2422176",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "பகிரி",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "நான்கு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆகஸ்ட் 10",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "கொழும்பு கோட்டை நீதவான்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "5வது லேன்",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "கொழும்பு",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜூலை 9.(டி.எஸ்.பி",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}