{
  "newspaper_id": "ada-lk",
  "url": "https://www.ada.lk/breaking_news/අර්බුදයට-විසඳුම්-සොයා-ඇමතිවරු-විදෙස්ගත-වෙති/11-394901",
  "time_ut": 1656382737,
  "original_lang": "si",
  "original_title": "අර්බුදයට විසඳුම් සොයා ඇමතිවරු විදෙස්ගත වෙති",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Ministers go abroad to find solutions to crisis",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "Several ministers left the Katunayake airport on the night of 06/27 and the morning of 06/28 in search of a solution to the fuel crisis in Sri Lanka.",
        "Accordingly, the Minister of Energy Kanchana Wijesekera has left for Qatar on the night of 06/27. The Minister had left Doha, Qatar on a Qatar Airways flight QR-655 on 08/27 at 08.15 pm from the Katunayake Airport.",
        "He was accompanied by Environment Minister Nasir Ahmed on the same flight to Doha, Qatar. They are scheduled to visit Qatar to find a regular fuel supplier.",
        "In addition, Minister Susil Premajayantha has left for Dubai on the morning of 06/28 to leave for France. He had left Dubai for Katunayake on 06/28 at 03.15 am on an Emirates flight EK-649.",
        "A delegation including Minister Susil Premajayantha and former Sri Lankan Ambassador to Russia Dr. Saman Weerasinghe is scheduled to leave for Moscow, Russia on July 3 to find a solution to the fuel crisis."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "the night",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "06/28",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Qatar",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Doha",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Qatar",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Qatar Airways",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "08/27",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "08.15 pm",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Katunayake Airport",
            "label": "FAC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Nasir Ahmed",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Doha",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Qatar",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Qatar",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Susil Premajayantha",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Dubai",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "06/28",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "France",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Dubai",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "06/28",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "03.15 am",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "Emirates",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Susil Premajayantha",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lankan",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Russia",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Saman Weerasinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Moscow",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Russia",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "July 3",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "අර්බුදයට විසඳුම් සොයා ඇමතිවරු විදෙස්ගත වෙති",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ ඉන්ධන අර්බුදයට විසදුම් සොයා ඇමතිවරු කීප දෙනෙකු කටුනායක ගුවන් තොටුපළෙන් 06/27 රාත්‍රී සහ 06/28 දින අලුයම විදේශ ගත වී තිබේ.",
        "ඒ අනුව බලශක්ති අමාත්‍ය කංචන විජේසේකර මහතා 06/27 දින රාත්‍රී කටාර් රාජ්‍යය බලා පිටත්ව ගොස් තිබේ. අමාත්‍යවරයා 06/27 දින රාත්‍රී 08.15 ට කටාර් ගුවන් සේවයේ කිව්.ආර්.- 655 දරන ගුවන් යානයෙන් කටාර් රාජ්‍යයේ දෝහා වෙත කටුනායක ගුවන් තොටුපළෙන් පිටත්ව ගොස් තිබුණි.",
        "ඔහු සමග පරිසර අමාත්‍ය නසීර් අහමඩ් මහතා ද මෙම ගුවන් යානයෙන්ම කටාර්  රාජ්‍යයේ දෝහා බලා පිටත්ව ගොස් තිබේ. ඔවුන් කටාර් රාජ්‍යයේ නිත්‍ය ඉන්ධන සැපයුම්කරුවෙකු සොයා ගැනීමට මෙම සංචාරයේ දී කටයුතු කිරීමට නියමිතය.",
        "මීට අමතරව සුසිල් ප්‍රේමජයන්ත අමාත්‍යවරයා ද 06/28 දින අලුයම ප්‍රංශය බලා පිටත්ව යාම සදහා ඩුබායි වෙත පිටත්ව ගොස් තිබේ. ඔහු 06/28 දින අලුයම 03.15 ට එමිරේට්ස් ගුවන් සේවයේ ඊ.කේ.- 649 දරන ගුවන් යානයෙන් ඒ සදහා ඩුබායි වෙත කටුනායක ගුවන් තොටුපළෙන් පිටත්ව ගොස් තිබුණි.",
        "එළඹෙන ජුලි මස 03 වැනි දින අමාත්‍ය සුසිල් ප්‍රේමජයන්ත සහ රුසියාවේ හිටපු ශ්‍රී ලංකා තානාපති  වෛද්‍ය  සමන් වීරසිංහ මහතා ඇතුළු කණ්ඩායමක් ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ ඉන්ධන අර්බුදයට විසදුම් සොයා රුසියාවේ මොස්කව් නුවර බලා පිටත්ව යාමට නියමිතය."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "රාත්රිය",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "06/28",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "කටාර්",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "දෝහා",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "කටාර්",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "කටාර් එයාර්වේස්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "08/27",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ප.ව.08.15",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "කටුනායක ගුවන් තොටුපළ",
            "label": "FAC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "නසීර් අහමඩ්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "දෝහා",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "කටාර්",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "කටාර්",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "සුසිල් ප්‍රේමජයන්ත",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඩුබායි",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "06/28",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ප්රංශය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඩුබායි",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "06/28",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "03.15 පෙ.ව",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "එමිරේට්ස්",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "සුසිල් ප්‍රේමජයන්ත",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලාංකික",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "රුසියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "සමන් වීරසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "මොස්කව්",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "රුසියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජූලි 3",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "நெருக்கடிகளுக்கு தீர்வு காண அமைச்சர்கள் வெளிநாடு செல்கிறார்கள்",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "இலங்கையில் ஏற்பட்டுள்ள எரிபொருள் நெருக்கடிக்கு தீர்வு காணும் நோக்கில் பல அமைச்சர்கள் 06/27 இரவு மற்றும் 06/28 காலை கட்டுநாயக்க விமான நிலையத்திலிருந்து புறப்பட்டனர்.",
        "இதன்படி, எரிசக்தி அமைச்சர் காஞ்சன விஜேசேகர 06/27 இரவு கட்டார் நோக்கிச் சென்றுள்ளார். 08/27 அன்று இரவு 08.15 மணியளவில் கட்டுநாயக்க விமான நிலையத்திலிருந்து கத்தார் எயார்வேஸின் QR-655 விமானத்தில் கத்தாரின் தோஹாவிலிருந்து அமைச்சர் புறப்பட்டார்.",
        "அவருடன் சுற்றுச்சூழல் அமைச்சர் நசீர் அகமதுவும் அதே விமானத்தில் கத்தாரின் தோஹாவுக்குச் சென்றார். வழக்கமான எரிபொருள் சப்ளையரைக் கண்டறிய அவர்கள் கத்தாருக்குச் செல்ல உள்ளனர்.",
        "மேலும், அமைச்சர் சுசில் பிரேமஜயந்த 06/28 காலை பிரான்ஸ் செல்வதற்காக டுபாய் சென்றுள்ளார். இவர் துபாயிலிருந்து 06/28 ஆம் திகதி அதிகாலை 03.15 மணியளவில் EK-649 என்ற எமிரேட்ஸ் விமானத்தில் கட்டுநாயக்கவிற்கு சென்றுள்ளார்.",
        "எரிபொருள் நெருக்கடிக்கு தீர்வு காண்பதற்காக அமைச்சர் சுசில் பிரேமஜயந்த மற்றும் ரஷ்யாவுக்கான முன்னாள் இலங்கை தூதுவர் கலாநிதி சமன் வீரசிங்க உள்ளிட்ட குழுவினர் ஜூலை 3 ஆம் திகதி ரஷ்யாவின் மொஸ்கோ நகருக்கு செல்ல உள்ளனர்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "அந்த இரவு",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "06/28",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "கத்தார்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "தோஹா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "கத்தார்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "கத்தார் ஏர்வேஸ்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "08/27",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "இரவு 08.15 மணி",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "கட்டுநாயக்க விமான நிலையம்",
            "label": "FAC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "நசீர் அகமது",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "தோஹா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "கத்தார்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "கத்தார்",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "சுசில் பிரேமஜயந்த",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "துபாய்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "06/28",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "பிரான்ஸ்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "துபாய்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "06/28",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "காலை 03.15 மணி",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "எமிரேட்ஸ்",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "சுசில் பிரேமஜயந்த",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரஷ்யா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சமன் வீரசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "மாஸ்கோ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரஷ்யா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜூலை 3",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}