{
  "newspaper_id": "ada-derana-lk",
  "url": "http://www.adaderana.lk/news/84604/three-arrested-for-damaging-mps-houses",
  "time_ut": 1661751540,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Three arrested for damaging MPs’ houses",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Three arrested for damaging MPs’ houses",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "Three suspects have been arrested in relation to the incidents of attacking the houses of three MPs and damaging their property.",
        "The suspects were arrested for the damages caused to the houses of MPs Wimal Weerawansa, Lasantha Alagiyawanna and Arundika Fernando.",
        "A 37-year-old resident of the Hokandara area was arrested regarding the attack on MP Wimal Weerawansa’s house by Malabe police, yesterday (28).",
        "The suspect arrested in connection with damaging the house of MP Lasantha Alagiyawanna was a resident of the Kiridiwela area, who is aged 43.",
        "He was arrested by the Western Province-North division officials yesterday (28).",
        "Meanwhile, a 45-year-old resident of Dankotuwa has been arrested by Dankotuwa police with regard to the damages caused to the house of MP Arundika Fernando."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Three",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Three",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "three",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Wimal Weerawansa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Lasantha Alagiyawanna",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Arundika Fernando",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "37-year-old",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Wimal Weerawansa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "yesterday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "28",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Lasantha Alagiyawanna",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kiridiwela",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "43",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the Western Province-North",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "yesterday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "28",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "45-year-old",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Dankotuwa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Dankotuwa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Arundika Fernando",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "මන්ත්‍රීවරුන්ගේ නිවාසවලට හානි කළ තිදෙනෙක් අත්අඩංගුවට",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "මන්ත්‍රීවරුන් තිදෙනෙකුගේ නිවෙස්වලට පහරදී දේපළවලට හානි කිරීමේ සිද්ධීන් සම්බන්ධයෙන් සැකකරුවන් තිදෙනෙකු අත්අඩංගුවට ගෙන තිබෙනවා.",
        "විමල් වීරවංශ, ලසන්ත අලගියවන්න සහ අරුන්දික ප්‍රනාන්දු යන පාර්ලිමේන්තු මන්ත්‍රීවරුන්ගේ නිවාසවලට අලාභ හානි සිදුකිරීම සම්බන්ධයෙන් සැකකරුවන් අත්අඩංගුවට ගෙන ඇත.",
        "පාර්ලිමේන්තු මන්ත්‍රී විමල් වීරවංශ මහතාගේ නිවසට පහරදීම සම්බන්ධයෙන් මාලඹේ පොලිසිය විසින් ඊයේ (28) අත්අඩංගුවට ගෙන ඇත්තේ හෝකන්දර ප්‍රදේශයේ පදිංචි 37 හැවිරිදි පුද්ගලයෙක්.",
        "පාර්ලිමේන්තු මන්ත්‍රී ලසන්ත අලගියවන්න මහතාගේ නිවසට හානි කිරීම සම්බන්ධයෙන් අත්අඩංගුවට ගත් සැකකරු කිරිදිවැල ප්‍රදේශයේ පදිංචි 43 හැවිරිදි අයෙකි.",
        "බස්නාහිර පළාත් උතුරු කොට්ඨාශ නිලධාරීන් විසින් ඔහු ඊයේ (28) අත්අඩංගුවට ගෙන ඇත.",
        "මේ අතර අරුන්දික ප්‍රනාන්දු මන්ත්‍රීවරයාගේ නිවසට සිදුවූ අලාභහානි සම්බන්ධයෙන් දංකොටුව ප්‍රදේශයේ පදිංචි 45 හැවිරිදි පුද්ගලයෙකු දංකොටුව පොලීසිය විසින් අත්අඩංගුවට ගෙන තිබෙනවා."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "තුන්",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "තුන්",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "තුන්",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "විමල් වීරවංශ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ලසන්ත අලගියවන්න",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "අරුන්දික ප්‍රනාන්දු",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "37 හැවිරිදිය",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "විමල් වීරවංශ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඊයේ",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "28",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ලසන්ත අලගියවන්න",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "කිරිදිවැල",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "43",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "බස්නාහිර පළාත - උතුර",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඊයේ",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "28",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "45 හැවිරිදිය",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "දන්කොටුව",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "දන්කොටුව",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "අරුන්දික ප්‍රනාන්දු",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "எம்.பி.க்களின் வீடுகளை சேதப்படுத்தியதாக மூவர் கைது",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "மூன்று பாராளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர்களின் வீடுகளைத் தாக்கி அவர்களின் சொத்துக்களுக்கு சேதம் விளைவித்த சம்பவங்கள் தொடர்பில் மூன்று சந்தேகநபர்கள் கைது செய்யப்பட்டுள்ளனர்.",
        "பாராளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர்களான விமல் வீரவன்ச, லசந்த அழகியவன்ன மற்றும் அருந்திக பெர்னாண்டோ ஆகியோரின் வீடுகளுக்கு சேதம் ஏற்படுத்தியமை தொடர்பில் சந்தேகநபர்கள் கைது செய்யப்பட்டுள்ளனர்.",
        "பாராளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர் விமல் வீரவன்சவின் வீட்டின் மீது மாலபே பொலிஸாரால் நேற்று (28) தாக்குதல் நடத்தப்பட்ட சம்பவம் தொடர்பில் ஹோகந்தர பிரதேசத்தைச் சேர்ந்த 37 வயதுடைய நபர் ஒருவர் கைது செய்யப்பட்டுள்ளார்.",
        "பாராளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர் லசந்த அழகியவண்ணவின் வீட்டிற்கு சேதம் விளைவித்தமை தொடர்பில் கைது செய்யப்பட்ட சந்தேகநபர் கிரிதிவெல பிரதேசத்தை சேர்ந்த 43 வயதுடையவர்.",
        "மேல் மாகாண-வடக்கு பிரிவு அதிகாரிகளால் நேற்று (28) கைது செய்யப்பட்டுள்ளார்.",
        "இதேவேளை, பாராளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர் அருந்திக பெர்னாண்டோவின் வீட்டிற்கு சேதம் ஏற்படுத்தியமை தொடர்பில் தங்கொட்டுவ பிரதேசத்தை சேர்ந்த 45 வயதுடைய ஒருவர் தங்கொடுவ பொலிஸாரால் கைது செய்யப்பட்டுள்ளார்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "மூன்று",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "மூன்று",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "மூன்று",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "விமல் வீரவன்ச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "லசந்த அழகியவன்ன",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "அருந்திக பெர்னாண்டோ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "37 வயது",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "விமல் வீரவன்ச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "நேற்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "28",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "லசந்த அழகியவன்ன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "கிரிடிவெல",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "43",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "மேல் மாகாணம்-வடக்கு",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "நேற்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "28",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "45 வயது",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "தங்கொடுவ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "தங்கொடுவ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "அருந்திக பெர்னாண்டோ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}