{
  "newspaper_id": "virakesari-lk",
  "url": "http://www.virakesari.lk/article/132438",
  "time_ut": 1659067895,
  "original_lang": "ta",
  "original_title": "அரசாங்கத்திற்கு இம்முறை ஜெனிவாவில் பாரிய நெருக்கடி ஏற்படும் - பேராசிரியர் ஜி.எல் பீரிஸ்",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "The Government will face a massive crisis this time in Geneva - Professor GL Peiris",
      "author": "T. Saranya",
      "body_lines": [
        "Emergency law, violations of democratic rights will be given special attention during the 51st session of the United Nations Human Rights Council. Sri Lanka Podujana Peramuna is currently acting contrary to the policy and the constitution of the party, said Prof. GL Peiris, Deputy Director of Podujana Peramuna.",
        "He mentioned the above while attending a press conference in Colombo yesterday.",
        "I voted against the Emergency because it would affect the fundamental rights of the people of the country. There is no need to implement emergency law in the current state. Emergency law will call into question human rights.",
        "The Emergency Act has been imposed against the policy of the Sri Lanka Podujana Peramuna and against the party's constitution. Podujana Peramuna is currently acting in an unprincipled manner. Activities contrary to the policy of the party are currently being carried out.",
        "If emergency laws are imposed to suppress democratic people's struggle, the result will be adverse. Emergency law can call into question all other laws except the Constitution. Emergency law also affects human rights.",
        "The international community has paid special attention to Sri Lanka due to the implementation of the emergency law while expecting international assistance while facing a severe economic crisis. All over the world countries and human rights organizations have expressed their strong condemnation of the brutal attack on the empty-faced protestors.",
        "Sri Lanka will definitely face huge challenges during the 51st session of the United Nations Human Rights Council in September. GSP's anti-democratic activities. He said that the provision of plus tax credit has been taken to the point of cancellation."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Geneva",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "GL Peiris",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "the 51st",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the United Nations Human Rights Council",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Podujana Peramuna",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "GL Peiris",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Podujana Peramuna",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Colombo",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "yesterday",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "The Emergency Act",
            "label": "LAW"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "Podujana Peramuna",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Podujana Peramuna",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Constitution",
            "label": "LAW"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the 51st",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the United Nations Human Rights Council",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "September",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "GSP",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "ජිනීවාහිදී රජය මෙවර දැවැන්ත අර්බුදයකට මුහුණ දෙනවා - මහාචාර්ය ජී එල් පීරිස්",
      "author": "T. Saranya",
      "body_lines": [
        "එක්සත් ජාතීන්ගේ මානව හිමිකම් කවුන්සිලයේ 51 වැනි සැසිවාරයේදී හදිසි නීතිය, ප්‍රජාතන්ත්‍රවාදී අයිතීන් උල්ලංඝනය කිරීම් සම්බන්ධයෙන් විශේෂ අවධානයක් යොමු කෙරේ. ශ්‍රී ලංකා පොදුජන පෙරමුණ මේ වන විට පක්ෂයේ ප්‍රතිපත්තියට සහ ව්‍යවස්ථාවට පටහැනිව කටයුතු කරන බව පොදුජන පෙරමුණේ නියෝජ්‍ය අධ්‍යක්ෂ මහාචාර්ය ජී.එල්.",
        "ඔහු මේ බව සඳහන් කළේ ඊයේ කොළඹදී පැවති මාධ්‍ය හමුවකට එක්වෙමින්.",
        "මම හදිසි නීතියට විරුද්ධව ඡන්දය දුන්නේ රටේ ජනතාවගේ මූලික අයිතිවාසිකම්වලට එය බලපාන නිසයි. වත්මන් තත්ත්වය තුළ හදිසි නීතිය ක්‍රියාත්මක කිරීමට අවශ්‍ය නැත.හදිසි නීතිය මානව හිමිකම් ප්‍රශ්න කරනු ඇත.",
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකා පොදුජන පෙරමුණේ ප්‍රතිපත්තියට පටහැනිව සහ පක්ෂ ව්‍යවස්ථාවට පටහැනිව හදිසි නීතිය පනවා තිබේ. පොදුජන පෙරමුණ මේ වන විට ප්‍රතිපත්ති විරහිතව කටයුතු කරනවා. පක්‍ෂයේ ප‍්‍රතිපත්තියට පටහැනි කි‍්‍රයාකාරිත්වයක් මේ වන විට සිදුවෙමින් පවතිනවා.",
        "ප‍්‍රජාතන්ත‍්‍රවාදී ජනතා අරගලය මර්ධනය කිරීමට හදිසි නීති පනවන්නේ නම් එහි ප‍්‍රතිඵලය අයහපත් වනු ඇත. හදිසි නීතිය මගින් ආණ්ඩුක්‍රම ව්‍යවස්ථාව හැර අනෙකුත් සියලුම නීති ප්‍රශ්න කළ හැකිය. හදිසි නීතිය ද මානව හිමිකම්වලට බලපායි.",
        "දැඩි ආර්ථික අර්බුදයකට මුහුණ දී සිටින අතරතුර ජාත්‍යන්තර සහය අපේක්ෂා කරන අතරතුර හදිසි නීතිය ක්‍රියාත්මක කිරීම හේතුවෙන් ශ්‍රී ලංකාව කෙරෙහි ජාත්‍යන්තර ප්‍රජාවගේ විශේෂ අවධානය යොමුව තිබෙනවා. ලොව පුරා රටවල් සහ මානව හිමිකම් සංවිධාන හිස් මුහුණින් විරෝධතාකරුවන්ට එල්ල කරන ලද ම්ලේච්ඡ ප්‍රහාරය දැඩි ලෙස හෙළා දැක තිබේ.",
        "සැප්තැම්බරයේ පැවැත්වෙන එක්සත් ජාතීන්ගේ මානව හිමිකම් කවුන්සිලයේ 51 වැනි සැසියේදී ශ්‍රී ලංකාව නිසැකවම දැවැන්ත අභියෝගවලට මුහුණ දෙනු ඇත.ජීඑස්පී ප්‍රජාතන්ත්‍ර විරෝධී ක්‍රියාකාරකම්. ප්ලස් බදු බැර ලබාදීම අවලංගු කරන තැනට ගෙන ගොස් ඇති බවද ඔහු පැවසීය."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ජිනීවා",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "ජී එල් පීරිස්",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "51 වැනි",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "එක්සත් ජාතීන්ගේ මානව හිමිකම් කවුන්සිලය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "පොදුජන පෙරමුණ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජී එල් පීරිස්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "පොදුජන පෙරමුණ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "කොළඹ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඊයේ",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "හදිසි නීතිය",
            "label": "LAW"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "පොදුජන පෙරමුණ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "පොදුජන පෙරමුණ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ආණ්ඩුක්රම ව්යවස්ථාව",
            "label": "LAW"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "51 වැනි",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "එක්සත් ජාතීන්ගේ මානව හිමිකම් කවුන්සිලය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "සැප්තැම්බර්",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජී.එස්.පී",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "அரசாங்கத்திற்கு இம்முறை ஜெனிவாவில் பாரிய நெருக்கடி ஏற்படும் - பேராசிரியர் ஜி.எல் பீரிஸ்",
      "author": "T. Saranya",
      "body_lines": [
        "அவசரகால சட்டம், ஜனநாயக உரிமை மீறல்கள், குறித்து ஐக்கிய நாடுகள் மனித உரிமை பேரவையின் 51ஆவது கூட்டத்தொடரின் போது விசேட கவனம் செலுத்தப்படும். கொள்கைக்கும்,கட்சியின் அரசியலமைப்பிற்கு முரணாகவே  ஸ்ரீ லங்கா பொதுஜன பெரமுன தற்போது செயற்படுகிறது என பொதுஜன பெரமுனவின் தவிசாளர் பேராசிரியர் ஜி.எல் பீரிஸ் தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "கொழும்பில் நேற்று வியாழக்கிழமை இடம்பெற்ற ஊடகவியலாளர் சந்திப்பில் கலந்துக்கொண்டு கருத்துரைக்கையில் மேற்கண்டவாறு குறிப்பிட்டார்.",
        "நாட்டு மக்களின் அடிப்படை உரிமைகளுக்கு அவசரகால சட்டம் பாதிப்பை ஏற்படுத்தும் என்ற காரணத்தினால் அதற்கு எதிராக வாக்களித்தேன். தற்போதைய நிலையில் அவசரகால சட்டத்தை அமுல்படுத்த வேண்டிய தேவை கிடையாது.அவசரகால சட்டம் மனித உரிமைகளை கேள்விக்குள்ளாக்கும்.",
        "ஸ்ரீ லங்கா பொதுஜன பெரமுனவின் கொள்கைக்கும், கட்சியின் அரசியலமைப்பிற்கு முரணாகவும் அவசர கால சட்டம் அமுல்படுத்தப்பட்டுள்ளது. பொதுஜன பெரமுன தற்போது கொள்கையற்ற வகையில் செயற்படுகிறது. கட்சியின் கொள்கைக்கு முரணான செயற்பாடுகள் தற்போது முன்னெடுக்கப்படுகின்றன.",
        "ஜனநாயக ரீதியிலான மக்கள் போராட்டத்தை முடக்க அவசரகால சட்டத்தை அமுல்படுத்தினால், அதன் பெறுபேறு பாதகமானதாக அமையும். அவசரகால சட்டம் அரசியலமைப்பினை தவிர்த்து ஏனைய சகல சட்டங்களையும் கேள்விக்குள்ளாக்கும். மனித உரிமைக்கும் அவசரகால சட்டம் பாதிப்பை ஏற்படுத்தும்.",
        "பொருளாதார ரீதியில் மோசமான நெருக்கடியினை எதிர்க்கொண்டுள்ள நிலையில் சர்வதேசத்தின் உதவியை எதிர்பார்த்துள்ள போது அவசரகால சட்டத்தை அமுலபடுத்தியுள்ளதால் சர்வதேசம் இலங்கை குறித்து விசேட அவதானம் செலுத்தியுள்ளது. காலி முகத்திடல் போராட்டகாரர்கள் மீது மேற்கொண்ட மிலேட்சத்தனமான தாக்குதலுக்கு முழு உலக நாடுகளும்,மனித உரிமை அமைப்புக்களும் கடும் கண்டனத்தை வெளிப்படுத்தியுள்ளன.",
        "எதிர்வரும் செப்டெம்பர் மாதம் ஐக்கிய நாடுகள் மனித உரிமைகள் பேரவையில் இடம்பெறவுள்ள 51ஆவது கூட்டத்தொடரின் போது இலங்கை பாரிய சவால்களை நிச்சயம் எதிர்கொள்ளும்.ஜனநாயகத்திற்கு முரணான செயற்பாடுகள் ஜி.எஸ்.பி. பிளஸ் வரிச்சலுகை வழங்கலை இரத்து செய்யும் நிலைக்கு கொண்டு சென்றுள்ளது என்றார்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ஜெனீவா",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "ஜி.எல்.பீரிஸ்",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "51வது",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஐக்கிய நாடுகளின் மனித உரிமைகள் பேரவை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "பொதுஜன பெரமுன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜி.எல்.பீரிஸ்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "பொதுஜன பெரமுன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "கொழும்பு",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "நேற்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "அவசர சட்டம்",
            "label": "LAW"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "பொதுஜன பெரமுன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "பொதுஜன பெரமுன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "அரசியலமைப்பு",
            "label": "LAW"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "51வது",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஐக்கிய நாடுகளின் மனித உரிமைகள் பேரவை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "செப்டம்பர்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜி.எஸ்.பி",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}