{
  "newspaper_id": "news-first-lk",
  "url": "https://www.newsfirst.lk/2022/07/26/archaeology-probe-at-presidents-house/",
  "time_ut": 1658821320,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Archaeology probe at President’s House",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Archaeology probe at President’s House",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); The Department of Archaeology said that it will launch an investigation on Wednesday to determine if any damage was caused to the items of archaeological value at the President’s House.",
        "Director General of Archaeology Professor Anura Manatunga speaking to News 1st said that a special team will be assigned for this investigation.",
        "Director General of Archaeology Professor Anura Manatunga said investigations in to the damage caused to the President’s House is yet to be completed, and the damage is yet to be estimated.",
        "Professor Manatunga emphasized that there is no truth to the reports circulating about such damage estimates.",
        "He also noted that the team of officers will conduct an investigation of the President’s House, estimated the damage, and submit a report to the President’s Secretary, Police and other security agencies."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "House",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "News 1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "The Department of Archaeology",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Wednesday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "House",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Anura Manatunga",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "News 1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Anura Manatunga",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "House",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Manatunga",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "House",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "ජනාධිපති මන්දිරයේ පුරාවිද්‍යා පරීක්ෂණයක්",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); ජනාධිපති මන්දිරයේ ඇති පුරාවිද්‍යාත්මක වටිනාකමකින් යුත් භාණ්ඩවලට යම් හානියක් සිදුවී ඇත්දැයි සොයා බැලීම සඳහා බදාදා විමර්ශනයක් ආරම්භ කරන බව පුරාවිද්‍යා දෙපාර්තමේන්තුව පවසයි.",
        "පුරාවිද්‍යා අධ්‍යක්ෂ ජනරාල් මහාචාර්ය අනුර මනතුංග මහතා News 1st වෙත අදහස් දක්වමින් කියා සිටියේ මෙම පරීක්ෂණය සඳහා විශේෂ කණ්ඩායමක් යොදවන බවයි.",
        "පුරාවිද්‍යා අධ්‍යක්ෂ ජනරාල් මහාචාර්ය අනුර මනතුංග මහතා සඳහන් කළේ ජනාධිපති මන්දිරයට සිදුවූ අලාභහානි පිළිබඳ පරීක්ෂණ තවමත් අවසන් වී නොමැති අතර හානිය තක්සේරු කර නොමැති බවයි.",
        "එවැනි හානි ඇස්තමේන්තු සම්බන්ධයෙන් පැතිර යන වාර්තාවල කිසිදු සත්‍යතාවක් නොමැති බව මහාචාර්ය මනතුංග මහතා අවධාරණය කළේය.",
        "එම නිලධාරීන් කණ්ඩායම ජනාධිපති මන්දිරයේ පරීක්ෂණයක් පවත්වා හානිය තක්සේරු කර වාර්තාවක් ජනාධිපති ලේකම්වරයාට, පොලිසියට සහ අනෙකුත් ආරක්ෂක අංශ වෙත ඉදිරිපත් කිරීමට නියමිත බව ද ඔහු සඳහන් කළේය."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "නිවස",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "News 1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "පුරාවිද්‍යා දෙපාර්තමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "බදාදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "නිවස",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "අනුර මනතුංග",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "News 1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "අනුර මනතුංග",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "නිවස",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "මනතුංග ය",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "නිවස",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "ஜனாதிபதி மாளிகையில் தொல்லியல் ஆய்வு",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); ஜனாதிபதி மாளிகையில் உள்ள தொல்பொருள் பெறுமதியான பொருட்களுக்கு ஏதேனும் சேதம் ஏற்பட்டுள்ளதா என்பது தொடர்பில் விசாரணைகளை புதன்கிழமை ஆரம்பிக்கவுள்ளதாக தொல்பொருள் திணைக்களம் தெரிவித்துள்ளது.",
        "இந்த விசாரணைக்காக விசேட குழுவொன்று நியமிக்கப்படும் என தொல்பொருள் பணிப்பாளர் நாயகம் பேராசிரியர் அனுர மானதுங்க நியூஸ் 1ஸ்டிடம் தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "ஜனாதிபதி மாளிகைக்கு ஏற்பட்ட சேதம் தொடர்பான விசாரணைகள் இன்னும் நிறைவடையவில்லை எனவும், சேதம் மதிப்பிடப்படவில்லை எனவும் தொல்பொருள் பணிப்பாளர் நாயகம் பேராசிரியர் அனுர மனதுங்க தெரிவித்துள்ளார்.",
        "இத்தகைய சேத மதிப்பீடுகள் குறித்து பரப்பப்படும் செய்திகளில் எந்த உண்மையும் இல்லை என்று பேராசிரியர் மனதுங்க வலியுறுத்தினார்.",
        "அதிகாரிகள் குழு ஜனாதிபதி மாளிகையில் விசாரணை நடத்தி, சேதத்தை மதிப்பிட்டு, ஜனாதிபதியின் செயலாளர், காவல்துறை மற்றும் பிற பாதுகாப்பு நிறுவனங்களுக்கு அறிக்கையை சமர்ப்பிக்கும் என்றும் அவர் குறிப்பிட்டார்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "வீடு",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "News 1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "தொல்லியல் துறை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "புதன்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "வீடு",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "அனுர மனதுங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "News 1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "அனுர மனதுங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "வீடு",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "மனதுங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "வீடு",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}