{
  "newspaper_id": "daily-mirror-lk",
  "url": "https://www.dailymirror.lk/breaking_news/Its-time-to-show-SL-bowlers-batters-who-they-are-Mahela/108-244119",
  "time_ut": 1662008467,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "It’s time to show SL bowlers, batters who they are: Mahela",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "It’s time to show SL bowlers, batters who they are: Mahela",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "Former Sri Lankan skipper Mahela Jayawardene said that it’s time for Sri Lanka bowlers to show the class and batters to show who they are on the field, ahead of the T-20 match between Sri Lanka and Bangladesh at the Asia Cup today.",
        "He made these remarks on Tweeter in response to a comment made by Bangladesh Coach Khaled Mahmud.",
        "Responding to a statement made by Sri Lanka captain Dasun Shanaka that Bangladesh has only two world class bowlers compared to Afghanistan, Bangladesh Coach Khaled Mahmud said yesterday that he doesn’t think Sri Lanka has any world class bowlers.",
        "“I don’t know why Dasun Shanaka said such a thing. I heard that he said Bangladesh does not have world class bowlers except Shakib Al Hassan and Mustafizur. In fact, I do not see a single world class bowler in the Sri Lankan camp,” Mahmud said during a press conference on yesterday.",
        "He said at least Bangladesh have two world class bowlers. “But Sri Lanka does not even have anyone who bears the quality of Shakib and Mustafizur in their side,” Mahmud added.",
        "“Looks like it’s time for Sri Lanka's bowlers to show the class and batters to show who they are on the field,\" Mahela tweeted."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Mahela",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Mahela Jayawardene",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "T-20",
            "label": "PRODUCT"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Bangladesh",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Asia Cup",
            "label": "EVENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Khaled Mahmud",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Dasun Shanaka",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Bangladesh",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "two",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Afghanistan",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Khaled Mahmud",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "yesterday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Dasun Shanaka",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Al Hassan",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Mustafizur",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lankan",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "Mahmud",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "yesterday",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "two",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "Mustafizur",
            "label": "PRODUCT"
          },
          {
            "text": "Mahmud",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka's",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Mahela",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "ශ්‍රී ලංකා පන්දු යවන්නන්ට, පිතිකරුවන්ට ඔවුන් කවුදැයි පෙන්වීමට කාලයයි මේ: මහේල",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකාව සහ බංග්ලාදේශය අතර අද පැවැත්වෙන ආසියානු කුසලාන පන්දුවාර විස්සයි විස්ස තරඟයට පෙර ශ්‍රී ලංකා පන්දු යවන්නන්ට තමන් පිටියේ සිටින්නේ කවුරුන්ද යන්න පෙන්වීමට ශ්‍රී ලංකා පන්දු යවන්නන්ට පන්තිය සහ පිතිකරුවන් පෙන්වීමට කාලය එළඹ ඇති බව හිටපු ශ්‍රී ලංකා නායක මහේල ජයවර්ධන ප්‍රකාශ කළා.",
        "ඔහු මෙම අදහස් පළ කළේ බංගලාදේශ පුහුණුකරු Khaled Mahmud විසින් කරන ලද අදහසකට ප්‍රතිචාර දක්වමින් Tweeter හි ය.",
        "ඇෆ්ගනිස්ථානයට සාපේක්ෂව බංගලාදේශයට සිටින්නේ ලෝක මට්ටමේ පන්දු යවන්නන් දෙදෙනෙක් පමණක් බවට ශ්‍රී ලංකා නායක දසුන් ශානක කළ ප්‍රකාශයකට පිළිතුරු දෙමින් බංග්ලාදේශ පුහුණුකරු කලීඩ් මහමුද් ඊයේ ප්‍රකාශ කළේ ශ්‍රී ලංකාවට ලෝක මට්ටමේ පන්දු යවන්නන් ඇතැයි තමන් නොසිතන බවයි.",
        "“දසුන් ශානක එහෙම දෙයක් කිව්වේ ඇයි කියලා මම දන්නේ නැහැ. ශකීබ් අල් හසන් සහ මුස්තාෆිසුර් හැර බංග්ලාදේශයට ලෝක මට්ටමේ පන්දු යවන්නන් නොමැති බව ඔහු පැවසූ බව මට ආරංචි විය. ඇත්ත වශයෙන්ම, මම ශ්‍රී ලංකා කඳවුරේ එකම ලෝක මට්ටමේ පන්දු යවන්නෙකුවත් දකින්නේ නැහැ, ”මහමුද් ඊයේ පැවති මාධ්‍ය හමුවකදී පැවසීය.",
        "අවම වශයෙන් බංග්ලාදේශයට ලෝක මට්ටමේ පන්දු යවන්නන් දෙදෙනෙකු සිටින බව ඔහු පැවසීය. \"නමුත් ශකීබ්ගේ සහ මුස්තාෆිසුර්ගේ ගුණය උසුලන කිසිවෙක් ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ ඔවුන්ගේ පැත්තේවත් නැත,\" මහමුද් වැඩිදුරටත් පැවසීය.",
        "“ශ්‍රී ලංකා පන්දු යවන්නන්ට පන්තිය පෙන්වීමට සහ පිතිකරුවන් පිටියේ සිටින අය කවුරුන්ද යන්න පෙන්වීමට කාලය පැමිණ ඇති බව පෙනේ,” මහේල ට්විටර් පණිවුඩයක් නිකුත් කළේය."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "මහේල",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "මහේල ජයවර්ධන",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "T-20",
            "label": "PRODUCT"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "බංග්ලාදේශය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ආසියානු කුසලානය",
            "label": "EVENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "කලීඩ් මහමුද්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "දසුන් ශානක",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "බංග්ලාදේශය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "දෙක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඇෆ්ගනිස්ථානය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "කලීඩ් මහමුද්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඊයේ",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "දසුන් ශානක",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "අල් හසන්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "මුස්තාෆිසුර්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලාංකික",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "මහමුද්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඊයේ",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "දෙක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "මුස්තාෆිසුර්",
            "label": "PRODUCT"
          },
          {
            "text": "මහමුද්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මහේල",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "SL பந்து வீச்சாளர்கள், பேட்டர்கள் யார் என்பதை காட்ட வேண்டிய நேரம் இது: மஹேல",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "ஆசியக் கோப்பையில் இன்று நடைபெறவுள்ள இலங்கை மற்றும் பங்களாதேஷ் அணிகளுக்கு இடையிலான T-20 போட்டிக்கு முன்னதாக, இலங்கை பந்துவீச்சாளர்கள் தாங்கள் யார் களத்தில் இருக்கிறோம் என்பதைக் காட்ட, துடுப்பாட்ட வீரர்களைக் காட்ட வேண்டிய நேரம் இது என இலங்கை அணியின் முன்னாள் தலைவர் மஹேல ஜெயவர்தன தெரிவித்துள்ளார்.",
        "பங்களாதேஷ் பயிற்சியாளர் காலித் மஹ்மூத் தெரிவித்த கருத்துக்கு பதிலளிக்கும் வகையில் அவர் ட்வீட்டரில் இந்த கருத்துக்களை தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "ஆப்கானிஸ்தானை விட பங்களாதேஷில் இரண்டு உலகத்தரம் வாய்ந்த பந்துவீச்சாளர்கள் மட்டுமே உள்ளனர் என இலங்கை அணித்தலைவர் தசுன் ஷனக தெரிவித்த கருத்துக்கு பதிலளித்த பங்களாதேஷ் பயிற்சியாளர் காலித் மஹ்மூத், இலங்கையில் உலகத்தரம் வாய்ந்த பந்துவீச்சாளர்கள் இருப்பதாக தாம் நினைக்கவில்லை என நேற்று தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "“தசுன் ஷனக ஏன் அப்படிச் சொன்னார் என்று எனக்குத் தெரியவில்லை. வங்கதேசத்தில் ஷகிப் அல் ஹசன் மற்றும் முஸ்தாபிசூர் தவிர உலகத்தரம் வாய்ந்த பந்துவீச்சாளர்கள் இல்லை என்று அவர் கூறியதாக கேள்விப்பட்டேன். உண்மையில், இலங்கை முகாமில் உலகத்தரம் வாய்ந்த ஒரு பந்து வீச்சாளரையும் நான் காணவில்லை” என நேற்றைய செய்தியாளர் சந்திப்பின் போது மஹ்மூத் கூறினார்.",
        "பங்களாதேஷில் குறைந்தபட்சம் இரண்டு உலகத்தரம் வாய்ந்த பந்துவீச்சாளர்கள் உள்ளனர் என்றார். \"ஆனால் இலங்கையில் ஷகிப் மற்றும் முஸ்தாபிசூரின் தரத்தை தாங்கிய எவரும் தங்கள் தரப்பில் இல்லை\" என்று மஹ்மூத் மேலும் கூறினார்.",
        "\"இலங்கையின் பந்துவீச்சாளர்கள் அவர்கள் களத்தில் யார் என்பதைக் காட்டுவதற்கு கிளாஸ் மற்றும் பேட்டர்களைக் காட்ட வேண்டிய நேரம் இது போல் தெரிகிறது\" என்று மஹேல ட்வீட் செய்துள்ளார்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "மஹேல",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "மஹேல ஜயவர்தன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "டி-20",
            "label": "PRODUCT"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "பங்களாதேஷ்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆசிய கோப்பை",
            "label": "EVENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "கலீத் மஹ்மூத்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "தசுன் ஷனக",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "பங்களாதேஷ்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இரண்டு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆப்கானிஸ்தான்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "கலீத் மஹ்மூத்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "நேற்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "தசுன் ஷனக",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "அல் ஹசன்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "முஸ்தாபிஸூர்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "மஹ்மூத்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "நேற்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இரண்டு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "முஸ்தாபிஸூர்",
            "label": "PRODUCT"
          },
          {
            "text": "மஹ்மூத்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கையின்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "மஹேல",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}