{
  "newspaper_id": "ada-derana-lk",
  "url": "http://www.adaderana.lk/news/83573/special-party-leaders-meeting-to-be-held-today",
  "time_ut": 1657510620,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Special party leaders’ meeting to be held today",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Special party leaders’ meeting to be held today",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "A special meeting of the party leaders has been called today (11) to discuss the future political affairs of the country.",
        "The Communications Department of Parliament stated that the party leaders’ meeting chaired by Speaker Mahinda Yapa Abeywardena will be held today at 2.00 pm.",
        "The appointment of a new President and the formation of a new government after Gotabaya Rajapaksa steps down from the presidency on the 13th of July are scheduled to be discussed at today’s meeting.",
        "It is reported that final agreements are expected to be reached regarding the next steps.",
        "Meanwhile, political sources reveal that several special discussions are planned to be held today between the main political parties regarding the current situation in the country.",
        "Justice Minister Wijedasa Rajapaksa stated that a general consensus should be reached in the party leaders’ meeting on the formation of a new government under a practical system.",
        "Former Member of Parliament D.E.W. Gunasekara points out that there is a need for the Speaker to act as Acting President until a new government is established.",
        "Member of Parliament of the National People’s Power, Dr. Harini Amarasuriya said that in view of the current situation, a short-term interim government that can achieve the goals of the people’s struggle (Aragalaya) should be appointed immediately."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "today",
          "label": "DATE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "11",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "The Communications Department of Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Mahinda Yapa Abeywardena",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "2.00 pm",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Gotabaya Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the 13th of July",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Justice",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Wijedasa Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Parliament D.E.W. Gunasekara",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Parliament of the National People’s Power",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Harini Amarasuriya",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "විශේෂ පක්ෂ නායක රැස්වීමක් අද පැවැත්වෙනවා",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "රටේ ඉදිරි දේශපාලන කටයුතු පිළිබඳව සාකච්ඡා කිරීම සඳහා විශේෂ පක්ෂ නායක රැස්වීමක් අද (11) කැඳවා තිබේ.",
        "කථානායක මහින්ද යාපා අබේවර්ධන මහතාගේ ප්‍රධානත්වයෙන් පක්ෂ නායක රැස්වීම අද පස්වරු 2.00ට පැවැත්වෙන බව පාර්ලිමේන්තුවේ සන්නිවේදන දෙපාර්තමේන්තුව ප්‍රකාශ කළා.",
        "ජුලි 13 වැනිදා ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ මහතා ජනාධිපති ධුරයෙන් ඉල්ලා අස්වීමෙන් පසු නව ජනාධිපතිවරයෙකු පත් කිරීම සහ නව රජයක් පිහිටුවීම පිළිබඳව අද දිනයේ දී සාකච්ඡා කිරීමට නියමිතයි.",
        "ඉදිරි පියවර සම්බන්ධයෙන් අවසන් එකඟතාවන්ට පැමිණීමට බලාපොරොත්තු වන බව වාර්තා වේ.",
        "මේ අතර රටේ වත්මන් තත්ත්වය සම්බන්ධයෙන් ප්‍රධාන දේශපාලන පක්ෂ අතර විශේෂ සාකච්ඡා කිහිපයක් අද පැවැත්වීමට සැලසුම් කර ඇති බව දේශපාලන ආරංචි මාර්ග අනාවරණය කරයි.",
        "ප්‍රායෝගික ක්‍රමවේදයක් යටතේ නව ආණ්ඩුවක් පිහිටුවීම සම්බන්ධයෙන් පක්ෂ නායක රැස්වීමේදී පොදු එකඟතාවකට පැමිණිය යුතු බව අධිකරණ අමාත්‍ය විජේදාස රාජපක්ෂ ප්‍රකාශ කළා.",
        "හිටපු පාර්ලිමේන්තු මන්ත්‍රී ඩී.ඊ.ඩබ්ලිව්. ගුණසේකර පෙන්වා දෙන්නේ නව රජයක් පිහිටුවන තුරු වැඩබලන ජනාධිපතිවරයා ලෙස කථානායකවරයා කටයුතු කිරීමේ අවශ්‍යතාවය මතුව ඇති බවයි.",
        "පවතින තත්ත්වය හමුවේ ජන අරගලයේ (අරගලය) ඉලක්ක සපුරාගත හැකි කෙටිකාලීන අන්තර්වාර ආණ්ඩුවක් වහා පත් කළ යුතු බව ජාතික ජන බලවේගයේ පාර්ලිමේන්තු මන්ත්‍රී ආචාර්ය හරිනි අමරසූරිය මහත්මිය පැවසුවාය."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "අද",
          "label": "DATE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "11",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුවේ සන්නිවේදන දෙපාර්තමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "මහින්ද යාපා අබේවර්ධන",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "2.00 ප.ව",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජූලි 13 වෙනිදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "යුක්තිය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "විජේදාස රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තු ඩී.ඊ.ඩබ්ලිව්. ගුණසේකර",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ජාතික ජන බලය පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "හරිනි අමරසූරිය",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "கட்சித் தலைவர்களின் விசேட கூட்டம் இன்று இடம்பெறவுள்ளது",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "நாட்டின் எதிர்கால அரசியல் விவகாரங்கள் தொடர்பில் கலந்துரையாடுவதற்காக இன்று (11) கட்சித் தலைவர்களின் விசேட கூட்டமொன்றுக்கு அழைப்பு விடுக்கப்பட்டுள்ளது.",
        "சபாநாயகர் மஹிந்த யாப்பா அபேவர்தன தலைமையில் கட்சித் தலைவர்கள் கூட்டம் இன்று பிற்பகல் 2.00 மணிக்கு இடம்பெறவுள்ளதாக பாராளுமன்ற தகவல் தொடர்பாடல் திணைக்களம் தெரிவித்துள்ளது.",
        "எதிர்வரும் ஜூலை மாதம் 13ஆம் திகதி ஜனாதிபதி பதவியிலிருந்து கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ச விலகியதன் பின்னர் புதிய ஜனாதிபதியை நியமிப்பது மற்றும் புதிய அரசாங்கத்தை அமைப்பது தொடர்பில் இன்றைய கூட்டத்தில் கலந்துரையாடப்படவுள்ளது.",
        "அடுத்த கட்ட நடவடிக்கைகள் குறித்து இறுதி உடன்பாடுகள் எட்டப்படும் என எதிர்பார்க்கப்படுவதாகத் தெரிவிக்கப்படுகிறது.",
        "இதேவேளை, நாட்டின் தற்போதைய நிலைமை தொடர்பில் பிரதான அரசியல் கட்சிகளுக்கிடையில் இன்று விசேட கலந்துரையாடல் ஒன்று இடம்பெறவுள்ளதாக அரசியல் வட்டாரங்கள் தெரிவிக்கின்றன.",
        "நடைமுறை முறைமையின் கீழ் புதிய அரசாங்கத்தை அமைப்பது தொடர்பில் கட்சித் தலைவர்கள் கூட்டத்தில் பொது இணக்கப்பாடு எட்டப்பட வேண்டுமென நீதி அமைச்சர் விஜேதாச ராஜபக்ஷ தெரிவித்துள்ளார்.",
        "முன்னாள் நாடாளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர் டி.இ.டபிள்யூ. புதிய அரசாங்கம் அமைக்கப்படும் வரை சபாநாயகர் பதில் ஜனாதிபதியாக செயற்பட வேண்டிய தேவை ஏற்பட்டுள்ளதாக குணசேகர சுட்டிக்காட்டியுள்ளார்.",
        "தற்போதைய நிலவரத்தை கருத்தில் கொண்டு மக்கள் போராட்டத்தின் (அறகலய) இலக்குகளை அடையக்கூடிய குறுகிய கால இடைக்கால அரசாங்கம் உடனடியாக நியமிக்கப்பட வேண்டும் என தேசிய மக்கள் சக்தியின் பாராளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர் கலாநிதி ஹரிணி அமரசூரிய தெரிவித்தார்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "இன்று",
          "label": "DATE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "11",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றத்தின் தகவல் தொடர்பு துறை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "மஹிந்த யாப்பா அபேவர்தன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "மதியம் 2.00 மணி",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜூலை 13 ஆம் தேதி",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "நீதி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "விஜேதாச ராஜபக்ஷ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்ற டி.இ.டபிள்யூ. குணசேகரன்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "தேசிய மக்கள் சக்தியின் பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஹரிணி அமரசூரிய",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}