{
  "newspaper_id": "ada-derana-lk",
  "url": "http://www.adaderana.lk/news/84360/passenger-duty-free-shop-staffer-held-with-95-kg-of-gold-bars",
  "time_ut": 1660732260,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Passenger, Duty Free shop staffer held with 9.5 kg of gold bars",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Passenger, Duty Free shop staffer held with 9.5 kg of gold bars",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "Two suspects including an airline passenger and a female staff member of a Duty Free shop have been arrested at the Katunayake Airport while attempting to smuggle 9.5 kg of gold biscuits worth over Rs. 200 million into the country.",
        "Sri Lanka Customs said a passenger who had arrived from Dubai by the flight EK650 and a female staff member of a Duty Free shop at the airport have been taken into custody.",
        "The detection and the investigation are carried out by the officers attached to Narcotics Control Unit of Sri Lanka Customs at the airport.",
        "Around 80 gold biscuits were found in the possession of the suspects while the total value of the gold taken into custody is estimated at Rs. 205 million."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Duty Free",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "9.5 kg",
          "label": "QUANTITY"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Two",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Duty Free",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Katunayake Airport",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "200 million",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka Customs",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Dubai",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "EK650",
            "label": "PRODUCT"
          },
          {
            "text": "Duty Free",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Narcotics Control Unit of Sri Lanka Customs",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "80",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "205 million",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "මගී, තීරුබදු රහිත සාප්පු සේවකයා රත්‍රං පොලු කිලෝග්‍රෑම් 9.5ක් සමඟ අත්අඩංගුවට ගෙන ඇත",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "රුපියල් කෝටියකට අධික වටිනාකමකින් යුත් රන් බිස්කට් කිලෝග්‍රෑම් 9.5ක් නීතිවිරෝධී ලෙස රැගෙන යාමට උත්සාහ කළ ගුවන් මගියකු සහ තීරු බදු රහිත සාප්පුවක සේවක සේවිකාවක් ඇතුළු සැකකරුවන් දෙදෙනෙකු කටුනායක ගුවන් තොටුපළේදී අත්අඩංගුවට ගෙන තිබේ. මිලියන 200ක් රටට.",
        "EK650 දරණ ගුවන් යානයෙන් ඩුබායි සිට පැමිණි මගියෙකු සහ ගුවන් තොටුපළේ තීරු බදු රහිත සාප්පුවක සේවක සේවිකාවක් මෙලෙස අත්අඩංගුවට ගෙන ඇති බව ශ්‍රී ලංකා රේගුව පවසයි.",
        "ගුවන් තොටුපළේ ශ්‍රී ලංකා රේගුවේ මත්ද්‍රව්‍ය පාලන ඒකකයට අනුයුක්ත නිලධාරීන් විසින් අනාවරණය කර ගැනීම සහ විමර්ශනය සිදු කරනු ලබයි.",
        "සැකකරුවන් සන්තකයේ තිබී රන් බිස්කට් 80ක් පමණ සොයාගෙන ඇති අතර අත්අඩංගුවට ගත් රත්‍රංවල මුළු වටිනාකම රු. මිලියන 205 කි."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "තිරබදු රහිත",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "කිලෝ ග්රෑම් 9.5 කි",
          "label": "QUANTITY"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "දෙක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "තිරබදු රහිත",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "කටුනායක ගුවන් තොටුපළ",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "මිලියන 200 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකා රේගුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඩුබායි",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "EK650",
            "label": "PRODUCT"
          },
          {
            "text": "තිරබදු රහිත",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකා රේගුවේ මත්ද්‍රව්‍ය පාලන ඒකකය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "80",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "මිලියන 205 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "9.5 கிலோ தங்கக் கட்டிகளுடன் பயணி, டூட்டி ஃப்ரீ ஷாப் ஊழியர் கைது செய்யப்பட்டார்",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "9.5 கிலோ கிராம் தங்க பிஸ்கட்டுகளை கடத்திச் செல்ல முற்பட்ட வேளையில், விமானப் பயணி மற்றும் கடமையில்லா கடையின் பெண் ஊழியர் உட்பட இருவர் கட்டுநாயக்க விமான நிலையத்தில் வைத்து கைது செய்யப்பட்டுள்ளனர். நாட்டிற்கு 200 மில்லியன்.",
        "டுபாயில் இருந்து EK650 என்ற விமானத்தில் வந்த பயணி ஒருவரும், விமான நிலையத்தில் உள்ள டியூட்டி ஃப்ரீ கடையின் பெண் ஊழியர் ஒருவரும் கைது செய்யப்பட்டுள்ளதாக இலங்கை சுங்கத்துறை தெரிவித்துள்ளது.",
        "விமான நிலையத்தில் உள்ள இலங்கை சுங்கத்தின் போதைப்பொருள் கட்டுப்பாட்டுப் பிரிவின் அதிகாரிகளால் கண்டறிதல் மற்றும் விசாரணைகள் மேற்கொள்ளப்படுகின்றன.",
        "சந்தேகநபர்களிடம் இருந்து சுமார் 80 தங்க பிஸ்கட்டுகள் கண்டுபிடிக்கப்பட்டுள்ளதுடன், கைது செய்யப்பட்ட தங்கத்தின் மொத்த மதிப்பு ரூ. 205 மில்லியன்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "டூட்டி ஃப்ரீ",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "9.5 கிலோ",
          "label": "QUANTITY"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "இரண்டு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "டூட்டி ஃப்ரீ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "கட்டுநாயக்க விமான நிலையம்",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "200 மில்லியன்",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை சுங்கம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "துபாய்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "EK650",
            "label": "PRODUCT"
          },
          {
            "text": "டூட்டி ஃப்ரீ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை சுங்கத்தின் போதைப்பொருள் கட்டுப்பாட்டு பிரிவு",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "80",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "205 மில்லியன்",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}