{
  "newspaper_id": "virakesari-lk",
  "url": "http://www.virakesari.lk/article/131907",
  "time_ut": 1658334450,
  "original_lang": "ta",
  "original_title": "சிரேஷ்ட பிரதிப் பொலிஸ் மா அதிபர் தேசபந்து குறித்த வழக்கு ஒத்திவைப்பு",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Adjournment of the case against Senior Deputy Inspector General of Police Deshabandhu",
      "author": "T Yuwaraj",
      "body_lines": [
        "The report of the investigation regarding Senior Deputy Inspector General of Police Deshabandhu Tennakone has been handed over to the Attorney General for alleged dereliction of duty during the outrageous attacks by government supporters on Maina Ko Kama and Kota Ko Kama.",
        "Today (20) informed Fort Justice Dilina Kamage that they have handed over the report of the investigation done so far to the Attorney General.",
        "The cases related to the outrageous attacks on Maina Ko Kama, Kota Ko Kama by government supporters came up for hearing today in the presence of Fort Justice Dilina Gamage. Meanwhile, the CIT informed the judge.",
        "When the case came up for hearing today, the CIT presented one person as the 36th suspect in the case.",
        "The suspect himself was accused of organizing a pro-Mahinda Rajapaksa rally at Alari House, where he eventually incited the crowd to move to Kota Goma and Maina Go Goma.",
        "Justice Dilina Gamage inquired from the CIT about Senior Deputy Inspector General of Police Deshabandhu Tennakone in response to the request made by the President's lawyer Maithiri Gunaratne who appeared in the forum on behalf of the affected parties.",
        "At the same time, the CID replied that the investigation report on him has been handed over to the Attorney General. In this case, the said case was adjourned till the coming 3rd of August."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Deshabandhu Tennakone",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Maina Ko Kama",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kota Ko Kama",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Today",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "20",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Fort Justice",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "Dilina Kamage",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Maina Ko Kama",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kota Ko Kama",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Fort Justice",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "Dilina Gamage",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "CIT",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "CIT",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "one",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "36th",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "pro-Mahinda",
            "label": "EVENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Alari House",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kota Goma",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Maina Go Goma",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Dilina Gamage",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "CIT",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Deshabandhu Tennakone",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Maithiri Gunaratne",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "CID",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "August",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "ජ්‍යෙෂ්ඨ නියෝජ්‍ය පොලිස්පති දේශබන්ධුට එරෙහි නඩුව කල් තැබීම",
      "author": "ටී යුවරාජ්",
      "body_lines": [
        "මයිනා කෝ කමට සහ කොටා කෝ කමට රජයේ ආධාරකරුවන් කළ සාහසික ප්‍රහාරවලදී රාජකාරි පැහැර හැරීම සම්බන්ධයෙන් ජ්‍යෙෂ්ඨ නියෝජ්‍ය පොලිස්පති දේශබන්ධු තෙන්නකෝන් සම්බන්ධයෙන් සිදුකළ විමර්ශන වාර්තාව නීතිපතිවරයා වෙත භාරදී තිබෙනවා.",
        "මෙතෙක් සිදුකළ විමර්ශන වාර්තාව නීතිපතිවරයා වෙත භාරදුන් බව අද (20) කොටුව විනිසුරු දිලින කමගේට දැනුම් දුන්නා.",
        "මයිනා කෝ කමා, කොට කෝ කාමා යන අයට රජයේ ආධාරකරුවන් විසින් එල්ල කරන ලද සාහසික ප්‍රහාරවලට අදාළ නඩු අද කොටුව විනිසුරු දිලින ගමගේ මහතා ඉදිරියේ විභාගයට ගැනිණි. මේ අතර CIT විනිසුරුවරයාට දන්වා සිටියේය.",
        "මෙම නඩුව අද විභාගයට ගත් අවස්ථාවේදී අපරාධ පරීක්ෂණ දෙපාර්තමේන්තුව විසින් නඩුවේ 36 වැනි සැකකරු ලෙස එක් පුද්ගලයෙකු ඉදිරිපත් කළා.",
        "මහින්ද රාජපක්ෂට හිතවත් අලරි මන්දිරයේ රැස්වීමක් සංවිධානය කළ බවට සැකකරුටම චෝදනා එල්ල වූ අතර එහිදී ඔහු කොට ගෝම සහ මයිනා ගෝම වෙත යාමට සෙනඟ උසිගන්වන ලදී.",
        "විපතට පත් පාර්ශ්ව වෙනුවෙන් එම සංසදයේ පෙනී සිටි ජනාධිපති නීතිඥ මෛත්‍රී ගුණරත්න මහතා කළ ඉල්ලීමට ප්‍රතිචාර දක්වමින් විනිසුරු දිලින ගමගේ මහතා ජ්‍යෙෂ්ඨ නියෝජ්‍ය පොලිස්පති දේශබන්ධු තෙන්නකෝන් මහතා සම්බන්ධයෙන් අපරාධ පරීක්ෂණ දෙපාර්තමේන්තුවෙන් විමසා සිටියේය.",
        "ඒ සමගම අපරාධ පරීක්ෂණ දෙපාර්තමේන්තුව පිළිතුරු දුන්නේ ඔහු පිළිබඳ විමර්ශන වාර්තාව නීතිපතිවරයා වෙත භාරදී ඇති බවයි. මෙම නඩුවේදී එම නඩුව ලබන අගෝස්තු 3 වැනිදාට කල් තැබිණි."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Deshabandhu Tennakone",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "මයිනා කෝ කාමා",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "කොට කෝ කාමා",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "20",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "කොටුව යුක්තිය",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "Dilina Kamage",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "මයිනා කෝ කාමා",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "කොට කෝ කාමා",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "කොටුව යුක්තිය",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "දිලින ගමගේ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "CIT",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "CIT",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "එක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "36 වැනි",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "මහින්ද හිතවාදී",
            "label": "EVENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "අලාරි නිවස",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "කොට ගෝමා",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Maina Go Goma",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "දිලින ගමගේ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "CIT",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Deshabandhu Tennakone",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "මෛත්‍රී ගුණරත්න",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "CID",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "අගෝස්තු",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "சிரேஷ்ட பிரதிப் பொலிஸ் மா அதிபர் தேசபந்து குறித்த வழக்கு ஒத்திவைப்பு",
      "author": "T Yuwaraj",
      "body_lines": [
        "மைனா கோ கம, கோட்டா கோ கம மீதான அரசாங்க ஆதரவாளர்களின் அத்துமீறிய தாக்குதல்களின் போது, கடமை தவறியதாக கூறி  சிரேஷ்ட பிரதிப் பொலிஸ் மா அதிபர் தேசபந்து தென்னகோன் தொடர்பில் இடம்பெற்ற விசாரணை அறிக்கை சட்ட மா அதிபருக்கு  கையளிக்கப்பட்டுள்ளது.",
        "சி.ஐ.டி.யினர்  இதுவரை செய்த விசாரணையின் அறிக்கையை இவ்வாறு  சட்ட மா அதிபருக்கு கையளித்துள்ளதாக,  கோட்டை நீதிவான் திலின கமகேவுக்கு இன்று ( 20) அறிவித்தனர்.",
        "மைனா கோ கம,கோட்டா கோ கம மீதான அரசாங்க ஆதரவாளர்களின் அத்துமீறிய தாக்குதல்கள் தொடர்பிலான  வழக்கு விசாரணைகள் இன்று கோட்டை நீதிவான் திலின கமகே முன்னிலையில்  விசாரணைக்கு வந்தது. இதன்போதே சி.ஐ.டி.யினர் இதனை நீதிவானுக்கு அறிவித்தனர்.",
        "இன்று வழக்கு விசாரணைக்கு வந்த போது, வழக்கின் 36 ஆவது சந்தேக நபராக ஒருவரை சி.ஐ.டி.யினர் மன்றில் ஆஜர் செய்தனர்.",
        "குறித்த சந்தேக நபரே அலரி  மாளிகையில் நடந்த, மஹிந்த ராஜபக்ஷவுக்கு சார்பான கூட்டத்தை தொகுத்தளித்ததாகவும், அவர் இறுதியில் கோட்டா கோம, மற்றும் மைனா கோ கம நோக்கி செல்ல அங்கு திரண்டவர்களை தூண்டியதாகவும் குற்றம் சுமத்தப்பட்டது.",
        "இந் நிலையில் பாதிக்கப்பட்ட தரப்பினர் சார்பில் மன்றில் ஆஜரான ஜனாதிபதி சட்டடத்தரணி  மைத்திரி குணரத்ன முன் வைத்த கோரிக்கைக்கு அமைய,  சிரேஷ்ட பிரதிப் பொலிஸ்  மா அதிபர் தேசபந்து தென்னகோன் தொடர்பில் நீதிவான் திலின கமகே சி.ஐ.டி.யினரிடம் வினவினார்.",
        "இதன்போதே, அவர் குறித்த விசாரணை அறிக்கை  சட்ட மா அதிபருக்கு கையளிக்கப்பட்டுள்ளதாக சி.ஐ.டி.யினர் பதிலளித்தனர்.  இந் நிலையில் குறித்த வழக்கானது எதிர்வரும் ஆகஸ்ட் 3 ஆம் திகதிவரை ஒத்தி வைக்கப்பட்டது."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Deshabandhu Tennakone",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "மைனா கோ காமா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "கோட்டா கோ காமா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "20",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "கோட்டை நீதி",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "Dilina Kamage",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "மைனா கோ காமா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "கோட்டா கோ காமா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "கோட்டை நீதி",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "திலின கமகே",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "சிஐடி",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சிஐடி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஒன்று",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "36வது",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "மஹிந்த ஆதரவு",
            "label": "EVENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "ராஜபக்சே",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "அலரி மாளிகை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "கோட்டா கோமா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Maina Go Goma",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "திலின கமகே",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "சிஐடி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Deshabandhu Tennakone",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "மைத்திரி குணரத்ன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "சி.ஐ.டி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆகஸ்ட்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}