{
  "newspaper_id": "economy-next-com",
  "url": "https://economynext.com/sri-lankas-novice-mps-apply-for-personal-firearm-report-96440/",
  "time_ut": 1656149640,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Sri Lanka’s novice MPs apply for personal firearm: report",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Sri Lanka’s novice MPs apply for personal firearm: report",
      "author": "",
      "body_lines": [
        "ECONOMYNEXT – Some 15 newcomer MPs in Sri Lanka have applied for a personal firearm, the weekly Sunday Lankadeepa reported.",
        "These new MPs, who hadn’t voluntarily obtained a firearm, have applied for a pistol taking into consideration the “prevailing situation”, the privately owned weekly newspaper reported in its June 26 edition citing parliamentary sources.",
        "According to the report, the Members’ Service Office has already issued the relevant application forms which, once filled, will be directed to the Ministry of Defence that is supposed to release the weapons.",
        "On May 09, the private residences and offices of several MPs – most of whom were government members – were torched by angry mobs in a nationwide wave of retaliatory violence after supporters of then Prime Minister Mahinda Rajapaksa launched an unprovoked attack on peaceful protestors gathered outside his official residence Temple Trees in Colombo.",
        "One government MP, Amarakeerthi Athukorala, was killed by a mob on his way back from Colombo that afternoon. (Colombo/Jun25/2022)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Sri Lanka’s",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "weekly",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sunday Lankadeepa",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "weekly",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "June 26",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the Members’ Service Office",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Ministry of Defence",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "May 09",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Mahinda Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Temple Trees in Colombo",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "One",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Amarakeerthi Athukorala",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "afternoon",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "Colombo/Jun25/2022",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ නවක මන්ත්‍රීවරුන් පුද්ගලික ගිනි අවියක් සඳහා ඉල්ලුම් කරයි: වාර්තාව",
      "author": "",
      "body_lines": [
        "ECONOMYNEXT - ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ නවක මන්ත්‍රීවරුන් 15 දෙනෙකු පමණ පුද්ගලික ගිනි අවියක් සඳහා ඉල්ලුම් කර ඇති බව සතිපතා ඉරිදා ලංකාදීප වාර්තා කරයි.",
        "ස්වේච්ඡාවෙන් ගිනි අවියක් ලබා නොගත් මෙම නවක මන්ත්‍රීවරුන් \"පවතින තත්ත්වය\" සැලකිල්ලට ගනිමින් පිස්තෝලයක් සඳහා ඉල්ලුම් කර ඇති බව පුද්ගලික හිමිකාරීත්වය දරන සතිපතා පුවත්පත පාර්ලිමේන්තු මූලාශ්‍ර උපුටා දක්වමින් ජුනි 26 වන දින සිය සංස්කරණයේ වාර්තා කළේය.",
        "වාර්තාවට අනුව, සාමාජිකයින්ගේ සේවා කාර්යාලය විසින් අදාළ අයදුම්පත් දැනටමත් නිකුත් කර ඇති අතර, එය පිරවූ පසු, ආයුධ මුදා හැරීමට නියමිත ආරක්ෂක අමාත්‍යාංශය වෙත යොමු කරනු ලැබේ.",
        "මැයි 09 වෙනිදා, එවකට අගමැති මහින්ද රාජපක්ෂගේ ආධාරකරුවන් විසින් ඔහුගේ පිටත රැස්ව සිටි සාමකාමී විරෝධතාකරුවන්ට ප්‍රකෝපකාරී ලෙස ප්‍රහාරයක් දියත් කිරීමෙන් පසු රටපුරා ඇති වූ පළිගැනීමේ ප්‍රචණ්ඩත්වය හේතුවෙන් කෝපාවිෂ්ට වූ මැර කල්ලි විසින් - ඔවුන්ගෙන් වැඩි දෙනෙක් ආණ්ඩු පක්ෂයේ මන්ත්‍රීවරුන් කිහිප දෙනෙකුගේ පෞද්ගලික නිවාස සහ කාර්යාල ගිනිබත් කරන ලදී. කොළඹ අරලියගහ මන්දිරයේ නිල නිවස.",
        "ආණ්‌ඩුවේ එක්‌ මන්ත්‍රීවරයකු වූ අමරකීර්ති අතුකෝරළ එදින සවස කොළඹ සිට ආපසු එමින් සිටියදී මැර පිරිසක්‌ විසින් ඝාතනය කරන ලදී. (කොළඹ/ජුනි25/2022)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "සතිපතා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉරිදා ලංකාදීප",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "සතිපතා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජූනි 26",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "සාමාජිකයින්ගේ සේවා කාර්යාලය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ආරක්ෂක අමාත්යාංශය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "මැයි 09",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මහින්ද රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "කොළඹ අරලියගහ මන්දිරය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "එක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "අමරකීර්ති අතුකෝරල",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "දහවල්",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "කොළඹ/ජුනි25/2022",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "இலங்கையின் புதிய பாராளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர்கள் தனிப்பட்ட துப்பாக்கிக்கு விண்ணப்பம்: அறிக்கை",
      "author": "",
      "body_lines": [
        "ECONOMYNEXT – இலங்கையில் 15 புதுமுக எம்.பி.க்கள் தனிப்பட்ட துப்பாக்கிக்கு விண்ணப்பித்துள்ளதாக வாராந்திர சண்டே லங்காதீப தெரிவித்துள்ளது.",
        "தானாக முன்வந்து துப்பாக்கியைப் பெறாத இந்த புதிய எம்.பி.க்கள், \"தற்போதைய சூழ்நிலையை\" கருத்தில் கொண்டு கைத்துப்பாக்கிக்கு விண்ணப்பித்துள்ளதாக, தனியாருக்குச் சொந்தமான வார இதழ் தனது ஜூன் 26 பதிப்பில் நாடாளுமன்ற ஆதாரங்களை மேற்கோள் காட்டி செய்தி வெளியிட்டுள்ளது.",
        "அறிக்கையின்படி, உறுப்பினர்களின் சேவை அலுவலகம் ஏற்கனவே தொடர்புடைய விண்ணப்பப் படிவங்களை வழங்கியுள்ளது, அது நிரப்பப்பட்டவுடன், ஆயுதங்களை வெளியிட வேண்டிய பாதுகாப்பு அமைச்சகத்திற்கு அனுப்பப்படும்.",
        "மே 09 அன்று, பிரதமர் மகிந்த ராஜபக்சவின் ஆதரவாளர்கள் அவருக்கு வெளியே கூடியிருந்த அமைதியான போராட்டக்காரர்கள் மீது தூண்டுதல் இல்லாமல் தாக்குதல் நடத்தியதைத் தொடர்ந்து, நாடு முழுவதும் பதிலடி கொடுக்கும் வன்முறை அலையில், பல பாராளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர்களின் தனிப்பட்ட வீடுகள் மற்றும் அலுவலகங்கள் - அவர்களில் பெரும்பாலோர் அரசாங்க உறுப்பினர்கள் - கோபமான கும்பல்களால் எரிக்கப்பட்டனர். உத்தியோகபூர்வ இல்லம் கொழும்பில் உள்ள ஆலய மரங்கள்.",
        "அன்றைய தினம் பிற்பகல் கொழும்பில் இருந்து திரும்பி வரும் வழியில் அரசாங்கத்தின் பாராளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர் அமரகீர்த்தி அத்துகோரல ஒரு கும்பலால் கொல்லப்பட்டார். (கொழும்பு/ஜூன்25/2022)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "இலங்கையின்",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "வாரந்தோறும்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஞாயிறு லங்காதீப",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "வாரந்தோறும்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜூன் 26",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "உறுப்பினர் சேவை அலுவலகம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாதுகாப்பு அமைச்சகம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "மே 09",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "மஹிந்த ராஜபக்ஷ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "கொழும்பில் உள்ள கோவில் மரங்கள்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஒன்று",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "அமரகீர்த்தி அத்துகோரல",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "பிற்பகல்",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "கொழும்பு/ஜூன்25/2022",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}