{
  "newspaper_id": "daily-ft-lk",
  "url": "https://www.ft.lk/news/India-gifts-Dornier-aircraft-to-strengthen-maritime-security-of-SL/56-738717",
  "time_ut": 1660593688,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "India gifts Dornier aircraft to strengthen maritime security of SL",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "India gifts Dornier aircraft to strengthen maritime security of SL",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "India yesterday gifted a Dornier Maritime Reconnaissance aircraft on 15 August 2022 towards strengthening the maritime security of Sri Lanka at a special event held in Sri Lanka Air Force Base, Katunayake. Navy and Air Force personnel of Sri Lanka who received training in India for close to four months shall operate the aircraft. They will also receive operational support from their Indian counterparts.",
        "President Ranil Wickremesinghe, Indian High Commissioner Gopal Baglay, Chief of Staff to the President Sagala Ratnayaka, Defence Secretary General Kamal Gunaratne, Indian Navy Vice Chief of Naval Staff Vice Admiral S.N. Ghormade, Defence Staff Chief General Shavendra Silva and Army, Navy and Air Force Chiefs of Sri Lanka graced the occasion. The landmark event coincided with the celebration of India’s 75th anniversary of independence.",
        "The aircraft would act as a force multiplier, enabling Sri Lanka to tackle multiple challenges such as human and drug trafficking, smuggling and other organised forms of crime in its coastal waters more effectively. Induction of the aircraft is timely in view of the current challenges to Sri Lanka’s maritime security.",
        "Capability of the aircraft to undertake Search and Rescue operations exemplifies its direct benefit to the people. The gift to the people of Sri Lanka will equip the country to contribute more towards the security of the Indian Ocean Region at large. It may be recalled that maritime security has been identified as a key pillar of the Colombo Security Conclave.  Speaking on the occasion, High Commissioner Gopal Baglay emphasised that induction of the aircraft will help in creating a peaceful environment for progress and prosperity of the people of India and Sri Lanka.",
        "Gifting of Dornier aircraft underscores the cooperation between the two maritime neighbours in the defence and security spheres.",
        "Such cooperation is envisaged to add further capability and capacity to Sri Lanka and is in line with the vision of Security and Growth for All in the Region (SAGAR)."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "India",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "Dornier",
          "label": "LOC"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "India",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "yesterday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "15 August 2022",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "Katunayake",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Navy",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Air Force",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "India",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "close to four months",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Indian",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Indian",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Gopal Baglay",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sagala Ratnayaka",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Defence",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kamal Gunaratne",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Indian Navy",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "S.N. Ghormade",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Defence Staff",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Shavendra Silva",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Army",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Navy",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Air Force Chiefs of Sri Lanka",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "India",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "75th",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka’s",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Search and Rescue",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Indian Ocean Region",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Colombo Security Conclave",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Gopal Baglay",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "India",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "two",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "SAGAR",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ සමුද්‍රීය ආරක්ෂාව තර කිරීම සඳහා ඉන්දියාව විසින් ඩෝනියර් ගුවන් යානයක් තෑගි කරයි",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "කටුනායක, ශ්‍රී ලංකා ගුවන් හමුදා කඳවුරේ පැවති විශේෂ උත්සවයකදී ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ සමුද්‍රීය ආරක්ෂාව ශක්තිමත් කිරීම සඳහා 2022 අගෝස්තු 15 වන දින ඉන්දියාව විසින් ඩෝනියර් සමුද්‍රීය ඔත්තු බැලීමේ ගුවන් යානයක් තෑගි කරන ලදී. මාස හතරකට ආසන්න කාලයක් ඉන්දියාවේ පුහුණුව ලැබූ ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ නාවික හා ගුවන් හමුදා සාමාජිකයින් ගුවන් යානා මෙහෙයවිය යුතුය. ඔවුන්ට ඔවුන්ගේ ඉන්දියානු සගයන්ගෙන් මෙහෙයුම් සහාය ද ලැබෙනු ඇත.",
        "ජනාධිපති රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ, ඉන්දීය මහ කොමසාරිස් ගෝපාල් බග්ලේ, ජනාධිපති කාර්ය මණ්ඩල ප්‍රධානී සාගල රත්නායක, ආරක්ෂක ලේකම් ජනරාල් කමල් ගුණරත්න, ඉන්දීය නාවික හමුදා උප නාවික මාණ්ඩලික ප්‍රධානී වයිස් අද්මිරාල් එස්.එන්. Ghormade, ආරක්ෂක මාණ්ඩලික ප්‍රධානී ජෙනරාල් ශවේන්ද්‍ර සිල්වා සහ ශ්‍රී ලංකා යුද, නාවික සහ ගුවන් හමුදා ප්‍රධානීන් මෙම අවස්ථාවට සහභාගි වූහ. මෙම සුවිශේෂී සිදුවීම ඉන්දියාවේ 75 වැනි නිදහස් සංවත්සරය සැමරීම සමග සමපාත විය.",
        "මෙම ගුවන් යානය ශ්‍රී ලංකාවට සිය වෙරළබඩ මුහුදේ මිනිස් සහ මත්ද්‍රව්‍ය ජාවාරම්, ජාවාරම් සහ අනෙකුත් සංවිධානාත්මක අපරාධ වැනි බහුවිධ අභියෝගවලට වඩාත් ඵලදායී ලෙස මුහුණ දීමට හැකි වන පරිදි බල ගුණකයක් ලෙස ක්‍රියා කරනු ඇත. ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ සමුද්‍රීය ආරක්‍ෂාවට දැනට පවතින අභියෝග හමුවේ ගුවන් යානා ඇතුළත් කිරීම කාලෝචිත වේ.",
        "සෙවුම් සහ ගලවා ගැනීමේ මෙහෙයුම් සිදු කිරීමට ගුවන් යානයට ඇති හැකියාව එහි සෘජු ප්‍රතිලාභය ජනතාවට ලබා දෙයි. ශ්‍රී ලංකාවාසී ජනතාවට ලබා දෙන ත්‍යාගය ඉන්දියානු සාගර කලාපයේ ආරක්ෂාව සඳහා වැඩි දායකත්වයක් ලබා දීමට රට සන්නද්ධ කරනු ඇත. කොළඹ ආරක්‍ෂක සමුළුවේ ප්‍රධාන කුළුණක් ලෙස සමුද්‍ර ආරක්‍ෂාව හඳුනාගෙන ඇති බව සිහිපත් කළ හැකිය. මෙම අවස්ථාවට අදහස් දක්වමින් මහ කොමසාරිස් ගෝපාල් බග්ලේ මහතා අවධාරණය කළේ මෙම ගුවන් යානය හඳුන්වාදීම ඉන්දියාවේ සහ ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ ජනතාවගේ ප්‍රගතිය සහ සමෘද්ධිය සඳහා සාමකාමී පරිසරයක් නිර්මාණය කිරීමට උපකාරී වන බවයි.",
        "ඩෝනියර් ගුවන් යානා පිරිනැමීම සමුද්‍රීය අසල්වැසියන් දෙදෙනා අතර ආරක්ෂක සහ ආරක්ෂක ක්ෂේත්‍රවල සහයෝගීතාවය අවධාරනය කරයි.",
        "එවැනි සහයෝගීතාවයක් ශ්‍රී ලංකාවට තවදුරටත් හැකියාව සහ ධාරිතාව එක් කිරීමට අපේක්ෂා කරන අතර කලාපයේ සැමට ආරක්ෂාව සහ වර්ධනය (සාගර්) යන දැක්මට අනුකූල වේ."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ඉන්දියාව",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "ඩෝනියර්",
          "label": "LOC"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඊයේ",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "15 අගෝස්තු 2022",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "කටුනායක",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "නාවික",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගුවන් හමුදා",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මාස හතරකට කිට්ටුයි",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දීය",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දීය",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගෝපාල් බග්ලේ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "සාගල රත්නායක",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ආරක්ෂක",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "කමල් ගුණරත්න",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දීය නාවික හමුදාව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "එස්.එන්. ගෝර්මඩ්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ආරක්ෂක කාර්ය මණ්ඩලය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශවේන්ද්‍ර සිල්වා",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "හමුදා",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "නාවික",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ ගුවන් හමුදා ප්‍රධානීන්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "75 වැනි",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "සෙවීම සහ ගැලවීම",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දියානු සාගර කලාපය",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "කොළඹ ආරක්ෂක සමුළුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගෝපාල් බග්ලේ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "දෙක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "සාගර්",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "இலங்கையின் கடல்சார் பாதுகாப்பை வலுப்படுத்த இந்தியா டோர்னியர் விமானத்தை பரிசாக அளித்துள்ளது",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "இலங்கையின் கடல் பாதுகாப்பை வலுப்படுத்தும் நோக்கில், கட்டுநாயக்கா, இலங்கை விமானப்படை தளத்தில் நடைபெற்ற சிறப்பு நிகழ்வில், இந்தியா நேற்று 15 ஆகஸ்ட் 2022 அன்று டோர்னியர் கடல்சார் உளவு விமானத்தை பரிசாக வழங்கியது. இந்தியாவில் நான்கு மாதங்கள் பயிற்சி பெற்ற இலங்கை கடற்படை மற்றும் விமானப்படை வீரர்கள் விமானத்தை இயக்க வேண்டும். அவர்கள் தங்கள் இந்திய சகாக்களிடமிருந்து செயல்பாட்டு ஆதரவையும் பெறுவார்கள்.",
        "ஜனாதிபதி ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க, இந்திய உயர்ஸ்தானிகர் கோபால் பாக்லே, ஜனாதிபதியின் பிரதானி சாகல ரத்நாயக்க, பாதுகாப்புச் செயலாளர் நாயகம் கமல் குணரத்ன, இந்திய கடற்படையின் கடற்படைத் துணைத் தலைவர் வைஸ் அட்மிரல் எஸ்.என். கோர்மடே, பாதுகாப்புப் படைகளின் பிரதானி ஜெனரல் ஷவேந்திர சில்வா மற்றும் இலங்கையின் இராணுவ, கடற்படை மற்றும் விமானப்படைத் தலைவர்கள் ஆகியோர் இந்நிகழ்வில் கலந்து சிறப்பித்தனர். மைல்கல் நிகழ்வு இந்தியாவின் 75 வது சுதந்திர தின கொண்டாட்டத்துடன் ஒத்துப்போனது.",
        "மனித மற்றும் போதைப்பொருள் கடத்தல், கடத்தல் மற்றும் பிற ஒழுங்கமைக்கப்பட்ட குற்றங்கள் போன்ற பல சவால்களை இலங்கை தனது கரையோர கடற்பகுதியில் மிகவும் திறம்பட சமாளிக்கும் வகையில் இந்த விமானம் ஒரு சக்தி பெருக்கியாக செயல்படும். இலங்கையின் கடல்சார் பாதுகாப்பிற்கு தற்போது உள்ள சவால்களை கருத்தில் கொண்டு விமானத்தை அறிமுகப்படுத்துவது சரியான நேரத்தில் உள்ளது.",
        "தேடுதல் மற்றும் மீட்பு நடவடிக்கைகளை மேற்கொள்வதற்கான விமானத்தின் திறன் மக்களுக்கு அதன் நேரடியான பலனை எடுத்துக்காட்டுகிறது. இலங்கை மக்களுக்கு வழங்கப்பட்டுள்ள இந்த பரிசு, இந்து சமுத்திரப் பிராந்தியத்தின் பாதுகாப்பிற்கு பெருமளவிலான பங்களிப்பை வழங்குவதற்கு நாட்டை தயார்படுத்தும். கொழும்பு பாதுகாப்பு மாநாட்டின் முக்கிய தூணாக கடல்சார் பாதுகாப்பு அடையாளம் காணப்பட்டுள்ளமை நினைவுகூரத்தக்கது. இந்நிகழ்ச்சியில் பேசிய உயர் ஸ்தானிகர் கோபால் பாக்லே, இந்தியா மற்றும் இலங்கை மக்களின் முன்னேற்றம் மற்றும் செழிப்புக்கான அமைதியான சூழலை உருவாக்க இந்த விமானத்தின் தூண்டுதல் உதவும் என்று வலியுறுத்தினார்.",
        "டோர்னியர் விமானத்தை பரிசளிப்பது, பாதுகாப்பு மற்றும் பாதுகாப்புத் துறைகளில் இரு கடல்சார் அண்டை நாடுகளுக்கு இடையிலான ஒத்துழைப்பை அடிக்கோடிட்டுக் காட்டுகிறது.",
        "இத்தகைய ஒத்துழைப்பு இலங்கைக்கு மேலும் ஆற்றலையும் ஆற்றலையும் சேர்க்க திட்டமிடப்பட்டுள்ளது மற்றும் பிராந்தியத்தில் உள்ள அனைவருக்கும் பாதுகாப்பு மற்றும் வளர்ச்சியின் (SAGAR) பார்வைக்கு ஏற்ப உள்ளது."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "இந்தியா",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "டோர்னியர்",
          "label": "LOC"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "இந்தியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "நேற்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "15 ஆகஸ்ட் 2022",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "கட்டுநாயக்கா",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "கடற்படை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "விமானப்படை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்தியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "நான்கு மாதங்களுக்கு அருகில்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்தியன்",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்தியன்",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "கோபால் பாக்லே",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "சாகல ரத்நாயக்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாதுகாப்பு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "கமல் குணரத்ன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்திய கடற்படை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "எஸ்.என். கோர்மேட்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாதுகாப்பு ஊழியர்கள்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "சவேந்திர சில்வா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இராணுவம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "கடற்படை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கையின் விமானப்படைத் தலைவர்கள்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்தியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "75வது",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கையின்",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "தேடல் மற்றும் மீட்பு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்தியப் பெருங்கடல் பகுதி",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "கொழும்பு பாதுகாப்பு மாநாடு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "கோபால் பாக்லே",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்தியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இரண்டு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சாகர்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}