{
  "newspaper_id": "ada-lk",
  "url": "https://www.ada.lk/breaking_news/මන්ත්‍රීවරුන්ට-හමුදාවෙන්-ඉන්ධන/11-395514",
  "time_ut": 1658142248,
  "original_lang": "si",
  "original_title": "මන්ත්‍රීවරුන්ට හමුදාවෙන් ඉන්ධන",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "MPs get fuel from the army",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "It is reported that necessary facilities have been provided for MPs coming to Parliament to get fuel from army camps in their areas of residence.",
        "According to a complaint made by a group of MPs to the Speaker that there is no system to get fuel for coming to Parliament, this facility has been provided to get fuel.",
        "Furthermore, Acting President Ranil Wickramasinghe has instructed the Chief of Security Staff, the Commanders of the three armed forces and the Inspector General of Police to provide special police protection to all the MPs coming to the Parliament to participate in the voting to elect the new President."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickramasinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Security Staff",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "three",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Inspector General of Police",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "මන්ත්‍රීවරුන්ට හමුදාවෙන් ඉන්ධන",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "පාර්ලිමේන්තුවට පැමිණෙන මන්ත්‍රීවරුන් සඳහා  තමන් පදිංචි ප්‍රදේශයන්හි  යුද හමුදා කඳවුරුවලින් ඉන්ධන ලබා ගැනීමට අවශ්‍ය පහසුකම් සපයා  ඇතැයි  වාර්තා වේ.",
        "පාර්ලිමේන්තුවට පැමිණීම සඳහා ඉන්ධන ලබා ගැනීමට ක්‍රමවේදයක් නොමැති බවට මන්ත්‍රීවරුන් පිරිසක් කතානායකවරයාට කළ පැමිණිල්ලකට අනුව ඉන්ධන ලබා ගැනීම සඳහා  මෙම පහසුකම සලසා දී ඇත.",
        "තවද නව  ජනාධිපතිවරයා තෝරාපත් කරගන්නා ඡන්ද විමසීමේ අවස්ථාවට සහභාගීවීම සඳහා පාර්ලිමේන්තුවට  පැමිණෙන සියලුම මන්ත්‍රීවරුන්ට විශේෂ පොලිස් ආරක්ෂාව ලබාදීමට  වැඩබලන ජනාධිපති රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතා ආරක්ෂක මාණ්ඩලික ප්‍රධානී, ත්‍රිවිධ හමුදාපතිවරුන් සහ පොලිස්පතිවරයාට උපදෙස්දී තිබේ."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ආරක්ෂක කාර්ය මණ්ඩලය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "තුන්",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "පොලිස්පති",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "பாராளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர்கள் இராணுவத்திடம் இருந்து எரிபொருள் பெறுகின்றனர்",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "பாராளுமன்றத்திற்கு வரும் பாராளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர்களுக்கு அவர்கள் வசிக்கும் பகுதிகளில் உள்ள இராணுவ முகாம்களில் இருந்து எரிபொருளை பெற்றுக்கொள்ள தேவையான வசதிகள் செய்து கொடுக்கப்பட்டுள்ளதாக தெரிவிக்கப்படுகின்றது.",
        "பாராளுமன்றத்திற்கு வருவதற்கு எரிபொருளை பெற்றுக்கொள்ளும் முறைமை இல்லை என பாராளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர்கள் குழு சபாநாயகரிடம் செய்த முறைப்பாட்டின் பிரகாரம் எரிபொருளை பெற்றுக்கொள்ள இந்த வசதி வழங்கப்பட்டுள்ளது.",
        "மேலும், புதிய ஜனாதிபதியை தெரிவு செய்வதற்கான வாக்கெடுப்பில் கலந்துகொள்வதற்காக பாராளுமன்றத்திற்கு வரும் அனைத்து பாராளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர்களுக்கும் விசேட பொலிஸ் பாதுகாப்பை வழங்குமாறு பதில் ஜனாதிபதி ரணில் விக்ரமசிங்க, பாதுகாப்பு அதிகாரிகளின் பிரதானி, முப்படைகளின் தளபதிகள் மற்றும் பொலிஸ் மா அதிபர் ஆகியோருக்கு பணிப்புரை விடுத்துள்ளார். ."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாதுகாப்பு ஊழியர்கள்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "மூன்று",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்ஸ்பெக்டர் ஜெனரல் ஆஃப் போலீஸ்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}