{
  "newspaper_id": "daily-mirror-lk",
  "url": "https://www.dailymirror.lk/latest_news/Three-Indians-nabbed-with-gold-jewellery-worth-Rs-18mn/342-243423",
  "time_ut": 1660977190,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Three Indians nabbed with gold jewellery worth Rs.18mn",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Three Indians nabbed with gold jewellery worth Rs.18mn",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "Officers attached to the customs Narcotics Control Unit apprehended three Indian Nationals with gold jewellery while attempting to smuggle into the country, Customs Media Spokesman Deputy Customs Director (Legal Affairs) Sudatta Silva said.",
        "He said the suspects were arrested while attempting to smuggle the jewellery through the customs Green Channel at the Bandaranayake International Airport (BIA).",
        "The jewellery weighing 1,200g with a street value of approximately Rs.18 million were found concealed with them, he said.",
        "The suspects aged 38 and 28 years of age were attempting to pass the gold jewellery through the customs Green Channel without declaring them to the Customs, the spokesman said.",
        "The customs investigation are continuing. (Chaturanga Samarawickrama and T.K.G. Kapila)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Three",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "Indians",
          "label": "NORP"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "three",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Indian",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Customs Media",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Customs",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Legal Affairs",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sudatta Silva",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the customs Green Channel",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Bandaranayake International Airport",
            "label": "FAC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "1,200",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "approximately Rs.18 million",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "38 and 28 years of age",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Customs",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Chaturanga Samarawickrama",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "T.K.G. Kapila",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "රුපියල් මිලියන 18ක් වටිනා රන් ආභරණ සමඟ ඉන්දීය ජාතිකයින් තිදෙනෙකු මාට්ටු",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "රේගු මත්ද්‍රව්‍ය නාශක අංශයේ නිලධාරීන් විසින් රන් ආභරණ සමඟ ඉන්දීය ජාතිකයින් තිදෙනෙකු නීතිවිරෝධී ලෙස මෙරටට රැගෙන ඒමට උත්සාහ කිරීමේදී අත්අඩංගුවට ගත් බව රේගු මාධ්‍ය ප්‍රකාශක නියෝජ්‍ය රේගු අධ්‍යක්ෂ (නීති කටයුතු) සුදත්ත සිල්වා මහතා පැවසීය.",
        "බණ්ඩාරනායක ජාත්‍යන්තර ගුවන්තොටුපලේ (BIA) රේගු ග්‍රීන් චැනල් හරහා මෙම ස්වර්ණාභරණ නීතිවිරෝධී ලෙස රැගෙන යාමට උත්සාහ කිරීමේදී සැකකරුවන් අත්අඩංගුවට ගත් බව ඔහු පැවසීය.",
        "ග්‍රෑම් 1200ක් බරැති මෙම ස්වර්ණාභරණ තොගයේ වීදි වටිනාකම ආසන්න වශයෙන් රුපියල් මිලියන 18ක් පමණ සඟවා තිබියදී සොයාගත් බවද ඔහු පැවසීය.",
        "වයස අවුරුදු 38 සහ 28 යන වයස්වල පසුවන සැකකරුවන් එම රන් ආභරණ රේගුවට ප්‍රකාශ නොකර රේගු ග්‍රීන් චැනල් හරහා රැගෙන යාමට උත්සාහ කරමින් සිටි බව ප්‍රකාශකවරයා පැවසීය.",
        "රේගු පරීක්ෂණ තවදුරටත් ක්‍රියාත්මකයි. (චතුරංග සමරවික්‍රම සහ ටී.කේ.ජී. කපිල)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "තුන්",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "ඉන්දියානුවන්",
          "label": "NORP"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "තුන්",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දීය",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "රේගු මාධ්ය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "රේගුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "නීති කටයුතු",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "සුදත්ත සිල්වා",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "රේගු හරිත නාලිකාව",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "බණ්ඩාරනායක ජාත්‍යන්තර ගුවන්තොටුපළ",
            "label": "FAC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "1,200 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ආසන්න වශයෙන් රුපියල් මිලියන 18 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "වයස අවුරුදු 38 සහ 28",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "රේගුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "චතුරංග සමරවික්‍රම",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "ටී.කේ.ජී. කපිල",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "18 மில்லியன் மதிப்புள்ள தங்க நகைகளுடன் 3 இந்தியர்கள் கைது",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "சுங்க போதைப்பொருள் கட்டுப்பாட்டு பிரிவின் அதிகாரிகள் தங்க நகைகளுடன் மூன்று இந்திய பிரஜைகளை நாட்டிற்கு கடத்த முயன்ற போது கைது செய்ததாக சுங்க ஊடகப் பேச்சாளர் பிரதி சுங்கப் பணிப்பாளர் (சட்ட விவகாரங்கள்) சுதத்த சில்வா தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "பண்டாரநாயக்க சர்வதேச விமான நிலையத்தில் (BIA) சுங்க கிரீன் சேனல் ஊடாக நகைகளை கடத்த முற்பட்ட போது சந்தேகநபர்கள் கைது செய்யப்பட்டதாக அவர் கூறினார்.",
        "சுமார் 18 மில்லியன் ரூபா பெறுமதியான 1,200 கிராம் எடையுள்ள நகைகள் மறைத்து வைக்கப்பட்டிருந்தன.",
        "38 மற்றும் 28 வயதுடைய சந்தேகநபர்கள் தங்க நகைகளை சுங்கத்திற்கு அறிவிக்காமல் சுங்க கிரீன் சேனல் ஊடாக கடத்த முற்பட்டதாக பேச்சாளர் தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "சுங்கத்துறை விசாரணை தொடர்கிறது. (சதுரங்க சமரவிக்ரம மற்றும் டி.கே.ஜி. கபில)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "மூன்று",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "இந்தியர்கள்",
          "label": "NORP"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "மூன்று",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்தியன்",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "சுங்க ஊடகம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "சுங்கம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "சட்ட விவகாரங்கள்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "சுதத்த சில்வா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "சுங்க கிரீன் சேனல்",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "பண்டாரநாயக்க சர்வதேச விமான நிலையம்",
            "label": "FAC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "1,200",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "தோராயமாக ரூ.18 மில்லியன்",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "38 மற்றும் 28 வயது",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சுங்கம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "சதுரங்க சமரவிக்ரம",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "டி.கே.ஜி. கபிலா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}