{
  "newspaper_id": "b-b-c-com-sinhala",
  "url": "https://www.bbc.com/sinhala/sri-lanka-62160681",
  "time_ut": 1657762840,
  "original_lang": "si",
  "original_title": "'ජනපති ඉල්ලා අස්වීමේ ලිපිය නොදෙන්නේ නම් ධුරය හැරගියා සේ සලකනවා' - කථානායක",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "'If the President does not give the letter of resignation, he will be considered as having left office' - Speaker",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "Speaker Mahinda Yapa Abeywardena revealed that Gotabhaya Rajapaksa has not yet received the letter of resignation from the presidency.",
        "He said that if the President does not give the letter of resignation, he will look into legal provisions to treat him as having left office.",
        "Gotabhaya Rajapaksa had previously promised the Speaker and Acting President and Prime Minister Ranil Wickresinghe that he would resign from the presidency on July 13.",
        "The Speaker also stated yesterday that he was informed that the President who called him on the phone will leave office on July 13.",
        "Also, the speaker said that he will send the letter of resignation to him yesterday.",
        "It is reported that President Gotabhaya Rapaksha, who left for the Maldivian capital city of Male yesterday (July 13) in the early morning of yesterday (July 13), is still staying at a resort in the country. The President left for the Maldives with his wife and two security personnel.",
        "International media reported that the President is ready to leave Male for Singapore, but so far he has not been able to leave the country.",
        "Protests were also held in the capital city of Male on July 13, demanding the extradition of Gotabhaya Rajapakse from the Maldives.",
        "The international media also revealed that Gotabaya Rajapaksa, who announced that he could not travel on the Singapore Airlines plane which was scheduled to fly to Singapore at 23:55 Sri Lanka time yesterday, has requested to prepare a private jet to fly to Singapore. That is because of the possible objection from civilian passengers.",
        "Although the President has not yet resigned, a gazette notice has been issued appointing Prime Minister Ranil Wickremesinghe as the Acting President.",
        "Accordingly, nominations will be called on July 19 to elect a new president through a vote held in Parliament. A new president is scheduled to be elected through a vote held in the parliament on July 20.",
        "Why is President Gotabaya Rajapaksa, who is fleeing from Sri Lanka, postponing his resignation?",
        "Gotabaya Rajapaksa will not resign until he goes to a safe place. A former US citizen, Rajapaksa renounced his US citizenship to run in Sri Lanka's presidential election in 2019.",
        "It is extremely difficult to obtain a visa to enter the United States after one renounces US citizenship.",
        "As Executive President of Sri Lanka, Rajapaksa enjoys diplomatic immunity and will serve as head of state until he resigns.",
        "Gotabaya Rajapaksa is using his position as the head of state to secure a position.",
        "At present, the activists have intensified their protest and they emphasize that President Gotabaya Rajapaksa as well as Ranil Wickramasinghe should resign from office. They said their struggle has been won so far.",
        "Therefore, they are working to hand over the President's Office, the Presidential Palace and the Prime Minister's Office, which have been taken over by now.",
        "They also protested near the Parliament and last night there was a tense situation at the Polduwa intersection.",
        "On July 13, 84 people who were injured in various incidents in Colombo have been admitted to the National Hospital. 79 of them are male and 5 are female.",
        "One protester has already died due to difficulty in breathing due to the tear gas attack.",
        "UN Secretary General Antonio Gutierrez said that the situation in Sri Lanka is being closely monitored.",
        "He said it was important to address the \"root causes of the conflict and the grievances of the protesters\" and urged all party leaders to start a dialogue for a peaceful and democratic transition."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Mahinda Yapa Abeywardena",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Gotabhaya Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "Gotabhaya Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickresinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "July 13",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "yesterday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "July 13",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "yesterday",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Gotabhaya Rapaksha",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Maldivian",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "yesterday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "July 13",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the early morning of yesterday",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "July 13",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Maldives",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "two",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Male for Singapore",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Protests",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "July 13",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Gotabhaya Rajapakse",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Maldives",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Gotabaya Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Singapore Airlines",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Singapore",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "23:55 Sri Lanka",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "yesterday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Singapore",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "July 19",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "July 20",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Gotabaya Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Gotabaya Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "US",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Rajapaksa",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "US",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka's",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "2019",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the United States",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "one",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "US",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Rajapaksa",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Gotabaya Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Gotabaya Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickramasinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the Presidential Palace",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "last night",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "Polduwa",
            "label": "PRODUCT"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "July 13",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "84",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Colombo",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the National Hospital",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "79",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "5",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "One",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "UN",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Antonio Gutierrez",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        []
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "'ජනපති ඉල්ලා අස්වීමේ ලිපිය නොදෙන්නේ නම් ධුරය හැරගියා සේ සලකනවා' - කථානායක",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ ජනාධිපතිධුරයෙන් ඉල්ලා අස්වීමේ ලිපිය මෙතෙක් තමන් වෙත ලැබී නැතැ යි කථානායක මහින්ද යාපා අබේවර්ධන අනාවරණය කළේ ය.",
        "ජනපති ඉල්ලා අස්වීමේ ලිපිය ලබා නොදෙන්නේ නම්, ධුරය හැර ගියා සේ සලකා කටයුතු කිරීමට නීතිමය ප්‍රතිපාදන සොයා බලන බව ඔහු පැවසීය.",
        "තමා ජූලි 13 ජනාධිපතිධුරයෙන් ඉල්ලා අස්වන බවට ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ කථානායකවරයාට ද, වැඩබලන ජනාධිපති සහ අග්‍රාමාත්‍ය රනිල් වික්‍රසිංහට ද මීට පෙර පොරොන්දුවී තිබුණි.",
        "කථානායකවරයා ඊයේ දිනයේ ද ප්‍රකාශ කළේ දුරකතනයෙන් තමා ඇමතූ ජනපතිවරයා ජූලි 13 වැනිදා ධුරයෙන් ඉවත්වන්නේයැ යි තමාට දැනුම්දුන් බව යි.",
        "එමෙන්ම ඉල්ලා අස්වීමේ ලිපිය ද ඊයේ දිනය තුළම තමා වෙත ලැබීමට සලස්වන බව ඔහු පැවසුවේයැ යි කථානායකවරයා ප්‍රකාශ කළේ ය.",
        "ජනතා විරෝධය හමුවේ ඊයේ (ජුලි 13) අලුයම ගුවන් හමුදා යානයකින් මාලදිවයිනේ මාලේ අගනුවර බලා පිටත්ව ගිය ජනපති ගෝඨාභය රාපක්ෂ තවමත් එරට නිකේතනයක රැඳීසිටින බව වාර්තා වෙයි. ජනාධිපතිවරයා මාලදිවයින බලා පිටත්ව ගියේ සිය බිරිඳ සහ ආරක්ෂක නිලධාරීන් දෙදෙනෙකු සමග ය.",
        "ජනාධිපතිවරයා මාලේ සිට සිංගප්පූරුව බලා පිටත්වයාමට සූදානමින් සිටින බව ජාත්‍යන්තර මාධ්‍ය වාර්තා කළත් මෙතෙක් ඔහුට එරටින් පිටව යාමට හැකි වී නැත.",
        "ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ මාලදිවයිනෙන් පිටුවහල් කරන ලෙස ඉල්ලා ජූලි 13 වැනිදා මාලේ අගනුවර විරෝධතා ද පැවැත්විණ.",
        "ඊයේ ශ්‍රී ලංකා වේලාවෙන් පැය 23:55ට සිංගප්පූරුව බලා පියාසර කිරීමට නියමිතව තිබූ සිංගප්පූරු ගුවන් සේවයේ යානයෙන් ගමන් ගැනීමට නොහැකි බව දැන්වූ ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ සිංගප්පූරුවට පියාසර කිරීමට පෞද්ගලික ජෙට් යානයක් සූදානම් කරන ලෙස ඉල්ලා ඇති බව ද ජාත්‍යන්තර මාධ්‍ය අනාවරණය කළේ ය. ඒ, සිවිල් මඟීන්ගෙන් එල්ලවිය හැකි විරෝධය හේතුවෙනි.",
        "ජනාධිපතිවරයා මෙතෙක් ධුරයෙන් ඉල්ලා අස්වී නැතත්, මේ වන විට වැඩබලන ජනාධිපතිවරයා වශයෙන් අග්‍රාමාත්‍ය රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ පත්කරමින් ගැසට් නිවේදනයක් නිකුත්කර තිබේ.",
        "ඒ අනුව පාර්ලිමේන්තුවේ පැවැත්වෙන ඡන්දයක් තුළින් නව ජනාධිපතිවරයෙකු තෝරාගැනීම සඳහා ජූලි 19 වැනිදා නාම යෝජනා කැඳවීමට නියමිත ය. ජූලි 20 වැනිදා පාර්ලිමේන්තුවේ පැවැත්වෙන ඡන්දයක් තුළින් නව ජනාධිපතිවරයෙකු තෝරා පත්කර ගැනීමට නියමිතව ඇත.",
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවෙන් පලා යන ජනාධිපති ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ සිය ඉල්ලා අස්වීම කල් දමන්නේ ඇයි?",
        "ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ ආරක්‍ෂිත ස්ථානයකට යනතුරු ඉල්ලා අස්වන්නේ නැත. හිටපු එක්සත් ජනපද ජාතිකයෙකු වූ රාජපක්ෂ 2019 දී ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ ජනාධිපතිවරණයට තරග කිරීම සඳහා ඔහුගේ එක්සත් ජනපද පුරවැසිභාවය අත්හැරියේය.",
        "යමෙක් එක්සත් ජනපද පුරවැසිභාවය අත්හැරීමෙන් පසු එක්සත් ජනපදයට ඇතුළු වීමට වීසා බලපත්‍රයක් ලබා ගැනීම අතිශයින් දුෂ්කර ය.",
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ විධායක ජනාධිපතිවරයා ලෙස රාජපක්ෂ රාජ්‍ය තාන්ත්‍රික මුක්තිය භුක්ති විඳින අතර ඔහු ඉල්ලා අස්වන තුරු රාජ්‍ය නායකයා ලෙස කටයුතු කරනු ඇත.",
        "ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්‍ෂ ආරක්‍ෂිත ස්‌ථානයකට පැමිණීම සඳහා රාජ්‍ය නායකයා ලෙස තම තත්ත්වය භාවිත කරමින් සිටී.",
        "මේ වන විට අරගලකරුවන් සිය විරෝධතාව දැඩිකර ඇති අතර ජනාධිපති ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ මෙන්ම රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ ද ධුරයෙන් ඉල්ලා අස්විය යුතු බව ඔවුහු අවධාරණය කරති.  ඔවුන් පවසුවේ ඔවුන්ගේ අරගලය මේ වන විට ජයග්‍රහණය කර ඇති බවයි.",
        "එම නිසා මේ වන විට සිය ග්‍රහණයට ගෙන ඇති ජනාධිපති කාර්යාලය, ජනාධිපති මන්ධිරය මෙන්ම අග්‍රාමාත්‍ය කාර්යාලය  නැවත භාරදීමට තමන්කටයුතු කරන බවයි.",
        "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව අසල ද ඔවුන් විරෝධතාවයේ නිරතවූ අතර පොල්දූව මංසන්ධියේ ඊයේ රාත්‍රියේ නොසන්සුන්කාරී තත්ත්වයක් ද ඇතිවිය.",
        "ජූලි 13 වැනිදා කොළඹ විවිධ ස්ථානවල ඇතිවූ සිදුවීම්වලින් තුවාල ලැබූ 84 දෙනෙකු ජාතික රෝහලට ඇතුලත් කර තිබේ. ඉන් 79 දෙනෙකු පිරිමින් වන අතර 5 දෙනෙකු කාන්තාවන් ය.",
        "එක් විරෝධතාකරුවකු මේ වන විට මිය ගොස් ඇත ඒ කඳුළුගෑස් ප්‍රහාරයක් හමුවේ හුස්මගැනීමට අපහසුවීම හේතුවෙනි.",
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ තත්ත්වය ඉතා සමීපව නීරීක්ෂණය කරන බව එක්සත් ජාතීන්ගේ මහලේකම් අන්තෝනියෝ ගුටියරෙස් පැවසීය.",
        "\"ගැටුමේ මූල හේතු සහ විරෝධතාකරුවන්ගේ දුක්ගැනවිලි\" ආමන්ත්‍රණය කිරීම වැදගත් බව පවසන ඔහු සාමකාමී සහ ප්‍රජාතන්ත්‍රවාදී සංක්‍රාන්තියක් සඳහා කතිකාවතක් අරඹන්නැ යි සියලුම පක්ෂ නායකයින්ගෙන් ඉල්ලා සිටින බව ද ප්‍රකාශ කළේ ය."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "මහින්ද යාපා අබේවර්ධන",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජූලි 13",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ඊයේ",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජූලි 13",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ඊයේ",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "මාලදිවයින්",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඊයේ",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජූලි 13",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඊයේ හිමිදිරි පාන්දර",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජූලි 13",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මාලදිවයින",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "දෙක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "සිංගප්පූරුවට පිරිමි",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "විරෝධතා",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජූලි 13",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "මාලදිවයින",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "සිංගප්පූරු ගුවන් සේවය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "සිංගප්පූරුව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "23:55 ශ්‍රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඊයේ",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "සිංගප්පූරුව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ජූලි 19",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජූලි 20",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "එක්සත් ජනපදය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "එක්සත් ජනපදය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "2019",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "එක්සත් ජනපදය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "එක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "එක්සත් ජනපදය",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ජනාධිපති මන්දිරය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "අවසන් රාත්රිය",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "පොල්දූව",
            "label": "PRODUCT"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ජූලි 13",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "84",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "කොළඹ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජාතික රෝහල",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "79",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "5",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "එක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "එ.ජා",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Antonio Gutierrez",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        []
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "'ஜனாதிபதி ராஜினாமா கடிதம் கொடுக்காவிட்டால், அவர் பதவியில் இருந்து விலகியதாக கருதப்படும்' - சபாநாயகர்",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "கோத்தபாய ராஜபக்சவுக்கு ஜனாதிபதி பதவியில் இருந்து விலகுவதற்கான கடிதம் இதுவரை கிடைக்கவில்லை என சபாநாயகர் மஹிந்த யாப்பா அபேவர்தன தெரிவித்துள்ளார்.",
        "ஜனாதிபதி ராஜினாமா கடிதத்தை வழங்கவில்லை என்றால், அவரை பதவியில் இருந்து விலகியதாக கருதுவதற்கான சட்ட ஏற்பாடுகளை ஆராய்வதாக அவர் கூறினார்.",
        "ஜனாதிபதி பதவியிலிருந்து ஜூலை 13 ஆம் திகதி இராஜினாமா செய்வதாக சபாநாயகர் மற்றும் பதில் ஜனாதிபதி மற்றும் பிரதமர் ரணில் விக்ரமசிங்கவிடம் கோத்தபாய ராஜபக்ச ஏற்கனவே உறுதியளித்திருந்தார்.",
        "தமக்கு தொலைபேசியில் அழைப்பு விடுத்த ஜனாதிபதி ஜூலை 13ஆம் திகதி பதவியை விட்டு வெளியேறுவார் என தனக்கு அறிவிக்கப்பட்டதாகவும் சபாநாயகர் நேற்று குறிப்பிட்டார்.",
        "மேலும், ராஜினாமா கடிதத்தை நேற்று அவருக்கு அனுப்பி வைப்பதாக சபாநாயகர் தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "நேற்று (ஜூலை 13) அதிகாலை மாலைதீவின் தலைநகரான மாலேவுக்குச் சென்ற ஜனாதிபதி கோட்டாபய ரபக்ஷ, இன்னும் நாட்டிலுள்ள ஓய்வு விடுதி ஒன்றில் தங்கியிருப்பதாகத் தெரிவிக்கப்படுகிறது. ஜனாதிபதி தனது மனைவி மற்றும் இரண்டு பாதுகாப்பு அதிகாரிகளுடன் மாலைதீவுக்கு புறப்பட்டார்.",
        "மாலேயில் இருந்து சிங்கப்பூர் செல்ல ஜனாதிபதி தயாராக இருப்பதாகவும், ஆனால் இதுவரை அவரால் நாட்டை விட்டு வெளியேற முடியவில்லை எனவும் சர்வதேச ஊடகங்கள் செய்தி வெளியிட்டுள்ளன.",
        "மாலத்தீவில் இருந்து கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ஷவை நாடு கடத்தக் கோரி ஜூலை 13 அன்று தலைநகர் மாலேயிலும் போராட்டங்கள் நடத்தப்பட்டன.",
        "இலங்கை நேரப்படி நேற்று பிற்பகல் 23.55க்கு சிங்கப்பூர் செல்லவிருந்த சிங்கப்பூர் ஏர்லைன்ஸ் விமானத்தில் பயணிக்க முடியாது என அறிவித்த கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ஷ, சிங்கப்பூர் செல்வதற்கு தனியார் ஜெட் விமானத்தை தயார் செய்யுமாறு கோரிக்கை விடுத்துள்ளதாகவும் சர்வதேச ஊடகங்கள் தெரிவித்துள்ளன. அதற்கு பொதுமக்கள் பயணிகளிடம் இருந்து வரக்கூடிய ஆட்சேபனையே காரணம்.",
        "ஜனாதிபதி இதுவரை பதவி விலகாத போதிலும், பதில் ஜனாதிபதியாக பிரதமர் ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்கவை நியமித்து வர்த்தமானி அறிவித்தல் வெளியிடப்பட்டுள்ளது.",
        "இதன்படி, பாராளுமன்றத்தில் வாக்கெடுப்பு மூலம் புதிய ஜனாதிபதியை தெரிவு செய்வதற்கான வேட்புமனுக்கள் ஜூலை 19 ஆம் திகதி கோரப்படும். ஜூலை 20ஆம் தேதி நாடாளுமன்றத்தில் நடைபெறும் வாக்கெடுப்பு மூலம் புதிய குடியரசுத் தலைவர் தேர்ந்தெடுக்கப்படுவார்.",
        "இலங்கையில் இருந்து தப்பிச் செல்லும் ஜனாதிபதி கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ச, தனது ராஜினாமாவை ஏன் ஒத்திவைக்கிறார்?",
        "கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ச பாதுகாப்பான இடத்திற்கு செல்லும் வரை பதவி விலக மாட்டார். முன்னாள் அமெரிக்க குடியுரிமை பெற்ற ராஜபக்சே, 2019-ம் ஆண்டு இலங்கை அதிபர் தேர்தலில் போட்டியிட அமெரிக்க குடியுரிமையை துறந்தார்.",
        "ஒருவர் அமெரிக்க குடியுரிமையை துறந்த பிறகு அமெரிக்காவிற்குள் நுழைவதற்கான விசா பெறுவது மிகவும் கடினம்.",
        "இலங்கையின் நிறைவேற்று அதிபராக, ராஜபக்சே ராஜினாமா செய்யும் வரை ராஜதந்திர விலக்கு பெறுகிறார்.",
        "கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ச தனது அரச தலைவர் பதவியை பயன்படுத்தி பதவியை பெற்றுக் கொள்கிறார்.",
        "தற்போது, ​​செயற்பாட்டாளர்கள் தமது போராட்டத்தை தீவிரப்படுத்தியுள்ளதுடன், ஜனாதிபதி கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ஷ மற்றும் ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க ஆகியோர் பதவி விலக வேண்டும் என அவர்கள் வலியுறுத்தியுள்ளனர். இதுவரை தங்கள் போராட்டம் வெற்றி பெற்றுள்ளது என்றார்கள்.",
        "எனவே தற்போது கையகப்படுத்தப்பட்டுள்ள ஜனாதிபதி அலுவலகம், ஜனாதிபதி மாளிகை, பிரதமர் அலுவலகம் போன்றவற்றை கையளிக்கும் பணிகளில் ஈடுபட்டுள்ளனர்.",
        "அவர்கள் பாராளுமன்றத்திற்கு அருகாமையிலும் ஆர்ப்பாட்டத்தில் ஈடுபட்டதுடன் நேற்று இரவு பொல்துவ சந்தியிலும் பதற்றமான சூழ்நிலை ஏற்பட்டது.",
        "ஜூலை 13ஆம் திகதி கொழும்பில் பல்வேறு சம்பவங்களில் காயமடைந்த 84 பேர் தேசிய வைத்தியசாலையில் அனுமதிக்கப்பட்டுள்ளனர். அவர்களில் 79 பேர் ஆண்கள், 5 பேர் பெண்கள்.",
        "கண்ணீர் புகைக்குண்டு தாக்குதலால் மூச்சு விடுவதில் சிரமம் ஏற்பட்டு போராட்டக்காரர் ஒருவர் ஏற்கனவே உயிரிழந்துள்ளார்.",
        "இலங்கையின் நிலைமையை உன்னிப்பாக அவதானித்து வருவதாக ஐக்கிய நாடுகள் சபையின் செயலாளர் நாயகம் அன்டோனியோ குட்டரெஸ் தெரிவித்துள்ளார்.",
        "\"மோதலின் மூல காரணங்கள் மற்றும் எதிர்ப்பாளர்களின் குறைகளை\" நிவர்த்தி செய்வது முக்கியம் என்றும், அமைதியான மற்றும் ஜனநாயக மாற்றத்திற்கான உரையாடலைத் தொடங்குமாறு அனைத்துக் கட்சித் தலைவர்களையும் வலியுறுத்தினார்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "மஹிந்த யாப்பா அபேவர்தன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "கோத்தபாய ராஜபக்ச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "கோத்தபாய ராஜபக்ச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜூலை 13",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "நேற்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜூலை 13",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "நேற்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "கோத்தபாய ரபக்ஷ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "மாலத்தீவு",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "நேற்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜூலை 13",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "நேற்று அதிகாலை",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜூலை 13",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "மாலத்தீவுகள்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இரண்டு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "சிங்கப்பூருக்கு ஆண்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "எதிர்ப்புகள்",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜூலை 13",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "கோத்தபாய ராஜபக்ஷ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "மாலத்தீவுகள்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "சிங்கப்பூர் ஏர்லைன்ஸ்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "சிங்கப்பூர்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "23:55 இலங்கை",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "நேற்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சிங்கப்பூர்",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஜூலை 19",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜூலை 20",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "எங்களுக்கு",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ராஜபக்சே",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "எங்களுக்கு",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கையின்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "2019",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஐக்கிய நாடுகள்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஒன்று",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "எங்களுக்கு",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ராஜபக்சே",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஜனாதிபதி மாளிகை",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "நேற்று இரவு",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "பொல்துவா",
            "label": "PRODUCT"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஜூலை 13",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "84",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "கொழும்பு",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "தேசிய மருத்துவமனை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "79",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "5",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஒன்று",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஐ.நா",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "அன்டோனியோ குட்டிரெஸ்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        []
      ]
    }
  }
}