{
  "newspaper_id": "ada-lk",
  "url": "https://www.ada.lk/technology/ලංකාවේ--විශාලතම-Hyper-Casual-–-eSports-Championship--අද-ඇරඹෙයි/5-378499",
  "time_ut": 1621063675,
  "original_lang": "si",
  "original_title": "ලංකාවේ  විශාලතම Hyper Casual – eSports Championship  අද ඇරඹෙයි",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Sri Lanka's biggest Hyper Casual – eSports Championship starts today",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "Sri Lanka's first and biggest Hyper Casual - eSports tournament, organized by the Ministry of Youth and Sports, IMI Games and SLT Mobitel, will start today (15) at 5 pm.",
        "The main objective of this tournament is to hone the skills of Sri Lankan cyber athletes and provide the necessary technical background and contribution to create cyber games.",
        "SLT Mobitel has come forward to provide all gifts and data to over 300 athletes who win the tournament.",
        "This Hyper Casual – eSports tournament held at the national level will be held for 02 days from today and the sportswomen will have to advance in this tournament through 06 games.",
        "All sportswomen who progress through the 06 related sports challenges will finally have the opportunity to reach the national scoreboard, where the player who scores the most points will be able to inherit the national championship.",
        "IMI Games, which introduced the Hyper Casual game to Sri Lanka, will perform all the technical and organizational work of this tournament and this will give Sri Lankan cyber sports players a new experience at the national level."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Sri Lanka's",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "today",
          "label": "DATE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka's",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "first",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Hyper Casual - eSports",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Ministry of Youth and Sports",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "IMI Games",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "SLT Mobitel",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "15",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "5 pm",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lankan",
            "label": "LOC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "SLT Mobitel",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "300",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "02 days",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "06",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "06",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "IMI Games",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lankan",
            "label": "LOC"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "ලංකාවේ  විශාලතම Hyper Casual – eSports Championship  අද ඇරඹෙයි",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "තරුණ හා ක්‍රීඩා අමාත්‍යංශය IMI Games සහ SLT මොබිටෙල් එක්ව පවත්වන ලංකාවේ ප්‍රථම හා විශාලතම Hyper Casual – eSports තරගාවලිය අද (15) සවස 5ට ආරම්භ වේ.",
        "ශ්‍රී ලාංකේය සයිබර් ක්‍රීඩක ක්‍රීඩිකාවන්ගේ කුසලතා ඔප්නැංවීම සහ සයිබර් ක්‍රීඩා නිර්මාණය කිරීමට අවශ්‍ය තාක්ෂණික පසුබිම හා දායකත්වය ලබාදීම මෙම තරගාවලියේ ප්‍රධාන අරමුණයි.",
        "තරගාවලිය ජයගන්නා 300 කට අධික ක්‍රීඩක ක්‍රීඩිකාවන්ට සියලුම තෑගි සහ Data ලබාදීමට SLT මොබිටෙල් ආයතනය ඉදිරිපත්වී සිටියි.",
        "ජාතික මට්ටමෙන් පැවැත්වෙන මෙම Hyper Casual – eSports තරගාවලිය අද සිට දින 02 ක් පුරා පැවැත්වෙන අතර ක්‍රීඩික ක්‍රීඩිකාවන්ට ක්‍රීඩා තරග 06 ක් ඔස්සේ මෙම තරගාවලියේ ඉදිරියට යාමට සිදුවනු ඇත.",
        "අදාළ ක්‍රීඩා තරග අභියෝග 06 ඔස්සේ ඉදිරියට යන සියලුම ක්‍රීඩික ක්‍රීඩිකාවන්ට අවසානයේ ජාතික ලකුණු පුවරුවට පැමිණීමේ අවස්ථාව උදාවන අතර එහිදී වැඩිම ලකුණු ලබාගන්නා ක්‍රීඩකයා හෝ ක්‍රීඩිකාව ජාතික ශූරතාවයට උරුමකම් කීමේ හැකියාව උදාවනු ඇත.",
        "Hyper Casual ක්‍රීඩාව මෙරටට හඳුන්වාදුන් IMI Games මෙම තරගාවලියේ සියලු තාක්ෂණික සහ සංවිධාන කටයුතු ඉටු කරන අතර මෙමගින් ශ්‍රී ලාංකේය සයිබර් ක්‍රීඩක ක්‍රිඩිකාවන්ට ජාතික මට්ටමේ නවමු අත්දැකීමක් හිමිවනු ඇත."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "අද",
          "label": "DATE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "පළමුවන",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Hyper Casual - eSports",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "යෞවන හා ක්‍රීඩා අමාත්‍යාංශය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "IMI ක්රීඩා",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "SLT මොබිටෙල්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "15",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "සවස 5",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලාංකික",
            "label": "LOC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "SLT මොබිටෙල්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "300",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "දින 02 යි",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "06",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "06",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "IMI ක්රීඩා",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලාංකික",
            "label": "LOC"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "இலங்கையின் மிகப்பெரிய ஹைப்பர் கேஷுவல் – ஈஸ்போர்ட்ஸ் சாம்பியன்ஷிப் இன்று தொடங்குகிறது",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "இளைஞர் மற்றும் விளையாட்டு அமைச்சு, IMI கேம்ஸ் மற்றும் SLT மொபிடெல் இணைந்து ஏற்பாடு செய்த இலங்கையின் முதல் மற்றும் மிகப்பெரிய ஹைப்பர் கேஷுவல் - ஈஸ்போர்ட்ஸ் போட்டி இன்று (15) மாலை 5 மணிக்கு ஆரம்பமாகவுள்ளது.",
        "இலங்கை சைபர் விளையாட்டு வீரர்களின் திறமைகளை மேம்படுத்துவது மற்றும் இணைய விளையாட்டுகளை உருவாக்க தேவையான தொழில்நுட்ப பின்னணி மற்றும் பங்களிப்பை வழங்குவது இந்த போட்டியின் முக்கிய நோக்கமாகும்.",
        "போட்டியில் வெற்றிபெறும் 300க்கும் மேற்பட்ட விளையாட்டு வீரர்களுக்கு அனைத்து பரிசுகளையும் தரவுகளையும் வழங்க SLT மொபிடெல் முன்வந்துள்ளது.",
        "தேசிய மட்டத்தில் நடைபெறும் இந்த ஹைப்பர் கேஷுவல் – ஈஸ்போர்ட்ஸ் போட்டிகள் இன்று முதல் 02 நாட்களுக்கு நடைபெறவுள்ளதுடன், விளையாட்டுப் பெண்கள் 06 விளையாட்டுக்கள் மூலம் இந்தப் போட்டியில் முன்னேற வேண்டும்.",
        "06 தொடர்புடைய விளையாட்டு சவால்களின் மூலம் முன்னேறும் அனைத்து விளையாட்டுப் பெண்களும் இறுதியாக தேசிய ஸ்கோர்போர்டை அடையும் வாய்ப்பைப் பெறுவார்கள், இதில் அதிக புள்ளிகளைப் பெறும் வீராங்கனை தேசிய சாம்பியன்ஷிப்பைப் பெற முடியும்.",
        "ஹைப்பர் கேஷுவல் விளையாட்டை இலங்கைக்கு அறிமுகம் செய்த IMI கேம்ஸ், இந்தப் போட்டியின் அனைத்து தொழில்நுட்ப மற்றும் நிறுவனப் பணிகளையும் செய்யும், இது இலங்கை சைபர் விளையாட்டு வீரர்களுக்கு தேசிய மட்டத்தில் புதிய அனுபவத்தை வழங்கும்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "இலங்கையின்",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "இன்று",
          "label": "DATE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கையின்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "முதலில்",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஹைப்பர் கேஷுவல் - ஈஸ்போர்ட்ஸ்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இளைஞர் மற்றும் விளையாட்டு அமைச்சகம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "IMI விளையாட்டுகள்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "SLT மொபிடெல்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "15",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "மாலை 5 மணி",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "LOC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "SLT மொபிடெல்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "300",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "02 நாட்கள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "06",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "06",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "IMI விளையாட்டுகள்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "LOC"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}