{
  "newspaper_id": "news-first-lk",
  "url": "https://www.newsfirst.lk/2022/07/07/health-ministry-defers-exclusive-fuel-arrangement-for-health-workers/",
  "time_ut": 1657194120,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Health Ministry defers exclusive fuel arrangement for health workers",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Health Ministry defers exclusive fuel arrangement for health workers",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); The Ministry of Health has deferred the program which was operational to provide health workers with fuel on Fridays, for 48 hours.",
        "Accordingly, the Secretary to the Ministry of Health, Janaka Sri Chandraguptha says that a new date will be notified to resume the relevant program.",
        "The exclusive fuel arrangement was in place for a period of two weeks in order to enable health workers to obtain fuel."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Health Ministry",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "The Ministry of Health",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Fridays",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "48 hours",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the Ministry of Health",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Janaka Sri Chandraguptha",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "two weeks",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "සෞඛ්‍ය සේවකයින් සඳහා පමණක් ඉන්ධන සැපයීම සෞඛ්‍ය අමාත්‍යාංශය කල් දමයි",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); සෞඛ්‍ය සේවකයින්ට සිකුරාදා දිනවල ඉන්ධන ලබාදීමේ වැඩසටහන සෞඛ්‍ය අමාත්‍යාංශය විසින් පැය 48කට කල් දමා ඇත.",
        "ඒ අනුව අදාළ වැඩසටහන යළි ආරම්භ කිරීම සඳහා නව දිනයක් දැනුම් දෙන බව සෞඛ්‍ය අමාත්‍යාංශයේ ලේකම් ජනක ශ්‍රී චන්ද්‍රගුප්ත මහතා පවසයි.",
        "සෞඛ්‍ය සේවකයින්ට ඉන්ධන ලබාගැනීමට හැකිවන පරිදි සති දෙකක කාලයක් සඳහා මෙම සුවිශේෂී ඉන්ධන සැකැස්ම ක්‍රියාත්මක විය."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "සෞඛ්‍ය අමාත්‍යාංශය",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "සෞඛ්‍ය අමාත්‍යාංශය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "සිකුරාදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "පැය 48 යි",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "සෞඛ්ය අමාත්යාංශය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජනක ශ්‍රී චන්ද්‍රගුප්ත",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "සති දෙකක්",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "சுகாதார ஊழியர்களுக்கான பிரத்தியேக எரிபொருள் ஏற்பாட்டை சுகாதார அமைச்சகம் ஒத்திவைத்துள்ளது",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); வெள்ளிக்கிழமைகளில் சுகாதார ஊழியர்களுக்கு எரிபொருள் வழங்கும் திட்டத்தை சுகாதார அமைச்சு 48 மணிநேரத்திற்கு ஒத்திவைத்துள்ளது.",
        "இதன்படி, குறித்த வேலைத்திட்டத்தை மீள ஆரம்பிப்பதற்கு புதிய திகதியொன்று அறிவிக்கப்படும் என சுகாதார அமைச்சின் செயலாளர் ஜனக ஸ்ரீ சந்திரகுப்த தெரிவித்துள்ளார்.",
        "சுகாதார பணியாளர்கள் எரிபொருளைப் பெறுவதற்கு இரண்டு வாரங்களுக்கு பிரத்தியேக எரிபொருள் ஏற்பாடு செய்யப்பட்டது."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "சுகாதார அமைச்சகம்",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "சுகாதார அமைச்சு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "வெள்ளிக்கிழமைகள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "48 மணிநேரம்",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "சுகாதார அமைச்சகம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜனக ஸ்ரீ சந்திரகுப்தா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இரண்டு வாரங்கள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}