{
  "newspaper_id": "news-first-lk",
  "url": "https://www.newsfirst.lk/2022/07/28/no-split-in-the-slpp-but-there-is-a-conspiracy-kariyawasam/",
  "time_ut": 1659021360,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "NO split in the SLPP, but there is a conspiracy: Kariyawasam",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "NO split in the SLPP, but there is a conspiracy: Kariyawasam",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); The General Secretary of Sri Lanka Podujana Peramuna, Sagara Kariyawasam said that he believes that the day when the people who believed in the bond between the Rajapaksas and Sri Lanka will rise again, and stated that he believes that the people who love the country will once again stand with them.",
        "“The Rajapaksas represented the national force of this country, today, this national force has been dealt a severe blow. First, we must establish the rule of law in this country. The Sri Lanka Podujana Peramuna will be involved in these efforts as the most powerful political party in this country,” he said.",
        "When inquired about the difference of opinion between party members, Kariyawasam said that it is not a question about the Party breaking into sects, as MP Prof. G.L. Peiris, who said today that the imposition of the State of Emergency goes against the policies of the SLPP, was invited to the meeting, however, did not participate in it.",
        "He alleged that a conspiracy exists to destroy the majority power of the Sri Lanka Podujana Peramuna within the Parliament, as the same group even wrote letters requesting former President and Prime Minister to step down from their positions.",
        "Commenting on the statement made by Prof. Peiris, the General Secretary of SLPP said that the policy of the party says otherwise, and added that the recent people’s protests were not exactly a protest or a struggle, but a riot that managed to burn down houses belonging to certain MPs as well",
        "NO split in the SLPP, but there is a conspiracy: Kariyawasam"
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "News 1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Podujana Peramuna",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sagara Kariyawasam",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the day",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Rajapaksas",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Rajapaksas",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "First",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "Podujana Peramuna",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Kariyawasam",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Party",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "G.L. Peiris",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the State of Emergency",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "Podujana Peramuna",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Peiris",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "SLPP",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        []
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "ශ්‍රී ලංකා පොදුජන පෙරමුණේ බෙදීමක් නැහැ, නමුත් කුමන්ත්‍රණයක් තියෙනවා: කාරියවසම්",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); රාජපක්‍ෂලා සහ ශ්‍රී ලංකාව අතර බැඳීම විශ්වාස කළ ජනතාව යළි නැගිටින දිනයක් බව තමා විශ්වාස කරන බව පැවසූ ශ්‍රී ලංකා පොදුජන පෙරමුණේ ප්‍රධාන ලේකම් සාගර කාරියවසම් මහතා, රටට ආදරය කරන ජනතාව එක් වරක් එනු ඇතැයි තමා විශ්වාස කරන බවද ප්‍රකාශ කළේය. නැවතත් ඔවුන් සමඟ සිටගන්න.",
        "“රාජපක්ෂලා මේ රටේ ජාතික බලවේගය නියෝජනය කළා, අද මේ ජාතික බලවේගයට මරු පහරක් එල්ල වෙලා තියෙනවා. පළමුව මේ රටේ නීතියේ ආධිපත්‍යය ඇති කළ යුතුයි. මේ රටේ ප්‍රබලම දේශපාලන පක්ෂය ලෙස ශ්‍රී ලංකා පොදුජන පෙරමුණ මේ ප්‍රයත්නවලට සම්බන්ධ වෙනවා.”",
        "පාක්ෂිකයින් අතර පවතින මතභේදය පිළිබඳව කළ විමසීමකදී කාරියවසම් කියා සිටියේ හදිසි නීතිය පැනවීම රජයේ ප්‍රතිපත්තිවලට පටහැනි බව අද ප්‍රකාශ කළ පාර්ලිමේන්තු මන්ත්‍රී මහාචාර්ය ජී.එල්. ශ්‍රී ලංකා පොදුජන පෙරමුණට මෙම රැස්වීමට ආරාධනා කර තිබුණත් ඊට සහභාගි වූයේ නැත.",
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකා පොදුජන පෙරමුණේ බහුතර බලය පාර්ලිමේන්තුව තුළ විනාශ කිරීමේ කුමන්ත්‍රණයක් ක්‍රියාත්මක වන බවත් එම පිරිස හිටපු ජනපතිට සහ අගමැතිට එම තනතුරුවලින් ඉවත් වන ලෙසට ලිපි පවා ලියා ඇති බවත් ඔහු චෝදනා කළේය.",
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකා පොදුජන පෙරමුණේ ප්‍රතිපත්තිය වෙනස් බව පවසන බව පවසන ශ්‍රී ලංකා පොදුජන පෙරමුණේ ප්‍රධාන ලේකම් මහාචාර්ය පීරිස්ගේ ප්‍රකාශය සම්බන්ධයෙන් අදහස් දැක්වූ එම පක්ෂයේ ප්‍රධාන ලේකම්වරයා, පසුගිය කාලයේ ඇතිවූ ජනතා උද්ඝෝෂණ හරියටම විරෝධතාවක් හෝ අරගලයක් නොවන බවත්, එය නිවාස ගිනි තැබීමට සමත් වූ කැරැල්ලක් බවත් පැවසීය. ඇතැම් මන්ත්‍රීවරුන්ටත් අයත්",
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකා පොදුජන පෙරමුණේ බෙදීමක් නැහැ, නමුත් කුමන්ත්‍රණයක් තියෙනවා: කාරියවසම්"
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "News 1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "පොදුජන පෙරමුණ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "සාගර කාරියවසම්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "දවස",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "රාජපක්ෂලා",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "රාජපක්ෂලා",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "පළමුවන",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "පොදුජන පෙරමුණ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "කාරියවසම්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "පක්ෂය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජී.එල් පීරිස්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "හදිසි තත්ත්වය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "පොදුජන පෙරමුණ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "පීරිස්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "SLPP",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        []
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "ஸ்ரீலங்கா பொதுஜன பெரமுனவில் பிளவு இல்லை, ஆனால் சதி உள்ளது: காரியவசம்",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); ராஜபக்சவுக்கும் இலங்கைக்கும் இடையிலான பிணைப்பை நம்பியவர்கள் மீண்டும் எழுச்சி பெறும் நாள் என்று தாம் நம்புவதாகவும், நாட்டை நேசிக்கும் மக்கள் ஒருமுறை வருவார்கள் என நம்புவதாகவும் ஸ்ரீலங்கா பொதுஜன பெரமுனவின் பொதுச் செயலாளர் சாகர காரியவசம் தெரிவித்துள்ளார். மீண்டும் அவர்களுடன் நிற்க.",
        "“இந்த நாட்டின் தேசிய சக்தியை பிரதிநிதித்துவப்படுத்திய ராஜபக்சக்கள் இன்று இந்த தேசிய சக்திக்கு கடுமையான அடி கொடுக்கப்பட்டுள்ளது. முதலில் இந்த நாட்டில் சட்டத்தின் ஆட்சியை நிறுவ வேண்டும். ஸ்ரீலங்கா பொதுஜன பெரமுன இந்த நாட்டின் பலம் வாய்ந்த அரசியல் கட்சியாக இந்த முயற்சிகளில் ஈடுபடும்” என்று அவர் கூறினார்.",
        "கட்சி உறுப்பினர்களுக்கிடையிலான கருத்து வேறுபாடு தொடர்பில் வினவியபோது, ​​அவசரகாலச் சட்டத்தை அமுல்படுத்துவது அரசாங்கத்தின் கொள்கைகளுக்கு முரணானது என பாராளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர் பேராசிரியர் ஜீ.எல்.பீரிஸ் இன்று கூறியது போன்று கட்சி பிரிந்து செல்வது பற்றிய கேள்வியல்ல என காரியவசம் தெரிவித்தார். SLPP, கூட்டத்திற்கு அழைக்கப்பட்டிருந்தும், அதில் பங்கேற்கவில்லை.",
        "பாராளுமன்றத்தில் ஸ்ரீலங்கா பொதுஜன பெரமுனவின் பெரும்பான்மை பலத்தை அழிக்கும் சதி நடப்பதாக அவர் குற்றம் சுமத்தியுள்ளார். அதே குழுவினர் முன்னாள் ஜனாதிபதி மற்றும் பிரதமரை பதவியில் இருந்து விலகுமாறு கோரி கடிதம் எழுதியுள்ளனர்.",
        "ஸ்ரீலங்கா பொதுஜன பெரமுனவின் கொள்கை வேறுவிதமாக கூறுகிறது என பேராசிரியர் பீரிஸ் கூறியது குறித்து கருத்து தெரிவித்த அக்கட்சியின் பொதுச்செயலாளர், அண்மைய மக்கள் நடத்திய போராட்டம் சரியாக போராட்டமோ போராட்டமோ அல்ல, வீடுகளை எரிக்கும் கலவரம் என்றார். சில பாராளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர்களுக்கும் சொந்தமானது",
        "ஸ்ரீலங்கா பொதுஜன பெரமுனவில் பிளவு இல்லை, ஆனால் சதி உள்ளது: காரியவசம்"
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "News 1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "பொதுஜன பெரமுன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "சாகர காரியவசம்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "தினம்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ராஜபக்சேக்கள்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ராஜபக்சேக்கள்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "முதலில்",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "பொதுஜன பெரமுன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "காரியவசம்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "பார்ட்டி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜி.எல்.பீரிஸ்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "அவசர நிலை",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "பொதுஜன பெரமுன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பீரிஸ்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "எஸ்.எல்.பி.பி",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        []
      ]
    }
  }
}