{
  "newspaper_id": "daily-ft-lk",
  "url": "https://www.ft.lk/news/Japan-provides-Rs-761-m-grant-aid-for-Human-Resource-Development-Scholarship-project/56-738595",
  "time_ut": 1660253670,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Japan provides Rs. 761 m grant aid for Human Resource Development Scholarship project",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Japan provides Rs. 761 m grant aid for Human Resource Development Scholarship project",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "The Government of Japan has provided a grant aid worth approximately Rs. 761 million for the Human Resource Development Scholarship (JDS) project to enhance the capacity building of public sector officials.",
        "The sum of Japanese Yen 282 million (approximately Rs. 761 million) grant will be extended to train young executive officers in the public sector at various universities in Japan and develop their skills in order to qualify them as future national leaders in their respective fields. Under the project, 17 public sector officials will be sent to pursue a two-year Master or PhD degree from 2023 to 2025. Areas of their degrees cover Public Policy, Macroeconomics, Public Finance and Investment Management, Industry Development Policy and Investment Promotion, and Urban and Regional Development.",
        "The Exchange of Notes for this project was signed on 8 August at the Ministry of Finance, Economic Stabilisation and National Policies between Japan to Sri Lanka Ambassador Mizukoshi Hideaki and Ministry of Finance Secretary K.M.M. Siriwardana, Economic Stabilisation and National Policies.",
        "As a long-standing friend, Japan has placed great emphasis on assistance in human resource development via many capacity building and skills development programs in order to accelerate long-term sustainable economic development.",
        "Since its inception in 2010, JDS project has supported 188 public sector officials in Sri Lanka. The project will contribute not only to enhancing individual capacities but also to improving institutional capacity of the public sector in Sri Lanka, which helps Sri Lanka to overcome various difficulties related to the current economic hardships and to achieve prosperity further in the future. JDS fellows are also expected to solidify foundations to further bilateral relations with Japan by utilising their human network developed through academic and social activities while in Japan.",
        "Japan, which enjoys 70 years of close friendship with Sri Lanka, will remain committed to stand in solidarity with Sri Lanka."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Japan",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "Rs",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "761",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "Human Resource Development Scholarship",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Japan",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Rs",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "761 million",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Human Resource Development Scholarship",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "JDS",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Japanese",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Yen",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Rs",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "761 million",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Japan",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "17",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "two-year",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "PhD",
            "label": "WORK_OF_ART"
          },
          {
            "text": "2023 to 2025",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Investment Management, Industry Development Policy and Investment Promotion",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Urban",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "The Exchange of Notes",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "8 August",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Ministry of Finance",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Economic Stabilisation",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "National Policies",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Japan",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Mizukoshi Hideaki",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ministry of Finance",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "K.M.M. Siriwardana",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Economic Stabilisation",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Japan",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "2010",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "JDS",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "188",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "JDS",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Japan",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Japan",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Japan",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "70 years",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "ජපානය රු. මානව සම්පත් සංවර්ධන ශිෂ්‍යත්ව ව්‍යාපෘතිය සඳහා මීටර් 761 ක ආධාර",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "ජපාන රජය දළ වශයෙන් රුපියල් මිලියන 100 ක ප්‍රදාන ආධාරයක් ලබා දී ඇත. රාජ්‍ය අංශයේ නිලධාරීන්ගේ ධාරිතාව වර්ධනය කිරීම සඳහා මානව සම්පත් සංවර්ධන ශිෂ්‍යත්ව (JDS) ව්‍යාපෘතිය සඳහා රුපියල් මිලියන 761ක්.",
        "ජපානයේ විවිධ විශ්වවිද්‍යාලවල රාජ්‍ය අංශයේ තරුණ විධායක නිලධාරීන් පුහුණු කර ඔවුන්ගේ කුසලතා වර්ධනය කිරීම සඳහා ඔවුන් අදාළ ක්ෂේත්‍රවල අනාගත ජාතික නායකයින් ලෙස සුදුසුකම් ලබා ගැනීම සඳහා ජපන් යෙන් මිලියන 282 (ආසන්න වශයෙන් රුපියල් මිලියන 761) ප්‍රදානය දීර්ඝ කෙරේ. ව්‍යාපෘතිය යටතේ, රාජ්‍ය අංශයේ නිලධාරීන් 17 දෙනෙකු 2023 සිට 2025 දක්වා වසර දෙකක ශාස්ත්‍රපති හෝ ආචාර්ය උපාධියක් හැදෑරීමට යවනු ලැබේ. ඔවුන්ගේ උපාධි ක්ෂේත්‍ර රාජ්‍ය ප්‍රතිපත්ති, සාර්ව ආර්ථික විද්‍යාව, රාජ්‍ය මූල්‍ය සහ ආයෝජන කළමනාකරණය, කර්මාන්ත සංවර්ධන ප්‍රතිපත්ති සහ ආයෝජන ප්‍රවර්ධනය, සහ නාගරික හා ප්‍රාදේශීය සංවර්ධනය.",
        "මෙම ව්‍යාපෘතිය සඳහා මුදල්, ආර්ථික ස්ථායීකරණ සහ ජාතික ප්‍රතිපත්ති අමාත්‍යාංශයේ දී ජපානයේ ශ්‍රී ලංකා තානාපති Mizukoshi Hideaki සහ මුදල් අමාත්‍යාංශයේ ලේකම් කේ.එම්.එම්. සිරිවර්ධන, ආර්ථික ස්ථායීකරණ සහ ජාතික ප්‍රතිපත්ති.",
        "දිගුකාලීන මිතුරෙකු ලෙස ජපානය දිගු කාලීන තිරසාර ආර්ථික සංවර්ධනයක් වේගවත් කිරීම සඳහා බොහෝ ධාරිතා ගොඩනැගීම සහ කුසලතා සංවර්ධන වැඩසටහන් හරහා මානව සම්පත් සංවර්ධනය සඳහා සහය දැක්වීම කෙරෙහි විශාල අවධානයක් යොමු කර ඇත.",
        "2010 වසරේ ආරම්භයේ සිට, JDS ව්‍යාපෘතිය ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ රාජ්‍ය අංශයේ නිලධාරීන් 188 දෙනෙකුට සහාය වී ඇත. මෙම ව්‍යාපෘතිය පුද්ගල ධාරිතාවන් ඉහළ නැංවීමට පමණක් නොව ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ රාජ්‍ය අංශයේ ආයතනික ධාරිතාව වැඩි දියුණු කිරීමට ද දායක වන අතර එමඟින් වත්මන් ආර්ථික දුෂ්කරතා හා සම්බන්ධ විවිධ දුෂ්කරතා මඟහරවා ගැනීමට සහ අනාගතයේදී සමෘද්ධිය ළඟා කර ගැනීමට ශ්‍රී ලංකාවට උපකාරී වේ. JDS සාමාජිකයින් ජපානයේ සිටියදී අධ්‍යයන හා සමාජීය ක්‍රියාකාරකම් හරහා වර්ධනය කර ගත් ඔවුන්ගේ මානව ජාලය භාවිතා කරමින් ජපානය සමඟ ද්විපාර්ශ්වික සබඳතා තවදුරටත් ශක්තිමත් කර ගැනීමට ද අපේක්ෂා කෙරේ.",
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකාව සමඟ වසර 70 ක සමීප මිත්‍රත්වයක් භුක්ති විඳින ජපානය ශ්‍රී ලංකාව සමඟ සහයෝගීතාවයෙන් සිටීමට කැපවී සිටිනු ඇත."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ජපානය",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "රුපියල්",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "761",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "මානව සම්පත් සංවර්ධන ශිෂ්‍යත්වය",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ජපානය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "රුපියල්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "මිලියන 761 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "මානව සම්පත් සංවර්ධන ශිෂ්‍යත්වය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "JDS",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ජපන්",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "යෙන්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "රුපියල්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "මිලියන 761 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජපානය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "17",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "වසර දෙකක",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ආචාර්ය උපාධිය",
            "label": "WORK_OF_ART"
          },
          {
            "text": "2023 සිට 2025 දක්වා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ආයෝජන කළමනාකරණය, කර්මාන්ත සංවර්ධන ප්‍රතිපත්ති සහ ආයෝජන ප්‍රවර්ධනය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "නාගරික",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "සටහන් හුවමාරුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "8 අගෝස්තු",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මුදල් අමාත්යාංශය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ආර්ථික ස්ථාවරත්වය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජාතික ප්‍රතිපත්ති",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජපානය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Mizukoshi Hideaki",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "මුදල් අමාත්යාංශය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "කේ.එම්.එම්. සිරිවර්ධන",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ආර්ථික ස්ථාවරත්වය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ජපානය",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "2010",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "JDS",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "188",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "JDS",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජපානය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජපානය",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ජපානය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "අවුරුදු 70 යි",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "ஜப்பான் ரூ. மனிதவள மேம்பாட்டு உதவித்தொகை திட்டத்திற்கு 761 மீ மானிய உதவி",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "ஜப்பான் அரசாங்கம் தோராயமாக ரூ. பொதுத்துறை அதிகாரிகளின் திறனை மேம்படுத்த மனித வள மேம்பாட்டு உதவித்தொகை (JDS) திட்டத்திற்கு 761 மில்லியன்.",
        "ஜப்பானிய யென் 282 மில்லியன் (தோராயமாக ரூ. 761 மில்லியன்) மானியம், ஜப்பானில் உள்ள பல்வேறு பல்கலைக்கழகங்களில் பொதுத் துறையில் உள்ள இளம் நிர்வாக அதிகாரிகளுக்குப் பயிற்சி அளிக்கவும், அவர்களின் திறன்களை மேம்படுத்தவும், அவர்கள் அந்தந்தத் துறைகளில் எதிர்கால தேசியத் தலைவர்களாகத் தகுதிபெறும் வகையில் நீட்டிக்கப்படும். திட்டத்தின் கீழ், 17 பொதுத்துறை அதிகாரிகள் 2023 முதல் 2025 வரை இரண்டு ஆண்டு முதுகலை அல்லது பிஎச்டி பட்டம் பெற அனுப்பப்படுவார்கள். அவர்களின் பட்டங்களின் பகுதிகள் பொதுக் கொள்கை, மேக்ரோ எகனாமிக்ஸ், பொது நிதி மற்றும் முதலீட்டு மேலாண்மை, தொழில் வளர்ச்சிக் கொள்கை மற்றும் முதலீட்டு ஊக்குவிப்பு மற்றும் நகர்ப்புற மற்றும் பிராந்திய வளர்ச்சி.",
        "இந்த திட்டத்திற்கான குறிப்புகள் பரிமாற்றம் ஆகஸ்ட் 8 ஆம் தேதி நிதி, பொருளாதார ஸ்திரப்படுத்தல் மற்றும் தேசிய கொள்கைகள் அமைச்சில் ஜப்பானுக்கான இலங்கை தூதுவர் மிசுகோஷி ஹிடேகி மற்றும் நிதி அமைச்சின் செயலாளர் கே.எம்.எம். சிறிவர்தன, பொருளாதார ஸ்திரப்படுத்தல் மற்றும் தேசிய கொள்கைகள்.",
        "நீண்டகால நண்பராக, ஜப்பான் நீண்டகால நிலையான பொருளாதார வளர்ச்சியை விரைவுபடுத்துவதற்காக பல திறன் மேம்பாடு மற்றும் திறன் மேம்பாட்டுத் திட்டங்கள் மூலம் மனித வள மேம்பாட்டிற்கான உதவிக்கு அதிக முக்கியத்துவம் அளித்துள்ளது.",
        "2010 இல் ஆரம்பிக்கப்பட்டதிலிருந்து, JDS திட்டம் இலங்கையில் 188 பொதுத்துறை அதிகாரிகளுக்கு ஆதரவளித்துள்ளது. இந்தத் திட்டம் தனிமனித திறன்களை மேம்படுத்துவதோடு மட்டுமல்லாமல், இலங்கையின் பொதுத்துறையின் நிறுவனத் திறனை மேம்படுத்துவதற்கும் பங்களிக்கும், இது தற்போதைய பொருளாதார நெருக்கடிகள் தொடர்பான பல்வேறு சிரமங்களை சமாளிக்கவும் எதிர்காலத்தில் மேலும் செழிப்பை அடையவும் இலங்கைக்கு உதவுகிறது. ஜேடிஎஸ் கூட்டாளிகள் ஜப்பானில் இருக்கும் போது கல்வி மற்றும் சமூக நடவடிக்கைகளின் மூலம் உருவாக்கப்பட்ட மனித வலையமைப்பைப் பயன்படுத்தி ஜப்பானுடனான இருதரப்பு உறவுகளை மேலும் வலுப்படுத்துவதற்கான அடித்தளத்தை உறுதிப்படுத்துவார்கள் என்று எதிர்பார்க்கப்படுகிறது.",
        "இலங்கையுடன் 70 வருட நெருங்கிய நட்புறவைக் கொண்டிருக்கும் ஜப்பான், இலங்கையுடன் ஒற்றுமையாக நிற்க உறுதி பூண்டிருக்கும்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ஜப்பான்",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "ரூ",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "761",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "மனித வள மேம்பாட்டு உதவித்தொகை",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ஜப்பான்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரூ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "761 மில்லியன்",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "மனித வள மேம்பாட்டு உதவித்தொகை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜேடிஎஸ்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஜப்பானியர்",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "யென்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரூ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "761 மில்லியன்",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜப்பான்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "17",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "இரண்டு ஆண்டுகள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "முனைவர் பட்டம்",
            "label": "WORK_OF_ART"
          },
          {
            "text": "2023 முதல் 2025 வரை",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "முதலீட்டு மேலாண்மை, தொழில் வளர்ச்சிக் கொள்கை மற்றும் முதலீட்டு ஊக்குவிப்பு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "நகர்ப்புறம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "குறிப்புகள் பரிமாற்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "8 ஆகஸ்ட்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "நிதி அமைச்சகம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "பொருளாதார ஸ்திரத்தன்மை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "தேசிய கொள்கைகள்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜப்பான்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Mizukoshi Hideaki",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "நிதி அமைச்சகம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "கே.எம்.எம். சிறிவர்தன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "பொருளாதார ஸ்திரத்தன்மை",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஜப்பான்",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "2010",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜேடிஎஸ்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "188",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜேடிஎஸ்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜப்பான்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜப்பான்",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஜப்பான்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "70 ஆண்டுகள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}