{
  "newspaper_id": "economy-next-com",
  "url": "https://economynext.com/sri-lanka-imf-deal-should-be-be-tabled-in-parliament-harsha-99441/",
  "time_ut": 1662367020,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Sri Lanka IMF deal should be be tabled in parliament: Harsha",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Sri Lanka IMF deal should be be tabled in parliament: Harsha",
      "author": "",
      "body_lines": [
        "ECONOMYNEXT – Sri Lanka’s agreement with the International Monetary Fund should be tabled in parliament, opposition legislator Harsha de Silva who also heads a panel on public finance said.",
        "The IMF staff level agreement plans a correction of the primary deficit from 4.0 percent of gross domestic product this year to 2.3 percent surplus by 2024.",
        "“There will have to be new taxes,” de Silva told reporters. “There may have to be taxes on dividends or indirect taxes.",
        "In the past finalized IMF programs have been released to the public after they were approved by the IMF’s board and the first disbursement made.",
        "Under Sri Lanka’s constitution parliament had control of the budget.",
        "“This has not been passed by parliament,” he said. “If it is not tabled in parliament by Tuesday I will take some actions as the chairman of the Public Finance Committee.”",
        "An IMF program series of prior actions before it is approved by its board.",
        "This may include an interim budget. In the case of the current passing the 2023 budget is a prior action, officials have said."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Sri Lanka",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka’s",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the International Monetary Fund",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Harsha de Silva",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "IMF",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "4.0 percent",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "this year",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "2.3 percent",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "2024",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "de Silva",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the past finalized",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "first",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka’s",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Tuesday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Public Finance Committee",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "2023",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "ශ්‍රී ලංකා IMF ගනුදෙනුව පාර්ලිමේන්තුවට ඉදිරිපත් කළ යුතුයි: හර්ෂ",
      "author": "",
      "body_lines": [
        "ECONOMYNEXT - ජාත්‍යන්තර මූල්‍ය අරමුදල සමඟ ශ්‍රී ලංකාව කර ඇති ගිවිසුම පාර්ලිමේන්තුවේ සභාගත කළ යුතු බව රාජ්‍ය මූල්‍ය පිළිබඳ මණ්ඩලයක ප්‍රධානියා ද වන විපක්ෂ ව්‍යවස්ථාදායක හර්ෂ ද සිල්වා මහතා පැවසීය.",
        "IMF කාර්ය මණ්ඩල මට්ටමේ ගිවිසුම මගින් ප්‍රාථමික හිඟය මේ වසරේ දළ දේශීය නිෂ්පාදිතයෙන් සියයට 4.0 සිට 2024 වන විට අතිරික්තය සියයට 2.3 දක්වා නිවැරදි කිරීමට සැලසුම් කරයි.",
        "\"අලුත් බදු පැනවීමට සිදුවනු ඇත,\" ද සිල්වා වාර්තාකරුවන්ට පැවසීය. “ලාභාංශ හෝ වක්‍ර බදු මත බදු පැනවීමට සිදු විය හැක.",
        "අතීතයේ දී අවසන් කරන ලද IMF වැඩසටහන් මහජනතාවට නිකුත් කර ඇත්තේ IMF මණ්ඩලයේ අනුමැතියෙන් පසුව සහ පළමු මුදල් ලබා දීමෙන් පසුවය.",
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකා ආණ්ඩුක්‍රම ව්‍යවස්ථාව යටතේ අයවැය පාලනය පාර්ලිමේන්තුව සතු විය.",
        "\"මෙය පාර්ලිමේන්තුවෙන් සම්මත කර නැත,\" ඔහු පැවසීය. \"අඟහරුවාදා වන විට එය පාර්ලිමේන්තුවට ඉදිරිපත් නොකළහොත් රාජ්‍ය මූල්‍ය කමිටුවේ සභාපතිවරයා ලෙස මම යම් ක්‍රියාමාර්ගයක් ගන්නවා.\"",
        "IMF වැඩසටහන් මාලාවක් එහි මණ්ඩලය විසින් අනුමත කිරීමට පෙර පූර්ව ක්‍රියාමාර්ග.",
        "මෙයට අතුරු අයවැයක් ඇතුළත් විය හැකිය. වත්මන් 2023 අයවැය සම්මත කිරීමේදී පූර්ව ක්‍රියාමාර්ගයක් බව නිලධාරීහු පවසති."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජාත්‍යන්තර මුල්‍ය අරමුදල",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "හර්ෂ ද සිල්වා",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "IMF",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "සියයට 4.0 කි",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "මේ වසරේ",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "සියයට 2.3 කි",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "2024",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ද සිල්වා",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "අතීතය අවසන් විය",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "පළමුවන",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "අඟහරුවාදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "රාජ්ය මූල්ය කමිටුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "2023",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "இலங்கை சர்வதேச நாணய நிதியத்தின் ஒப்பந்தம் பாராளுமன்றத்தில் சமர்ப்பிக்கப்பட வேண்டும்: ஹர்ஷ",
      "author": "",
      "body_lines": [
        "பொருளாதாரம் - சர்வதேச நாணய நிதியத்துடனான இலங்கையின் ஒப்பந்தம் பாராளுமன்றத்தில் சமர்ப்பிக்கப்பட வேண்டும் என்று பொது நிதி தொடர்பான குழுவின் தலைவரான எதிர்க்கட்சி சட்டமன்ற உறுப்பினர் ஹர்ஷ டி சில்வா தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "IMF பணியாளர் நிலை ஒப்பந்தம் முதன்மை பற்றாக்குறையை இந்த ஆண்டு மொத்த உள்நாட்டு உற்பத்தியில் 4.0 சதவீதத்தில் இருந்து 2024க்குள் 2.3 சதவீத உபரியாக மாற்ற திட்டமிட்டுள்ளது.",
        "\"புதிய வரிகள் இருக்க வேண்டும்,\" டி சில்வா செய்தியாளர்களிடம் கூறினார். \"ஈவுத்தொகை அல்லது மறைமுக வரிகள் மீது வரிகள் இருக்க வேண்டும்.",
        "கடந்த காலத்தில் இறுதி செய்யப்பட்ட IMF திட்டங்கள், IMF இன் வாரியத்தால் அங்கீகரிக்கப்பட்டு முதல் விநியோகம் செய்யப்பட்ட பிறகு பொதுமக்களுக்கு வெளியிடப்பட்டது.",
        "இலங்கையின் அரசியலமைப்பின் கீழ் வரவு செலவுத் திட்டத்தை பாராளுமன்றம் கட்டுப்படுத்தும்.",
        "இது நாடாளுமன்றத்தில் நிறைவேற்றப்படவில்லை என்றும் அவர் கூறினார். செவ்வாய்கிழமைக்குள் பாராளுமன்றத்தில் சமர்ப்பிக்கப்படாவிட்டால் பொது நிதிக் குழுவின் தலைவர் என்ற வகையில் நான் சில நடவடிக்கைகளை மேற்கொள்வேன்.",
        "ஒரு IMF திட்டத் தொடர் அதன் குழுவால் அங்கீகரிக்கப்படுவதற்கு முன் முந்தைய செயல்களின் தொடர்.",
        "இதில் இடைக்கால பட்ஜெட் அடங்கும். தற்போது 2023-ம் ஆண்டுக்கான பட்ஜெட் தாக்கல் செய்யப்பட உள்ள நிலையில், அதற்கு முந்தைய நடவடிக்கை என அதிகாரிகள் தெரிவித்துள்ளனர்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "இலங்கை",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கையின்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சர்வதேச நாணய நிதியம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஹர்ஷ டி சில்வா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "IMF",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "4.0 சதவீதம்",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்த வருடம்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "2.3 சதவீதம்",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "2024",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "டி சில்வா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "கடந்த காலம் இறுதி செய்யப்பட்டது",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "முதலில்",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கையின்",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "செவ்வாய்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "பொது நிதிக் குழு",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "2023",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}