{
  "newspaper_id": "news-first-lk",
  "url": "https://www.newsfirst.lk/2022/07/11/speaker-reveals-decisions-taken-at-crucial-party-leaders-meeting/",
  "time_ut": 1657544580,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Speaker reveals decisions taken at crucial party leaders meeting",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Speaker reveals decisions taken at crucial party leaders meeting",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); Sri Lanka’s Parliament Speaker has announced the decisions reached at Monday’s (11) meeting between the Party Leaders.",
        "He said the objective of the meeting was to decide on the future steps that need to be taken following the resignation of President Gotabaya Rajapaksa, who has informed the speaker that he will step down on Wednesday, the 13th of July.",
        "Accordingly, the Party Leaders had noted the need to act as per the Presidential Elections (Special Provisions) Act (No. 2 of 1981) within a short period of time.",
        "Therefore, Parliament will convene on the 15th of July as per the act and the house will be informed of the vacant Presidency.",
        "Thereafter, on the 19th of July nominations will be called for, and on the 20th of July as per the existing legal provisions a vote will be called for to elect the new President.",
        "The new President will then form an all-party government and should pave the way for the continuation of constitutional provisions, as well as essential services.",
        "Chief Government Whip Prasanna Ranatunga had stated that if an all-party government will be formed tomorrow, the entire Cabinet led by the Prime Minister is ready to step down.",
        "Speaker Mahinda Yapa Abeywardena has requested all Party Leaders to support these efforts."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "News 1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka’s",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Monday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "11",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Party Leaders",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Gotabaya Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Wednesday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the 13th of July",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the Party Leaders",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Presidential Elections (Special Provisions) Act",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "2",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "1981",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the 15th of July",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the 19th of July",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the 20th of July",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "Prasanna Ranatunga",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "tomorrow",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Cabinet",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Mahinda Yapa Abeywardena",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Party Leaders",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "තීරණාත්මක පක්ෂ නායක රැස්වීමේදී ගත් තීරණ කතානායක හෙළි කරයි",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); ශ්‍රී ලංකා පාර්ලිමේන්තුවේ කථානායකවරයා විසින් සඳුදා (11) පක්ෂ නායක රැස්වීමේදී එළැඹුණු තීරණ ප්‍රකාශයට පත් කර තිබේ.",
        "ජූලි 13 වැනි බදාදා ඉල්ලා අස්වන බව කථානායකවරයාට දන්වා ඇති ජනාධිපති ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ මහතා ඉල්ලා අස්වීමෙන් පසු ගත යුතු ඉදිරි ක්‍රියාමාර්ග පිළිබඳව තීරණය කිරීම මෙම රැස්වීමේ අරමුණ බව ඔහු පැවසීය.",
        "ඒ අනුව කෙටි කාලයක් තුළ ජනාධිපතිවරණ (විශේෂ විධිවිධාන) පනත (1981 අංක 2) ප්‍රකාරව ක්‍රියා කිරීමේ අවශ්‍යතාව පක්ෂ නායකයන් විසින් සටහන් කර තිබුණි.",
        "එබැවින් එම පනතට අනුව පාර්ලිමේන්තුව ජූලි මස 15 වැනිදා රැස්වන අතර පුරප්පාඩු වන ජනාධිපති ධුරය පිළිබඳව සභාවට දැනුම් දෙනු ඇත.",
        "ඉන් අනතුරුව ජූලි මස 19 වනදා නාමයෝජනා කැදවන අතර, පවතින නීතිමය ප්‍රතිපාදන අනුව ජුලි 20 වනදා නව ජනාධිපතිවරයා තෝරා පත් කර ගැනීම සඳහා ඡන්ද විමසීමක් සිදුකිරීමට නියමිතයි.",
        "නව ජනාධිපතිවරයා සර්ව පාක්ෂික ආණ්ඩුවක් පිහිටුවනු ඇති අතර ව්‍යවස්ථාපිත ප්‍රතිපාදන මෙන්ම අත්‍යවශ්‍ය සේවා අඛණ්ඩව පවත්වාගෙන යාමට මග පෑදිය යුතුය.",
        "හෙට දිනයේ සර්ව පාක්ෂික ආණ්ඩුවක් පිහිටුවන්නේ නම් අග්‍රාමාත්‍යවරයා ප්‍රමුඛ සමස්ත කැබිනට් මණ්ඩලයම ඉවත් වීමට සූදානම් බව ආණ්ඩු පක්ෂයේ ප්‍රධාන සංවිධායක ප්‍රසන්න රණතුංග ප්‍රකාශ කර තිබුණා.",
        "මෙම ප්‍රයත්නයන් සඳහා සහයෝගය ලබා දෙන ලෙස කථානායක මහින්ද යාපා අබේවර්ධන මහතා සියලුම පක්ෂ නායකයින්ගෙන් ඉල්ලා සිටී."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "News 1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "සඳුදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "11",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "පක්ෂ නායකයන්",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "බදාදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජූලි 13 වෙනිදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "පක්ෂ නායකයන්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජනාධිපති මැතිවරණ (විශේෂ විධිවිධාන) පනත",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "2",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "1981",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජූලි 15 වෙනිදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ජූලි 19 වෙනිදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජූලි 20 වෙනිදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "ප්‍රසන්න රණතුංග",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "හෙට",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මණ්ඩල",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "මහින්ද යාපා අබේවර්ධන",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "පක්ෂ නායකයන්",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "கட்சித் தலைவர்கள் கூட்டத்தில் எடுக்கப்பட்ட முடிவுகளை சபாநாயகர் வெளியிட்டார்",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); கட்சித் தலைவர்களுக்கு இடையில் திங்கட்கிழமை (11) நடைபெற்ற கூட்டத்தில் எடுக்கப்பட்ட தீர்மானங்களை இலங்கை நாடாளுமன்ற சபாநாயகர் அறிவித்துள்ளார்.",
        "எதிர்வரும் ஜுலை 13ஆம் திகதி பதவி விலகப் போவதாக சபாநாயகருக்கு அறிவித்துள்ள ஜனாதிபதி கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ஷவின் இராஜினாமாவை அடுத்து மேற்கொள்ள வேண்டிய எதிர்கால நடவடிக்கைகள் குறித்து தீர்மானிப்பதே இந்த சந்திப்பின் நோக்கமாகும் என்றார்.",
        "இதன்படி, ஜனாதிபதித் தேர்தல்கள் (விசேட ஏற்பாடுகள்) சட்டத்தின் (1981 இலக்கம் 2) பிரகாரம் குறுகிய காலத்திற்குள் செயற்பட வேண்டியதன் அவசியத்தை கட்சித் தலைவர்கள் குறிப்பிட்டுள்ளனர்.",
        "எனவே, சட்டத்தின் பிரகாரம் ஜூலை 15ஆம் திகதி நாடாளுமன்றம் கூடி வெற்றிடமாகவுள்ள ஜனாதிபதி பதவி தொடர்பில் சபைக்கு அறிவிக்கப்படும்.",
        "அதன்பிறகு, ஜூலை 19ஆம் தேதி வேட்புமனுக்கள் கோரப்பட்டு, தற்போதுள்ள சட்ட விதிகளின்படி ஜூலை 20ஆம் தேதி புதிய குடியரசுத் தலைவரை தேர்ந்தெடுப்பதற்கான வாக்கெடுப்பு நடத்தப்படும்.",
        "புதிய ஜனாதிபதி பின்னர் அனைத்துக் கட்சி அரசாங்கத்தை அமைப்பார் மற்றும் அரசியலமைப்பு விதிகள் மற்றும் அத்தியாவசிய சேவைகள் தொடர்வதற்கு வழி வகுக்க வேண்டும்.",
        "நாளைய தினம் சர்வகட்சி அரசாங்கம் அமைக்கப்படுமாயின் பிரதமர் தலைமையிலான முழு அமைச்சரவையும் பதவி விலகத் தயார் என அரசாங்கத்தின் பிரதம கொறடா பிரசன்ன ரணதுங்க தெரிவித்துள்ளார்.",
        "இந்த முயற்சிகளுக்கு ஆதரவளிக்குமாறு சபாநாயகர் மஹிந்த யாப்பா அபேவர்தன அனைத்து கட்சி தலைவர்களிடமும் கோரிக்கை விடுத்துள்ளார்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "News 1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கையின்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "திங்கட்கிழமை",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "11",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "கட்சி தலைவர்கள்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "புதன்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜூலை 13 ஆம் தேதி",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "கட்சி தலைவர்கள்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜனாதிபதி தேர்தல்கள் (சிறப்பு ஏற்பாடுகள்) சட்டம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "2",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "1981",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜூலை 15 ஆம் தேதி",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஜூலை 19 ஆம் தேதி",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜூலை 20 ஆம் தேதி",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "பிரசன்ன ரணதுங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "நாளை",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "மந்திரி சபை",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "மஹிந்த யாப்பா அபேவர்தன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "கட்சித் தலைவர்கள்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}