{
  "newspaper_id": "lankadeepa-lk",
  "url": "https://www.lankadeepa.lk/world_news/බ්‍රිතාන්‍යයේ-මුදල්-ඇමැති-සෞඛ්‍ය-ඇමැති-ඉල්ලා-අස්වෙති/14-615927",
  "time_ut": 1657071103,
  "original_lang": "si",
  "original_title": "බ්‍රිතාන්‍යයේ මුදල් ඇමැති සෞඛ්‍ය ඇමැති ඉල්ලා අස්වෙති",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Britain's finance minister and health minister resign",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "Plunging British Prime Minister Boris Johnson's government into crisis, the country's Finance Minister (Chancellor) Rishi Sunak and Health Minister (Health Secretary) Sajid Javad resigned.",
        "Rishi Sunak, in his resignation letter to Prime Minister Johnson, stated that he was sorry to leave the government and that he could no longer remain in his position under the current circumstances.",
        "People expect a competent and strong as well as reliable government. But I do not see that such a government exists. I am resigning. This may be the last time I hold a ministerial post. Rishi Sunak's letter of resignation to Prime Minister Johnson said, \"I cannot remain in my position as per my heart\".",
        "Finance Minister Rishi Sunak and Health Minister Sajeed Javad decided to resign from their positions due to the growing displeasure of Prime Minister Boris Johnson, the British media has explained.",
        "I lost my trust in you. Even if we expect further change under your leadership, it is clear that there will be no change. It is a pity to have to say about it. That is why I have decided to resign from the post,' said Health Minister Sajid Javad in his resignation letter to Prime Minister Boris Johnson.",
        "Prime Minister Boris Johnson leads the Conservative Party. With the country locked down and people confined to their homes during the 'Covid' pandemic, Prime Minister Johnson has on several occasions held secret honeymoons for members of his Prime Minister's Office staff. There was also a birthday party. The party took place at the Prime Minister's official residence at No. 10 Downing Street",
        "It was the opposition Labor Party that revealed to Parliament that Prime Minister Johnson had been holding parties in breach of health restrictions imposed by his government, following health sector advice. Even Prime Minister Johnson's Conservative Party members found out about it after the revelation.",
        "Although the opposition's accusations were strongly denied at first, Prime Minister Johnson admitted that he had held secret honeymoons when the evidence presented itself. A police investigation was also held and Prime Minister Johnson apologized to Parliament and his Conservative Party as well as the people of the country. He also paid a fine for violating quarantine rules. As a result, Prime Minister Johnson was disliked by the Conservative Party. Rishi Sunak and Sajeed Javad are two strongmen of Johnson's government who expressed displeasure.",
        "In addition, Prime Minister Boris Johnson recently offered a government position to MP Chris Pincher, who has been accused of corruption. Rishi Sunak and Sajeed Javad have said that they do not approve of giving a high government position to MP Chris Pincher who misused his position without conducting any investigation or disciplinary inquiry.",
        "In the meantime, Prime Minister Boris Johnson appointed Nadeem Sawahi, who is of Iraqi Kurdish origin, as the Minister of Education, to the vacant position of Finance Minister.",
        "The British media has reported that Queen Elizabeth II has also approved the appointment of Nadeem Sawahi as the Minister of Finance. Rishi Sunak, who resigned from the post of Finance Minister, is of Indian origin."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Britain",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "British",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Boris Johnson's",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Rishi Sunak",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Rishi Sunak",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Johnson",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Rishi Sunak's",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Johnson",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Rishi Sunak",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sajeed Javad",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Boris Johnson",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "British",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Health",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sajid Javad",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Boris Johnson",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Boris Johnson",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Conservative Party",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Johnson",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "10",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Labor Party",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Johnson",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Johnson",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Conservative Party",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "first",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Johnson",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Johnson",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Conservative Party",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Johnson",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Conservative Party",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Rishi Sunak",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sajeed Javad",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "two",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Johnson",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Boris Johnson",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Chris Pincher",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Rishi Sunak",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sajeed Javad",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Chris Pincher",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Boris Johnson",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Nadeem Sawahi",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Iraqi",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kurdish",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Finance",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "British",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Queen Elizabeth II",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Nadeem Sawahi",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Finance",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Rishi Sunak",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Indian",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "බ්‍රිතාන්‍යයේ මුදල් ඇමැති සෞඛ්‍ය ඇමැති ඉල්ලා අස්වෙති",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "බ්‍රිතාන්‍ය අග්‍රාමාත්‍ය බොරිස් ජොන්සන්ගේ රජය අර්බුදයකට ඇද දමමින්, එරට මුදල් අමාත්‍ය (චාන්සලර්) රිෂී සුනාක් සහ සෞඛ්‍ය අමාත්‍ය (සෞඛ්‍ය ලේකම්) සජීද් ජාවඩ් ඉල්ලා අස්වූහ.",
        "රිෂී සුනාක්, අග්‍රාමාත්‍ය ජොන්සන්ට යොමු කළ ඉල්ලා අස්වීමේ ලිපියෙහි සඳහන් වී ඇත්තේ, රජයෙන් ඉවත් වීමට ලැබීම කනගාටුවක් බවත්, පවතින වාතාවරණය යටතේ තමන්ට තව දුරටත් තම ධුරයේ රැඳී සිටිය නොහැකි බවත්ය.",
        "‘දක්ෂ සහ ශක්තිමත් මෙන්ම විශ්වාසවන්ත රජයක් ජනතාව අපේක්ෂා කරනවා. ඒත් එවැනි රජයක් පවතිනවා යැයි මට පෙනෙන්නේ නැහැ. මා ධුරයෙන් ඉවත් වෙනවා. මෙය මා අමාත්‍ය ධුරයක් හෙබවූ අවසන් අවස්ථාව වන්න පුළුවනි. සිතට එකඟව මට මගේ ධුරයේ රැඳී සිටින්න බැහැ’ යනුවෙන් ද රිෂී සුනාක් අග්‍රාමාත්‍ය ජොන්සන්ට යොමු කළ ඉල්ලා අස්වීමේ ලිපියෙහි සඳහන් වී ඇත.",
        "මුදල් අමාත්‍ය රිෂී සුනාක් සහ සෞඛ්‍ය අමාත්‍ය සජීද් ජාවඩ් ඔවුන්ගේ ධුරවලින් ඉල්ලා අස්වීමට තීරණය කළේ අග්‍රාමාත්‍ය බොරිස් ජොන්සන් කෙරෙහි ඔවුන් තුළ ඇති වුණු අප්‍රසාදය වර්ධනය වීම හේතුවෙන් බව බ්‍රිතාන්‍ය මාධ්‍ය පැහැදිලි කර තිබේ.",
        "‘ඔබ කෙරෙහි මා තැබූ විශ්වාසය නැතිවුණා. ඔබගේ නායකත්වය යටතේ තව දුරටත් වෙනසක් අපේක්ෂා කළත්, එසේ වෙනසක් නොවන බව පැහැදිලියි. ඒ ගැන පවසන්න සිදුවීම කනගාටුවක්. මා ධුරයෙන් ඉවත් වීමට තීරණය කළේ ඒ නිසයි.’ යැයි සෞඛ්‍ය අමාත්‍ය සජීද් ජාවඩ්, අග්‍රාමාත්‍ය බොරිස් ජොන්සන්ට යොමු කළ ඉල්ලා අස්වීමේ ලිපියෙහි සඳහන් වී ඇත.",
        "අග්‍රාමාත්‍ය බොරිස් ජොන්සන් නායකත්වය දෙන්නේ, කොන්සවර්ටිව් පක්ෂයටය. ‘කොවිඩ්’ වසංගත සමයේ රට ලොක්ඩවුන් කර, ජනතාව නිවෙස්වලට කොටු කර තිබියදී, අග්‍රාමාත්‍ය ජොන්සන්, ඔහුගේ අග්‍රාමාත්‍ය කාර්යාලයේ කාර්ය මණ්ඩල සාමාජිකයන් වෙනුවෙන් අවස්ථා කීපයකදී රහසේ මධුවිත සාද පැවැත්වීය. උපන් දින සාදයක් ද ඒ අතර විය. සාද පැවැත්වීම සිදුවූයේ අංක 10 ඩවුනිං වීදියේ අග්‍රාමාත්‍ය නිල නිවසේදීය.‍",
        "අග්‍රාමාත්‍ය ජොන්සන්, සෞඛ්‍ය අංශ උපදෙස් අනුව, ඔහුගේ රජය විසින් පනවනු ලැබූ සෞඛ්‍ය තහංචි උල්ලංඝනය කරමින්, සාද පැවැත්වීම පාර්ලිමේන්තුවට අනාවරණය කළේ විපක්ෂය වන කම්කරු පක්ෂයයි. අග්‍රාමාත්‍ය ජොන්සන්ගේ කොන්සවර්ටිව් පක්ෂ සාමාජිකයන් පවා ඒ ගැන දැනගත්තේ එම අනාවරණයෙන් පසුවය.",
        "මුලදී විපක්ෂයේ චෝදනා තරයේ ප්‍රතික්ෂේප කළත්, සාක්ෂි ඉදිරිපත් වෙද්දී තමන් රහසේ මධුවිත සාද පැවැත්වූ බව අග්‍රාමාත්‍ය ජොන්සන් පිළිගත්තේය. පොලිස් පරීක්ෂණයක් ද ඒ සම්බන්ධයෙන් පැවැත්වුණු අතර, අග්‍රාමාත්‍ය ජොන්සන් පාර්ලිමේන්තුවෙන් සහ සිය කොන්සවර්ටිව් පක්ෂයෙන් මෙන්ම රටේ ජනතාවගෙන් ද සමාව ඉල්ලීමක් කළේය. නිරෝධායන නීති කඩකිරීම සම්බන්ධයෙන් දඩ ගෙවීමක් ද කළේය. කොන්සවර්ටිව් පක්ෂය තුළින් අග්‍රාමාත්‍ය ජොන්සන්ට අප්‍රසාදයක් ගොඩ නැගෙන්න වූයේ ඒ අනුවය. එසේ අප්‍රසාදය පළ කළ ජොන්සන්ගේ රජයේ ප්‍රබලයන් දෙදෙකු වන්නේ රිෂී සුනාක් සහ සජීද් ජාවඩ් ය‍.",
        "මීට අමතරව, දූෂණ චෝදනා එල්ල වී ඇති ක්‍රිස් පින්චර් නමැති මන්ත්‍රීවරයාට පසුගිය දා රජයේ තනතුරක් පිරිනැමීමට ද අග්‍රාමාත්‍ය බොරිස් ජොන්සන් කටයුතු කළේය. තම ධුරය අවභාවිතයට ලක් කළ ක්‍රිස් පින්චර් මන්ත්‍රීවරයා සම්බන්ධයෙන් කිසිදු විමර්ශනයක් හෝ විනය පරීක්ෂණයක් හෝ නොපවත්වා ඔහුට රජයේ ඉහළ තනතුරක් ලබා දීම අනුමත නොකරන බව රිෂී සුනාක් සහ සජීද් ජාවඩ් පවසා තිබේ.",
        "මේ අතර පුරප්පාඩු වුණු මුදල් අමාත්‍ය ධුරයට, අධ්‍යාපන අමාත්‍යවරයා ලෙස කටයුතු කරන ඉරාක කුර්දි සම්භවයක් ඇති නදීම් සවාහී නම් කිරීමට අග්‍රාමාත්‍ය බොරිස් ජොන්සන් කටයුතු කළේය.",
        "මුදල් අමාත්‍ය ධුරය නදීම් සවාහී ලබා දීම සම්බන්ධයෙන් දෙවැනි එලිසබත් මහ රැජිනගේ ද අනුමැතිය හිමිවී ඇතැයි බ්‍රිතාන්‍ය මාධ්‍ය වාර්තා කර තිබේ. මුදල් අමාත්‍ය ධුරයෙන් ඉල්ලා අස්වුණු රිෂී සුනාක්, ඉන්දීය සම්භවයක් ඇත්තෙකි."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "බ්රිතාන්යය",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "බ්රිතාන්ය",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "බොරිස් ජොන්සන්ගේ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "රිෂි සුනක්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "රිෂි සුනක්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජොන්සන්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "රිෂි සුනක්ගේ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජොන්සන්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "රිෂි සුනක්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "සජීඩ් ජාවාඩ්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "බොරිස් ජොන්සන්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "බ්රිතාන්ය",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "සෞඛ්යය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "සජිඩ් ජාවාඩ්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "බොරිස් ජොන්සන්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "බොරිස් ජොන්සන්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "කොන්සර්වේටිව් පක්ෂය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජොන්සන්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "10",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "කම්කරු පක්ෂය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජොන්සන්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජොන්සන්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "කොන්සර්වේටිව් පක්ෂය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "පළමුවන",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජොන්සන්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජොන්සන්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "කොන්සර්වේටිව් පක්ෂය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජොන්සන්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "කොන්සර්වේටිව් පක්ෂය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "රිෂි සුනක්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "සජීඩ් ජාවාඩ්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "දෙක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජොන්සන්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "බොරිස් ජොන්සන්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ක්රිස් පින්චර්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "රිෂි සුනක්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "සජීඩ් ජාවාඩ්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ක්රිස් පින්චර්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "බොරිස් ජොන්සන්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "නදීම් සවාහි",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉරාක",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "කුර්දි",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "මූල්ය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "බ්රිතාන්ය",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "දෙවන එලිසබෙත් රැජින",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "නදීම් සවාහි",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "මූල්ය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "රිෂි සුනක්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දීය",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "பிரிட்டன் நிதியமைச்சர் மற்றும் சுகாதார அமைச்சர் ராஜினாமா",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "பிரிட்டிஷ் பிரதமர் போரிஸ் ஜான்சனின் அரசாங்கத்தை நெருக்கடியில் ஆழ்த்தி, நாட்டின் நிதியமைச்சர் (வேந்தர்) ரிஷி சுனக் மற்றும் சுகாதார அமைச்சர் (சுகாதார செயலாளர்) சஜித் ஜாவத் ஆகியோர் ராஜினாமா செய்தனர்.",
        "ரிஷி சுனக், பிரதமர் ஜான்சனுக்கு தனது ராஜினாமா கடிதத்தில், அரசாங்கத்தை விட்டு வெளியேறுவதற்கு வருந்துவதாகவும், தற்போதைய சூழ்நிலையில் இனி தனது பதவியில் இருக்க முடியாது என்றும் குறிப்பிட்டுள்ளார்.",
        "திறமையான மற்றும் வலுவான மற்றும் நம்பகமான அரசாங்கத்தை மக்கள் எதிர்பார்க்கிறார்கள். ஆனால் அப்படியொரு அரசாங்கம் இருப்பதாக நான் பார்க்கவில்லை. நான் ராஜினாமா செய்கிறேன். நான் அமைச்சர் பதவி வகிக்கும் கடைசி நேரமாக இது இருக்கலாம். பிரதமர் ஜான்சனுக்கு ரிஷி சுனக் ராஜினாமா கடிதத்தில், \"எனது இதயத்தின்படி என்னால் என் பதவியில் இருக்க முடியாது\" என்று கூறப்பட்டுள்ளது.",
        "பிரதமர் போரிஸ் ஜான்சனின் அதிருப்தியால் நிதியமைச்சர் ரிஷி சுனக் மற்றும் சுகாதார அமைச்சர் சஜீத் ஜாவத் ஆகியோர் தங்கள் பதவிகளை ராஜினாமா செய்ய முடிவு செய்ததாக பிரிட்டிஷ் ஊடகங்கள் விளக்கமளித்துள்ளன.",
        "நான் உங்கள் மீது நம்பிக்கையை இழந்துவிட்டேன். உங்கள் தலைமையில் மேலும் மாற்றத்தை எதிர்பார்த்தாலும், எந்த மாற்றமும் ஏற்படாது என்பது தெளிவாகிறது. அதைப் பற்றிச் சொல்ல வேண்டியதே பரிதாபம். அதனால் தான் பதவியை ராஜினாமா செய்ய முடிவு செய்துள்ளேன்' என சுகாதார அமைச்சர் சஜித் ஜாவத், பிரதமர் போரிஸ் ஜான்சனுக்கு தனது ராஜினாமா கடிதத்தில் தெரிவித்துள்ளார்.",
        "கன்சர்வேட்டிவ் கட்சிக்கு பிரதமர் போரிஸ் ஜான்சன் தலைமை தாங்குகிறார். 'கோவிட்' தொற்றுநோய்களின் போது நாடு பூட்டப்பட்டு மக்கள் தங்கள் வீடுகளுக்குள் அடைத்து வைக்கப்பட்டுள்ள நிலையில், பிரதமர் ஜான்சன் பல சந்தர்ப்பங்களில் தனது பிரதமர் அலுவலக ஊழியர்களுக்கு ரகசிய தேனிலவை நடத்தியுள்ளார். பிறந்தநாள் விழாவும் நடந்தது. எண் 10 டவுனிங் தெருவில் உள்ள பிரதமரின் அதிகாரப்பூர்வ இல்லத்தில் இந்த விருந்து நடந்தது",
        "சுகாதாரத் துறையின் ஆலோசனையைப் பின்பற்றி, பிரதமர் ஜான்சன் தனது அரசாங்கத்தால் விதிக்கப்பட்ட சுகாதாரக் கட்டுப்பாடுகளை மீறி விருந்துகளை நடத்துகிறார் என்பதை எதிர்க்கட்சியான தொழிலாளர் கட்சி நாடாளுமன்றத்தில் வெளிப்படுத்தியது. பிரதம மந்திரி ஜான்சனின் கன்சர்வேடிவ் கட்சி உறுப்பினர்கள் கூட இந்த வெளிப்பாட்டிற்குப் பிறகு அதைக் கண்டுபிடித்தனர்.",
        "எதிர்க்கட்சிகளின் குற்றச்சாட்டுகள் முதலில் கடுமையாக மறுக்கப்பட்ட போதிலும், ஆதாரங்கள் முன்வைக்கப்பட்ட போது, ​​பிரதமர் ஜான்சன் ரகசிய தேனிலவை நடத்தியதாக ஒப்புக்கொண்டார். பொலிஸ் விசாரணையும் நடத்தப்பட்டது மற்றும் பிரதமர் ஜான்சன் பாராளுமன்றம் மற்றும் அவரது கன்சர்வேடிவ் கட்சி மற்றும் நாட்டு மக்களிடம் மன்னிப்பு கேட்டார். தனிமைப்படுத்தப்பட்ட விதிகளை மீறியதற்காக அபராதமும் செலுத்தினார். இதன் விளைவாக, பிரதமர் ஜான்சன் கன்சர்வேடிவ் கட்சியால் பிடிக்கவில்லை. ரிஷி சுனக் மற்றும் சஜீத் ஜாவத் ஆகியோர் அதிருப்தியை வெளிப்படுத்திய ஜான்சனின் அரசாங்கத்தின் இரண்டு வலிமையானவர்கள்.",
        "மேலும், ஊழல் குற்றச்சாட்டுக்கு உள்ளான எம்.பி கிறிஸ் பின்சருக்கு பிரதமர் போரிஸ் ஜான்சன் சமீபத்தில் அரசு பதவியை வழங்கினார். எந்த விசாரணையும், ஒழுங்கு விசாரணையும் நடத்தாமல், தனது பதவியை தவறாகப் பயன்படுத்திய எம்.பி., கிறிஸ் பிஞ்சருக்கு, உயர் அரசு பதவி வழங்குவதை, தாங்கள் ஏற்கவில்லை என, ரிஷி சுனக் மற்றும் சஜீத் ஜாவத் தெரிவித்துள்ளனர்.",
        "இதற்கிடையில், பிரதமர் போரிஸ் ஜான்சன், ஈராக் குர்திஷ் வம்சாவளியைச் சேர்ந்த நதீம் சவாஹியை கல்வி அமைச்சராக நியமித்தார்.",
        "நதீம் சவாஹியை நிதியமைச்சராக நியமிக்க இரண்டாம் எலிசபெத் மகாராணியும் ஒப்புதல் அளித்துள்ளதாக பிரித்தானிய ஊடகங்கள் செய்தி வெளியிட்டுள்ளன. நிதி அமைச்சர் பதவியை ராஜினாமா செய்த ரிஷி சுனக் இந்திய வம்சாவளியைச் சேர்ந்தவர்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "பிரிட்டன்",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "பிரிட்டிஷ்",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "போரிஸ் ஜான்சனின்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரிஷி சுனக்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ரிஷி சுனக்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜான்சன்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ரிஷி சுனக் தான்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜான்சன்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ரிஷி சுனக்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "சஜீத் ஜாவத்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "போரிஸ் ஜான்சன்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "பிரிட்டிஷ்",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஆரோக்கியம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "சஜித் ஜாவத்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "போரிஸ் ஜான்சன்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "போரிஸ் ஜான்சன்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "கன்சர்வேடிவ் கட்சி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜான்சன்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "10",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "தொழிலாளர் கட்சி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜான்சன்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜான்சன்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "கன்சர்வேடிவ் கட்சி",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "முதலில்",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜான்சன்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜான்சன்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "கன்சர்வேடிவ் கட்சி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜான்சன்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "கன்சர்வேடிவ் கட்சி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரிஷி சுனக்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "சஜீத் ஜாவத்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இரண்டு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜான்சன்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "போரிஸ் ஜான்சன்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "கிறிஸ் பின்சர்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரிஷி சுனக்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "சஜீத் ஜாவத்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "கிறிஸ் பின்சர்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "போரிஸ் ஜான்சன்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "நதீம் சவாஹி",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஈராக்",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "குர்திஷ்",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "நிதி",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பிரிட்டிஷ்",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ராணி எலிசபெத் II",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "நதீம் சவாஹி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "நிதி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரிஷி சுனக்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்தியன்",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}