{
  "newspaper_id": "ada-derana-lk",
  "url": "http://www.adaderana.lk/news/83308/hrcsl-starts-independent-probes-on-rambukkana-shooting-and-violence-on-may-9-10",
  "time_ut": 1656435960,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "HRCSL starts independent probes on Rambukkana shooting and violence on May 9, 10",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "HRCSL starts independent probes on Rambukkana shooting and violence on May 9, 10",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "The Human Rights Commission of Sri Lanka (HRCSL) says it has commenced an independent inquiry on the police shooting incident at Rambukkana on 19th April and an independent inquiry on the alleged violations of the Rule of Law on 9th and 10th May 2022.",
        "Island-wide public protests continued to occur owing to fuel, Gas, and essential food shortage in the country since April 2022.",
        "On 19th April a group of protestors gathered near a Fuel station in Rambukkana in the Kegalle District and continued to protest for 2 days, 18th and 19th April 2022. During the protest, the police had used firearms to disperse the crowd resulting in one death and injuries to several protestors.",
        "The team of officials of the Human Rights Commission of Sri Lanka (HRCSL) visited the site at which the chain of events took place on the 20th itself and conducted the initial site inspection and primary inquiry.",
        "On 24th April 2022, the Minister of Public Security had requested the HRCSL to conduct an independent inquiry into the shooting incident. Pursuant to the request and power under the HRCSL Act no 21 of 1996 section 14, HRCSL appointed a multidisciplinary Panel of experts with the mandate to conduct an independent investigation.",
        "The Panel of experts consisted of Former Retired High Court Judge K.H Sumathipala, Former Retired High Court Judge. Sudath N. Gopallawa, Former Retired Government Analyst Dr. W.D.S Gunathilake, Senior Attorney–At–Law Mr. Prasantha Lal De Alwis PC, Senior Attorney–At–Law Mr. Amal Randeniya, Consultant Judicial Medical Officer Dr. Channa Perera, Engineer Mr. S. Suriyaarachchi (University of Moratuwa), and Technical Officer Mr. A.M.S Nilan (University of Moratuwa).",
        "The experts have had several sessions so far and are expected to submit their report after concluding its further proceedings, the commission said.",
        "Meanwhile the HRCSL said it has also started an independent inquiry on the alleged violations of the rule of law on 9th and 10th May 2022.",
        "On 9th May 2022, after a discussion at The Temple trees (the official residence of the Prime Minister), a group of people attacked two peaceful protests in front of the Temple Trees and Galle Face (in front of the Presidential Secretariat).",
        "Later violence spread all over the country and the properties of politicians and others were targeted and set on fire. The same day a group of prisoners were assaulted by an unidentified group.",
        "The HRCSL said it believed that the 9th and 10th of May violations led the country to lawlessness and alleged violation of the rule of law.",
        "Therefore, the HRCSL decided to appoint a Special Rapporteur to investigate and report to the HRCSL as to whether the law enforcement authorities provided adequate protection to the people, the damaged houses and in an extension of the efforts taken to uphold the rule of law on 9th and 10th of May 2022 are adequate and in line with the existing legal framework.",
        "Accordingly, the HRCSL appointed a Special Rapporteur for this task, and he has started his mission and is expected to submit his report after concluding its further proceedings, the statement said."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Rambukkana",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "May 9",
          "label": "DATE"
        },
        {
          "text": "10",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "The Human Rights Commission",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Rambukkana",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "19th April",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "April 2022",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "19th April",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Rambukkana",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Kegalle District",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "2 days",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "18th and 19th April 2022",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "one",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the Human Rights Commission",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the 20th",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "24th April 2022",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the HRCSL Act no 21 of 1996",
            "label": "LAW"
          },
          {
            "text": "14",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "HRCSL",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Retired High Court",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "K.H Sumathipala",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Retired High Court",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sudath N. Gopallawa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Retired Government",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "W.D.S Gunathilake",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Prasantha Lal De Alwis",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Amal Randeniya",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Channa Perera",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "S. Suriyaarachchi",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "University of Moratuwa",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "A.M.S Nilan",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "University of Moratuwa",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "HRCSL",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "9th and 10th May 2022",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "9th May 2022",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "two",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Temple Trees",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Presidential Secretariat",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "The same day",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "HRCSL",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the 9th and 10th of May",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "9th and 10th of May 2022",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        []
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "රඹුක්කන වෙඩි තැබීම සහ ප්‍රචණ්ඩත්වය සම්බන්ධයෙන් මානව හිමිකම් කොමිසම විසින් ස්වාධීන පරීක්ෂණ මැයි 9 සහ 10 යන දිනවල ආරම්භ කරයි",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "අප්‍රේල් 19 වන දින රඹුක්කන පොලිස් වෙඩි තැබීමේ සිද්ධිය සම්බන්ධයෙන් ස්වාධීන පරීක්ෂණයක් සහ 2022 මැයි 9 සහ 10 යන දිනවල නීතියේ ආධිපත්‍යය උල්ලංඝනය කිරීම සම්බන්ධයෙන් ස්වාධීන පරීක්ෂණයක් ආරම්භ කර ඇති බව ශ්‍රී ලංකා මානව හිමිකම් කොමිෂන් සභාව (HRCSL) පවසයි.",
        "2022 අප්‍රේල් මාසයේ සිට රට තුළ ඉන්ධන, ගෑස් සහ අත්‍යවශ්‍ය ආහාර හිඟය හේතුවෙන් දීප ව්‍යාප්ත මහජන විරෝධතා අඛණ්ඩව සිදු විය.",
        "අප්‍රේල් 19 වැනි දින කෑගල්ල දිස්ත්‍රික්කයේ රඹුක්කන ඉන්ධන පිරවුම්හලක් අසලට රැස්වූ විරෝධතාකරුවන් පිරිසක් 2022 අප්‍රේල් 18 සහ 19 යන දින දෙක පුරාවට අඛණ්ඩව විරෝධතාවයේ නිරත වූහ. එම විරෝධතාව අතරතුරදී පොලිසිය ගිනි අවි භාවිත කරමින් පිරිස විසුරුවා හැරීමට කටයුතු කර ඇති අතර එයින් එක් අයෙක් මිය ගියේය. විරෝධතාකරුවන් කිහිප දෙනෙකුට තුවාල.",
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකා මානව හිමිකම් කොමිෂන් සභාවේ (HRCSL) නිලධාරීන් කණ්ඩායම පසුගිය 20 වැනිදාම සිදුවීම් දාමය සිදුවූ ස්ථානයට ගොස් මූලික ස්ථාන පරීක්‍ෂණය සහ මූලික විමර්ශනය සිදු කළහ.",
        "2022 අප්‍රේල් 24 වන දින මහජන ආරක්ෂක අමාත්‍යවරයා විසින් වෙඩි තැබීමේ සිද්ධිය සම්බන්ධයෙන් ස්වාධීන පරීක්ෂණයක් පවත්වන ලෙස මානව හිමිකම් කොමිසමෙන් ඉල්ලා තිබුණි. 1996 අංක 21 දරන HRCSL පනත යටතේ 14 වැනි වගන්තිය යටතේ ඉල්ලීම සහ බලය අනුව, HRCSL ස්වාධීන පරීක්ෂණයක් පැවැත්වීම සඳහා ජනවරමක් සහිත බහුවිධ විශේෂඥ මණ්ඩලයක් පත් කළේය.",
        "හිටපු විශ්‍රාමික මහාධිකරණ විනිසුරු කේ.එච් සුමතිපාල, හිටපු විශ්‍රාමික මහාධිකරණ විනිසුරු යන මහත්වරුන්ගෙන් මෙම විද්වත් මණ්ඩලය සමන්විත විය. සුදත් එන්.ගොපල්ලව, හිටපු විශ්‍රාමලත් රජයේ රස පරීක්ෂක ආචාර්ය ඩබ්ලිව්.ඩී.එස් ගුණතිලක, ජ්‍යෙෂ්ඨ නීතිඥ ජනාධිපති නීතිඥ ප්‍රසන්න ලාල් ද අල්විස්, ජ්‍යෙෂ්ඨ නීතිඥ අමල් රන්දෙණිය, උපදේශක අධිකරණ වෛද්‍ය නිලධාරී වෛද්‍ය චන්න පෙරේරා, ඉංජිනේරු එස්.සූරියආරච්චි (මොරටුව විශ්වවිද්‍යාලය), සහ තාක්ෂණ නිලධාරී ඒ.එම්.එස්. නිලාන් මහතා (මොරටුව විශ්වවිද්‍යාලය).",
        "විශේෂඥයින් විසින් මේ වන විට සැසිවාර කිහිපයක් පවත්වා ඇති අතර, එහි ඉදිරි කටයුතු අවසන් කිරීමෙන් පසු ඔවුන්ගේ වාර්තාව ඉදිරිපත් කිරීමට අපේක්ෂා කරන බව කොමිසම පවසයි.",
        "මේ අතර, 2022 මැයි 9 සහ 10 යන දෙදින තුළ නීතියේ ආධිපත්‍යය උල්ලංඝනය කිරීම සම්බන්ධයෙන් ස්වාධීන පරීක්ෂණයක් ද ආරම්භ කර ඇති බව HRCSL ප්‍රකාශ කළේය.",
        "2022 මැයි 9 වන දින අරලියගහ මන්දිරයේ (අගමැති නිල නිවස) පැවති සාකච්ඡාවකින් අනතුරුව අරලියගහ මන්දිරය සහ ගාලු මුවදොර (ජනාධිපති ලේකම් කාර්යාලය ඉදිරිපිට) පැවති සාමකාමී විරෝධතා දෙකකට පිරිසක් පහර දුන්හ.",
        "පසුව ප්‍රචණ්ඩත්වය රට පුරා පැතිර ගිය අතර දේශපාලකයන්ගේ සහ වෙනත් අයගේ දේපළ ඉලක්ක කර ගිනි තැබීය. එදිනම සිරකරුවන් පිරිසකට නාඳුනන පිරිසක් විසින් පහර දෙන ලදී.",
        "මැයි 9 සහ 10 උල්ලංඝනය කිරීම් රට අවනීතියට ගෙන ගිය බවත්, නීතියේ ආධිපත්‍යය උල්ලංඝනය කිරීමක් යැයි කියනු ලබන බවත් තමන් විශ්වාස කරන බව HRCSL පැවසීය.",
        "එබැවින් නීතිය ක්‍රියාත්මක කරන බලධාරීන් ජනතාවට, හානියට පත් නිවාසවලට ප්‍රමාණවත් ආරක්ෂාවක් ලබා දුන්නේද යන්න සහ නීතියේ ආධිපත්‍යය තහවුරු කිරීමට ගන්නා උත්සාහයේ දිගුවක් ලෙස විමර්ශනය කර HRCSL වෙත වාර්තා කිරීම සඳහා විශේෂ වාර්තාකරුවෙකු පත් කිරීමට HRCSL තීරණය කළේය. සහ 2022 මැයි 10 ප්‍රමාණවත් වන අතර පවතින නීතිමය රාමුවට අනුකූල වේ.",
        "ඒ අනුව, HRCSL විසින් මෙම කාර්යය සඳහා විශේෂ වාර්තාකරුවෙකු පත් කළ අතර, ඔහු සිය මෙහෙවර ආරම්භ කර ඇති අතර, එහි ඉදිරි කටයුතු අවසන් කිරීමෙන් පසු සිය වාර්තාව ඉදිරිපත් කිරීමට අපේක්ෂා කරන බව එම නිවේදනයේ සඳහන් වේ."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "රඹුක්කන",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "මැයි 9",
          "label": "DATE"
        },
        {
          "text": "10",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "මානව හිමිකම් කොමිසම",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "රඹුක්කන",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "අප්රේල් 19",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "අප්රේල් 2022",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "අප්රේල් 19",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "රඹුක්කන",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "කෑගල්ල දිස්ත්‍රික්කය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "දින 2 යි",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "2022 අප්‍රේල් 18 සහ 19",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "එක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "මානව හිමිකම් කොමිසම",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "20 වැනි",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "2022 අප්‍රේල් 24",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "1996 අංක 21 දරන HRCSL පනත",
            "label": "LAW"
          },
          {
            "text": "14",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "HRCSL",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "විශ්රාමික මහාධිකරණය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "කේ.එච් සුමතිපාල",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "විශ්රාමික මහාධිකරණය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "සුදත් එන් ගොපල්ලව",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "විශ්‍රාමික රජය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඩබ්ලිව්.ඩී.එස් ගුණතිලක",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ප්‍රසන්ත ලාල් ද අල්විස්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "අමල් රන්දෙණිය",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "චන්න පෙරේරා",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "එස්.සූරියආරච්චි",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "මොරටුව විශ්වවිද්‍යාලය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "A.M.S නිලාන්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "මොරටුව විශ්වවිද්‍යාලය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "HRCSL",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "2022 මැයි 9 සහ 10",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "2022 මැයි 9",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "දෙක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "අරලියගහ මන්දිරය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජනාධිපති ලේකම් කාර්යාලය",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "එදිනම",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "HRCSL",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "මැයි 9 සහ 10",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "2022 මැයි 9 සහ 10",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        []
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "ரம்புக்கன துப்பாக்கிச் சூடு மற்றும் வன்முறை தொடர்பான சுயாதீன விசாரணைகளை மே 9, 10 ஆம் திகதிகளில் HRCSL ஆரம்பிக்கிறது",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "ஏப்ரல் 19ஆம் திகதி ரம்புக்கனையில் இடம்பெற்ற பொலிஸ் துப்பாக்கிச் சூடு சம்பவம் தொடர்பில் சுயாதீன விசாரணையையும், 2022 மே 9 மற்றும் 10ஆம் திகதிகளில் சட்ட விதி மீறல்கள் தொடர்பில் சுயாதீன விசாரணையையும் ஆரம்பித்துள்ளதாக இலங்கை மனித உரிமைகள் ஆணைக்குழு (HRCSL) தெரிவித்துள்ளது.",
        "ஏப்ரல் 2022 முதல் நாட்டில் எரிபொருள், எரிவாயு மற்றும் அத்தியாவசிய உணவுப் பற்றாக்குறை காரணமாக நாடளாவிய ரீதியில் பொதுமக்கள் போராட்டங்கள் தொடர்ந்து நடைபெற்று வருகின்றன.",
        "ஏப்ரல் 19 ஆம் தேதி கேகாலை மாவட்டத்தில் ரம்புக்கனையில் உள்ள எரிபொருள் நிரப்பு நிலையத்திற்கு அருகில் ஒன்று கூடி 2022 ஆம் ஆண்டு ஏப்ரல் 18 மற்றும் 19 ஆம் திகதிகளில் 2 நாட்கள் ஆர்ப்பாட்டத்தில் ஈடுபட்டுள்ளனர். போராட்டத்தின் போது கூட்டத்தை கலைக்க பொலிஸார் துப்பாக்கி பிரயோகம் மேற்கொண்டதில் ஒருவர் உயிரிழந்தார். பல போராட்டக்காரர்களுக்கு காயம்.",
        "இலங்கை மனித உரிமைகள் ஆணைக்குழுவின் (HRCSL) அதிகாரிகள் குழு கடந்த 20ஆம் திகதியே நிகழ்வுகள் இடம்பெற்ற இடத்திற்குச் சென்று முதற்கட்ட ஆய்வு மற்றும் ஆரம்ப விசாரணைகளை மேற்கொண்டது.",
        "24 ஏப்ரல் 2022 அன்று, துப்பாக்கிச் சூடு சம்பவம் குறித்து சுதந்திரமான விசாரணையை நடத்துமாறு பொது பாதுகாப்பு அமைச்சர் மனித உரிமை ஆணையத்திடம் கோரியிருந்தார். 1996 பிரிவு 14 இன் HRCSL சட்டம் எண் 21 இன் கீழ் கோரிக்கை மற்றும் அதிகாரத்திற்கு இணங்க, HRCSL ஒரு சுயாதீனமான விசாரணையை நடத்துவதற்கான ஆணையைக் கொண்ட ஒரு பல்துறை நிபுணர் குழுவை நியமித்தது.",
        "முன்னாள் ஓய்வுபெற்ற உயர்நீதிமன்ற நீதிபதி கே.எச்.சுமதிபால, முன்னாள் ஓய்வுபெற்ற உயர்நீதிமன்ற நீதிபதி ஆகியோரைக் கொண்ட நிபுணர் குழு இடம்பெற்றது. சுதத் என்.கோபல்லவ, முன்னாள் ஓய்வுபெற்ற அரச பகுப்பாய்வாளர் கலாநிதி டபிள்யூ.டி.எஸ் குணதிலக்க, சிரேஷ்ட சட்டத்தரணி திரு. பிரசாந்த லால் டி அல்விஸ் பி.சி., சிரேஷ்ட சட்டத்தரணி திரு. அமல் ரந்தெனிய, ஆலோசகர் நீதித்துறை வைத்திய அதிகாரி டொக்டர் சன்ன பெரேரா, பொறியியலாளர் திரு. எஸ்.சூரியராச்சி (மொரட்டுவ பல்கலைக்கழகம்), மற்றும் தொழில்நுட்ப உத்தியோகத்தர் திரு. ஏ.எம்.எஸ் நிலன் (மொரட்டுவ பல்கலைக்கழகம்).",
        "நிபுணர்கள் இதுவரை பல அமர்வுகளை நடத்தியுள்ளனர் மற்றும் அதன் மேலதிக நடவடிக்கைகளை முடித்த பின்னர் தங்கள் அறிக்கையை சமர்பிப்பார்கள் என்று ஆணையம் தெரிவித்துள்ளது.",
        "இதற்கிடையில், 2022 மே 9 மற்றும் 10 ஆம் தேதிகளில் சட்டத்தின் ஆட்சி மீறல்கள் குறித்து சுயாதீன விசாரணையைத் தொடங்கியுள்ளதாக HRCSL தெரிவித்துள்ளது.",
        "9 மே 2022 அன்று, டெம்பிள் ட்ரீஸில் (பிரதமரின் உத்தியோகபூர்வ இல்லமான) கலந்துரையாடலுக்குப் பிறகு, அலரி மாளிகை மற்றும் காலி முகத்திடலுக்கு (ஜனாதிபதி செயலகத்திற்கு முன்னால்) இரண்டு அமைதியான போராட்டங்களை ஒரு குழுவினர் தாக்கினர்.",
        "பின்னர் நாடு முழுவதும் வன்முறை பரவி அரசியல்வாதிகள் மற்றும் பிறரின் சொத்துக்கள் குறிவைக்கப்பட்டு தீவைக்கப்பட்டன. அதே நாளில் அடையாளம் தெரியாத குழுவினரால் கைதிகள் குழு தாக்கப்பட்டது.",
        "மே மாதம் 9ஆம் மற்றும் 10ஆம் திகதிகளில் இடம்பெற்ற மீறல்கள் நாட்டை சட்டமீறலுக்கு இட்டுச் சென்றதாகவும், சட்டத்தின் ஆட்சி மீறப்பட்டதாகக் கூறப்படும் எனவும் தாம் நம்புவதாக HRCSL தெரிவித்துள்ளது.",
        "எனவே, மக்களுக்கும், சேதமடைந்த வீடுகளுக்கும், சட்ட அமலாக்க அதிகாரிகள் போதிய பாதுகாப்பை வழங்கினரா என்பது குறித்தும், சட்டத்தின் ஆட்சியை நிலைநாட்ட எடுக்கப்பட்ட முயற்சிகளின் நீட்டிப்பு குறித்தும் விசாரித்து அறிக்கை தாக்கல் செய்ய, சிறப்பு அறிக்கையாளரை நியமிக்க, HRCSL முடிவு செய்தது. மற்றும் மே 10, 2022 போதுமானது மற்றும் தற்போதுள்ள சட்ட கட்டமைப்பிற்கு இணங்க உள்ளது.",
        "அதன்படி, HRCSL இந்த பணிக்காக ஒரு சிறப்பு அறிக்கையாளரை நியமித்துள்ளது, மேலும் அவர் தனது பணியைத் தொடங்கியுள்ளார் மற்றும் அதன் அடுத்த நடவடிக்கைகளை முடித்த பின்னர் தனது அறிக்கையை சமர்ப்பிப்பார் என்று எதிர்பார்க்கப்படுகிறது."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ரம்புக்கன",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "மே 9",
          "label": "DATE"
        },
        {
          "text": "10",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "மனித உரிமைகள் ஆணையம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரம்புக்கன",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஏப்ரல் 19",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஏப்ரல் 2022",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஏப்ரல் 19",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரம்புக்கன",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "கேகாலை மாவட்டம்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "2 நாட்கள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "18 மற்றும் 19 ஏப்ரல் 2022",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஒன்று",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "மனித உரிமைகள் ஆணையம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "20 ஆம் தேதி",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "24 ஏப்ரல் 2022",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "HRCSL சட்டம் எண் 21 1996",
            "label": "LAW"
          },
          {
            "text": "14",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "HRCSL",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஓய்வு பெற்ற உயர்நீதிமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "கே.எச் சுமதிபால",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஓய்வு பெற்ற உயர்நீதிமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "சுதத் என்.கோபல்லவ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஓய்வு பெற்ற அரசு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "டபிள்யூ.டி.எஸ் குணதிலக்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "பிரசாந்த லால் டி அல்விஸ்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "அமல் ரந்தெனிய",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "சன்ன பெரேரா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "எஸ்.சூரியாராச்சி",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "மொரட்டுவ பல்கலைக்கழகம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஏ.எம்.எஸ் நிலன்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "மொரட்டுவ பல்கலைக்கழகம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "HRCSL",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "9 மற்றும் 10 மே 2022",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "9 மே 2022",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இரண்டு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "கோவில் மரங்கள்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜனாதிபதி செயலகம்",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "அதே நாள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "HRCSL",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "மே 9 மற்றும் 10 ஆம் தேதிகளில்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "9 மற்றும் 10 மே 2022",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        []
      ]
    }
  }
}