{
  "newspaper_id": "lankadeepa-lk",
  "url": "https://www.lankadeepa.lk/news/චීන-නැවට-හම්බන්තොටට-එන්න-අවසර/101-618054",
  "time_ut": 1660403570,
  "original_lang": "si",
  "original_title": "චීන නැවට හම්බන්තොටට එන්න අවසර",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "The Chinese ship is allowed to come to Hambantota",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "The Ministry of Foreign Affairs of Sri Lanka announced in a statement that the Chinese research vessel Yuan Wang 5 was allowed to anchor at Hambantota port from August 16-22.",
        "In the announcement, the Chinese government informed the Ministry of Foreign Affairs that the Yuan Wang 5 ship could reach Hambantota port on August 16 and requested the Ministry of Foreign Affairs to allow it to anchor at Hambantota from August 16-22 to get fuel and other supplies. is shown.",
        "After considering all the issues, Sri Lanka's Ministry of Foreign Affairs today (13) gave permission to the research ship Yuan Wang 5 to anchor at Hambantota port from August 16-22, it is stated in the announcement.",
        "The Ministry of Foreign Affairs once again emphasized that Sri Lanka's policy is to work with all countries in cooperation and friendship.",
        "The Ministry of Foreign Affairs stated that Sri Lanka will always give priority to the security and cooperation of its neighbour."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Chinese",
          "label": "NORP"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "The Ministry of Foreign Affairs of Sri Lanka",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Chinese",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Yuan Wang",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Hambantota",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "August 16-22",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Chinese",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Ministry of Foreign Affairs",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Hambantota",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "August 16",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Ministry of Foreign Affairs",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "August 16-22",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka's",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ministry of Foreign Affairs",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "13",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Yuan Wang",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Hambantota",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "August 16-22",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "The Ministry of Foreign Affairs",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka's",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "The Ministry of Foreign Affairs",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "චීන නැවට හම්බන්තොටට එන්න අවසර",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "යුවාන් වැන්ග් 5 චීන පර්යේෂණ නෞකාව අගෝස්තු 16-22 දක්වා හම්බන්තොට වරායේ නැංගුරම් ලෑමට අවසර ලබා දුන් බව ශ්‍රී ලංකා විදේශ කටයුතු අමාත්‍යංශය නිවේදනයක් නිකුත් කරමින් ප්‍රකාශ කළේය.",
        "යුවාන් වැන්ග් 5 නෞකාව අගෝස්තු 16 වෙනි දින හම්බන්තොට වරායට ළඟා විය හැකි බව චීන රජය විදේශ කටයුතු අමාත්‍යංශයට දැන්වූ බවත් ඉන්ධන සහ අනෙකුත් සැපයුම් ලබා ගැනීම සඳහා අගෝස්තු 16-22 වෙනි දින දක්වා හම්බන්තොට වාරයේ නැංගුරම් ලෑමට අවසර දෙන ලෙස විදේශ කටයුතු අමාත්‍යංශයෙන් ඉල්ලා සිටි බවත් එම නිවේදනයේ දැක්වේ.",
        "සියලු කාරණා සලකා බැලීමෙන් අනතුරුව අද(13) ශ්‍රී ලංකා විදේශ කටයුතු අමාත්‍යංශය අගෝස්තු 16-22 දක්වා යුවාන් වැන්ග් 5 පර්යේෂණ නෞකාවට හම්බන්තොට වරායේ නැංගුරම් ලෑමට අවසර දුන් බව එම නිවේදනයේ සඳහන් වේ.",
        "සියලු රටවල් සමඟ සහයෝගීත්වයෙන් සහ මිත්‍රත්වයෙන් කටයුතු කිරීම ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ ප්‍රතිපත්තිය බව විදේශ කටයුතු අමාත්‍යංශය නැවත වරක් අවධාරණය කළේය.",
        "අසල්වැසියාගේ ආරක්ෂාව සහ සහයෝගීත්වයට ශ්‍රී ලංකාව සැමවිටම ප්‍රමුඛතාව ලබා දෙන බව විදේශ කටයුතු අමාත්‍යංශය ප්‍රකාශ කළේය."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "චීන",
          "label": "NORP"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ විදේශ කටයුතු අමාත්‍යාංශය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "චීන",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Yuan Wang",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "හම්බන්තොට",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "අගෝස්තු 16-22",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "චීන",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "විදේශ කටයුතු අමාත්යාංශය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "හම්බන්තොට",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "අගෝස්තු 16",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "විදේශ කටයුතු අමාත්යාංශය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "අගෝස්තු 16-22",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "විදේශ කටයුතු අමාත්යංශය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "13",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Yuan Wang",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "හම්බන්තොට",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "අගෝස්තු 16-22",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "විදේශ කටයුතු අමාත්‍යාංශය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "විදේශ කටයුතු අමාත්‍යාංශය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "சீனக் கப்பல் ஹம்பாந்தோட்டைக்கு வர அனுமதிக்கப்பட்டுள்ளது",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "சீன ஆராய்ச்சிக் கப்பலான யுவான் வாங் 5 ஆகஸ்ட் 16 முதல் 22 வரை ஹம்பாந்தோட்டை துறைமுகத்தில் நங்கூரமிட அனுமதிக்கப்பட்டுள்ளதாக இலங்கை வெளிவிவகார அமைச்சு அறிவித்துள்ளது.",
        "அந்த அறிவிப்பில், சீன அரசாங்கம் யுவான் வாங் 5 கப்பல் ஆகஸ்ட் 16 ஆம் தேதி அம்பாந்தோட்டை துறைமுகத்தை அடையலாம் என்றும், எரிபொருள் மற்றும் பிறவற்றைப் பெறுவதற்கு ஆகஸ்ட் 16-22 வரை ஹம்பாந்தோட்டையில் நங்கூரமிட அனுமதிக்குமாறு வெளியுறவு அமைச்சகத்திடம் கோரிக்கை விடுத்துள்ளது. பொருட்கள் காட்டப்பட்டுள்ளன.",
        "அனைத்து விடயங்களையும் பரிசீலித்த இலங்கையின் வெளிவிவகார அமைச்சு யுவான் வாங் 5 என்ற ஆராய்ச்சிக் கப்பலுக்கு ஆகஸ்ட் 16-22 ஆம் திகதிகளில் ஹம்பாந்தோட்டை துறைமுகத்தில் நங்கூரமிடுவதற்கு இன்று (13) அனுமதி வழங்கியுள்ளதாக அந்த அறிவிப்பில் தெரிவிக்கப்பட்டுள்ளது.",
        "அனைத்து நாடுகளுடனும் ஒத்துழைப்புடனும் நட்புறவும் செயற்படுவதே இலங்கையின் கொள்கை என வெளிவிவகார அமைச்சு மீண்டும் வலியுறுத்தியுள்ளது.",
        "அண்டை நாடுகளின் பாதுகாப்பு மற்றும் ஒத்துழைப்புக்கு இலங்கை எப்போதும் முன்னுரிமை அளிக்கும் என வெளிவிவகார அமைச்சு தெரிவித்துள்ளது."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "சீன",
          "label": "NORP"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கையின் வெளிவிவகார அமைச்சு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "சீன",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Yuan Wang",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஹம்பாந்தோட்டை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆகஸ்ட் 16-22",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "சீன",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "வெளியுறவு அமைச்சகம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஹம்பாந்தோட்டை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆகஸ்ட் 16",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "வெளியுறவு அமைச்சகம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆகஸ்ட் 16-22",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கையின்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "வெளிநாட்டு அலுவல்கள் அமைச்சு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "13",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Yuan Wang",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஹம்பாந்தோட்டை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆகஸ்ட் 16-22",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "வெளியுறவு அமைச்சகம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கையின்",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "வெளியுறவு அமைச்சகம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}