{
  "newspaper_id": "ada-lk",
  "url": "https://www.ada.lk/breaking_news/ස්ථාවරය-වෙනස්-වී-ඇත්දැයි-සජිත්-ආණ්ඩුවෙන්-අසයි/11-396693",
  "time_ut": 1661750916,
  "original_lang": "si",
  "original_title": "ස්ථාවරය වෙනස් වී ඇත්දැයි සජිත් ආණ්ඩුවෙන් අසයි",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Sajith asks the government if the position has changed",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "Mr. Sajith Premadasa, the leader of the opposition, asked the government if the stated position of giving the positions of chairmanship of COP and COPA committees to the opposition has changed now.",
        "The leader of the opposition also said that when the current president was working as the prime minister, he announced that the position would be given to the opposition.",
        "He also said that the names of members of Samagi Jana Balavega, Eran Wickramaratne and Kabir Hashim, have been proposed for COP and COPA chairmanships."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Sajith Premadasa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "COP",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "COPA",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "Samagi",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Jana Balavega",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Eran Wickramaratne",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kabir Hashim",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "COP",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "COPA",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "ස්ථාවරය වෙනස් වී ඇත්දැයි සජිත් ආණ්ඩුවෙන් අසයි",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "පාර්ලිමේන්තුවේ කෝප් හා කෝපා කමිටුවල සභාපති ධුර විපක්ෂයට ලබාදෙන බවට සඳහන් කළ ස්ථාවරය මේ වන විට වෙනස්ව ඇත්දැයි විපක්ෂනායක සජිත් ප්‍රේමදාස මහතා ආණ්ඩුවෙන් විමසා සිටියේය.",
        "වත්මන් ජනපතිවරයා අග්‍රාමාත්‍යධුරයේ කටයුතු කරන විට එම ධුර විපක්ෂයට ලබාදෙන බවට ප්‍රකාශ කළ බවද විපක්ෂනායකවරයා පැවැසීය.",
        "කෝප් හා කෝපා සභාපතිධුර සඳහා සමගි ජන බලවේගයේ එරාන් වික්‍රමරත්න හා කබීර් හෂීම් යන මන්ත්‍රීවරුන්ගේ නම් යෝජනා කර ඇති බවද ඔහු පැවැසීය."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "සජිත් ප්‍රේමදාස",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "COP",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "COPA",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "සමගි",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජන බලවේගය",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "එරාන් වික්‍රමරත්න",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "කබීර් හෂීම්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "COP",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "COPA",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "நிலை மாறிவிட்டதா என்று சஜித் அரசாங்கத்திடம் கேட்கிறார்",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "கோப் மற்றும் கோபா குழுக்களின் தலைவர் பதவிகளை எதிர்க்கட்சிகளுக்கு வழங்குவதாக கூறப்பட்ட நிலைப்பாட்டில் தற்போது மாற்றம் ஏற்பட்டுள்ளதா என எதிர்க்கட்சித் தலைவர் திரு.சஜித் பிரேமதாச அரசாங்கத்திடம் வினவினார்.",
        "தற்போதைய ஜனாதிபதி பிரதமராக செயற்படும் போது எதிர்க்கட்சிக்கு அந்த பதவி வழங்கப்படும் என அறிவித்ததாகவும் எதிர்க்கட்சித் தலைவர் தெரிவித்துள்ளார்.",
        "சமகி ஜன பலவேகவின் உறுப்பினர்களான எரான் விக்கிரமரத்ன மற்றும் கபீர் ஹாசிம் ஆகியோரின் பெயர்கள் COP மற்றும் COPA தலைவர் பதவிகளுக்கு முன்மொழியப்பட்டுள்ளதாகவும் அவர் கூறினார்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "சஜித் பிரேமதாச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "சிஓபி",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "COPA",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "சமகி",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜன பலவேகா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "எரான் விக்கிரமரத்ன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "கபீர் ஹாசிம்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "சிஓபி",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "COPA",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}