{
  "newspaper_id": "news-first-lk",
  "url": "https://www.newsfirst.lk/2022/07/21/sri-lanka-police-hunt-for-three-heroin-peddlers-after-rs-380-mn-heroin-bust-in-embilipitiya/",
  "time_ut": 1658401260,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Sri Lanka: Police hunt for three heroin peddlers after Rs. 380 Mn heroin bust in Embilipitiya",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Sri Lanka: Police hunt for three heroin peddlers after Rs. 380 Mn heroin bust in Embilipitiya",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); Sri Lanka Police is seeking public assistance to track down three people wanted in connection to a heroin peddling ring in the country.",
        "On the 11th of July 2022 the Embilipitiya Police arrested two suspects, a mother and son, for the possession of 38 kg and 360 grams of heroin worth over Rs. 380 million.",
        "The suspects were held under detention orders, and investigation revealed that three other suspects were connected to the ring.",
        "The general public is requested to call the following numbers with information regarding the whereabouts of these suspects.",
        "Assistant Director of the Police Narcotic Bureau: 071 859 27 27",
        "Sri Lanka: Police hunt for three heroin peddlers after Rs. 380 Mn heroin bust in Embilipitiya"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "three",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "Mn",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "Embilipitiya",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "News 1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka Police",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "three",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the 11th of July 2022",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Embilipitiya Police",
            "label": "LAW"
          },
          {
            "text": "two",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "38 kg",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "Rs",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "380 million",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "three",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "the Police Narcotic Bureau",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "071",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "three",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Mn",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Embilipitiya",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "ශ්‍රී ලංකාව: රුපියල් කෝටි 100 කට පසු හෙරොයින් ජාවාරම්කරුවන් තිදෙනෙකු සොයා පොලිසිය සොයයි. ඇඹිලිපිටියෙන් මිලියන 380ක හෙරොයින් තොගයක්",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); මෙරට හෙරොයින් ජාවාරමට සම්බන්ධ පුද්ගලයන් තිදෙනෙකු සොයා ගැනීමට ශ්‍රී ලංකා පොලිසිය මහජන සහය පතයි.",
        "2022 ජුලි මස 11 වන දින ඇඹිලිපිටිය පොලිසිය විසින් රුපියල් කෝටි 38 කට අධික වටිනාකමකින් යුත් හෙරොයින් කිලෝග්‍රෑම් 38 යි ග්‍රෑම් 360 ක් සන්තකයේ තබාගෙන සැකකරුවන් දෙදෙනෙකු, මව සහ පුතු අත්අඩංගුවට ගෙන ඇත. මිලියන 380 කි.",
        "සැකකරුවන් රැඳවුම් නියෝග යටතේ රඳවාගෙන සිටි අතර, විමර්ශනවලදී හෙළි වූයේ මෙම මුද්දට තවත් සැකකරුවන් තිදෙනෙකු සම්බන්ධ බවයි.",
        "මෙම සැකකරුවන් සිටින ස්ථාන පිළිබඳ තොරතුරු පහත අංකවලට අමතන ලෙස සාමාන්‍ය ජනතාවගෙන් ඉල්ලා සිටී.",
        "පොලිස් මත්ද්‍රව්‍ය නාශක කාර්යාංශයේ සහකාර අධ්‍යක්ෂ: 071 859 27 27",
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකාව: රුපියල් කෝටි 100 කට පසු හෙරොයින් ජාවාරම්කරුවන් තිදෙනෙකු සොයා පොලිසිය සොයයි. ඇඹිලිපිටියෙන් මිලියන 380ක හෙරොයින් තොගයක්"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "තුන්",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "Mn",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "ඇඹිලිපිටිය",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "News 1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකා පොලිසිය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "තුන්",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "2022 ජූලි 11 වැනිදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඇඹිලිපිටිය පොලිසිය",
            "label": "LAW"
          },
          {
            "text": "දෙක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "කිලෝ ග්රෑම් 38 කි",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "රුපියල්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "මිලියන 380 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "තුන්",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "පොලිස් මත්ද්‍රව්‍ය නාශක කාර්යාංශය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "071",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "තුන්",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Mn",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඇඹිලිපිටිය",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "இலங்கை: ஹெராயின் போதைப் பொருள் கடத்தல்காரர்களை போலீசார் தேடி வருகின்றனர். எம்பிலிப்பிட்டியவில் 380 மில்லியன் ஹெரோயின் கடத்தல்!",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); நாட்டில் ஹெரோயின் கடத்தல் கும்பலுடன் தொடர்புடைய மூவரைக் கண்டுபிடிப்பதற்காக இலங்கை காவல்துறை பொதுமக்களின் உதவியை நாடியுள்ளது.",
        "2022 ஆம் ஆண்டு ஜூலை மாதம் 11 ஆம் திகதி எம்பிலிப்பிட்டிய பொலிஸார் 38 கிலோ 360 கிராம் ஹெரோயின் போதைப்பொருளை வைத்திருந்த தாய் மற்றும் மகன் ஆகிய இரு சந்தேக நபர்களை கைது செய்தனர். 380 மில்லியன்.",
        "சந்தேகநபர்கள் தடுப்புக் காவலில் வைக்கப்பட்டுள்ளனர், மேலும் மூன்று சந்தேக நபர்கள் மோதிரத்துடன் தொடர்புடையவர்கள் என்பது விசாரணையில் தெரியவந்தது.",
        "இந்த சந்தேக நபர்களின் இருப்பிடம் தொடர்பான தகவல்களை பின்வரும் இலக்கங்களுக்கு தொடர்பு கொள்ளுமாறு பொது மக்கள் கேட்டுக்கொள்ளப்படுகிறார்கள்.",
        "பொலிஸ் போதைப்பொருள் பணியகத்தின் உதவிப் பணிப்பாளர்: 071 859 27 27",
        "இலங்கை: ஹெராயின் போதைப் பொருள் கடத்தல்காரர்களை போலீசார் தேடி வருகின்றனர். எம்பிலிப்பிட்டியவில் 380 மில்லியன் ஹெரோயின் கடத்தல்!"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "மூன்று",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "Mn",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "எம்பிலிபிட்டிய",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "News 1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை காவல்துறை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "மூன்று",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஜூலை 11, 2022",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "எம்பிலிபிட்டிய பொலிஸ்",
            "label": "LAW"
          },
          {
            "text": "இரண்டு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "38 கி.கி",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரூ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "380 மில்லியன்",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "மூன்று",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "பொலிஸ் போதைப்பொருள் பணியகம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "071",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "மூன்று",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Mn",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "எம்பிலிபிட்டிய",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}