{
  "newspaper_id": "news-first-lk",
  "url": "https://www.newsfirst.lk/2022/07/23/cpc-assures-sufficient-fuel-reserves-for-a-month/",
  "time_ut": 1658551620,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "CPC assures sufficient fuel reserves for a month",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "CPC assures sufficient fuel reserves for a month",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); The Ceylon Petroleum Corporation assures that there are sufficient diesel reserves in the country for the next 30 days.",
        "Accordingly, the CPC stated that there is enough petrol reserves for 22 days in Sri Lanka as well.",
        "Yesterday, 4,000 metric tons of diesel was distributed to fuel stations all over the island.",
        "The Ceylon Petroleum Corporation also mentioned that 3,000 metric tons of petrol has also been distributed to petrol stations.",
        "Meanwhile, the All Ceylon Petrol Station Owners Association says that the program to provide fuel according to the last number on the number plate of each vehicle, has received a good response..",
        "Its Chairman, Kumara Rajapaksa said that the queues for fuel are also reducing as an effect of this measure.",
        "Meanwhile, Shanta Silva, joint secretary of Ceylon Petroleum Private Tanker Owners Association, also assured that the fuel distribution activities will be continuously carried out.",
        "Govt and Govt approved private schools to resume activities on 25th July"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "CPC",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "a month",
          "label": "DATE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "News 1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "The Ceylon Petroleum Corporation",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the next 30 days",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "CPC",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "22 days",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Yesterday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "4,000 metric tons",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "The Ceylon Petroleum Corporation",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "3,000 metric tons",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the All Ceylon Petrol Station Owners Association",
            "label": "LAW"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Kumara Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Shanta Silva",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ceylon Petroleum Private Tanker Owners Association",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Govt",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "25th July",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "CPC මාසයකට ප්‍රමාණවත් ඉන්ධන සංචිතයක් සහතික කරයි",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); ඉදිරි දින 30 සඳහා ප්‍රමාණවත් ඩීසල් සංචිතයක් රට තුළ පවතින බව ලංකා ඛනිජ තෙල් නීතිගත සංස්ථාව සහතික කරයි.",
        "ඒ අනුව ශ්‍රී ලංකාව තුළද දින 22කට අවශ්‍ය තරම් පෙට්‍රල් සංචිත පවතින බවයි ඛනිජ තෙල් නීතිගත සංස්ථාව ප්‍රකාශ කළේ.",
        "ඊයේ දිනයේදී දිවයින පුරා පිහිටි ඉන්ධන පිරවුම්හල් වෙත ඩීසල් මෙට්‍රික් ටොන් 4000ක් බෙදා හැර තිබෙනවා.",
        "ඉන්ධන පිරවුම්හල් වෙත පෙට්‍රල් මෙට්‍රික් ටොන් 3000ක් ද බෙදා හැර ඇති බව ලංකා ඛනිජ තෙල් නීතිගත සංස්ථාව සඳහන් කරයි.",
        "මේ අතර, එක් එක් වාහනවල අංක තහඩුවේ අවසන් අංකයට අනුව ඉන්ධන ලබාදීමේ වැඩපිළිවෙළට යහපත් ප්‍රතිචාර ලැබී ඇති බව සමස්ත ලංකා ඉන්ධන පිරවුම්හල් හිමියන්ගේ සංගමය පවසයි.",
        "එහි සභාපති කුමාර රාජපක්ෂ මහතා පැවසුවේ, මේ හේතුවෙන් ඉන්ධන පෝලිම් ද අඩුවෙමින් පවතින බවයි.",
        "මේ අතර, ඉන්ධන බෙදා හැරීමේ කටයුතු අඛණ්ඩව සිදු කරන බවට ලංකා ඛනිජ තෙල් පෞද්ගලික ටැංකි හිමියන්ගේ සංගමයේ සම ලේකම් ශාන්ත සිල්වා ද සහතික විය.",
        "රජයේ සහ රජයේ පෞද්ගලික පාසල් ජූලි 25 වැනි දින නැවත ක්‍රියාකාරකම් ආරම්භ කිරීමට අනුමැතිය ලබා දී ඇත"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "CPC",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "මාසයක්",
          "label": "DATE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "News 1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ලංකා ඛනිජ තෙල් නීතිගත සංස්ථාව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉදිරි දින 30",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "CPC",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "දින 22 යි",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ඊයේ",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මෙට්‍රික් ටොන් 4,000 කි",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ලංකා ඛනිජ තෙල් නීතිගත සංස්ථාව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "මෙට්‍රික් ටොන් 3,000 කි",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "සමස්ත ලංකා ඉන්ධන පිරවුම්හල් හිමියන්ගේ සංගමය",
            "label": "LAW"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "කුමාර රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශාන්ත සිල්වා",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ලංකා ඛනිජ තෙල් පෞද්ගලික ටැංකි හිමියන්ගේ සංගමය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "රජය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජූලි 25",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "CPC ஒரு மாதத்திற்கு போதுமான எரிபொருள் இருப்புக்களை உறுதி செய்கிறது",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); அடுத்த 30 நாட்களுக்கு நாட்டில் போதுமான டீசல் இருப்புக்கள் இருப்பதாக இலங்கை பெற்றோலியக் கூட்டுத்தாபனம் உறுதியளிக்கிறது.",
        "அதன்படி, இலங்கையிலும் 22 நாட்களுக்கு போதுமான பெட்ரோல் கையிருப்பு இருப்பதாக CPC தெரிவித்துள்ளது.",
        "நேற்று நாடளாவிய ரீதியில் உள்ள எரிபொருள் நிரப்பு நிலையங்களுக்கு 4000 மெற்றிக் தொன் டீசல் விநியோகிக்கப்பட்டுள்ளது.",
        "மேலும் 3,000 மெட்ரிக் தொன் பெற்றோல் எரிபொருள் நிரப்பு நிலையங்களுக்கு விநியோகிக்கப்பட்டுள்ளதாகவும் இலங்கை பெற்றோலிய கூட்டுத்தாபனம் குறிப்பிட்டுள்ளது.",
        "இதேவேளை, ஒவ்வொரு வாகனத்தின் இலக்கத் தகட்டின் கடைசி இலக்கத்திற்கேற்ப எரிபொருள் வழங்கும் திட்டத்திற்கு நல்ல வரவேற்பு கிடைத்துள்ளதாக அகில இலங்கை பெற்றோல் நிலைய உரிமையாளர்கள் சங்கம் தெரிவித்துள்ளது.",
        "இந்த நடவடிக்கையின் விளைவாக எரிபொருளுக்கான வரிசைகளும் குறைந்து வருவதாக அதன் தலைவர் குமார ராஜபக்ஷ தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "இதேவேளை, எரிபொருள் விநியோக நடவடிக்கைகள் தொடர்ச்சியாக முன்னெடுக்கப்படும் என இலங்கை பெற்றோலிய தனியார் டேங்கர் உரிமையாளர்கள் சங்கத்தின் இணைச் செயலாளர் சாந்த சில்வாவும் உறுதியளித்துள்ளார்.",
        "தனியார் பள்ளிகள் ஜூலை 25 ஆம் தேதி மீண்டும் செயல்பட அரசு மற்றும் அரசு ஒப்புதல் அளித்துள்ளது"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "CPC",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "ஒரு மாதம்",
          "label": "DATE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "News 1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை பெற்றோலியக் கூட்டுத்தாபனம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "அடுத்த 30 நாட்கள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "CPC",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "22 நாட்கள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "நேற்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "4,000 மெட்ரிக் டன்",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை பெற்றோலியக் கூட்டுத்தாபனம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "3,000 மெட்ரிக் டன்",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "அகில இலங்கை பெற்றோல் நிலைய உரிமையாளர்கள் சங்கம்",
            "label": "LAW"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "குமார ராஜபக்ஷ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "சாந்த சில்வா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை பெற்றோலியம் தனியார் தாங்கி உரிமையாளர்கள் சங்கம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "அரசு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜூலை 25",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}