{
  "newspaper_id": "d-b-s-jeyaraj-com",
  "url": "https://dbsjeyaraj.com/dbsj/archives/79023",
  "time_ut": 1660590360,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "China’s satellite tracking vessel Yuan Wang 5  arrives at Sri Lanka’s southern Hambantota Port  on August 16  despite India and the U.S. voicing concern with Colombo over the military ship’s visit.",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "China’s satellite tracking vessel Yuan Wang 5  arrives at Sri Lanka’s southern Hambantota Port  on August 16  despite India and the U.S. voicing concern with Colombo over the military ship’s visit.",
      "author": "Administrator",
      "body_lines": [
        "China’s satellite tracking vessel Yuan Wang 5 on August 16 arrived at Sri Lanka’s southern Hambantota Port, despite India and the U.S. voicing concern with Colombo over the military ship’s visit. Hours after the vessel reached the Sri Lankan port, China said the “marine scientific research” activities of the vessel were “consistent with international law” and did not impact “any other country’s security interests”.",
        "According to Colombo-based official sources, both India and the U.S. had conveyed their apprehensions to the Sri Lankan Government at the highest level, citing the vessel’s “military capabilities” while in the Indian Ocean Region. Apparently addressing the concerns, Chinese Foreign Ministry spokesperson Wang Wenbin on August 16 said, “I want to stress again that the marine scientific research activities of the Yuan Wang 5 ship are consistent with international law and international common practice. They do not affect the security and the economic interests of any country and should not be obstructed by any third party.”",
        "China earlier slammed New Delhi’s apprehensions as “unjustified” and “morally irresponsible”, and “urged” New Delhi to “not disturb normal exchanges” between the two countries. New Delhi “rejected insinuations” that Sri Lanka was pressured.",
        "Although the vessel’s arrival was deferred by a few days subsequent to Colombo’s request, the ship will be docked at Hambantota for a week as was earlier planned. “It will take some time for the Yuan Wang 5 research ship to complete the replenishment of necessary supplies,” Mr. Wang said at the daily briefing in Beijing.",
        "China, he said, is ready to work with Sri Lankan side to “consolidate political mutual trust, deepen win-win cooperation and promote sound and steady development of bilateral relations”. Sri Lanka has maintained strong ties with China over the years. Colombo recently said it firmly backs the ‘One China Policy’, and asked countries to “refrain from provocations”, just after U.S. House Speaker Nancy Pelosi’s controversial visit to Taiwan.",
        "Further, the Sri Lankan Government is counting on China to help in the island’s efforts to restructure its external debt, to be eligible for crucial IMF support amid an agonising economic downturn. Chinese loans account for about 10% of Sri Lanka’s total foreign debt.",
        "China extended about $2.8 billion to Sri Lanka soon after the pandemic hit but has not stepped in much this year, even as the island’s economy collapsed rapidly. Beijing, which announced a $74 million grant in May, is yet to respond to Colombo’s request for bridge financing, reportedly totally $4 billion. India has extended about $3.8 billion this year to help Sri Lanka cope with its economic crisis.",
        "Responding to a query on Chinese assistance, the Foreign Ministry spokesman said, “We feel deeply for the economic and social difficulties that Sri Lankan side is currently facing. For quite some time, we have been providing active support to Sri Lanka for it to overcome the difficulties. That is what we did and what we will continue to do.” A team of Sri Lankan MPs and Chinese officials were present at the ceremonial welcome to the vessel on August 16. “Long live China and Sri Lanka friendship,” a red banner held by the crew on the upper deck of the vessel read.",
        "The Chinese vessel arrived in Sri Lanka a day after India gifted a Dornier marine surveillance aircraft to the island nation to “enhance” its security capabilities."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "China",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "Yuan Wang",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "5",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "Sri Lanka’s",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "Hambantota Port",
          "label": "FAC"
        },
        {
          "text": "August 16",
          "label": "DATE"
        },
        {
          "text": "India",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "U.S.",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "Colombo",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "China",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Yuan Wang",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "August 16",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka’s",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Hambantota Port",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "India",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "U.S.",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Colombo",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Hours",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lankan",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "China",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "India",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "U.S.",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Sri Lankan Government",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Indian Ocean Region",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "Chinese Foreign Ministry",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Wang Wenbin",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "August 16",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "third",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "China",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "New Delhi’s",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "New Delhi",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "two",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "New Delhi",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "a few days",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Colombo",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "a week",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "5",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Wang",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "daily",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Beijing",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "China",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lankan",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "China",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the years",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the ‘One China Policy’",
            "label": "EVENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "U.S. House",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Nancy Pelosi’s",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Taiwan",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the Sri Lankan Government",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "China",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Chinese",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "about 10%",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "China",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "about $2.8 billion",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "this year",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Beijing",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "$74 million",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "May",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Colombo",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "$4 billion",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "India",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "about $3.8 billion",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "this year",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Chinese",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Foreign Ministry",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lankan",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lankan",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Chinese",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "August 16",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "China",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Chinese",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "a day",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "India",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Dornier",
            "label": "LOC"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "චීනයේ චන්ද්‍රිකා ලුහුබැඳීමේ යාත්‍රාව යුවාන් වැන්ග් 5 අගෝස්තු 16 දා ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ දකුණු හම්බන්තොට වරායට පැමිණෙන්නේ ඉන්දියාව සහ එක්සත් ජනපදය හමුදා නෞකාවේ සංචාරය පිළිබඳව කොළඹට කනස්සල්ල පළ කළ ද ය.",
      "author": "පරිපාලක",
      "body_lines": [
        "යුආන් වැන්ග් 5 නම් චීනයේ චන්ද්‍රිකා ලුහුබැඳීමේ යාත්‍රාව අගෝස්තු 16 වැනි දින ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ දකුණු හම්බන්තොට වරායට පැමිණියේ, ඉන්දියාව සහ එක්සත් ජනපදය හමුදා නෞකාවේ සංචාරය සම්බන්ධයෙන් කොළඹට කනස්සල්ල පළ කළ ද ය. යාත්‍රාව ශ්‍රී ලංකා වරායට ළඟා වී පැය කිහිපයකට පසු, චීනය ප්‍රකාශ කළේ යාත්‍රාවේ “සාගර විද්‍යාත්මක පර්යේෂණ” ක්‍රියාකාරකම් “ජාත්‍යන්තර නීතියට අනුකූල” බවත් “වෙනත් කිසිදු රටක ආරක්‍ෂක අවශ්‍යතාවලට” බලපෑමක් නොවන බවත්ය.",
        "කොළඹ පදනම් වූ නිල මූලාශ්‍රවලට අනුව, ඉන්දීය සාගර කලාපයේ සිටියදී යාත්‍රාවේ “මිලිටරි හැකියාවන්” උපුටා දක්වමින් ඉන්දියාව සහ එක්සත් ජනපදය යන දෙකම ශ්‍රී ලංකා රජයට ඉහළම මට්ටමින් තම බිය දන්වා ඇත. පැහැදිලිවම උත්සුකයන් වෙත අවධානය යොමු කරමින්, චීන විදේශ අමාත්‍යාංශයේ ප්‍රකාශක වැන්ග් වෙන්බින් අගෝස්තු 16 දින පැවසුවේ, “යුවාන් වැන්ග් 5 නෞකාවේ සාගර විද්‍යාත්මක පර්යේෂණ ක්‍රියාකාරකම් ජාත්‍යන්තර නීතියට සහ ජාත්‍යන්තර පොදු භාවිතයට අනුකූල බව මට නැවත අවධාරණය කිරීමට අවශ්‍යයි. ඒවා කිසිම රටක ආරක්ෂාවට සහ ආර්ථික අවශ්‍යතාවලට බලපාන්නේ නැති අතර කිසිම තුන්වන පාර්ශ්වයකින් බාධා නොකළ යුතුයි.”",
        "චීනය මීට පෙර නවදිල්ලියේ භීතිකාවන් \"අසාධාරණ\" සහ \"සදාචාරාත්මක වගකීම් විරහිත\" ලෙස විවේචනය කළ අතර, දෙරට අතර \"සාමාන්‍ය හුවමාරුවලට බාධා නොකරන ලෙස\" නවදිල්ලියෙන් \"ඉල්ලුවේය\". ශ්‍රී ලංකාවට පීඩනයක් එල්ල වූ බවට නව දිල්ලිය \"ප්‍රතික්ෂේප කළේය\".",
        "කොළඹගේ ඉල්ලීම මත යාත්‍රාව පැමිණීම දින කිහිපයකින් කල් දැමුවද, කලින් සැලසුම් කර තිබූ පරිදි සතියක කාලයක් නෞකාව හම්බන්තොටට නැංගුරම් ලෑමට නියමිතය. “යුවාන් වැන්ග් 5 පර්යේෂණ නෞකාවට අවශ්‍ය සැපයුම් නැවත පිරවීම සම්පූර්ණ කිරීමට යම් කාලයක් ගතවනු ඇත,” වැන්ග් මහතා බීජිං හි දෛනික සාකච්ඡාවේදී පැවසීය.",
        "“දේශපාලන අන්‍යෝන්‍ය විශ්වාසය තහවුරු කර ගැනීමට, ජයග්‍රාහී සහයෝගීතාව ගැඹුරු කිරීමට සහ ද්විපාර්ශ්වික සබඳතාවල හොඳ සහ ස්ථාවර සංවර්ධනයක් ප්‍රවර්ධනය කිරීමට” ශ්‍රී ලංකා පාර්ශවය සමඟ එක්ව කටයුතු කිරීමට චීනය සූදානම් බව ඔහු පැවසීය. ශ්‍රී ලංකාව වසර ගණනාවක් පුරා චීනය සමඟ ශක්තිමත් සබඳතා පවත්වයි. එක්සත් ජනපද සභා කථානායක නැන්සි පෙලෝසිගේ මතභේදාත්මක තායිවාන සංචාරයෙන් පසුව, කොලඹ මෑතකදී ‘එක් චීනයේ ප්‍රතිපත්තියට’ දැඩි ලෙස සහාය දක්වන බව ප්‍රකාශ කළ අතර “ප්‍රකෝප කිරීම්වලින් වළකින ලෙස” රටවලින් ඉල්ලා සිටියේය.",
        "තවද, වේදනාකාරී ආර්ථික පසුබෑමක් මධ්‍යයේ තීරනාත්මක ජාත්‍යන්තර මූල්‍ය අරමුදලේ සහය සඳහා සුදුසුකම් ලැබීමට, සිය විදේශ ණය ප්‍රතිව්‍යුහගත කිරීමේ දිවයිනේ ප්‍රයත්නයන්ට සහාය වීමට ශ්‍රී ලංකා රජය චීනය කෙරෙහි විශ්වාසය තබයි. ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ මුළු විදේශ ණය ප්‍රමාණයෙන් 10% ක් පමණ චීන ණය වේ.",
        "වසංගතයෙන් පසු චීනය ඩොලර් බිලියන 2.8 ක් පමණ ශ්‍රී ලංකාවට ලබා දුන් නමුත් දිවයිනේ ආර්ථිකය ශීඝ්‍රයෙන් කඩා වැටී තිබියදීත් මේ වසරේ වැඩි පියවරක් ගෙන නැත. මැයි මාසයේදී ඩොලර් මිලියන 74 ක ප්‍රදානයක් ප්‍රකාශයට පත් කළ බීජිං, පාලම් මූල්‍යකරණය සඳහා වූ කොළඹගේ ඉල්ලීමට තවමත් ප්‍රතිචාර දක්වා නැත, වාර්තා වන පරිදි සම්පූර්ණයෙන් ඩොලර් බිලියන 4 කි. ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ ආර්ථික අර්බුදයට මුහුණ දීම සඳහා ඉන්දියාව මේ වසරේ ඩොලර් බිලියන 3.8 ක් පමණ දීර්ඝ කර ඇත.",
        "චීන ආධාර පිළිබඳ විමසුමකට පිළිතුරු දෙමින් විදේශ අමාත්‍යාංශයේ ප්‍රකාශකවරයා පැවසුවේ, “ශ්‍රී ලංකාව දැනට මුහුණ දී සිටින ආර්ථික හා සමාජීය දුෂ්කරතා පිළිබඳව අපට දැඩි ලෙස හැඟෙනවා. සෑහෙන කාලයක් තිස්සේ අපි ශ්‍රී ලංකාවට දුෂ්කරතා මඟහරවා ගැනීම සඳහා ක්‍රියාකාරී සහයෝගය ලබා දෙන්නෙමු. ඒක තමයි අපි කළේ, ඉදිරියටත් කරන්න යන්නේ.” අගෝස්තු 16 වන දින යාත්‍රාව වෙත චාරිත්‍රානුකූලව පිළිගැනීමේ උත්සවයට ශ්‍රී ලංකා මන්ත්‍රීවරුන් සහ චීන නිලධාරීන් කණ්ඩායමක් පැමිණ සිටියහ. \"චීනය සහ ශ්‍රී ලංකා මිත්‍රත්වය දීර්ඝායු වේවා\" යනුවෙන් යාත්‍රාවේ ඉහළ තට්ටුවේ කාර්ය මණ්ඩලය විසින් රඳවාගෙන සිටි රතු බැනරයක සඳහන් විය.",
        "චීන යාත්‍රාව ශ්‍රී ලංකාවට පැමිණියේ ඉන්දියාව සිය ආරක්‍ෂක හැකියාවන් “වැඩිදියුණු කිරීම” සඳහා දිවයිනට ඩෝනියර් සමුද්‍ර නිරීක්ෂණ ගුවන් යානයක් තෑගි කිරීමෙන් දිනකට පසුවය."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "චීනය",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "Yuan Wang",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "5",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "හම්බන්තොට වරාය",
          "label": "FAC"
        },
        {
          "text": "අගෝස්තු 16",
          "label": "DATE"
        },
        {
          "text": "ඉන්දියාව",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "එක්සත් ජනපදය.",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "කොළඹ",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "චීනය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Yuan Wang",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "අගෝස්තු 16",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "හම්බන්තොට වරාය",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "එක්සත් ජනපදය.",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "කොළඹ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "පැය",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලාංකික",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "චීනය",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "එක්සත් ජනපදය.",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකා රජය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දියානු සාගර කලාපය",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "චීන විදේශ අමාත්‍යාංශය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Wang Wenbin",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "අගෝස්තු 16",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "තෙවන",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "චීනය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "නවදිල්ලියේ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "නව දිල්ලි",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "දෙක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "නව දිල්ලි",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "දින කිහිපයක්",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "කොළඹ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "සතියක්",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "5",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "වැන්ග්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "දිනපතා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "බීජිං",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "චීනය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලාංකික",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "චීනය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "වසර",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "'එක් චීනයේ ප්‍රතිපත්තිය'",
            "label": "EVENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "එක්සත් ජනපද මන්දිරය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "නැන්සි පෙලෝසිගේ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "තායිවානය",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකා රජය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "චීනය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "චීන",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "10% පමණ",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "චීනය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඩොලර් බිලියන 2.8 ක් පමණ",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මේ වසරේ",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "බීජිං",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඩොලර් මිලියන 74 කි",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "මැයි",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "කොළඹ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඩොලර් බිලියන 4 යි",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඩොලර් බිලියන 3.8 ක් පමණ",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "මේ වසරේ",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "චීන",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "විදේශ අමාත්‍යාංශය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලාංකික",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලාංකික",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "චීන",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "අගෝස්තු 16",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "චීනය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "චීන",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "දවසක්",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඩෝනියර්",
            "label": "LOC"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "சீனாவின் செயற்கைக்கோள் கண்காணிப்பு கப்பலான யுவான் வாங் 5 ஆகஸ்ட் 16 அன்று இலங்கையின் தெற்கு ஹம்பாந்தோட்டை துறைமுகத்தை வந்தடைகிறது, இராணுவக் கப்பலின் வருகை குறித்து கொழும்பில் இந்தியாவும் அமெரிக்காவும் கவலை தெரிவித்த போதிலும்.",
      "author": "நிர்வாகி",
      "body_lines": [
        "சீனாவின் செயற்கைக்கோள் கண்காணிப்பு கப்பல் யுவான் வாங் 5 ஆகஸ்ட் 16 அன்று இலங்கையின் தெற்கு அம்பாந்தோட்டை துறைமுகத்தை வந்தடைந்தது, இராணுவக் கப்பலின் வருகை குறித்து கொழும்பில் இந்தியாவும் அமெரிக்காவும் கவலை தெரிவித்த போதிலும். கப்பல் இலங்கை துறைமுகத்தை அடைந்த சில மணி நேரங்களுக்குப் பிறகு, கப்பலின் \"கடல் அறிவியல் ஆராய்ச்சி\" நடவடிக்கைகள் \"சர்வதேச சட்டத்திற்கு இணங்க\" மற்றும் \"வேறு எந்த நாட்டின் பாதுகாப்பு நலன்களையும்\" பாதிக்கவில்லை என்று சீனா கூறியது.",
        "கொழும்பை தளமாகக் கொண்ட உத்தியோகபூர்வ ஆதாரங்களின்படி, இந்தியப் பெருங்கடல் பிராந்தியத்தில் இருந்தபோது கப்பலின் \"இராணுவ திறன்களை\" மேற்கோள் காட்டி, இந்தியா மற்றும் அமெரிக்கா ஆகிய இரண்டும் இலங்கை அரசாங்கத்திற்கு உயர் மட்டத்தில் தங்கள் அச்சங்களைத் தெரிவித்துள்ளன. சீனாவின் வெளியுறவு அமைச்சகத்தின் செய்தித் தொடர்பாளர் ஆகஸ்ட் 16 அன்று, வெளிப்படையாக கவலைகளை உரையாற்றினார், \"யுவான் வாங் 5 கப்பலின் கடல் அறிவியல் ஆராய்ச்சி நடவடிக்கைகள் சர்வதேச சட்டம் மற்றும் சர்வதேச பொதுவான நடைமுறைக்கு இசைவானவை என்பதை நான் மீண்டும் வலியுறுத்த விரும்புகிறேன். அவை எந்தவொரு நாட்டின் பாதுகாப்பு மற்றும் பொருளாதார நலன்களை பாதிக்காது மற்றும் மூன்றாம் தரப்பினரால் தடுக்கப்படக்கூடாது.",
        "சீனா முன்னதாக புது தில்லியின் அச்சங்களை \"நியாயமற்றது\" மற்றும் \"தார்மீக பொறுப்பற்றது\" என்று சாடியது, மேலும் இரு நாடுகளுக்கு இடையேயான \"சாதாரண பரிமாற்றங்களைத் தொந்தரவு செய்ய வேண்டாம்\" என்று புதுடெல்லியை \"வற்புறுத்தியது\". இலங்கைக்கு அழுத்தம் கொடுக்கப்பட்டதாக புதுடில்லி \"நிராகரித்தது\".",
        "கொழும்பின் கோரிக்கையை அடுத்து கப்பலின் வருகை சில நாட்களுக்கு ஒத்திவைக்கப்பட்டாலும், முன்னர் திட்டமிட்டபடி ஒரு வாரத்திற்கு அம்பாந்தோட்டையில் கப்பல் நிறுத்தப்படும். \"யுவான் வாங் 5 ஆராய்ச்சிக் கப்பல் தேவையான பொருட்களை நிரப்புவதற்கு சிறிது நேரம் எடுக்கும்\" என்று பெய்ஜிங்கில் தினசரி மாநாட்டில் திரு. வாங் கூறினார்.",
        "\"அரசியல் பரஸ்பர நம்பிக்கையை பலப்படுத்தவும், வெற்றி-வெற்றி ஒத்துழைப்பை ஆழப்படுத்தவும், இருதரப்பு உறவுகளின் உறுதியான மற்றும் நிலையான வளர்ச்சியை மேம்படுத்தவும்\" இலங்கை தரப்புடன் இணைந்து பணியாற்ற சீனா தயாராக உள்ளது என்றார். பல ஆண்டுகளாக சீனாவுடன் இலங்கை வலுவான உறவுகளைப் பேணி வருகிறது. அண்மையில் கொழும்பு, ‘ஒன் சீனா கொள்கையை’ உறுதியாக ஆதரிப்பதாகக் கூறியதுடன், அமெரிக்க நாடாளுமன்ற சபாநாயகர் நான்சி பெலோசியின் சர்ச்சைக்குரிய தைவான் பயணத்திற்குப் பிறகு, “ஆத்திரமூட்டல்களைத் தவிர்க்குமாறு” நாடுகளைக் கேட்டுக் கொண்டது.",
        "மேலும், இலங்கை அரசாங்கம் தனது வெளிநாட்டுக் கடனை மறுசீரமைப்பதற்கான தீவின் முயற்சிகளுக்கு உதவுவதற்கு சீனாவை நம்புகிறது, இது ஒரு வேதனையான பொருளாதார வீழ்ச்சிக்கு மத்தியில் முக்கியமான சர்வதேச நாணய நிதியத்தின் ஆதரவைப் பெறுவதற்குத் தகுதி பெறுகிறது. இலங்கையின் மொத்த வெளிநாட்டுக் கடனில் சுமார் 10% சீனக் கடன்கள்.",
        "தொற்றுநோய் தாக்குதலுக்குப் பிறகு சீனா சுமார் 2.8 பில்லியன் டாலர்களை இலங்கைக்கு நீட்டித்துள்ளது, ஆனால் தீவின் பொருளாதாரம் வேகமாக சரிந்தபோதும், இந்த ஆண்டு அதிகம் அடியெடுத்து வைக்கவில்லை. மே மாதம் $74 மில்லியன் மானியத்தை அறிவித்த பெய்ஜிங், பாலம் நிதியுதவிக்கான கொழும்பின் கோரிக்கைக்கு இன்னும் பதிலளிக்கவில்லை, மொத்தம் $4 பில்லியன் என்று கூறப்படுகிறது. இலங்கையின் பொருளாதார நெருக்கடியைச் சமாளிக்க இந்தியா இந்த ஆண்டு சுமார் 3.8 பில்லியன் டாலர்களை நீட்டித்துள்ளது.",
        "சீன உதவி குறித்த கேள்விக்கு பதிலளித்த வெளிவிவகார அமைச்சின் பேச்சாளர், “இலங்கை தரப்பு தற்போது எதிர்கொள்ளும் பொருளாதார மற்றும் சமூக சிரமங்களை நாங்கள் ஆழமாக உணர்கிறோம். சில காலமாக, சிரமங்களை சமாளிக்க இலங்கைக்கு நாங்கள் தீவிர ஆதரவை வழங்கி வருகிறோம். அதைத்தான் நாங்கள் செய்தோம், தொடர்ந்து செய்வோம். ஆகஸ்ட் 16 அன்று கப்பலுக்கு சம்பிரதாய வரவேற்பு அளிக்கும் நிகழ்வில் இலங்கை எம்.பி.க்கள் மற்றும் சீன அதிகாரிகள் குழு கலந்து கொண்டனர். \"சீனா மற்றும் இலங்கை நட்புறவு வாழ்க\" என்று கப்பலின் மேல் தளத்தில் பணியாளர்கள் வைத்திருந்த சிவப்பு நிற பதாகை எழுதப்பட்டிருந்தது.",
        "இந்தியா தனது பாதுகாப்பு திறன்களை \"மேம்படுத்த\" தீவு நாட்டிற்கு டோர்னியர் கடல் கண்காணிப்பு விமானத்தை பரிசாக வழங்கிய ஒரு நாளுக்குப் பிறகு சீனக் கப்பல் இலங்கையை வந்தடைந்தது."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "சீனா",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "Yuan Wang",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "5",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "இலங்கையின்",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "அம்பாந்தோட்டை துறைமுகம்",
          "label": "FAC"
        },
        {
          "text": "ஆகஸ்ட் 16",
          "label": "DATE"
        },
        {
          "text": "இந்தியா",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "எங்களுக்கு.",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "கொழும்பு",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "சீனா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Yuan Wang",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆகஸ்ட் 16",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கையின்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "அம்பாந்தோட்டை துறைமுகம்",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்தியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "எங்களுக்கு.",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "கொழும்பு",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "மணி",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "சீனா",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இந்தியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "எங்களுக்கு.",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை அரசு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்தியப் பெருங்கடல் பகுதி",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "சீன வெளியுறவு அமைச்சகம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Wang Wenbin",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆகஸ்ட் 16",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "மூன்றாவது",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "சீனா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "புது டெல்லியின்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "புது தில்லி",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இரண்டு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "புது தில்லி",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஒரு சில நாட்கள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "கொழும்பு",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஒரு வாரம்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "5",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "வாங்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "தினசரி",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "பெய்ஜிங்",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "சீனா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சீனா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆண்டுகள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "‘ஒரு சீனா கொள்கை’",
            "label": "EVENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "அமெரிக்க மாளிகை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "நான்சி பெலோசியின்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "தைவான்",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை அரசு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "சீனா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சீன",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "சுமார் 10%",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "சீனா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சுமார் $2.8 பில்லியன்",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்த வருடம்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "பெய்ஜிங்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "$74 மில்லியன்",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "மே",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "கொழும்பு",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "$4 பில்லியன்",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்தியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சுமார் $3.8 பில்லியன்",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்த வருடம்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "சீன",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "வெளியுறவு அமைச்சகம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "சீன",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆகஸ்ட் 16",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சீனா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "சீன",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஒரு நாள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்தியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "டோர்னியர்",
            "label": "LOC"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}