{
  "newspaper_id": "island-lk",
  "url": "http://island.lk/ranil-has-neither-learned-nor-departed/",
  "time_ut": 1657968960,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Ranil has neither learned nor departed",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Ranil has neither learned nor departed",
      "author": "Thilina Walpola",
      "body_lines": [
        "Acting President Ranil Wickremesinghe’s fidelity to his alma mater, Royal College, is very well known. He has long been accused of cronyism concerning his batch mates and schoolmates in the school “where our fathers learned the way before us.” In fact, it had been made public not very long ago that he and his wife, Maithree, who are childless, will leave their recently torched Fifth Lane, Kollupitiya home to Royal College. That venerable institution is but a stone’s throw away from the Wickremesinghe home. Given his connections with and affection for his old school, he would be more than familiar with its Latin motto, Disce Aut Disce De – Learn or Depart. But this, unfortunately is what Wickremesinghe has failed to do. The country awaits his resignation. He awaits election as president to serve out the balance of Gotabaya Rajapaksa’s term.",
        "Ranil Wickremesinghe continues in office, allegedly minding the shop for the discredited Rajapaksas despite extensive public demands for his resignation. Wickremesinghe was born with the proverbial silver spoon in his mouth. He is a grandson of D.R. Wijewardene, the Beaverbrook of what was then Ceylon, who through his newspaper empire influenced the politics of this country and the direction of its governance, perhaps more than most others, before and after Independence. His father, Esmond Wickremesinghe, who succeeded Wijewardene on the editorial throne at Lake House, was well known for his skills at political maneuver. Esmond is credited for the defeat of Mrs. Sirima Bandaranaike’s left-backed government in 1964. He played a significant role in the election of its UNP successor in 1965 disproving Prime Minister SWRD Bandaranaike’s assertion in 1956 that “the last nail had been drive into the UNP’s coffin.”",
        "The political journey of Ranil Wickremesinghe began at an auspicious moment months before the 1977 landslide election victory of his kinsman, J.R. Jayewardene, who won an unprecedented five sixths majority in parliament. JRJ who by this victory banished what had been a powerful left movement in this country to zero representation in the legislature, appointed RW elected MP for Biyagama as deputy minister of foreign affairs. Incidentally Biyagama is close to Sedawatte where the Wijewardenes have their roots. Wickremesinghe was then barely 28-years old. The foreign ministry was newly created, with what was previously styled the ministry of defence and external affairs held by the prime minister. Thus Ranil assumed what was perhaps the most prestigious deputy ministry in the newly elected Jayewardene government.",
        "Within a very short period, Uncle Dickie gave him full cabinet rank as minister of youth affairs and employment. Thereafter he was given further responsibility as minister of education. Clearly JRJ saw succession potential in RW who however, was not able to outshine either Gamini Dissanayake or Lalith Athulathmudai fiercely battling to succeed Jayewardene together with then Prime Minister R. Premadasa. The late Sarath Muttetuwegama once said that Gamini and Lalith were playing the game on one pitch while the prime minister was batting on another. However that be, Premadasa got rid of both Dissanayake and Athulathmudali who colluded to impeach him while Ranil remained loyal. This paid off and Wickremesinghe won the first of his six terms as prime minister following Premadasa’s assassination.",
        "All that is now water under the bridge. To the detriment on Sri Lanka, gripped today in a state of near anarchy, there is no clarity of what will follow. The going, going Gota has now finally gone, having emailed his resignation on Thursday from the Sri Lanka High Commission in Singapore. He is believed bound for the Middle East, probably Dubai, with the United Arab Emirates reputed to be a haven for fleeing dictators from Pakistan, Bangladesh, Afghanistan and Thailand among others. The city is also believed to be a safe destination for ‘hot’ money from many parts of the world. Wherever GR is headed, the U.S, having refused him entry following his renunciation of citizenship of that country (but his wife and son are U.S. citizen), it is unlikely that he will be back here in the absence of a dramatic reversal of fortunes. GR picked RW to replace MR as prime minister, following the latter’s ignominiously forced exit. This despite RW’s recent record of leading the UNP to zero at the last election. This maneuver was obviously a move to protect Rajapaksa interests as RW is alleged to have done during yahapalana period. Remember his appointment as prime minister was widely derided by calling him Ranil Rajapaksa.",
        "Unfortunately the political bushfire now engulfing this nation had totally submerged the economic crisis which, more than anything else, is crying for solution. The people are less interested in Gotabaya’s successor than in when they will get fuel and gas and the cost of living halted even at its present levels. The political sense as this was being written was that Wickremesinghe will run for president when parliament next week elects one among their number to serve GR’s balance term. Various names have been mentioned as aspirants but the bottom line is that the SLPP, if it stands united, can ensure the election of the candidate of it choice. RW remained prime minister these few weeks thanks to SLPP support. Basil Rajapaksa, the SLPP puppeteer, is still here despite his best efforts to get out. Can he still manage to pull the strings for RW’s benefit? If that be so, the Aragalaya will attract fresh momentum.",
        "Leave a Reply Cancel replyYour email address will not be published. Required fields are marked *Comment Name *",
        "Save my name, email, and website in this browser for the next time I comment."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Royal College",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Maithree",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Fifth Lane",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kollupitiya",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Royal College",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "Latin",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Disce Aut Disce De",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Depart",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Gotabaya Rajapaksa’s",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Rajapaksas",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "D.R. Wijewardene",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Esmond Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Wijewardene",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Lake House",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "Esmond",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sirima Bandaranaike",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "1964",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "UNP",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "1965",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "SWRD Bandaranaike",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "1956",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "UNP",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "an auspicious moment months",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "1977",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "J.R. Jayewardene",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "five",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "zero",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Biyagama",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Biyagama",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Wijewardenes",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "28-years old",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the ministry of defence and external affairs",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ranil",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Jayewardene",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Uncle Dickie",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "RW",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Gamini Dissanayake",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "R. Premadasa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sarath Muttetuwegama",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Gamini",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Lalith",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "one",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Premadasa",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Dissanayake",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Athulathmudali",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ranil",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "first",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "six",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Premadasa",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Gota",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Thursday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Sri Lanka High Commission",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "Singapore",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Middle East",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "Dubai",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the United Arab Emirates",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Pakistan",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Bangladesh",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Afghanistan",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Thailand",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "U.S",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "U.S.",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "RW",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "MR",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "UNP",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "zero",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Rajapaksa",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "RW",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ranil Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Gotabaya",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "next week",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "these few weeks",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Basil Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "SLPP",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Aragalaya",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [],
        []
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "රනිල් ඉගෙන ගත්තෙත් නැහැ, ගියෙත් නැහැ",
      "author": "තිළිණ වල්පොල",
      "body_lines": [
        "වැඩබලන ජනාධිපති රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතා රාජකීය විද්‍යාලයට දක්වන විශ්වාසවන්තකම ඉතා ප්‍රසිද්ධය. “අපේ පියවරුන් අපට පෙර ඉගෙන ගත්” පාසලේ ඔහුගේ කණ්ඩායම් සගයන් සහ පාසල් මිතුරන් සම්බන්ධයෙන් ඔහුට බොහෝ කලක සිට ගජමිතුරු චෝදනා එල්ල වී තිබේ. ඇත්ත වශයෙන්ම, දරුවන් නොමැති ඔහු සහ ඔහුගේ බිරිඳ මෛත්‍රී මෑතකදී ගිනිබත් කරන ලද ඔවුන්ගේ පස්වන පටුමග, කොල්ලුපිටියේ රාජකීය විද්‍යාලයට යන බව බොහෝ කලකට පෙර ප්‍රසිද්ධියට පත් විය. එම ගෞරවනීය ආයතනය ඇත්තේ වික්‍රමසිංහ නිවසට ගලක් ඈතිනි. ඔහුගේ පැරණි පාසල සමඟ ඇති සබඳතා සහ සෙනෙහස සැලකිල්ලට ගත් විට, ඔහු එහි ලතින් ආදර්ශ පාඨය වන Disce Aut Disce De - Learn or Depart යන්නට වඩා හුරුපුරුදු වනු ඇත. නමුත් අවාසනාවකට වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතාට කිරීමට නොහැකි වී ඇත්තේ මෙයයි. ඔහුගේ ඉල්ලා අස්වීම රටම බලා සිටී. ඔහු ජනාධිපති ලෙස තේරී පත්වන තෙක් බලා සිටින්නේ ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂගේ ධූර කාලයෙහි ඉතිරිය ඉටු කිරීමටය.",
        "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතා සිය ඉල්ලා අස්වන ලෙස මහජනතාවගේ විස්තීර්ණ ඉල්ලීම් නොතකා අපකීර්තියට පත් රාජපක්ෂලාට කඩේ යන බවට චෝදනා කරමින් තවදුරටත් ධුරයේ කටයුතු කරයි. වික්‍රමසිංහ උපන්නේ රිදී හැන්ද කටේ තබාගෙනය. ඔහු ඩී.ආර්. විජේවර්ධන, නිදහසට පෙර සහ පසුව, ඔහුගේ පුවත්පත් අධිරාජ්‍යය හරහා මේ රටේ දේශපාලනයට සහ එහි පාලනයේ දිශානතියට, සමහර විට අනෙක් බොහෝ දෙනෙකුට වඩා බලපෑම් කළ, එවකට ලංකාවේ වූ බීවර්බෲක් ය. විජේවර්ධනගෙන් පසු ලේක්හවුස් ආයතනයේ කතුවැකි සිංහාසනයට පත් වූ ඔහුගේ පියා එස්මන්ඩ් වික්‍රමසිංහ දේශපාලන උපාමාරුවල දක්ෂතා සම්බන්ධයෙන් ප්‍රකට විය. 1964 දී සිරිමා බණ්ඩාරනායක මැතිනියගේ වාමාංශික ආන්ඩුව පරාජය කිරීමේ ගෞරවය හිමිවන්නේ එස්මන්ඩ් ය. 1965 දී එහි එජාප අනුප්‍රාප්තිකයා තෝරා පත් කර ගැනීමේදී ඔහු සැලකිය යුතු කාර්යභාරයක් ඉටු කළේ, 1956 දී අගමැති එස්.ඩබ්ලිව්.ආර්.ඩී. එජාපයේ මිනී පෙට්ටිය.”",
        "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහගේ දේශපාලන ගමන ආරම්භ වූයේ 1977 පාර්ලිමේන්තුවේ පෙර නොවූ විරූ හයෙන් පහක බලයක් ලබාගත් තම ඥාති මිත්‍ර ජේ.ආර්.ජයවර්ධනගේ අතිවිශිෂ්ට මැතිවරණ ජයග්‍රහණයට මාස කිහිපයකට පෙර සුබ මොහොතකය. මේ ජයග්‍රහණයෙන් මේ රටේ ප්‍රබල වමේ ව්‍යාපාරයක් වූ ව්‍යවස්ථාදායකයේ නියෝජනය ශුන්‍යයට පන්නා දැමූ JRJ විදේශ කටයුතු නියෝජ්‍ය අමාත්‍යවරයා ලෙස තේරී පත් වූ බියගම මන්ත්‍රී ආර්.ඩබ්ලිව්. අහඹු ලෙස බියගම විජේවර්ධනලාගේ මුල් ඇති සේදවත්තට ආසන්නය. එවිට වික්‍රමසිංහගේ වයස යන්තම් අවුරුදු 28 කි. විදේශ අමාත්‍යාංශය අලුතින් නිර්මාණය කරන ලද අතර, මීට පෙර අග්‍රාමාත්‍යවරයා විසින් දැරූ ආරක්ෂක සහ විදේශ කටයුතු අමාත්‍යාංශය ලෙස හැඩගස්වා ඇත. මේ අනුව, අලුතින් පත් වූ ජයවර්ධන ආණ්ඩුවේ කීර්තිමත්ම නියෝජ්‍ය අමාත්‍යාංශය කුමක්දැයි රනිල් භාර ගත්තේය.",
        "ඉතා කෙටි කාලයක් තුළ ඩිකී මාමා ඔහුට තරුණ කටයුතු හා රැකියා ඇමති ලෙස සම්පූර්ණ කැබිනට් නිලය ලබා දුන්නේය. ඉන් අනතුරුව අධ්‍යාපන අමාත්‍යවරයා ලෙස ඔහුට තවදුරටත් වගකීම පැවරුණා. කෙසේ වෙතත්, ජයවර්ධනගේ අනුප්‍රාප්තිකයා වීමට එවකට අග්‍රාමාත්‍ය ආර්. ප්‍රේමදාස සමඟ එක්ව දැඩි සටනක නිරත වූ ගාමිණී දිසානායක හෝ ලලිත් ඇතුලත්මුදායි හෝ අභිබවා යාමට නොහැකි වූ RW තුළ JRJ අනුප්‍රාප්තික විභවය දුටු බව පැහැදිලිය. දිවංගත සරත් මුත්තෙටුවේගම වරක් ප්‍රකාශ කළේ ගාමිණී සහ ලලිත් එක් පිට්ටනියක ක්‍රීඩා කරන අතර අගමැතිවරයා තවත් තණතීරුවක ක්‍රීඩා කරන බවයි. කෙසේ වෙතත්, රනිල් පක්ෂපාතීව සිටියදී තමාට දෝෂාභියෝගයක් ගෙන ඒමට කුමන්ත්‍රණය කළ දිසානායක සහ ඇතුලත්මුදලි යන දෙදෙනාම ප්‍රේමදාස ඉවත් කළේය. මෙය සාර්ථක වූ අතර වික්‍රමසිංහ ප්‍රේමදාස ඝාතනයෙන් පසු අගමැති ධුර කාලය හයෙන් පළමු අවස්ථාව ජයග්‍රහණය කළේය.",
        "ඒ සියල්ල දැන් පාලම යට ජලයයි. අරාජිකත්වයට ආසන්න තත්ත්වයක අද ග්‍රහණය වී ඇති ශ්‍රී ලංකාවට අවාසිදායක ලෙස, ඊළඟට කුමක් සිදුවේද යන්න පිළිබඳ පැහැදිලි බවක් නොමැත. සිංගප්පූරුවේ ශ්‍රී ලංකා මහ කොමසාරිස් කාර්යාලයට බ්‍රහස්පතින්දා සිය ඉල්ලා අස්වීමේ ලිපිය විද්‍යුත් තැපෑලෙන් එවා ඇති ගෝඨා දැන් ගොස් ඇත. එක්සත් අරාබි එමීර් රාජ්‍යය පාකිස්තානය, බංග්ලාදේශය, ඇෆ්ගනිස්ථානය සහ තායිලන්තය වැනි රටවලින් පලා යන ඒකාධිපතියන් සඳහා තෝතැන්නක් ලෙස ප්‍රසිද්ධියට පත් වූ ඔහු මැදපෙරදිගට, සමහරවිට ඩුබායි වෙත බැඳී ඇතැයි විශ්වාස කෙරේ. මෙම නගරය ලෝකයේ බොහෝ ප්‍රදේශවලින් ‘උණුසුම්’ මුදල් සඳහා ආරක්ෂිත ගමනාන්තයක් ලෙස ද විශ්වාස කෙරේ. ජීආර් කොතැනට ගියත්, ඔහු එම රටේ පුරවැසිභාවය අත්හැරීමෙන් පසු එක්සත් ජනපදය ඔහුට ඇතුළුවීම ප්‍රතික්ෂේප කර ඇත (නමුත් ඔහුගේ බිරිඳ සහ පුතා එක්සත් ජනපද පුරවැසියෙකි), වාසනාවේ නාටකාකාර ආපසු හැරීමක් නොමැති විට ඔහු නැවත මෙහි පැමිණෙනු ඇතැයි සිතිය නොහැක. ජීආර් විසින් අගමැති ලෙස එම්ආර් වෙනුවට ආර්ඩබ්ලිව්ව තෝරා ගන්නා ලදී, පසුව ඔහුගේ නින්දිත ලෙස බලහත්කාරයෙන් ඉවත් විය. මෙය පසුගිය මැතිවරණයේදී එජාපය බිංදුවට ගෙනයාමේ RW ගේ මෑත වාර්තාව තිබියදීය. මෙම උපාමාරුව පැහැදිලිවම රාජපක්ෂලාගේ අවශ්‍යතා ආරක්‍ෂා කිරීමේ පියවරක් විය. යහපාලන සමයේ RW කළා යැයි කියනු ලැබේ. ඔහු අගමැති ධූරයට පත් කිරීම රනිල් රාජපක්‍ෂ ලෙස හඳුන්වමින් බොහෝ දෙනාගේ උපහාසයට ලක් වූ බව මතක තබා ගන්න.",
        "අවාසනාවකට මෙන්, දැන් මේ ජාතිය ගිලගෙන ඇති දේශපාලන ලැව්ගින්න, අන් සියල්ලටම වඩා, විසඳුම් ඉල්ලා හඬා වැලපෙන ආර්ථික අර්බුදය මුළුමනින්ම යටපත් කර තිබුණි. තමන්ට ඉන්ධන සහ ගෑස් ලැබෙන්නේ කවදාද යන්නට වඩා ගෝඨාභයගේ අනුප්‍රාප්තිකයා ගැන ජනතාව උනන්දු වන්නේ අඩුවෙන් වන අතර ජීවන වියදම වර්තමාන මට්ටමෙන් පවා නතර වේ. මෙය ලියා ඇති දේශපාලන අර්ථය වූයේ ලබන සතියේ පාර්ලිමේන්තුව ජීආර්ගේ ඉතිරි ධුර කාලය සඳහා ඔවුන්ගේ සංඛ්‍යාවෙන් කෙනෙකු තෝරා ගන්නා විට වික්‍රමසිංහ ජනාධිපති ධුරයට තරඟ කරන බවයි. අපේක්‍ෂකයන් ලෙස විවිධ නම් සඳහන් වී ඇති නමුත් අවසාන කරුණ නම් ශ්‍රී ලංකා පොදුජන පෙරමුණ එක්සත්ව සිටින්නේ නම් තමන් කැමති අපේක්ෂකයා තෝරා පත් කර ගැනීම සහතික කළ හැකි බවයි. SLPP සහයෝගයට ස්තුතිවන්ත වන්නට RW මේ සති කිහිපයේ අගමැති ලෙස කටයුතු කළේය. ශ්‍රී ලංකා පොදුජන පෙරමුණේ රූකඩකාරයා වන බැසිල් රාජපක්ෂ එළියට යාමට කොතරම් උත්සාහ කළත් තවමත් මෙහි සිටී. ඔහුට තවමත් RW ගේ ප්‍රයෝජනය සඳහා නූල් අදින්නට සමත් විය හැකිද? එය එසේ නම්, අරගලය නැවුම් ගම්‍යතාවයක් ආකර්ෂණය වනු ඇත.",
        "පිළිතුරක් දෙන්න පිළිතුර අවලංගු කරන්න ඔබගේ විද්‍යුත් තැපැල් ලිපිනය ප්‍රකාශයට පත් නොකෙරේ. අවශ්‍ය ක්ෂේත්‍ර සලකුණු කර ඇත *අදහස් නම *",
        "මම ඊළඟ වතාවේ අදහස් දැක්වීම සඳහා මගේ නම, විද්‍යුත් තැපෑල සහ වෙබ් අඩවිය මෙම බ්‍රවුසරයේ සුරකින්න."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "රාජකීය විද්‍යාලය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "මෛත්‍රී",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "පස්වන පටුමග",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "කොල්ලුපිටිය",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "රාජකීය විද්‍යාලය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "ලතින්",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Disce Aut Disce De",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "පිටත් වෙනවා",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂගේ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "රාජපක්ෂලා",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ආචාර්ය. විජේවර්ධනයි",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "එස්මන්ඩ් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "විජේවර්ධනයි",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ලේක්හවුස්",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "එස්මන්ඩ්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "සිරිමා බණ්ඩාරනායක",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "1964",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "එජාප",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "1965",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "SWRD බණ්ඩාරනායක",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "1956",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "එජාප",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "සුබ මොහොතක් මාස",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "1977",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජයවර්ධන ජේ.ආර්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "පහ",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශුන්ය",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "බියගම",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "බියගම",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "විජේවර්ධනයන් ය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "වයස අවුරුදු 28 යි",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ආරක්ෂක හා විදේශ කටයුතු අමාත්යාංශය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "රනිල්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජයවර්ධන ය",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ඩිකී මාමා",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "RW",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගාමිණී දිසානායක",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ආර් ප්‍රේමදාස",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "සරත් මුත්තෙටුවේගම",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගාමිණී",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ලලිත්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "එක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ප්‍රේමදාස ය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "දිසානායක",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඇතුලත්මුදලි",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "රනිල්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "පළමුවන",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "හය",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ප්‍රේමදාස ය",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගෝඨා",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "බ්රහස්පතින්දා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකා මහ කොමසාරිස් කාර්යාලය",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "සිංගප්පූරුව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මැද පෙරදිග",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඩුබායි",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "එක්සත් අරාබි එමීර් රාජ්‍යය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "පකිස්ථානය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "බංග්ලාදේශය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඇෆ්ගනිස්ථානය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "තායිලන්තය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "එක්සත් ජනපදය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "එක්සත් ජනපදය.",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "RW",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "මහතා",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "එජාප",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශුන්ය",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "RW",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "රනිල් රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ගෝඨාභය",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඊළඟ සතිය",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මෙම සති කිහිපය",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "බැසිල් රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "SLPP",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "අරගලය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [],
        []
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "ரணில் கற்கவும் இல்லை, விலகவும் இல்லை",
      "author": "திலின வல்பொல",
      "body_lines": [
        "ஜனாதிபதி ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க தனது கல்வி நிறுவனமான றோயல் கல்லூரிக்கு விசுவாசமாக செயற்பட்டமை நன்கு அறியப்பட்டதாகும். \"எங்கள் தந்தைகள் எங்களுக்கு முன் வழியைக் கற்றுக்கொண்ட பள்ளியில்\" அவரது தொகுதி தோழர்கள் மற்றும் பள்ளி தோழர்கள் தொடர்பாக அவர் நீண்டகாலமாக குற்றம் சாட்டப்பட்டார். உண்மையில், குழந்தை இல்லாத அவரும் அவரது மனைவி மைத்ரியும் சமீபத்தில் எரிக்கப்பட்ட கொல்லுப்பிட்டி ஐந்தாவது பாதையை றோயல் கல்லூரிக்கு விட்டுச் செல்வார்கள் என்று வெகு காலத்திற்கு முன்பே பகிரங்கப்படுத்தப்பட்டது. அந்த மரியாதைக்குரிய நிறுவனம் விக்கிரமசிங்க வீட்டில் இருந்து ஒரு கல் தூரத்தில் உள்ளது. அவரது பழைய பள்ளியுடனான தொடர்புகள் மற்றும் பாசத்தின் அடிப்படையில், அவர் அதன் லத்தீன் பொன்மொழியான Disce Aut Disce De - Learn or Depart உடன் நன்கு அறிந்திருப்பார். ஆனால், துரதிஷ்டவசமாக இதைத்தான் விக்கிரமசிங்க செய்யத் தவறிவிட்டார். அவர் ராஜினாமா செய்ய நாடு காத்திருக்கிறது. கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்சவின் பதவிக்காலத்தை நிறைவேற்றுவதற்காக அவர் ஜனாதிபதியாக தேர்தலை எதிர்நோக்கியுள்ளார்.",
        "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க பதவியில் தொடர்கிறார், ராஜினாமா செய்ய வேண்டும் என்று பொதுமக்கள் பலத்த கோரிக்கைகளை முன்வைத்த போதிலும் மதிப்பிழந்த ராஜபக்சக்களுக்கு கடை பிடிக்கிறார் என்று கூறப்படுகிறது. விக்கிரமசிங்க வாயில் வெள்ளிக் கரண்டியுடன் பிறந்தவர். இவர் டி.ஆரின் பேரன். விஜேவர்தன, அப்போதைய சிலோனின் பீவர்புரூக், அவர் தனது செய்தித்தாள் சாம்ராஜ்யத்தின் மூலம் இந்த நாட்டின் அரசியலையும் அதன் ஆளுகையின் திசையையும், சுதந்திரத்திற்கு முன்னும் பின்னும், மற்றவர்களை விட அதிகமாக செல்வாக்கு செலுத்தினார். விஜேவர்தனவுக்குப் பின் லேக் ஹவுஸில் தலையங்க சிம்மாசனத்தில் அமர்ந்த அவரது தந்தை எஸ்மண்ட் விக்கிரமசிங்க, அரசியல் சூழ்ச்சியில் தனது திறமைக்காக நன்கு அறியப்பட்டவர். 1964 இல் திருமதி. சிறிமா பண்டாரநாயக்கவின் இடது ஆதரவுடைய அரசாங்கத்தை தோற்கடித்ததற்காக எஸ்மண்ட் புகழாரம் சூட்டப்பட்டவர். 1965 இல் அதன் UNP வாரிசைத் தேர்ந்தெடுப்பதில் அவர் கணிசமான பங்கைக் கொண்டிருந்தார், 1956 இல் பிரதமர் SWRD பண்டாரநாயக்கவின் கூற்றை \"கடைசி ஆணி அடிக்கப்பட்டது.\" ஐக்கிய தேசியக் கட்சியின் சவப்பெட்டி”",
        "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்கவின் அரசியல் பயணம் 1977 ஆம் ஆண்டு பாராளுமன்றத்தில் முன்னோடியில்லாத வகையில் ஆறில் ஐந்து பெரும்பான்மையைப் பெற்ற அவரது உறவினர் ஜே.ஆர். இந்த வெற்றியின் மூலம் இந்த நாட்டில் சக்தி வாய்ந்த இடதுசாரி இயக்கமாக இருந்ததை சட்டமன்றத்தில் பூஜ்ஜிய பிரதிநிதித்துவத்திற்கு விரட்டிய ஜே.ஆர்.ஜே, பியகம பாராளுமன்ற உறுப்பினராக தேர்ந்தெடுக்கப்பட்ட RW ஐ வெளிவிவகார பிரதி அமைச்சராக நியமித்தார். தற்செயலாக பியகம விஜேவர்தன அவர்களின் வேர்களைக் கொண்ட சேடவத்தைக்கு அருகில் உள்ளது. அப்போது விக்கிரமசிங்கவுக்கு வெறும் 28 வயதுதான். வெளியுறவு அமைச்சகம் புதிதாக உருவாக்கப்பட்டது, முன்பு பாதுகாப்பு மற்றும் வெளியுறவு அமைச்சகம் பிரதமரால் நடத்தப்பட்டது. இவ்வாறு ரணில் புதிதாகத் தேர்ந்தெடுக்கப்பட்ட ஜெயவர்த்தன அரசாங்கத்தில் ஒருவேளை மிகவும் மதிப்புமிக்க பிரதி அமைச்சுப் பதவியை ஏற்றுக்கொண்டார்.",
        "மிகக் குறுகிய காலத்திற்குள், மாமா டிக்கி அவருக்கு இளைஞர் விவகாரங்கள் மற்றும் வேலைவாய்ப்பு அமைச்சராக முழு அமைச்சரவை அந்தஸ்தையும் வழங்கினார். அதன்பிறகு அவருக்கு கல்வி அமைச்சராக கூடுதல் பொறுப்பு வழங்கப்பட்டது. ஜே.ஆர்.ஜே. RW இல் வாரிசு திறனைக் கண்டார். எனினும், காமினி திசாநாயக்கா அல்லது லலித் அத்துலத்முடை ஜெயவர்த்தனவுக்குப் பிறகு அப்போதைய பிரதமர் ஆர். பிரேமதாசவுடன் இணைந்து கடுமையாகப் போராடிய இருவரையும் மிஞ்ச முடியவில்லை. மறைந்த சரத் முத்தேடுவேகம ஒருமுறை, காமினியும் லலித்தும் ஒரு ஆடுகளத்தில் ஆட்டம் ஆடும்போது, ​​பிரதமர் மற்றொரு ஆடுகளத்தில் விளையாடிக்கொண்டிருந்தார். எப்படியிருந்தாலும், ரணில் விசுவாசமாக இருந்தபோது அவரைக் குற்றஞ்சாட்டுவதற்கு கூட்டுச் சேர்ந்த திஸாநாயக்க மற்றும் அதுலத்முதலி இருவரையும் பிரேமதாச அகற்றினார். இது பலனளித்தது மற்றும் பிரேமதாசாவின் படுகொலையைத் தொடர்ந்து விக்ரமசிங்கே தனது ஆறு முறை பிரதமராக பதவியேற்றதில் முதலாவதாக வெற்றி பெற்றார்.",
        "அதெல்லாம் இப்போது பாலத்தின் அடியில் தண்ணீர். இலங்கைக்கு பாதகமாக, இன்று ஒரு அராஜக நிலையில் உள்ள நிலையில், அடுத்து என்ன நடக்கப் போகிறது என்ற தெளிவு இல்லை. சிங்கப்பூரில் உள்ள இலங்கை உயர்ஸ்தானிகராலயத்தில் இருந்து வியாழன் அன்று தனது ராஜினாமா கடிதத்தை மின்னஞ்சலில் அனுப்பிய கோட்டா இப்போது இறுதியாக சென்றுவிட்டார். பாக்கிஸ்தான், பங்களாதேஷ், ஆப்கானிஸ்தான் மற்றும் தாய்லாந்தில் இருந்து சர்வாதிகாரிகளை தப்பியோடுவதற்கான புகலிடமாக ஐக்கிய அரபு எமிரேட்ஸ் புகழுடன் அவர் மத்திய கிழக்கிற்கு, அநேகமாக துபாய்க்கு கட்டுப்பட்டதாக நம்பப்படுகிறது. உலகின் பல பகுதிகளிலிருந்தும் 'சூடான' பணத்திற்கான பாதுகாப்பான இடமாக இந்த நகரம் நம்பப்படுகிறது. GR எங்கு சென்றாலும், அந்த நாட்டின் குடியுரிமையை அவர் துறந்ததைத் தொடர்ந்து அவரை நுழைய மறுத்த யு.எஸ். (ஆனால் அவரது மனைவியும் மகனும் அமெரிக்க குடியுரிமை பெற்றவர்கள்), வியத்தகு அதிர்ஷ்டம் இல்லாத நிலையில் அவர் இங்கு திரும்புவது சாத்தியமில்லை. MR இன் இழிவான முறையில் கட்டாயமாக வெளியேறியதைத் தொடர்ந்து, MRக்குப் பதிலாக RW ஐ GR தேர்ந்தெடுத்தார். கடந்த தேர்தலில் யூஎன்பியை பூஜ்ஜியத்திற்கு இட்டுச் சென்ற RW இன் சமீபத்திய சாதனை இருந்தபோதிலும் இது. இந்த சூழ்ச்சியானது, யஹபாலன காலத்தில் RW செய்ததாகக் கூறப்படும் ராஜபக்சவின் நலன்களைப் பாதுகாப்பதற்கான ஒரு நடவடிக்கையாகும். அவர் பிரதமராக நியமிக்கப்பட்டதை ரணில் ராஜபக்சே என்று அழைப்பதன் மூலம் பரவலாக கேலி செய்யப்பட்டதை நினைவில் கொள்க.",
        "துரதிர்ஷ்டவசமாக இப்போது இந்த தேசத்தை சூழ்ந்துள்ள அரசியல் காட்டுத்தீயானது பொருளாதார நெருக்கடியை முழுவதுமாக மூழ்கடித்துவிட்டது, இது எல்லாவற்றையும் விட, தீர்வுக்காக அழுகிறது. எரிபொருள் மற்றும் எரிவாயு மற்றும் வாழ்க்கைச் செலவுகள் தற்போதைய மட்டத்தில் நிறுத்தப்படும் என்பதை விட கோட்டாபயவின் வாரிசு மீது மக்கள் ஆர்வம் காட்டவில்லை. இது எழுதப்பட்ட அரசியல் உணர்வு என்னவென்றால், அடுத்த வாரம் பாராளுமன்றம் ஜி.ஆரின் இருப்புப் பதவிக் காலத்தை நிறைவேற்ற அவர்களில் ஒருவரைத் தேர்ந்தெடுக்கும் போது விக்கிரமசிங்க ஜனாதிபதித் தேர்தலில் போட்டியிடுவார். பல்வேறு பெயர்கள் அபிலாஷையாளர்களாகக் குறிப்பிடப்பட்டுள்ளன, ஆனால் இதன் முக்கிய அம்சம் என்னவென்றால், SLPP, ஐக்கியமாக இருந்தால், தாம் விரும்பும் வேட்பாளரைத் தேர்ந்தெடுப்பதை உறுதிப்படுத்த முடியும். SLPP ஆதரவின் காரணமாக RW இந்த சில வாரங்களில் பிரதமராக இருந்தார். எஸ்.எல்.பி.பியின் கைப்பாவையான பசில் ராஜபக்ச, வெளியே வருவதற்கு எவ்வளவோ முயற்சி செய்தும் இன்னும் இங்கேயே இருக்கிறார். RW இன் நன்மைக்காக அவர் இன்னும் சரங்களை இழுக்க முடியுமா? அப்படி இருந்தால், அரகலயா புதிய வேகத்தை ஈர்க்கும்.",
        "ஒரு பதிலை விடுங்கள் பதிலை ரத்துசெய் உங்கள் மின்னஞ்சல் முகவரி வெளியிடப்படாது. தேவையான புலங்கள் குறிக்கப்பட்டுள்ளன *கருத்து பெயர் *",
        "அடுத்த முறை நான் கருத்து தெரிவிக்க, எனது பெயர், மின்னஞ்சல் மற்றும் இணையதளத்தை இந்த உலாவியில் சேமிக்கவும்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ராயல் கல்லூரி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "மைத்திரி",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஐந்தாவது பாதை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "கொள்ளுப்பிட்டி",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ராயல் கல்லூரி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "லத்தீன்",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Disce Aut Disce De",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "புறப்படு",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்சவின்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ராஜபக்சேக்கள்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "டி.ஆர். விஜேவர்தன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "எஸ்மன்ட் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "விஜேவர்தன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "லேக் ஹவுஸ்",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "எஸ்மண்ட்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "சிறிமா பண்டாரநாயக்கா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "1964",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஐ.தே.க",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "1965",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "எஸ்.டபிள்யூ.ஆர்.டி பண்டாரநாயக்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "1956",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஐ.தே.க",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஒரு நல்ல தருணம் மாதங்கள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "1977",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜே.ஆர்.ஜெயவர்தன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஐந்து",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "பூஜ்யம்",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "பியகம",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "பியகம",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "விஜேவர்தனஸ்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "28-வயது",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாதுகாப்பு மற்றும் வெளியுறவு அமைச்சகம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரணில்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜெயவர்த்தன",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "டிக்கி மாமா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "RW",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "காமினி திசாநாயக்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆர்.பிரேமதாச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "சரத் ​​முத்தேடுவேகம",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "காமினி",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "லலித்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஒன்று",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "பிரேமதாச",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "திசாநாயக்க",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "அதுலத்முதலி",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரணில்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "முதலில்",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆறு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "பிரேமதாச",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "கிடைத்தது ஒரு",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "வியாழன்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை உயர்ஸ்தானிகராலயம்",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "சிங்கப்பூர்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "மத்திய கிழக்கு",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "துபாய்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஐக்கிய அரபு எமிரேட்ஸ்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாகிஸ்தான்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "பங்களாதேஷ்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆப்கானிஸ்தான்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "தாய்லாந்து",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "எங்களுக்கு",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "எங்களுக்கு.",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "RW",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "திரு",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஐ.தே.க",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "பூஜ்யம்",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ராஜபக்சே",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "RW",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரணில் ராஜபக்ச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "கோட்டாபய",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "அடுத்த வாரம்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்த சில வாரங்கள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "பசில் ராஜபக்ச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "எஸ்.எல்.பி.பி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "அரகலயா",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [],
        []
      ]
    }
  }
}