{
  "newspaper_id": "news-first-lk",
  "url": "https://www.newsfirst.lk/2022/08/29/bandula-prasanna-wimal-at-hrcsl/",
  "time_ut": 1661755440,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Bandula, Prasanna, & Wimal at HRCSL",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Bandula, Prasanna, & Wimal at HRCSL",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); Ministers Dr. Bandula Gunawardena, Prasanna Ranatunga, and MP Wimal Weerawansa have been summoned to the Human Rights Commission of Sri Lanka (HRCSL) today (29).",
        "A spokesperson to the HRCSL says the MPs have been summoned to record statements for the special investigation on property damage that was reported on the 9th of May and the days that followed.",
        "The three parliamentarians have lodged complaints with the HRCSL about their houses being set on fire.",
        "According to the HRCSL spokesperson, several local council chairmen whose houses and property were damaged during the violence on and after the 9th of May, have also been summoned before the commission today, to record statements."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Bandula",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "Prasanna",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "News 1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Bandula Gunawardena",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Prasanna Ranatunga",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Wimal Weerawansa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Human Rights Commission of Sri Lanka",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "29",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "HRCSL",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "9th",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "May",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the days",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "three",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "9th",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "May",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "බන්දුල, ප්‍රසන්න, සහ විමල් මානව හිමිකම් කොමිසමේ",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); අමාත්‍යවරුන් වන ආචාර්ය බන්දුල ගුණවර්ධන, ප්‍රසන්න රණතුංග සහ පාර්ලිමේන්තු මන්ත්‍රී විමල් වීරවංශ අද (29) ශ්‍රී ලංකා මානව හිමිකම් කොමිෂන් සභාවට (HRCSL) කැඳවා තිබේ.",
        "මැයි 9 වැනිදා සහ ඉන් පසු දිනවලදී වාර්තා වූ දේපළ හානි පිළිබඳ විශේෂ විමර්ශනය සඳහා ප්‍රකාශ සටහන් කර ගැනීම සඳහා මන්ත්‍රීවරුන් කැඳවා ඇති බව මානව හිමිකම් කොමිසමේ ප්‍රකාශකයෙක් පවසයි.",
        "පාර්ලිමේන්තු මන්ත්‍රීවරුන් තිදෙනා තම නිවාසවලට ගිනි තැබීම සම්බන්ධයෙන් මානව හිමිකම් කොමිසමට පැමිණිලි කර ඇත.",
        "මානව හිමිකම් කවුන්සිලයේ ප්‍රකාශකවරයාට අනුව, මැයි 9 වැනිදා සහ ඉන් පසුව ඇති වූ ප්‍රචණ්ඩ ක්‍රියාවලදී නිවාස හා දේපළවලට හානි වූ ප්‍රාදේශීය සභා සභාපතිවරුන් කිහිප දෙනෙකු ද ප්‍රකාශ සටහන් කර ගැනීම සඳහා අද කොමිසම හමුවට කැඳවා ඇත."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "බන්දුල",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "ප්‍රසන්න",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "News 1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "බන්දුල ගුණවර්ධන",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ප්‍රසන්න රණතුංග",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "විමල් වීරවංශ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකා මානව හිමිකම් කොමිෂන් සභාව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "29",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "HRCSL",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "9 වැනි",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "මැයි",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "දවස්",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "තුන්",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "9 වැනි",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "මැයි",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "HRCSL இல் பந்துல, பிரசன்னா மற்றும் விமல்",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); அமைச்சர்களான கலாநிதி பந்துல குணவர்தன, பிரசன்ன ரணதுங்க மற்றும் பாராளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர் விமல் வீரவன்ச ஆகியோர் இன்று (29) இலங்கை மனித உரிமைகள் ஆணைக்குழுவிற்கு அழைக்கப்பட்டுள்ளனர்.",
        "மே மாதம் 9ஆம் திகதி மற்றும் அதற்குப் பின்னரான நாட்களில் இடம்பெற்ற சொத்துச் சேதங்கள் தொடர்பான விசேட விசாரணைக்காக வாக்குமூலங்களைப் பதிவுசெய்வதற்காக பாராளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர்கள் அழைக்கப்பட்டுள்ளதாக HRCSL இன் செய்தித் தொடர்பாளர் தெரிவித்துள்ளார்.",
        "மூன்று பாராளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர்களும் தமது வீடுகளுக்கு தீ வைக்கப்பட்டது குறித்து மனித உரிமை ஆணையத்தில் முறைப்பாடு செய்துள்ளனர்.",
        "மே மாதம் 9ஆம் திகதி மற்றும் அதற்குப் பின்னரான காலப்பகுதியில் இடம்பெற்ற வன்முறைகளின் போது வீடுகள் மற்றும் சொத்துக்கள் சேதப்படுத்தப்பட்ட பல உள்ளூராட்சி மன்ற தலைவர்களும் வாக்குமூலங்களைப் பதிவுசெய்வதற்காக இன்று ஆணைக்குழுவில் அழைக்கப்பட்டுள்ளதாக மனித உரிமை ஆணையத்தின் பேச்சாளர் தெரிவித்துள்ளார்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "பந்துல",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "பிரசன்னா",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "News 1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "பந்துல குணவர்தன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "பிரசன்ன ரணதுங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "விமல் வீரவன்ச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை மனித உரிமைகள் ஆணைக்குழு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "29",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "HRCSL",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "9வது",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "மே",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "நாட்கள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "மூன்று",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "9வது",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "மே",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}