{
  "newspaper_id": "lankadeepa-lk",
  "url": "https://www.lankadeepa.lk/news/කුරුණෑගලනුත්-එක්දින-ගුවන්-ගමන්-බලපත්‍ර/101-616179",
  "time_ut": 1657462517,
  "original_lang": "si",
  "original_title": "කුරුණෑගලනුත් එක්දින ගුවන් ගමන් බලපත්‍ර",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "One-day flight tickets to Kurunegala",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "Ms. Piyumi Bandara, the media spokesperson of the department, said that the second step in issuing passports from the regional offices of the Immigration and Emigration Department, the issuance of passports from the Kurunegala office will start tomorrow (11) and accordingly, passports will be issued to applicants who have booked an earlier date and time.",
        "Ms. Bandara states that passports will only be issued to applicants who have reserved a date and time from the regional offices of Matara, Vavuniya, Kandy and Kurunegala under the one-day and regular services and persons who have not reserved a date and time will not be allowed to enter the head office or regional offices.",
        "She further said that a date and time can be reserved by visiting the website of the Immigration Department, Aagasapapasatoresadabagatadagakana, and the number of applicants booking dates and times has increased."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "One-day",
          "label": "DATE"
        },
        {
          "text": "Kurunegala",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Piyumi Bandara",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "second",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Immigration and Emigration Department",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kurunegala",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "tomorrow",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "11",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Bandara",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Matara",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Vavuniya",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kandy",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kurunegala",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "one-day",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the Immigration Department",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Aagasapapasatoresadabagatadagakana",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "කුරුණෑගලනුත් එක්දින ගුවන් ගමන් බලපත්‍ර",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "ආගමන හා විගමන දෙපාර්තමේන්තුවේ ප්‍රාදේශීය කාර්යාලවලින් විදේශ ගමන් බලපත්‍ර නිකුත් කිරීමේ දෙවැනි පියවර වන කුරුණෑගල කාර්යාලයෙන් ගමන් බලපත්‍ර නිකුත් කිරීම හෙට (11) ආරම්භ වන බවත් ඒ අනුව කලින් දිනය සහ වේලාව වෙන්කරගත් අයදුම්කරුවන්ට ගමන් බලපත්‍ර නිකුත් කරන බවත් එම දෙපාර්තමේන්තුවේ මාධ්‍ය ප්‍රකාශක පියුමි බණ්ඩාර මහත්මිය පැවසුවාය.",
        "මාතර, වවුනියාව, මහනුවර සහ කුරුණෑගල ප්‍රදේශීය කාර්යාලවලින් එක්දින සහ සාමාන්‍ය සේවා යටතේ දිනයක් සහ වේලාවක් වෙන්කරගත් අයදුම්කරුවන්ට පමණක් ගමන් බලපත්‍ර නිකුත් කරන බවත් දිනයක් සහ වේලාවක් වෙන්කර නොගත් පුද්ගලයන්ට ප්‍රධාන කාර්යාලයට හෝ ප්‍රාදේශීය කාර්යාලවලට ඇතුල්විය අවසර නොලැබෙන බවත් බණ්ඩාර මහත්මිය සඳහන් කරයි.",
        "ආගමන විගමන දෙපාර්තමේන්තුවේ අඅඅගසපපසටර්එසදබගටදඩගකන යන වෙබ් අඩවියට පිවිසීමෙන් දිනයක් සහ වේලාවක් වෙන්කර ගත හැකි බවත් දිනයන් සහ වේලාවන් වෙන්කරගන්නා අයදුම්කරුවන්ගේ සංඛ්‍යාව ඉහළ නංවා ඇති බවත් ඇය වැඩි දුරටත් කීවාය."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "එක දවසක්",
          "label": "DATE"
        },
        {
          "text": "කුරුණෑගල",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "පියුමි බණ්ඩාර",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "දෙවැනි",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ආගමන විගමන දෙපාර්තමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "කුරුණෑගල",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "හෙට",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "11",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "බණ්ඩාර ය",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "මාතර",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "වවුනියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මහනුවර",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "කුරුණෑගල",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "එක දවසක්",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ආගමන දෙපාර්තමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "අගසපපාසතොරෙසදබගතදගකන",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "குருநாகலுக்கு ஒரு நாள் விமான டிக்கெட்டுகள்",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "குடிவரவு மற்றும் குடியகல்வு திணைக்களத்தின் பிராந்திய அலுவலகங்களில் கடவுச்சீட்டு வழங்கும் இரண்டாம் கட்டமாக குருநாகல் காரியாலயத்தில் கடவுச்சீட்டு வழங்கும் பணிகள் நாளை (11) ஆரம்பமாகவுள்ளதாக திணைக்களத்தின் ஊடகப் பேச்சாளர் திருமதி பியுமி பண்டார தெரிவித்தார். முந்தைய தேதி மற்றும் நேரத்தை முன்பதிவு செய்த விண்ணப்பதாரர்களுக்கு வழங்கப்படும்.",
        "மாத்தறை, வவுனியா, கண்டி மற்றும் குருநாகல் பிராந்திய அலுவலகங்களில் ஒரு நாள் மற்றும் வழக்கமான சேவைகளின் கீழ் தேதி மற்றும் நேரத்தை ஒதுக்கிய விண்ணப்பதாரர்களுக்கு மட்டுமே கடவுச்சீட்டு வழங்கப்படும் என்று திருமதி பண்டார கூறுகிறார். தலைமை அலுவலகம் அல்லது மண்டல அலுவலகங்களுக்குள் நுழைய அனுமதிக்கப்படவில்லை.",
        "குடிவரவுத் திணைக்களத்தின் அகசபபாசடோரேசடபகததககன என்ற இணையத்தளத்திற்குச் சென்று தேதியையும் நேரத்தையும் முன்பதிவு செய்துகொள்ளலாம் என்றும், தேதிகள் மற்றும் நேரங்களை முன்பதிவு செய்யும் விண்ணப்பதாரர்களின் எண்ணிக்கை அதிகரித்துள்ளது என்றும் அவர் மேலும் கூறினார்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ஒரு நாள்",
          "label": "DATE"
        },
        {
          "text": "குருநாகல்",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "பியுமி பண்டார",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இரண்டாவது",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "குடிவரவு மற்றும் குடியகல்வு திணைக்களம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "குருநாகல்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "நாளை",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "11",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பண்டார",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "மாத்தறை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "வவுனியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "கண்டி",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "குருநாகல்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஒரு நாள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "குடிவரவுத் துறை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆகஸபபசடோரேசடபகததககன",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}