{
  "newspaper_id": "lankadeepa-lk",
  "url": "https://www.lankadeepa.lk/news/පා--මන්ත්‍රී-ගයාෂාන්ගෙන්-පෙත්සමක්/101-619202",
  "time_ut": 1662117435,
  "original_lang": "si",
  "original_title": "පා. මන්ත්‍රී ගයාෂාන්ගෙන් පෙත්සමක්",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Pa. A petition from MP Gayashan",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "Sri Lanka Podujana United Peramuna's Monaragala District Member of Parliament Mr. Gayashan Navanandana has filed a fundamental rights petition before the Supreme Court requesting an order to prevent his removal from the post of Member of Parliament.",
        "Democratic Left Front leader Vasudeva Nanayakkara, Sri Lanka Podujana Peramuna General Secretary Advocate Sagara Kariyawasam, Secretary General of Parliament, Election Commission and others have been named as respondents in this petition filed by Vidanapathirana Association Law Firm.",
        "The complainant stated in his complaint that he, who is a doctor by profession, was expelled from the party membership by the Central Committee stating that he acted contrary to the decisions of the Democratic Left Front.",
        "The petitioner has requested to issue a notice to the defendants in this regard as it is against the principle of natural justice as well as against the law and unfair action without holding any fair hearing in this regard."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Pa.",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "United Peramuna's",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Monaragala District",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Gayashan Navanandana",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Supreme Court",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Democratic",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Vasudeva Nanayakkara",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Podujana Peramuna",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Advocate Sagara Kariyawasam",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament, Election Commission",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the Central Committee",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Democratic",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        []
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "පා. මන්ත්‍රී ගයාෂාන්ගෙන් පෙත්සමක්",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "තමන්ව පාර්ලිමේන්තු මන්ත්‍රී ධූරයෙන් නෙරපීම වළක්වන නියෝගයක් නිකුත් කරන ලෙස ඉල්ලා ශ්‍රී ලංකා පොදුජන එක්සත් පෙරමුණේ මොණරාගල දිස්ත්‍රික් පාර්ලිමේන්තු මන්ත්‍රී වෛද්‍ය ගයාෂාන් නවනන්දන මහතා ශ්‍රේෂ්ඨාධිකරණය හමුවේ මූලික අයිතිවාසිකම් පෙත්සමක් ගොනු කරනු ලැබ ඇත.",
        "විදානපතිරණ ඇසෝසියේෂන් නීතීඥ සමාගම මගින් ගොනු කර ඇති මෙම පෙත්සමේ වගඋත්තරකරුවන් ලෙස ප්‍රජාතන්ත්‍රවාදී වාමාංශික පෙරමුණේ නායක වාසුදේව නානායක්කාර, ශ්‍රී ලංකා පොදුජන පෙරමුණේ මහ ලේකම් නීතිඥ සාගර කාරියවසම්, පාර්ලිමේන්තුවේ මහලේකම්, මැතිවරණ කොමිසම ඇතුළු පිරිසක් නම් කරනු ලැබ තිබේ.",
        "වෘත්තියෙන් වෛද්‍යවරයෙක් වන තමන් ප්‍රජාතන්ත්‍රවාදී වාමාංශික පෙරමුණේ තීන්දු තීරණවලට පටහැනිව කටයුතු කරන ලදැයි සඳහන් කරමින් මධ්‍යම කාරක සභාව විසින් පක්ෂ සාමාජිකත්වයෙන් නෙරපා හරිනු ලැබ ඇති බව සඳහන් කරමින් ඉකුත් අගෝස්තු මස 8 වැනි දින ලිපියකින් දැනුම්දී දැනුම්දී ඇති බව පැමිණිලිකරු සිය පැමිණිල්ලෙන් දක්වා ඇත.",
        "ඒ සම්බන්ධයෙන් කිසිදු සාධාරණ විභාගයක් හෝ නොපවත්වා මෙසේ කටයුතු කිරීම ස්වභාවයුක්ති මූලධර්මයට පටහැනි මෙන්ම  නීතියට පටහැනි සහ අසාධාරණ ක්‍රියාවක් බැවින් මේ සම්බන්ධයෙන් වග කරුවන්ට නොතීසි නිකුත් කරන ලෙස පෙත්සම්කරු සිය පැතුම් ඉල්ලා තිබේ ."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "පා.",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "එක්සත් පෙරමුණේ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මොනරාගල දිස්ත්‍රික්කය",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගයාෂාන් නවනන්දන",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රේෂ්ඨාධිකරණය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ප්‍රජාතන්ත්‍රවාදී",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "වාසුදේව නානායක්කාර",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "පොදුජන පෙරමුණ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "අධිනීතිඥ සාගර කාරියවසම්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව, මැතිවරණ කොමිසම",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "මධ්යම කාරක සභාව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ප්‍රජාතන්ත්‍රවාදී",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        []
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "பா. எம்.பி கயாஷானிடம் இருந்து ஒரு மனு",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "ஶ்ரீலங்கா பொதுஜன ஐக்கிய பெரமுனவின் மொனராகலை மாவட்ட நாடாளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர் திரு.கயாஷான் நவநந்தன தனது நாடாளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர் பதவியில் இருந்து நீக்குவதைத் தடுக்குமாறு கோரி உச்ச நீதிமன்றத்தில் அடிப்படை உரிமை மனுவொன்றை தாக்கல் செய்துள்ளார்.",
        "ஜனநாயக இடதுசாரி முன்னணியின் தலைவர் வாசுதேவ நாணயக்கார, ஶ்ரீலங்கா பொதுஜன பெரமுனவின் பொதுச் செயலாளர் சட்டத்தரணி சாகர காரியவசம், பாராளுமன்ற செயலாளர் நாயகம், தேர்தல்கள் ஆணைக்குழு மற்றும் பலர் பிரதிவாதிகளாக விதானபத்திரன சங்க சட்ட நிறுவனம் தாக்கல் செய்த இந்த மனுவில் குறிப்பிடப்பட்டுள்ளது.",
        "தொழில் ரீதியாக மருத்துவரான தன்னை ஜனநாயக இடதுசாரி முன்னணியின் முடிவுகளுக்கு மாறாகச் செயல்பட்டதாகக் கூறி மத்தியக் குழுவால் கட்சி உறுப்பினர் பதவியில் இருந்து நீக்கப்பட்டதாக புகார்தாரர் தனது புகாரில் குறிப்பிட்டுள்ளார்.",
        "இது இயற்கை நீதிக்கும், சட்டத்துக்கும் முரணானது என்றும், நியாயமான விசாரணையை நடத்தாமல் நியாயமற்ற நடவடிக்கை என்றும், இது தொடர்பாக பிரதிவாதிகளுக்கு நோட்டீஸ் அனுப்ப மனுதாரர் கோரியுள்ளார்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "பா.",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ஐக்கிய பெரமுனாவின்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "மொனராகலை மாவட்டம்",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "கயஷன் நவநந்தன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "உச்ச நீதிமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஜனநாயகம்",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "வாசுதேவ நாணயக்கார",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "பொதுஜன பெரமுன",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "வழக்கறிஞர் சாகர காரியவசம்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம், தேர்தல் ஆணையம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "மத்திய குழு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜனநாயகம்",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        []
      ]
    }
  }
}