{
  "newspaper_id": "virakesari-lk",
  "url": "http://www.virakesari.lk/article/131945",
  "time_ut": 1658390545,
  "original_lang": "ta",
  "original_title": "\"கோ ஹோம் ரணில்\" போராட்டத்தை தடையின்றி நடத்த விஹாரமகாதேவி பூங்கா ?",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Viharamakadevi Park to hold \"Go Home Ranil\" protest without hindrance?",
      "author": "",
      "body_lines": [
        "Member of Parliament Mano Ganesan mentioned on his Facebook page that President Ranil Wickramasinghe has said that Colombo Viharamakadevi Park area will be set aside for the protestors to conduct their \"Go-Home-Ranil\" protest.",
        "Ranil Wickremesinghe today held a special meeting with party leaders after being sworn in as President.",
        "Member of Parliament Mano Ganesan mentioned on his Facebook page that the President said the above.",
        "Parliament will be adjourned for 24 hours for a fresh start, President Ranil Wickremesinghe told us in a special meeting with party leaders.",
        "He also said that Colombo Viharamakadevi Park area will be set aside for the protestors to carry out their \"Go-Home-Run\" protest without any hindrance.",
        "The President also told us that he wants to bring the original 19th Amendment document of his good governance period into the Constitution as soon as possible.",
        "The recording also mentioned that the President said that he wants to form and run the government, parliament and departmental committees consisting of parliamentarians."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Viharamakadevi Park",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "Go Home Ranil",
          "label": "WORK_OF_ART"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Mano Ganesan",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickramasinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Colombo Viharamakadevi Park",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "Go-Home-Ranil",
            "label": "WORK_OF_ART"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Mano Ganesan",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "24 hours",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Go-Home-Run",
            "label": "WORK_OF_ART"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Constitution",
            "label": "LAW"
          }
        ],
        []
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "විහාරමකාදේවි උද්‍යානයේ \"යන්න රනිල්\" විරෝධතාව බාධාවකින් තොරව පවත්වයි?",
      "author": "",
      "body_lines": [
        "පාර්ලිමේන්තු මන්ත්‍රී මනෝ ගනේෂන් සිය ෆේස්බුක් පිටුවේ සඳහන් කළේ විරෝධතාකරුවන්ට \"ගෙදර යන්න - රනිල්\" විරෝධතාව පැවැත්වීම සඳහා කොළඹ විහාරමකාදේවි උද්‍යාන පරිශ්‍රය වෙන් කරන බව ජනාධිපති රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ ප්‍රකාශ කර ඇති බවයි.",
        "ජනාධිපති ලෙස දිවුරුම් දීමෙන් පසු රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතා අද පක්ෂ නායකයින් සමඟ විශේෂ හමුවක් පැවැත්වීය.",
        "ජනාධිපතිවරයා ඉහත ප්‍රකාශය කළ බව පාර්ලිමේන්තු මන්ත්‍රී මනෝ ගනේෂන් සිය ෆේස්බුක් පිටුවේ සඳහන් කළා.",
        "නව ආරම්භයක් සඳහා පාර්ලිමේන්තුව පැය 24කට කල් තබන බව ජනාධිපති රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතා පක්ෂ නායකයින් සමග පැවති විශේෂ හමුවකදී අප සමග පැවසීය.",
        "කොළඹ විහාරමකාදේවි උද්‍යාන ප්‍රදේශය විරෝධතාකරුවන්ට බාධාවකින් තොරව \"ගෙදර යන්න - දුවන්න\" විරෝධතාව පැවැත්වීම සඳහා වෙන් කරන බවද ඔහු පැවසීය.",
        "තම යහපාලන සමයේ මුල් 19 වැනි සංශෝධන ලේඛනය හැකි ඉක්මනින් ආණ්ඩුක්‍රම ව්‍යවස්ථාවට ගෙන ඒමට අවශ්‍ය බව ද ජනාධිපතිවරයා අප සමඟ පැවසීය.",
        "පාර්ලිමේන්තු මන්ත්‍රීවරුන්ගෙන් සමන්විත රජය, පාර්ලිමේන්තුව සහ දෙපාර්තමේන්තු කමිටු පිහිටුවා ගෙන යාමට අවශ්‍ය බව ජනාධිපතිවරයා ප්‍රකාශ කළ බවද එම හඬපටයේ සඳහන් වේ."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "විහාරමකාදේවි උද්‍යානය",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "රනිල් ගෙදර යන්න",
          "label": "WORK_OF_ART"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Mano Ganesan",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "කොළඹ විහාරමකාදේවි උද්‍යානය",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගෙදර යන්න-රනිල්",
            "label": "WORK_OF_ART"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Mano Ganesan",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "පැය 24",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Go-Home-Run",
            "label": "WORK_OF_ART"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ව්යවස්ථාව",
            "label": "LAW"
          }
        ],
        []
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "\"கோ ஹோம் ரணில்\" போராட்டத்தை தடையின்றி நடத்த விஹாரமகாதேவி பூங்கா ?",
      "author": "",
      "body_lines": [
        "போராட்டக்காரர்கள் தமது \"கோ-ஹோம்-ரணில்\"  போராட்டத்தை, தடையின்றி நடத்த கொழும்பு விஹாரமகாதேவி பூங்கா பிரதேசம் ஒதுக்கி தரப்படும் என்று ஜனாதிபதி ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க தெரிவித்ததாக பாராளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர் மனோ கணேசன் தனது பேஸ்புக் பக்கத்தில் குறிப்பிட்டுள்ளார்.",
        "ஜனாதிபதியாக இன்றையதினம் ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க பாராளுமன்றில் சத்தியப்பிரமாணம் செய்ததையடுத்து கட்சி தலைவர்களுடன் விசேட சந்திப்பை முன்னெடுத்தார்.",
        "இதன்போதே ஜனாதிபதி மேற்கண்டவாறு தெரிவித்ததாக பாராளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர் மனோ கணேசன் தனது பேஸ்புக் பக்கத்தில் குறிப்பிட்டுள்ளார்.",
        "பாராளுமன்றம், புது ஆரம்பத்துக்காக 24 மணி நேரம் ஒத்தி வைக்கப்படும் என ஜனாதிபதி  ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க கட்சி தலைவர்களுடன் நடத்திய விசேட சந்திப்பில் எமக்கு கூறினார்.",
        "போராட்டக்காரர்கள் தமது \"கோ-ஹோம்-ரணில்\"  போராட்டத்தை, தடையின்றி நடத்த கொழும்பு விஹாரமகாதேவி பூங்கா பிரதேசம் ஒதுக்கி தரப்படும் என்றும் தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "தமது நல்லாட்சி காலகட்ட அசல் 19 ஆம் திருத்த ஆவணம், எவ்வளவு சீக்கிரம் முடியுமோ, அவ்வளவு சீக்கிரமாக அரசியலமைப்புக்குள் கொண்டு வர விரும்புவதாகவும் ஜனாதிபதி எமக்கு  தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "மேலும் அரசாங்கத்தையும், பாராளுமன்றத்தையும்,  பாராளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர்களைக் கொண்ட துறைசார் குழுக்களை அமைத்து நடத்த விரும்புவதாகவும் ஜனாதிபதி கூறினார் என அந்தப் பதிவில் மேலும் குறிப்பிட்டுள்ளார்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "விகாரமகாதேவி பூங்கா",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "ரணில் வீட்டுக்கு போ",
          "label": "WORK_OF_ART"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Mano Ganesan",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "கொழும்பு விகாரமகாதேவி பூங்கா",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "வீட்டுக்குப் போ- ரணில்",
            "label": "WORK_OF_ART"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Mano Ganesan",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "24 மணி நேரம்",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "செல்-ஹோம்-ரன்",
            "label": "WORK_OF_ART"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "அரசியலமைப்பு",
            "label": "LAW"
          }
        ],
        []
      ]
    }
  }
}