{
  "newspaper_id": "news-first-lk",
  "url": "https://www.newsfirst.lk/2022/06/28/pucsl-to-seek-public-opinion-on-tariff-revision/",
  "time_ut": 1656405420,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "PUCSL to seek public opinion on tariff revision",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "PUCSL to seek public opinion on tariff revision",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); The Public Utilities Commission of Sri Lanka (PUCSL) has decided to seek public opinion on the proposed revision of electricity tariffs for the year 2022.",
        "The Ceylon Electricity Board has proposed to raise its revenue by 82% with the implementation of the proposed tariff.",
        "However, the PUCSL is of the view that the maximum revenue increase should not be more than 57% for which the Commission recommends the Treasury to pay Rs. 60 billion as the subsidy for Ceylon Electricity Board.",
        "The Commission intends to conduct the Stakeholder Consultation as prescribed under section 17 of the Public Utilities Commission of Sri Lanka Act No. 35 of 2002 and according to the procedure approved by the Commission for Stakeholder Consultation.",
        "#Rambukkana Shooting: HR Commission tells AG to file criminal action against SSP Keerthiratne"
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "The Public Utilities Commission",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the year 2022",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "The Ceylon Electricity Board",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "82%",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "PUCSL",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "more than 57%",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "Commission",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Treasury",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "60 billion",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ceylon Electricity Board",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the Stakeholder Consultation",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "section 17",
            "label": "LAW"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Public Utilities Commission",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "35 of 2002",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Stakeholder Consultation",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Rambukkana",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "HR Commission",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "AG",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "SSP Keerthiratne",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "තීරුබදු සංශෝධනය පිළිබඳ මහජන මතය විමසීමට PUCSL",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); 2022 වසර සඳහා යෝජිත විදුලි ගාස්තු සංශෝධනය සම්බන්ධයෙන් මහජන අදහස් විමසීමට ශ්‍රී ලංකා මහජන උපයෝගිතා කොමිෂන් සභාව (PUCSL) තීරණය කර ඇත.",
        "යෝජිත ගාස්තු ක්‍රියාත්මක කිරීමත් සමඟ ලංකා විදුලිබල මණ්ඩලය සිය ආදායම 82%කින් ඉහළ නංවා ගැනීමට යෝජනා කර ඇත.",
        "කෙසේ වෙතත්, මහජන උපයෝගිතා කොමිසමේ අදහස වන්නේ උපරිම ආදායම් වැඩිවීම 57% ට වඩා වැඩි නොවිය යුතු බවයි, ඒ සඳහා කොමිෂන් සභාව විසින් භාණ්ඩාගාරයට රු. ලංකා විදුලිබල මණ්ඩලයේ සහනාධාරය ලෙස රුපියල් බිලියන 60ක්.",
        "2002 අංක 35 දරන ශ්‍රී ලංකා මහජන උපයෝගිතා කොමිෂන් සභා පනතේ 17 වැනි වගන්තිය යටතේ නියම කර ඇති පරිදි සහ පාර්ශ්වකරුවන්ගේ උපදේශන කොමිෂන් සභාව විසින් අනුමත කරන ලද ක්‍රියා පටිපාටියට අනුව පාර්ශවකරුවන්ගේ උපදේශනය පැවැත්වීමට කොමිෂන් සභාව අදහස් කරයි.",
        "#රඹුක්කන වෙඩි තැබීම: ජ්‍යෙෂ්ඨ පොලිස් අධිකාරී කීර්තිරත්නට එරෙහිව අපරාධ නඩු පවරන්නැයි මානව සම්පත් කොමිසම නීතිපතිට කියයි"
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "මහජන උපයෝගිතා කොමිෂන් සභාව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "වසර 2022",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ලංකා විදුලිබල මණ්ඩලය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "82%",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "PUCSL",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "57% ට වඩා",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "කොමිසම",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "භාණ්ඩාගාර",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "බිලියන 60 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ලංකා විදුලිබල මණ්ඩලය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "පාර්ශවකරුවන්ගේ උපදේශනය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "17 වගන්තිය",
            "label": "LAW"
          },
          {
            "text": "මහජන උපයෝගිතා කොමිෂන් සභාව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "2002 35",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ශවකරුවන්ගේ උපදේශනය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "රඹුක්කන",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "මානව සම්පත් කොමිසම",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "AG",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජ්‍යෙෂ්ඨ පොලිස් අධිකාරී කීර්තිරත්න",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "கட்டணத் திருத்தம் குறித்து பொதுமக்களின் கருத்தைப் பெற PUCSL",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); 2022 ஆம் ஆண்டிற்கான உத்தேச மின்சாரக் கட்டணத் திருத்தம் தொடர்பில் பொதுமக்களின் கருத்தைப் பெறுவதற்கு இலங்கை பொதுப் பயன்பாடுகள் ஆணைக்குழு (PUCSL) தீர்மானித்துள்ளது.",
        "உத்தேச கட்டணத்தை நடைமுறைப்படுத்துவதன் மூலம் இலங்கை மின்சார சபை தனது வருமானத்தை 82% ஆல் உயர்த்துவதற்கு முன்மொழிந்துள்ளது.",
        "எவ்வாறாயினும், அதிகபட்ச வருவாய் அதிகரிப்பு 57% ஐ விட அதிகமாக இருக்கக்கூடாது என்று PUCSL கருதுகிறது, இதற்காக ஆணையம் கருவூலத்திற்கு ரூ. இலங்கை மின்சார சபைக்கான மானியமாக 60 பில்லியன்.",
        "2002 ஆம் ஆண்டின் 35 ஆம் இலக்க இலங்கை பொதுப் பயன்பாடுகள் ஆணைக்குழுவின் 17 ஆம் பிரிவின் கீழ் பரிந்துரைக்கப்பட்டுள்ளபடி பங்குதாரர்களின் ஆலோசனையை ஆணைக்குழு நடத்த உத்தேசித்துள்ளது.",
        "#ரம்புக்கன துப்பாக்கிச் சூடு: எஸ்எஸ்பி கீர்த்திரத்ன மீது குற்றவியல் நடவடிக்கை எடுக்குமாறு மனிதவள ஆணையம் ஏஜியிடம் கூறியுள்ளது"
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "பொது பயன்பாட்டு ஆணையம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "2022 ஆம் ஆண்டு",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை மின்சார சபை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "82%",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "PUCSL",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "57%க்கு மேல்",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "தரகு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "கருவூலம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "60 பில்லியன்",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை மின்சார சபை",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பங்குதாரர் ஆலோசனை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "பிரிவு 17",
            "label": "LAW"
          },
          {
            "text": "பொது பயன்பாட்டு ஆணையம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "2002 இன் 35",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "பங்குதாரர் ஆலோசனை",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ரம்புக்கன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "மனிதவள ஆணையம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஏஜி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "எஸ்.எஸ்.பி கீர்த்திரத்ன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}