{
  "newspaper_id": "lankadeepa-lk",
  "url": "https://www.lankadeepa.lk/news/ආර්නිමේනියාව-ලංකාවට-සහෝදර-දෑත-දිගු-කරයි/101-618618",
  "time_ut": 1661248630,
  "original_lang": "si",
  "original_title": "ආර්නිමේනියාව ලංකාවට සහෝදර දෑත දිගු කරයි",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Armenia extends brotherly arms to Sri Lanka",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "The President of Armenia Mr. Vahagn Khachaturyan has stated in a congratulatory message to President Ranil Wickramasinghe that he is committed to further strengthen the cooperation between the Republic of Armenia and Sri Lanka for the benefit of the people of both countries.",
        "The President of Armenia has congratulated Mr. Ranil Wickramasinghe who has been elected as the President and has appreciated the commitment of Mr. Wickramasinghe for the progress of Sri Lanka.",
        "The congratulatory message of the Armenian President further states that he wishes good health, success and peace to the friendly people of Sri Lanka."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Sri Lanka",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Armenia",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Vahagn Khachaturyan",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickramasinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Republic of Armenia and Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Armenia",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickramasinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Wickramasinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Armenian",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "ආර්නිමේනියාව ලංකාවට සහෝදර දෑත දිගු කරයි",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "ආර්මේනියා ජනරජය සහ ශ්‍රී ලංකාව අතර සහයෝගීතාව දෙරටේම ජනතාවගේ ප්‍රයෝජනය සදහා තවදුරත් ශක්තිමත් කර ගැනීමට කැපවන බව ආර්මේනියා ජනාධිපති වහග්න් ඛචතුරියන් මහතා (Vahagn Khachaturyan) ජනාධිපති රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතා වෙත සුබපැතුම් පණිවුඩයක් යොමු කරමින් සඳහන් කර ඇත.",
        "ජනාධිපති ධූරයට පත් රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතාට සුබපැතුම් පිරිනමා ඇති ආර්මේනියා ජනාධිපතිවරයා ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ ප්‍රගතිය වෙනුවෙන් වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතාගේ කැපවීම ඇගයීමට ලක් කර තිබේ.",
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ මිත්‍රශීලී ජනතාවට යහපත් සෞඛ්‍ය, සාර්ථකත්වය සහ සාමය ප්‍රාර්ථනා කරන බව ද ආර්මේනියානු ජනාධිපතිවරයාගේ සුබපැතුම් පණිවුඩයේ තවදුරටත් සඳහන් වේ."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ආර්මේනියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "වහග්ං ඛචතුර්යං",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ආර්මේනියා ජනරජය සහ ශ්‍රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ආර්මේනියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ආර්මේනියානු",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "ஆர்மீனியா இலங்கைக்கு சகோதர கரங்களை நீட்டுகிறது",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "இரு நாட்டு மக்களின் நலனுக்காக ஆர்மேனியா குடியரசுக்கும் இலங்கைக்கும் இடையிலான ஒத்துழைப்பை மேலும் வலுப்படுத்த உறுதி பூண்டுள்ளதாக ஜனாதிபதி ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்கவுக்கு அனுப்பி வைத்துள்ள வாழ்த்துச் செய்தியில் ஆர்மேனியாவின் ஜனாதிபதி திரு.வாகன் கச்சதுரியன் தெரிவித்துள்ளார்.",
        "ஜனாதிபதியாக தெரிவுசெய்யப்பட்டுள்ள திரு.ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்கவிற்கு வாழ்த்துக்களை தெரிவித்துள்ள ஆர்மேனியா ஜனாதிபதி, இலங்கையின் முன்னேற்றத்திற்காக திரு.விக்கிரமசிங்கவின் அர்ப்பணிப்பை பாராட்டியுள்ளார்.",
        "இலங்கையின் நட்புறவு கொண்ட மக்களுக்கு நல்ல ஆரோக்கியம், வெற்றி மற்றும் அமைதி கிடைக்க வாழ்த்துவதாக ஆர்மேனிய ஜனாதிபதியின் வாழ்த்துச் செய்தியில் மேலும் தெரிவிக்கப்பட்டுள்ளது."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "இலங்கை",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ஆர்மீனியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "வஹகன் கச்சதுரியன்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆர்மீனியா குடியரசு மற்றும் இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஆர்மீனியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "விக்கிரமாதித்தன்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஆர்மேனியன்",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}