{
  "newspaper_id": "island-lk",
  "url": "http://island.lk/share-market-gains-as-a-result-of-fuel-price-reduction/",
  "time_ut": 1658158200,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Share market gains as a result of fuel price reduction",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Share market gains as a result of fuel price reduction",
      "author": "Sahan Weerasooriya",
      "body_lines": [
        "The stock market gained sharply yesterday in the aftermath of the peaceful revolt by the people against the incumbent regime and also on account of the recent fuel price reduction which resulted from the global oil price coming down, stock market analysts said.",
        "The fuel price was the main contributory factor to the country’s inflationary pressure and some positive behaviour was observed in the market after the announcement of the Rs 20 reduction by the Ceylon Petroleum Corporation (CPC) and Lanka IOC, market analysts said.",
        "It is said that owing to the global recession world oil prices are also coming down, which would positively impact the Sri Lanka economy. Further, certain media reports revealed a probable foreign exchange inflow to Sri Lanka. These positive statements sent the market to positive territory, which resulted in more investor participation in the market, stock brokers said.",
        "The stock market witnessed share gains in mid-morning trade with the liquid index moving up over 1 per cent and ending on a positive note. The active S&PSL20 Index gained by over 5 per cent and the benchmark ASPI by over 3 per cent. The All- Share Price Index went up by 68.8 points and S and P SL20 rose by 18.6 points. Turnover stood at Rs 1.4 billion with a single crossing from JKH, which crossed 900,000 shares to the tune of Rs 109.8 million; its shares traded at Rs 122.",
        "In the retail market top seven companies that mainly contributed to the turnover were; Hayleys Rs 367 million (5.1 million shares traded), Browns Investments Rs 171 million (21.5 million shares traded), Lanka IOC Rs 164.8 million (two million shares traded), Expolanka Holdings Rs 137 million (764,000 shares traded), Kelani Valley Plantations Rs 42.4 million (505,000 shares traded), LOLC Finance Rs 31.5 million (4.1 million shares traded) and Agalawatta Plantation Rs 27.4 million ( 831,000 shares traded). During the day 64.9 million share volume changed hands in 14000 transactions.",
        "Meanwhile, the company with the biggest market capitalization at the CSE reported a major transaction recently. Expolanka Holdings, one of the subsidiaries Expolanka Freight (Pvt) Ltd., divested two companies belonging to them; namely, Pulsar Shipping (Pvt) Ltd., and Pulsar Marine Services (Pvt) Ltd., to PB Logistics (Pvt) Ltd. The total consideration of the two transactions was Rs 1.34 billion.",
        "Expolanka Holdings divested the two companies as a strategic move and their market capitalization in the CSE was 10.8 per cent or Rs 349 billion.",
        "Yesterday the Central Bank US dollar buying rate was Rs 357.60 and the selling rate Rs 368.34. Inflation is at 45.30 per cent at the moment but this rate would likely decline if the global oil prices come down drastically with the ongoing global recession. At present, the crude oil price is US $ 100 and is expected to come down to US $ 60 or little more than that and would benefit the balance of payments issue to a greater extent, some economists said.",
        "Leave a Reply Cancel replyYour email address will not be published. Required fields are marked *Comment Name *",
        "Save my name, email, and website in this browser for the next time I comment."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "yesterday",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "20",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Ceylon Petroleum Corporation",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "CPC",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Lanka IOC",
            "label": "LOC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "mid-morning",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "over 1 per cent",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "over 5 per cent",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "over 3 per cent",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "All-",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "68.8",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "18.6",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Rs 1.4 billion",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "JKH",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "900,000",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "109.8 million",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "122",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "seven",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "367 million",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "5.1 million",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Browns Investments Rs",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "171 million",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "21.5 million",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Lanka IOC Rs 164.8 million",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "two million",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "137 million",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "764,000",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "42.4 million",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "505,000",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "LOLC",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "31.5 million",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "4.1 million",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Agalawatta Plantation Rs",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "27.4 million",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "831,000",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "the day",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "64.9 million",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "14000",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "CSE",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Expolanka Holdings",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "one",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Expolanka Freight",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "two",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Pulsar Shipping",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Pulsar Marine Services",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "PB Logistics (Pvt) Ltd.",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "two",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "1.34 billion",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Expolanka Holdings",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "two",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "CSE",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "10.8 per cent",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "349 billion",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Yesterday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Central Bank",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "US",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "368.34",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "45.30 per cent",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "US",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "100",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "60",
            "label": "MONEY"
          }
        ],
        [],
        []
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "ඉන්ධන මිල අඩුකිරීමේ ප්‍රතිඵලයක් ලෙස කොටස් වෙළදපොලේ ලාභය",
      "author": "සහන් වීරසූරිය",
      "body_lines": [
        "වත්මන් පාලනයට එරෙහිව ජනතාව විසින් දියත් කරන ලද සාමකාමී කැරැල්ලෙන් පසුව සහ ගෝලීය තෙල් මිල පහළ යාමේ ප්‍රතිඵලයක් ලෙස පසුගියදා සිදුවූ ඉන්ධන මිල අඩුවීම හේතුවෙන් කොටස් වෙළෙඳපොළ ඊයේ දිනයේදී ශීඝ්‍ර ලෙස ඉහළ ගිය බව කොටස් වෙළෙඳපොළ විශ්ලේෂකයෝ පවසති.",
        "රටේ උද්ධමන පීඩනයට ඉන්ධන මිල ප්‍රධානතම සාධකය වූ අතර ලංකා ඛණිජ තෙල් සංස්ථාව (CPC) සහ Lanka IOC විසින් රුපියල් 20කින් අඩු කිරීම ප්‍රකාශ කිරීමෙන් පසු වෙළෙඳපොළ තුළ යම් ධනාත්මක හැසිරීමක් දක්නට ලැබුණු බව වෙළෙඳපොළ විශ්ලේෂකයෝ පවසති.",
        "ගෝලීය අවපාතය හේතුවෙන් ලෝක තෙල් මිල ද පහළ යමින් පවතින අතර එය ශ්‍රී ලංකා ආර්ථිකයට ධනාත්මක බලපෑමක් ඇති කරනු ඇතැයි පැවසේ. තවද, ඇතැම් මාධ්‍ය වාර්තා මගින් ශ්‍රී ලංකාවට විදේශ විනිමය ගලා ඒම සිදුවිය හැකි බව අනාවරණය විය. මෙම ධනාත්මක ප්‍රකාශයන් වෙළඳපල ධනාත්මක ප්‍රදේශයකට යවන ලද අතර එමඟින් වෙළඳපල තුළ වැඩි ආයෝජකයින්ගේ සහභාගීත්වය ඇති වූ බව කොටස් තැරැව්කරුවන් පවසයි.",
        "ද්‍රව දර්ශකය සියයට 1 ට වඩා ඉහළ ගොස් ධනාත්මක සටහනකින් අවසන් වීමත් සමඟ කොටස් වෙලඳපොල මධ්‍යම උදෑසන වෙළඳාමේ කොටස් ලාභයක් පෙන්නුම් කළේය. සක්‍රීය S&PSL20 දර්ශකය සියයට 5කට වඩා වැඩි ප්‍රමාණයකින් සහ මිණුම් ලකුණ ASPI සියයට 3කට වඩා වැඩි විය. සියලු කොටස් මිල දර්ශකය ඒකක 68.8 කින් ඉහළ ගිය අතර S සහ P SL20 ඒකක 18.6 කින් ඉහළ ගියේය. JKH හි එක් හරස් මාර්ගයකින් පිරිවැටුම රුපියල් බිලියන 1.4 ක් වූ අතර එය කොටස් 900,000 ඉක්මවා රුපියල් මිලියන 109.8 ක් විය. එහි කොටස් රුපියල් 122 ට ගනුදෙනු විය.",
        "සිල්ලර වෙළඳපොලේ පිරිවැටුම සඳහා ප්‍රධාන වශයෙන් දායක වූ සමාගම් හත වූයේ; හේලීස් රුපියල් මිලියන 367 (කොටස් මිලියන 5.1 ක් ගනුදෙනු), බ්‍රවුන්ස් ඉන්වෙස්ට්මන්ට්ස් රුපියල් මිලියන 171 (කොටස් මිලියන 21.5 ක් ගනුදෙනු), ලංකා අයිඕසී රුපියල් මිලියන 164.8 (කොටස් මිලියන දෙකක්), එක්ස්පෝලංකා හෝල්ඩිංග්ස් රුපියල් මිලියන 137 (කොටස් 764,000 ක් ගනුදෙනු), කැලණිවැලි වැවිලි ප්ලාන්ටේෂන්ස් රු. මිලියන 42.4 ක් (කොටස් 505,000 ක් ගනුදෙනු කර ඇත), LOLC ෆිනෑන්ස් රුපියල් මිලියන 31.5 ක් (කොටස් මිලියන 4.1 ක් ගනුදෙනු කර ඇත) සහ අගලවත්ත වැවිලි සමාගම රුපියල් මිලියන 27.4 ක් (කොටස් 831,000 ක් ගනුදෙනු කර ඇත). දවස තුළ ගනුදෙනු 14000 කදී කොටස් පරිමාව මිලියන 64.9 ක් වෙනස් විය.",
        "මේ අතර, CSE හි විශාලතම වෙළඳපල ප්‍රාග්ධනීකරණය ඇති සමාගම පසුගියදා ප්‍රධාන ගනුදෙනුවක් වාර්තා කළේය. Expolanka Freight (Pvt) Ltd. හි අනුබද්ධිත සමාගමක් වන Expolanka Holdings, ඔවුන්ට අයත් සමාගම් දෙකක් ඉවත් කරන ලදී; එනම්, Pulsar Shipping (Pvt) Ltd., සහ Pulsar Marine Services (Pvt) Ltd., PB Logistics (Pvt) Ltd. මෙම ගනුදෙනු දෙකෙහි මුළු සලකා බැලීම රුපියල් බිලියන 1.34 කි.",
        "එක්ස්පෝලංකා හෝල්ඩිංග්ස් විසින් උපායමාර්ගික පියවරක් ලෙස සමාගම් දෙක ඉවත් කර ඇති අතර කොළඹ කොටස් වෙළඳපොලේ ඔවුන්ගේ වෙළඳපල ප්‍රාග්ධනීකරණය සියයට 10.8ක් හෙවත් රුපියල් බිලියන 349ක් විය.",
        "ඊයේ දිනයේදී මහ බැංකුවේ ඩොලරයේ ගැනුම් අනුපාතිකය රුපියල් 357.60ක් වූ අතර විකුණුම් මිල රුපියල් 368.34ක් විය. උද්ධමනය මේ වන විට සියයට 45.30 මට්ටමේ පවතින නමුත් පවතින ගෝලීය අවපාතයත් සමඟ ගෝලීය තෙල් මිල විශාල ලෙස පහත වැටුණහොත් මෙම අනුපාතය පහත වැටීමට ඉඩ ඇත. වර්තමානයේ බොරතෙල් මිල ඇමෙරිකානු ඩොලර් 100 ක් වන අතර එය ඇමෙරිකානු ඩොලර් 60 ක් හෝ ඊට වඩා ටිකක් අඩු වනු ඇතැයි අපේක්ෂා කරන අතර එය ගෙවුම් ශේෂ නිකුතුවට විශාල වශයෙන් වාසිදායක වනු ඇතැයි සමහර ආර්ථික විද්‍යාඥයින් පවසයි.",
        "පිළිතුරක් දෙන්න පිළිතුර අවලංගු කරන්න ඔබගේ විද්‍යුත් තැපැල් ලිපිනය ප්‍රකාශයට පත් නොකෙරේ. අවශ්‍ය ක්ෂේත්‍ර සලකුණු කර ඇත *අදහස් නම *",
        "මම ඊළඟ වතාවේ අදහස් දැක්වීම සඳහා මගේ නම, විද්‍යුත් තැපෑල සහ වෙබ් අඩවිය මෙම බ්‍රවුසරයේ සුරකින්න."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ඊයේ",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "20",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ලංකා ඛනිජ තෙල් නීතිගත සංස්ථාව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "CPC",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ලංකා IOC",
            "label": "LOC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "මධ්යම උදෑසන",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "සියයට 1 කට වඩා",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "සියයට 5 කට වඩා",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "සියයට 3 කට වඩා",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "සියලුම-",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "68.8",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "18.6",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "රුපියල් බිලියන 1.4 කි",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජේ.කේ.එච්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "900,000 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "මිලියන 109.8 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "122",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "හත",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "මිලියන 367 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "මිලියන 5.1 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Browns Investments රු",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "මිලියන 171 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "මිලියන 21.5 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ලංකා IOC රුපියල් මිලියන 164.8 කි",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "මිලියන දෙකක්",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "මිලියන 137 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "764,000 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "මිලියන 42.4 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "505,000 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "LOLC",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "මිලියන 31.5 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "මිලියන 4.1 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "අගලවත්ත වැවිලි රු",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "මිලියන 27.4 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "831,000 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "දවස",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මිලියන 64.9 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "14000",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "CSE",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "එක්ස්පෝලංකා හෝල්ඩිංග්ස්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "එක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "එක්ස්පෝලංකා භාණ්ඩ ප්‍රවාහනය",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "දෙක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "පල්සර් නැව්ගත කිරීම",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "පල්සර් නාවික සේවා",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "PB Logistics (Pvt) Ltd.",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "දෙක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "බිලියන 1.34 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "එක්ස්පෝලංකා හෝල්ඩිංග්ස්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "දෙක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "CSE",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "සියයට 10.8 කි",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "බිලියන 349 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ඊයේ",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මහ බැංකුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "එක්සත් ජනපදය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "368.34 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "සියයට 45.30 කි",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "එක්සත් ජනපදය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "100",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "60",
            "label": "MONEY"
          }
        ],
        [],
        []
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "எரிபொருள் விலை குறைப்பின் விளைவாக பங்குச் சந்தை லாபம்",
      "author": "சஹான் வீரசூரிய",
      "body_lines": [
        "தற்போதைய ஆட்சிக்கு எதிராக மக்கள் நடத்திய அமைதியான கிளர்ச்சியின் விளைவாகவும், சர்வதேச சந்தையில் கச்சா எண்ணெய் விலை சரிந்ததன் விளைவாக சமீபத்திய எரிபொருள் விலைக் குறைப்பு காரணமாகவும் பங்குச் சந்தை நேற்று கடுமையாக உயர்ந்தது என்று பங்குச் சந்தை ஆய்வாளர்கள் தெரிவித்தனர்.",
        "நாட்டின் பணவீக்க அழுத்தத்திற்கு எரிபொருள் விலையே முக்கிய காரணியாக இருந்ததுடன், இலங்கை பெற்றோலியக் கூட்டுத்தாபனம் (CPC) மற்றும் லங்கா IOC ஆகியவற்றின் 20 ரூபா குறைப்பு அறிவிப்பின் பின்னர் சந்தையில் சில சாதகமான நடத்தைகள் காணப்பட்டதாக சந்தை ஆய்வாளர்கள் தெரிவித்தனர்.",
        "உலகப் பொருளாதார மந்தநிலை காரணமாக உலக எண்ணெய் விலைகளும் வீழ்ச்சியடைந்து வருவதாகவும், இது இலங்கையின் பொருளாதாரத்தை சாதகமாக பாதிக்கும் என்றும் கூறப்படுகிறது. மேலும், சில ஊடக அறிக்கைகள் இலங்கைக்கு அந்நிய செலாவணி வருவதற்கான சாத்தியக்கூறுகளை வெளிப்படுத்தின. இந்த நேர்மறை அறிக்கைகள் சந்தையை நேர்மறையான பகுதிக்கு அனுப்பியது, இதன் விளைவாக சந்தையில் அதிக முதலீட்டாளர்கள் பங்கேற்பதாக பங்கு தரகர்கள் தெரிவித்தனர்.",
        "பங்குச் சந்தையானது, பங்குச் சந்தையானது, பங்குச் சந்தையின் பங்கு லாபத்தைக் கண்டது. செயலில் உள்ள எஸ்&பிஎஸ்எல்20 இன்டெக்ஸ் 5 சதவீதத்திற்கும் அதிகமாகவும், பெஞ்ச்மார்க் ஏஎஸ்பிஐ 3 சதவீதத்திற்கும் அதிகமாகவும் அதிகரித்தது. அனைத்துப் பங்கு விலைச் சுட்டெண் 68.8 புள்ளிகளாலும், S மற்றும் P SL20 18.6 புள்ளிகளாலும் அதிகரித்தன. விற்றுமுதல் JKH இலிருந்து ரூ 1.4 பில்லியனாக இருந்தது, இது 900,000 பங்குகளை தாண்டி ரூ 109.8 மில்லியனை எட்டியது; அதன் பங்குகள் 122 ரூபாய்க்கு வர்த்தகம் செய்யப்பட்டது.",
        "சில்லறை விற்பனைச் சந்தையில் முதன்மையான ஏழு நிறுவனங்கள் விற்றுமுதல் பங்களித்தன; ஹேலிஸ் ரூ 367 மில்லியன் (5.1 மில்லியன் பங்குகள் வர்த்தகம்), பிரவுன்ஸ் இன்வெஸ்ட்மென்ட் ரூ 171 மில்லியன் (21.5 மில்லியன் பங்குகள் வர்த்தகம்), லங்கா ஐஓசி ரூ 164.8 மில்லியன் (இரண்டு மில்லியன் பங்குகள் வர்த்தகம்), எக்ஸ்போலங்கா ஹோல்டிங்ஸ் ரூ 137 மில்லியன் (764,000 பங்குகள் வர்த்தகம்), களனி வேலி பிளான்டேஷன்ஸ் ரூ. 42.4 மில்லியன் (505,000 பங்குகள் வர்த்தகம்), LOLC Finance ரூ 31.5 மில்லியன் (4.1 மில்லியன் பங்குகள் வர்த்தகம்) மற்றும் அகலவத்த தோட்டம் ரூ 27.4 மில்லியன் (831,000 பங்குகள் வர்த்தகம்). நாளின் போது 14000 பரிவர்த்தனைகளில் 64.9 மில்லியன் பங்கு அளவு மாறியது.",
        "இதற்கிடையில், CSE இல் மிகப்பெரிய சந்தை மூலதனத்தைக் கொண்ட நிறுவனம் சமீபத்தில் ஒரு பெரிய பரிவர்த்தனையைப் புகாரளித்தது. Expolanka Freight (Pvt) Ltd. என்ற துணை நிறுவனங்களில் ஒன்றான எக்ஸ்போலங்கா ஹோல்டிங்ஸ், அவர்களுக்குச் சொந்தமான இரண்டு நிறுவனங்களை விலக்கியது; அதாவது பல்சர் ஷிப்பிங் (பிரைவேட்) லிமிடெட், மற்றும் பல்சர் மரைன் சர்வீசஸ் (பிரைவேட்) லிமிடெட், பிபி லாஜிஸ்டிக்ஸ் (பிரைவேட்) லிமிடெட் ஆகிய இரண்டு பரிவர்த்தனைகளின் மொத்தக் கருத்தில் ரூ. 1.34 பில்லியன்.",
        "எக்ஸ்போலங்கா ஹோல்டிங்ஸ் இரண்டு நிறுவனங்களையும் ஒரு மூலோபாய நடவடிக்கையாக விலக்கியது மற்றும் CSE இல் அவற்றின் சந்தை மூலதனம் 10.8 சதவீதம் அல்லது ரூ 349 பில்லியனாக இருந்தது.",
        "நேற்று மத்திய வங்கியின் அமெரிக்க டொலர் கொள்வனவு விலை 357.60 ரூபாவாகவும் விற்பனை விலை 368.34 ரூபாவாகவும் இருந்தது. இந்த நேரத்தில் பணவீக்கம் 45.30 சதவீதமாக உள்ளது, ஆனால் தற்போதைய உலகளாவிய மந்தநிலையால் உலக எண்ணெய் விலை கடுமையாகக் குறைந்தால் இந்த விகிதம் குறைய வாய்ப்புள்ளது. தற்போது, ​​கச்சா எண்ணெய் விலை 100 அமெரிக்க டாலர்களாக உள்ளது, மேலும் இது 60 அமெரிக்க டாலர்கள் அல்லது அதற்கும் குறைவாக வரும் என்று எதிர்பார்க்கப்படுகிறது, மேலும் இது பேலன்ஸ் ஆஃப் பேமென்ட் பிரச்சினைக்கு அதிக அளவில் பயனளிக்கும் என்று சில பொருளாதார வல்லுநர்கள் தெரிவித்தனர்.",
        "ஒரு பதிலை விடுங்கள் பதிலை ரத்துசெய் உங்கள் மின்னஞ்சல் முகவரி வெளியிடப்படாது. தேவையான புலங்கள் குறிக்கப்பட்டுள்ளன *கருத்து பெயர் *",
        "அடுத்த முறை நான் கருத்து தெரிவிக்க, எனது பெயர், மின்னஞ்சல் மற்றும் இணையதளத்தை இந்த உலாவியில் சேமிக்கவும்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "நேற்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "20",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை பெற்றோலியக் கூட்டுத்தாபனம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "CPC",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "லங்கா ஐ.ஓ.சி",
            "label": "LOC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "நண்பகல்",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "1 சதவீதத்திற்கு மேல்",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "5 சதவீதத்திற்கு மேல்",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "3 சதவீதத்திற்கும் மேல்",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "அனைத்தும்-",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "68.8",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "18.6",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரூ 1.4 பில்லியன்",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜே.கே.எச்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "900,000",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "109.8 மில்லியன்",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "122",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஏழு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "367 மில்லியன்",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "5.1 மில்லியன்",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "பிரவுன்ஸ் முதலீடுகள் ரூ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "171 மில்லியன்",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "21.5 மில்லியன்",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "லங்கா ஐஓசி ரூ 164.8 மில்லியன்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இரண்டு மில்லியன்",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "137 மில்லியன்",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "764,000",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "42.4 மில்லியன்",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "505,000",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "LOLC",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "31.5 மில்லியன்",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "4.1 மில்லியன்",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "அகலவத்தை தோட்டம் ரூ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "27.4 மில்லியன்",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "831,000",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "தினம்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "64.9 மில்லியன்",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "14000",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "CSE",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "எக்ஸ்போலங்கா ஹோல்டிங்ஸ்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஒன்று",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "எக்ஸ்போலங்கா சரக்கு",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இரண்டு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "பல்சர் கப்பல் போக்குவரத்து",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "பல்சர் மரைன் சர்வீசஸ்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "PB Logistics (Pvt) Ltd.",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இரண்டு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "1.34 பில்லியன்",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "எக்ஸ்போலங்கா ஹோல்டிங்ஸ்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இரண்டு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "CSE",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "10.8 சதவீதம்",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "349 பில்லியன்",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "நேற்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "மத்திய வங்கி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "எங்களுக்கு",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "368.34",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "45.30 சதவீதம்",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "எங்களுக்கு",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "100",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "60",
            "label": "MONEY"
          }
        ],
        [],
        []
      ]
    }
  }
}