{
  "newspaper_id": "lankadeepa-lk",
  "url": "https://www.lankadeepa.lk/latest_news/දිස්ත්‍රික්කවලට-පොහොර-බෙදෙන්නේ-මෙහෙමයි/1-616527",
  "time_ut": 1657962701,
  "original_lang": "si",
  "original_title": "දිස්ත්‍රික්කවලට පොහොර බෙදෙන්නේ මෙහෙමයි",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Fertilizer is distributed to the districts as follows",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "The Department of Agricultural Services Development mentioned that the bulk distribution of urea fertilizer given to Sri Lanka by the Government of India is currently being done very successfully.",
        "102.5 metric tons of urea fertilizer has been supplied to Polonnaruwa district, 196.84 metric tons to Hambantota district, 63 metric tons to Monaragala district, and 25 metric tons to Matale district.",
        "The Department of Agricultural Development says that the fertilizer distribution will be done for the next few days. These fertilizer distribution activities are carried out by the two government-owned fertilizer companies Lanka Fertilizer Company and Lanka Commercial Fertilizer Company."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "The Department of Agricultural Services Development",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Government of India",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "102.5 metric tons",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "Polonnaruwa",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "196.84 metric tons",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "Hambantota district",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "63 metric tons",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "Monaragala",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "25 metric tons",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "Matale",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "The Department of Agricultural Development",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the next few days",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "two",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Lanka Fertilizer Company",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Commercial Fertilizer Company",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "දිස්ත්‍රික්කවලට පොහොර බෙදෙන්නේ මෙහෙමයි",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "ඉන්දීය රජය විසින් මෙරටට ලබා දෙන ලද යුරියා පොහොර තොග බෙදාහැරීම මේ වනවිට ඉතාමත් සාර්ථකව සිදු කරන බව ගොවිජන සේවා සංවර්ධන දෙපාර්තමේන්තුව සඳහන් කළේය.",
        "පොළොන්නරුව දිස්ත්‍රික්කයට  යුරියා පොහොර මෙට්‍රික් ටොන් 102.5ක්, හම්බන්තොට දිස්ත්‍රික්කයට මෙට්‍රික් ටොන්196.84ක්, මොනරාගල දිස්ත්‍රික්කයට මෙට්‍රික් ටොන් 63ක්, හා මාතලේ දිස්ත්‍රික්කයට මෙට්‍රික් ටොන් 25ක් ද වශයෙන් සපයනු ලැබ තිබේ.",
        "ඉදිරි දින කිහිපය පුරාම පොහොර බෙදාහැරීමේ කටයුතු සිදු කෙරෙන බව ගොවිජන සංවර්ධන දෙපාර්තමේන්තුව පවසයි. මෙම පොහොර බෙදාහැරීම් කටයුතු රජයට අයත් පොහොර සමාගම් දෙක වන  ලංකා පොහොර සමාගම හා ලංකා කොමර්ෂල් පොහොර සමාගම විසින් සිදු කරනු ලබයි."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "කෘෂිකර්ම සේවා සංවර්ධන දෙපාර්තමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දීය රජය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "මෙට්රික් ටොන් 102.5 කි",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "පොළොන්නරුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "මෙට්‍රික් ටොන් 196.84 කි",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "හම්බන්තොට දිස්ත්‍රික්කය",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "මෙට්රික් ටොන් 63 කි",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "මොනරාගල",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මෙට්රික් ටොන් 25 කි",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "මාතලේ",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "කෘෂිකර්ම සංවර්ධන දෙපාර්තමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉදිරි දින කිහිපය",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "දෙක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ලංකා පොහොර සමාගම",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "වාණිජ පොහොර සමාගම",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "கீழ்க்கண்டவாறு மாவட்டங்களுக்கு உரம் விநியோகிக்கப்படுகிறது",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "இந்திய அரசாங்கத்தினால் இலங்கைக்கு வழங்கப்பட்ட யூரியா உரத்தின் மொத்த விநியோகம் தற்போது மிகவும் வெற்றிகரமாக நடைபெற்று வருவதாக விவசாய சேவைகள் அபிவிருத்தி திணைக்களம் குறிப்பிட்டுள்ளது.",
        "பொலன்னறுவை மாவட்டத்திற்கு 102.5 மெற்றிக்தொன் யூரியா உரமும், ஹம்பாந்தோட்டை மாவட்டத்திற்கு 196.84 மெற்றிக்தொன்னும், மொனராகலை மாவட்டத்திற்கு 63 மெற்றிக்தொன்னும், மாத்தளை மாவட்டத்திற்கு 25 மெற்றிக்தொன்னும் வழங்கப்பட்டுள்ளன.",
        "உர விநியோகம் எதிர்வரும் சில நாட்களுக்கு மேற்கொள்ளப்படும் என விவசாய அபிவிருத்தி திணைக்களம் தெரிவித்துள்ளது. இந்த உர விநியோக நடவடிக்கைகளை அரசாங்கத்திற்குச் சொந்தமான இரண்டு உர நிறுவனங்களான லங்கா உர நிறுவனம் மற்றும் லங்கா கொமர்ஷல் உரக் கம்பனி என்பன முன்னெடுக்கின்றன."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "விவசாய சேவைகள் அபிவிருத்தி திணைக்களம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்திய அரசு",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "102.5 மெட்ரிக் டன்",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "பொலன்னறுவை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "196.84 மெட்ரிக் டன்",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஹம்பாந்தோட்டை மாவட்டம்",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "63 மெட்ரிக் டன்",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "மொனராகலை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "25 மெட்ரிக் டன்",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "மாத்தளை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "வேளாண்மை வளர்ச்சித் துறை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "அடுத்த சில நாட்கள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இரண்டு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "லங்கா உர நிறுவனம்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "வணிக உர நிறுவனம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}