{
  "newspaper_id": "news-first-lk",
  "url": "https://www.newsfirst.lk/2022/07/16/maithripala-warns-of-a-divide-in-parliament/",
  "time_ut": 1657953660,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Maithripala warns of a divide in Parliament",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Maithripala warns of a divide in Parliament",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); Former President and the Chairman of the Sri Lanka Freedom Party (SLFP) Maithripala Sirisena says that the current situation of multiple candidates being proposed as Presidential Candidates could cause for a rift within the Parliament.",
        "Speaking to News 1st, the former President stated that no matter whoever may win out of the three candidates proposed, it would create a divide, and the best possible alternative is for the Party Leaders to discuss and propose a single candidate for the Presidential election.",
        "He further stated that this divide within the Parliament would end up being an issue for any Government that is yet to come.",
        "However, the former President said that the Sri Lanka Freedom Party has not yet taken a decision in this regard, and will come into a consensus after the nominations are handed over.",
        "The former President also added that although there were requests, he will not be contesting for Presidency, and will support an existing candidate.",
        "I will serve the country even after my resignation: former President"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Maithripala",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "Parliament",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "News 1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Sri Lanka Freedom Party",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Maithripala Sirisena",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "three",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the Sri Lanka Freedom Party",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [],
        []
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව බෙදීමක් ගැන මෛත්‍රීපාල අනතුරු අඟවයි",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); ජනාධිපති අපේක්ෂකයින් ලෙස අපේක්ෂකයින් කිහිප දෙනෙකු යෝජනා වීම වත්මන් තත්ත්වය හේතුවෙන් පාර්ලිමේන්තුව තුළ ගැටුමක් ඇති විය හැකි බව හිටපු ජනාධිපති, ශ්‍රී ලංකා නිදහස් පක්ෂ සභාපති මෛත්‍රීපාල සිරිසේන පවසනවා.",
        "News 1st වෙත අදහස් දක්වමින් හිටපු ජනාධිපතිවරයා ප්‍රකාශ කළේ යෝජනා කර ඇති අපේක්ෂකයින් තිදෙනාගෙන් කවුරුන් ජයග්‍රහණය කළත් එය භේදයක් ඇති කරන බවත්, හැකි හොඳම විකල්පය පක්ෂ නායකයන් සාකච්ඡා කර ජනාධිපතිවරණය සඳහා තනි අපේක්ෂකයෙකු යෝජනා කිරීම බවත්ය.",
        "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව තුළ ඇති වන මෙම බෙදීම ඉදිරියේදී එන ඕනෑම රජයකට ප්‍රශ්නයක් බවට පත්වන බවද ඔහු වැඩිදුරටත් ප්‍රකාශ කළේය.",
        "කෙසේ වෙතත්, ශ්‍රී ලංකා නිදහස් පක්ෂය මේ සම්බන්ධයෙන් මෙතෙක් තීරණයක් ගෙන නොමැති බවත්, නාමයෝජනා භාරදීමෙන් පසු පොදු එකඟතාවකට පැමිණෙන බවත් හිටපු ජනාධිපතිවරයා සඳහන් කළේය.",
        "ඉල්ලීම් තිබුණද තමන් ජනාධිපතිවරණයට ඉදිරිපත් නොවන බවත් දැනට සිටින අපේක්ෂකයෙකුට සහය පළ කරන බවත් හිටපු ජනාධිපතිවරයා වැඩිදුරටත් පැවසීය.",
        "ඉල්ලා අස් වූ පසුවත් මම රටට සේවය කරනවා: හිටපු ජනපති"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "මෛත්‍රීපාල",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "News 1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකා නිදහස් පක්ෂය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "මෛත්‍රීපාල සිරිසේන",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "තුන්",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකා නිදහස් පක්ෂය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [],
        []
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "பாராளுமன்றத்தில் பிளவு ஏற்படும் என மைத்திரிபால எச்சரித்துள்ளார்",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); ஜனாதிபதி வேட்பாளராக பல வேட்பாளர்கள் முன்மொழியப்படும் தற்போதைய சூழ்நிலை பாராளுமன்றத்திற்குள் குழப்பத்தை ஏற்படுத்தக்கூடும் என முன்னாள் ஜனாதிபதியும் ஸ்ரீலங்கா சுதந்திரக் கட்சியின் தலைவருமான மைத்திரிபால சிறிசேன தெரிவித்துள்ளார்.",
        "நியூஸ் 1ஸ்டுக்கு கருத்து தெரிவித்த முன்னாள் ஜனாதிபதி, முன்மொழியப்பட்ட மூன்று வேட்பாளர்களில் யார் வெற்றி பெற்றாலும் அது பிளவை உருவாக்கும் எனவும், ஜனாதிபதித் தேர்தலுக்கு தனி வேட்பாளரை கட்சித் தலைவர்கள் கலந்துரையாடி முன்மொழிவதே சிறந்த மாற்று வழி எனவும் தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "பாராளுமன்றத்திற்குள் ஏற்பட்டுள்ள இந்த பிளவு இனி வரப்போகும் எந்தவொரு அரசாங்கத்திற்கும் ஒரு பிரச்சினையாகவே முடிவடையும் என அவர் மேலும் தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "எவ்வாறாயினும், இது தொடர்பில் ஸ்ரீலங்கா சுதந்திரக் கட்சி இன்னும் தீர்மானம் எடுக்கவில்லை எனவும், வேட்புமனுக்கள் கையளிக்கப்பட்டதன் பின்னர் இணக்கப்பாட்டிற்கு வரும் எனவும் முன்னாள் ஜனாதிபதி தெரிவித்துள்ளார்.",
        "கோரிக்கைகள் முன்வைக்கப்பட்ட போதிலும், தான் ஜனாதிபதி தேர்தலில் போட்டியிடப் போவதில்லை என்றும், தற்போதுள்ள வேட்பாளருக்கு ஆதரவளிப்பதாகவும் முன்னாள் ஜனாதிபதி மேலும் தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "பதவி விலகினாலும் நாட்டுக்கு சேவை செய்வேன்: முன்னாள் ஜனாதிபதி"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "மைத்திரிபால",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "News 1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஸ்ரீலங்கா சுதந்திரக் கட்சி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "மைத்திரிபால சிறிசேன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "மூன்று",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஸ்ரீலங்கா சுதந்திரக் கட்சி",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [],
        []
      ]
    }
  }
}