{
  "newspaper_id": "d-b-s-jeyaraj-com",
  "url": "https://dbsjeyaraj.com/dbsj/archives/78484",
  "time_ut": 1657306800,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Thousands of protesters continue to occupy the President’s House, the Presidential Secretariat and Temple Trees at  night after breaking into them earlier in the day demanding the immediate resignation of President Gotabaya Rajapaksa and Prime Minister Ranil Wickremesinghe",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Thousands of protesters continue to occupy the President’s House, the Presidential Secretariat and Temple Trees at  night after breaking into them earlier in the day demanding the immediate resignation of President Gotabaya Rajapaksa and Prime Minister Ranil Wickremesinghe",
      "author": "Administrator",
      "body_lines": [
        "Thousands of protesters continued to occupy the President’s House, the Presidential Secretariat and Temple Trees last night after breaking into them earlier in the day as they demanded the immediate resignation of President Gotabaya Rajapaksa and Prime Minister Ranil Wickremesinghe.",
        "Protesters also converged on Parliament and Premier Wickremesinghe’s private residence located at 5th Lane off Thurstan Road in Colombo 3.",
        "Police fired water cannon and teargas last evening to disperse those gathered near the Premier’s private residence.   Protesters demanding the immediate resignation of President Rajapaksa first broke into the President’s House in Fort after breaking through multiple security barricades. They later breached the security parameters of the Presidential Secretariat, outside which they had been protesting since April.",
        "Police fired numerous rounds of teargas and used several water cannon trucks to hold back the protesters from marching up Chatham Street and breaking down barricades to reach the President’s House. Police and security forces personnel, though, were ultimately overwhelmed by the sheer weight of numbers from the protesters’ ranks.",
        "Several MPs from the opposition, including Samagi Jana Balawegaya’s (SJB) Field Marshal Sarath Fonseka and Harsha De Silva joined yesterday’s protest. SJB MPs Rajitha Senaratne, however, was attacked by protesters when he attempted to join the protest and had to flee from the scene. SJB MP Vadivel Suresh, meanwhile, also suffered injuries in a fall after being manhandled by some protesters.",
        "President Gotabaya Rajapaksa was not at the President’s House at the time it was breached and his whereabouts were unknown as of last evening.",
        "A group of 16 Sri Lanka Podujana Peramuna (SLPP) MPs wrote to President Rajapaksa yesterday, asking him to immediately step down and pave the way for a mature leader representing Parliament who can win a parliamentary majority and who is not facing allegations of corruption. The group includes former ministers Dullas Alahapperuma, Channa Jayasumana and Nalaka Godahewa.",
        "Earlier, tens of thousands of protesters descended on Colombo after overcoming severe transport difficulties. Bus and transport services, which had already been affected by the prevailing fuel crisis, were further curtailed initially after a police curfew was imposed in seven police divisions of the Western Province. The curfew, widely condemned by lawyers and opposition parties as being illegal and a violation of fundamental rights, was lifted at 8am yesterday.",
        "With buses being in short supply, protesters used any vehicles at their disposal to get to Colombo for the “Go Home Gota” protest announced for yesterday. There were angry scenes at several train stations, including Kandy and Galle, when crowds attempting to make their way to Colombo found there were no trains. Eventually, however, a train left from Kandy carrying protesters while a train from Matara picked up those in Galle.",
        "Protesters in Galle also took over the ramparts of the Galle Fort, from where spectators had been kept away by police and security forces personnel during the ongoing test series between Sri Lanka and Australia.",
        "Those who could not make it to Colombo took to the streets in other parts of the country, where protests, both large and small, were held"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Thousands",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "House",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "the Presidential Secretariat",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "Gotabaya Rajapaksa",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "Ranil Wickremesinghe",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Thousands",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "House",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Presidential Secretariat",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "last night",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "Gotabaya Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "5th Lane",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "Thurstan Road in Colombo 3",
            "label": "FAC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "last evening",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "House",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Fort",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Presidential Secretariat",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "April",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Chatham Street",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "House",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Samagi Jana Balawegaya’s",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Harsha De Silva",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "yesterday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Rajitha Senaratne",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Vadivel Suresh",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Gotabaya Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "last evening",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "16",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Podujana Peramuna",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "yesterday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Dullas Alahapperuma",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Jayasumana",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Nalaka Godahewa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "tens of thousands",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "seven",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Western Province",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "8am",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "yesterday",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "yesterday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kandy",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Galle",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kandy",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Matara",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Galle",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Galle",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Galle Fort",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Australia",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        []
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "ජනාධිපති ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ මහතාට සහ අගමැති රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතාට වහාම ඉල්ලා අස්විය යුතු බවට බලකරමින් දහස් සංඛ්‍යාත විරෝධතාකරුවෝ පෙරේදා රාත්‍රියේ ජනාධිපති මන්දිරය, ජනාධිපති ලේකම් කාර්යාලය සහ අරලියගහ මන්දිරයට කඩා වැදී අඛණ්ඩව සිටිති.",
      "author": "පරිපාලක",
      "body_lines": [
        "ජනාධිපති ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ මහතාට සහ අගමැති රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතාට වහාම ඉල්ලා අස්විය යුතු බවට බලකරමින් දහස් සංඛ්‍යාත විරෝධතාකරුවන් ඊයේ රාත්‍රියේ ජනාධිපති මන්දිරය, ජනාධිපති ලේකම් කාර්යාලය සහ අරලියගහ මන්දිරයට කඩා වැදී අඛණ්ඩව වාඩි වී සිටියහ.",
        "කොළඹ 3 තර්ස්ටන් පාරට ඔබ්බෙන් 5 වන පටුමගේ පිහිටි පාර්ලිමේන්තුව සහ අග්‍රාමාත්‍ය වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතාගේ පෞද්ගලික නිවස වෙත ද විරෝධතාකරුවන් රැස්ව සිටියහ.",
        "අග්‍රාමාත්‍යවරයාගේ පෞද්ගලික නිවස අසල රැස්ව සිටි පිරිස් විසුරුවා හැරීමට පොලීසිය ඊයේ පස්වරුවේ ජල ප්‍රහාර සහ කඳුළු ගෑස් ප්‍රහාර එල්ල කළා. රාජපක්ෂ ජනාධිපතිවරයා වහා ඉල්ලා අස්විය යුතු බවට බලකරමින් විරෝධතාකරුවන් පළමුවෙන් කොටුව ජනාධිපති මන්දිරයට කඩා වැදුණේ ආරක්ෂක බාධක කිහිපයක් බිඳ දමාගෙනය. පසුව ඔවුන් අප්‍රේල් මාසයේ සිට විරෝධතාවයේ නිරත වූ ජනාධිපති ලේකම් කාර්යාලයේ ආරක්‍ෂක පරාමිතීන් ද කඩ කළහ.",
        "විරෝධතාකරුවන් චැතම් වීදිය දක්වා පා ගමනින් ගොස් ජනාධිපති මන්දිරයට පැමිණීමට තිබූ බාධක බිඳ දැමූ විරෝධතාකරුවන් මැඩපැවැත්වීම සඳහා පොලිසිය කඳුළු ගෑස් වට ගණනාවක් ප්‍රහාර එල්ල කළ අතර ජල ප්‍රහාරක රථ කිහිපයක් ද භාවිත කළේය. කෙසේ වෙතත්, පොලිසිය සහ ආරක්ෂක හමුදා නිලධාරීන් අවසානයේ විරෝධතාකරුවන්ගේ ශ්‍රේණියේ සංඛ්‍යාවේ බරින් යටපත් විය.",
        "සමගි ජන බලවේගයේ ෆීල්ඩ් මාර්ෂල් සරත් ෆොන්සේකා, හර්ෂ ද සිල්වා ඇතුළු විපක්ෂයේ මන්ත්‍රීවරුන් කිහිප දෙනෙකු ඊයේ විරෝධතාවයට එක්ව සිටියා. කෙසේ වෙතත්, SJB පාර්ලිමේන්තු මන්ත්‍රීවරුන් වන රාජිත සේනාරත්න මහතා විරෝධතාවයට එක්වීමට උත්සාහ කිරීමේදී විරෝධතාකරුවන් විසින් ප්‍රහාරයට ලක් වූ අතර එම ස්ථානයෙන් පලා යාමට සිදු විය. මේ අතර SJB පාර්ලිමේන්තු මන්ත්‍රී වඩිවෙල් සුරේෂ් ද ඇතැම් විරෝධතාකරුවන් විසින් පහර දීමෙන් පසු ඇද වැටීමෙන් තුවාල ලබා ඇත.",
        "ජනාධිපති මන්දිරය කඩා බිඳ දමන අවස්ථාවේ ජනාධිපති ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ මහතා එහි නොසිටි අතර ඊයේ සවස් වන විටත් ඔහු සිටියේ කොහේදැයි දැන ගැනීමට නොහැකි විය.",
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකා පොදුජන පෙරමුණේ (SLPP) මන්ත්‍රීවරුන් 16 දෙනෙකුගෙන් යුත් කණ්ඩායමක් ඊයේ ජනාධිපති රාජපක්ෂ මහතාට ලිපියක් යවමින් ඉල්ලා සිටියේ ඔහු වහා ඉල්ලා අස්වී පාර්ලිමේන්තු බහුතරයක් දිනාගත හැකි, දූෂණ චෝදනාවලට මුහුණ නොදෙන පරිණත නායකයෙකුට පාර කපන ලෙස ඉල්ලමිනි. එම කණ්ඩායමට හිටපු අමාත්‍යවරුන් වන ඩලස් අලහප්පෙරුම, චන්න ජයසුමන සහ නාලක ගොඩහේවා ඇතුළත්.",
        "මීට පෙර දස දහස් සංඛ්‍යාත විරෝධතාකරුවන් දැඩි ප්‍රවාහන දුෂ්කරතා මඟහරවාගෙන කොළඹට බැස්සේය. පවතින ඉන්ධන අර්බුදයෙන් දැනටමත් පීඩාවට පත්ව තිබූ බස් රථ සහ ප්‍රවාහන සේවා බස්නාහිර පළාතේ පොලිස් වසම් හතකට පොලිස් ඇඳිරි නීතිය පැනවීමෙන් පසු මුලදී තවදුරටත් සීමා කෙරිණි. නීතිවිරෝධී සහ මූලික අයිතිවාසිකම් කඩකිරීමක් ලෙස නීතීඥයින් සහ විරුද්ධ පක්ෂ විසින් පුළුල් ලෙස හෙළා දකින ඇඳිරි නීතිය ඊයේ පෙරවරු 8 ට ඉවත් කෙරුණා.",
        "බස් හිඟය හේතුවෙන් විරෝධතාකරුවන් ඊයේ ප්‍රකාශයට පත් කරන ලද “ගොටා යන්න” විරෝධතාව සඳහා කොළඹට පැමිණීමට තමන් සතුව ඇති ඕනෑම වාහනයක් භාවිතා කළහ. මහනුවර සහ ගාල්ල ඇතුළු දුම්රිය ස්ථාන කිහිපයක ජනතාව කොළඹට යාමට උත්සාහ කරන විට දුම්රිය නොමැති බව දැකීමෙන් කෝපයට පත් දර්ශන විය. කෙසේ වෙතත් අවසානයේ විරෝධතාකරුවන් රැගත් දුම්රියක් මහනුවරින් පිටත් වූ අතර මාතර සිට පැමිණි දුම්රියක් ගාල්ලේ සිටි පිරිස් රැගෙන ගියේය.",
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකාව සහ ඕස්ට්‍රේලියාව අතර පැවැත්වෙන ටෙස්ට් තරඟාවලියේදී පොලිස් සහ ආරක්ෂක අංශ සාමාජිකයින් විසින් නරඹන්නන් ඉවත් කර තිබූ ගාලු කොටුවේ බලකොටු ද ගාල්ලේ විරෝධතාකරුවන් විසින් අත්පත් කර ගත්හ.",
        "කොළඹට එන්න බැරි අය රටේ අනිත් පළාත්වල පාරට බැහැලා ලොකු කුඩා විරෝධතා පැවැත්වුණා."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "දහස්",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "නිවස",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "ජනාධිපති ලේකම් කාර්යාලය",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "දහස්",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "නිවස",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජනාධිපති ලේකම් කාර්යාලය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "අවසන් රාත්රිය",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "5 වන පටුමග",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "කොළඹ 3 තර්ස්ටන් පාර",
            "label": "FAC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ඊයේ සවස",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "නිවස",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "බලකොටුව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජනාධිපති ලේකම් කාර්යාලය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "අප්රේල්",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "චැතම් වීදිය",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "නිවස",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "සමගි ජන බලවේගය",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "හර්ෂ ද සිල්වා",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඊයේ",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "රාජිත සේනාරත්න",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "වඩිවෙල් සුරේෂ්",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඊයේ සවස",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "16",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "පොදුජන පෙරමුණ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඊයේ",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඩලස් අලහප්පෙරුම",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජයසුමන",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "නාලක ගොඩහේවා",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "දස දහස් ගණනක්",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "හත",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "බස්නාහිර පළාත",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "පෙ.ව. 8",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඊයේ",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ඊයේ",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මහනුවර",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගාල්ල",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මහනුවර",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "මාතර",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගාල්ල",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ගාල්ල",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගාලු කොටුව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඕස්ට්රේලියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        []
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "ஜனாதிபதி கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ஷ மற்றும் பிரதமர் ரணில் விக்ரமசிங்கவை உடனடியாக பதவி விலகுமாறு கோரி, நேற்று முன்தினம் இரவு, ஜனாதிபதி மாளிகை, ஜனாதிபதி செயலகம் மற்றும் அலரிமாளிகையை ஆக்கிரமித்து ஆயிரக்கணக்கானோர் தொடர்ந்தும் போராட்டத்தில் ஈடுபட்டுள்ளனர்.",
      "author": "நிர்வாகி",
      "body_lines": [
        "ஜனாதிபதி கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ஷ மற்றும் பிரதமர் ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்கவை உடனடியாக பதவி விலகுமாறு கோரி ஆயிரக்கணக்கான மக்கள் ஜனாதிபதி மாளிகை, ஜனாதிபதி செயலகம் மற்றும் அலரிமாளிகையை நேற்றிரவு முற்றுகையிட்டனர்.",
        "ஆர்ப்பாட்டக்காரர்கள் பாராளுமன்றம் மற்றும் கொழும்பு 3 இல் தர்ஸ்டன் வீதியில் 5 வது பாதையில் அமைந்துள்ள பிரதமர் விக்ரமசிங்கவின் தனிப்பட்ட இல்லத்திலும் கூடினர்.",
        "பிரதமரின் தனிப்பட்ட இல்லத்திற்கு அருகில் திரண்டிருந்தவர்களைக் கலைப்பதற்காக பொலிஸார் நேற்று மாலை நீர்த்தாரை மற்றும் கண்ணீர் புகைக் குண்டுகளை வீசினர். ஜனாதிபதி ராஜபக்சவை உடனடியாக பதவி விலகக் கோரி ஆர்ப்பாட்டக்காரர்கள் முதலில் கோட்டையில் உள்ள ஜனாதிபதி மாளிகைக்குள் பல பாதுகாப்பு தடுப்புகளை உடைத்துக்கொண்டு நுழைந்தனர். அவர்கள் பின்னர் ஜனாதிபதி செயலகத்தின் பாதுகாப்பு அளவுகோல்களை மீறினர், அதற்கு வெளியே அவர்கள் ஏப்ரல் முதல் எதிர்ப்பு தெரிவித்தனர்.",
        "சத்தம் தெரு வரை பேரணியாகச் சென்ற போராட்டக்காரர்களை தடுத்து நிறுத்துவதற்கும், ஜனாதிபதி மாளிகையை அடைவதற்கு தடுப்புகளை உடைப்பதற்கும் பொலிஸார் பல தடவைகள் கண்ணீர் புகை குண்டுகளை வீசியும், பல நீர் பீரங்கி வாகனங்களையும் பயன்படுத்தினர். இருப்பினும், காவல்துறை மற்றும் பாதுகாப்புப் படை வீரர்கள், இறுதியில் எதிர்ப்பாளர்களின் எண்ணிக்கையில் இருந்த எண்ணிக்கையின் சுத்த எடையால் மூழ்கிவிட்டனர்.",
        "சமகி ஜன பலவேகயவின் (SJB) பீல்ட் மார்ஷல் சரத் பொன்சேகா மற்றும் ஹர்ஷ டி சில்வா உட்பட எதிர்க்கட்சிகளைச் சேர்ந்த பல பாராளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர்கள் நேற்றைய ஆர்ப்பாட்டத்தில் கலந்துகொண்டனர். எவ்வாறாயினும், SJB பாராளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர்களான ராஜித சேனாரத்ன, ஆர்ப்பாட்டத்தில் ஈடுபட முற்பட்ட போது, ​​எதிர்ப்பாளர்களால் தாக்கப்பட்டு, அங்கிருந்து தப்பிச் செல்ல நேர்ந்தது. இதற்கிடையில், எஸ்ஜேபி எம்பி வடிவேல் சுரேஷும் சில எதிர்ப்பாளர்களால் தாக்கப்பட்டதில் விழுந்ததில் காயமடைந்தார்.",
        "ஜனாதிபதி மாளிகையை உடைக்கும் போது ஜனாதிபதி கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ஷ அங்கு இல்லை என்பதுடன் நேற்று மாலை வரை அவர் இருந்த இடம் தெரியவில்லை.",
        "16 ஸ்ரீலங்கா பொதுஜன பெரமுனா (SLPP) எம்.பி.க்கள் குழு, ஜனாதிபதி ராஜபக்ஷவை உடனடியாக பதவி விலகுமாறும், பாராளுமன்றத்தை பிரதிநிதித்துவப்படுத்தும் முதிர்ச்சியடைந்த தலைவருக்கு பாராளுமன்ற பெரும்பான்மையை வெல்லக்கூடிய மற்றும் ஊழல் குற்றச்சாட்டுகளை எதிர்கொள்வதற்கு வழி வகுக்கும்படி நேற்று ஜனாதிபதிக்கு கடிதம் எழுதியுள்ளது. இந்தக் குழுவில் முன்னாள் அமைச்சர்களான டலஸ் அழகப்பெரும, சன்ன ஜயசுமன மற்றும் நாலக கொடஹேவா ஆகியோர் அடங்குவர்.",
        "முன்னதாக, பல்லாயிரக்கணக்கான போராட்டக்காரர்கள் கடுமையான போக்குவரத்து சிரமங்களைக் கடந்து கொழும்பில் இறங்கினர். ஏற்கனவே நிலவும் எரிபொருள் நெருக்கடியால் பாதிக்கப்பட்டிருந்த பஸ் மற்றும் போக்குவரத்து சேவைகள், மேல் மாகாணத்தின் ஏழு பொலிஸ் பிரிவுகளில் பொலிஸ் ஊரடங்குச் சட்டம் அமுல்படுத்தப்பட்ட பின்னர் ஆரம்பத்தில் மேலும் குறைக்கப்பட்டது. சட்ட விரோதமானது மற்றும் அடிப்படை உரிமை மீறல் என சட்டத்தரணிகள் மற்றும் எதிர்க்கட்சிகளால் பரவலாக கண்டிக்கப்பட்ட ஊரடங்கு சட்டம் நேற்று காலை 8 மணிக்கு தளர்த்தப்பட்டது.",
        "பேருந்துகள் பற்றாக்குறையாக உள்ளதால், நேற்றைய தினம் அறிவிக்கப்பட்ட \"வீட்டுக்கு செல்\" போராட்டத்திற்காக, கொழும்பிற்கு செல்வதற்கு, எதிர்ப்பாளர்கள் தங்கள் வசம் உள்ள எந்த வாகனத்தையும் பயன்படுத்தினர். கண்டி மற்றும் காலி உட்பட பல ரயில் நிலையங்களில் கொழும்பிற்குச் செல்ல முற்பட்ட மக்கள் ரயில்கள் இல்லாததைக் கண்டு கோபமான காட்சிகள் இருந்தன. எவ்வாறாயினும், இறுதியில், கண்டியில் இருந்து ஒரு ரயில் ஆர்ப்பாட்டக்காரர்களை ஏற்றிக்கொண்டு புறப்பட்டது, அதே நேரத்தில் மாத்தறையில் இருந்து ஒரு ரயில் காலியில் உள்ளவர்களை ஏற்றிச் சென்றது.",
        "இலங்கைக்கும் அவுஸ்திரேலியாவுக்கும் இடையில் நடைபெற்று வரும் டெஸ்ட் தொடரின் போது பார்வையாளர்கள் பொலிஸ் மற்றும் பாதுகாப்புப் படையினரால் தடுத்து வைக்கப்பட்டிருந்த காலி கோட்டையின் அரண்களையும் காலியில் ஆர்ப்பாட்டக்காரர்கள் கைப்பற்றினர்.",
        "கொழும்பிற்கு செல்ல முடியாதவர்கள் நாட்டின் ஏனைய பகுதிகளில் வீதிகளில் இறங்கி பெரியவர்களும் சிறியவர்களும் போராட்டங்களை நடத்தினர்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ஆயிரக்கணக்கில்",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "வீடு",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "ஜனாதிபதி செயலகம்",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ச",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ஆயிரக்கணக்கில்",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "வீடு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜனாதிபதி செயலகம்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "நேற்று இரவு",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "5வது லேன்",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "கொழும்பு 3 இல் உள்ள தர்ஸ்டன் வீதி",
            "label": "FAC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "நேற்று மாலை",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "ராஜபக்சே",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "வீடு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "கோட்டை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜனாதிபதி செயலகம்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஏப்ரல்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "சாத்தம் தெரு",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "வீடு",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "சமகி ஜன பலவேகயா’",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஹர்ஷ டி சில்வா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "நேற்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ராஜித சேனாரத்ன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "வடிவேல் சுரேஷ்",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "நேற்று மாலை",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "16",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "பொதுஜன பெரமுன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ராஜபக்சே",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "நேற்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "டலஸ் அழகப்பெரும",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜெயசுமண",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "நாலக கொடஹேவா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பல்லாயிரக்கணக்கானவர்கள்",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஏழு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "மேல் மாகாணம்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "காலை 8 மணி",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "நேற்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "நேற்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "கண்டி",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "காலி",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "கண்டி",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "மாத்தறை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "காலி",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "காலி",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "காலி கோட்டை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆஸ்திரேலியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        []
      ]
    }
  }
}