{
  "newspaper_id": "economy-next-com",
  "url": "https://economynext.com/australia-to-provide-25-mn-usd-in-additional-emergency-aid-to-sri-lanka-98780/",
  "time_ut": 1660888980,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Australia to provide 25 mn USD in additional emergency aid to Sri Lanka",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Australia to provide 25 mn USD in additional emergency aid to Sri Lanka",
      "author": "Neshella Perera",
      "body_lines": [
        "ECONOMYNEXT – Australia said it will provide Sri Lanka 25 million US dollars to help Sri Lanka meet urgent food and healthcare needs as the island nation confronts its worst economic crisis in 74 years.",
        "“During this challenging period, Australia stands with the people of Sri Lanka, especially those experiencing severe hardship,” Australia’s Minister for Foreign Affairs Penny Wong said in a statement on Friday August 19..",
        "On June 20 Australia provided 50 million US dollars in food and medicine aid and this additional support brings Australia’s Official Development Assistance response to 75 million dollars.",
        "The extra humanitarian assistance is in addition to the 23 million dollars in ongoing development assistance to Sri Lanka in 2022-23.",
        "“Our support will be delivered through UN agencies to provide food, health and nutrition services, access to safe water and essential support for those at risk, including women and children,” the statement said.",
        "The World Food Program in July’s Food Security Monitoring report noted that the proportion of households identified as food insecure was 49.4 percent in July compared to 31.5 percent in June 2022.",
        "The UN Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs on August 06 reported that 5.7 million people in Sri Lanka were in need of humanitarian assistance, with 4.9 million being food insecure. (Colombo/Aug19/2022)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Australia",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "25 mn USD",
          "label": "QUANTITY"
        },
        {
          "text": "Sri Lanka",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Australia",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "25 million US dollars",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "74 years",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Australia",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Australia",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Penny Wong",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Friday August 19",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "June 20",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Australia",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "50 million US dollars",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "Australia",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "75 million dollars",
            "label": "MONEY"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the 23 million dollars",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "2022-23",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "UN",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "The World Food Program",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "July",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "49.4 percent",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "July",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "31.5 percent",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "June 2022",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "The UN Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "August 06",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "5.7 million",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "4.9 million",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Colombo/Aug19/2022",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "ඔස්ට්‍රේලියාව ශ්‍රී ලංකාවට අතිරේක හදිසි ආධාර ලෙස ඇමරිකානු ඩොලර් මිලියන 25ක් ලබා දීමට තීරණය කර තිබේ",
      "author": "නෙෂෙල්ලා පෙරේරා",
      "body_lines": [
        "ECONOMYNEXT - වසර 74 ක් තුළ දිවයිනේ දරුණුතම ආර්ථික අර්බුදයට මුහුණ දී සිටින ශ්‍රී ලංකාවට හදිසි ආහාර සහ සෞඛ්‍ය අවශ්‍යතා සපුරාලීම සඳහා ශ්‍රී ලංකාවට ඇමරිකානු ඩොලර් මිලියන 25 ක් ලබා දෙන බව ඕස්ට්‍රේලියාව පැවසීය.",
        "\"මෙම අභියෝගාත්මක කාල පරිච්ෙඡ්දය තුළ, ඕස්ට්‍රේලියාව ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ ජනතාව සමඟ, විශේෂයෙන් දැඩි දුෂ්කරතා අත්විඳින ජනතාව සමඟ සිට,\" ඕස්ට්‍රේලියානු විදේශ කටයුතු අමාත්‍ය Penny Wong සිකුරාදා අගෝස්තු 19 වන දින ප්‍රකාශයක් නිකුත් කරමින් කියා සිටියේය.",
        "ජූනි 20 වැනි දින ඔස්ට්‍රේලියාව විසින් ආහාර සහ ඖෂධ ආධාර වශයෙන් ඇමෙරිකානු ඩොලර් මිලියන 50ක් ලබා දුන් අතර මෙම අතිරේක ආධාරය ඔස්ට්‍රේලියාවේ නිල සංවර්ධන ආධාර ප්‍රතිචාරය ඩොලර් මිලියන 75 දක්වා ගෙන එයි.",
        "අතිරේක මානුෂීය ආධාර වන්නේ 2022-23 දී ශ්‍රී ලංකාවට දැනට පවතින සංවර්ධන ආධාර වශයෙන් ඩොලර් මිලියන 23 ට අමතරව ය.",
        "\"ආහාර, සෞඛ්‍ය සහ පෝෂණ සේවා සැපයීම, ආරක්ෂිත ජලය සඳහා ප්‍රවේශය සහ කාන්තාවන් සහ ළමුන් ඇතුළු අවදානමට ලක්ව සිටින අයට අත්‍යවශ්‍ය ආධාර සැපයීම සඳහා අපගේ සහයෝගය එක්සත් ජාතීන්ගේ නියෝජිතායතන හරහා ලබා දෙනු ඇත\" යනුවෙන් එම ප්‍රකාශය පවසයි.",
        "ජුලි මාසයේ ආහාර සුරක්ෂිතතා අධීක්ෂණ වාර්තාවේ ලෝක ආහාර වැඩසටහන සඳහන් කළේ ආහාර අනාරක්ෂිත ලෙස හඳුනාගෙන ඇති කුටුම්භ අනුපාතය 2022 ජූනි මාසයේ පැවති සියයට 31.5ට සාපේක්ෂව ජූලි මාසයේදී සියයට 49.4ක් බවයි.",
        "එක්සත් ජාතීන්ගේ මානුෂීය කටයුතු සම්බන්ධීකරණ කාර්යාලය අගෝස්තු 06 වැනි දින වාර්තා කළේ ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ මිලියන 5.7 ක ජනතාවකට මානුෂීය ආධාර අවශ්‍ය වන අතර මිලියන 4.9 ක් ආහාර අනාරක්ෂිතව සිටින බවයි. (කොළඹ/අගෝස්තු 19/2022)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ඕස්ට්රේලියාව",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "ඩොලර් මිලියන 25 කි",
          "label": "QUANTITY"
        },
        {
          "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ඕස්ට්රේලියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඩොලර් මිලියන 25 කි",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "අවුරුදු 74 යි",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ඕස්ට්රේලියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඕස්ට්රේලියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "පෙනි වොන්ග්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "අගෝස්තු 19 සිකුරාදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ජූනි 20",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඕස්ට්රේලියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඩොලර් මිලියන 50 කි",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඕස්ට්රේලියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඩොලර් මිලියන 75 කි",
            "label": "MONEY"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ඩොලර් මිලියන 23 කි",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "2022-23",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "එ.ජා",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ලෝක ආහාර වැඩසටහන",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජුලි",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "සියයට 49.4 කි",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජුලි",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "සියයට 31.5 කි",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "2022 ජූනි",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "මානුෂීය කටයුතු සම්බන්ධීකරණය සඳහා එක්සත් ජාතීන්ගේ කාර්යාලය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "අගෝස්තු 06",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මිලියන 5.7 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මිලියන 4.9 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "කොළඹ/අගෝ.19/2022",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "இலங்கைக்கு மேலதிக அவசர உதவியாக 25 மில்லியன் அமெரிக்க டொலர்களை அவுஸ்திரேலியா வழங்கவுள்ளது",
      "author": "நெஷெல்லா பெரேரா",
      "body_lines": [
        "ECONOMYNEXT – 74 வருடங்களில் தீவு நாடு மிக மோசமான பொருளாதார நெருக்கடியை எதிர்கொண்டுள்ள நிலையில், இலங்கையின் அவசர உணவு மற்றும் சுகாதாரத் தேவைகளைப் பூர்த்தி செய்ய இலங்கைக்கு 25 மில்லியன் அமெரிக்க டொலர்களை வழங்குவதாக அவுஸ்திரேலியா தெரிவித்துள்ளது.",
        "\"இந்த சவாலான காலகட்டத்தில், அவுஸ்திரேலியா இலங்கை மக்களுடன், குறிப்பாக கடுமையான கஷ்டங்களை அனுபவிக்கும் மக்களுடன் நிற்கிறது\" என்று ஆஸ்திரேலியாவின் வெளிவிவகார அமைச்சர் பென்னி வோங் வெள்ளிக்கிழமை ஆகஸ்ட் 19 அன்று ஒரு அறிக்கையில் தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "ஜூன் 20 அன்று ஆஸ்திரேலியா 50 மில்லியன் அமெரிக்க டாலர்களை உணவு மற்றும் மருந்து உதவியாக வழங்கியது மேலும் இந்த கூடுதல் ஆதரவு ஆஸ்திரேலியாவின் உத்தியோகபூர்வ மேம்பாட்டு உதவிக்கான பதிலை 75 மில்லியன் டாலர்களாகக் கொண்டுவருகிறது.",
        "2022-23 ஆம் ஆண்டில் இலங்கைக்கு வழங்கப்பட்டு வரும் 23 மில்லியன் டொலர்களுக்கு மேலதிகமாக மனிதாபிமான உதவி வழங்கப்பட்டுள்ளது.",
        "\"உணவு, சுகாதாரம் மற்றும் ஊட்டச்சத்து சேவைகள், பாதுகாப்பான நீர் அணுகல் மற்றும் பெண்கள் மற்றும் குழந்தைகள் உட்பட ஆபத்தில் உள்ளவர்களுக்கு அத்தியாவசிய ஆதரவை வழங்குவதற்கு ஐ.நா. ஏஜென்சிகள் மூலம் எங்கள் ஆதரவு வழங்கப்படும்\" என்று அந்த அறிக்கையில் கூறப்பட்டுள்ளது.",
        "ஜூலை மாத உணவுப் பாதுகாப்பு கண்காணிப்பு அறிக்கையில் உலக உணவுத் திட்டம், ஜூன் 2022 இல் 31.5 சதவீதத்துடன் ஒப்பிடும்போது, ​​ஜூலை மாதத்தில் உணவுப் பாதுகாப்பற்ற குடும்பங்களின் விகிதம் 49.4 சதவீதமாக இருந்தது என்று குறிப்பிட்டுள்ளது.",
        "இலங்கையில் 5.7 மில்லியன் மக்களுக்கு மனிதாபிமான உதவி தேவைப்படுவதாகவும், 4.9 மில்லியன் மக்கள் உணவுப் பாதுகாப்பற்ற நிலையில் இருப்பதாகவும் மனிதாபிமான விவகாரங்களுக்கான ஒருங்கிணைப்புக்கான ஐ.நா அலுவலகம் ஆகஸ்ட் 06 அன்று தெரிவித்தது. (கொழும்பு/ஆகஸ்ட்19/2022)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ஆஸ்திரேலியா",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "25 மில்லியன் அமெரிக்க டாலர்",
          "label": "QUANTITY"
        },
        {
          "text": "இலங்கை",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ஆஸ்திரேலியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "25 மில்லியன் அமெரிக்க டாலர்கள்",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "74 ஆண்டுகள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஆஸ்திரேலியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆஸ்திரேலியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "பென்னி வோங்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆகஸ்ட் 19 வெள்ளிக்கிழமை",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஜூன் 20",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆஸ்திரேலியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "50 மில்லியன் அமெரிக்க டாலர்கள்",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆஸ்திரேலியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "75 மில்லியன் டாலர்கள்",
            "label": "MONEY"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "23 மில்லியன் டாலர்கள்",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "2022-23",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஐ.நா",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "உலக உணவு திட்டம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜூலை",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "49.4 சதவீதம்",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜூலை",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "31.5 சதவீதம்",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜூன் 2022",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "மனிதாபிமான விவகாரங்களின் ஒருங்கிணைப்புக்கான ஐ.நா",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆகஸ்ட் 06",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "5.7 மில்லியன்",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "4.9 மில்லியன்",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "கொழும்பு/ஆகஸ்ட்19/2022",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}