{
  "newspaper_id": "news-first-lk",
  "url": "https://www.newsfirst.lk/2022/07/15/political-stability-is-paramount-cbsl-chief/",
  "time_ut": 1657893300,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Political Stability is paramount – CBSL Chief",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Political Stability is paramount – CBSL Chief",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); The Governor of the Central Bank of Sri Lanka, Dr. Nandalal Weerasinghe says that the progress on getting an international bailout package depends on political stability in the country.",
        "Speaking to the BBC Sinhala Service, Dr. Weerasinghe stated that it is also impossible for Sri Lanka to get out of its current condition without a stable administration.",
        "Therefore, he appealed for the public to work as one for political stability in Sri Lanka.",
        "Pointing out that even now, there is a lack of essentials in the country, Dr. Weerasinghe stated that while some shipments of Petrol and Diesel have been acquired, the industries in the country also need to function for the economy to run smoothly.",
        "“However, without political stability, the people will have to face worse situations than they are facing now,” he added.",
        "FUTA wants Ranil to step down & NOT contest election in Parliament for President"
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "News 1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Central Bank of Sri Lanka",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Nandalal Weerasinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the BBC Sinhala Service",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Weerasinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "one",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Weerasinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "FUTA",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ranil",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "දේශපාලන ස්ථාවරත්වය ඉතා වැදගත් - මහ බැංකු ප්‍රධානියා",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); ජාත්‍යන්තර ඇපදීමේ පැකේජයක් ලබා ගැනීමේ ප්‍රගතිය රඳා පවතින්නේ රටේ දේශපාලන ස්ථාවරත්වය මත බව ශ්‍රී ලංකා මහ බැංකුවේ අධිපති ආචාර්ය නන්දලාල් වීරසිංහ මහතා පවසයි.",
        "බීබීසී සිංහල සේවයට අදහස් දක්වමින් ආචාර්ය වීරසිංහ ප්‍රකාශ කළේ ස්ථාවර පරිපාලනයකින් තොරව ශ්‍රී ලංකාවට ද වත්මන් තත්ත්වයෙන් ගොඩ ඒමට නොහැකි බවයි.",
        "එබැවින් ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ දේශපාලන ස්ථාවරත්වය සඳහා එකාවන්ව කටයුතු කරන ලෙස ඔහු මහජනතාවගෙන් ඉල්ලා සිටියේය.",
        "මේ වන විටත් රට තුළ අත්‍යාවශ්‍ය ද්‍රව්‍ය හිඟයක් පවතින බව පෙන්වා දුන් ආචාර්ය වීරසිංහ ප්‍රකාශ කළේ පෙට්‍රල් සහ ඩීසල් නැව්ගත කිරීම් කිහිපයක් ලබාගෙන ඇති අතර ආර්ථිකය යහපත්ව පවත්වාගෙන යාමට මෙරට කර්මාන්ත ද ක්‍රියාත්මක විය යුතු බවයි.",
        "\"කෙසේ වෙතත්, දේශපාලන ස්ථාවරත්වයක් නොමැති නම්, ජනතාවට දැන් මුහුණදීමට වඩා නරක තත්ත්වයන්ට මුහුණ දීමට සිදුවනු ඇත,\" ඔහු වැඩිදුරටත් පැවසීය.",
        "FUTA ට අවශ්‍ය වී ඇත්තේ රනිල් ඉල්ලා අස්වීම සහ ජනාධිපතිවරණයට පාර්ලිමේන්තුවට ඉදිරිපත් නොවීමයි"
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "News 1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකා මහ බැංකුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "නන්දලාල් වීරසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "බීබීසී සිංහල සේවය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "වීරසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "එක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "වීරසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "FUTA",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "රනිල්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "அரசியல் ஸ்திரத்தன்மை மிக முக்கியமானது - CBSL தலைவர்",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); சர்வதேச பிணை எடுப்புப் பொதியைப் பெறுவதற்கான முன்னேற்றம் நாட்டின் அரசியல் ஸ்திரத்தன்மையில் தங்கியுள்ளது என இலங்கை மத்திய வங்கியின் ஆளுநர் கலாநிதி நந்தலால் வீரசிங்க தெரிவித்துள்ளார்.",
        "பிபிசி சிங்கள சேவையிடம் பேசிய கலாநிதி வீரசிங்க, ஸ்திரமான நிர்வாகம் இல்லாமல் இலங்கையின் தற்போதைய நிலையில் இருந்து மீள்வது சாத்தியமற்றது என்றும் குறிப்பிட்டார்.",
        "எனவே, இலங்கையின் அரசியல் ஸ்திரத்தன்மைக்காக பொதுமக்கள் ஒன்றுபட்டு உழைக்க வேண்டுமென அவர் வேண்டுகோள் விடுத்துள்ளார்.",
        "தற்போதும் நாட்டில் அத்தியாவசியப் பொருட்கள் பற்றாக்குறை நிலவுவதாகச் சுட்டிக்காட்டிய கலாநிதி வீரசிங்க, பெற்றோல் மற்றும் டீசல் சில ஏற்றுமதிகள் கையகப்படுத்தப்பட்டுள்ள அதேவேளை, பொருளாதாரம் சீராக இயங்குவதற்கு நாட்டிலுள்ள கைத்தொழில்களும் செயற்பட வேண்டும் எனவும் குறிப்பிட்டார்.",
        "\"எனினும், அரசியல் ஸ்திரத்தன்மை இல்லாவிட்டால், மக்கள் இப்போது எதிர்நோக்குவதை விட மோசமான சூழ்நிலைகளை எதிர்கொள்ள வேண்டியிருக்கும்\" என்று அவர் மேலும் கூறினார்.",
        "FUTA ரணில் பதவி விலக வேண்டும் மற்றும் ஜனாதிபதி தேர்தலில் பாராளுமன்ற தேர்தலில் போட்டியிட வேண்டாம்"
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "News 1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை மத்திய வங்கி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "நந்தலால் வீரசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பிபிசி சிங்கள சேவை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "வீரசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஒன்று",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "வீரசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "FUTA",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரணில்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}