{
  "newspaper_id": "news-first-lk",
  "url": "https://www.newsfirst.lk/2022/07/21/20000-mt-of-urea-for-tea-cultivations/",
  "time_ut": 1658384580,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "20,000 MT of Urea for Tea Cultivations",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "20,000 MT of Urea for Tea Cultivations",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); The Ministry of Plantation Industries has decided to distribute 20,000 MT of urea fertilizer for tea cultivation.",
        "The fertilizer will be distributed through the Tea Small Holdings Development Authority.",
        "The Chairman of Tea Small Holdings Development Authority Thushara Priyadarshana noted that urea fertilizer will be distributed through small tea estate societies and tea factories.a",
        "The Chairman also said that steps will be taken to provide the relevant fertilizer to farmers for a reasonable price.",
        "Ranil Wickremesinghe sworn in as 8th Executive President of Sri Lanka",
        "‘I am a friend of the people, but forced occupation of offices is illegal’ – President"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "20,000",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "News 1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "The Ministry of Plantation Industries",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "20,000",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the Tea Small Holdings Development Authority",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Tea Small Holdings Development Authority",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Priyadarshana",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "8th",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        []
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "තේ වගාව සඳහා යූරියා මෙ.ටොන් 20,000ක්",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); තේ වගාව සඳහා යූරියා පොහොර මෙට්‍රික් ටොන් 20,000ක් බෙදා හැරීමට වැවිලි කර්මාන්ත අමාත්‍යාංශය තීරණය කර තිබේ.",
        "කුඩා තේ වතු සංවර්ධන අධිකාරිය හරහා පොහොර බෙදා හැරීම සිදු කෙරේ.",
        "කුඩා තේ වතු සංවර්ධන අධිකාරියේ සභාපති තුෂාර ප්‍රියදර්ශන සඳහන් කළේ කුඩා තේ වතු සමිති සහ තේ කර්මාන්ත ශාලා හරහා යූරියා පොහොර බෙදා හැරීමට කටයුතු කරන බවයි.",
        "අදාළ පොහොර සාධාරණ මිලකට ගොවීන්ට ලබාදීමට පියවර ගන්නා බව ද සභාපතිවරයා පැවසීය.",
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ 8 වැනි විධායක ජනාධිපතිවරයා ලෙස රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතා දිවුරුම් දුන්නේය",
        "‘මම ජනතාවගේ මිතුරෙක්, නමුත් බලහත්කාරයෙන් කාර්යාල අත්පත් කර ගැනීම නීති විරෝධීයි’ – ජනපති"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "20,000 කි",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "News 1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "වැවිලි කර්මාන්ත අමාත්‍යාංශය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "20,000 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "කුඩා තේ වතු සංවර්ධන අධිකාරිය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "කුඩා තේ වතු සංවර්ධන අධිකාරිය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ප්‍රියදර්ශන",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "8 වැනි",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        []
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "தேயிலை சாகுபடிக்கு 20,000 மெட்ரிக் டன் யூரியா",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); தேயிலை பயிர்ச்செய்கைக்காக 20,000 மெட்ரிக் டன் யூரியா உரத்தை விநியோகிக்க பெருந்தோட்ட கைத்தொழில் அமைச்சு தீர்மானித்துள்ளது.",
        "சிறு தேயிலை தோட்ட அபிவிருத்தி அதிகார சபையின் ஊடாக இந்த உரம் விநியோகிக்கப்படவுள்ளது.",
        "சிறு தேயிலை தோட்ட சங்கங்கள் மற்றும் தேயிலை தொழிற்சாலைகள் ஊடாக யூரியா உரம் விநியோகிக்கப்படும் என சிறு தேயிலை தோட்ட அபிவிருத்தி அதிகார சபையின் தலைவர் துஷார பிரியதர்சன தெரிவித்துள்ளார்.",
        "உரிய உரத்தை நியாயமான விலையில் விவசாயிகளுக்கு வழங்க நடவடிக்கை எடுக்கப்படும் என்றும் தலைவர் தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "இலங்கையின் 8வது நிறைவேற்று ஜனாதிபதியாக ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க பதவியேற்றார்",
        "‘நான் மக்களின் நண்பன், ஆனால் பலவந்தமாக அலுவலகங்களை ஆக்கிரமிப்பது சட்டவிரோதமானது’ – ஜனாதிபதி"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "20,000",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "News 1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "பெருந்தோட்ட கைத்தொழில் அமைச்சு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "20,000",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "தேயிலை சிறு தோட்டங்கள் அபிவிருத்தி அதிகாரசபை",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "தேயிலை சிறு தோட்டங்கள் அபிவிருத்தி அதிகாரசபை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "பிரியதர்ஷனா",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "8வது",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        []
      ]
    }
  }
}