{
  "newspaper_id": "ada-lk",
  "url": "https://www.ada.lk/breaking_news/ගෝඨා-සිටි-බව-කියන-හෝටලයේ-රාත්‍රියක-වියදම-ඩොලර්-5900---8700ත්-අතර/11-395425",
  "time_ut": 1657785588,
  "original_lang": "si",
  "original_title": "ගෝඨා සිටි බව කියන හෝටලයේ රාත්‍රියක වියදම ඩොලර් 5900 - 8700ත් අතර",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "The cost of a night in the hotel where Gotha is said to be between 5900 - 8700 dollars.",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "Maldives media reports that Sri Lankan President Gotabaya Rajapaksa stayed at the famous Waldorf Astoria Ithaafushi hotel during his stay in Maldives. This hotel chain belongs to a well-known businessman, Mohammad Ali Jana.",
        "He is close to Maldives Foreign Minister Abdullah Shahid. The Maldivian staff of this hotel chain have confirmed that the President is staying at the hotel.",
        "However, the staff expressed displeasure about the President staying there.",
        "The cost of spending a night in this hotel chain is between US$ 5,903 and US$ 8,760. The Government of Maldives has not yet issued a statement in this regard."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Gotha",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "between 5900 - 8700 dollars",
          "label": "DATE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lankan",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Gotabaya Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Waldorf Astoria Ithaafushi",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Maldives",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Mohammad Ali Jana",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Abdullah Shahid",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Maldivian",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "a night",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "between US$ 5,903",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "8,760",
            "label": "MONEY"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "ගෝඨා සිටි බව කියන හෝටලයේ රාත්‍රියක වියදම ඩොලර් 5900 - 8700ත් අතර",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකා ජනාධිපති ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ මහතා මාලදිවයිනේ රැදී සිටි කාලයේදී මාලදිවයිනේ සුප්‍රසිද්ධ Waldorf Astoria Ithaafushi නම් මහා පරිමාණ හෝටලයේ නවාතැන්ගෙන ඇති බව මාලදිවයිනේ මාධ්‍ය වාර්තා කරයි. ප්‍රකට ව්‍යාපාරිකයෙක් වන මොහොමඩ් අලි ජානාට මෙම හෝටල් ජාලය අයත් වෙයි.",
        "ඔහු මාලදිවයිනේ විදේශ අමාත්‍ය අබ්දුල්ලා ෂාහිඩ්ගේ සමීපතමයෙකි. මෙම හෝටල් ජාලයේ මාලදිවයින් කාර්ය මණ්ඩලය ජනපතිවරයා එම හෝටලයේ රැදී සිටින බවට තහවුරු කර තිබේ.",
        "කෙසේ වෙතත් ජනපතිවරයා එහි රැදි සිටීම පිළිබඳ එම කාර්ය මණ්ඩලය අප්‍රසාදය පළ කර ඇත.",
        "මෙම හෝටල් ජාලයෙහි රාත්‍රියක් ගත කිරිම වෙනුවෙන් වැයවන මුදල ඇමෙරිකානු ඩොලර් 5,903 සහ ඇමෙරිකානු ඩොලර් 8,760 අතර මුදලක් වෙයි. මාලදිවයිනේ රජය තවමත් මේ සම්බන්ධයෙන් ප්‍රකාශයක් නිකුත් කර නොමැත."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ගෝතා",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "ඩොලර් 5900 - 8700 අතර",
          "label": "DATE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලාංකික",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Waldorf Astoria Ithaafushi",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "මාලදිවයින",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මොහොමඩ් අලි ජනා",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "අබ්දුල්ලා ෂාහිඩ්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "මාලදිවයින්",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "රාත්රියක්",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "US$ 5,903 අතර",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "8,760 කි",
            "label": "MONEY"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "கோதா ஹோட்டலில் ஒரு இரவு செலவு 5900 - 8700 டாலர்கள்.",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "இலங்கை ஜனாதிபதி கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ச மாலைதீவில் தங்கியிருந்த போது புகழ்பெற்ற Waldorf Astoria Ithaafushi ஹோட்டலில் தங்கியிருந்ததாக மாலைதீவு ஊடகங்கள் தெரிவிக்கின்றன. இந்த ஹோட்டல் சங்கிலி முகமது அலி ஜானா என்ற பிரபல தொழிலதிபருக்கு சொந்தமானது.",
        "இவர் மாலத்தீவு வெளியுறவு அமைச்சர் அப்துல்லா ஷாஹித்துக்கு நெருக்கமானவர். ஜனாதிபதி ஹோட்டலில் தங்கியிருப்பதை இந்த ஹோட்டல் சங்கிலியின் மாலைதீவு ஊழியர்கள் உறுதிப்படுத்தியுள்ளனர்.",
        "எனினும், ஜனாதிபதி அங்கு தங்கியிருப்பது குறித்து ஊழியர்கள் அதிருப்தி தெரிவித்தனர்.",
        "இந்த ஹோட்டல் சங்கிலியில் ஒரு இரவைக் கழிப்பதற்கான செலவு US$ 5,903 மற்றும் US$ 8,760 ஆகும். இது தொடர்பாக மாலத்தீவு அரசு இன்னும் அறிக்கை வெளியிடவில்லை."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "கோதா",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "5900 - 8700 டாலர்களுக்கு இடையில்",
          "label": "DATE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "வால்டோர்ஃப் அஸ்டோரியா இத்தாஃபுஷி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "மாலத்தீவுகள்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "முகமது அலி ஜனா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "அப்துல்லா ஷாஹித்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "மாலத்தீவு",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஒரு இரவு",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "5,903 அமெரிக்க டாலர்களுக்கு இடையே",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "8,760",
            "label": "MONEY"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}