{
  "newspaper_id": "economy-next-com",
  "url": "https://economynext.com/sri-lanka-police-arrest-key-protest-leader-amid-fears-of-august-9-agitation-98104/",
  "time_ut": 1659412020,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Sri Lanka police arrest key protest leader amid fears of August 9 agitation",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Sri Lanka police arrest key protest leader amid fears of August 9 agitation",
      "author": "Neshella Perera",
      "body_lines": [
        "ECONOMYNEXT- A prominent Sri Lankan protester has been arrested by the Colombo Crimes Division after a number of  arrests have been made over illegally entering public properties during the July 9 protest which led former president Gotabaya Rajapaksa to flee the country and amid fears of a similar protest on August 9.",
        "A social activist and Youtuber Rathindu Senaratne commonly known as “Ratta” was arrested on Monday (01) for violating the law and breaching a court order during a protest held on a main road in front of the island nation’s World Trade Center on 21 May, which was held against the government’s mismanagement.",
        "Ratta was arrested while he had voluntarily appeared to produce a statement on behalf of the arrest of another protest leader Pathum Kerner, who was also arrested for breaching police barriers near a parliament junction.",
        "The series of arrests come after protesters have planned another massive protest on August 9 similar to the one that forced former president Rajapaksa to flee the country fearing for his life. The planned protest on August 9 is to force President Ranil Wickremesinghe, who succeed Rajapaksa through a parliament vote, to resign.",
        "Wickremesinghe has been tough of protesters, some activists say and he has repeatedly said nobody can burn houses of people in the name of protest.",
        "Wickremesinghe on July 18 has declared state of emergency which gives wide powers for police to arrest people.",
        "A day after Wickremesinghe took over as the president on July 21, the military attacked and evicted the protesters inside and near the presidential secretariat which was occupied by the agitators from July 9.",
        "The number of protesters near the presidential secretariat also has declined sharply amid series of arrests and some protesters withdrawing from the agitation which has been taking place since April 9. They have been demanding former president Gotabaya Rajapaksa to resign and all Rajapaksa family members to leave from the key governmental positions.",
        "The protesters have said the day 9th of the each month has been a lucky day for them after former Prime Minister Mahinda Rajapaksa was forced to resign on May 9, his brother an former Finance Minister Basil Rajapaksa resigned on June 9 and ex-president Gotabaya Rajapapksa fled the presidential palace on July 9 before fleeing the country and resigning from Singapore via an email.",
        "The July 9 protest saw at least 200,000 people joining the key protesters near the presidential secretariat. They stormed into the presidential palace, presidential secretariat, prime minister’s official residence, and burnt then prime minister Wickremesinghe’s private residence. The police has been now investigating into the incidence.",
        "Government officials have said Wickremesinghe administration has been fearing of August 9 protest.  (Colombo/Aug 02/2022)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Sri Lanka",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "August 9",
          "label": "DATE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lankan",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Colombo Crimes Division",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the July 9",
            "label": "EVENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "Gotabaya Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "August 9",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Youtuber Rathindu Senaratne",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ratta",
            "label": "WORK_OF_ART"
          },
          {
            "text": "Monday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "01",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "World Trade Center",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "21 May",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Pathum Kerner",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "August 9",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "August 9",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "July 18",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "July 21",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "July 9",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "April 9",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Gotabaya Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "day 9th",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the each month",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Mahinda Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "May 9",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Finance",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Basil Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "June 9",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Gotabaya Rajapapksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "July 9",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Singapore",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "July 9",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "at least 200,000",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "August 9",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "අගෝස්තු 9 උද්ඝෝෂණයට ඇති බිය මධ්‍යයේ ශ්‍රී ලංකා පොලිසිය ප්‍රධාන විරෝධතා නායකයා අත්අඩංගුවට ගනී",
      "author": "නෙෂෙල්ලා පෙරේරා",
      "body_lines": [
        "ECONOMYNEXT- හිටපු ජනාධිපති ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ මහතා රටින් පලා යාමට තුඩු දුන් ජූලි 9 වන දින පැවති විරෝධතාවයේදී නීති විරෝධී ලෙස පොදු දේපළවලට ඇතුළුවීම සම්බන්ධයෙන් අත්අඩංගුවට ගැනීම් ගණනාවක් සිදු කිරීමෙන් පසු ප්‍රමුඛ පෙළේ ශ්‍රී ලාංකික විරෝධතාකරුවෙකු කොළඹ අපරාධ කොට්ඨාශය විසින් අත්අඩංගුවට ගෙන ඇත. අගෝස්තු 9 වෙනිදා.",
        "මැයි 21 වන දින දිවයිනේ ලෝක වෙළඳ මධ්‍යස්ථානය ඉදිරිපිට ප්‍රධාන මාර්ගයක පැවති විරෝධතාවකදී නීතිය කඩ කිරීම සහ අධිකරණ නියෝගය කඩ කිරීම සම්බන්ධයෙන් සමාජ ක්‍රියාකාරිකයෙකු සහ යූ ටියුබ්කරුවෙකු වන \"රට්ටා\" ලෙසින් හඳුන්වනු ලබන රතිඳු සේනාරත්න සඳුදා (01) අත්අඩංගුවට ගන්නා ලදී. ආණ්ඩුවේ වැරදි කළමනාකරණයට එරෙහිව පැවැත්වූ",
        "පාර්ලිමේන්තු හන්දියක් අසලදී පොලිස් බාධක බිඳීම සම්බන්ධයෙන් අත්අඩංගුවට ගත් තවත් විරෝධතා නායක පැතුම් කර්නර් අත්අඩංගුවට ගැනීම වෙනුවෙන් ප්‍රකාශයක් ඉදිරිපත් කිරීමට ස්වේච්ඡාවෙන් ඉදිරිපත්ව සිටියදී රට්ටා අත්අඩංගුවට ගෙන ඇත.",
        "මෙම අත්අඩංගුවට ගැනීම් මාලාව සිදුවන්නේ හිටපු ජනාධිපති රාජපක්ෂට ජීවිතයට බියෙන් රටින් පලා යාමට බල කළ විරෝධතාවයට සමාන තවත් දැවැන්ත විරෝධතාවක් අගෝස්තු 9 වනදා විරෝධතාකරුවන් විසින් සැලසුම් කිරීමෙන් පසුවය. අගෝස්තු 9 වැනිදා සැලසුම් කර ඇති විරෝධතාව වන්නේ පාර්ලිමේන්තු ඡන්දයකින් රාජපක්ෂගෙන් පසු බලයට පත්වන ජනාධිපති රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහට ඉල්ලා අස්වන ලෙස බල කිරීමයි.",
        "වික්‍රමසිංහ විරෝධතාකරුවන්ට දැඩි ලෙස ක්‍රියා කර ඇති අතර, ඇතැම් ක්‍රියාකාරීන් පවසන අතර, විරෝධතා නාමයෙන් කිසිවෙකුට මිනිසුන්ගේ ගෙවල් ගිනි තැබිය නොහැකි බව ඔහු පුන පුනා පවසා ඇත.",
        "ජුලි 18 දින වික්‍රමසිංහ විසින් හදිසි නීතිය ප්‍රකාශයට පත් කර ඇති අතර එමඟින් පුද්ගලයන් අත්අඩංගුවට ගැනීමට පොලිසියට පුලුල් බලතල ඇත.",
        "ජූලි 21 වැනිදා වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතා ජනාධිපතිවරයා ලෙස වැඩ භාර ගැනීමෙන් දිනකට පසු, ජූලි 9 වැනිදා සිට උද්ඝෝෂකයින් විසින් අල්ලාගෙන සිටි ජනාධිපති ලේකම් කාර්යාලය තුළ සහ ඒ අසල විරෝධතාකරුවන්ට හමුදාව පහර දී ඉවත් කළේය.",
        "අත්අඩංගුවට ගැනීම් මාලාවක් සහ ඇතැම් විරෝධතාකරුවන් අප්‍රේල් 9 වැනිදා සිට ක්‍රියාත්මක කළ උද්ඝෝෂණ ව්‍යාපාරයෙන් ඉවත්වීම මධ්‍යයේ ජනාධිපති ලේකම් කාර්යාලය අසල විරෝධතාකරුවන් සංඛ්‍යාවද ශීඝ්‍රයෙන් අඩුවී ඇත.ඔවුන් හිටපු ජනාධිපති ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ මහතාට ඉල්ලා අස්වන ලෙසත් රාජපක්ෂ පවුලේ සියලුම දෙනාට ඉන් ඉවත් වන ලෙසත් බලකරයි. ප්රධාන රජයේ තනතුරු.",
        "හිටපු අග්‍රාමාත්‍ය මහින්ද රාජපක්ෂ මහතාට මැයි 9 වැනිදා ඉල්ලා අස්වීමට බලකිරීමත්, ඔහුගේ සොහොයුරෙකු වූ හිටපු මුදල් අමාත්‍ය බැසිල් රාජපක්ෂ මහතා ජුනි 9දාත්, හිටපු ජනාධිපති ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ මහතාත් ඉල්ලා අස්වීමෙන් පසු සෑම මසකම 9 වැනි දිනය තමන්ට වාසනාවන්ත දිනයක් වූ බව විරෝධතාකරුවන් පවසා තිබේ. ජූලි 9 වැනි දින ජනාධිපති මන්දිරයෙන් පලා ගොස් රටින් පලා යාමට පෙර සිංගප්පූරුවෙන් ඊමේල් පණිවුඩයක් මගින් ඉල්ලා අස්විය.",
        "ජුලි 9 විරෝධතාවයේ දී අවම වශයෙන් 200,000 ක ජනතාවක් ජනාධිපති ලේකම් කාර්යාලය අසල ප්‍රධාන විරෝධතාකරුවන් සමඟ එක් වූහ. ඔවුන් ජනාධිපති මන්දිරයට, ජනාධිපති ලේකම් කාර්යාලයට, අගමැති නිල නිවසට කඩා වැදී එවකට අගමැති වික්‍රමසිංහගේ පෞද්ගලික නිවසට ගිනි තැබූහ. සිද්ධිය සම්බන්ධයෙන් මේ වන විට පොලිසිය පරීක්ෂණ ආරම්භ කර තිබේ.",
        "වික්‍රමසිංහ පාලනය අගෝස්තු 9 විරෝධතාවට බියෙන් පසුවන බව රජයේ නිලධාරීන් පවසා ඇත. (කොළඹ/අගෝස්තු 02/2022)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "අගෝස්තු 9",
          "label": "DATE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලාංකික",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "කොළඹ අපරාධ කොට්ඨාශය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජූලි 9",
            "label": "EVENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "අගෝස්තු 9",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Youtuber Rathindu Senaratne",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "රට්ටා",
            "label": "WORK_OF_ART"
          },
          {
            "text": "සඳුදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "01",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ලෝක වෙළඳ මධ්යස්ථානය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "21 මැයි",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "පැතුම් කර්නර්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "අගෝස්තු 9",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "අගෝස්තු 9",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "ජූලි 18",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජූලි 21",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජූලි 9",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "අප්රේල් 9",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "9 වන දිනය",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "සෑම මාසයකම",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මහින්ද රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "මැයි 9",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මූල්ය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "බැසිල් රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජූනි 9",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජූලි 9",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "සිංගප්පූරුව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ජූලි 9",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "අවම වශයෙන් 200,000",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "අගෝස්තු 9",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "ஆகஸ்ட் 9 கிளர்ச்சியின் அச்சத்தின் மத்தியில் இலங்கை காவல்துறை முக்கிய போராட்டத் தலைவரை கைது செய்தது",
      "author": "நெஷெல்லா பெரேரா",
      "body_lines": [
        "பொருளாதாரம்- முன்னாள் ஜனாதிபதி கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ச நாட்டை விட்டு வெளியேற வழிவகுத்த ஜூலை 9 ஆம் தேதி நடந்த ஆர்ப்பாட்டத்தின் போது பொது சொத்துக்களுக்கு சட்டவிரோதமாக நுழைந்ததற்காக பல கைதுகள் செய்யப்பட்ட பின்னர், இலங்கையின் முக்கிய எதிர்ப்பாளர் ஒருவர் கொழும்பு குற்றப்பிரிவினால் கைது செய்யப்பட்டுள்ளார். ஆகஸ்ட் 9 அன்று.",
        "மே 21 ஆம் திகதி தீவு நாட்டின் உலக வர்த்தக நிலையத்திற்கு முன்பாக பிரதான வீதியொன்றில் இடம்பெற்ற ஆர்ப்பாட்டத்தின் போது சட்டத்தை மீறி நீதிமன்ற உத்தரவை மீறிய குற்றத்திற்காக சமூக செயற்பாட்டாளரும் யூடியூபருமான ரதிந்து சேனாரத்ன திங்கட்கிழமை (01) கைது செய்யப்பட்டார். அரசின் தவறான நிர்வாகத்திற்கு எதிராக நடத்தப்பட்டது.",
        "மற்றொரு போராட்டத் தலைவரான பாத்தும் கெர்னரின் கைது சார்பாக அறிக்கை ஒன்றைத் தயாரிக்க அவர் தானாக முன்வந்து ஆஜராகியிருந்த வேளையில், ரட்டா கைது செய்யப்பட்டார், மேலும் அவர் நாடாளுமன்றச் சந்திப்புக்கு அருகில் பொலிஸ் தடைகளை மீறியதற்காக கைது செய்யப்பட்டார்.",
        "முன்னாள் ஜனாதிபதி ராஜபக்ச உயிருக்கு பயந்து நாட்டை விட்டு வெளியேற நிர்ப்பந்தித்ததைப் போன்றே ஆகஸ்ட் 9 ஆம் தேதி மற்றொரு மாபெரும் போராட்டத்தை எதிர்ப்பாளர்கள் திட்டமிட்டதைத் தொடர்ந்து இந்த தொடர் கைதுகள் வந்துள்ளன. ஆகஸ்ட் 9-ம் தேதி திட்டமிடப்பட்ட போராட்டம், நாடாளுமன்ற வாக்கெடுப்பு மூலம் ராஜபக்சேவுக்குப் பிறகு ஜனாதிபதி ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்கவை ராஜினாமா செய்ய கட்டாயப்படுத்துவதாகும்.",
        "விக்கிரமசிங்க எதிர்ப்பாளர்களிடம் கடுமையாக நடந்துகொண்டார், சில ஆர்வலர்கள் கூறுகிறார்கள் மற்றும் அவர் மீண்டும் மீண்டும் கூறியது மக்கள் வீடுகளை யாரும் எதிர்ப்பு என்ற பெயரில் எரிக்க முடியாது.",
        "ஜூலை 18 அன்று விக்கிரமசிங்க அவசரகால நிலையைப் பிரகடனப்படுத்தினார், இது மக்களைக் கைது செய்ய காவல்துறைக்கு பரந்த அதிகாரங்களை வழங்குகிறது.",
        "ஜூலை 21 அன்று விக்கிரமசிங்க ஜனாதிபதியாக பதவியேற்ற ஒரு நாளுக்குப் பிறகு, ஜூலை 9 முதல் போராட்டக்காரர்களால் ஆக்கிரமிக்கப்பட்ட ஜனாதிபதி செயலகத்திற்கு உள்ளேயும் அருகாமையிலும் போராட்டக்காரர்களை இராணுவம் தாக்கி வெளியேற்றியது.",
        "கடந்த ஏப்ரல் 9ஆம் தேதி முதல் நடைபெற்று வரும் போராட்டங்களில் இருந்து சில போராட்டக்காரர்கள் பின்வாங்கி, கைது நடவடிக்கைகளுக்கு மத்தியில் ஜனாதிபதி செயலகத்திற்கு அருகில் ஆர்ப்பாட்டக்காரர்களின் எண்ணிக்கையும் வெகுவாகக் குறைந்துள்ளது. முக்கிய அரசாங்க பதவிகள்.",
        "முன்னாள் பிரதமர் மகிந்த ராஜபக்ச மே 9ஆம் திகதி இராஜினாமா செய்ய நிர்ப்பந்திக்கப்பட்டதையடுத்து, அவரது சகோதரரும், முன்னாள் நிதியமைச்சருமான பசில் ராஜபக்ச ஜூன் 9ஆம் திகதி பதவி விலகியதுடன், முன்னாள் ஜனாதிபதி கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ஷவும், ஒவ்வொரு மாதமும் 9ஆம் திகதி தமக்கு அதிர்ஷ்டமான நாளாக இருந்ததாக ஆர்ப்பாட்டக்காரர்கள் தெரிவித்துள்ளனர். ஜூலை 9 அன்று ஜனாதிபதி மாளிகையை விட்டு வெளியேறி நாட்டை விட்டு வெளியேறி சிங்கப்பூரில் இருந்து மின்னஞ்சல் மூலம் ராஜினாமா செய்தார்.",
        "ஜூலை 9 ஆர்ப்பாட்டத்தில் குறைந்தது 200,000 பேர் ஜனாதிபதி செயலகத்திற்கு அருகில் முக்கிய எதிர்ப்பாளர்களுடன் இணைந்தனர். அவர்கள் ஜனாதிபதி மாளிகை, ஜனாதிபதி செயலகம், பிரதமரின் உத்தியோகபூர்வ இல்லம், பிரதமர் விக்ரமசிங்கவின் தனிப்பட்ட இல்லம் என்பனவற்றிற்குள் நுழைந்து தீவைத்தனர். இந்த சம்பவம் குறித்து போலீசார் தற்போது விசாரணை நடத்தி வருகின்றனர்.",
        "ஆகஸ்ட் 9ம் தேதி நடக்கும் போராட்டத்திற்கு விக்கிரமசிங்க நிர்வாகம் அஞ்சுவதாக அரசு அதிகாரிகள் தெரிவித்துள்ளனர். (கொழும்பு/ஆகஸ்ட் 02/2022)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "இலங்கை",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "ஆகஸ்ட் 9",
          "label": "DATE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "கொழும்பு குற்றப்பிரிவு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜூலை 9",
            "label": "EVENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆகஸ்ட் 9",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "யூடியூபர் ரதிந்து சேனாரத்ன",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரட்டா",
            "label": "WORK_OF_ART"
          },
          {
            "text": "திங்கட்கிழமை",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "01",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "உலக வர்த்தக மையம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "21 மே",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பாத்தும் கெர்னர்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஆகஸ்ட் 9",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ராஜபக்சே",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆகஸ்ட் 9",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ராஜபக்சே",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஜூலை 18",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜூலை 21",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜூலை 9",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஏப்ரல் 9",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ராஜபக்சே",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "நாள் 9",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஒவ்வொரு மாதமும்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "மஹிந்த ராஜபக்ஷ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "மே 9",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "நிதி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "பசில் ராஜபக்ஷ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜூன் 9",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜூலை 9",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சிங்கப்பூர்",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஜூலை 9",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "குறைந்தது 200,000",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆகஸ்ட் 9",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}