{
  "newspaper_id": "d-b-s-jeyaraj-com",
  "url": "https://dbsjeyaraj.com/dbsj/archives/79123",
  "time_ut": 1661282100,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Police  Storm Into Press Conference Held at CSR in Maradana to Protest  Against Detention of Three IUSF  Activists Stating  they Want to Arrest Eranga Gunasekara the  National Organiser of the Socialist Youth Union without possessing a  Valid Arrest Warrant",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Police  Storm Into Press Conference Held at CSR in Maradana to Protest  Against Detention of Three IUSF  Activists Stating  they Want to Arrest Eranga Gunasekara the  National Organiser of the Socialist Youth Union without possessing a  Valid Arrest Warrant",
      "author": "Administrator",
      "body_lines": [
        "The Police raided a press conference called by the Inter University Student Federation at the CSR in Maradana  yesterday (23).",
        "The press conference was called to mark the united opposition of political parties, trade unions, public organisations and social activists against the detention of the three student leaders, Wasantha Mudalige, Galwewa Siridhamma Thera and Hashan Jeevantha, using the Prevention of Terrorism Act.",
        "When Ceylon Today inquired about the situation from the Educational Secretary of Frontline Socialist Party (FSP), Pubudu Jagoda, he said the Police forcefully stormed the place saying that they wanted to arrest Eranga Gunasekara, National Organiser of the Socialist Youth Union. However, the Police officers did not have any valid documents related to the arrest, he said.",
        "He said the Police had to retreat due to strong opposition from the representatives who came to the press conference.",
        "“By breaking into press conferences like this, it is sure they are trying to create fear and terror in society. From that point of view, we can see that the terrorists are Ranil Rajapaksa and the gang that hides behind him. Not the people fighting for their lives, for their fair rights,” he said."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "CSR",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "Maradana",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "Three",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "National Organiser of the Socialist Youth Union",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "Valid Arrest Warrant",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "the Inter University Student Federation",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "CSR",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Maradana",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "yesterday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "23",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the united opposition of political",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "three",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Wasantha Mudalige",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Galwewa Siridhamma Thera",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Hashan Jeevantha",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Prevention of Terrorism Act",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Frontline Socialist Party",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Pubudu Jagoda",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Eranga Gunasekara",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "National Organiser of the Socialist Youth Union",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "Ranil Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "වලංගු අත්අඩංගුවට ගැනීමේ වරෙන්තුවක් නොමැතිව සමාජවාදී තරුණ සංගමයේ ජාතික සංවිධායක එරංග ගුණසේකර අත්අඩංගුවට ගැනීමට අවශ්‍ය බව පවසමින් අන්තර් විශ්වවිද්‍යාල ශිෂ්‍ය බල මණ්ඩලයේ ක්‍රියාකාරීන් තිදෙනෙකු රඳවා තබා ගැනීමට එරෙහිව විරෝධතාවයක් සඳහා මරදාන CSR හිදී මාධ්‍ය හමුවක් පැවැත්විණි.",
      "author": "පරිපාලක",
      "body_lines": [
        "අන්තර් විශ්වවිද්‍යාල ශිෂ්‍ය බලමණ්ඩලය විසින් ඊයේ (23) මරදාන සමාජ සත්කාරක මධ්‍යස්ථානයේදී කැඳවා තිබූ මාධ්‍ය හමුවක් පොලිසිය විසින් වටලා තිබේ.",
        "වසන්ත මුදලිගේ, ගල්වැව සිරිධම්ම හිමි සහ හෂාන් ජීවන්ත යන ශිෂ්‍ය නායකයින් තිදෙනා ත්‍රස්තවාදය වැලැක්වීමේ පනත යොදා ගනිමින් රඳවා තබා ගැනීමට එරෙහිව දේශපාලන පක්ෂ, වෘත්තීය සමිති, පොදු සංවිධාන සහ සමාජ ක්‍රියාකාරීන්ගේ ඒකාබද්ධ විරෝධය සනිටුහන් කරමින් මෙම මාධ්‍ය හමුව කැඳවා තිබුණි.",
        "මෙම තත්ත්වය පිළිබඳව Ceylon Today පෙරටුගාමී සමාජවාදී පක්ෂයේ (පෙසප) අධ්‍යාපන ලේකම් පුබුදු ජාගොඩගෙන් කළ විමසීමකදී ඔහු කියා සිටියේ සමාජවාදී තරුණ සංගමයේ ජාතික සංවිධායක එරංග ගුණසේකර අත්අඩංගුවට ගැනීමට අවශ්‍ය බව පවසමින් පොලිසිය බලහත්කාරයෙන් එම ස්ථානයට කඩා වැදුණු බවයි. කෙසේ වෙතත්, මෙම අත්අඩංගුවට ගැනීම සම්බන්ධයෙන් වලංගු ලියකියවිලි කිසිවක් පොලිස් නිලධාරීන් සතුව නොතිබූ බවද ඔහු පැවසීය.",
        "මාධ්‍ය හමුවට පැමිණි නියෝජිතයන්ගෙන් එල්ල වූ දැඩි විරෝධය හේතුවෙන් පොලිසියට පසුබැසීමට සිදුවූ බව ඔහු පැවසීය.",
        "“මෙවැනි මාධ්‍ය සාකච්ඡාවලට කඩා වැදීමෙන් ඔවුන් සමාජය තුළ භීතිය හා භීෂණය ඇති කිරීමට උත්සාහ කරන බව නිසැකය. එහෙම බැලුවම අපිට පේනවා ත්‍රස්තවාදීන් රනිල් රාජපක්ෂ සහ ඔහු පිටුපස සැඟවී සිටින කල්ලිය බව. තම ජීවිතය වෙනුවෙන්, ඔවුන්ගේ සාධාරණ අයිතීන් වෙනුවෙන් සටන් කරන මිනිසුන් නොවේ,” ඔහු පැවසීය."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "CSR",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "මරදාන",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "තුන්",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "සමාජවාදී තරුණ සංගමයේ ජාතික සංවිධායක",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "වලංගු අත්අඩංගුවට ගැනීමේ වරෙන්තුව",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "අන්තර් විශ්වවිද්‍යාල ශිෂ්‍ය බල මණ්ඩලය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "CSR",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "මරදාන",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඊයේ",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "23",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "දේශපාලනයේ ඒකාබද්ධ විපක්ෂය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "තුන්",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "වසන්ත මුදලිගේ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගල්වැව සිරිධම්ම හිමි",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "හෂාන් ජීවන්ත",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ත්‍රස්තවාදය වැළැක්වීමේ පනත",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "පෙරටුගාමී සමාජවාදී පක්ෂය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "පුබුදු ජාගොඩ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Eranga Gunasekara",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "සමාජවාදී තරුණ සංගමයේ ජාතික සංවිධායක",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "රනිල් රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "சோசலிச வாலிபர் சங்கத்தின் தேசிய அமைப்பாளர் எரங்க குணசேகரவை செல்லுபடியான கைது உத்தரவு இல்லாமல் கைது செய்ய விரும்புவதாக தெரிவித்து மூன்று IUSF செயற்பாட்டாளர்கள் கைது செய்யப்பட்டதற்கு எதிர்ப்பு தெரிவிக்கும் வகையில் மருதானை CSR இல் ஊடகவியலாளர் மாநாட்டில் பொலிசார் தாக்குதல் நடத்தினர்.",
      "author": "நிர்வாகி",
      "body_lines": [
        "நேற்று (23) மருதானையில் உள்ள CSR இல் பல்கலைக்கழகங்களுக்கு இடையிலான மாணவர் சம்மேளனம் ஏற்பாடு செய்திருந்த ஊடகவியலாளர் மாநாட்டை பொலிஸார் சோதனையிட்டனர்.",
        "வசந்த முதலிகே, கல்வெவ சிறிதம்ம தேரர் மற்றும் ஹஷான் ஜீவந்த ஆகிய மூன்று மாணவர் தலைவர்கள் பயங்கரவாதத் தடைச் சட்டத்தின் மூலம் தடுத்து வைக்கப்பட்டுள்ளமைக்கு எதிராக அரசியல் கட்சிகள், தொழிற்சங்கங்கள், பொது அமைப்புகள் மற்றும் சமூக ஆர்வலர்கள் ஒன்றிணைந்த எதிர்ப்பைக் குறிக்கும் வகையில் இந்த ஊடகவியலாளர் சந்திப்பு ஏற்பாடு செய்யப்பட்டிருந்தது.",
        "முன்னிலை சோசலிசக் கட்சியின் (FSP) கல்விச் செயலாளர் புபுது ஜாகொடவிடம் சிலோன் டுடே நிலைமை குறித்து வினவியபோது, ​​சோசலிச வாலிபர் சங்கத்தின் தேசிய அமைப்பாளர் எரங்க குணசேகரவை கைது செய்ய வேண்டும் எனக் கூறி பொலிஸார் பலவந்தமாக தாக்கியதாக தெரிவித்தார். எவ்வாறாயினும், கைது செய்யப்பட்டமை தொடர்பான சரியான ஆவணங்கள் எதுவும் பொலிஸ் அதிகாரிகளிடம் இல்லை என்றும் அவர் கூறினார்.",
        "ஊடகவியலாளர் மாநாட்டிற்கு வந்த பிரதிநிதிகளின் கடும் எதிர்ப்பு காரணமாக பொலிஸார் பின்வாங்க நேரிட்டதாக அவர் தெரிவித்துள்ளார்.",
        "“இதுபோன்ற செய்தியாளர் சந்திப்புகளை உடைப்பதன் மூலம், அவர்கள் சமூகத்தில் அச்சத்தையும் பயங்கரவாதத்தையும் உருவாக்க முயற்சிக்கிறார்கள் என்பது உறுதி. அந்த வகையில் பார்த்தால், பயங்கரவாதிகள் ரணில் ராஜபக்சவும் அவருக்குப் பின்னால் ஒளிந்திருக்கும் கும்பலும்தான் என்பதை அறியலாம். தங்கள் உயிருக்காக போராடும் மக்கள் அல்ல, அவர்களின் நியாயமான உரிமைகளுக்காக, ”என்று அவர் கூறினார்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "CSR",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "மருதானை",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "மூன்று",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "சோசலிச வாலிபர் சங்கத்தின் தேசிய அமைப்பாளர்",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "செல்லுபடியாகும் கைது வாரண்ட்",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "பல்கலைக்கழகங்களுக்கு இடையிலான மாணவர் கூட்டமைப்பு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "CSR",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "மருதானை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "நேற்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "23",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஒன்றிணைந்த அரசியல் எதிர்க்கட்சி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "மூன்று",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "வசந்த முதலிகே",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "கல்வெவ சிறிதம்ம தேரர்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஹஷன் ஜீவந்த",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "பயங்கரவாதத் தடைச் சட்டம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "முன்னணி சோசலிஸ்ட் கட்சி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "புபுது ஜாகொட",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Eranga Gunasekara",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "சோசலிச வாலிபர் சங்கத்தின் தேசிய அமைப்பாளர்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "ரணில் ராஜபக்ச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}