{
  "newspaper_id": "ada-derana-lk",
  "url": "http://www.adaderana.lk/news/84682/two-accused-in-jeyaraj-fernandopulle-assassination-acquitted",
  "time_ut": 1662015840,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Two accused in Jeyaraj Fernandopulle assassination acquitted",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Two accused in Jeyaraj Fernandopulle assassination acquitted",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "Two accused, who were in remand custody in connection with the assassination of former minister Jeyaraj Fernandopulle and 15 others, were acquitted and released today.",
        "The verdict was delivered when the lawsuit was called before Gampaha Magistrate Sahan Mapa this morning (Sep 01).",
        "Accordingly, former Superintendent of Police (SP) of Gampaha, Lakshman Cooray and ex-LTTE cadre Selvaraja Kirubakaran were ordered to be acquitted and released in the murder case.",
        "Cooray and Kirubakaran were indicted under 31 charges including conspiring of the suicide bomb attack on April 06, 2008 in which 16 individuals including former Minister Fernandopulle were killed and dozens of others were injured at a Kanthi Staidum in Weliweriya area.",
        "Fernandopulle was serving as the Minister of Highways and Road Development and the Chief Government Whip at the time of his demise."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Two",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "Jeyaraj Fernandopulle",
          "label": "FAC"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Two",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Jeyaraj Fernandopulle",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "15",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Gampaha Magistrate",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sahan Mapa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "this morning",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sep 01",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Superintendent of Police",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Gampaha",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Lakshman Cooray",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Selvaraja Kirubakaran",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Kirubakaran",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "31",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "April 06, 2008",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "16",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Fernandopulle",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "dozens",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "a Kanthi Staidum",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Weliweriya",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        []
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "ජෙයරාජ් ප්‍රනාන්දුපුල්ලේ ඝාතනයේ විත්තිකරුවන් දෙදෙනෙකු නිදොස් කොට නිදහස් කෙරේ",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "හිටපු අමාත්‍ය ජෙයරාජ් ප්‍රනාන්දුපුල්ලේ මහතා ඇතුළු 15 දෙනෙකු ඝාතනය සම්බන්ධයෙන් රක්ෂිත බන්ධනාගාරගතව සිටි විත්තිකරුවන් දෙදෙනෙකු අද නිදොස් කොට නිදහස් කෙරුණා.",
        "මෙම නඩුව අද (සැප් 01) පෙරවරුවේ ගම්පහ මහේස්ත්‍රාත් සහන් මාපා හමුවේ කැඳවූ අවස්ථාවේදී මෙම තීන්දුව ප්‍රකාශයට පත් කරන ලදී.",
        "ඒ අනුව මෙම ඝාතන නඩුවෙන් ගම්පහ හිටපු පොලිස් අධිකාරී ලක්ෂ්මන් කුරේ සහ හිටපු එල්.ටී.ටී.ඊ සාමාජික සෙල්වරාජා කිරුබාකරන් නිදොස් කොට නිදහස් කිරීමට නියෝග කෙරුණා.",
        "2008 අප්‍රේල් 06 වැනිදා වැලිවේරිය ප්‍රදේශයේ කාන්ති ක්‍රීඩාංගනයකදී හිටපු අමාත්‍ය ප්‍රනාන්දුපුල්ලේ ඇතුළු 16 දෙනෙකු ඝාතනය කර තවත් දුසිම් ගනනකට තුවාල සිදුකල මරාගෙන මැරෙන බෝම්බ ප්‍රහාරයට කුමන්ත්‍රණය කිරීම ඇතුළු චෝදනා 31ක් යටතේ කුරේට සහ කිරුබාකරන්ට අධිචෝදනා ගොනුකර තිබුණි.",
        "ප්‍රනාන්දුපුල්ලේ මහතා අභාවප්‍රාප්ත වන විට මහාමාර්ග හා මාර්ග සංවර්ධන අමාත්‍යවරයා සහ ආණ්ඩු පක්ෂයේ ප්‍රධාන සංවිධායකවරයා ලෙස කටයුතු කරමින් සිටියේය."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "දෙක",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "ජෙයරාජ් ප්‍රනාන්දුපුල්ලේ",
          "label": "FAC"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "දෙක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජෙයරාජ් ප්‍රනාන්දුපුල්ලේ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "15",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ගම්පහ මහේස්ත්‍රාත්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "සහන් මාපා",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "මේ උදෑසන",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "සැප් 01",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "පොලිස් අධිකාරී",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගම්පහ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ලක්ෂ්මන් කුරේ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "සෙල්වරාජා කිරුබාකරන්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Kirubakaran",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "31",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "2008 අප්‍රේල් 06",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "16",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ප්‍රනාන්දුපුල්ලේ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "දුසිම්",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "කාන්ති ක්‍රීඩාංගනයකි",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "වැලිවේරිය",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        []
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "ஜெயராஜ் பெர்னாண்டோபுள்ளே படுகொலை வழக்கில் குற்றம் சாட்டப்பட்ட இருவர் விடுதலை செய்யப்பட்டுள்ளனர்",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "முன்னாள் அமைச்சர் ஜெயராஜ் பெர்னாண்டோபுள்ளே மற்றும் 15 பேர் படுகொலை செய்யப்பட்ட சம்பவம் தொடர்பில் விளக்கமறியலில் வைக்கப்பட்டிருந்த இரண்டு சந்தேகநபர்கள் இன்று விடுவிக்கப்பட்டு விடுதலை செய்யப்பட்டுள்ளனர்.",
        "குறித்த வழக்கு இன்று (செப். 01) கம்பஹா நீதவான் சஹான் மாபா முன்னிலையில் விசாரணைக்கு எடுத்துக் கொள்ளப்பட்ட போதே இந்த தீர்ப்பு வழங்கப்பட்டுள்ளது.",
        "இதன்படி, கொலை வழக்கில் கம்பஹா முன்னாள் பொலிஸ் அத்தியட்சகர் லக்ஷ்மன் குரே மற்றும் முன்னாள் புலி உறுப்பினர் செல்வராஜா கிருபாகரன் ஆகியோரை விடுதலை செய்து விடுதலை செய்ய உத்தரவிடப்பட்டுள்ளது.",
        "2008 ஆம் ஆண்டு ஏப்ரல் 06 ஆம் திகதி வெலிவேரிய பிரதேசத்தில் உள்ள காந்தி மைதானத்தில் முன்னாள் அமைச்சர் பெர்னாண்டோபுள்ளே உட்பட 16 பேர் கொல்லப்பட்டதுடன் டஜன் கணக்கானவர்கள் காயமடைந்து தற்கொலை குண்டுத் தாக்குதலுக்கு சதி செய்தமை உட்பட 31 குற்றச்சாட்டுகளின் கீழ் குரே மற்றும் கிருபாகரன் ஆகியோர் மீது குற்றஞ்சாட்டப்பட்டது.",
        "பெர்னாண்டோபுள்ளே இறக்கும் போது நெடுஞ்சாலைகள் மற்றும் வீதி அபிவிருத்தி அமைச்சராகவும் அரசாங்கத்தின் பிரதம கொறடாவாகவும் கடமையாற்றியிருந்தார்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "இரண்டு",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "ஜெயராஜ் பெர்னாண்டோபுள்ளே",
          "label": "FAC"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "இரண்டு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜெயராஜ் பெர்னாண்டோபுள்ளே",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "15",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "கம்பஹா நீதவான்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "சஹான் மாபா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று காலை",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "செப் 01",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "காவல் கண்காணிப்பாளர்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "கம்பஹா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "லக்ஷ்மன் குரே",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "செல்வராஜா கிருபாகரன்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Kirubakaran",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "31",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஏப்ரல் 06, 2008",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "16",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "பெர்னாண்டோபுள்ளே",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "டஜன் கணக்கான",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஒரு காந்தி ஸ்டேடியம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "வெலிவேரிய",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        []
      ]
    }
  }
}