{
  "newspaper_id": "news-first-lk",
  "url": "https://www.newsfirst.lk/2022/07/05/pms-plan-on-debt-also-impossible-harsha/",
  "time_ut": 1657012500,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "PM’s plan on debt also impossible: Harsha",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "PM’s plan on debt also impossible: Harsha",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); Opposition Parliamentarian Dr. Harsha de Silva says that it is not possible to restructure the country’s debts by August, despite the Prime Minister’s assurances.",
        "The Samagi Jana Balawegaya MP, citing the Prime Minister’s speech with regard to the IMF debt restructuring, stated that although Prime Minister himself said that if the plan presented by NPP Leader Anura Kumara Dissanayake to revitalize the country’s economy within six months’ time is impractical, the plan presented by the Prime Minister himself is one which might end up in the Book of Guinness World Records if achieved.",
        "“There are only three weeks left in August. I am not confident that this loan can be restructured in three weeks,” he added."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Opposition Parliamentarian Dr.",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Harsha de Silva",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "August",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Jana Balawegaya MP",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "IMF",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "NPP",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Anura Kumara Dissanayake",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "six months",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Book of Guinness World Records",
            "label": "WORK_OF_ART"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "only three weeks",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "August",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "three weeks",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "ණය ගැන අගමැතිගේ සැලැස්මත් බෑ: හර්ෂ",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); අග්‍රාමාත්‍යවරයාගේ සහතිකය තිබියදීත් අගෝස්තු මාසය වන විට රටේ ණය ප්‍රතිව්‍යුහගත කිරීමට නොහැකි බව විපක්ෂ පාර්ලිමේන්තු මන්ත්‍රී ආචාර්ය හර්ෂ ද සිල්වා මහතා පවසයි.",
        "ජාත්‍යන්තර මූල්‍ය අරමුදලේ ණය ප්‍රතිව්‍යුහගත කිරීම සම්බන්ධයෙන් අග්‍රාමාත්‍යවරයා කළ කතාව උපුටා දක්වමින් සමගි ජන බලවේගයේ මන්ත්‍රීවරයා කියා සිටියේ මාස හයක් ඇතුළත රටේ ආර්ථිකය නඟා සිටුවීමට එජාප නායක අනුර කුමාර දිසානායක මහතා ඉදිරිපත් කළ සැලැස්ම ප්‍රායෝගික නොවන බව අග්‍රාමාත්‍යවරයාම පැවසුවද, අග්‍රාමාත්‍යවරයා විසින්ම ඉදිරිපත් කරන ලද මෙම සැලැස්ම සාර්ථක වුවහොත් ගිනස් ලෝක වාර්තා පොතට ඇතුළත් විය හැකි එකකි.",
        "“අගෝස්තු මාසයට ඉතිරිව ඇත්තේ සති තුනක් පමණි. මෙම ණය මුදල සති තුනකින් ප්‍රතිව්‍යුහගත කළ හැකි බවට මට විශ්වාසයක් නැහැ,” ඔහු වැඩිදුරටත් පැවසීය."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "විපක්ෂ පාර්ලිමේන්තු මන්ත්‍රී ආචාර්ය.",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "හර්ෂ ද සිල්වා",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "අගෝස්තු",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ජන බලවේගය පා.ම",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "IMF",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "එන්පීපී",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "අනුර කුමාර දිසානායක",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "මාස හයක්",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගිනස් ලෝක වාර්තා පොත",
            "label": "WORK_OF_ART"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "සති තුනක් පමණි",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "අගෝස්තු",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "සති තුනක්",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "பிரதமரின் கடன் திட்டமும் சாத்தியமற்றது: ஹர்ஷா",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); பிரதமர் உறுதியளித்த போதிலும் ஆகஸ்ட் மாதத்திற்குள் நாட்டின் கடன்களை மறுசீரமைக்க முடியாது என எதிர்க்கட்சி நாடாளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர் கலாநிதி ஹர்ஷ டி சில்வா தெரிவித்துள்ளார்.",
        "சர்வதேச நாணய நிதியத்தின் கடன் மறுசீரமைப்பு தொடர்பில் பிரதமரின் உரையை மேற்கோள்காட்டி சமகி ஜன பலவேகய பாராளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர், ஆறு மாத காலத்திற்குள் நாட்டின் பொருளாதாரத்தை புத்துயிர் பெற NPP தலைவர் அனுரகுமார திஸாநாயக்க முன்வைத்த திட்டம் நடைமுறைக்கு சாத்தியமற்றது என பிரதமரே கூறியிருந்தாலும், பிரதமரே முன்வைத்த திட்டம் கின்னஸ் உலக சாதனை புத்தகத்தில் இடம்பிடிக்கும் ஒன்றாகும்.",
        "“ஆகஸ்ட் மாதத்தில் இன்னும் மூன்று வாரங்கள் மட்டுமே உள்ளன. இந்தக் கடனை மூன்று வாரங்களில் மறுசீரமைக்க முடியும் என்பதில் எனக்கு நம்பிக்கை இல்லை,” என்று அவர் மேலும் கூறினார்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "எதிர்க்கட்சி நாடாளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர் டாக்டர்.",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஹர்ஷ டி சில்வா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆகஸ்ட்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஜன பலவேகய எம்.பி",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "IMF",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "NPP",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "அனுரகுமார திஸாநாயக்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆறு மாதங்கள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "கின்னஸ் உலக சாதனை புத்தகம்",
            "label": "WORK_OF_ART"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "மூன்று வாரங்கள் மட்டுமே",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆகஸ்ட்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "மூன்று வாரங்கள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}