{
  "newspaper_id": "daily-mirror-lk",
  "url": "https://www.dailymirror.lk/top_story/Travel-advisories-against-SL-galore-as-uncertainty-mounts/155-240498",
  "time_ut": 1657142432,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Travel advisories against SL galore as uncertainty mounts",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Travel advisories against SL galore as uncertainty mounts",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "UK, New Zealand issue fresh warnings to their citizens against visiting SL",
        "Worsening of economic crisis and potential for civil unrest cited as reasons",
        "USA, EU, Canada, Australia and Ireland continue to maintain their travel advisories issued months ago",
        "Likely to have a massive impact on already struggling tourism sector in country",
        "SLTDA chief says steps will be taken to “soften” impact of such warnings where possible",
        "The travel advisories against visiting Sri Lanka, which were slightly relaxed just weeks ago, are now back and they could further hurt the already struggling tourism sector.",
        "As the situation in the country is showing no signs of improving and with public agitation against the government led by President Gotabaya Rajapaksa and Prime Minister Ranil Wickremesinghe getting intensified, governments across the world are cautioning their citizens against visiting Sri Lanka.",
        "The United Kingdom and New Zealand issued fresh warnings to their citizens this week, advising them against any non-essential travel to Sri Lanka.",
        "The two governments updated their respective travel advisories by citing the worsening economic crisis and the potential for civil unrest. In mid-June, Tourism Minister Harin Fernando was in the United Kingdom, where he met with the UK travel and tourism industry personnel to increase tourist traffic from that country.  Fernando also held discussions with New Zealand High Commissioner in Colombo Michael Appleton last week, where the duo discussed how the two countries can work together to develop tourism and other areas.",
        "Other nations that continue to maintain travel advisories against Sri Lanka include the United States of America, Europe Union, Canada, Australia and Ireland.",
        "Commenting on the travel advisories, Sri Lanka Tourism Development Authority (SLTDA) Chairman Priantha Fernando said it is the responsibility of the respective governments to inform their citizens of ground conditions abroad.",
        "“What is being touched upon are the inconveniences tourists might have to undergo in #SriLanka due to the current conditions,” tweeted Fernando yesterday.",
        "The SLTDA chief said the required steps would be taken to “soften” the impact of such warnings where possible.",
        "“We are continuously working on providing a hassle-free experience to tourists who visit #SriLanka,” he added in his tweet.",
        "Tourist arrivals to Sri Lanka for the month of June totalled 32,856, recording a marginal increase when compared with the previous month, largely influenced by the Australia tour of Sri Lanka, which commenced in early June.",
        "For the first half of 2022, a total of 411,337 tourists had visited Sri Lanka against the 17,000 tourists in the COVID-hit first half of 2021."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "SL",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "UK",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "New Zealand",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "SL",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "USA",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "EU",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Canada",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Australia",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ireland",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "months ago",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "SLTDA",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "just weeks ago",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Gotabaya Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "The United Kingdom and New Zealand",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "this week",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "two",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "mid-June",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Harin Fernando",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the United Kingdom",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "UK",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "New Zealand",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Michael Appleton",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "last week",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "two",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the United States of America",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Europe Union",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Canada",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Australia",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ireland",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka Tourism Development Authority",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Priantha Fernando",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "SriLanka",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Fernando",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "yesterday",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "SLTDA",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "SriLanka",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the month of June",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "32,856",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "the previous month",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Australia",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "early June",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the first half of 2022",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "411,337",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "17,000",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "first half of 2021",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "අවිනිශ්චිතතාවය වැඩි වන විට ශ්‍රී ලංකාවට එරෙහිව සංචාරක උපදේශන",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "එක්සත් රාජධානිය, නවසීලන්තය ශ්‍රී ලංකාවට පැමිණීමට එරෙහිව ඔවුන්ගේ පුරවැසියන්ට නැවුම් අනතුරු ඇඟවීම් නිකුත් කරයි",
        "ආර්ථික අර්බුද උග්‍රවීම සහ සිවිල් නොසන්සුන්තාවයන් සඳහා ඇති හැකියාව හේතු ලෙස දක්වා ඇත",
        "ඇමරිකා එක්සත් ජනපදය, යුරෝපා සංගමය, කැනඩාව, ඕස්ට්‍රේලියාව සහ අයර්ලන්තය මාස කිහිපයකට පෙර නිකුත් කළ සංචාරක උපදේශන දිගටම පවත්වාගෙන යයි",
        "රටේ දැනටමත් අරගල කරන සංචාරක ක්ෂේත්‍රයට විශාල බලපෑමක් ඇති කිරීමට ඉඩ ඇත",
        "SLTDA ප්‍රධානියා පවසන්නේ හැකි සෑම විටම එවැනි අනතුරු ඇඟවීම් වල බලපෑම \"මෘදු\" කිරීමට පියවර ගන්නා බවයි",
        "සති කිහිපයකට පෙර ශ්‍රී ලංකාවට පැමිණීමට එරෙහිව තරමක් ලිහිල් වූ සංචාරක උපදේශන දැන් නැවත පැමිණ ඇති අතර ඒවා දැනටමත් අරගල කරමින් සිටින සංචාරක ක්ෂේත්‍රයට තවත් හානියක් විය හැකිය.",
        "රටේ තත්ත්වය යහපත් අතට හැරෙන ලකුණු නොපෙනීමත්, ජනාධිපති ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ සහ අගමැති රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ ප්‍රමුඛ රජයට එරෙහිව මහජන උද්ඝෝෂණ උත්සන්න වීමත් සමඟ ලොව පුරා රජයන් ශ්‍රී ලංකාවට පැමිණීමෙන් වළකිමින් සිය පුරවැසියන්ට අවවාද කරමින් සිටියි.",
        "එක්සත් රාජධානිය සහ නවසීලන්තය ශ්‍රී ලංකාවට අත්‍යවශ්‍ය නොවන ඕනෑම සංචාරයකට එරෙහිව උපදෙස් දෙමින් මේ සතියේ සිය පුරවැසියන්ට නව අනතුරු ඇඟවීම් නිකුත් කළේය.",
        "නරක අතට හැරෙන ආර්ථික අර්බුදය සහ සිවිල් නොසන්සුන්තාවයේ විභවයන් උපුටා දක්වමින් ආන්ඩු දෙක ඔවුන්ගේ සංචාරක උපදේශන යාවත්කාලීන කළේය. ජූනි මස මැද භාගයේදී සංචාරක අමාත්‍ය හරීන් ප්‍රනාන්දු එක්සත් රාජධානියේ සිටි අතර එහිදී ඔහු එරට සංචාරක සහ සංචාරක ක්ෂේත්‍රයේ නිලධාරීන් හමුවී එරටින් සංචාරක ප්‍රවාහය වැඩි කිරීමට කටයුතු කළේය. ප්‍රනාන්දු මහතා පසුගිය සතියේ කොළඹ නවසීලන්ත මහ කොමසාරිස් මයිකල් ඇපල්ටන් මහතා සමඟ ද සාකච්ඡා පැවැත්වූ අතර එහිදී දෙරට එක්ව සංචාරක හා අනෙකුත් ක්ෂේත්‍ර දියුණු කිරීමට කටයුතු කරන්නේ කෙසේදැයි සාකච්ඡා කළහ.",
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවට එරෙහිව සංචාරක උපදේශන දිගටම පවත්වාගෙන යන අනෙකුත් ජාතීන් අතර ඇමරිකා එක්සත් ජනපදය, යුරෝපා සංගමය, කැනඩාව, ඕස්ට්‍රේලියාව සහ අයර්ලන්තය ඇතුළත් වේ.",
        "සංචාරක උපදේශන පිළිබඳව අදහස් දක්වමින් ශ්‍රී ලංකා සංචාරක සංවර්ධන අධිකාරියේ (SLTDA) සභාපති ප්‍රියන්ත ප්‍රනාන්දු මහතා පැවසුවේ විදේශයන්හි සිටින ඔවුන්ගේ පුරවැසියන් ඔවුන්ගේ පුරවැසියන් දැනුවත් කිරීම අදාළ රජයන්ගේ වගකීමක් බවයි.",
        "ප්‍රනාන්දු ඊයේ ට්විටර් පණිවුඩයක් නිකුත් කරමින් කියා සිටියේ, “ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ වත්මන් තත්ත්වය හේතුවෙන් සංචාරකයින්ට සිදු විය හැකි අපහසුතාවයන් පිළිබඳවයි.",
        "SLTDA ප්‍රධානියා පැවසුවේ හැකි සෑම විටම එවැනි අනතුරු ඇඟවීම්වල බලපෑම \"මෘදු\" කිරීමට අවශ්‍ය පියවර ගන්නා බවයි.",
        "“#SriLanka වෙත පැමිණෙන සංචාරකයින්ට කරදරයකින් තොර අත්දැකීමක් ලබාදීමට අපි අඛණ්ඩව කටයුතු කරමින් සිටිමු,” ඔහු සිය ට්විටර් පණිවුඩයේ වැඩිදුරටත් සඳහන් කර ඇත.",
        "ජුනි මාසය සඳහා ශ්‍රී ලංකාවට පැමිණි සංචාරකයින් සංඛ්‍යාව 32,856 ක් වූ අතර, එය පෙර මාසය හා සැසඳීමේ දී ආන්තික වර්ධනයක් වාර්තා කළ අතර, ජුනි මස මුලදී ආරම්භ වූ ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ ඕස්ට්‍රේලියානු සංචාරය බොහෝ දුරට බලපෑවේය.",
        "2022 පළමු භාගය සඳහා, 2021 පළමු භාගයේ COVID- බලපෑමට ලක් වූ සංචාරකයින් 17,000 ට සාපේක්ෂව සංචාරකයින් 411,337 ක් ශ්‍රී ලංකාවට පැමිණ තිබේ."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "එස්.එල්",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "එක්සත් රාජධානිය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "නවසීලන්තය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "එස්.එල්",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "ඇඑජ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "EU",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "කැනඩාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඕස්ට්රේලියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "අයර්ලන්තය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මාසයකට කලින්",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "SLTDA",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "සති කිහිපයකට පෙර",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "එක්සත් රාජධානිය සහ නවසීලන්තය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මෙම සතිය",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "දෙක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජුනි මැද",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "හරීන් ප්‍රනාන්දු",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "එක්සත් රාජධානිය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "එක්සත් රාජධානිය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "නවසීලන්තය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මයිකල් ඇපල්ටන්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගිය සතිය",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "දෙක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඇමරිකා එක්සත් ජනපදය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "යුරෝපා සංගමය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "කැනඩාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඕස්ට්රේලියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "අයර්ලන්තය",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකා සංචාරක සංවර්ධන අධිකාරිය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ප්‍රියන්ත ප්‍රනාන්දු",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ප්‍රනාන්දු",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඊයේ",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "SLTDA",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජුනි මාසය",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "32,856 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "පෙර මාසය",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඕස්ට්රේලියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජූනි මස මුල",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "2022 පළමු භාගය",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "411,337 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "17,000 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "2021 පළමු භාගය",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "நிச்சயமற்ற தன்மை அதிகரித்து வருவதால் SL க்கு எதிரான பயண ஆலோசனைகள்",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "இங்கிலாந்து, நியூசிலாந்து ஆகிய நாடுகள் இலங்கைக்கு வருகை தருவதற்கு எதிராக தங்கள் குடிமக்களுக்கு புதிய எச்சரிக்கைகளை வழங்குகின்றன",
        "பொருளாதார நெருக்கடி மோசமடைதல் மற்றும் உள்நாட்டு அமைதியின்மைக்கான சாத்தியக்கூறுகள் காரணங்களாகக் குறிப்பிடப்படுகின்றன",
        "அமெரிக்கா, ஐரோப்பிய ஒன்றியம், கனடா, ஆஸ்திரேலியா மற்றும் அயர்லாந்து ஆகியவை மாதங்களுக்கு முன்பு வெளியிடப்பட்ட பயண ஆலோசனைகளைத் தொடர்ந்து பராமரிக்கின்றன",
        "நாட்டில் ஏற்கனவே போராடி வரும் சுற்றுலாத் துறையில் பாரிய தாக்கத்தை ஏற்படுத்தும்",
        "SLTDA தலைவர் கூறுகையில், இதுபோன்ற எச்சரிக்கைகளின் தாக்கத்தை \"மென்மையாக்க\" நடவடிக்கை எடுக்கப்படும்",
        "சில வாரங்களுக்கு முன்னர் சற்று தளர்வாக இருந்த இலங்கைக்கு விஜயம் செய்வதற்கு எதிரான பயண ஆலோசனைகள் தற்போது மீண்டும் வந்துள்ளன, மேலும் அவை ஏற்கனவே போராடி வரும் சுற்றுலாத் துறையை மேலும் பாதிக்கலாம்.",
        "ஜனாதிபதி கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ஷ மற்றும் பிரதமர் ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க தலைமையிலான அரசாங்கத்திற்கு எதிராக மக்கள் கிளர்ச்சிகள் தீவிரமடைந்து வருவதால், நாட்டின் நிலைமையில் முன்னேற்றம் ஏற்படுவதற்கான அறிகுறிகள் தென்படவில்லை, உலகெங்கிலும் உள்ள அரசாங்கங்கள் தங்கள் குடிமக்களை இலங்கைக்கு விஜயம் செய்ய வேண்டாம் என்று எச்சரித்து வருகின்றன.",
        "ஐக்கிய இராச்சியம் மற்றும் நியூசிலாந்து ஆகிய நாடுகள் இந்த வாரம் தங்கள் குடிமக்களுக்கு புதிய எச்சரிக்கைகளை விடுத்துள்ளன, இலங்கைக்கு எந்தவொரு அத்தியாவசியமற்ற பயணத்திற்கும் எதிராக அவர்களுக்கு அறிவுறுத்துகின்றன.",
        "மோசமான பொருளாதார நெருக்கடி மற்றும் உள்நாட்டு அமைதியின்மைக்கான சாத்தியக்கூறுகளை மேற்கோள் காட்டி இரு அரசாங்கங்களும் தத்தமது பயண ஆலோசனைகளை புதுப்பித்தன. ஜூன் நடுப்பகுதியில், சுற்றுலா அமைச்சர் ஹரின் பெர்னாண்டோ ஐக்கிய இராச்சியத்தில் இருந்தார், அங்கு அவர் அந்த நாட்டிலிருந்து சுற்றுலாப் பயணிகளின் வருகையை அதிகரிக்க இங்கிலாந்து பயண மற்றும் சுற்றுலாத் துறை அதிகாரிகளைச் சந்தித்தார். பெர்னாண்டோ கடந்த வாரம் கொழும்பில் உள்ள நியூசிலாந்து உயர்ஸ்தானிகர் மைக்கேல் அப்பிள்டனுடன் கலந்துரையாடினார், அங்கு இருவரும் சுற்றுலா மற்றும் பிற பகுதிகளை மேம்படுத்துவதற்கு இரு நாடுகளும் எவ்வாறு இணைந்து செயல்படுவது என்பது குறித்து இருவரும் விவாதித்தனர்.",
        "அமெரிக்கா, ஐரோப்பிய ஒன்றியம், கனடா, அவுஸ்திரேலியா மற்றும் அயர்லாந்து ஆகிய நாடுகள் இலங்கைக்கு எதிரான பயண ஆலோசனைகளை தொடர்ந்து பேணுகின்ற ஏனைய நாடுகள்.",
        "பயண ஆலோசனைகள் குறித்து கருத்து தெரிவித்த இலங்கை சுற்றுலா அபிவிருத்தி அதிகார சபையின் (SLTDA) தலைவர் பிரியந்த பெர்னாண்டோ, வெளிநாட்டில் நிலத்தடி நிலைமைகள் குறித்து பிரஜைகளுக்கு தெரியப்படுத்துவது அந்தந்த அரசாங்கங்களின் பொறுப்பாகும்.",
        "\"தற்போதைய நிலைமைகள் காரணமாக #இலங்கையில் சுற்றுலாப் பயணிகள் அனுபவிக்க வேண்டிய அசௌகரியங்கள் என்னவென்பதைத் தொடுவது\" என்று பெர்னாண்டோ நேற்று ட்வீட் செய்தார்.",
        "அத்தகைய எச்சரிக்கைகளின் தாக்கத்தை \"மென்மையாக்க\" தேவையான நடவடிக்கைகள் எடுக்கப்படும் என்று SLTDA தலைவர் கூறினார்.",
        "\"#SriLanka விற்கு வருகை தரும் சுற்றுலாப் பயணிகளுக்கு இடையூறு இல்லாத அனுபவத்தை வழங்குவதில் நாங்கள் தொடர்ந்து பணியாற்றி வருகிறோம்,\" என்று அவர் தனது ட்வீட்டில் மேலும் கூறினார்.",
        "ஜூன் மாதத்தில் இலங்கைக்கான சுற்றுலாப் பயணிகளின் வருகை மொத்தம் 32,856 ஆக இருந்தது, இது முந்தைய மாதத்துடன் ஒப்பிடும் போது ஒரு சிறிய அதிகரிப்பை பதிவு செய்துள்ளது, இது ஜூன் மாத தொடக்கத்தில் தொடங்கிய இலங்கைக்கான ஆஸ்திரேலியா சுற்றுப்பயணத்தால் பெரிதும் பாதிக்கப்பட்டது.",
        "2022 இன் முதல் பாதியில், மொத்தம் 411,337 சுற்றுலாப் பயணிகள் 2021 இன் கோவிட்-பாதிக்கப்பட்ட முதல் பாதியில் 17,000 சுற்றுலாப் பயணிகளுக்கு எதிராக இலங்கைக்கு வருகை தந்துள்ளனர்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "எஸ்.எல்",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "யுகே",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "நியூசிலாந்து",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "எஸ்.எல்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "அமெரிக்கா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "EU",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "கனடா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆஸ்திரேலியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "அயர்லாந்து",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "மாதங்களுக்கு முன்பு",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "SLTDA",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "வாரங்களுக்கு முன்பு",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "யுனைடெட் கிங்டம் மற்றும் நியூசிலாந்து",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்த வாரம்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இரண்டு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜூன் நடுப்பகுதி",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஹரின் பெர்னாண்டோ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஐக்கிய இராச்சியம்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "யுகே",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "நியூசிலாந்து",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "மைக்கேல் ஆப்பிள்டன்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "கடந்த வாரம்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இரண்டு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஐக்கிய அமெரிக்கா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஐரோப்பிய ஒன்றியம்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "கனடா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆஸ்திரேலியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "அயர்லாந்து",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை சுற்றுலா அபிவிருத்தி அதிகாரசபை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "பிரியந்த பெர்னாண்டோ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "பெர்னாண்டோ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "நேற்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "SLTDA",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜூன் மாதம்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "32,856",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "முந்தைய மாதம்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆஸ்திரேலியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜூன் தொடக்கத்தில்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "2022 முதல் பாதி",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "411,337",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "17,000",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "2021 இன் முதல் பாதி",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}