{
  "newspaper_id": "news-first-lk",
  "url": "https://www.newsfirst.lk/2022/07/26/sri-lankas-fuel-bill-increased-by-usd-4-bn-bandula/",
  "time_ut": 1658819040,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Sri Lanka’s Fuel Bill increased by USD 4 Bn – Bandula",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Sri Lanka’s Fuel Bill increased by USD 4 Bn – Bandula",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); Cabinet Spokesperson Dr. Bandula Gunawardena said that the Cabinet of Ministers was informed that there would be no shortage of gas in the country from the 1st of August 2022.",
        "Dr. Gunawardena said a serious issue has arisen with regard to fuel as the it is the highest expenditure for the state at present.",
        "He said that USD 6.7 Billion was estimated for fuel purchases for 2022, however, the cost of importing fuel has increased by USD 4 Billion, adding that such an increase is one that cannot be easily undertaken by a small economy like Sri Lanka.",
        "He said in order to address the issue, the government allowed the Energy Minister to introduce the QR Code System to issue fuel based on a quota system.",
        "The Cabinet Spokesperson said that Four Million vehicles have registered for this program, and on Monday (25) at 245 Filling Stations across the country Diesel and Petrol was issued for 70,123 vehicles solely based on the QR system.",
        "He urged the general public to exercise patience when purchasing fuel, given the issue at hand."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Sri Lanka’s",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "News 1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Spokesperson",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Bandula Gunawardena",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Cabinet of Ministers",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the 1st of August 2022",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Gunawardena",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "2022",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Energy",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "The Cabinet Spokesperson",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Four Million",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Monday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "25",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "245",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Filling Stations",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "70,123",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        []
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ ඉන්ධන බිල ඇමෙරිකානු ඩොලර් බිලියන 4කින් වැඩි විය - බන්දුල",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); 2022 අගෝස්තු 01 වැනිදා සිට රට තුළ ගෑස් හිඟයක් ඇති නොවන බවට අමාත්‍ය මණ්ඩලයට දැනුම් දුන් බව කැබිනට් ප්‍රකාශක ආචාර්ය බන්දුල ගුණවර්ධන මහතා පැවසීය.",
        "මේ වන විට රාජ්‍යයට වැඩිම වියදමක් දැරීමට සිදුවන බැවින් ඉන්ධන සම්බන්ධයෙන් බරපතළ ගැටලුවක් මතුව ඇතැයි වෛද්‍ය ගුණවර්ධන මහතා පැවසීය.",
        "2022 වසර සඳහා ඉන්ධන මිලදී ගැනීම් සඳහා ඇමෙරිකානු ඩොලර් බිලියන 6.7ක් ඇස්තමේන්තු කර ඇති නමුත්, ඉන්ධන ආනයනය කිරීමේ වියදම ඇමෙරිකානු ඩොලර් බිලියන 4කින් ඉහළ ගොස් ඇති බවත්, එවැනි වැඩිවීමක් ශ්‍රී ලංකාව වැනි කුඩා ආර්ථිකයකට ලෙහෙසියෙන් සිදු කළ නොහැකි එකක් බවත් ඔහු සඳහන් කළේය.",
        "මෙම ගැටළුව විසඳීම සඳහා කෝටා ක්‍රමයක් මත ඉන්ධන නිකුත් කිරීම සඳහා QR කේත පද්ධතිය හඳුන්වා දීමට රජය බලශක්ති අමාත්‍යවරයාට අවසර දුන් බව ඔහු පැවසීය.",
        "මෙම වැඩසටහන සඳහා වාහන මිලියන හතරක් ලියාපදිංචි වී ඇති අතර සඳුදා (25) දිවයින පුරා පිහිටි පිරවුම්හල් 245කදී QR පද්ධතිය මත පදනම්ව වාහන 70,123ක් සඳහා ඩීසල් සහ පෙට්‍රල් නිකුත් කළ බව කැබිනට් ප්‍රකාශකවරයා පැවසීය.",
        "පවතින ගැටලුව හමුවේ ඉන්ධන මිලදී ගැනීමේදී ඉවසීමෙන් කටයුතු කරන ලෙස ඔහු සාමාන්‍ය ජනතාවගෙන් ඉල්ලා සිටියේය."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "News 1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ප්‍රකාශක",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "බන්දුල ගුණවර්ධන",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "අමාත්ය මණ්ඩලය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "2022 අගෝස්තු 1 වෙනිදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ගුණවර්ධන ය",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "2022",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශක්තිය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "කැබිනට් ප්‍රකාශක",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "මිලියන හතරක්",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "සඳුදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "25",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "245",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "පිරවුම්හල්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "70,123 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        []
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "இலங்கையின் எரிபொருள் கட்டணம் 4 பில்லியன் அமெரிக்க டொலர்களால் அதிகரித்துள்ளது – பந்துல",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); 2022 ஓகஸ்ட் முதலாம் திகதி முதல் நாட்டில் எரிவாயு தட்டுப்பாடு ஏற்படாது என அமைச்சரவைக்கு அறிவிக்கப்பட்டுள்ளதாக அமைச்சரவை பேச்சாளர் கலாநிதி பந்துல குணவர்தன தெரிவித்துள்ளார்.",
        "தற்சமயம் அரசிற்கு அதிகளவு செலவீனமாக உள்ளதால் எரிபொருள் தொடர்பில் பாரிய பிரச்சினை எழுந்துள்ளதாக கலாநிதி குணவர்தன தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "2022 ஆம் ஆண்டிற்கான எரிபொருள் கொள்வனவுகளுக்காக 6.7 பில்லியன் அமெரிக்க டொலர்கள் மதிப்பிடப்பட்டுள்ளதாகவும், எனினும், எரிபொருள் இறக்குமதிக்கான செலவு 4 பில்லியன் அமெரிக்க டொலர்களால் அதிகரித்துள்ளதாகவும், இவ்வாறான அதிகரிப்பு இலங்கை போன்ற சிறிய பொருளாதாரத்தினால் இலகுவில் மேற்கொள்ள முடியாத ஒன்றாகும் எனவும் அவர் தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "இப்பிரச்னைக்கு தீர்வு காணும் வகையில், கோட்டா முறையின் அடிப்படையில் எரிபொருளை வழங்குவதற்கு QR குறியீடு முறையை அறிமுகப்படுத்த எரிசக்தி அமைச்சருக்கு அரசாங்கம் அனுமதி அளித்துள்ளது என்றார்.",
        "நான்கு மில்லியன் வாகனங்கள் இத்திட்டத்திற்காக பதிவு செய்துள்ளதாகவும், திங்கட்கிழமை (25) நாடு முழுவதிலும் உள்ள 245 எரிபொருள் நிரப்பு நிலையங்களில் 70,123 வாகனங்களுக்கு டீசல் மற்றும் பெற்றோல் QR அமைப்பின் அடிப்படையில் மட்டுமே வழங்கப்பட்டதாக அமைச்சரவை பேச்சாளர் தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "எரிபொருளை கொள்வனவு செய்யும் போது பொதுமக்கள் பொறுமையாக செயற்படுமாறு அவர் வேண்டுகோள் விடுத்துள்ளார்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "இலங்கையின்",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "News 1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "செய்தி தொடர்பாளர்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "பந்துல குணவர்தன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "மந்திரிசபை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆகஸ்ட் 1, 2022",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "குணவர்தன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "2022",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஆற்றல்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "அமைச்சரவை செய்தி தொடர்பாளர்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "நான்கு மில்லியன்",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "திங்கட்கிழமை",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "25",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "245",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "நிரப்பு நிலையங்கள்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "70,123",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        []
      ]
    }
  }
}