{
  "newspaper_id": "news-first-lk",
  "url": "https://www.newsfirst.lk/2022/07/16/parliament-meets-after-presidents-resignation/",
  "time_ut": 1657946520,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Parliament meets after President’s resignation",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Parliament meets after President’s resignation",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); Parliament is scheduled to convene today (16) at 10.00 AM to officially announce the President’s resignation.",
        "Vacancy in the office of President to be announced to Parliament today (16).",
        "As previously decided, nominations will be called on the 19th, and the President will be elected on the 20th – Speaker informs at the party leaders’ meeting held today.",
        "According to the Constitution and Section 4 of the Election of the President (Special Provisions) Act No. 2 of 1981, the Parliament is scheduled to meet today (16) Saturday at 10.00 am, the Secretary General of the Parliament Mr. Dhammika Dasanayake informs all Members of Parliament.",
        "According to Section 4 of the Presidential Elections (Special Provisions) Act No. 2 of 1981, the Parliament should be convened within three days after the vacancy occurs.",
        "Thus, the Secretary-General is scheduled to announce today (16) that there is a vacancy in the office of the President according to Section 5 of the said Act.",
        "Meanwhile, at the Party Leaders and the Committee on Parliamentary Business meeting held today at 10.00 am, the Speaker Hon. Mahinda Yapa Abeywardena informed that the new President will be elected by the Parliament on the 20th as previously decided by the party leaders.",
        "Accordingly, the speaker said that the nominations will be called on the 19th Tuesday and subsequently, a member of parliament will be elected for the presidency after the election held in the Parliament on the 20th Wednesday.",
        "The speaker further said that he expects the support of all parties to carry out this process quickly without any hindrance within the democratic framework.",
        "SLPP must support candidate fielded by the party: G.L. Peiris"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Parliament",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "News 1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "16",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "10.00 AM",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "16",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the 19th",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the 20th",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Constitution",
            "label": "LAW"
          },
          {
            "text": "2",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "1981",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "16) Saturday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "10.00",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Dhammika Dasanayake",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Section 4 of",
            "label": "LAW"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Presidential Elections (Special Provisions",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "2",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "1981",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "three days",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "16",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Section 5",
            "label": "LAW"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the Committee on Parliamentary Business",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "10.00",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Yapa Abeywardena",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Parliament on the 20th",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the 19th Tuesday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the 20th",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Wednesday",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "G.L. Peiris",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "ජනාධිපතිවරයා ඉල්ලා අස්වීමෙන් පසු පාර්ලිමේන්තුව රැස්වේ",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); ජනාධිපතිවරයාගේ ඉල්ලා අස්වීම නිල වශයෙන් ප්‍රකාශයට පත් කිරීම සඳහා පාර්ලිමේන්තුව අද (16) පෙරවරු 10.00 ට රැස්වීමට නියමිතය.",
        "ජනාධිපති ධූරයේ පුරප්පාඩුව අද (16) පාර්ලිමේන්තුවට ප්‍රකාශයට පත් කිරීමට නියමිතයි.",
        "කලින් තීරණය කළ පරිදි 19 වැනිදා නාමයෝජනා කැඳවා 20 වැනිදා ජනාධිපතිවරයා තෝරා පත් කර ගන්නා බව කථානායක අද පැවැති පක්ෂ නායක රැස්වීමේදී දැනුම් දෙයි.",
        "ආණ්ඩුක්‍රම ව්‍යවස්ථාව සහ 1981 අංක 2 දරන ජනාධිපතිවරණ (විශේෂ විධිවිධාන) පනතේ 4 වැනි වගන්තියට අනුව පාර්ලිමේන්තුව අද (16) සෙනසුරාදා පෙරවරු 10.00 ට රැස්වීමට නියමිත බව පාර්ලිමේන්තු මහලේකම් ධම්මික දසනායක මහතා දැනුම් දෙයි. සියලුම පාර්ලිමේන්තු මන්ත්‍රීවරුන්.",
        "1981 අංක 2 දරන ජනාධිපතිවරණ (විශේෂ විධිවිධාන) පනතේ 4 වැනි වගන්තියට අනුව පුරප්පාඩුව ඇති වී දින තුනක් ඇතුළත පාර්ලිමේන්තුව කැඳවිය යුතුය.",
        "මේ අනුව, එම පනතේ 5 වැනි වගන්තිය අනුව ජනාධිපති කාර්යාලයේ පුරප්පාඩුවක් පවතින බව මහලේකම්වරයා විසින් අද (16) නිවේදනය කිරීමට නියමිතය.",
        "මේ අතර, අද පෙරවරු 10.00ට පැවති පක්ෂ නායකයින් සහ පාර්ලිමේන්තු කටයුතු පිළිබඳ කාරක සභා රැස්වීමේදී කථානායක ගරු. පක්ෂ නායකයන් විසින් කලින් තීරණය කළ පරිදි නව ජනාධිපතිවරයා ලබන 20 වැනිදා පාර්ලිමේන්තුවේදී තෝරා පත් කර ගන්නා බව මහින්ද යාපා අබේවර්ධන මහතා දැනුම් දුන්නේය.",
        "ඒ අනුව 19 වැනි අඟහරුවාදා නාමයෝජනා කැඳවීමට නියමිත බවත් ඉන් අනතුරුව 20 වැනි බදාදා පාර්ලිමේන්තුවේ පැවැත්වෙන ඡන්ද විමසීමෙන් පසු පාර්ලිමේන්තු මන්ත්‍රීවරයකු ජනාධිපති ධුරය සඳහා තෝරා පත් කර ගන්නා බවත් කතානායකවරයා පැවසීය.",
        "ප‍්‍රජාතන්ත‍්‍රවාදී රාමුව තුළ කිසිදු බාධාවකින් තොරව මෙම කි‍්‍රයාවලිය කඩිනමින් සිදුකිරීමට සියලූ පාර්ශ්වවල සහයෝගය අපේක්ෂා කරන බවද කථානායකවරයා වැඩිදුරටත් පැවසීය.",
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකා පොදුජන පෙරමුණ ඉදිරිපත් කරන අපේක්ෂකයාට සහය දිය යුතුයි: ජී එල් පීරිස්"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "News 1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "16",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "10.00 පෙ.ව",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "16",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "19 වැනි",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "20 වැනි",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ආණ්ඩුක්රම ව්යවස්ථාව",
            "label": "LAW"
          },
          {
            "text": "2",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "1981",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "16) සෙනසුරාදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "10.00",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ධම්මික දසනායක",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "4 වන කොටස",
            "label": "LAW"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජනාධිපතිවරණ (විශේෂ විධිවිධාන",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "2",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "1981",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "දවස් තුනක්",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "16",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "5 කොටස",
            "label": "LAW"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තු කටයුතු පිළිබඳ කාරක සභාව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "10.00",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "යාපා අබේවර්ධන",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "20 වැනිදා පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "19 වන අඟහරුවාදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "20 වැනි",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "බදාදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "ජී.එල් පීරිස්",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "ஜனாதிபதி ராஜினாமா செய்த பிறகு பாராளுமன்றம் கூடுகிறது",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); ஜனாதிபதியின் இராஜினாமாவை உத்தியோகபூர்வமாக அறிவிப்பதற்காக பாராளுமன்றம் இன்று (16) காலை 10.00 மணிக்கு கூடவுள்ளது.",
        "ஜனாதிபதி பதவிக்கான வெற்றிடம் இன்று (16) பாராளுமன்றத்தில் அறிவிக்கப்படவுள்ளது.",
        "முன்னதாக தீர்மானித்தபடி, 19ஆம் திகதி வேட்புமனுக்கள் கோரப்பட்டு, 20ஆம் திகதி ஜனாதிபதி தெரிவு செய்யப்படும் – சபாநாயகர் இன்று நடைபெற்ற கட்சித் தலைவர்கள் கூட்டத்தில் தெரிவிக்கிறார்.",
        "அரசியலமைப்பு மற்றும் 1981 ஆம் ஆண்டு 2 ஆம் இலக்க ஜனாதிபதி தேர்தல் (விசேட ஏற்பாடுகள்) சட்டத்தின் 4 ஆம் பிரிவின் பிரகாரம் பாராளுமன்றம் இன்று (16) சனிக்கிழமை காலை 10.00 மணிக்கு கூடவுள்ளதாக பாராளுமன்ற செயலாளர் நாயகம் தம்மிக்க தசநாயக்க தெரிவித்துள்ளார். அனைத்து பாராளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர்கள்.",
        "1981 ஆம் ஆண்டின் 2 ஆம் இலக்க ஜனாதிபதித் தேர்தல்கள் (சிறப்பு ஏற்பாடுகள்) சட்டத்தின் 4 ஆவது பிரிவின்படி, வெற்றிடம் ஏற்பட்ட பின்னர் பாராளுமன்றம் மூன்று நாட்களுக்குள் கூட்டப்பட வேண்டும்.",
        "இதனால், மேற்படி சட்டத்தின் 5ஆவது பிரிவின் பிரகாரம் ஜனாதிபதி அலுவலகம் வெற்றிடமாக உள்ளதாக செயலாளர் நாயகம் இன்று (16) அறிவிக்க உள்ளார்.",
        "இதேவேளை, இன்று முற்பகல் 10.00 மணிக்கு நடைபெற்ற கட்சித் தலைவர்கள் மற்றும் பாராளுமன்ற அலுவல்கள் தொடர்பான குழுக் கூட்டத்தில், சபாநாயகர் கௌரவ. கட்சித் தலைவர்கள் முன்னரே தீர்மானித்தபடி எதிர்வரும் 20ஆம் திகதி புதிய ஜனாதிபதியை நாடாளுமன்றம் தெரிவு செய்யவுள்ளதாக மஹிந்த யாப்பா அபேவர்தன தெரிவித்துள்ளார்.",
        "இதன்படி எதிர்வரும் 19ஆம் திகதி செவ்வாய்க்கிழமை வேட்புமனுக்கள் கோரப்படும் எனவும், அதனைத் தொடர்ந்து எதிர்வரும் 20ஆம் திகதி புதன்கிழமை நாடாளுமன்றத்தில் இடம்பெற்ற தேர்தலின் பின்னர் ஜனாதிபதித் தேர்தலுக்கு நாடாளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர் ஒருவர் தெரிவு செய்யப்படுவார் எனவும் சபாநாயகர் தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "ஜனநாயக கட்டமைப்பிற்குள் எவ்வித இடையூறும் இன்றி இந்த செயற்பாட்டை விரைவாக முன்னெடுக்க அனைத்து தரப்பினரின் ஆதரவையும் எதிர்பார்ப்பதாக சபாநாயகர் மேலும் தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "SLPP நிறுத்தும் வேட்பாளரை ஆதரிக்க வேண்டும்: ஜி.எல்.பீரிஸ்"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "News 1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "16",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "காலை 10.00 மணி",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "16",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "19 ஆம் தேதி",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "20 ஆம் தேதி",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "அரசியலமைப்பு",
            "label": "LAW"
          },
          {
            "text": "2",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "1981",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "16) சனிக்கிழமை",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "10.00",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "தம்மிக்க தசநாயக்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பிரிவு 4 இன்",
            "label": "LAW"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜனாதிபதி தேர்தல்கள் (சிறப்பு ஏற்பாடுகள்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "2",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "1981",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "மூன்று நாட்கள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "16",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "பிரிவு 5",
            "label": "LAW"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்ற விவகாரங்களுக்கான குழு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "10.00",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "யாப்பா அபேவர்தன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "20ஆம் தேதி நாடாளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "19 செவ்வாய்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "20 ஆம் தேதி",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "புதன்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஜி.எல்.பீரிஸ்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}