{
  "newspaper_id": "news-first-lk",
  "url": "https://www.newsfirst.lk/2022/06/29/foreign-secretary-meets-us-delegation/",
  "time_ut": 1656479700,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Foreign Secretary meets US delegation",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Foreign Secretary meets US delegation",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); Secretary, Foreign Affairs Aruni Wijewardane met a senior delegation representing the United States Department of the Treasury and the Department of State led by the Deputy Assistant Secretary of Treasury for Asia Robert Kaproth and the Deputy Assistant Secretary of State for South & Central Asia Ambassador Kelly Keiderling at the Ministry of Foreign Affairs in Colombo on Tuesday 28 June, 2022.",
        "Foreign Secretary Wijewardane welcomed the strong and multifaceted bilateral partnership between the two countries which is mutually beneficial and contributes, inter alia, towards the wellbeing of the people of Sri Lanka. The Sri Lanka side also discussed possible areas of support from the U.S. in addressing the multiple challenges faced by Sri Lanka due to the prevailing economic situation in the country.",
        "The visiting delegation welcomed the opportunity to meet senior interlocutors of the Sri Lankan Government and discuss issues of relevance, as well as aspects of the long-term partnership of the U.S. with Sri Lanka.",
        "The visiting delegation was accompanied by the Ambassador of the U.S. to Sri Lanka Julie Chung and other officials from the U.S.Department of Treasury, the U.S. Department of State and the U.S. Embassy in Colombo. Additional Secretary, Bilateral Affairs (West) Manisha Gunasekera; Director General, Economic Affairs Chandana Weerasena; and Director, Americas Chatura Perera of the Ministry of Foreign Affairs were associated with the Foreign Secretary at the meeting.",
        "During their visit from 26 to 29 June 2022, the delegation also called on President Gotabaya Rajapaksa, and met Prime Minister Ranil Wickremesinghe, Minister of Foreign Affairs Prof. G.L. Peiris, Minister of Power and Energy Kanchana Wijesekera, Governor of the Central Bank of Sri Lanka Dr. P. Nandalal Weerasinghe and Secretary to the Treasury Mahinda Siriwardana."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "US",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Foreign Affairs",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Aruni Wijewardane",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the United States Department of the",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Treasury",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Department of State",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Treasury",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Robert Kaproth",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "State for South & Central Asia",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kelly Keiderling",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Ministry of Foreign Affairs in Colombo",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Tuesday 28 June, 2022",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Wijewardane",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "two",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "U.S.",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the Sri Lankan Government",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "U.S.",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "U.S.",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Julie Chung",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Treasury",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the U.S. Department of State",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the U.S. Embassy",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Colombo",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Bilateral Affairs",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Manisha Gunasekera",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Chandana Weerasena",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Perera",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Ministry of Foreign Affairs",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "26 to 29 June 2022",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Gotabaya Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Foreign Affairs",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "G.L. Peiris",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Central Bank of Sri Lanka",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "P. Nandalal Weerasinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Treasury",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "විදේශ ලේකම් ඇමෙරිකානු නියෝජිත පිරිසක් හමුවෙයි",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); විදේශ කටයුතු ලේකම් අරුණි විජේවර්ධන, ආසියා නියෝජ්‍ය භාණ්ඩාගාර සහකාර ලේකම් රොබට් කප්‍රෝත් සහ දකුණු සහ මධ්‍යම ආසියානු නියෝජ්‍ය සහකාර රාජ්‍ය ලේකම් කෙලී කීඩර්ලින් ප්‍රමුඛ එක්සත් ජනපද භාණ්ඩාගාර දෙපාර්තමේන්තුව සහ රාජ්‍ය දෙපාර්තමේන්තුව නියෝජනය කරන ජ්‍යෙෂ්ඨ නියෝජිත පිරිසක් හමුවිය. 2022 ජුනි 28 වැනි අඟහරුවාදා කොළඹ විදේශ කටයුතු අමාත්‍යාංශයේදී.",
        "දෙරට අතර අන්‍යෝන්‍ය වශයෙන් වාසිදායක සහ අන්‍යෝන්‍ය වශයෙන් ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ ජනතාවගේ යහපැවැත්ම සඳහා දායක වන ශක්තිමත් සහ බහුවිධ ද්විපාර්ශ්වික හවුල්කාරිත්වය විදේශ ලේකම් විජේවර්ධන විසින් පිළිගනු ලැබීය. රට තුළ පවතින ආර්ථික තත්ත්වය හේතුවෙන් ශ්‍රී ලංකාව මුහුණ දෙන බහුවිධ අභියෝගවලට මුහුණ දීම සඳහා එක්සත් ජනපදයෙන් සහාය විය හැකි ක්ෂේත්‍ර පිළිබඳව ද ශ්‍රී ලංකා පාර්ශ්වය සාකච්ඡා කළේය.",
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකා රජයේ ජ්‍යෙෂ්ඨ මැදිහත්කරුවන් හමුවීමට සහ අදාළ ගැටළු මෙන්ම ශ්‍රී ලංකාව සමඟ එක්සත් ජනපදයේ දිගුකාලීන හවුල්කාරිත්වයේ පැති පිළිබඳව සාකච්ඡා කිරීමට ලැබුණු අවස්ථාව සංචාරක නියෝජිත පිරිස විසින් පිළිගනු ලැබීය.",
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ එක්සත් ජනපද තානාපතිනී ජුලී චුන්ග් සහ එක්සත් ජනපද භාණ්ඩාගාර දෙපාර්තමේන්තුව, එක්සත් ජනපද රාජ්‍ය දෙපාර්තමේන්තුව සහ කොළඹ පිහිටි එක්සත් ජනපද තානාපති කාර්යාලයේ අනෙකුත් නිලධාරීන් මෙම සංචාරයට පැමිණි දූත පිරිස සමඟ එක්ව සිටියහ. අතිරේක ලේකම්, ද්විපාර්ශ්වික කටයුතු (බටහිර) මනීෂා ගුණසේකර; අධ්‍යක්ෂ ජනරාල්, ආර්ථික කටයුතු චන්දන වීරසේන; සහ විදේශ කටයුතු අමාත්‍යාංශයේ ඇමරිකාස් අධ්‍යක්ෂ චතුර පෙරේරා මහතා විදේශ ලේකම්වරයා සමඟ මෙම හමුවට සම්බන්ධ විය.",
        "2022 ජූනි 26 සිට 29 දක්වා ඔවුන්ගේ සංචාරය අතරතුර, දූත පිරිස ජනාධිපති ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ මහතා ද හමු වූ අතර, අග්‍රාමාත්‍ය රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ, විදේශ කටයුතු අමාත්‍ය මහාචාර්ය ජී.එල්. පීරිස්, විදුලිබල හා බලශක්ති අමාත්‍ය කාංචනා විජේසේකර, ශ්‍රී මහ බැංකුවේ අධිපති කාංචනා විජේසේකර යන මහත්ම මහත්මීන් හමුවිය. ලංකා ආචාර්ය පී. නන්දලාල් වීරසිංහ සහ භාණ්ඩාගාර ලේකම් මහින්ද සිරිවර්ධන."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "එක්සත් ජනපදය",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "විදේශ කටයුතු",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "අරුණි විජේවර්ධන",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "එක්සත් ජනපද දෙපාර්තමේන්තුවේ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "භාණ්ඩාගාර",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "රාජ්ය දෙපාර්තමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "භාණ්ඩාගාර",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "රොබට් කප්රොත්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "දකුණු සහ මධ්‍යම ආසියාව සඳහා ප්‍රාන්තය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "කෙලී කීඩර්ලින්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "විදේශ කටයුතු අමාත්‍යාංශය කොළඹ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "2022 ජූනි 28 අඟහරුවාදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "විජේවර්ධන ය",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "දෙක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "එක්සත් ජනපදය.",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකා රජය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "එක්සත් ජනපදය.",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "එක්සත් ජනපදය.",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජූලි චුන්ග්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "භාණ්ඩාගාර",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "එක්සත් ජනපද රාජ්ය දෙපාර්තමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "එක්සත් ජනපද තානාපති කාර්යාලය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "කොළඹ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ද්විපාර්ශ්වික කටයුතු",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "මනීෂා ගුණසේකර",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "චන්දන වීරසේන",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "පෙරේරා",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "විදේශ කටයුතු අමාත්යාංශය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "2022 ජූනි 26 සිට 29 දක්වා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "විදේශ කටයුතු",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජී.එල් පීරිස්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකා මහ බැංකුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "පී.නන්දලාල් වීරසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "භාණ්ඩාගාර",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "வெளியுறவு செயலாளர் அமெரிக்க பிரதிநிதிகளை சந்தித்தார்",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); வெளிவிவகார செயலாளர் அருணி விஜேவர்தன, ஆசியாவிற்கான பிரதி உதவி திறைசேரி செயலாளர் ரொபேர்ட் கப்ரோத் மற்றும் தெற்கு மற்றும் மத்திய ஆசியாவிற்கான பிரதி உதவி செயலாளர் கெல்லி கெய்டர்லிங் தலைமையிலான அமெரிக்க திறைசேரி மற்றும் இராஜாங்க திணைக்களத்தை பிரதிநிதித்துவப்படுத்தும் சிரேஷ்ட பிரதிநிதிகளை சந்தித்தார். ஜூன் 28, 2022 செவ்வாய்க்கிழமை கொழும்பில் உள்ள வெளிவிவகார அமைச்சில்.",
        "இரு நாடுகளுக்குமிடையிலான வலுவான மற்றும் பன்முகத்தன்மை கொண்ட இருதரப்பு பங்காளித்துவத்தை வெளிவிவகார செயலாளர் விஜேவர்தன வரவேற்றார், இது பரஸ்பரம் நன்மை பயக்கும் மற்றும் இலங்கை மக்களின் நல்வாழ்வை நோக்கி பங்களிக்கிறது. நாட்டில் நிலவும் பொருளாதார நிலைமை காரணமாக இலங்கை எதிர்கொள்ளும் பல சவால்களை எதிர்கொள்வதில் அமெரிக்காவின் ஆதரவின் சாத்தியமான பகுதிகள் குறித்தும் இலங்கை தரப்பு விவாதித்தது.",
        "வருகை தந்த தூதுக்குழு இலங்கை அரசாங்கத்தின் சிரேஷ்ட உரையாசிரியர்களைச் சந்தித்து பொருத்தமான விடயங்கள் மற்றும் இலங்கையுடனான அமெரிக்காவின் நீண்டகால பங்காளித்துவத்தின் அம்சங்களைப் பற்றி கலந்துரையாடுவதற்கான வாய்ப்பை வரவேற்றது.",
        "இலங்கைக்கான அமெரிக்கத் தூதுவர் ஜூலி சுங் மற்றும் அமெரிக்க திறைசேரி திணைக்களம், அமெரிக்க இராஜாங்கத் திணைக்களம் மற்றும் கொழும்பில் உள்ள அமெரிக்கத் தூதரகம் ஆகியவற்றின் அதிகாரிகளும் வருகை தந்த குழுவினருடன் சென்றிருந்தனர். கூடுதல் செயலாளர், இருதரப்பு விவகாரங்கள் (மேற்கு) மனிஷா குணசேகர; பணிப்பாளர் நாயகம், பொருளாதார விவகாரங்கள் சந்தன வீரசேன; மற்றும் வெளிவிவகார அமைச்சின் பணிப்பாளர், அமெரிக்காஸ் சத்துர பெரேரா ஆகியோர் இந்த சந்திப்பில் வெளிவிவகார செயலாளருடன் இணைந்திருந்தனர்.",
        "2022 ஆம் ஆண்டு ஜூன் 26 முதல் 29 ஆம் திகதி வரையான தமது விஜயத்தின் போது, ​​ஜனாதிபதி கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ஷவைச் சந்தித்த பிரதிநிதிகள், பிரதமர் ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க, வெளிவிவகார அமைச்சர் பேராசிரியர் ஜி.எல். பீரிஸ், மின்சக்தி மற்றும் எரிசக்தி அமைச்சர் காஞ்சனா விஜேசேகர, ஸ்ரீ மத்திய வங்கியின் ஆளுநர் ஆகியோரைச் சந்தித்தனர். லங்கா கலாநிதி பி.நந்தலால் வீரசிங்க மற்றும் திறைசேரியின் செயலாளர் மஹிந்த சிறிவர்தன."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "எங்களுக்கு",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "வெளிநாட்டு விவகாரங்கள்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "அருணி விஜேவர்தன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "யுனைடெட் ஸ்டேட்ஸ் துறை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "கருவூலம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "மாநிலத் துறை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "கருவூலம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ராபர்ட் கப்ரோத்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "தெற்கு மற்றும் மத்திய ஆசியாவிற்கான மாநிலம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "கெல்லி கெய்டர்லிங்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "கொழும்பில் உள்ள வெளிவிவகார அமைச்சு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "28 ஜூன், 2022 செவ்வாய்க் கிழமை",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "விஜேவர்தன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இரண்டு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "எங்களுக்கு.",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை அரசு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "எங்களுக்கு.",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "எங்களுக்கு.",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜூலி சுங்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "கருவூலம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "அமெரிக்க வெளியுறவுத்துறை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "அமெரிக்க தூதரகம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "கொழும்பு",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இருதரப்பு விவகாரங்கள்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "மனிஷா குணசேகர",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "சந்தன வீரசேன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "பெரேரா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "வெளியுறவு அமைச்சகம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "26 முதல் 29 ஜூன் 2022 வரை",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "வெளிநாட்டு விவகாரங்கள்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜி.எல்.பீரிஸ்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை மத்திய வங்கி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "பி.நந்தலால் வீரசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "கருவூலம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}