{
  "newspaper_id": "economy-next-com",
  "url": "https://economynext.com/sri-lanka-coal-deal-awarded-on-6-month-credit-amid-queries-99081/",
  "time_ut": 1661588220,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Sri Lanka coal deal awarded on 6-month credit amid queries",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Sri Lanka coal deal awarded on 6-month credit amid queries",
      "author": "",
      "body_lines": [
        "ECONOMYNEXT – Sri Lanka has awarded a deal to supply coal to Ceylon Electricity Board on a 6-month credit facility Energy Minister Kanchana Wijesekera said amid opposition queries.",
        "The tender was awarded to the lowest bidder, Minister Wijesekera said.",
        "“Due procurement process followed with evaluation & approval from STEC, SSCAPC. Supplier will provide 6 months credit facility from the date of supply of each shipment,” he said in a twitter.com message.",
        "Opposition legislator Harsha de Silva queried why are two year deal was awarded to a company that was not originally shortlisted.",
        "Was #SriLanka’s LARGEST EVER PROCUREMENT amounting to USD 1,477 million to purchase 4.5m MT of coal on a 2 year term deal AWARDED today to a company that was NOT even SHORTLISTED by the tender committee? Can @TimesOnlineLK who y’day made the allegation this could happen, confirm? pic.twitter.com/BRPekGRivd",
        "Global coal and oil prices are at high levels in 2021 amid the so-called Powell Bubble fired by the US Federal Reserve.",
        "The Fed however is tightening monetary policy and the US dollar is already strengthening. Commodity prices are expected to edge down as monetary tightening takes effect.",
        "Sri Lanka has a 900MW coal plant which supplies over 30 percent of the energy needs. (Colombo/Aug27/2022)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Sri Lanka",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "6-month",
          "label": "DATE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ceylon Electricity Board",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "6-month",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Energy",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kanchana Wijesekera",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Wijesekera",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "STEC",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "SSCAPC",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "6 months",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Harsha de Silva",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "two year",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "SriLanka",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "4.5",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "2 year",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "y’day",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "2021",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Powell",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the US Federal Reserve",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Fed",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "US",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "900MW",
            "label": "PRODUCT"
          },
          {
            "text": "30 percent",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "විමසීම් මධ්‍යයේ ශ්‍රී ලංකා ගල් අඟුරු ගනුදෙනුව මාස 6ක ණය මත ප්‍රදානය කරන ලදී",
      "author": "",
      "body_lines": [
        "ECONOMYNEXT - මාස 6ක ණය පහසුකමක් මත ලංකා විදුලිබල මණ්ඩලයට ගල් අඟුරු සැපයීමේ ගනුදෙනුවක් ශ්‍රී ලංකාව විසින් ලබාදී ඇති බව විපක්ෂයේ ප්‍රශ්න කිරීම් මධ්‍යයේ බලශක්ති අමාත්‍ය කංචන විජේසේකර මහතා පැවසීය.",
        "අඩුම ලංසුවට ටෙන්ඩරය ලබාදුන් බව ඇමති විජේසේකර මහතා පැවසීය.",
        "“STEC, SSCAPC වෙතින් ඇගයීම සහ අනුමැතිය සමඟ නියමිත ප්‍රසම්පාදන ක්‍රියාවලිය අනුගමනය කෙරේ. එක් එක් නැව්ගත කිරීම සපයන දිනයේ සිට මාස 6 ක ණය පහසුකම් සැපයුම්කරු විසින් ලබා දෙනු ඇත, ”ඔහු twitter.com පණිවිඩයක් මගින් පැවසීය.",
        "විපක්ෂයේ මන්ත්‍රී හර්ෂ ද සිල්වා ප්‍රශ්න කළේ මුලින් කෙටි ලැයිස්තුගත නොකළ සමාගමකට වසර දෙකක ගනුදෙනුවක් ලබා දුන්නේ මන්දැයි යන්නයි.",
        "වසර 2ක කාලීන ගනුදෙනුවක් මත ගල් අඟුරු මෙට්‍රික් ටොන් 4.5ක් මිලදී ගැනීමට #ශ්‍රීලංකාවේ මෙතෙක් සිදු කළ විශාලතම ප්‍රසම්පාදන මුදල USD මිලියන 1,477ක් වූයේ ටෙන්ඩර් කමිටුව විසින් කෙටි ලැයිස්තුගත කර නොතිබූ සමාගමකටද? මෙය සිදු විය හැකි බවට චෝදනා එල්ල කළ @TimesOnlineLK හට තහවුරු කළ හැකිද? pic.twitter.com/BRPekGRivd",
        "එක්සත් ජනපද ෆෙඩරල් සංචිතය විසින් නිකුත් කරන ලද ඊනියා Powell Bubble මධ්‍යයේ 2021 දී ගෝලීය ගල් අඟුරු සහ තෙල් මිල ඉහළ මට්ටමක පවතී.",
        "කෙසේ වෙතත් ෆෙඩරල් බැංකුව මූල්‍ය ප්‍රතිපත්තිය දැඩි කරමින් සිටින අතර එක්සත් ජනපද ඩොලරය දැනටමත් ශක්තිමත් වෙමින් පවතී. මුදල් දැඩි කිරීම බලපැවැත්වෙන පරිදි භාණ්ඩ මිල පහත වැටෙනු ඇතැයි අපේක්ෂා කෙරේ.",
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකාව සතුව මෙගාවොට් 900 ක ගල් අඟුරු බලාගාරයක් ඇති අතර එය බලශක්ති අවශ්‍යතාවයෙන් සියයට 30 කට වඩා සපයයි. (කොළඹ/අගෝස්තු 27/2022)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "6-මාස",
          "label": "DATE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ලංකා විදුලිබල මණ්ඩලය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "6-මාස",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශක්තිය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "කාංචන විජේසේකර",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "විජේසේකර",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "STEC",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "SSCAPC",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මාස 6 යි",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "හර්ෂ ද සිල්වා",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "වසර දෙකක්",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "4.5",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "අවුරුදු 2 යි",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "දවසේ",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "2021",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "පවෙල්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "එක්සත් ජනපද ෆෙඩරල් සංචිතය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ෆෙඩරල්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "එක්සත් ජනපදය",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "900MW",
            "label": "PRODUCT"
          },
          {
            "text": "සියයට 30 කි",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "கேள்விகளுக்கு மத்தியில் இலங்கை நிலக்கரி ஒப்பந்தம் 6 மாத கடனில் வழங்கப்பட்டது",
      "author": "",
      "body_lines": [
        "ECONOMYNEXT - இலங்கை மின்சார சபைக்கு 6 மாத கடன் வசதியில் நிலக்கரி வழங்குவதற்கான ஒப்பந்தத்தை இலங்கை வழங்கியுள்ளது என எதிர்க்கட்சிகளின் கேள்விகளுக்கு மத்தியில் எரிசக்தி அமைச்சர் காஞ்சன விஜேசேகர தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "மிகக்குறைந்த விலைமனுதாரருக்கு இந்த ஒப்பந்தப்புள்ளி வழங்கப்பட்டுள்ளதாக அமைச்சர் விஜேசேகர தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "“STEC, SSCAPC இலிருந்து மதிப்பீடு மற்றும் ஒப்புதலுடன் உரிய கொள்முதல் செயல்முறை பின்பற்றப்பட்டது. ஒவ்வொரு கப்பலுக்கும் சப்ளை செய்யப்பட்ட நாளிலிருந்து சப்ளையர் 6 மாத கடன் வசதியை வழங்குவார்,” என்று அவர் twitter.com செய்தியில் தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "முதலில் பட்டியலிடப்படாத ஒரு நிறுவனத்திற்கு இரண்டு வருட ஒப்பந்தம் ஏன் வழங்கப்பட்டது என்று எதிர்க்கட்சி சட்டமன்ற உறுப்பினர் ஹர்ஷ டி சில்வா வினவினார்.",
        "2 வருட கால ஒப்பந்தத்தின் பேரில் 4.5 மில்லியன் மெட்ரிக் டன் நிலக்கரியை வாங்குவதற்கான #SriLanka இன் மிகப் பெரிய கொள்முதல் தொகையான 1,477 மில்லியன் அமெரிக்க டாலர்கள் இன்று டெண்டர் குழுவால் குறுகிய பட்டியலிடப்படாத ஒரு நிறுவனத்திற்கு வழங்கப்பட்டதா? இது நடக்கலாம் என்ற குற்றச்சாட்டை அன்று கூறிய @TimesOnlineLK உறுதிப்படுத்த முடியுமா? pic.twitter.com/BRPekGRivd",
        "அமெரிக்க பெடரல் ரிசர்வ் எரியும் Powell Bubble என்று அழைக்கப்படுவதற்கு மத்தியில் 2021 ஆம் ஆண்டில் உலகளாவிய நிலக்கரி மற்றும் எண்ணெய் விலைகள் அதிக அளவில் உள்ளன.",
        "இருப்பினும் மத்திய வங்கி பணவியல் கொள்கையை கடுமையாக்குகிறது மற்றும் அமெரிக்க டாலர் ஏற்கனவே வலுவடைந்து வருகிறது. பண இறுக்கம் அமலுக்கு வருவதால் பொருட்களின் விலைகள் குறையும் என எதிர்பார்க்கப்படுகிறது.",
        "இலங்கையில் 900 மெகாவாட் நிலக்கரி ஆலை உள்ளது, இது 30 சதவீத ஆற்றல் தேவையை வழங்குகிறது. (கொழும்பு/ஆகஸ்ட்27/2022)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "இலங்கை",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "6-மாதம்",
          "label": "DATE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை மின்சார சபை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "6-மாதம்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆற்றல்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "காஞ்சனா விஜேசேகர",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "விஜேசேகர",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "STEC",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "எஸ்.எஸ்.சி.ஏ.பி.சி",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "6 மாதங்கள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஹர்ஷ டி சில்வா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இரண்டு வருடம்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "4.5",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "2 வருடம்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "நாள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "2021",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "பவல்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "அமெரிக்க பெடரல் ரிசர்வ்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஊட்டி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "எங்களுக்கு",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "900மெகாவாட்",
            "label": "PRODUCT"
          },
          {
            "text": "30 சதவீதம்",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}