{
  "newspaper_id": "lankadeepa-lk",
  "url": "https://www.lankadeepa.lk/latest_news/අගමැතිකම-දිනේෂ්ට-දෙන්න/1-616476",
  "time_ut": 1657890193,
  "original_lang": "si",
  "original_title": "අගමැතිකම දිනේෂ්ට දෙන්න",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Give Prime Ministership to Dinesh",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "Sri Lanka Podujana Peramuna Gampaha District Member of Parliament Mr. Sisira Jayakodi has requested the Acting President to appoint Speaker of the House Dinesh Gunawardena as Acting Prime Minister.",
        "He also points out that this can be done according to the provisions of the constitution.",
        "After the office of President becomes vacant, the Prime Minister shall act in the office of President during the period between the appointment of a new President. He mentioned that since the post of Prime Minister will be vacant, the Acting President should appoint another cabinet minister according to the constitution to fill that position.",
        "He also states that this is stated in Article 40 (1) (c) of the Constitution.",
        "If the current Prime Minister is Acting President, according to the Constitution he must now appoint a Cabinet Minister for the post of Prime Minister. In 1993, Mr. Ranil Wickramasinghe, who was then the leader of the House, became the Prime Minister. After the assassination of President Ranasinghe Premadasa, the then Prime Minister DB Wijetunga became the Acting President, and Mr. Wijetunga appointed Ranil Wickramasinghe, who was a member of the Cabinet at that time, as the Prime Minister. There, the tradition was to treat the Leader of the House of Parliament as senior and worthy after the Prime Minister. Accordingly, Mr. Jayakodi states that this time, Mr. Dinesh Gunawardena, who is the leader of the House and also a senior minister, should be appointed as the Acting Prime Minister."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Podujana Peramuna",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Gampaha",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sisira Jayakodi",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "House",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "Article 40",
            "label": "LAW"
          },
          {
            "text": "1",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Constitution",
            "label": "LAW"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Constitution",
            "label": "LAW"
          },
          {
            "text": "Cabinet",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "1993",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickramasinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "House",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ranasinghe Premadasa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "DB Wijetunga",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Wijetunga",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickramasinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Cabinet",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the House of Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Jayakodi",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Dinesh Gunawardena",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "House",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "අගමැතිකම දිනේෂ්ට දෙන්න",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "සභානායක දිනේෂ් ගුණවර්ධන මහතා  වැඩබලන අගමැතිවරයා ලෙස පත් කරන ලෙස ශ්‍රී ලංකා පොදුජන පෙරමුණේ ගම්පහ දිස්ත්‍රික් පාර්ලිමේන්තු මන්ත්‍රී  සිසිර ජයකොඩි මහතා වැඩබලන ජනාධිපතිවරයාගෙන් ඉල්ලීමක් කර ඇත.",
        "ව්‍යවස්ථා ප්‍රතිපාදන අනුව එසේ කටයුතු කළ හැකි බවද ඔහු පෙන්වා දෙයි.",
        "ජනාධිපති ධුරය හිස් වීමෙන් පසු ,  නව ජනාධිපතිවරයකු පත් කර ගැනීම අතර කාලයේදී ,  අග්‍රාමාත්‍යවරයා ජනාධිපති ධුරයේ වැඩ බැලිය යුතුය. එවිට අග්‍රාමාත්‍ය ධුරය හිස්වන බැවින්, එම ධුරයේ වැඩබැලීම සඳහා වැඩබලන ජනාධිපතිවරයා විසින් ආණ්ඩු ක්‍රම ව්‍යවස්ථාව අනුව   කැබිනට් මණ්ඩලයේ වෙනත් අමාත්‍යවරයකු පත්  කරනු ලැබිය යුතුව  ඇතැයි  හෙතෙම සඳහන් කළේය.",
        "මේ බව සඳහන් වන්නේ, ආණ්ඩුක්‍රම ව්‍යවස්ථාවේ, 40 (1) (ඇ) වගන්තියේ බවත්  ඔහු ප්‍රකාශ කරයි.",
        "වත්මන් අගමැති, වැඩබලන ජනාධිපති නම්, ව්‍යවස්ථාවට අනුව ඔහු දැන් අගමැති ධුරය සඳහා කැබිනට් මණ්ඩලයේ අමාත්‍යවරයකු  පත්කළ යුතුය. 1993දී මෙසේ අගමැති වූයේ එවකට සභානායක වූ රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතාය. ඒ, රණසිංහ ප්‍රේමදාස ජනාධිපතිතුමා ඝාතනය කිරීමත් සමග, එවකට  අගමැති ඩී.බී.විජේතුංග මහතා, වැඩබලන ජනාධිපති ධුරයට පත්වීමත් සමග, විජේතුංග මහතා, එවකට කැබිනට් මණ්ඩලයේ සාමාජිකයකු වූ රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතා  අගමැති ලෙස පත්  කළේය. එහිදී සම්ප්‍රදාය වූයේ අගමැතිගෙන් පසු පාර්ලිමේන්තුවේ සභානායකවරයා ජ්‍යෙෂ්ඨ හා සුදුස්සා ලෙස සැලකීමේ ක්‍රමවේදයයි. ඒ අනුව මෙවර සභානායක වන, අමාත්‍යවරයකුද වන ජ්‍යෙෂ්ඨයාද වන, දිනේෂ් ගුණවර්ධන මහතා වැඩබලන අගමැති ධුරයට පත් කිරීම කළ යුතු බව ජයකොඩි මහතා සඳහන් කරයි."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "පොදුජන පෙරමුණ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගම්පහ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "සිසිර ජයකොඩි",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "නිවස",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "40 වැනි වගන්තිය",
            "label": "LAW"
          },
          {
            "text": "1",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ව්යවස්ථාව",
            "label": "LAW"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ව්යවස්ථාව",
            "label": "LAW"
          },
          {
            "text": "මණ්ඩල",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "1993",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "නිවස",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "රණසිංහ ප්‍රේමදාස",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඩී බී විජේතුංග",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "විජේතුංග",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "මණ්ඩල",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තු සභාව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජයකොඩි",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "දිනේෂ් ගුණවර්ධන",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "නිවස",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "தினேஷுக்கு பிரதமர் பதவி கொடுங்கள்",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "சபாநாயகர் தினேஷ் குணவர்தனவை பதில் பிரதமராக நியமிக்குமாறு ஸ்ரீலங்கா பொதுஜன பெரமுனவின் கம்பஹா மாவட்ட நாடாளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர் திரு.சிசிர ஜயக்கொடி பதில் ஜனாதிபதியிடம் கோரிக்கை விடுத்துள்ளார்.",
        "அரசியலமைப்பின் விதிகளுக்கு அமைய இதனை மேற்கொள்ள முடியும் எனவும் அவர் சுட்டிக்காட்டியுள்ளார்.",
        "குடியரசுத் தலைவர் பதவி காலியான பிறகு, புதிய குடியரசுத் தலைவரை நியமிப்பதற்கு இடைப்பட்ட காலத்தில் பிரதமர் குடியரசுத் தலைவர் அலுவலகத்தில் செயல்படுவார். பிரதமர் பதவி வெற்றிடமாக இருக்கும் என்பதால், அந்த பதவியை நிரப்புவதற்கு அரசியலமைப்பின் பிரகாரம் மற்றுமொரு அமைச்சரவை அமைச்சரை பதில் ஜனாதிபதி நியமிக்க வேண்டும் என அவர் குறிப்பிட்டுள்ளார்.",
        "இது அரசியலமைப்பின் 40 (1) (c) வில் கூறப்பட்டுள்ளது என்றும் அவர் கூறுகிறார்.",
        "தற்போதைய பிரதமர் தற்காலிக ஜனாதிபதியாக இருந்தால், அரசியலமைப்பின் படி அவர் இப்போது பிரதமர் பதவிக்கு கேபினட் அமைச்சரை நியமிக்க வேண்டும். 1993 இல், அப்போது சபைத் தலைவராக இருந்த திரு.ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க பிரதமரானார். ஜனாதிபதி ரணசிங்க பிரேமதாசவின் படுகொலையின் பின்னர், அப்போதைய பிரதமர் டி.பி.விஜேதுங்க பதில் ஜனாதிபதியானார், அப்போது அமைச்சரவையில் அங்கம் வகித்த ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்கவை பிரதமராக திரு.விஜேதுங்க நியமித்தார். அங்கு, நாடாளுமன்ற அவைத் தலைவரை பிரதமருக்குப் பிறகு மூத்தவராகவும் தகுதியானவராகவும் கருதுவது மரபு. இதன்படி இம்முறை சபைத் தலைவரும் சிரேஷ்ட அமைச்சருமான திரு.தினேஷ் குணவர்தனவை பதில் பிரதமராக நியமிக்க வேண்டுமென ஜயக்கொடி குறிப்பிடுகின்றார்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "பொதுஜன பெரமுன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "கம்பஹா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "சிசிர ஜெயக்கொடி",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "வீடு",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "கட்டுரை 40",
            "label": "LAW"
          },
          {
            "text": "1",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "அரசியலமைப்பு",
            "label": "LAW"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "அரசியலமைப்பு",
            "label": "LAW"
          },
          {
            "text": "மந்திரி சபை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "1993",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "வீடு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரணசிங்க பிரேமதாச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "டி.பி.விஜேதுங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "விஜேதுங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "மந்திரி சபை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்ற சபை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜெயக்கொடி",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "தினேஷ் குணவர்தன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "வீடு",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}