{
  "newspaper_id": "lankadeepa-lk",
  "url": "https://www.lankadeepa.lk/news/‘‘අරගලකරුවන්-ගිනි-තැබූ-ගෙවල්-හදා-ගන්න-රජයෙන්-පිහිටක්-නෑ‘‘/101-618448",
  "time_ut": 1660984787,
  "original_lang": "si",
  "original_title": "‘‘අරගලකරුවන් ගිනි තැබූ ගෙවල් හදා ගන්න රජයෙන් පිහිටක් නෑ‘‘",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "\"There is no help from the government to repair the houses burnt by the militants\"",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "The members of the Sri Lanka Podujana Peramuna have alleged that no support has been received from the government for the construction of the houses of the members of the Sri Lanka Podujana Peramuna which were destroyed by the violent among the activists.",
        "They point out that Mr. Gotabhaya Rajapaksa had given some support for the construction of houses when he was the President, but no support has been received from the current government.",
        "It is reported that the construction of MP's houses is further delayed due to this reason",
        "Mr. Ranil Wickramasinghe made a promise to the Sri Lanka Podujana Peramuna before he was appointed as the successor president that he would provide the necessary support to build the houses of the MPs destroyed by the violent.",
        "The MPs whose properties have been damaged have been given the opportunity to get houses on rental basis from the Battaramulla Viat Pura House Scheme and it is reported that only a few MPs have got the houses so far.",
        "A group of councilors said that it is very difficult to get those houses as there is a huge monthly premium.",
        "Meanwhile, it is reported that the family members of Sri Lanka Podujana Peramuna's Polonnaru District Member of Parliament Mr. Amarakirthi Athukorala, who was killed by a group of violent people, have not received any assistance so far.",
        "Former minister Mr. Wimalaweera Dissanayake, who commented in this regard at the recently held government party meeting, has stated that since the family members of Mr. Amarakirthi Athukorala have not received any relief so far, he is requesting the President to take immediate action.",
        "On the 9th of May last May 9th, the property of the members of parliament and representatives of the local government bodies of the Sri Lanka Podujana Peramuna was destroyed, including the houses of nearly one hundred people."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "Podujana Peramuna",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "Podujana Peramuna",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Gotabhaya Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickramasinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "Podujana Peramuna",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "monthly",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Podujana Peramuna's",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Polonnaru District",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Amarakirthi Athukorala",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Wimalaweera Dissanayake",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Amarakirthi Athukorala",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "9th",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "May last May 9th",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "Podujana Peramuna",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "nearly one hundred",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "‘‘අරගලකරුවන් ගිනි තැබූ ගෙවල් හදා ගන්න රජයෙන් පිහිටක් නෑ‘‘",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "අරගලකරුවන් අතර සිටි ප්‍රචණ්ඩකාරීන් විසින් විනාශ කෙරුණු ශ්‍රී ලංකා පොදුජන පෙරමුණේ මන්ත්‍රීවරුන්ගේ නිවාස ඉදිකරගැනීම සඳහා රජයෙන් කිසිදු අනුග්‍රහයක් මෙතෙක් ලැබී නැතැයි එම මන්ත්‍රීවරු චෝදනා කරති.",
        "ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ මහතා ජනාධිපතිවරයා ලෙස සිටියදී නිවාස ඉදිකරගැනීම සඳහා යම් ආධාරයක් කර ඇතත් වර්තමාන රජයෙන් ඒ සඳහා කිසිදු අනුග්‍රහයක් මෙතෙක් ලැබී නැතැයි ඔවුහු පෙන්වා දෙති.",
        "මන්ත්‍රීවරුන්ගේ නිවාස ඉදිකරගැනීම මේ හේතුව නිසා තවදුරටත් ප්‍රමාද වෙමින් පවතින බව වාර්තා වේ",
        "ප්‍රචණ්ඩකාරීන් විසින් විනාශ කරන ලද මන්ත්‍රීවරුන්ගේ නිවාස ඉදිකර ගැනීම සඳහා අවශ්‍ය සහයෝගය ලබාදෙන බවට රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතා අනුප්‍රාප්තික ජනාධිපතිවරයා ලෙස පත්වීමට පෙර ශ්‍රී ලංකා පොදුජන පෙරමුණට පොරොන්දුවක් ලබා දුන්නේය.",
        "දේපළ හානි වූ මන්ත්‍රීවරුන්ට බත්තරමුල්ලේ වියත් පුර නිවාස යෝජනා ක්‍රමයෙන් නිවාස කුලී පදනම මත ලබා ගැනීමට අවස්ථාව සලසා දී ඇති අතර එම නිවාස දැනට ලබාගෙන ඇත්තේ මන්ත්‍රීවරුන් කිහිප දෙනෙකු පමණක් බව වාර්තා වේ.",
        "විශාල මාසික වාරිකයක් පවතින හෙයින් එම නිවාස ලබා ගැනීම ඉතා දුෂ්කර බව මන්ත්‍රීවරු පිරිසක් පැවසූහ.",
        "මේ අතර ප්‍රචණ්ඩකාරීන් පිරිසක් විසින් ඝාතනය කෙරුණු ශ්‍රී ලංකා පොදුජන පෙරමුණේ පොලොන්නරු දිස්ත්‍රික් පාර්ලිමේන්තු මන්ත්‍රී අමරකීර්ති අතුකෝරල මහතාගේ පවුලේ උදවියටද මෙතෙක් කිසිදු ආධාරයක් ලැබී නැතැයි වාර්තා වේ.",
        "පසුගියදා පැවති ආණ්ඩු පක්ෂ රැස්වීමේදී මේ සම්බන්ධයෙන් අදහස් දක්වා ඇති හිටපු අමාත්‍ය විමලවීර දිසානායක මහතා ප්‍රකාශ කර ඇත්තේ අමරකීර්ති අතුකෝරල මහතාගේ පවුලේ උදවියට මෙතෙක් කිසිදු සහනයක් ලැබී නැති හෙයින් ඒ සඳහා වහාම කටයුතු කරන ලෙස ජනාධිපතිවරයාගෙන් ඉල්ලා සිටින බවයි.",
        "අරගල කරුවන් අතර සිටි ප්‍රචණ්ඩකාරීන් විසින් ඉකුත් මැයි මස 9 වැනිදා කරන ලද ප්‍රහාරවලින් ශ්‍රී ලංකා පොදුජන පෙරමුණේ පාර්ලිමේන්තු මන්ත්‍රීවරුන් සහ පළාත් පාලන ආයතන නියෝජිතයන් සියයකට ආසන්න පිරිසකගේ නිවාස ඇතුලු දේපළ විනාශයට පත්විය."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "පොදුජන පෙරමුණ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "පොදුජන පෙරමුණ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "පොදුජන පෙරමුණ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "මාසිකව",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "පොදුජන පෙරමුණේ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "පොලොන්නරු දිස්ත්‍රික්කය",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "අමරකීර්ති අතුකෝරල",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "විමලවීර දිසානායක",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "අමරකීර්ති අතුකෝරල",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "9 වැනි",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "පසුගිය මැයි 9 වැනිදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "පොදුජන පෙරමුණ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "සියයකට ආසන්න",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "\"தீவிரவாதிகளால் எரிக்கப்பட்ட வீடுகளை சீரமைக்க அரசிடம் இருந்து எந்த உதவியும் இல்லை\"",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "ஶ்ரீலங்கா பொதுஜன பெரமுனவின் உறுப்பினர்களின் வீடுகளை நிர்மாணிப்பதற்கு அரசாங்கத்திடம் இருந்து எவ்வித ஆதரவும் கிடைக்கவில்லை என ஸ்ரீலங்கா பொதுஜன பெரமுனவின் உறுப்பினர்கள் குற்றம் சுமத்தியுள்ளனர்.",
        "திரு.கோத்தபாய ராஜபக்ச ஜனாதிபதியாக இருந்த போது வீடுகளை நிர்மாணிப்பதற்கு சில ஆதரவை வழங்கியிருந்த போதிலும், தற்போதைய அரசாங்கத்திடம் இருந்து எவ்வித ஆதரவும் கிடைக்கவில்லை எனவும் அவர்கள் சுட்டிக்காட்டுகின்றனர்.",
        "இதன்காரணமாக பாராளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர்களின் வீடுகள் நிர்மாணிக்கப்படுவதில் மேலும் தாமதம் ஏற்பட்டுள்ளதாக தெரிவிக்கப்படுகின்றது",
        "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க, ஸ்ரீலங்கா பொதுஜன பெரமுனவுக்கு அடுத்த ஜனாதிபதியாக நியமிக்கப்படுவதற்கு முன்னர், வன்முறைகளால் அழிக்கப்பட்ட பாராளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர்களின் வீடுகளை நிர்மாணிப்பதற்குத் தேவையான ஆதரவை வழங்குவதாக வாக்குறுதியளித்திருந்தார்.",
        "பத்தரமுல்லை வியாட் புர வீடு திட்டத்தில் சொத்துக்கள் சேதமடைந்த பாராளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர்களுக்கு வாடகை அடிப்படையில் வீடுகளை பெற்றுக் கொள்வதற்கான சந்தர்ப்பம் வழங்கப்பட்டுள்ளதுடன், சில பாராளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர்களுக்கு மாத்திரமே இதுவரை வீடுகள் கிடைத்துள்ளதாக தெரிவிக்கப்படுகின்றது.",
        "மாதாந்திர பிரீமியம் அதிகமாக இருப்பதால், அந்த வீடுகள் கிடைப்பது மிகவும் சிரமமாக உள்ளதாக கவுன்சிலர்கள் குழுவினர் தெரிவித்தனர்.",
        "இதேவேளை, வன்முறையாளர்களால் கொல்லப்பட்ட ஸ்ரீலங்கா பொதுஜன பெரமுனவின் பொலன்னறு மாவட்ட நாடாளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர் திரு.அமரகீர்த்தி அத்துகோரளவின் குடும்ப உறுப்பினர்களுக்கு இதுவரை எவ்வித உதவிகளும் கிடைக்கவில்லை என தெரிவிக்கப்படுகிறது.",
        "அண்மையில் நடைபெற்ற அரசாங்கக் கட்சிக் கூட்டத்தில் இது தொடர்பில் கருத்து தெரிவித்த முன்னாள் அமைச்சர் திரு.விமலவீர திஸாநாயக்க, திரு.அமரகீர்த்தி அத்துகோரலவின் குடும்ப உறுப்பினர்களுக்கு இதுவரை நிவாரணம் கிடைக்காததால் உடனடியாக நடவடிக்கை எடுக்குமாறு ஜனாதிபதியிடம் கோரிக்கை விடுப்பதாக தெரிவித்துள்ளார்.",
        "கடந்த மே மாதம் 9ஆம் திகதி ஶ்ரீலங்கா பொதுஜன பெரமுனவின் நாடாளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர்கள் மற்றும் உள்ளூராட்சி மன்ற பிரதிநிதிகளின் சொத்துக்கள், நூறு பேரின் வீடுகள் உள்ளிட்டவை அழிக்கப்பட்டன."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "பொதுஜன பெரமுன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "பொதுஜன பெரமுன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "கோத்தபாய ராஜபக்ச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "பொதுஜன பெரமுன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "மாதாந்திர",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "பொதுஜன பெரமுனவின்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "பொலன்னறு மாவட்டம்",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "அமரகீர்த்தி அத்துகோரல",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "விமலவீர திஸாநாயக்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "அமரகீர்த்தி அத்துகோரல",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "9வது",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "கடந்த மே 9ஆம் தேதி மே",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "பொதுஜன பெரமுன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "கிட்டத்தட்ட நூறு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}