{
  "newspaper_id": "economy-next-com",
  "url": "https://economynext.com/sri-lanka-remittances-down-42-pct-in-june-2022-in-non-credible-peg-97215/",
  "time_ut": 1657504080,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Sri Lanka remittances down 42-pct in June 2022 in non-credible peg",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Sri Lanka remittances down 42-pct in June 2022 in non-credible peg",
      "author": "",
      "body_lines": [
        "ECONOMYNEXT – Sri Lanka’s official remittances were down 42 percent from a year earlier 274.1 million US dollars, with money being channeled to traditional gross settlement systems, with the credibility of a pegged exchange rate being lost.",
        "Sri Lanka usually gets around 500 to 600 million US dollars a month through official channels.",
        "Around May 2021 the central bank started to enforce a non-credible peg at 199.50 to the US dollar and by August 2021 parallel exchange rates started to develop in the official market.",
        "Sri Lanka rupee 203 non-credible peg to US dollar hanging by a thread",
        "Sri Lanka rupee non-credible peg breaks to 211-215 to US dollar",
        "Remittances started drop sharply from September as banks were prohibited from offering higher rates to exporters.",
        "In early May the rupee was trading around 370/380 to the US dollar and Middle East exchange houses were offering around 102 rupees to the Dirham.",
        "A new non-credible peg was then imposed at 360 to the US dollar. (Colombo/July11/2022)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Sri Lanka",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "42",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "June 2022",
          "label": "DATE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka’s",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "42 percent",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "a year earlier",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "274.1 million US dollars",
            "label": "MONEY"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "around 500 to 600 million US dollars",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "May 2021",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "199.50",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "US",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "August 2021",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "203",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "US",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "211",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "US",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "September",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "early May",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "US",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Middle East",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "Dirham",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "360",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "US",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ ප්‍රේෂණ 2022 ජූනි මාසයේදී විශ්වාස කළ නොහැකි අගයකින් සියයට 42 කින් පහත වැටී ඇත.",
      "author": "",
      "body_lines": [
        "ECONOMYNEXT - ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ නිල ප්‍රේෂණ වසරකට පෙර ඇමරිකානු ඩොලර් මිලියන 274.1 ට වඩා සියයට 42 කින් අඩු වී ඇති අතර, සම්ප්‍රදායික දළ පියවීම් පද්ධති වෙත මුදල් යොමු කිරීමත් සමඟ, විනිමය අනුපාතිකයේ විශ්වසනීයත්වය අහිමි විය.",
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවට සාමාන්‍යයෙන් නිල මාර්ග හරහා මසකට ඩොලර් මිලියන 500ක් 600ක් පමණ ලැබේ.",
        "2021 මැයි මාසයේදී මහ බැංකුව විසින් එක්සත් ජනපද ඩොලරයට 199.50 ට විශ්වාසනීය නොවන ඇණවුමක් බලාත්මක කිරීමට පටන් ගත් අතර 2021 අගෝස්තු වන විට සමාන්තර විනිමය අනුපාත නිල වෙළඳපොලේ වර්ධනය වීමට පටන් ගත්තේය.",
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකා රුපියල 203 ත්‍රෙඩ් එකකින් ඇමෙරිකන් ඩොලරයට විශ්වාසනීය නොවන ඇණයක්",
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකා රුපියල එක්සත් ජනපද ඩොලරයට අනුව 211-215 දක්වා බිඳ වැටේ",
        "අපනයනකරුවන්ට ඉහළ පොලී අනුපාත පිරිනැමීම බැංකු විසින් තහනම් කර ඇති හෙයින් සැප්තැම්බර් මාසයේ සිට ප්‍රේෂණ තියුනු ලෙස පහත වැටීමට පටන් ගත්තේය.",
        "මැයි මස මුලදී රුපියල එක්සත් ජනපද ඩොලරයට 370/380 පමණ වෙළඳාම් වූ අතර මැදපෙරදිග විනිමය ආයතන ඩිරාම් සඳහා රුපියල් 102 ක් පමණ ලබා දුන්නේය.",
        "පසුව එක්සත් ජනපද ඩොලරයට 360 ට විශ්වාසනීය නොවන නව ඇණයක් පනවන ලදී. (කොළඹ/ජූලි11/2022)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "42",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "2022 ජූනි",
          "label": "DATE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "සියයට 42 කි",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "වසරකට පෙර",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඩොලර් මිලියන 274.1 කි",
            "label": "MONEY"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඩොලර් මිලියන 500 සිට 600 දක්වා",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "2021 මැයි",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "199.50 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "එක්සත් ජනපදය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "2021 අගෝස්තු",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "203",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "එක්සත් ජනපදය",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "211",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "එක්සත් ජනපදය",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "සැප්තැම්බර්",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "මැයි මුල",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "එක්සත් ජනපදය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මැද පෙරදිග",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඩිරාම්",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "360",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "එක්සත් ජනපදය",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "2022 ஆம் ஆண்டு ஜூன் மாதத்தில் நம்பகத்தன்மையற்ற பணத்தில் இலங்கையின் பணம் 42 சதவிகிதம் குறைந்துள்ளது.",
      "author": "",
      "body_lines": [
        "ECONOMYNEXT - இலங்கையின் உத்தியோகபூர்வ பணம் ஒரு வருடத்திற்கு முந்தைய 274.1 மில்லியன் அமெரிக்க டாலர்களை விட 42 சதவீதம் குறைந்துள்ளது, பாரம்பரிய மொத்த தீர்வு முறைகளுக்கு பணம் அனுப்பப்பட்டது, ஒரு நிலையான மாற்று விகிதத்தின் நம்பகத்தன்மை இழக்கப்படுகிறது.",
        "இலங்கை வழக்கமாக உத்தியோகபூர்வ வழிகள் மூலம் மாதமொன்றுக்கு சுமார் 500 முதல் 600 மில்லியன் அமெரிக்க டொலர்களைப் பெறுகிறது.",
        "மே 2021 இல், மத்திய வங்கி அமெரிக்க டாலருக்கு 199.50 இல் நம்பகத்தன்மையற்ற பெக்கைச் செயல்படுத்தத் தொடங்கியது மற்றும் ஆகஸ்ட் 2021 இல் அதிகாரப்பூர்வ சந்தையில் இணையான மாற்று விகிதங்கள் உருவாகத் தொடங்கின.",
        "இலங்கை ரூபாய் 203 அமெரிக்க டாலருக்கு நம்பகத்தன்மையற்ற ஆப்பு ஒரு நூலால் தொங்குகிறது",
        "அமெரிக்க டொலருக்கு நிகரான இலங்கை ரூபாயின் நம்பகத்தன்மையற்ற பெக் முறிந்து 211-215",
        "ஏற்றுமதியாளர்களுக்கு அதிக விலையை வழங்க வங்கிகள் தடை செய்யப்பட்டதால், செப்டம்பரில் இருந்து பணம் அனுப்புவது கடுமையாக குறையத் தொடங்கியது.",
        "மே மாத தொடக்கத்தில் அமெரிக்க டாலருக்கு நிகரான ரூபாய் 370/380 ஆக வர்த்தகம் செய்யப்பட்டது மற்றும் மத்திய கிழக்கு மாற்று நிறுவனங்கள் திர்ஹாமுக்கு சுமார் 102 ரூபாய் வழங்குகின்றன.",
        "அமெரிக்க டாலருக்கு ஒரு புதிய நம்பகத்தன்மையற்ற ஆப்பு 360 என விதிக்கப்பட்டது. (கொழும்பு/ஜூலை11/2022)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "இலங்கை",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "42",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "ஜூன் 2022",
          "label": "DATE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கையின்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "42 சதவீதம்",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஒரு வருடம் முன்பு",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "274.1 மில்லியன் அமெரிக்க டாலர்கள்",
            "label": "MONEY"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சுமார் 500 முதல் 600 மில்லியன் அமெரிக்க டாலர்கள்",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "மே 2021",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "199.50",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "எங்களுக்கு",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆகஸ்ட் 2021",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "203",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "எங்களுக்கு",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "211",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "எங்களுக்கு",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "செப்டம்பர்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஆரம்ப மே",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "எங்களுக்கு",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "மத்திய கிழக்கு",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "திர்ஹம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "360",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "எங்களுக்கு",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}