{
  "newspaper_id": "virakesari-lk",
  "url": "http://www.virakesari.lk/article/132261",
  "time_ut": 1658803365,
  "original_lang": "ta",
  "original_title": "சீனா தொடர்பான கொள்கைகளில் அடிப்படை மாற்றம் ஏற்படாது- ரணில் சீனாவிற்கு விஜயம் மேற்கொள்ள திட்டம் - பாலித கோஹன",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "No fundamental change in policy towards China - Ranil plans to visit China - Palita Kohana",
      "author": "Rajeeban",
      "body_lines": [
        "Sri Lanka has requested China to help in trade, investment and tourism.",
        "The Sri Lankan ambassador to China said this as efforts are underway to secure a $4 million emergency aid package for Sri Lanka to recover from the economic crisis.",
        "Sri Lanka is facing its worst economic crisis since independence with a total loss of 22 million shillings in foreign exchange.",
        "Protesters angered by shortages of fuel, food and medicine have ousted Rajapaksa's ruling family from power.",
        "Ambassador Polithagohana's comment that China is important to Sri Lanka's recovery from the economic crisis reveals China's status as Sri Lanka's biggest creditor.",
        "Japan and China are the countries that have given most loans to Sri Lanka. Sri Lanka must pay 10% of its debt to China.",
        "In an interview given to Reuters at the Sri Lankan embassy in China, the Sri Lankan ambassador to China said that the Chinese government should ask Chinese companies to buy more Sri Lankan tea, gems, clothes, etc.",
        "He also called for China's import policies to be made more transparent and easier to use.",
        "He appealed to China to invest more in massive China-backed port projects in Colombo and Ambandottai, noting that China's massive investment projects have not been possible due to the Covid pandemic.",
        "In addition, Sri Lanka is expecting more tourists. The number of tourist arrivals which was 265,000 in 2018 became zero after the suicide attack of Corona.",
        "President Ranil Wickremesinghe is planning to visit China for talks on cooperation in many sectors including trade, investment and tourism, said Palitakohana.",
        "Wickramasinghe is not new to China, when he visited China in 2016 as the Prime Minister, a picture of him shaking hands with the Chinese President can be seen at the Chinese Embassy.",
        "Palitakohana said there will be no fundamental changes in the new government's China policy.",
        "Palita Kohana stated that China is in a position to help Sri Lanka immediately because China is in a position to help many other countries that are under financial crisis based on the fact that it is the main lender of the world and said that if only Sri Lanka was affected, they could have taken a decision quickly.",
        "For the past several months, Sri Lanka has been in talks with China for $4 billion in financial aid, of which $1 billion is to be repaid to China this year.",
        "Paulitha Kohana says that this loan is for the import of goods needed for Sri Lanka's income-generating garment industry.",
        "Palitakohana said that the negotiations regarding the loan with China are continuing but the next date has not been announced."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "China",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "China",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "China",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "China",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "$4 million",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "22 million",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Rajapaksa",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Polithagohana",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "China",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka's",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "China",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka's",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Japan",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "China",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "10%",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "China",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Reuters",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lankan",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "China",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lankan",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "China",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Chinese",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Chinese",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lankan",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "China",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "China",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "China",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Colombo",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ambandottai",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "China",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "265,000",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "2018",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "zero",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Corona",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "China",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Palitakohana",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Wickramasinghe",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "China",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "China",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "2016",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Chinese",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Chinese",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Palitakohana",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "China",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Palita Kohana",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "China",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "China",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the past several months",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "China",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "$4 billion",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "$1 billion",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "China",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "this year",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Paulitha Kohana",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka's",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Palitakohana",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "China",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "චීනය සම්බන්ධයෙන් ප්‍රතිපත්තියේ මූලික වෙනසක් නෑ - රනිල් චීනයේ සංචාරයක - පාලිත කොහන",
      "author": "රජීබන්",
      "body_lines": [
        "වෙළෙඳ, ආයෝජන සහ සංචාරක ක්ෂේත්‍ර සඳහා ආධාර කරන ලෙස ශ්‍රී ලංකාව චීනයෙන් ඉල්ලීමක් කර තිබේ.",
        "ආර්ථික අර්බුදයෙන් ගොඩ ඒම සඳහා ශ්‍රී ලංකාවට ඩොලර් මිලියන 4 ක හදිසි ආධාර පැකේජයක් ලබා ගැනීමට උත්සාහ කරමින් සිටින බැවින් චීනයේ ශ්‍රී ලංකා තානාපතිවරයා මේ බව පැවසීය.",
        "නිදහසින් පසු ශ්‍රී ලංකාව මුහුණ දී සිටින දරුණුතම ආර්ථික අර්බුදයට මුහුන දී සිටින්නේ සිලිං මිලියන 22ක විදේශ විනිමය අහිමි වීමෙනි.",
        "ඉන්ධන, ආහාර සහ ඖෂධ හිඟයෙන් කෝපයට පත් විරෝධතාකරුවන් රාජපක්ෂගේ පාලක පවුල බලයෙන් පහ කර ඇත.",
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකාව ආර්ථික අර්බුදයෙන් ගොඩ ඒමට චීනය වැදගත් බවට තානාපති පොලිතගොහන මහතා කළ ප්‍රකාශය ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ විශාලතම ණයකරුවා ලෙස චීනයේ තත්ත්වය හෙළිදරව් කරයි.",
        "ජපානය සහ චීනය ශ්‍රී ලංකාවට වැඩිපුරම ණය දී ඇති රටවල් වේ. ශ්‍රී ලංකාව චීනයට ණයෙන් 10%ක් ගෙවිය යුතුයි.",
        "චීනයේ ශ්‍රී ලංකා තානාපති කාර්යාලයේ රොයිටර් පුවත් සේවයට ලබා දුන් සම්මුඛ සාකච්ඡාවකදී චීනයේ ශ්‍රී ලංකා තානාපතිවරයා කියා සිටියේ ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ තේ, මැණික්, ඇඳුම් පැළඳුම් ආදිය වැඩිපුර මිලදී ගන්නා ලෙස චීන රජය චීන සමාගම්වලින් ඉල්ලා සිටිය යුතු බවයි.",
        "චීනයේ ආනයන ප්‍රතිපත්ති වඩාත් විනිවිදභාවයෙන් හා භාවිතයට පහසු කරන ලෙස ද ඔහු ඉල්ලා සිටියේය.",
        "කොවිඩ් වසංගතය හේතුවෙන් චීනයේ දැවැන්ත ආයෝජන ව්‍යාපෘති ක්‍රියාත්මක කිරීමට නොහැකි වී ඇති බව සඳහන් කළ ඔහු, කොළඹ සහ අම්බන්ඩොට්ටායි හි චීනයේ ආධාර ලබන දැවැන්ත වරාය ව්‍යාපෘති සඳහා වැඩි ආයෝජනයක් කරන ලෙස චීනයෙන් ඉල්ලා සිටියේය.",
        "මීට අමතරව, ශ්‍රී ලංකාව තවත් සංචාරකයින් අපේක්ෂා කරයි. 2018 වසරේ 265,000ක් වූ සංචාරකයින් සංඛ්‍යාව කොරෝනා මරාගෙන මැරෙන ප්‍රහාරයෙන් පසු බිංදුව බවට පත් විය.",
        "වෙළෙඳ, ආයෝජන, සංචාරක ඇතුළු ක්ෂේත්‍ර රැසක සහයෝගිතාව පිළිබඳ සාකච්ඡා සඳහා ජනාධිපති රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතා චීනයේ සංචාරයක නිරත වීමට සැලසුම් කර ඇති බව පාලිතකොහන මහතා පැවසීය.",
        "වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතා චීනයට අලුත් දෙයක් නොවේ, ඔහු 2016 වසරේ අග්‍රාමාත්‍යවරයා ලෙස චීනයේ සංචාරයක නිරත වූ අවස්ථාවේදී චීන ජනාධිපතිවරයාට අතට අත දෙන ඡායාරූපයක් චීන තානාපති කාර්යාලයේ දක්නට ලැබේ.",
        "නව රජයේ චීන ප්‍රතිපත්තියේ මූලික වෙනසක් සිදු නොවන බව පාලිතකොහන මහතා පැවසීය.",
        "ලෝකයේ ප්‍රධාන ණය දෙන්නා වීම මත මුල්‍ය අර්බුදවලට ලක්ව සිටින තවත් බොහෝ රටවලට උදව් කිරීමට චීනයට හැකි නිසා චීනය ශ්‍රී ලංකාවට වහා උදව් කළ හැකි තත්ත්වයක සිටින බව ප්‍රකාශ කළ පාලිත කොහන මහතා ශ්‍රී ලංකාව පමණක් නම් බලපෑවා, ඉක්මනින් තීරණයක් ගන්න තිබුණා.",
        "පසුගිය මාස කිහිපය තුළ ශ්‍රී ලංකාව ඩොලර් බිලියන 4 ක මූල්‍ය ආධාර සඳහා චීනය සමඟ සාකච්ඡා කළ අතර එයින් ඩොලර් බිලියනයක් මේ වසරේ චීනයට ආපසු ගෙවීමට නියමිතය.",
        "මෙම ණය මුදල ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ ආදායම් උපදවන ඇඟලුම් කර්මාන්තයට අවශ්‍ය භාණ්ඩ ආනයනය කිරීම සඳහා බව පාලිත කොහන පවසයි.",
        "පාලිතකොහන කියා සිටියේ චීනය සමඟ ණය ලබාදීම සම්බන්ධයෙන් සාකච්ඡා අඛණ්ඩව සිදුවන නමුත් මීළඟ දිනය ප්‍රකාශ කර නොමැති බවයි."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "චීනය",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "චීනය",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "චීනය",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "චීනය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඩොලර් මිලියන 4 යි",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මිලියන 22 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "පොලිතගොහන",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "චීනය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "චීනය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ජපානය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "චීනය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "10%",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "චීනය",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "රොයිටර්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලාංකික",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "චීනය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලාංකික",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "චීනය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "චීන",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "චීන",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලාංකික",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "චීනය",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "චීනය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "චීනය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "කොළඹ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "අම්බන්ඩොට්ටයි",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "චීනය",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "265,000 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "2018",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශුන්ය",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "කොරෝනා",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "චීනය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාලිතකොහන",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "චීනය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "චීනය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "2016",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "චීන",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "චීන",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "පාලිතකොහන",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "චීනය",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "පාලිත කොහන",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "චීනය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "චීනය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "පසුගිය මාස කිහිපය",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "චීනය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඩොලර් බිලියන 4 යි",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඩොලර් බිලියන 1",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "චීනය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මේ වසරේ",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "පාලිත කොහන",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "පාලිතකොහන",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "චීනය",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "சீனா தொடர்பான கொள்கைகளில் அடிப்படை மாற்றம் ஏற்படாது- ரணில் சீனாவிற்கு விஜயம் மேற்கொள்ள திட்டம் - பாலித கோஹன",
      "author": "Rajeeban",
      "body_lines": [
        "வர்த்தகம் முதலீடு மற்றும் சுற்றுலாத்துறைகளில் சீனா உதவவேண்டும் என இலங்கை வேண்டுகோள் விடுத்துள்ளது.",
        "பொருளாதார நெருக்கடியிலிருந்து மீள்வதற்காக இலங்கை 4 மில்லியன் டொலர் அவசரஉதவி திட்டத்தை பெறுவதற்கான முயற்சிகளில் ஈடுபட்டுள்ள வேளையில் சீனாவிற்கான இலங்கை தூதுவர் இதனை தெரிவித்துள்ளார்.",
        "22 மில்லியன் சனத்தொiய கொண்ட இலங்கை அந்நியசெலாவணி முற்றாக அற்றுப்போனதை தொடர்ந்து சுதந்திரத்தின் பின்னரான மோசமான பொருளாதார நெருக்கடியை எதிர்கொண்டுள்ளது.",
        "எரிபொருள் உணவு மருந்து தட்டுப்பாடு காரணமாக சீற்றமடைந்த ஆர்ப்பாட்டக்காராகள் ராஜபக்சவின் ஆளும் குடும்பத்தை அதிகாரத்திலிருந்து அகற்றியுள்ளனர்.",
        "இலங்கை பொருளாதார நெருக்கடியிலிருந்து மீள்வதற்கு சீனா முக்கியம் என்ற தூதுவர் பாலிதகோஹனவின் கருத்து இலங்கைக்கு அதிகளவு கடன்வழங்கிய நாடு என்ற சீனாவின் நிலையை வெளிப்படுத்துகின்றது.",
        "ஜப்பானும் சீனாவுமே இலங்கைக்கு அதிகளவு கடன் வழங்கிய நாடுகள் . இலங்கை தனது கடனில் பத்துவீதத்தை சீனாவிற்கு செலுத்தவேண்டும்.",
        "சீனாவில் உள்ள இலங்கை தூதரகத்தில் வைத்து ரொய்ட்டருக்கு வழங்கிய பேட்டியில்  சீனாவிற்கான இலங்கை தூதுவர் சீன நிறுவனங்கள்அதிகளவு இலங்கை தேயிலை மாணிக்கற்கள் ஆடைகள் போன்றவற்றை கொள்வனவு செய்யவேண்டும் என சீன அரசாங்கம் கேட்டுக்கொள்ளவேண்டும் என தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "சீனாவின் இறக்குமதிகொள்கைகளை அதிகளவு வெளிப்படை தன்மை மிக்கவையாகவும் பயன்படுத்துவதற்கு இலகுவானவையாகவும் மாற்றவேண்டும் எனவும் அவர் வேண்டுகோள் விடுத்தார்.",
        "கொழும்பு மற்றும் அம்பாந்தோட்டையில் உள்ள பாரிய சீனா ஆதரவுடனான துறைமுகதிட்டங்களில் சீனா மேலும் முதலீடு செய்யவேண்டும் என வேண்டுகோள் விடுத்த அவர் கொவிட் பெருந்தொற்று காரணமாக சீனாவின் பாரிய முதலீட்டு திட்டங்கள் சாத்தியமாகவில்லை என குறிப்பிட்டார்.",
        "மேலதிகமாக இலங்கை அதிகளவு சுற்றுலாப்பயணிகளை எதிர்பார்க்கின்றது. 2018 இல் 265,000 மா காணப்பட்ட சுற்றுலாப்பயணிகள் எண்ணிக்கை தற்கொலை தாக்குதல் கொரோனாவின் பின்னர் பூஜ்ஜியமாக மாறியது.",
        "வர்த்தகம் முதலீடு சுற்றுலாத்துறை உட்பட பல துறைகளில் ஒத்துழைப்பு குறித்த பேச்சுவார்த்தைகளிற்காக ஜனாதிபதி ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க சீனாவிற்கு விஜயம் மேற்கொள்ள திட்டமிட்டுள்ளார் எனவும் பாலிதகோஹன தெரிவித்துள்ளார்.",
        "விக்கிரமசிங்க சீனாவிற்கு புதியவரல்ல,2016 இல் பிரதமர் என்ற அடிப்படையில் சீனாவிற்கு விஜயம் மேற்கொண்டவேளை சீன ஜனாதிபதியுடன் அவர் கைகுலுக்கிக்கொள்ளும் படத்தை சீன தூதரகத்தில் காணமுடிகின்றது.",
        "புதிய அரசாங்கத்தின் சீனா தொடர்பான கொள்கையில்  அடிப்படை மாற்றங்கள் எதுவும் ஏற்படாது என பாலிதகோஹன தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "உலகின் முக்கிய கடன் வழங்கும் நாடு என்ற அடிப்படையில் நிதிநெருக்கடியில் சிக்கியுள்ள வேறு பல நாடுகளிற்கும் உதவவேண்டிய நிலையில் சீனா உள்ளதாலேயே இலங்கைக்கு உடனடியாக உதவ முடியாத நிலையில் சீனா உள்ளது என தெரிவித்துள்ள பாலித கோஹன இலங்கை மாத்திரம் பாதிக்கப்பட்டிருந்தால் அவர்கள் விரைவாக தீர்மானம் எடுத்திருக்கலாம் எனவும் தெரிவித்துள்ளார்.",
        "கடந்த பல மாதங்களாக சீனாவுடன் 4 பில்லியன் டொலர் நிதி உதவிக்கான பேச்சுவார்த்தைகளில் இலங்கை ஈடுபட்டுள்ளது.இதில் ஒரு பில்லியன் டொலர் இந்த வருடம் சீனாவிற்கு திரும்பி செலுத்தவேண்டிய கடனிற்கானது.",
        "இலங்கையின் வருமானம் ஈட்டித்தரும் ஆடைதொழிற்துறைக்கு தேவையான பொருட்களை இறக்குமதி செய்வதற்கே இந்த கடனுதவி என பாலித கோஹன தெரிவிக்கின்றார்.",
        "சீனாவுடன் கடனுதவி தொடர்பான பேச்சுவார்த்தைகள் தொடர்கின்றன ஆனால் அடுத்த திகதி எப்போது என அறிவிக்கப்படவில்லை என பாலிதகோஹன தெரிவித்துள்ளார்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "சீனா",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "சீனா",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சீனா",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "சீனா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "$4 மில்லியன்",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "22 மில்லியன்",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ராஜபக்சே",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பொலிதகோஹனா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "சீனா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கையின்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சீனா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கையின்",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஜப்பான்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சீனா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "10%",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "சீனா",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ராய்ட்டர்ஸ்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "சீனா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "சீனா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சீன",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "சீன",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "சீனா",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "சீனா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சீனா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "கொழும்பு",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "அம்பந்தோட்டை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சீனா",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "265,000",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "2018",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "பூஜ்யம்",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "கொரோனா",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "சீனா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாலிடகோஹனா",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "விக்கிரமாதித்தன்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "சீனா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சீனா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "2016",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சீன",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "சீன",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பாலிடகோஹனா",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "சீனா",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பாலித கொஹன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "சீனா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சீனா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "கடந்த பல மாதங்களாக",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சீனா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "$4 பில்லியன்",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "$1 பில்லியன்",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "சீனா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்த வருடம்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பாலித கொஹனா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கையின்",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பாலிடகோஹனா",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "சீனா",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}