{
  "newspaper_id": "daily-mirror-lk",
  "url": "https://www.dailymirror.lk/business-news/Tourism-sector-doing-everything-possible-to-stay-afloat/273-239787",
  "time_ut": 1656115024,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Tourism sector doing “everything possible” to stay afloat",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Tourism sector doing “everything possible” to stay afloat",
      "author": "",
      "body_lines": [
        "SLTDA chief says tourists do not experience difficulties faced by locals",
        "Industry stakeholders doing their maximum to cushion tourists from implications stemming from economic crisis",
        "Says priority is to ensure the few tourists visiting go back with a positive message",
        "“We need to speak the truth and get the facts right,” says Fernando",
        "Key authorities of Sri Lanka Tourism said they are doing “everything possible” and are exploring all avenues to pull the sector towards the positive growth trajectory, an effort that is becoming increasingly challenging as economic conditions worsen in the country.",
        "The locals are faced with the worst possible living conditions experienced in history. However, tourism sector stakeholders are stretching themselves to ensure the experiences are not witnessed by the few international tourists coming into the island nation, said Sri Lanka Tourism Development Authority (SLTDA) Chairman Priantha Fernando.",
        "“The tourists are not inconvenienced in any way due to the economic crisis that is taking place at present. The sector stakeholders, across all levels are doing the maximum to ensure the few international travellers coming in are cushioned from the crisis.",
        "“We want to make sure they go back with a positive message, and they go back with a memorable experience despite the ongoing issues in the country. That is our priority at present,” Fernando told Mirror Business.",
        "The SLTDA chief stressed that it is critical for Sri Lanka to not lose its credibility and image on the international stage, for which the reality of the country should not be hidden.",
        "“The message we need to deliver to source markets is that despite the difficulties faced, destination Sri Lanka continues to cater to its visitors, ensuring they have a positive experience. We need to speak the truth and get the facts right,” he stressed.   The ongoing ODI series between Australia and Sri Lanka is a definite positive for Sri Lanka Tourism, Fernando said, as it provides the opportunity for the sector stakeholders to showcase their potential during the crisis.   Further, while acknowledging that the government has no room to extend support to the struggling tourism sector, the SLTDA head said the industry should also not be forgotten for support measures that could be rolled out going forward. Reason being, the industry is a foreign income earner to the country and is currently in need of assistance to sustain."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "SLTDA",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "Fernando",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka Tourism",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Priantha Fernando",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "Fernando",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Mirror Business",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "SLTDA",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Australia",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka Tourism",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Fernando",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "SLTDA",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "සංචාරක අංශය නොසැලී සිටීමට \"හැකි සියල්ල\" කරයි",
      "author": "",
      "body_lines": [
        "SLTDA ප්‍රධානියා පවසන්නේ සංචාරකයින්ට ප්‍රදේශවාසීන් මුහුණ දෙන දුෂ්කරතා අත්විඳිය නොහැකි බවයි",
        "ආර්ථික අර්බුදයෙන් පැන නගින ඇඟවුම් වලින් සංචාරකයින් මුදවා ගැනීමට කර්මාන්ත පාර්ශවකරුවන් ඔවුන්ගේ උපරිමය කරයි",
        "පැමිණෙන සංචාරකයින් කිහිප දෙනෙකු ධනාත්මක පණිවිඩයක් සමඟ ආපසු යාම සහතික කිරීම ප්‍රමුඛතාවය බව පවසයි",
        "\"අපි ඇත්ත කතා කර කරුණු නිවැරදි කර ගත යුතුයි\" ප්‍රනාන්දු පවසයි",
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකා සංචාරක ව්‍යාපාරයේ ප්‍රධාන බලධාරීන් පැවසුවේ ඔවුන් “හැකි සෑම දෙයක්ම” කරමින් සිටින බවත්, රටේ ආර්ථික තත්ත්වයන් නරක අතට හැරෙන විට වඩ වඩාත් අභියෝගාත්මක වෙමින් පවතින ප්‍රයත්නයක් වන ධනාත්මක වර්ධන මාවතට ක්ෂේත්‍රය ඇද ගැනීමට සියලු මාර්ග ගවේෂණය කරමින් සිටින බවත්ය.",
        "ඉතිහාසයේ අත්විඳිය හැකි නරකම ජීවන තත්වයන්ට ප්‍රදේශවාසීන් මුහුණ දී සිටිති. කෙසේ වෙතත්, දිවයිනට පැමිණෙන ජාත්‍යන්තර සංචාරකයින් කිහිප දෙනෙකුට අත්දැකීම් නොලැබීම සහතික කිරීම සඳහා සංචාරක ක්ෂේත්‍රයේ පාර්ශවකරුවන් වෙහෙසෙමින් සිටින බව ශ්‍රී ලංකා සංචාරක සංවර්ධන අධිකාරියේ (SLTDA) සභාපති ප්‍රියන්ත ප්‍රනාන්දු මහතා පැවසීය.",
        "“දැනට ඇතිවී තිබෙන ආර්ථික අර්බුදය නිසා සංචාරකයන් කිසිම අයුරකින් අපහසුතාවයට පත්වෙලා නැහැ. ජාත්‍යන්තර සංචාරකයින් කිහිප දෙනෙකු අර්බුදයෙන් මිදීම සහතික කිරීම සඳහා සෑම තරාතිරමකම අංශයේ පාර්ශවකරුවන් උපරිමයෙන් කටයුතු කරයි.",
        "“අපට අවශ්‍ය වන්නේ ඔවුන් ධනාත්මක පණිවිඩයක් සමඟ ආපසු යන බවට සහතික කර ගැනීමටත්, රටේ පවතින ප්‍රශ්න නොතකා ඔවුන් අමතක නොවන අත්දැකීමක් සමඟින් ආපසු යන බවත්ය. දැනට අපේ ප්‍රමුඛතාවය එයයි,” ප්‍රනාන්දු මිරර් බිස්නස් වෙත පැවසීය.",
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවට ජාත්‍යන්තර තලයේ ඇති විශ්වසනීයත්වය සහ ප්‍රතිරූපය නැති කර නොගැනීම ඉතා වැදගත් බවත් ඒ සඳහා රටේ යථාර්ථය සැඟවිය යුතු නැති බවත් SLTDA ප්‍රධානියා අවධාරණය කළේය.",
        "“අප විසින් මූලාශ්‍ර වෙළඳපල වෙත ලබා දිය යුතු පණිවිඩය නම්, මුහුණ දෙන දුෂ්කරතා මධ්‍යයේ වුවද, ගමනාන්තය වන ශ්‍රී ලංකාව සිය අමුත්තන්ට ධනාත්මක අත්දැකීමක් ඇති බව සහතික කරමින්, ගමනාන්තය අඛණ්ඩව ඔවුන් වෙත ලබා දෙන බවයි. අපි ඇත්ත කතා කර කරුණු නිවැරැදි කර ගත යුතුයි,” ඔහු අවධාරණය කළේය. ඔස්ට්‍රේලියාව සහ ශ්‍රී ලංකාව අතර දැනට පැවැත්වෙන එක්දින තරඟාවලිය ශ්‍රී ලංකා සංචාරක ක්ෂේත්‍රයට නියත සාධනීය අවස්ථාවක් බව ප්‍රනාන්දු ප්‍රකාශ කළේ, අර්බුදකාරී අවස්ථාවේදී ක්ෂේත්‍රයේ පාර්ශවකරුවන්ට තම හැකියාවන් ප්‍රදර්ශනය කිරීමට එය අවස්ථාව සලසන බැවිනි. තවද, අරගලකාරී සංචාරක ක්ෂේත්‍රයට සහය දැක්වීමට රජයට ඉඩක් නොමැති බව පිළිගන්නා අතරම, SLTDA ප්‍රධානියා කියා සිටියේ, ඉදිරියට ගෙන යා හැකි සහාය ක්‍රියාමාර්ග සඳහා කර්මාන්තය ද අමතක නොකළ යුතු බවයි. හේතුව, මෙම කර්මාන්තය රටට විදේශ ආදායම් උපදවන ආයතනයක් වන අතර එය පවත්වාගෙන යාමට දැනට සහාය අවශ්‍ය වේ."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "SLTDA",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "ප්‍රනාන්දු",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකා සංචාරක ව්‍යාපාරය",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ප්‍රියන්ත ප්‍රනාන්දු",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "ප්‍රනාන්දු",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "මිරර් ව්‍යාපාරය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "SLTDA",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඕස්ට්රේලියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකා සංචාරක ව්‍යාපාරය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ප්‍රනාන්දු",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "SLTDA",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "சுற்றுலாத் துறையானது மிதமிஞ்சிய நிலையில் இருக்க \"முடிந்த அனைத்தையும்\" செய்கிறது",
      "author": "",
      "body_lines": [
        "உள்ளூர் மக்கள் எதிர்கொள்ளும் சிரமங்களை சுற்றுலாப் பயணிகள் அனுபவிப்பதில்லை என்று SLTDA தலைவர் கூறுகிறார்",
        "தொழில்துறை பங்குதாரர்கள் பொருளாதார நெருக்கடியில் இருந்து வரும் தாக்கங்களில் இருந்து சுற்றுலாப் பயணிகளை தங்களால் முடிந்தளவு செய்கிறார்கள்",
        "வருகை தரும் சில சுற்றுலாப் பயணிகள் நேர்மறையான செய்தியுடன் திரும்பிச் செல்வதை உறுதி செய்வதே முன்னுரிமை என்று கூறுகிறார்",
        "\"நாம் உண்மையைப் பேச வேண்டும் மற்றும் உண்மைகளை சரியாகப் பெற வேண்டும்\" என்று பெர்னாண்டோ கூறுகிறார்",
        "இலங்கை சுற்றுலாத்துறையின் முக்கிய அதிகாரிகள், தாங்கள் \"சாத்தியமான அனைத்தையும்\" செய்து வருவதாகவும், நாட்டின் பொருளாதார நிலைமைகள் மோசமடைந்து வருவதால், இத்துறையை சாதகமான வளர்ச்சிப் பாதையை நோக்கி இழுப்பதற்கான அனைத்து வழிகளையும் ஆராய்ந்து வருவதாகவும் தெரிவித்தனர்.",
        "உள்ளூர் மக்கள் வரலாற்றில் அனுபவித்த மிக மோசமான வாழ்க்கை நிலைமைகளை எதிர்கொண்டுள்ளனர். எவ்வாறாயினும், தீவு நாட்டிற்கு வரும் சில சர்வதேச சுற்றுலாப் பயணிகளால் அனுபவங்கள் காணப்படுவதில்லை என்பதை உறுதிப்படுத்த சுற்றுலாத் துறை பங்குதாரர்கள் தங்களை விரிவுபடுத்துகின்றனர் என்று இலங்கை சுற்றுலா அபிவிருத்தி அதிகார சபையின் (SLTDA) தலைவர் பிரியந்த பெர்னாண்டோ தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "“தற்போது நிலவும் பொருளாதார நெருக்கடியால் சுற்றுலாப் பயணிகள் எந்தவிதத்திலும் அசௌகரியம் அடையவில்லை. அனைத்து மட்டங்களிலும் உள்ள துறை பங்குதாரர்கள், வரும் சில சர்வதேச பயணிகள் நெருக்கடியிலிருந்து விடுபடுவதை உறுதிசெய்ய அதிகபட்சமாகச் செய்கிறார்கள்.",
        "\"அவர்கள் ஒரு நேர்மறையான செய்தியுடன் திரும்பிச் செல்வதை நாங்கள் உறுதிசெய்ய விரும்புகிறோம், மேலும் நாட்டில் நடந்துகொண்டிருக்கும் பிரச்சினைகள் இருந்தபோதிலும் அவர்கள் மறக்கமுடியாத அனுபவத்துடன் திரும்பிச் செல்கிறார்கள். அதுவே தற்போது எங்களின் முன்னுரிமை” என பெர்னாண்டோ Mirror Business இடம் தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "சர்வதேச அரங்கில் இலங்கை தனது நம்பகத்தன்மையையும் இமேஜையும் இழக்காமல் இருப்பது மிகவும் முக்கியமானது என்றும், அதற்காக நாட்டின் யதார்த்தத்தை மறைக்கக் கூடாது என்றும் SLTDA தலைவர் வலியுறுத்தினார்.",
        "\"மூலச் சந்தைகளுக்கு நாம் வழங்க வேண்டிய செய்தி என்னவென்றால், சிரமங்களை எதிர்கொண்ட போதிலும், இலக்கு இலங்கை அதன் பார்வையாளர்களை தொடர்ந்து பூர்த்திசெய்து, அவர்களுக்கு நேர்மறையான அனுபவத்தை உறுதிசெய்கிறது. நாம் உண்மையைப் பேச வேண்டும், உண்மைகளை சரியாகப் பெற வேண்டும்,” என்று அவர் வலியுறுத்தினார். அவுஸ்திரேலியாவுக்கும் இலங்கைக்கும் இடையில் நடைபெற்று வரும் ஒருநாள் தொடர் இலங்கை சுற்றுலாத்துறைக்கு ஒரு நிச்சயமான சாதகமாக உள்ளது, நெருக்கடியின் போது துறைசார் பங்குதாரர்கள் தங்கள் திறனை வெளிப்படுத்த வாய்ப்பளிப்பதாக பெர்னாண்டோ கூறினார். மேலும், போராடும் சுற்றுலாத் துறைக்கு ஆதரவை வழங்குவதற்கு அரசாங்கத்திற்கு இடமில்லை என்பதை ஒப்புக்கொண்ட SLTDA தலைவர், முன்னோக்கிச் செல்லக்கூடிய ஆதரவு நடவடிக்கைகளுக்காக தொழில்துறையையும் மறந்துவிடக் கூடாது என்றார். காரணம், இத்தொழில் நாட்டிற்கு வெளிநாட்டு வருமானம் ஈட்டித் தரும் ஒரு தொழிலாக இருப்பதால், அதை நிலைநிறுத்துவதற்கு தற்போது உதவி தேவைப்படுகிறது."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "SLTDA",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "பெர்னாண்டோ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை சுற்றுலா",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "பிரியந்த பெர்னாண்டோ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "பெர்னாண்டோ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "கண்ணாடி வணிகம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "SLTDA",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆஸ்திரேலியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை சுற்றுலா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "பெர்னாண்டோ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "SLTDA",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  },
  "title": "Tourism sector doing “everything possible” to stay afloat",
  "body_lines": [
    "SLTDA chief says tourists do not experience difficulties faced by locals",
    "Industry stakeholders doing their maximum to cushion tourists from implications stemming from economic crisis",
    "Says priority is to ensure the few tourists visiting go back with a positive message",
    "“We need to speak the truth and get the facts right,” says Fernando",
    "Key authorities of Sri Lanka Tourism said they are doing “everything possible” and are exploring all avenues to pull the sector towards the positive growth trajectory, an effort that is becoming increasingly challenging as economic conditions worsen in the country.",
    "The locals are faced with the worst possible living conditions experienced in history. However, tourism sector stakeholders are stretching themselves to ensure the experiences are not witnessed by the few international tourists coming into the island nation, said Sri Lanka Tourism Development Authority (SLTDA) Chairman Priantha Fernando.",
    "“The tourists are not inconvenienced in any way due to the economic crisis that is taking place at present. The sector stakeholders, across all levels are doing the maximum to ensure the few international travellers coming in are cushioned from the crisis.",
    "“We want to make sure they go back with a positive message, and they go back with a memorable experience despite the ongoing issues in the country. That is our priority at present,” Fernando told Mirror Business.",
    "The SLTDA chief stressed that it is critical for Sri Lanka to not lose its credibility and image on the international stage, for which the reality of the country should not be hidden.",
    "“The message we need to deliver to source markets is that despite the difficulties faced, destination Sri Lanka continues to cater to its visitors, ensuring they have a positive experience. We need to speak the truth and get the facts right,” he stressed.   The ongoing ODI series between Australia and Sri Lanka is a definite positive for Sri Lanka Tourism, Fernando said, as it provides the opportunity for the sector stakeholders to showcase their potential during the crisis.   Further, while acknowledging that the government has no room to extend support to the struggling tourism sector, the SLTDA head said the industry should also not be forgotten for support measures that could be rolled out going forward. Reason being, the industry is a foreign income earner to the country and is currently in need of assistance to sustain."
  ],
  "translate": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Tourism sector doing “everything possible” to stay afloat",
      "author": "",
      "body_lines": [
        "SLTDA chief says tourists do not experience difficulties faced by locals",
        "Industry stakeholders doing their maximum to cushion tourists from implications stemming from economic crisis",
        "Says priority is to ensure the few tourists visiting go back with a positive message",
        "“We need to speak the truth and get the facts right,” says Fernando",
        "Key authorities of Sri Lanka Tourism said they are doing “everything possible” and are exploring all avenues to pull the sector towards the positive growth trajectory, an effort that is becoming increasingly challenging as economic conditions worsen in the country.",
        "The locals are faced with the worst possible living conditions experienced in history. However, tourism sector stakeholders are stretching themselves to ensure the experiences are not witnessed by the few international tourists coming into the island nation, said Sri Lanka Tourism Development Authority (SLTDA) Chairman Priantha Fernando.",
        "“The tourists are not inconvenienced in any way due to the economic crisis that is taking place at present. The sector stakeholders, across all levels are doing the maximum to ensure the few international travellers coming in are cushioned from the crisis.",
        "“We want to make sure they go back with a positive message, and they go back with a memorable experience despite the ongoing issues in the country. That is our priority at present,” Fernando told Mirror Business.",
        "The SLTDA chief stressed that it is critical for Sri Lanka to not lose its credibility and image on the international stage, for which the reality of the country should not be hidden.",
        "“The message we need to deliver to source markets is that despite the difficulties faced, destination Sri Lanka continues to cater to its visitors, ensuring they have a positive experience. We need to speak the truth and get the facts right,” he stressed.   The ongoing ODI series between Australia and Sri Lanka is a definite positive for Sri Lanka Tourism, Fernando said, as it provides the opportunity for the sector stakeholders to showcase their potential during the crisis.   Further, while acknowledging that the government has no room to extend support to the struggling tourism sector, the SLTDA head said the industry should also not be forgotten for support measures that could be rolled out going forward. Reason being, the industry is a foreign income earner to the country and is currently in need of assistance to sustain."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "SLTDA",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "Fernando",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka Tourism",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Priantha Fernando",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "Fernando",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Mirror Business",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "SLTDA",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Australia",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka Tourism",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Fernando",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "SLTDA",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "සංචාරක අංශය නොසැලී සිටීමට \"හැකි සියල්ල\" කරයි",
      "author": "",
      "body_lines": [
        "SLTDA ප්‍රධානියා පවසන්නේ සංචාරකයින්ට ප්‍රදේශවාසීන් මුහුණ දෙන දුෂ්කරතා අත්විඳිය නොහැකි බවයි",
        "ආර්ථික අර්බුදයෙන් පැන නගින ඇඟවුම් වලින් සංචාරකයින් මුදවා ගැනීමට කර්මාන්ත පාර්ශවකරුවන් ඔවුන්ගේ උපරිමය කරයි",
        "පැමිණෙන සංචාරකයින් කිහිප දෙනෙකු ධනාත්මක පණිවිඩයක් සමඟ ආපසු යාම සහතික කිරීම ප්‍රමුඛතාවය බව පවසයි",
        "\"අපි ඇත්ත කතා කර කරුණු නිවැරදි කර ගත යුතුයි\" ප්‍රනාන්දු පවසයි",
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකා සංචාරක ව්‍යාපාරයේ ප්‍රධාන බලධාරීන් පැවසුවේ ඔවුන් “හැකි සෑම දෙයක්ම” කරමින් සිටින බවත්, රටේ ආර්ථික තත්ත්වයන් නරක අතට හැරෙන විට වඩ වඩාත් අභියෝගාත්මක වෙමින් පවතින ප්‍රයත්නයක් වන ධනාත්මක වර්ධන මාවතට ක්ෂේත්‍රය ඇද ගැනීමට සියලු මාර්ග ගවේෂණය කරමින් සිටින බවත්ය.",
        "ඉතිහාසයේ අත්විඳිය හැකි නරකම ජීවන තත්වයන්ට ප්‍රදේශවාසීන් මුහුණ දී සිටිති. කෙසේ වෙතත්, දිවයිනට පැමිණෙන ජාත්‍යන්තර සංචාරකයින් කිහිප දෙනෙකුට අත්දැකීම් නොලැබීම සහතික කිරීම සඳහා සංචාරක ක්ෂේත්‍රයේ පාර්ශවකරුවන් වෙහෙසෙමින් සිටින බව ශ්‍රී ලංකා සංචාරක සංවර්ධන අධිකාරියේ (SLTDA) සභාපති ප්‍රියන්ත ප්‍රනාන්දු මහතා පැවසීය.",
        "“දැනට ඇතිවී තිබෙන ආර්ථික අර්බුදය නිසා සංචාරකයන් කිසිම අයුරකින් අපහසුතාවයට පත්වෙලා නැහැ. ජාත්‍යන්තර සංචාරකයින් කිහිප දෙනෙකු අර්බුදයෙන් මිදීම සහතික කිරීම සඳහා සෑම තරාතිරමකම අංශයේ පාර්ශවකරුවන් උපරිමයෙන් කටයුතු කරයි.",
        "“අපට අවශ්‍ය වන්නේ ඔවුන් ධනාත්මක පණිවිඩයක් සමඟ ආපසු යන බවට සහතික කර ගැනීමටත්, රටේ පවතින ප්‍රශ්න නොතකා ඔවුන් අමතක නොවන අත්දැකීමක් සමඟින් ආපසු යන බවත්ය. දැනට අපේ ප්‍රමුඛතාවය එයයි,” ප්‍රනාන්දු මිරර් බිස්නස් වෙත පැවසීය.",
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවට ජාත්‍යන්තර තලයේ ඇති විශ්වසනීයත්වය සහ ප්‍රතිරූපය නැති කර නොගැනීම ඉතා වැදගත් බවත් ඒ සඳහා රටේ යථාර්ථය සැඟවිය යුතු නැති බවත් SLTDA ප්‍රධානියා අවධාරණය කළේය.",
        "“අප විසින් මූලාශ්‍ර වෙළඳපල වෙත ලබා දිය යුතු පණිවිඩය නම්, මුහුණ දෙන දුෂ්කරතා මධ්‍යයේ වුවද, ගමනාන්තය වන ශ්‍රී ලංකාව සිය අමුත්තන්ට ධනාත්මක අත්දැකීමක් ඇති බව සහතික කරමින්, ගමනාන්තය අඛණ්ඩව ඔවුන් වෙත ලබා දෙන බවයි. අපි ඇත්ත කතා කර කරුණු නිවැරැදි කර ගත යුතුයි,” ඔහු අවධාරණය කළේය. ඔස්ට්‍රේලියාව සහ ශ්‍රී ලංකාව අතර දැනට පැවැත්වෙන එක්දින තරඟාවලිය ශ්‍රී ලංකා සංචාරක ක්ෂේත්‍රයට නියත සාධනීය අවස්ථාවක් බව ප්‍රනාන්දු ප්‍රකාශ කළේ, අර්බුදකාරී අවස්ථාවේදී ක්ෂේත්‍රයේ පාර්ශවකරුවන්ට තම හැකියාවන් ප්‍රදර්ශනය කිරීමට එය අවස්ථාව සලසන බැවිනි. තවද, අරගලකාරී සංචාරක ක්ෂේත්‍රයට සහය දැක්වීමට රජයට ඉඩක් නොමැති බව පිළිගන්නා අතරම, SLTDA ප්‍රධානියා කියා සිටියේ, ඉදිරියට ගෙන යා හැකි සහාය ක්‍රියාමාර්ග සඳහා කර්මාන්තය ද අමතක නොකළ යුතු බවයි. හේතුව, මෙම කර්මාන්තය රටට විදේශ ආදායම් උපදවන ආයතනයක් වන අතර එය පවත්වාගෙන යාමට දැනට සහාය අවශ්‍ය වේ."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "SLTDA",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "ප්‍රනාන්දු",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකා සංචාරක ව්‍යාපාරය",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ප්‍රියන්ත ප්‍රනාන්දු",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "ප්‍රනාන්දු",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "මිරර් ව්‍යාපාරය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "SLTDA",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඕස්ට්රේලියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකා සංචාරක ව්‍යාපාරය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ප්‍රනාන්දු",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "SLTDA",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "சுற்றுலாத் துறையானது மிதமிஞ்சிய நிலையில் இருக்க \"முடிந்த அனைத்தையும்\" செய்கிறது",
      "author": "",
      "body_lines": [
        "உள்ளூர் மக்கள் எதிர்கொள்ளும் சிரமங்களை சுற்றுலாப் பயணிகள் அனுபவிப்பதில்லை என்று SLTDA தலைவர் கூறுகிறார்",
        "தொழில்துறை பங்குதாரர்கள் பொருளாதார நெருக்கடியில் இருந்து வரும் தாக்கங்களில் இருந்து சுற்றுலாப் பயணிகளை தங்களால் முடிந்தளவு செய்கிறார்கள்",
        "வருகை தரும் சில சுற்றுலாப் பயணிகள் நேர்மறையான செய்தியுடன் திரும்பிச் செல்வதை உறுதி செய்வதே முன்னுரிமை என்று கூறுகிறார்",
        "\"நாம் உண்மையைப் பேச வேண்டும் மற்றும் உண்மைகளை சரியாகப் பெற வேண்டும்\" என்று பெர்னாண்டோ கூறுகிறார்",
        "இலங்கை சுற்றுலாத்துறையின் முக்கிய அதிகாரிகள், தாங்கள் \"சாத்தியமான அனைத்தையும்\" செய்து வருவதாகவும், நாட்டின் பொருளாதார நிலைமைகள் மோசமடைந்து வருவதால், இத்துறையை சாதகமான வளர்ச்சிப் பாதையை நோக்கி இழுப்பதற்கான அனைத்து வழிகளையும் ஆராய்ந்து வருவதாகவும் தெரிவித்தனர்.",
        "உள்ளூர் மக்கள் வரலாற்றில் அனுபவித்த மிக மோசமான வாழ்க்கை நிலைமைகளை எதிர்கொண்டுள்ளனர். எவ்வாறாயினும், தீவு நாட்டிற்கு வரும் சில சர்வதேச சுற்றுலாப் பயணிகளால் அனுபவங்கள் காணப்படுவதில்லை என்பதை உறுதிப்படுத்த சுற்றுலாத் துறை பங்குதாரர்கள் தங்களை விரிவுபடுத்துகின்றனர் என்று இலங்கை சுற்றுலா அபிவிருத்தி அதிகார சபையின் (SLTDA) தலைவர் பிரியந்த பெர்னாண்டோ தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "“தற்போது நிலவும் பொருளாதார நெருக்கடியால் சுற்றுலாப் பயணிகள் எந்தவிதத்திலும் அசௌகரியம் அடையவில்லை. அனைத்து மட்டங்களிலும் உள்ள துறை பங்குதாரர்கள், வரும் சில சர்வதேச பயணிகள் நெருக்கடியிலிருந்து விடுபடுவதை உறுதிசெய்ய அதிகபட்சமாகச் செய்கிறார்கள்.",
        "\"அவர்கள் ஒரு நேர்மறையான செய்தியுடன் திரும்பிச் செல்வதை நாங்கள் உறுதிசெய்ய விரும்புகிறோம், மேலும் நாட்டில் நடந்துகொண்டிருக்கும் பிரச்சினைகள் இருந்தபோதிலும் அவர்கள் மறக்கமுடியாத அனுபவத்துடன் திரும்பிச் செல்கிறார்கள். அதுவே தற்போது எங்களின் முன்னுரிமை” என பெர்னாண்டோ Mirror Business இடம் தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "சர்வதேச அரங்கில் இலங்கை தனது நம்பகத்தன்மையையும் இமேஜையும் இழக்காமல் இருப்பது மிகவும் முக்கியமானது என்றும், அதற்காக நாட்டின் யதார்த்தத்தை மறைக்கக் கூடாது என்றும் SLTDA தலைவர் வலியுறுத்தினார்.",
        "\"மூலச் சந்தைகளுக்கு நாம் வழங்க வேண்டிய செய்தி என்னவென்றால், சிரமங்களை எதிர்கொண்ட போதிலும், இலக்கு இலங்கை அதன் பார்வையாளர்களை தொடர்ந்து பூர்த்திசெய்து, அவர்களுக்கு நேர்மறையான அனுபவத்தை உறுதிசெய்கிறது. நாம் உண்மையைப் பேச வேண்டும், உண்மைகளை சரியாகப் பெற வேண்டும்,” என்று அவர் வலியுறுத்தினார். அவுஸ்திரேலியாவுக்கும் இலங்கைக்கும் இடையில் நடைபெற்று வரும் ஒருநாள் தொடர் இலங்கை சுற்றுலாத்துறைக்கு ஒரு நிச்சயமான சாதகமாக உள்ளது, நெருக்கடியின் போது துறைசார் பங்குதாரர்கள் தங்கள் திறனை வெளிப்படுத்த வாய்ப்பளிப்பதாக பெர்னாண்டோ கூறினார். மேலும், போராடும் சுற்றுலாத் துறைக்கு ஆதரவை வழங்குவதற்கு அரசாங்கத்திற்கு இடமில்லை என்பதை ஒப்புக்கொண்ட SLTDA தலைவர், முன்னோக்கிச் செல்லக்கூடிய ஆதரவு நடவடிக்கைகளுக்காக தொழில்துறையையும் மறந்துவிடக் கூடாது என்றார். காரணம், இத்தொழில் நாட்டிற்கு வெளிநாட்டு வருமானம் ஈட்டித் தரும் ஒரு தொழிலாக இருப்பதால், அதை நிலைநிறுத்துவதற்கு தற்போது உதவி தேவைப்படுகிறது."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "SLTDA",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "பெர்னாண்டோ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை சுற்றுலா",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "பிரியந்த பெர்னாண்டோ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "பெர்னாண்டோ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "கண்ணாடி வணிகம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "SLTDA",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆஸ்திரேலியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை சுற்றுலா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "பெர்னாண்டோ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "SLTDA",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}