{
  "newspaper_id": "daily-ft-lk",
  "url": "https://www.ft.lk/news/Ranjan-apologises-profusely-to-CJ-SC-ahead-of-release/56-739105",
  "time_ut": 1661469028,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Ranjan apologises ‘profusely’ to CJ, SC ahead of release",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Ranjan apologises ‘profusely’ to CJ, SC ahead of release",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "Apologises to CJ and entire judiciary for derogatory and contemptuous statement",
        "Former Minister and Samagi Jana Balawegaya MP Ranjan Ramanayake has apologised to the courts through an affidavit on the comments he made about the conduct of judges that led to his incarceration after being found guilty of being in contempt.",
        "Ramanayake filed the affidavit containing his apology before courts yesterday after the Justice Minister Wijeyadasa Rajapakshe recommended his release from prison recently under a Presidential pardon subject to the condition that he expressed his regret over the comments made.",
        "In the affidavit, Ramanayake apologised to the court with regard to both contempt of court cases filed against him. He said having reflected deeply upon the statement, he admits it was completely and utterly false adding that it was also derogatory and contemptuous in nature to the entire judiciary including the Chief Justice.",
        "In it Ramanayake requested the forgiveness of the entire judiciary for the comments made by him on 21 August 2017 outside the Temple Trees and said he apologises humbly and profusely without any reservation to the Chief Justice and the judges of the Supreme Court, Appellate courts and others. Ramanayake also admitted he was in the wrong to say on several occasions that he would not withdraw the statement made by him.",
        "The former MP also assured the courts he would not make similar statements critical or derogatory in nature about the courts in the future.",
        "Following this submission, it is reported that Ramanayake will be released from the Welikada Prison where he is being housed shortly. Minister Harin Fernando in a tweet said it is likely Ramanayake will be released from prison either today or on Monday.",
        "Fernando said Ramanayake is being released after a request made by him and Minister Manusha Nanayakkara along with others to President Ranil Wickremesinghe. Fernando also thanked Justice Minister Wijeyadasa Rajapakshe for his tireless efforts to ensure Ramanayke’s release."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "SC",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "CJ",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Samagi",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ranjan Ramanayake",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "yesterday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Justice",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Wijeyadasa Rajapakshe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Ramanayake",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Ramanayake",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "21 August 2017",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Supreme Court",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Appellate",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ramanayake",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "Ramanayake",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Welikada Prison",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "Harin Fernando",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ramanayake",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Monday",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Ramanayake",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Manusha Nanayakkara",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Fernando",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Justice",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Wijeyadasa Rajapakshe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ramanayke",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "නිදහස් වීමට පෙර රංජන් CJ, SC ගෙන් ‘බොහෝ දුරට’ සමාව ඉල්ලයි",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "අවමන් සහගත සහ අපහාසාත්මක ප්‍රකාශයක් සම්බන්ධයෙන් අගවිනිසුරුවරයාගෙන් සහ සමස්ත අධිකරණයෙන් සමාව අයදියි",
        "අධිකරණයට අපහාස කිරීමේ චෝදනාවට වරදකරු වී සිරගත කිරීමට හේතු වූ විනිසුරුවරුන්ගේ හැසිරීම සම්බන්ධයෙන් තමන් කළ ප්‍රකාශය සම්බන්ධයෙන් හිටපු අමාත්‍ය සහ සමගි ජන බලවේගයේ පාර්ලිමේන්තු මන්ත්‍රී රන්ජන් රාමනායක දිවුරුම් ප්‍රකාශයක් මගින් අධිකරණයෙන් සමාව ඉල්ලා තිබේ.",
        "අධිකරණ අමාත්‍ය විජයදාස රාජපක්ෂ විසින් පසුගියදා ජනාධිපති සමාව යටතේ බන්ධනාගාරයෙන් මුදා හැරීමට නිර්දේශ කිරීමෙන් පසු රාමනායක ඊයේ අධිකරණය හමුවේ සමාව අයැදීම ඇතුළත් දිවුරුම් ප්‍රකාශය ගොනු කළේ තමන් කළ ප්‍රකාශ සම්බන්ධයෙන් කනගාටුව ප්‍රකාශ කිරීමේ කොන්දේසියට යටත්ව ය.",
        "එම දිවුරුම් ප්‍රකාශයෙන් රාමනායක තමන්ට එරෙහිව පවරා ඇති අධිකරණයට අපහාස කිරීමේ නඩු දෙකම සම්බන්ධයෙන් අධිකරණයෙන් සමාව අයැද සිටියේය. එම ප්‍රකාශය පිළිබඳව ගැඹුරින් සිතා බැලීමෙන් පසු එය සම්පූර්ණයෙන් සහ සම්පූර්ණයෙන් අසත්‍ය බව පිළිගන්නා බවත් එය අගවිනිසුරුවරයා ඇතුළු සමස්ත අධිකරණයටම අවමන් සහගත සහ නින්දා සහගත බවත් ඔහු පැවසීය.",
        "එහි දී රාමනායක මහතා 2017 අගෝස්තු 21 වැනිදා අරලියගහ මන්දිරයෙන් පිටතදී තමන් කළ ප්‍රකාශය සම්බන්ධයෙන් සමස්ත අධිකරණයෙන් සමාව ඉල්ලා සිටි අතර අගවිනිසුරුවරයාගෙන් සහ ශ්‍රේෂ්ඨාධිකරණ විනිසුරුවරුන්ගෙන්, අභියාචනාධිකරණ විනිසුරුවරුන්ගෙන් සහ අනෙකුත් අයගෙන් කිසිදු වෙනසක් නොකර නිහතමානීව සහ බලවත් ලෙස සමාව අයදින බවද රාමනායක මහතා ප්‍රකාශ කළේය. . තමන් කළ ප්‍රකාශය ඉල්ලා අස්කර නොගන්නා බවට අවස්ථා කිහිපයකදී ප්‍රකාශ කිරීම වැරදි බව රාමනායක ද පිළිගත්තේය.",
        "ඉදිරියේදී අධිකරණය සම්බන්ධයෙන් මෙවැනි විවේචනාත්මක හෝ අවමන් සහගත ප්‍රකාශ සිදු නොකරන බවටද හිටපු මන්ත්‍රීවරයා අධිකරණයට සහතික විය.",
        "මෙම කරුණු දැක්වීමෙන් පසු රාමනායක මහතා ළඟදීම ඔහු රඳවා සිටින වැලිකඩ බන්ධනාගාරයෙන් නිදහස් කිරීමට නියමිත බව වාර්තා වේ. අමාත්‍ය හරීන් ප්‍රනාන්දු ට්විටර් පණිවුඩයක් නිකුත් කරමින් කියා සිටියේ රාමනායක මහතා අද හෝ සඳුදා බන්ධනාගාරයෙන් නිදහස් වීමට ඉඩ ඇති බවයි.",
        "තමන් සහ මනූෂ නානායක්කාර අමාත්‍යවරයා ඇතුළු පිරිසක් ජනාධිපති රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතාගෙන් කළ ඉල්ලීමකට අනුව රාමනායක මහතා නිදහස් කරන බව ප්‍රනාන්දු මහතා පැවසීය. රාමනායක මහතා නිදහස් කර ගැනීම සඳහා දරන ලද නොපසුබස්නා උත්සාහයට ප්‍රනාන්දු මහතා අධිකරණ අමාත්‍ය විජයදාස රාජපක්ෂ මහතාට ස්තුතිය පුද කළේය."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "SC",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "CJ",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "සමගි",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "රන්ජන් රාමනායක",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ඊයේ",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "යුක්තිය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "විජයදාස රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "රාමනායක",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "රාමනායක",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "2017 අගෝස්තු 21",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රේෂ්ඨාධිකරණය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "අභියාචනය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "රාමනායක",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "රාමනායක",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "වැලිකඩ බන්ධනාගාරය",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "හරීන් ප්‍රනාන්දු",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "රාමනායක",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "සඳුදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "රාමනායක",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "මනූෂ නානායක්කාර",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ප්‍රනාන්දු",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "යුක්තිය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "විජයදාස රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "රාමනායක",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "விடுதலைக்கு முன்னதாக CJ, SC யிடம் ரஞ்சன் மன்னிப்பு கேட்கிறார்",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "இழிவான மற்றும் அவமதிப்பு அறிக்கைக்காக தலைமை நீதிபதி மற்றும் முழு நீதித்துறையிடம் மன்னிப்பு கேட்கிறேன்",
        "முன்னாள் அமைச்சரும், சமகி ஜன பலவேகய பாராளுமன்ற உறுப்பினருமான ரஞ்சன் ராமநாயக்க, நீதிமன்ற அவமதிப்பு வழக்கில் குற்றவாளியாக நிரூபிக்கப்பட்டதன் பின்னர், தம்மை சிறையில் அடைக்க வழிவகுத்த நீதிபதிகளின் நடத்தை குறித்து தெரிவித்த கருத்துக்கு, நீதிமன்றில் மன்னிப்பு கோரியுள்ளார்.",
        "நீதியமைச்சர் விஜயதாச ராஜபக்ஷ, ஜனாதிபதியின் பொது மன்னிப்பின் கீழ் சிறையில் இருந்து விடுவிக்கப்பட வேண்டுமென பரிந்துரைத்ததையடுத்து ராமநாயக்க நேற்று மன்னிப்பு கோரிய பிரமாண பத்திரத்தை நீதிமன்றில் தாக்கல் செய்தார்.",
        "அந்த வாக்குமூலத்தில், தமக்கு எதிராக தொடரப்பட்ட நீதிமன்ற அவமதிப்பு வழக்குகள் தொடர்பாக ராமநாயக்க நீதிமன்றத்தில் மன்னிப்பு கோரினார். இந்த அறிக்கையை ஆழ்ந்து சிந்தித்துப் பார்த்த அவர், இது முற்றிலும் தவறானது என்பதை ஒப்புக்கொள்கிறேன் என்று கூறிய அவர், இது தலைமை நீதிபதி உட்பட முழு நீதித்துறையையும் இழிவுபடுத்துவதாகவும், இழிவானதாகவும் இருந்தது என்றும் கூறினார்.",
        "அதில், 2017 ஆகஸ்ட் 21 அன்று அலரி மாளிகைக்கு வெளியே தாம் தெரிவித்த கருத்துக்களுக்காக முழு நீதித்துறையினரிடமும் மன்னிப்புக் கோரிய ராமநாயக்க, பிரதம நீதியரசர் மற்றும் உச்ச நீதிமன்ற நீதிபதிகள், மேன்முறையீட்டு நீதிமன்றங்கள் மற்றும் பிறரிடம் எவ்வித இடஒதுக்கீடும் இன்றி தாழ்மையுடன் மன்னிப்புக் கோருவதாகக் கூறினார். . ராமநாயக்கவும் தாம் கூறிய அறிக்கையை வாபஸ் பெறப் போவதில்லை என பல சந்தர்ப்பங்களில் கூறியது தவறு என ஒப்புக்கொண்டார்.",
        "எதிர்காலத்தில் நீதிமன்றங்களைப் பற்றி விமர்சிக்கவோ அல்லது இழிவுபடுத்தும் வகையிலோ இதுபோன்ற அறிக்கைகளை வெளியிட மாட்டோம் என்று முன்னாள் எம்.பி.",
        "இந்த சமர்ப்பிப்பை தொடர்ந்து ராமநாயக்க விரைவில் தடுத்து வைக்கப்பட்டுள்ள வெலிக்கடை சிறைச்சாலையில் இருந்து விடுவிக்கப்படுவார் என தெரிவிக்கப்படுகிறது. அமைச்சர் ஹரீன் பெர்னாண்டோ தனது டுவிட்டர் பதிவில் ராமநாயக்க இன்று அல்லது திங்கட்கிழமை சிறையிலிருந்து விடுவிக்கப்படுவார் எனத் தெரிவித்துள்ளார்.",
        "அவரும் அமைச்சர் மனுஷ நாணயக்காரவும் ஜனாதிபதி ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்கவிடம் விடுத்த கோரிக்கைக்கு அமைய ராமநாயக்க விடுவிக்கப்படுவதாக பெர்னாண்டோ கூறினார். ராமநாயக்கவின் விடுதலையை உறுதி செய்வதற்கு நீதியமைச்சர் விஜயதாச ராஜபக்ஷவின் அயராத முயற்சிகளுக்கு பெர்னாண்டோ நன்றி தெரிவித்தார்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "எஸ்சி",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "சி.ஜே",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "சமகி",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரஞ்சன் ராமநாயக்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "நேற்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "நீதி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "விஜயதாச ராஜபக்ஷ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ராமநாயக்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ராமநாயக்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "21 ஆகஸ்ட் 2017",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "உச்ச நீதிமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "மேல்முறையீடு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ராமநாயக்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "ராமநாயக்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "வெலிக்கடை சிறைச்சாலை",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஹரின் பெர்னாண்டோ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ராமநாயக்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "திங்கட்கிழமை",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ராமநாயக்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "மனுஷ நாணயக்கார",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "பெர்னாண்டோ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "நீதி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "விஜயதாச ராஜபக்ஷ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ராமநாயக்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}