{
  "newspaper_id": "ada-derana-lk",
  "url": "http://www.adaderana.lk/news/83459/hirunika-and-8-others-arrested-during-protest",
  "time_ut": 1657090380,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Hirunika and 8 others arrested during protest",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Hirunika and 8 others arrested during protest",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "Former MP Hirunika Premachandra and eight others have been arrested by police while protesting in front of the President’s House in Colombo Fort.",
        "They have been taken into custody by Fort Police, according to the Police Headquarters.",
        "A gathering of people including the former parliamentarian had been engaged in a protest opposite the President’s House in Fort this morning (06).",
        "They have been arrested during this protest. The arrested protesters include five females including Hirunika Premachandra and four males.",
        "Statements are currently being recorded from them while Fort Police is conducting further investigations."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "8",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "eight",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Fort Police",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "House",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Fort",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "this morning",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "06",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "five",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Hirunika Premachandra",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "four",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Fort Police",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "විරෝධතාවයේදී හිරුණිකා ඇතුළු 8 දෙනෙකු අත්අඩංගුවට",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "හිටපු පාර්ලිමේන්තු මන්ත්‍රීනී හිරුණිකා ප්‍රේමචන්ද්‍ර ඇතුළු 8 දෙනෙකු කොළඹ කොටුව ජනාධිපති මන්දිරය ඉදිරිපිට විරෝධතාවයක නිරත වෙමින් සිටියදී පොලීසිය විසින් අත්අඩංගුවට ගෙන තිබේ.",
        "ඔවුන් කොටුව පොලිසිය විසින් අත්අඩංගුවට ගෙන ඇති බව පොලිස් මූලස්ථානය පවසයි.",
        "හිටපු පාර්ලිමේන්තු මන්ත්‍රීවරයා ඇතුළු පිරිසක් අද (06) පෙරවරුවේ කොටුව ජනාධිපති මන්දිරය ඉදිරිපිට විරෝධතාවයක නිරත වී තිබුණා.",
        "මෙම විරෝධතාව අතරතුර ඔවුන් අත්අඩංගුවට ගෙන තිබේ. අත්අඩංගුවට ගත් විරෝධතාකරුවන් අතර හිරුණිකා ප්‍රේමචන්ද්‍ර ඇතුළු කාන්තාවන් 5 දෙනෙකු සහ පිරිමි පුද්ගලයින් සිව් දෙනෙකු ඇතුළත්.",
        "ඔවුන්ගෙන් මේ වන විට ප්‍රකාශ සටහන් කර ගනිමින් පවතින අතර කොටුව පොලිසිය වැඩිදුර විමර්ශන සිදු කරයි."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "8",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "අට",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "කොටුව පොලිසිය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "නිවස",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "බලකොටුව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මේ උදෑසන",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "06",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "පහ",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "හිරුණිකා ප්‍රේමචන්ද්‍ර",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "හතර",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "කොටුව පොලිසිය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "போராட்டத்தில் ஈடுபட்ட ஹிருணிகா உள்ளிட்ட 8 பேர் கைது செய்யப்பட்டனர்",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "முன்னாள் பாராளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர் ஹிருணிகா பிரேமச்சந்திர உள்ளிட்ட 8 பேர் கொழும்பு கோட்டையில் உள்ள ஜனாதிபதி மாளிகைக்கு முன்பாக ஆர்ப்பாட்டத்தில் ஈடுபட்டிருந்த போது பொலிஸாரால் கைது செய்யப்பட்டுள்ளனர்.",
        "இவர்கள் கோட்டை பொலிஸாரால் கைது செய்யப்பட்டுள்ளதாக பொலிஸ் தலைமையகம் தெரிவித்துள்ளது.",
        "இன்று (06) காலை கோட்டையிலுள்ள ஜனாதிபதி மாளிகைக்கு முன்பாக முன்னாள் பாராளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர் உள்ளிட்டோர் ஆர்ப்பாட்டத்தில் ஈடுபட்டுள்ளனர்.",
        "இந்த போராட்டத்தின் போது அவர்கள் கைது செய்யப்பட்டுள்ளனர். கைது செய்யப்பட்ட ஆர்ப்பாட்டக்காரர்களில் ஹிருணிகா பிரேமச்சந்திர உட்பட ஐந்து பெண்களும் நான்கு ஆண்களும் அடங்குவர்.",
        "அவர்களிடம் வாக்குமூலம் பதிவு செய்யப்பட்டு வருகின்ற நிலையில், கோட்டை பொலிஸார் மேலதிக விசாரணைகளை மேற்கொண்டு வருகின்றனர்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "8",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "எட்டு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "கோட்டை போலீஸ்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "வீடு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "கோட்டை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று காலை",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "06",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஐந்து",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஹிருணிகா பிரேமச்சந்திர",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "நான்கு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "கோட்டை போலீஸ்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}