{
  "newspaper_id": "virakesari-lk",
  "url": "http://www.virakesari.lk/article/131072",
  "time_ut": 1657280886,
  "original_lang": "ta",
  "original_title": "சுதந்திர கட்சியும் சம்பிக்கவின் 43 ஆவது படையணியும் ஒன்றிணைந்து சர்வக்கட்சி அரசாங்கத்தின் வியூகத்தை தயாரிக்க தீர்மானம் - தயாசிறி",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Freedom Party and Champika's 43rd Brigade resolve to come together to prepare strategy for all-party government - Dayasiri",
      "author": "Digital Desk 5",
      "body_lines": [
        "People who cannot participate in today's protest against the government in Colombo should participate in protests from their own places.",
        "Sri Lanka Freedom Party Secretary General Dayasiri Jayasekara said that the Freedom Party and the 43rd Brigade have decided to come together to prepare the strategy of the all-party government.",
        "He mentioned the above while attending a press conference held at the office of the Sri Lanka Freedom Party.",
        "The government led by President Gotabaya Rajapaksa and Prime Minister Ranil Wickremesinghe has no recognition among the people.",
        "The people's struggle against the government and the basic problems faced by the people are intensifying day by day and not diminishing. Prime Minister Ranil Wickremesinghe mentions about the crises but does not get any solution to the problems.",
        "Those who cannot participate in today's protest against the government in Colombo should participate in protests from their own places. The democratic struggle will surely win.",
        "He said the 43rd Brigade of Member of Parliament Batali Sambika and the Independence Party are determined to prepare the framework for a one-fifth all-party government."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Freedom Party and Champika's",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "43rd Brigade",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka Freedom Party",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Dayasiri Jayasekara",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Freedom Party",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the 43rd Brigade",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the Sri Lanka Freedom Party",
            "label": "FAC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Gotabaya Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "43rd Brigade",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Independence Party",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "one-fifth",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "නිදහස් පක්ෂය සහ චම්පිකගේ 43 වැනි බලසේනාව සර්ව පාක්ෂික ආණ්ඩුවක් සඳහා උපාය මාර්ග සකස් කිරීමට එක්වීමට තීරණය කරයි - දයාසිරි",
      "author": "ඩිජිටල් මේසය 5",
      "body_lines": [
        "ආණ්ඩුවට එරෙහිව අද කොළඹ පැවැත්වෙන උද්ඝෝෂණයට සහභාගි විය නොහැකි ජනතාව තම තමන්ගේ ස්ථානවල සිට විරෝධතාවලට සහභාගි විය යුතුයි.",
        "සර්ව පාක්ෂික ආණ්ඩුවේ උපාය මාර්ගය සකස් කිරීම සඳහා නිදහස් පක්ෂය සහ 43 වැනි බලසේනාව එක්වීමට තීරණය කර ඇති බව ශ්‍රී ලංකා නිදහස් පක්ෂයේ මහලේකම් දයාසිරි ජයසේකර මහතා පැවසීය.",
        "ඔහු මේ බව සඳහන් කළේ ශ්‍රී ලංකා නිදහස් පක්ෂ කාර්යාලයේ පැවති මාධ්‍ය හමුවකට එක්වෙමින්.",
        "ජනාධිපති ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ සහ අගමැති රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ ප්‍රමුඛ ආණ්ඩුවට ජනතාව අතර පිළිගැනීමක් නැහැ.",
        "රජයට එරෙහි ජනතා අරගලයත් ජනතාව මුහුණ දෙන මූලික ගැටලුත් දිනෙන් දින තීව්‍ර වෙනවා මිස අඩුවන්නේ නැහැ.අග්‍රාමාත්‍ය රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතා අර්බුද ගැන සඳහන් කරනවා මිස ගැටලුවලට විසඳුමක් ලැබෙන්නේ නැහැ.",
        "අද ආණ්ඩුවට එරෙහිව කොළඹ පැවැත්වෙන උද්ඝෝෂණයට සහභාගි විය නොහැකි අය තම තමන්ගේ ස්ථානවල සිට උද්ඝෝෂණවලට සහභාගි විය යුතුයි.ප්‍රජාතන්ත්‍රවාදී අරගලය අනිවාර්යයෙන්ම ජයග්‍රහණය කරනවා.",
        "පාර්ලිමේන්තු මන්ත්‍රී බටලී සම්බිකගේ 43 වැනි බලසේනාව සහ නිදහස් පක්ෂය පහෙන් එක සර්ව පාක්ෂික ආණ්ඩුවක් සඳහා අවශ්‍ය රාමුව සකස් කිරීමට අදිටන් කරගෙන සිටින බවද ඔහු පැවසීය."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "නිදහස් පක්ෂය සහ චම්පිකගේ",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "43 වැනි බලසේනාව",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකා නිදහස් පක්ෂය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "දයාසිරි ජයසේකර",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "නිදහස් පක්ෂය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "43 වැනි බලසේනාව",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකා නිදහස් පක්ෂය",
            "label": "FAC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "43 වැනි බලසේනාව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "නිදහස් පක්ෂය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "පහෙන් එකක්",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "சுதந்திர கட்சியும் சம்பிக்கவின் 43 ஆவது படையணியும் ஒன்றிணைந்து சர்வக்கட்சி அரசாங்கத்தின் வியூகத்தை தயாரிக்க தீர்மானம் - தயாசிறி",
      "author": "Digital Desk 5",
      "body_lines": [
        "அரசாங்கத்திற்கு எதிராக கொழும்பில் இன்று இடம்பெறும் போராட்டத்தில் கலந்துக்கொள்ள முடியாத மக்கள் தங்களின் சொந்த இடங்களில் இருந்து போராட்டங்களில் ஈடுப்பட வேண்டும்.",
        "சுதந்திர கட்சியும்,43ஆவது படையணியும் ஒன்றிணைந்து சர்வக்கட்சி அரசாங்கத்தின் வியூகத்தை தயாரிக்க தீர்மானிக்கப்பட்டுள்ளது என ஸ்ரீ லங்கா சுதந்திர கட்சியின் பொதுச்செயலாளர் தயாசிறி ஜெயசேகர தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "ஸ்ரீ லங்கா சுதந்திர கட்சியின் காரியாலயத்தில் இடம்பெற்ற ஊடகவியலாளர் சந்திப்பில் கலந்துக்கொண்டு கருத்துரைக்கையில் மேற்கண்டவாறு குறிப்பிட்டார்.",
        "ஜனாதிபதி கோட்டபய ராஜபக்ஷ, பிரதமர் ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க தலைமையிலான அரசாங்கத்திற்கு மக்கள் மத்தியில் அங்கிகாரம் கிடையாது.",
        "அரசாங்கத்திற்கு எதிரான மக்கள் போராட்டமும்,மக்கள் எதிர்கொண்டுள்ள அடிப்படை பிரச்சினைகளும் நாளுக்கு நாள் தீவிரமடைகிறதே தவிர குறைவடையவில்லை.பிரதமர் ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க நெருக்கடிகள் தொடர்பில் குறிப்பிடுகிறாரே தவிர எப்பிரச்சினைகளுக்கும் தீர்வினை பெற்றுக்கொடுக்கவில்லை.",
        "அரசாங்கத்திற்கு எதிராக கொழும்பில் இன்று இடம்பெறும் போராட்டத்தில் கலந்துக்கொள்ள முடியாதவர்கள் தங்களின் சொந்த இடங்களில் இருந்து போராட்டங்களில் ஈடுப்பட வேண்டும்.ஜனநாயக ரீதியிலான போராட்டம் நிச்சயம் வெற்றிப்பெறும்.",
        "பாராளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர் பாட்டலி சம்பிக்கவின் 43 ஆவது படையணி மற்றும் சுதந்திர கட்சி ஒன்றினைந்து சர்வக்கட்சி அரசாங்கத்திற்கான கட்டமைப்பை தயாரிக்க தீர்மானிக்கப்பட்டுள்ளது என்றார்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "சுதந்திரக் கட்சி மற்றும் சம்பிக்கவின்",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "43 வது படைப்பிரிவு",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஸ்ரீலங்கா சுதந்திரக் கட்சி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "தயாசிறி ஜயசேகர",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "சுதந்திரக் கட்சி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "43 வது படைப்பிரிவு",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஸ்ரீலங்கா சுதந்திரக் கட்சி",
            "label": "FAC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "43 வது படைப்பிரிவு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "சுதந்திரக் கட்சி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஐந்தில் ஒரு பங்கு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}