{
  "newspaper_id": "virakesari-lk",
  "url": "http://www.virakesari.lk/article/131833",
  "time_ut": 1658239902,
  "original_lang": "ta",
  "original_title": "முடிவு சிலவேளை மாறலாம் - தமிழ் மக்கள் தேசிய கூட்டணியின் தலைவர் சி.வி.விக்னேஸ்வரன்",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "The result may change - Tamil People's National Alliance President CV Wigneswaran",
      "author": "Vishnu",
      "body_lines": [
        "On Tuesday 19th, I handed over a letter containing 6 demands on behalf of the Tamil people to the President and the new presidential candidate, Ranil Wickramasinghe.",
        "Wigneswaran MP said his decision to remain neutral may change at times. He said.",
        "Presidential candidates such as Ranil Wickramasinghe, Dallas Alagapperuma and Anurakumara Dissanayake are involved in efforts to seek the support of the parties as the vote to elect the new President is to be held in Parliament at 10 am on Wednesday.",
        "In this case, the president of the Tamil People's National Alliance and Member of Parliament, Justice C.V. He said this when he was asked whether there were any changes in the decision of your middle position as the main opposition leader Sajith Premadasa withdrew from the race for the presidential post as already stated by Wigneswaran.",
        "We have handed over a letter containing 6 demands on behalf of the Tamil people to the replying president and the new presidential candidate, Ranil Wickramasinghe.",
        "He gave some assurances in this regard. However, I will take the final decision only after discussing with my partner parties and other Tamil party leaders. Then in some jobs the decision may change in the middle of the situation.",
        "Meanwhile, none of the other presidential candidates sought the support of my party. But it was Ranil Wickremesinghe who directly sought my support.",
        "That is why I personally handed him a letter containing 6 demands on behalf of the Tamil people. He immediately read it and gave some assurances. I was also going to hand over this letter to the Leader of the Opposition, Sajith Premadasa. But he said he did not hand him over as he withdrew from the race for the presidency at the last moment."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Tamil People's",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "National Alliance",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "CV Wigneswaran",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Tuesday 19th",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Tamil",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickramasinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Wigneswaran MP",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickramasinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Dallas Alagapperuma",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Anurakumara Dissanayake",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "10 am",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "Wednesday",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the Tamil People's",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "National Alliance",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "C.V. He",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sajith Premadasa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Wigneswaran",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Tamil",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickramasinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Tamil",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Tamil",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "ප්‍රතිඵලය වෙනස් විය හැකියි - දෙමළ ජනතා ජාතික සන්ධානයේ සභාපති සී.වී.විග්නේෂ්වරන්",
      "author": "විෂ්ණු",
      "body_lines": [
        "19 අඟහරුවාදා මම දෙමළ ජනතාව වෙනුවෙන් ඉල්ලීම් 6ක් ඇතුළත් ලිපියක් ජනාධිපතිතුමාට සහ නව ජනාධිපති අපේක්ෂක රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතාට භාර දුන්නා.",
        "විග්නේෂ්වරන් මන්ත්‍රීවරයා පැවසුවේ මධ්‍යස්ථව සිටීමට තමන් ගත් තීරණය විටින් විට වෙනස් විය හැකි බවයි. ඔහු කිව්වා.",
        "නව ජනාධිපතිවරයා තෝරා පත් කර ගැනීමේ ඡන්ද විමසීම බදාදා පෙරවරු 10 ට පාර්ලිමේන්තුවේදී පැවැත්වීමට නියමිත බැවින් රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ, ඩලස් අලගප්පෙරුම, අනුරකුමාර දිසානායක වැනි ජනාධිපති අපේක්ෂකයන් පක්ෂවල සහාය ලබාගැනීමේ උත්සාහයක නිරතව සිටිති.",
        "මෙම නඩුවේදී දෙමළ ජනතා ජාතික සන්ධානයේ සභාපති සහ පාර්ලිමේන්තු මන්ත්‍රී විනිසුරු සී.වී. විග්නේෂ්වරන් මහතා දැනටමත් ප්‍රකාශ කළ පරිදි ප්‍රධාන විපක්ෂ නායක සජිත් ප්‍රේමදාස මහතා ජනාධිපතිවරණ තරගයෙන් ඉවත් වූ බැවින් ඔබතුමාගේ මැද ස්ථාවරයේ වෙනසක් සිදුවී ඇත්දැයි ඇසූ විට ඔහු මේ බව පැවසීය.",
        "අපි දෙමළ ජනතාව වෙනුවෙන් ඉල්ලීම් 6ක් ඇතුළත් ලිපියක් පිළිතුරු දුන් ජනාධිපතිවරයාට සහ නව ජනාධිපති අපේක්ෂක රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතාට භාරදී තිබෙනවා.",
        "ඔහු මේ සම්බන්ධයෙන් යම් සහතිකයක් ලබා දුන්නේය. නමුත් මම අවසන් තීරණය ගන්නේ මගේ හවුල්කාර පක්ෂ සහ අනෙකුත් දෙමළ පක්ෂ නායකයන් සමඟ සාකච්ඡා කරලා පමණයි. එවිට සමහර රැකියා වලදී තත්වය මැද තීරණය වෙනස් විය හැකිය.",
        "මේ අතර අනෙකුත් ජනාධිපති අපේක්ෂකයන් කිසිවකු මගේ පක්‍ෂයේ සහාය ඉල්ලා සිටියේ නැත. නමුත් රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතා තමයි මගේ සහය කෙලින්ම ඉල්ලුවේ.",
        "දෙමළ ජනතාව වෙනුවෙන් ඉල්ලීම් 6ක් ඇතුළත් ලිපියක් මම පෞද්ගලිකව එතුමාට භාර දුන්නේ ඒ නිසයි. ඔහු වහාම එය කියවා යම් සහතිකයක් ලබා දුන්නේය. මම මේ ලිපිය විපක්ෂ නායක සජිත් ප්‍රේමදාස මහතාටත් භාර දෙන්නයි හිටියේ. එහෙත් අවසන් මොහොතේ ජනාධිපතිවරණ තරගයෙන් ඉවත් වූ නිසා ඔහුව භාර නොදුන් බව ඔහු පැවසීය."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "දෙමළ ජනතාවගේ",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "ජාතික සන්ධානය",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "සී.වී.විග්නේෂ්වරන්",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "19 අඟහරුවාදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "දෙමළ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "විග්නේෂ්වරන් පා.ම",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඩලස් අලගප්පෙරුම",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "අනුරකුමාර දිසානායක",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "පෙ.ව. 10",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "බදාදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "දෙමළ ජනතාවගේ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජාතික සන්ධානය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "CV. ඔහු",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "සජිත් ප්‍රේමදාස",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "විග්නේෂ්වරන්",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "දෙමළ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "දෙමළ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "දෙමළ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "முடிவு சிலவேளை மாறலாம் - தமிழ் மக்கள் தேசிய கூட்டணியின் தலைவர் சி.வி.விக்னேஸ்வரன்",
      "author": "Vishnu",
      "body_lines": [
        "தமிழ் மக்கள் சார்பில் 6 கோரிக்கைகள் அடங்கிய கடிதமொன்று  19 ஆம் திகதி செவ்வாய்க்கிழமை பதில் ஜனாதிபதியும் புதிய ஜனாதிபதி வேட்பாளருமான ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்கவிடம்  கையளித்துள்ளேன்.",
        "அவரின் உறுதிமொழிக்கமைய நடுநிலைமை என்ற தனது முடிவு சில வேளைகளில் மாறலாம் என விக்னேஸ்வரன் எம்.பி. தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "புதிய ஜனாதிபதியை தெரிவு செய்வதற்கான வாக்கெடுப்பு புதன்கிழமை காலை 10 மணிக்கு பாராளுமன்றத்தில் இடம்பெறவுள்ள நிலையில் கட்சிகளின் ஆதரவை கோரும் முயற்சிகளில் ஜனாதிபதி வேட்பாளர்களான ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க, டலஸ் அழகப்பெரும, அநுரகுமார திசாநாயக்க ஆகியோர்  ஈடுபட்டுள்ளனர்.",
        "இந்நிலையில் ஜனாதிபதி பதவிக்கான வாக்கெடுப்பில் நடு நிலையாக செயற்படபபோவதாக   தமிழ் மக்கள் தேசிய கூட்டணியின் தலைவரும் பாராளுமன்ற உறுப்பனருமான நீதியரசர் சி.வி. விக்னேஸ்வரனினால் ஏற்கனவே கூறப்பட்ட  நிலையில் தற்போது ஜனாதிபதி பதவிக்கான போட்டியிலிருந்து பிரதான எதிர்கட்சித்தலைவரான  சஜித் பிரேமதாச விலகியதால் உங்கள் நடு நிலைமை என்ற முடிவில் மாற்றங்கள் எதாவது உண்டா என அவரிடம் கேட்டபோதே அவர் இவ்வாறு தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "தமிழ் மக்கள் சார்பில் 6 கோரிக்கைகள் அடங்கிய கடித மொன்றை பதில் ஜனாதிபதியும் புதிய ஜனாதிபதி வேட்பாளருமான ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்கவிடம்   கையளித்துள்ளோம்.",
        "அது தொடர்பில் அவர் சில உறுதிமொழிகளை வழங்கினார். எனினும் தமது பங்காளிக்கட்சிகளுடனும் ஏனைய தமிழ் கட்சித்தலைவர்களுடனும் கலந்துரையாடிய பின்னரே  இறுதி தீர்மானத்தை எடுக்கவுள்ளேன். அப்போது சில வேலைகளில்  நடு  நிலைமை என்ற முடிவு மாற்றமடையலாம்.",
        "அதேவேளை ஏனைய   ஜனாதிபதி வேட்பாளர்கள் யாரும் எனது கட்சியின் ஆதரவை கோரவில்லை. ஆனால் ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்கவே என்னிடம் நேரடியாக ஆதரவு கோரினார்.",
        "அதனாலேயே தமிழ் மக்கள் சார்பில் 6 கோரிக்கைகள் அடங்கிய கடித மொன்றை அவரிடம் நேரில் கையளித்தேன். அவர் உடனடியாகவே படித்துப்பார்த்து சில உறுதி மொழிகளை வழங்கினார். இந்தக்கடிதத்தை எதிர்கட்சித்தலைவரான சஜித் பிரேமதசாவிடமும் கையளிக்க விருந்தேன். ஆனால் அவர் இறுதி நேரத்தில் ஜனாதிபதி பதவிக்கான போட்டியிலிருந்து விலகி விட்டதால் அவருக்கு கையளிக்கவில்லை என்றார்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "தமிழ் மக்கள்",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "தேசியக் கூட்டணி",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "சி.வி.விக்னேஸ்வரன்",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "செவ்வாய் 19",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "தமிழ்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "விக்னேஸ்வரன் எம்.பி",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "டலஸ் அழகப்பெரும",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "அனுரகுமார திஸாநாயக்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "காலை 10 மணி",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "புதன்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "தமிழ் மக்களின்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "தேசியக் கூட்டணி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "சுயவிவரம். அவர்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "சஜித் பிரேமதாச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "விக்னேஸ்வரன்",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "தமிழ்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "தமிழ்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "தமிழ்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}