{
  "newspaper_id": "news-first-lk",
  "url": "https://www.newsfirst.lk/2022/07/28/prof-tissa-vitharana-did-not-vote-parliament/",
  "time_ut": 1659010680,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Prof. Tissa Vitharana did not vote – Parliament",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Prof. Tissa Vitharana did not vote – Parliament",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); The Secretary General of the Parliament, Dhammika Dasanayake has confirmed in a letter that Member of Parliament (Prof.) Tissa Vitarana has not voted for the resolution concerning the Proclamation on the state of emergency declared by thenhhhhnhhb Acting President under the Public Security Ordinance which was debated and approved in Parliament yesterday (27).",
        "The Secretary-General has stated that according to the electronic voting records available in Parliament related to yesterday's (27th) voting, (Prof.) Tissa Vitarana has not voted for the resolution under the Public Security Ordinance.",
        "This letter has been forwarded following a request made by the Member of Parliament to the Secretary-General as it appeared in some media that the Member of Parliament (Prof.) Tissa Vitarana had voted in favor of the resolution under the Public Security Ordinance.",
        "Japan hands over donation of USD 1.5Mn to curb medicine crisis"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Tissa Vitharana",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "Parliament",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "News 1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Dhammika Dasanayake",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Tissa Vitarana",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "yesterday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "27",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "yesterday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "27th",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Tissa Vitarana",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Tissa Vitarana",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Japan",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "මහාචාර්ය තිස්ස විතාරණ ඡන්දය දුන්නේ නැහැ – පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); මහජන ආරක්ෂක ආඥාපනත යටතේ එවකට වැඩබලන ජනාධිපතිවරයා විසින් ප්‍රකාශයට පත් කරන ලද හදිසි නීතිය ප්‍රකාශයට පත් කිරීමට අදාළ යෝජනාවට පාර්ලිමේන්තු මන්ත්‍රී (මහාචාර්ය) තිස්ස විතාරණ ඡන්දය ප්‍රකාශ කර නොමැති බව පාර්ලිමේන්තු මහලේකම් ධම්මික දසනායක මහතා ලිපියක් මගින් තහවුරු කර තිබේ. ඊයේ (27) පාර්ලිමේන්තුවේ දී විවාදයට ගෙන අනුමත විය.",
        "ඊයේ (27දා) ඡන්දය ප්‍රකාශ කිරීමට අදාළව පාර්ලිමේන්තුවේ පවතින විද්‍යුත් ඡන්ද සටහන්වලට අනුව (මහාචාර්ය) තිස්ස විතාරණ මහතා මහජන ආරක්ෂක ආඥාපනත යටතේ යෝජනාවට ඡන්දය ප්‍රකාශ කර නොමැති බව මහලේකම්වරයා ප්‍රකාශ කර ඇත.",
        "පාර්ලිමේන්තු මන්ත්‍රී (මහාචාර්ය) තිස්ස විතාරණ මහතා මහජන ආරක්ෂක ආඥාපනත යටතේ යෝජනාවට පක්ෂව ඡන්දය ප්‍රකාශ කළ බවට ඇතැම් මාධ්‍යවල පළවීම නිසා මන්ත්‍රීවරයා මහලේකම්වරයාගෙන් කළ ඉල්ලීමකට අනුව මෙම ලිපිය යොමු කර ඇත.",
        "ජපානය ඖෂධ අර්බුදය මැඩපැවැත්වීම සඳහා ඩොලර් මිලියන 1.5 ක පරිත්‍යාගයක් ලබා දෙයි"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "තිස්ස විතාරණ",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "News 1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ධම්මික දසනායක",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "තිස්ස විතාරණ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඊයේ",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "27",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඊයේ",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "27 වැනි",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "තිස්ස විතාරණ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "තිස්ස විතාරණ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ජපානය",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "பேராசிரியர் திஸ்ஸ விதாரண வாக்களிக்கவில்லை – பாராளுமன்றம்",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); பொது பாதுகாப்பு கட்டளைச் சட்டத்தின் கீழ் அப்போதைய பதில் ஜனாதிபதி பிரகடனப்படுத்திய அவசரகால பிரகடனம் தொடர்பான தீர்மானத்திற்கு பாராளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர் (பேராசிரியர்) திஸ்ஸ விதாரண வாக்களிக்கவில்லை என பாராளுமன்ற செயலாளர் நாயகம் தம்மிக்க தசநாயக்க கடிதம் மூலம் உறுதிப்படுத்தியுள்ளார். நேற்று (27) பாராளுமன்றத்தில் விவாதம் செய்யப்பட்டு அங்கீகரிக்கப்பட்டது.",
        "நேற்றைய (27ஆம் திகதி) வாக்குப்பதிவு தொடர்பில் பாராளுமன்றத்தில் கிடைக்கப்பெற்ற இலத்திரனியல் வாக்குப்பதிவு பதிவுகளின் பிரகாரம், (பேராசிரியர்) திஸ்ஸ விதாரண பொது பாதுகாப்பு கட்டளைச் சட்டத்தின் கீழ் தீர்மானத்திற்கு வாக்களிக்கவில்லை என செயலாளர் நாயகம் தெரிவித்துள்ளார்.",
        "பாராளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர் (பேராசிரியர்) திஸ்ஸ விதாரண பொது பாதுகாப்பு கட்டளைச் சட்டத்தின் கீழ் பிரேரணைக்கு ஆதரவாக வாக்களித்ததாக சில ஊடகங்களில் வெளியான நிலையில், நாடாளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர் செயலாளர் நாயகத்திடம் விடுத்த கோரிக்கையை அடுத்து இந்தக் கடிதம் அனுப்பி வைக்கப்பட்டுள்ளது.",
        "மருத்துவ நெருக்கடியைக் கட்டுப்படுத்த ஜப்பான் 1.5 மில்லியன் அமெரிக்க டாலர்களை நன்கொடையாக வழங்குகிறது"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "திஸ்ஸ விதாரண",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "News 1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "தம்மிக்க தசநாயக்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "திஸ்ஸ விதாரண",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "நேற்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "27",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "நேற்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "27வது",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "திஸ்ஸ விதாரண",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "திஸ்ஸ விதாரண",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஜப்பான்",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}