{
  "newspaper_id": "news-first-lk",
  "url": "https://www.newsfirst.lk/2022/07/30/does-the-president-seek-to-misuse-idea-of-all-party-govt-ven-omalpe-sobhitha-thero/",
  "time_ut": 1659189300,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Does the President seek to misuse idea of All-party Govt? – Ven. Omalpe Sobhitha Thero",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Does the President seek to misuse idea of All-party Govt? – Ven. Omalpe Sobhitha Thero",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st): Ven. Omalpe Sobitha Thero questioned whether the President seeks to suppress the idea of an ​​all-party Government by misusing it.",
        "Speaking at a press conference by the People's Assembly, the Chief Sanghanayake (Dakshina Lankawa) of the Ramanna Sect, Ven. Omalpe Sobitha Thero pointed out that President Ranil Wickramasinghe, through letters, has requested parties to form an all-party Government.",
        "However in the interim, strict and repressive activities are being carried out against the respective groups which demanded for change, Ven. Sobhitha Thero said.",
        "The public did not ask for Ranil Wickremesinghe to take up Presidency, mentioned Ven. Omalpe Sobhitha Thero, adding what the President wants is to somehow hold onto power under the guise of the constitution.",
        "However, a commendable solution was recently presented at the Malwathu Maha Viharaya, Ven. Omalpe Sobhitha Thero said, adding that the time has come to appoint honest public representatives to the Parliament via an election.",
        "Does the President seek to misuse idea of All-party Govt? – Ven. Omalpe Sobhitha Thero",
        "IMF discussions continued with aim to reach Staff-Level Agreement: Finance Ministry"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Omalpe Sobhitha Thero",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "News 1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ven",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Omalpe Sobitha Thero",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the People's Assembly",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Dakshina Lankawa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Ramanna Sect",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Omalpe Sobitha Thero",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickramasinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Ven",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sobhitha Thero",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Omalpe Sobhitha Thero",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Maha Viharaya",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ven",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Omalpe Sobhitha Thero",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Omalpe Sobhitha Thero",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        []
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "ජනාධිපතිවරයා සර්ව පාක්ෂික ආණ්ඩුව පිළිබඳ අදහස අවභාවිත කිරීමට උත්සාහ කරනවාද? – හාමුදුරුවනේ. ඕමල්පේ සෝභිත හිමි",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st) : පූජ්‍ය නාහිමියෝ සර්ව පාක්ෂික ආණ්ඩුවක් පිළිබඳ අදහස අවභාවිත කරමින් එය යටපත් කිරීමට ජනාධිපතිවරයා උත්සාහ කරන්නේ දැයි ඕමල්පේ සෝභිත හිමියෝ ප්‍රශ්න කළහ.",
        "මහජන සභාව විසින් මාධ්‍ය හමුවකදී අදහස් දැක්වූ රාමඤ්ඤ නිකායේ ප්‍රධාන සංඝනායක (දක්ෂිණ ලංකාව) පූජ්‍ය පූජ්‍ය පූජ්‍ය පූජ්‍ය. සර්ව පාක්ෂික ආණ්ඩුවක් පිහිටුවන ලෙස ජනාධිපති රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතා ලිපි මගින් පක්ෂවලින් ඉල්ලීම් කර ඇති බව ඕමල්පේ සෝභිත හිමියෝ පෙන්වා දෙති.",
        "කෙසේ වෙතත් මේ අතරවාරයේදී වෙනසක් ඉල්ලා සිටි කණ්ඩායම්වලට එරෙහිව දැඩි හා මර්දනකාරී ක්‍රියාකාරකම් ක්‍රියාත්මක වෙමින් පවතින බවද පූජ්‍ය හිමියෝ පවසති. සෝභිත හිමියෝ පැවසූහ.",
        "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතා ජනාධිපති ධූරයට පත් කරන ලෙස ජනතාව ඉල්ලා නොසිටි බව පූජ්‍ය හිමියෝ සඳහන් කළහ. ජනාධිපතිවරයාට අවශ්‍ය වන්නේ කෙසේ හෝ ව්‍යවස්ථාවට මුවා වී බලය අල්ලා ගැනීම බව ඕමල්පේ සෝභිත හිමියෝ පවසති.",
        "කෙසේ වෙතත්, ප්‍රශංසනීය විසඳුමක් පසුගියදා මල්වතු මහා විහාරයේදී ඉදිරිපත් කෙරුණා. මැතිවරණයකින් පාර්ලිමේන්තුවට අවංක මහජන නියෝජිතයන් පත් කළ යුතු කාලය එළඹ ඇති බව ද ඕමල්පේ සෝභිත හිමියෝ පැවසූහ.",
        "ජනාධිපතිවරයා සර්ව පාක්ෂික ආණ්ඩුව පිළිබඳ අදහස අවභාවිත කිරීමට උත්සාහ කරනවාද? – හාමුදුරුවනේ. ඕමල්පේ සෝභිත හිමි",
        "IMF සාකච්ඡා මාණ්ඩලික මට්ටමේ එකඟතාවයකට පැමිණීමේ අරමුණින් දිගටම පැවතුනි: මුදල් අමාත්‍යාංශය"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ඕමල්පේ සෝභිත හිමි",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "News 1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "හාමුදුරුවෝ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඕමල්පේ සෝභිත හිමි",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "මහජන සභාව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "දක්ෂිණ ලංකාව",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "රාමඤ්ඤ නිකාය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඕමල්පේ සෝභිත හිමි",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "හාමුදුරුවෝ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "සෝභිත හාමුදුරුවෝ",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඕමල්පේ සෝභිත හිමි",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "මහා විහාරය",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "හාමුදුරුවෝ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඕමල්පේ සෝභිත හිමි",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ඕමල්පේ සෝභිත හිමි",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        []
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "சர்வகட்சி அரசாங்கத்தின் யோசனையை ஜனாதிபதி தவறாக பயன்படுத்த முற்படுகிறாரா? – வண. ஓமல்பே சோபித தேரர்",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st): வண. சர்வகட்சி அரசாங்கம் என்ற யோசனையை தவறாகப் பயன்படுத்துவதன் மூலம் ஜனாதிபதி அதனை நசுக்க முற்படுகின்றாரா என ஓமல்பே சோபித தேரர் கேள்வி எழுப்பியுள்ளார்.",
        "மக்கள் பேரவையின் செய்தியாளர் சந்திப்பில் பேசிய ராமண்ணா பிரிவின் தலைமை சங்கநாயக (தக்ஷிண லங்காவா) வண. ஜனாதிபதி ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க அனைத்துக் கட்சிகளையும் கொண்ட அரசாங்கத்தை அமைக்குமாறு கட்சிகளிடம் கடிதம் மூலம் கோரிக்கை விடுத்துள்ளதாக ஓமல்பே சோபித தேரர் சுட்டிக்காட்டியுள்ளார்.",
        "எவ்வாறாயினும், மாற்றத்தை கோரும் அந்தந்த குழுக்களுக்கு எதிராக இடைக்கால, கடுமையான மற்றும் அடக்குமுறை நடவடிக்கைகள் மேற்கொள்ளப்படுகின்றன. சோபித தேரர் தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்கவை ஜனாதிபதியாகப் பதவியேற்குமாறு பொதுமக்கள் கோரவில்லை என வண. அரசியலமைப்பு என்ற போர்வையில் எப்படியாவது அதிகாரத்தை பிடிப்பதையே ஜனாதிபதி விரும்புவதாக ஓமல்பே சோபித தேரர் மேலும் தெரிவித்துள்ளார்.",
        "எவ்வாறாயினும், அண்மையில் மல்வத்து மகா விகாரையில் ஒரு பாராட்டத்தக்க தீர்வு வழங்கப்பட்டது. நேர்மையான மக்கள் பிரதிநிதிகளை தேர்தலின் மூலம் பாராளுமன்றத்திற்கு நியமிக்க வேண்டிய தருணம் வந்துள்ளதாக ஓமல்பே சோபித தேரர் தெரிவித்துள்ளார்.",
        "சர்வகட்சி அரசாங்கத்தின் யோசனையை ஜனாதிபதி தவறாக பயன்படுத்த முற்படுகிறாரா? – வண. ஓமல்பே சோபித தேரர்",
        "பணியாளர்கள் நிலை ஒப்பந்தத்தை எட்டுவதற்கான நோக்கத்துடன் IMF விவாதங்கள் தொடர்ந்தன: நிதி அமைச்சகம்"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ஓமல்பே சோபித தேரர்",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "News 1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "வண",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஓமல்பே சோபித தேரர்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "மக்கள் பேரவை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "தக்ஷிண லங்காவா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ராமண்ணா பிரிவு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஓமல்பே சோபித தேரர்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "வண",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சோபித தேரோ",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஓமல்பே சோபித தேரர்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "மஹா விஹாரை",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "வண",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஓமல்பே சோபித தேரர்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஓமல்பே சோபித தேரர்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        []
      ]
    }
  }
}