{
  "newspaper_id": "economy-next-com",
  "url": "https://economynext.com/sri-lanka-main-opposition-dissident-mps-to-sit-out-crucial-budget-vote-99359/",
  "time_ut": 1662103740,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Sri Lanka main opposition, dissident MPs to sit out crucial budget vote",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Sri Lanka main opposition, dissident MPs to sit out crucial budget vote",
      "author": "Himal Kotelawala",
      "body_lines": [
        "ECONOMYNEXT – Sri Lanka’s main opposition the Samagi Jana Balawegaya (SJB) and a breakaway faction of the ruling Sri Lanka Podujana Peramuna (SLPP) will sit out a vote on President Ranil Wickremesinghe’s interim budget for 2022, the two parties said.",
        "SJB MP Thushara Indunil and SLPP (dissident) MP G L Peiris announced the two parties decision to abstain from voting in separate press briefings on Friday September 02, hours before the vote is to be taken.",
        "Peiris told reporters that the interim budget presented by Wickremesinghe, who is also Finance Minister, contains many “negative” proposals that are harmful to Sri Lanka. He said while his group of independent MPs do not intend in any way to scuttle Sri Lanka’s ongoing talks with the International Monetary Fund (IMF), but the party retains its right to express its independent views in parliament.",
        "“We did not get an opportunity express our views on the contents of this interim budget. Taking all this into account, we have decided to abstain from voting this evening,” he said.",
        "Peiris’ faction comprises 13 MPs including Dullas Alahapperuma who ran against Wickremesinghe for the presidency.",
        "MP Indunil meanwhile said the interim budget document does contains no propsals the SJB can support, but though there are grounds for opposing budget, the party won’t be so cruel as to send the wrong message to the world vis-à-vis the government.",
        "“As a party, we have decide to neither support nor oppose President Wickremesinghe’s budget and to abstain from voting instead,” he said.",
        "Political analysts say the main opposition’s and the independent MPs’ moves to sit out the crucial budget vote will throw a spanner in the works of the president’s repeated attempts to form an all-party government.",
        "Delivering the interim budget speech in parliament on Tuesday August 30, he reiterated the call, highlighting the importance of political stability bipartisan consensus in seeing Sri Lanka through much needed economic reforms.",
        "Meanwhile, former Sports Minister and SLPP MP Namal Rajapaksa, who is reportedly involved in efforts to revive the SLPP, said on Thursday that President Wickremesinghe ought to form a stable administration with the 134 ruling party MPs who elected him rather than pin his hopes on an all-party government.",
        "Sri Lanka president should form stable govt with SLPP: MP Namal Rajapaksa"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Sri Lanka",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka’s",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Samagi",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Jana Balawegaya",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "SJB",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "Podujana Peramuna",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "2022",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "two",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Thushara Indunil",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "G L Peiris",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "two",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Friday September 02, hours",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Peiris",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the International Monetary Fund",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "this evening",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Peiris’",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "13",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Dullas Alahapperuma",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Indunil",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "SJB",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "Tuesday August 30",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Namal Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Thursday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "134",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Namal Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ ප්‍රධාන විපක්ෂය, විරුද්ධ මත දරන මන්ත්‍රීවරුන් තීරණාත්මක අයවැය ඡන්ද විමසීමට",
      "author": "හිමාල් කොතලාවල",
      "body_lines": [
        "ආර්ථිකය - ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ ප්‍රධාන විපක්ෂය වන සමගි ජන බලවේගය (SJB) සහ පාලක ශ්‍රී ලංකා පොදුජන පෙරමුණේ (SLPP) බිඳී ගිය කන්ඩායමක් 2022 සඳහා ජනාධිපති රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහගේ අතුරු අයවැය සම්බන්ධයෙන් ඡන්දය ප්‍රකාශ කරන බව පක්ෂ දෙක පවසයි.",
        "SJB පාර්ලිමේන්තු මන්ත්‍රී තුෂාර ඉඳුනිල් සහ ශ්‍රී ලංකා පොදුජන පෙරමුණේ (විසංවාදී) පාර්ලිමේන්තු මන්ත්‍රී ජී එල් පීරිස් සැප්තැම්බර් 02 සිකුරාදා ඡන්ද විමසීමට පැය කිහිපයකට පෙර වෙන වෙනම මාධ්‍ය හමුවලදී පක්ෂ දෙක ඡන්දය දීමෙන් වැළකී සිටීමට තීරණය කළහ.",
        "මුදල් අමාත්‍යවරයා ද වන වික්‍රමසිංහ විසින් ඉදිරිපත් කරන ලද අතුරු අයවැයේ ශ්‍රී ලංකාවට හානිකර බොහෝ “සෘණාත්මක” යෝජනා ඇතුළත් බව පීරිස් වාර්තාකරුවන්ට පැවසීය. ජාත්‍යන්තර මූල්‍ය අරමුදල (IMF) සමඟ ශ්‍රී ලංකාව දැනට කරගෙන යන සාකච්ඡා කඩාකප්පල් කිරීමට තම ස්වාධීන මන්ත්‍රී කණ්ඩායම කිසිදු ආකාරයකින් අදහස් නොකරන නමුත්, පාර්ලිමේන්තුව තුළ ස්වාධීන අදහස් ප්‍රකාශ කිරීමේ අයිතිය පක්ෂයට පවතින බව ඔහු පැවසීය.",
        "“මේ අතුරු අයවැයේ අන්තර්ගතය ගැන අපේ අදහස් ප්‍රකාශ කරන්න අවස්ථාවක් ලැබුණේ නැහැ. මේ සියල්ල සැලකිල්ලට ගෙන අද සවස ඡන්දය දීමෙන් වැළකී සිටීමට අපි තීරණය කළා,” ඔහු පැවසීය.",
        "පීරිස්ගේ පිලට වික්‍රමසිංහට එරෙහිව ජනාධිපතිවරණයට ඉදිරිපත් වූ ඩලස් අලහප්පෙරුම ඇතුළු මන්ත්‍රීවරු 13 දෙනෙක් සිටිති.",
        "මේ අතර පාර්ලිමේන්තු මන්ත්‍රී ඉඳුනිල් කියා සිටියේ අතුරු අයවැය ලේඛනයේ SJB ට සහය දිය හැකි යෝජනා නොමැති බවත්, නමුත් අයවැයට විරුද්ධ වීමට හේතු තිබුණත්, රජයට එරෙහිව ලෝකයට වැරදි පණිවිඩයක් යැවීමට පක්ෂය එතරම් කුරිරු නොවන බවයි. .",
        "\"පක්ෂයක් ලෙස අපි තීරණය කර ඇත්තේ වික්‍රමසිංහ ජනාධිපතිවරයාගේ අයවැයට සහය දැක්වීමට හෝ විරුද්ධ වීමටත් ඒ වෙනුවට ඡන්දය දීමෙන් වැළකී සිටීමටත්\" ඔහු පැවසීය.",
        "දේශපාලන විශ්ලේෂකයින් පවසන්නේ තීරණාත්මක අයවැය ඡන්ද විමසීමට අසුන් ගැනීමට ප්‍රධාන විපක්ෂයේ සහ ස්වාධීන මන්ත්‍රීවරුන්ගේ පියවර සර්ව පාක්ෂික රජයක් පිහිටුවීමට ජනාධිපතිවරයා නැවත නැවතත් දරන උත්සාහයේ ක්‍රියාකාරිත්වයට විශාල බලපෑමක් ඇති කරනු ඇති බවයි.",
        "අගෝස්තු 30 අඟහරුවාදා පාර්ලිමේන්තුවේ අතුරු අයවැය කතාව ඉදිරිපත් කරමින් ඔහු නැවත නැවතත් කැඳවීම අවධාරණය කළේ, ශ්‍රී ලංකාව අත්‍යවශ්‍ය ආර්ථික ප්‍රතිසංස්කරණ හරහා දැකීමට දේශපාලන ස්ථාවරත්වය ද්විපාර්ශ්වික සම්මුතියේ වැදගත්කම අවධාරණය කරමිනි.",
        "මේ අතර, ශ්‍රී ලංකා පොදුජන පෙරමුණ යළි නඟා සිටුවීමේ ප්‍රයත්නවල නිරතව සිටින හිටපු ක්‍රීඩා අමාත්‍ය සහ ශ්‍රී ලංකා පොදුජන පෙරමුණේ පාර්ලිමේන්තු මන්ත්‍රී නාමල් රාජපක්ෂ බ්‍රහස්පතින්දා ප්‍රකාශ කළේ ජනාධිපති වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතා බලාපොරොත්තු තබා ගැනීමට වඩා තමන් පත් කළ ආණ්ඩු පක්ෂයේ මන්ත්‍රීවරුන් 134 දෙනා සමඟ ස්ථාවර පාලනයක් ඇති කළ යුතු බවයි. සර්ව පාක්ෂික රජය.",
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකා ජනාධිපතිවරයා ශ්‍රී ලංකා පොදුජන පෙරමුණ සමඟ ස්ථාවර ආණ්ඩුවක් පිහිටුවිය යුතුයි: පාර්ලිමේන්තු මන්ත්‍රී නාමල් රාජපක්ෂ"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "සමගි",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජන බලවේගය",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "එස්.ජේ.බී",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "පොදුජන පෙරමුණ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "2022",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "දෙක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "තුෂාර ඉඳුනිල්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජී එල් පීරිස්",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "දෙක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "සැප්තැම්බර් 02 සිකුරාදා, පැය",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "පීරිස්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජාත්‍යන්තර මුල්‍ය අරමුදල",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "අද සවස",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "පීරිස්'",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "13",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඩලස් අලහප්පෙරුම",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ඉඳුනිල්",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "එස්.ජේ.බී",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "අගෝස්තු 30 අඟහරුවාදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "නාමල් රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "බ්රහස්පතින්දා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "134",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "නාමල් රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "இலங்கையின் பிரதான எதிர்க்கட்சியான அதிருப்தி எம்.பி.க்கள் முக்கியமான வரவு செலவுத் திட்ட வாக்கெடுப்பில் அமர்ந்துள்ளனர்",
      "author": "ஹிமால் கொத்தலாவல",
      "body_lines": [
        "பொருளாதாரம் - இலங்கையின் பிரதான எதிர்க்கட்சியான சமகி ஜன பலவேகய (SJB) மற்றும் ஆளும் ஸ்ரீலங்கா பொதுஜன பெரமுனவின் (SLPP) பிரிந்து சென்ற 2022 ஆம் ஆண்டுக்கான ஜனாதிபதி ரணில் விக்ரமசிங்கவின் இடைக்கால வரவு செலவுத் திட்டம் மீது வாக்கெடுப்பு நடத்தப்படும் என இரு கட்சிகளும் தெரிவித்துள்ளன.",
        "SJB பாராளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர் துஷார இந்துனில் மற்றும் SLPP (அதிருப்தி) பாராளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர் ஜி எல் பீரிஸ் ஆகியோர் வாக்கெடுப்புக்கு சில மணிநேரங்களுக்கு முன்னர், செப்டம்பர் 02 வெள்ளிக்கிழமை தனித்தனியான செய்தியாளர் சந்திப்புகளில் வாக்களிப்பதில் இருந்து விலகி இரு கட்சிகளின் முடிவை அறிவித்தனர்.",
        "நிதி அமைச்சராகவும் இருக்கும் விக்ரமசிங்கவினால் முன்வைக்கப்பட்ட இடைக்கால வரவு செலவுத் திட்டத்தில் இலங்கைக்கு தீங்கு விளைவிக்கும் பல \"எதிர்மறையான\" முன்மொழிவுகள் உள்ளன என்று பீரிஸ் செய்தியாளர்களிடம் கூறினார். சர்வதேச நாணய நிதியத்துடனான (IMF) இலங்கையின் தற்போதைய பேச்சுக்களை சீர்குலைக்க தனது சுயேச்சை எம்.பி.க்கள் குழு எந்த வகையிலும் உத்தேசிக்கவில்லை, ஆனால் கட்சி தனது சுயாதீன கருத்துக்களை பாராளுமன்றத்தில் வெளிப்படுத்தும் உரிமையை தக்க வைத்துக் கொண்டுள்ளது.",
        "“இந்த இடைக்கால பட்ஜெட்டின் உள்ளடக்கங்கள் குறித்து எங்களின் கருத்துக்களை வெளிப்படுத்த எங்களுக்கு வாய்ப்பு கிடைக்கவில்லை. இதையெல்லாம் கருத்தில் கொண்டு இன்று மாலை வாக்களிக்காமல் இருக்க முடிவு செய்துள்ளோம்,'' என்றார்.",
        "பீரிஸ் அணியில் விக்ரமசிங்கவை எதிர்த்து போட்டியிட்ட டலஸ் அழகப்பெரும உட்பட 13 எம்.பி.க்கள் உள்ளனர்.",
        "இதற்கிடையில், இடைக்கால வரவு செலவுத் திட்ட ஆவணத்தில் SJB ஆதரிக்கும் முன்மொழிவுகள் இல்லை, ஆனால் வரவு செலவுத் திட்டத்தை எதிர்ப்பதற்கான காரணங்கள் இருந்தாலும், அரசாங்கத்திற்கு எதிராக உலகிற்கு தவறான செய்தியை அனுப்பும் அளவுக்கு அக்கட்சி கொடூரமாக நடந்து கொள்ளாது என்று பாராளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர் இந்துனில் கூறினார். .",
        "\"ஒரு கட்சி என்ற வகையில், ஜனாதிபதி விக்கிரமசிங்கவின் வரவு செலவுத் திட்டத்தை ஆதரிக்கவோ அல்லது எதிர்க்கவோ இல்லை, அதற்கு பதிலாக வாக்களிப்பதில் இருந்து விலகி இருக்க முடிவு செய்துள்ளோம்,\" என்று அவர் கூறினார்.",
        "முக்கியமான வரவு செலவுத் திட்ட வாக்கெடுப்பில் அமர்வதற்கான பிரதான எதிர்க்கட்சி மற்றும் சுயேட்சை பாராளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர்களின் நகர்வுகள், அனைத்துக் கட்சி அரசாங்கத்தை அமைப்பதற்கான ஜனாதிபதியின் தொடர்ச்சியான முயற்சிகளின் வேலைகளில் ஒரு இழுவை வீசும் என்று அரசியல் ஆய்வாளர்கள் கூறுகின்றனர்.",
        "செவ்வாய்க்கிழமை ஆகஸ்ட் 30 அன்று பாராளுமன்றத்தில் இடைக்கால வரவு செலவுத் திட்ட உரையை ஆற்றிய அவர், மிகவும் தேவையான பொருளாதார சீர்திருத்தங்கள் மூலம் இலங்கையைப் பார்ப்பதில் இரு கட்சிகளின் அரசியல் ஸ்திரத்தன்மையின் முக்கியத்துவத்தை எடுத்துரைத்து மீண்டும் அழைப்பு விடுத்தார்.",
        "இதேவேளை, SLPP க்கு புத்துயிர் கொடுக்கும் முயற்சியில் ஈடுபட்டுள்ளதாக கூறப்படும் முன்னாள் விளையாட்டு அமைச்சரும் SLPP பாராளுமன்ற உறுப்பினருமான நாமல் ராஜபக்ஷ, ஜனாதிபதி விக்ரமசிங்க 134 ஆளும் கட்சி எம்.பி.க்களுடன் ஸ்திரமான நிர்வாகத்தை உருவாக்க வேண்டும் என வியாழக்கிழமை தெரிவித்தார். அனைத்து கட்சி அரசு.",
        "இலங்கை ஜனாதிபதி SLPP உடன் இணைந்து நிலையான அரசாங்கத்தை அமைக்க வேண்டும்: பாராளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர் நாமல் ராஜபக்ஷ"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "இலங்கை",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கையின்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சமகி",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜன பலவேகயா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "எஸ்.ஜே.பி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "பொதுஜன பெரமுன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "2022",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இரண்டு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "துஷாரா இந்துனில்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜி எல் பீரிஸ்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இரண்டு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "வெள்ளிக்கிழமை செப்டம்பர் 02, மணி",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பீரிஸ்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சர்வதேச நாணய நிதியம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இன்று மாலை",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பீரிஸ்’",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "13",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "டலஸ் அழகப்பெரும",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இந்துனில்",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "எஸ்.ஜே.பி",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஆகஸ்ட் 30 செவ்வாய்கிழமை",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "நாமல் ராஜபக்ச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "வியாழன்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "134",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "நாமல் ராஜபக்ச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}