{
  "newspaper_id": "news-first-lk",
  "url": "https://www.newsfirst.lk/2022/09/03/positive-response-from-international-community-over-imf-mission-statement-on-sl/",
  "time_ut": 1662194460,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Positive response from International community over IMF mission statement on SL",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Positive response from International community over IMF mission statement on SL",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); Several International envoys have expressed positive reactions towards Sri Lanka arriving to a staff-level agreement with the International Monetary Fund (IMF), including the Australian High Commission, the representatives of the European Union and the Senate Foreign Relations Committee of the United States.",
        "China and India too expressed their sentiments, with the Chinese Foreign Ministry Spokesperson Zhao Lijan stating that China supports relevant financial institutions in consulting with Sri Lanka for proper solutions.",
        "Meanwhile, Indian Foreign Ministry Spokesperson Arindam Bagchi acknowledged that the staff agreement is an evolving situation, however, India has been advocating for assistance to Sri Lanka.",
        "The US Ambassador to Sri Lanka Julie Chung noted that US stands ready to assist Sri Lanka, as the IMF represents the best tools, approaches, and resources to enable Sri Lanka to overcome the ongoing economic crisis.",
        "The Senate Foreign Relations Committee mentioned that the IMF initial agreement is an important first step to get Sri Lanka on the path to economic stability and to address systemic corruption.",
        "\"Now Sri Lanka’s creditors, including China, must negotiate in good faith to provide Sri Lankans the debt relief they desperately need,\" the Senate Foreign Relations Committee stated.",
        "The Australian High Commission mentioned that Australia is ready to extend support in every way possible, and lauded Sri Lanka for reaching a staff-level agreement with the IMF. The High Commissioner also said that it is a welcome preliminary step forward in Sri Lanka’s economic recovery process.",
        "Positive response from International community over IMF mission statement on SL"
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "News 1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Several International",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the International Monetary Fund",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Australian High Commission",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the European Union",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Senate Foreign Relations Committee",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the United States",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "China",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "India",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Chinese Foreign Ministry",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Spokesperson Zhao Lijan",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "China",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Indian Foreign Ministry",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Spokesperson Arindam Bagchi",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "India",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "US",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "Julie Chung",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "US",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "IMF",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "The Senate Foreign Relations Committee",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "first",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "China",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lankans",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Senate Foreign Relations Committee",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "The Australian High Commission",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Australia",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka’s",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        []
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "ශ්‍රී ලංකාව පිළිබඳ IMF මෙහෙවර ප්‍රකාශය සම්බන්ධයෙන් ජාත්‍යන්තර ප්‍රජාවෙන් ධනාත්මක ප්‍රතිචාරයක්",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); ඕස්ට්‍රේලියානු මහ කොමසාරිස් කාර්යාලය, යුරෝපා සංගමයේ නියෝජිතයින් සහ එක්සත් ජනපදයේ සෙනෙට් විදේශ සබඳතා කමිටුව ඇතුළු ජාත්‍යන්තර මූල්‍ය අරමුදල (IMF) සමඟ කාර්ය මණ්ඩල මට්ටමේ ගිවිසුමකට ශ්‍රී ලංකාව පැමිණීම සම්බන්ධයෙන් ජාත්‍යන්තර නියෝජිතයින් කිහිප දෙනෙකු ධනාත්මක ප්‍රතිචාර දක්වා ඇත.",
        "චීනය සහ ඉන්දියාව ද සිය හැඟීම් ප්‍රකාශ කළ අතර චීන විදේශ අමාත්‍යාංශයේ ප්‍රකාශක Zhao Lijan ප්‍රකාශ කළේ නිසි විසඳුම් සඳහා ශ්‍රී ලංකාව සමඟ සාකච්ඡා කිරීමේදී අදාළ මූල්‍ය ආයතනවලට චීනය සහාය දක්වන බවයි.",
        "මේ අතර, ඉන්දීය විදේශ අමාත්‍යාංශයේ ප්‍රකාශක Arindam Bagchi කියා සිටියේ මාණ්ඩලික ගිවිසුම වර්ධනය වෙමින් පවතින තත්වයක් බවත්, කෙසේ වෙතත්, ඉන්දියාව ශ්‍රී ලංකාවට සහය ඉල්ලා සිටින බවයි.",
        "පවතින ආර්ථික අර්බුදයෙන් මිදීමට ශ්‍රී ලංකාවට හැකි හොඳම මෙවලම්, ප්‍රවේශයන් සහ සම්පත් නියෝජනය කරන්නේ ජාත්‍යන්තර මූල්‍ය අරමුදල බැවින් ශ්‍රී ලංකාවට සහය වීමට එක්සත් ජනපදය සූදානම් බව ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ ඇමරිකානු තානාපතිනි ජුලී චුන්ග් සඳහන් කළාය.",
        "ජාත්‍යන්තර මූල්‍ය අරමුදලේ මූලික ගිවිසුම ශ්‍රී ලංකාව ආර්ථික ස්ථාවරත්වය කරා ගෙන යාමට සහ පද්ධතිමය දූෂණයට පිළියම් යෙදීමට වැදගත් පළමු පියවරක් බව සෙනෙට් විදේශ සබඳතා කමිටුව සඳහන් කළේය.",
        "“දැන් චීනය ඇතුළු ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ ණයහිමියන් ශ්‍රී ලාංකිකයන්ට අත්‍යවශ්‍ය ණය සහන ලබා දීම සඳහා සද්භාවයෙන් සාකච්ඡා කළ යුතුයි,” සෙනෙට් විදේශ සබඳතා කමිටුව ප්‍රකාශ කළේය.",
        "ඔස්ට්‍රේලියාව හැකි සෑම ආකාරයකින්ම සහයෝගය ලබා දීමට සූදානම් බව සඳහන් කළ ඕස්ට්‍රේලියානු මහ කොමසාරිස් කාර්යාලය, ජාත්‍යන්තර මූල්‍ය අරමුදල සමඟ කාර්ය මණ්ඩල මට්ටමේ ගිවිසුමකට එළඹීම පිළිබඳව ශ්‍රී ලංකාවට ප්‍රශංසා කළේය. එය ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ ආර්ථික ප්‍රකෘති ක්‍රියාවලියේ ඉදිරි පියවරක් බව ද මහ කොමසාරිස්වරයා පැවසීය.",
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකාව පිළිබඳ IMF මෙහෙවර ප්‍රකාශය සම්බන්ධයෙන් ජාත්‍යන්තර ප්‍රජාවෙන් ධනාත්මක ප්‍රතිචාරයක්"
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "News 1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජාත්යන්තර කිහිපයක්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජාත්‍යන්තර මුල්‍ය අරමුදල",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඕස්ට්‍රේලියානු මහ කොමසාරිස් කාර්යාලය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "යුරෝපා සංගමය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "සෙනෙට් විදේශ සබඳතා කමිටුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "එක්සත් ජනපදය",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "චීනය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "චීන විදේශ අමාත්‍යාංශය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ප්‍රකාශක Zhao Lijan",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "චීනය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දීය විදේශ අමාත්‍යාංශය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ප්‍රකාශක Arindam Bagchi",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "එක්සත් ජනපදය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජූලි චුන්ග්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "එක්සත් ජනපදය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "IMF",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "සෙනෙට් විදේශ සබඳතා කමිටුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "පළමුවන",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "චීනය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලාංකිකයන්",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "සෙනෙට් විදේශ සබඳතා කමිටුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ඕස්ට්‍රේලියානු මහ කොමසාරිස් කාර්යාලය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඕස්ට්රේලියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        []
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "SL பற்றிய IMF பணி அறிக்கைக்கு சர்வதேச சமூகத்தின் நேர்மறையான பதில்",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); ஆஸ்திரேலிய உயர் ஸ்தானிகராலயம், ஐரோப்பிய ஒன்றியத்தின் பிரதிநிதிகள் மற்றும் அமெரிக்காவின் செனட் வெளிநாட்டு உறவுகள் குழு உட்பட சர்வதேச நாணய நிதியத்துடன் (IMF) பணியாளர்கள் மட்ட உடன்படிக்கைக்கு இலங்கை வந்துள்ளதற்கு பல சர்வதேச தூதர்கள் சாதகமான எதிர்வினைகளை வெளிப்படுத்தியுள்ளனர்.",
        "சீனாவும் இந்தியாவும் தங்கள் உணர்வுகளை வெளிப்படுத்தியது, சீன வெளியுறவு அமைச்சகத்தின் செய்தித் தொடர்பாளர் ஜாவோ லிஜான், சரியான தீர்வுகளுக்கு இலங்கையுடன் கலந்தாலோசிப்பதில் தொடர்புடைய நிதி நிறுவனங்களுக்கு சீனா ஆதரவளிக்கிறது என்று கூறினார்.",
        "இதற்கிடையில், இந்திய வெளிவிவகார அமைச்சின் பேச்சாளர் அரிந்தம் பாக்சி, ஊழியர் ஒப்பந்தம் வளர்ந்து வரும் சூழ்நிலை என்று ஒப்புக்கொண்டார், இருப்பினும், இந்தியா இலங்கைக்கு உதவி செய்ய வாதிடுகிறது.",
        "இலங்கையில் நிலவும் பொருளாதார நெருக்கடியை சமாளிப்பதற்கு சர்வதேச நாணய நிதியம் சிறந்த கருவிகள், அணுகுமுறைகள் மற்றும் வளங்களை பிரதிநிதித்துவப்படுத்துவதால், இலங்கைக்கு உதவ அமெரிக்கா தயாராக இருப்பதாக இலங்கைக்கான அமெரிக்க தூதுவர் ஜூலி சுங் குறிப்பிட்டார்.",
        "இலங்கையை பொருளாதார ஸ்திரத்தன்மைக்கான பாதையில் கொண்டு செல்வதற்கும் முறையான ஊழலை நிவர்த்தி செய்வதற்கும் சர்வதேச நாணய நிதியத்தின் ஆரம்ப உடன்படிக்கை ஒரு முக்கியமான முதல் படியாகும் என செனட் வெளிநாட்டு உறவுகள் குழு குறிப்பிட்டுள்ளது.",
        "\"இப்போது சீனா உட்பட இலங்கையின் கடனாளிகள், இலங்கையர்களுக்கு மிகவும் தேவையான கடன் நிவாரணங்களை வழங்குவதற்கு நல்லெண்ணத்துடன் பேச்சுவார்த்தை நடத்த வேண்டும்\" என்று செனட் வெளிநாட்டு உறவுகள் குழு தெரிவித்துள்ளது.",
        "ஆஸ்திரேலிய உயர் ஸ்தானிகராலயம் முடிந்தவரை அனைத்து வழிகளிலும் ஆதரவை வழங்கத் தயாராக இருப்பதாகக் குறிப்பிட்டதுடன், சர்வதேச நாணய நிதியத்துடன் பணியாளர் மட்ட ஒப்பந்தத்தை எட்டியதற்காக இலங்கையைப் பாராட்டியது. இலங்கையின் பொருளாதார மீட்சி செயல்பாட்டில் இது வரவேற்கத்தக்க முன்னோக்கிய படி என்றும் உயர்ஸ்தானிகர் கூறினார்.",
        "SL பற்றிய IMF பணி அறிக்கைக்கு சர்வதேச சமூகத்தின் நேர்மறையான பதில்"
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "News 1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "பல சர்வதேச",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சர்வதேச நாணய நிதியம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆஸ்திரேலிய உயர் ஸ்தானிகராலயம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஐரோப்பிய ஒன்றியம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "செனட் வெளியுறவுக் குழு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஐக்கிய நாடுகள்",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "சீனா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்தியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சீன வெளியுறவு அமைச்சகம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "செய்தி தொடர்பாளர் ஜாவோ லிஜன்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "சீனா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இந்திய வெளியுறவு அமைச்சகம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "செய்தி தொடர்பாளர் அரிந்தம் பாக்சி",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்தியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "எங்களுக்கு",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜூலி சுங்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "எங்களுக்கு",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "IMF",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "செனட் வெளியுறவுக் குழு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "முதலில்",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சீனா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கையர்கள்",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "செனட் வெளியுறவுக் குழு",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஆஸ்திரேலிய உயர் ஸ்தானிகராலயம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆஸ்திரேலியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கையின்",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        []
      ]
    }
  }
}