{
  "newspaper_id": "daily-mirror-lk",
  "url": "https://www.dailymirror.lk/breaking_news/Tokyo-will-coordinate-with-other-Sri-Lanka-creditors-on-debt-Japan-Finance-Minister/108-243992",
  "time_ut": 1661837072,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Tokyo will coordinate with other Sri Lanka creditors on debt: Japan Finance Minister",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Tokyo will coordinate with other Sri Lanka creditors on debt: Japan Finance Minister",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "Japanese Finance Minister Shunichi Suzuki said on Tuesday it was important for all creditor nations of Sri Lanka to gather to discuss Colombo’s debt issue, adding that Tokyo would coordinate with other creditors on the matter.",
        "Sri Lanka’s President Ranil Wickremesinghe told Reuters last month that Sri Lanka would ask Japan to invite the main creditor nations to talks on restructuring bilateral debts, the Reuters reported.",
        "Earlier on Tuesday, Japanese Foreign Minister Yoshimasa Hayashi said his country was not in talks with Sri Lanka to hold such a meeting.",
        "“We are having various interactions with the Sri Lanka side, but no preparation is going on with Sri Lanka for holding such talks,” Hayashi told a regular news conference."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Tokyo",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "Sri Lanka",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "Japan",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Japanese",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Shunichi Suzuki",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Tuesday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Colombo",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Tokyo",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka’s",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Reuters",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "last month",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Japan",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Reuters",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Earlier on",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Tuesday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Japanese",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Yoshimasa Hayashi",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Hayashi",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "ටෝකියෝ අනෙකුත් ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ ණය හිමියන් සමඟ සම්බන්ධීකරණය කරනු ඇත: ජපාන මුදල් අමාත්‍ය",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "ජපාන මුදල් අමාත්‍ය Shunichi Suzuki අඟහරුවාදා ප්‍රකාශ කළේ, කොළඹ ණය ප්‍රශ්නය පිළිබඳව සාකච්ඡා කිරීම සඳහා ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ සියලුම ණයහිමි රටවල් එක්රැස් වීම වැදගත් වන අතර, ටෝකියෝ මෙම කාරණය සම්බන්ධයෙන් අනෙකුත් ණය හිමියන් සමඟ සම්බන්ධීකරණය කරන බව පැවසීය.",
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ ජනාධිපති රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ පසුගිය මාසයේ රොයිටර් පුවත් සේවයට ප්‍රකාශ කළේ ද්විපාර්ශ්වික ණය ප්‍රතිව්‍යුහගත කිරීම පිළිබඳ සාකච්ඡා සඳහා ප්‍රධාන ණය දෙන ජාතීන්ට ආරාධනා කරන ලෙස ශ්‍රී ලංකාව ජපානයෙන් ඉල්ලා සිටින බව ය.",
        "මීට පෙර අඟහරුවාදා ජපාන විදේශ අමාත්‍ය Yoshimasa Hayashi කියා සිටියේ එවැනි හමුවක් පැවැත්වීමට තම රට ශ්‍රී ලංකාව සමඟ සාකච්ඡා නොකරන බවයි.",
        "\"අපි ශ්‍රී ලංකා පාර්ශ්වය සමඟ විවිධ අන්තර්ක්‍රියා කරමින් සිටිමු, නමුත් එවැනි සාකච්ඡා පැවැත්වීම සඳහා ශ්‍රී ලංකාව සමඟ කිසිදු සූදානමක් සිදු නොවේ,\" Hayashi නිත්‍ය ප්‍රවෘත්ති සාකච්ඡාවකදී පැවසීය."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ටෝකියෝ",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "ජපානය",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ජපන්",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Shunichi Suzuki",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "අඟහරුවාදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "කොළඹ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ටෝකියෝ",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "රොයිටර්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "පසුගිය මාසයේ",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජපානය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "රොයිටර්",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "කලින්",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "අඟහරුවාදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජපන්",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Yoshimasa Hayashi",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Hayashi",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "டோக்கியோ மற்ற இலங்கை கடனாளிகளுடன் கடன் தொடர்பாக ஒருங்கிணைக்கும்: ஜப்பான் நிதி அமைச்சர்",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "கொழும்பின் கடன் பிரச்சினை குறித்து விவாதிக்க இலங்கையின் அனைத்து கடன் வழங்கும் நாடுகளும் ஒன்று கூடுவது முக்கியம் என்று ஜப்பானிய நிதி அமைச்சர் ஷுனிச்சி சுசுகி செவ்வாயன்று கூறினார், டோக்கியோ இந்த விஷயத்தில் மற்ற கடன் வழங்குநர்களுடன் ஒருங்கிணைக்கும் என்று கூறினார்.",
        "இலங்கையின் ஜனாதிபதி ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க கடந்த மாதம் ராய்ட்டர்ஸிடம், இருதரப்புக் கடன்களை மறுசீரமைப்பது தொடர்பான பேச்சுவார்த்தைக்கு பிரதான கடன் வழங்கும் நாடுகளை அழைக்குமாறு ஜப்பானை இலங்கை கேட்கும் என்று கூறியதாக ராய்ட்டர்ஸ் செய்தி வெளியிட்டுள்ளது.",
        "முன்னதாக செவ்வாய்கிழமை, ஜப்பானிய வெளிவிவகார அமைச்சர் யோஷிமாசா ஹயாஷி, அவ்வாறான ஒரு சந்திப்பை நடத்துவதற்கு தமது நாடு இலங்கையுடன் பேச்சுவார்த்தை நடத்தவில்லை என்று கூறினார்.",
        "\"நாங்கள் இலங்கை தரப்புடன் பல்வேறு தொடர்புகளை மேற்கொண்டு வருகிறோம், ஆனால் அத்தகைய பேச்சுவார்த்தைகளை நடத்துவதற்கான எந்த தயாரிப்பும் இலங்கையுடன் நடைபெறவில்லை\" என்று ஹயாஷி ஒரு வழக்கமான செய்தி மாநாட்டில் கூறினார்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "டோக்கியோ",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "இலங்கை",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "ஜப்பான்",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ஜப்பானியர்",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Shunichi Suzuki",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "செவ்வாய்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "கொழும்பு",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "டோக்கியோ",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கையின்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ராய்ட்டர்ஸ்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "கடந்த மாதம்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜப்பான்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ராய்ட்டர்ஸ்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "முன்னதாக",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "செவ்வாய்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜப்பானியர்",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Yoshimasa Hayashi",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Hayashi",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}