{
  "newspaper_id": "lankadeepa-lk",
  "url": "https://www.lankadeepa.lk/latest_news/බ්‍රිතාන්‍යයට-අද-අලුත්-අගමැතිවරයෙක්/1-619297",
  "time_ut": 1662353188,
  "original_lang": "si",
  "original_title": "බ්‍රිතාන්‍යයට අද අලුත් අගමැතිවරයෙක්",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Britain has a new prime minister today",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "The election of the new Prime Minister of Great Britain takes place today (5). The Prime Minister of Great Britain is the leader of the ruling party. Currently, the ruling party is the Conservative Party.",
        "The party leader is elected by the party's internal vote. The poll was conducted among Conservative Party delegates, party activists and party members and the results will be announced today.",
        "The battle for the leadership of the party is between the two main candidates, the current Foreign Minister Liz Truss and the former Finance Minister (Chancellor) Rishi Sunak.",
        "Liz Truss, 47, will be the third woman to become British prime minister after Theresa May and Margaret Thatcher if she wins the party leadership and becomes prime minister.",
        "Since Rishi Sunak, 42, is of Indian origin, if he wins, he will be the first person of Indian origin to become British Prime Minister.",
        "Britain's ruling party had to appoint a new leader because Boris Johnson, who held the party leadership as well as the position of Prime Minister, left it.",
        "Johnson lost the party leadership because his actions caused displeasure among party members.",
        "Accordingly, from last July polls were held to elect a new leader for the party. The two finalists were Liz Truss and Rishi Sunak."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Britain",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "today",
          "label": "DATE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Great Britain",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "5",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Great Britain",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Conservative Party",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Conservative Party",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "two",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Liz Truss",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Finance",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Rishi Sunak",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Liz Truss",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "47",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "third",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "British",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Theresa May",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Margaret Thatcher",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Rishi Sunak",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "42",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Indian",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "first",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Indian",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "British",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Britain",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Boris Johnson",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Johnson",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "last July",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "two",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Liz Truss",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Rishi Sunak",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "බ්‍රිතාන්‍යයට අද අලුත් අගමැතිවරයෙක්",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "මහා බ්‍රිතාන්‍යයේ නව අග්‍රාමාත්‍යවරයා තෝරා ගැනීම අද (5) සිදුවෙයි. මහා බ්‍රිතාන්‍යයේ අග්‍රාමාත්‍ය ධුරය හිමිවන්නේ, පාලක පක්ෂයේ නායකයාටය. වර්තමානයේ පාලක පක්ෂය ලෙස කටයුතු කරන්නේ කොන්සවර්ටිව් පක්ෂයයි.",
        "පක්ෂ නායකයා තෝරා ගැනීම සිදුවන්නේ පක්ෂ අභ්‍යන්තරයේ ඡන්දයෙනි. කොන්සවර්ටිව් පක්ෂ නියෝජිතයන්, පක්ෂ ක්‍රියාකාරීන් සහ පක්ෂ සාමාජිකයන් අතරේ ඡන්ද විමසුම පැවැත්වුණු අතර එහි ප්‍රතිඵල අද ප්‍රකාශයට පත් කෙරේ.",
        "පක්ෂ නායකත්වය වෙනුවෙන් සටන පවතින්නේ ඊට ඉදිරිපත් වුණු ප්‍රධානතම අපේක්ෂකයන් දෙදෙනා වන වත්මන් විදේශ අමාත්‍යවරිය ලිස් ට්‍රස් සහ හිටපු මුදල් අමාත්‍ය (චාන්සලර්) රිෂී සුනාක් අතරේය.",
        "47 හැවිරිදි ලිස් ට්‍රස් පක්ෂ නායකත්වය හිමිවී, අග්‍රාමාත්‍ය ධුරයට පත්වුවහොත්, තරේසා මේ සහ මාග්‍රට් තැචර්ගෙන් පසු බි්‍රතාන්‍ය අග්‍රාමාත්‍ය ධුරයට පත්වන තෙවැනි කාන්තාව වනු ඇත.",
        "42 හැවිරිදි රිෂී සුනාක් ඉන්දීය සම්භවයක් ඇත්තකු බැවින්, ඔහු ජයග්‍රහණය කළහොත්, බ්‍රිතාන්‍ය අග්‍රාමාත්‍ය ධුරයට පත් වන ඉන්දීය සම්භවයක් ඇති පළමු තැනැත්තා ඔහු වනු ඇත.",
        "බ්‍රිතාන්‍යයේ පාලක පක්ෂයට නව නායකයකු පත් කර ගැනීමට සිදුවූයේ පක්ෂ නායකත්වය මෙන්ම අග්‍රාමාත්‍ය ධුරය ද හෙබවූ බොරිස් ජොන්සන් ඉන් ඉවත් වූ බැවිනි.",
        "ජොන්සන් ට පක්ෂ නායකත්වය අහිමි වූයේ ඔහුගේ ක්‍රියාකලාපය පක්ෂ සාමාජිකයන්ගේ අප්‍රසාදයට හේතුවක් වුණු බැවිනි.",
        "ඒ අනුව, පසුගිය ජූලි මාසයේ සිට පක්ෂයට නව නායකයකු තෝරා ගැනීම සඳහා ඡන්ද විමසුම් පැවැත්විණි. අවසාන වටයට ආ අපේක්ෂකයන් දෙදෙනා වූයේ ලිස් ට්‍රස් සහ රිෂී සුනාක් ය."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "බ්රිතාන්යය",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "අද",
          "label": "DATE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "මහා බ්‍රිතාන්‍යය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "5",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "මහා බ්‍රිතාන්‍යය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "කොන්සර්වේටිව් පක්ෂය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "කොන්සර්වේටිව් පක්ෂය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "දෙක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ලිස් ට්‍රස්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "මූල්ය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "රිෂි සුනක්",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ලිස් ට්‍රස්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "47",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "තෙවන",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "බ්රිතාන්ය",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "තෙරේසා මේ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "මාග්රට් තැචර්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "රිෂි සුනක්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "42",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දීය",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "පළමුවන",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දීය",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "බ්රිතාන්ය",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "බ්රිතාන්යය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "බොරිස් ජොන්සන්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ජොන්සන්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "පසුගිය ජූලි",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "දෙක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ලිස් ට්‍රස්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "රිෂි සුනක්",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "பிரிட்டனுக்கு இன்று புதிய பிரதமர் பதவியேற்றார்",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "பிரித்தானியாவின் புதிய பிரதமர் தெரிவு இன்று (5) நடைபெறுகிறது. கிரேட் பிரிட்டனின் பிரதமர் ஆளும் கட்சியின் தலைவர். தற்போது ஆளும் கட்சியாக கன்சர்வேட்டிவ் கட்சி உள்ளது.",
        "கட்சியின் உள் வாக்கு மூலம் கட்சியின் தலைவர் தேர்ந்தெடுக்கப்படுகிறார். கன்சர்வேட்டிவ் கட்சி பிரதிநிதிகள், கட்சி ஆர்வலர்கள் மற்றும் கட்சி உறுப்பினர்கள் மத்தியில் கருத்துக்கணிப்பு நடத்தப்பட்டு முடிவுகள் இன்று அறிவிக்கப்படும்.",
        "கட்சியின் தலைமைப் பதவிக்கான போட்டி இரண்டு முக்கிய வேட்பாளர்களான தற்போதைய வெளியுறவு அமைச்சர் லிஸ் ட்ரஸ் மற்றும் முன்னாள் நிதியமைச்சர் (அதிபர்) ரிஷி சுனக் ஆகியோருக்கு இடையே உள்ளது.",
        "47 வயதான லிஸ் ட்ரஸ், கட்சித் தலைமைப் பதவியை வென்று பிரதமரானால், தெரசா மே, மார்கரெட் தாட்சர் ஆகியோருக்குப் பிறகு பிரிட்டன் பிரதமராகும் மூன்றாவது பெண்மணி ஆவார்.",
        "42 வயதான ரிஷி சுனக் இந்திய வம்சாவளியைச் சேர்ந்தவர் என்பதால், அவர் வெற்றி பெற்றால், பிரிட்டிஷ் பிரதமராகும் முதல் இந்திய வம்சாவளியைச் சேர்ந்தவர்.",
        "பிரித்தானியாவின் ஆளும் கட்சிக்கு புதிய தலைவரை நியமிக்க வேண்டியதாயிற்று, ஏனெனில் கட்சித் தலைமையையும் பிரதமர் பதவியையும் வகித்த போரிஸ் ஜான்சன் அதை விட்டு வெளியேறினார்.",
        "ஜான்சனின் நடவடிக்கைகள் கட்சி உறுப்பினர்களிடையே அதிருப்தியை ஏற்படுத்தியதால் கட்சித் தலைமையை இழந்தார்.",
        "அதன்படி, கடந்த ஜூலை மாதம் முதல் அக்கட்சிக்கு புதிய தலைவரை தேர்ந்தெடுப்பதற்கான தேர்தல் நடைபெற்றது. இரண்டு இறுதிப் போட்டியாளர்கள் லிஸ் டிரஸ் மற்றும் ரிஷி சுனக்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "பிரிட்டன்",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "இன்று",
          "label": "DATE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "இங்கிலாந்து",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "5",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "இங்கிலாந்து",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "கன்சர்வேடிவ் கட்சி",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "கன்சர்வேடிவ் கட்சி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இரண்டு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "லிஸ் டிரஸ்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "நிதி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரிஷி சுனக்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "லிஸ் டிரஸ்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "47",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "மூன்றாவது",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "பிரிட்டிஷ்",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "தெரசா மே",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "மார்கரெட் தாட்சர்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ரிஷி சுனக்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "42",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்தியன்",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "முதலில்",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்தியன்",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "பிரிட்டிஷ்",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பிரிட்டன்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "போரிஸ் ஜான்சன்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஜான்சன்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "கடந்த ஜூலை",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இரண்டு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "லிஸ் டிரஸ்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரிஷி சுனக்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}