{
  "newspaper_id": "island-lk",
  "url": "http://island.lk/jica-launches-three-year-technical-cooperation-project-with-slcg-on-oil-spill-response-capability-improvement/",
  "time_ut": 1662306000,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "JICA launches three-year technical cooperation project with SLCG on oil spill response capability improvement",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "JICA launches three-year technical cooperation project with SLCG on oil spill response capability improvement",
      "author": "Thilina Walpola",
      "body_lines": [
        "Japan International Cooperation Agency (JICA) launched a three year new technical cooperation project together with Japan Coast Guard (JCG) and Sri Lanka Coast Guard(SLCG) in further assisting SLCG to establish an in-house oil spill response training system, an extension of past cooperation on oil spill incident management techniques.",
        "Sri Lanka located on the important maritime transport route between Asia and Europe/ Middle-east, a maritime accident would have major impacts on safe navigation of vessels, maritime environment and economic activities of the region. SLCG is recognized as one of the principal players to combat maritime oil spill incidents and JICA has extended its continuous support to SLCG since 2014 up to now, including provision of two (2) patrol vessels tailored in Japan and continuous technical training to enhance SLCG’s response capacity.",
        "Following the project Kickoff in July 2022, a JICA mission has been deployed to Sri Lanka Coast Guard from 29th August to 2nd September that consists of three (3) JCG officers including the Mobile Cooperation Team as JICA Experts and a Senior Advisor of JICA HQs to commence project activities in Sri Lanka. JICA Expert members conducted an inspection of the SLCG patrol vessel 501 Samudraraksha, and 502 Samaraksha which were handed over to SLCG in year 2018, and oil spill combat equipment expected to be used in the practical training sessions. 22 trained SLCG instructors are expected to receive additional intensive training in Japan and Sri Lanka through transfer of knowledge and skills used by JCG under Japan’s Official Development Assistance. A Joint Coordinating Committee Meeting was held between SLCG, JCG and JICA on 30th August to finalize the project approach including its operational plan for the next 3 years.",
        "“We are very grateful to SLCG for maintaining the vessels and equipment that JICA has granted in proper conditions. It is our expectation that SLCG will utilize this opportunity to further strengthen its capacity to combat oil spills and establish a sustainable mechanism to preserve the knowledge within SLCG. JICA and JCG team look forward to giving our best support in the next 3 years” said, TSUCHIYA Koji JICA Senior Advisor.",
        "NSB becomes Most Popular Banking & Finance Website for second consecutive year",
        "Pakistan finance chief wants nation to live within its means",
        "Leave a Reply Cancel replyYour email address will not be published. Required fields are marked *Comment Name *",
        "Save my name, email, and website in this browser for the next time I comment."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "JICA",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "three-year",
          "label": "DATE"
        },
        {
          "text": "SLCG",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Japan International Cooperation Agency",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "JICA",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "three year",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Japan Coast Guard",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "JCG",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka Coast",
            "label": "LOC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Asia",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "SLCG",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "JICA",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "SLCG",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "2014",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "two",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "2",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Japan",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "SLCG",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Kickoff",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "July 2022",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "JICA",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka Coast Guard",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "29th August to 2nd September",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "three",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "3",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Mobile Cooperation Team",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "SLCG",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "501",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "502",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "year 2018",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "22",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Japan",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "JCG",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Japan",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Joint Coordinating Committee Meeting",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "SLCG",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "JCG",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "JICA",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "30th August",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the next 3 years",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "JICA",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "SLCG",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "JICA",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "JCG",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the next 3 years",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "NSB",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Popular Banking & Finance",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "second consecutive year",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Pakistan",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [],
        []
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "JICA තෙල් කාන්දු ප්‍රතිචාර හැකියාව වැඩිදියුණු කිරීම සඳහා SLCG සමඟ තෙවසරක තාක්ෂණික සහයෝගීතා ව්‍යාපෘතිය දියත් කරයි",
      "author": "තිළිණ වල්පොල",
      "body_lines": [
        "ජපාන ජාත්‍යන්තර සහයෝගිතා නියෝජිතායතනය (JICA) ජපාන වෙරළාරක්‍ෂක බලකාය (JCG) සහ ශ්‍රී ලංකා වෙරළාරක්‍ෂක බලකාය (SLCG) සමඟ එක්ව තෙවසරක නව තාක්ෂණික සහයෝගිතා ව්‍යාපෘතියක් දියත් කළේ SLCG අභ්‍යන්තර තෙල් කාන්දු ප්‍රතිචාර පුහුණු පද්ධතියක් ස්ථාපිත කිරීම සඳහා තවදුරටත් සහාය වීම සඳහා ය. තෙල් කාන්දුවීම් කළමනාකරණ ශිල්පීය ක්‍රම පිළිබඳ අතීත සහයෝගීතාව.",
        "ආසියාව සහ යුරෝපය/මැදපෙරදිග අතර වැදගත් සමුද්‍රීය ප්‍රවාහන මාර්ගයේ ශ්‍රී ලංකාව පිහිටා ඇති අතර, සමුද්‍ර අනතුරක් යාත්‍රා වල ආරක්ෂිත නාවික ගමනාගමනයට, සමුද්‍රීය පරිසරයට සහ කලාපයේ ආර්ථික ක්‍රියාකාරකම් කෙරෙහි විශාල බලපෑමක් ඇති කරයි. SLCG සමුද්‍රීය තෙල් කාන්දුවීම් වලට එරෙහිව සටන් කිරීමේ ප්‍රධාන ක්‍රීඩකයෙකු ලෙස පිළිගැනෙන අතර JICA 2014 සිට මේ දක්වා SLCG වෙත සිය අඛණ්ඩ සහයෝගය ලබා දී ඇති අතර, ජපානයේ සකස් කරන ලද (2) මුර යාත්‍රා දෙකක් ලබා දීම සහ SLCG හි ප්‍රතිචාරය වැඩි දියුණු කිරීම සඳහා අඛණ්ඩ තාක්ෂණික පුහුණුව ඇතුළත් වේ. ධාරිතාව.",
        "2022 ජුලි මාසයේ කික්ඕෆ් ව්‍යාපෘතියෙන් පසුව, JICA විශේෂඥයින් ලෙස ජංගම සහයෝගිතා කණ්ඩායම ඇතුළු JCG නිලධාරීන් තිදෙනෙකු සහ JICA මූලස්ථානවල ජ්‍යෙෂ්ඨ උපදේශකයෙකුගෙන් සමන්විත JICA මෙහෙයුමක් අගෝස්තු 29 සිට සැප්තැම්බර් 2 දක්වා ශ්‍රී ලංකා වෙරළාරක්ෂක බලකායට යොදවා ඇත. ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ ව්‍යාපෘති කටයුතු ආරම්භ කිරීම. JICA විශේෂඥ සාමාජිකයින් විසින් 2018 වර්ෂයේදී SLCG වෙත භාර දුන් SLCG මුර යාත්‍රා 501 සමුද්‍රාරක්ෂා සහ 502 සමරක්‍ෂා සහ ප්‍රායෝගික පුහුණු සැසි සඳහා භාවිතා කිරීමට අපේක්ෂිත තෙල් කාන්දුවීම් මර්දන උපකරණ පරීක්ෂා කරන ලදී. පුහුණු SLCG උපදේශකයින් 22 දෙනෙකු ජපානයේ නිල සංවර්ධන ආධාර යටතේ JCG විසින් භාවිතා කරන දැනුම හා කුසලතා හුවමාරු කිරීම හරහා ජපානයේ සහ ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ අමතර දැඩි පුහුණුවක් ලබා ගැනීමට අපේක්ෂා කෙරේ. ඉදිරි වසර 3 සඳහා එහි මෙහෙයුම් සැලැස්ම ඇතුළුව ව්‍යාපෘති ප්‍රවේශය අවසන් කිරීම සඳහා SLCG, JCG සහ JICA අතර ඒකාබද්ධ සම්බන්ධීකරණ කමිටු රැස්වීමක් අගෝස්තු 30 වන දින පැවැත්විණි.",
        "“JICA විසින් ලබා දී ඇති යාත්‍රා සහ උපකරණ නිසි තත්ත්‍වයේ පවත්වාගෙන යාම පිළිබඳව SLCG ආයතනයට අපි බෙහෙවින් ස්තූතිවන්ත වෙනවා. SLCG තෙල් කාන්දුවීම් වලට එරෙහිව සටන් කිරීමට සහ SLCG තුළ ඇති දැනුම සුරැකීමට තිරසාර යාන්ත්‍රණයක් ස්ථාපිත කිරීමට ඇති හැකියාව තවදුරටත් ශක්තිමත් කිරීමට මෙම අවස්ථාව ප්‍රයෝජනයට ගනු ඇතැයි අපගේ අපේක්ෂාවයි. JICA සහ JCG කණ්ඩායම ඉදිරි වසර 3 තුළ අපගේ උපරිම සහයෝගය ලබා දීමට බලාපොරොත්තු වෙනවා” යනුවෙන් TSUCHIYA Koji JICA ජ්‍යෙෂ්ඨ උපදේශක පැවසීය.",
        "NSB අඛණ්ඩව දෙවන වසර සඳහා වඩාත්ම ජනප්‍රිය බැංකු සහ මූල්‍ය වෙබ් අඩවිය බවට පත් වේ",
        "පකිස්තාන මූල්‍ය ප්‍රධානියාට අවශ්‍ය වන්නේ ජාතිය තම හැකියාව තුළ ජීවත් වීමටයි",
        "පිළිතුරක් දෙන්න පිළිතුර අවලංගු කරන්න ඔබගේ විද්‍යුත් තැපැල් ලිපිනය ප්‍රකාශයට පත් නොකෙරේ. අවශ්‍ය ක්ෂේත්‍ර සලකුණු කර ඇත *අදහස් නම *",
        "මම ඊළඟ වතාවේ අදහස් දැක්වීම සඳහා මගේ නම, විද්‍යුත් තැපෑල සහ වෙබ් අඩවිය මෙම බ්‍රවුසරයේ සුරකින්න."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ජයිකා",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "අවුරුදු තුනක්",
          "label": "DATE"
        },
        {
          "text": "SLCG",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ජපාන ජාත්‍යන්තර සහයෝගිතා ඒජන්සිය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජයිකා",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "වසර තුනක්",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජපාන වෙරළාරක්ෂක බලකාය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "JCG",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකා වෙරළ තීරය",
            "label": "LOC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ආසියාව",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "SLCG",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජයිකා",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "SLCG",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "2014",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "දෙක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "2",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජපානය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "SLCG",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "පටන් ගන්න",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "2022 ජූලි",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජයිකා",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකා වෙරළාරක්ෂක බලකාය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "අගෝස්තු 29 සිට සැප්තැම්බර් 2 දක්වා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "තුන්",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "3",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජංගම සහයෝගිතා කණ්ඩායම",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "SLCG",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "501",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "502",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "වසර 2018",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "22",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජපානය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "JCG",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජපානය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඒකාබද්ධ සම්බන්ධීකරණ කමිටු රැස්වීම",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "SLCG",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "JCG",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජයිකා",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "අගෝස්තු 30",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉදිරි වසර 3",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ජයිකා",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "SLCG",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජයිකා",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "JCG",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉදිරි වසර 3",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "NSB",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජනප්‍රිය බැංකු සහ මුල්‍ය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "අඛණ්ඩව දෙවන වසර",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "පකිස්ථානය",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [],
        []
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "JICA எண்ணெய் கசிவு மறுமொழி திறன் மேம்பாட்டில் SLCG உடன் மூன்று ஆண்டு தொழில்நுட்ப ஒத்துழைப்பு திட்டத்தை அறிமுகப்படுத்துகிறது",
      "author": "திலின வல்பொல",
      "body_lines": [
        "ஜப்பான் சர்வதேச ஒத்துழைப்பு நிறுவனம் (JICA) ஜப்பான் கடலோர காவல்படை (JCG) மற்றும் இலங்கை கடலோர காவல்படை (SLCG) இணைந்து மூன்று வருட புதிய தொழில்நுட்ப ஒத்துழைப்பு திட்டத்தை அறிமுகப்படுத்தியது. எண்ணெய் கசிவு சம்பவ மேலாண்மை நுட்பங்களில் கடந்தகால ஒத்துழைப்பு.",
        "ஆசியா மற்றும் ஐரோப்பா/மத்திய கிழக்கு நாடுகளுக்கு இடையிலான முக்கியமான கடல் போக்குவரத்து பாதையில் அமைந்துள்ள இலங்கையானது, கப்பல்களின் பாதுகாப்பான வழிசெலுத்தல், கடல் சூழல் மற்றும் பிராந்தியத்தின் பொருளாதார நடவடிக்கைகளில் ஒரு கடல் விபத்து பெரும் தாக்கத்தை ஏற்படுத்தும். SLCG ஆனது கடல்சார் எண்ணெய் கசிவு சம்பவங்களை எதிர்த்துப் போராடுவதில் முதன்மையான வீரர்களில் ஒன்றாக அங்கீகரிக்கப்பட்டுள்ளது மற்றும் JICA 2014 முதல் SLCG க்கு அதன் தொடர்ச்சியான ஆதரவை வழங்கியுள்ளது, இதில் ஜப்பானில் வடிவமைக்கப்பட்ட இரண்டு (2) ரோந்து கப்பல்கள் மற்றும் SLCG இன் பதிலை மேம்படுத்த தொடர்ச்சியான தொழில்நுட்ப பயிற்சி ஆகியவை அடங்கும். திறன்.",
        "2022 ஆம் ஆண்டு ஜூலை மாதம் கிக்ஆஃப் திட்டத்தைத் தொடர்ந்து, JICA நிபுணர்கள் மற்றும் JICA தலைமையகங்களின் மூத்த ஆலோசகர் உட்பட மூன்று (3) JCG அதிகாரிகளை உள்ளடக்கிய மூன்று (3) JCG அதிகாரிகளை கொண்ட ஒரு JICA பணியானது ஆகஸ்ட் 29 முதல் செப்டம்பர் 2 வரை இலங்கை கடலோர காவல்படைக்கு அனுப்பப்பட்டது. இலங்கையில் திட்ட நடவடிக்கைகளை ஆரம்பிக்கவும். JICA நிபுணர் உறுப்பினர்கள் SLCG ரோந்துக் கப்பல் 501 சமுத்திரரக்ஷா மற்றும் 2018 ஆம் ஆண்டில் SLCG க்கு ஒப்படைக்கப்பட்ட 502 சமரக்ஷா மற்றும் நடைமுறை பயிற்சி அமர்வுகளில் பயன்படுத்தப்படும் என்று எதிர்பார்க்கப்படும் எண்ணெய் கசிவு போர் உபகரணங்களை ஆய்வு செய்தனர். 22 பயிற்சி பெற்ற SLCG பயிற்றுனர்கள் ஜப்பானின் உத்தியோகபூர்வ அபிவிருத்தி உதவியின் கீழ் JCG பயன்படுத்தும் அறிவு மற்றும் திறன்களை மாற்றுவதன் மூலம் ஜப்பான் மற்றும் இலங்கையில் கூடுதல் தீவிர பயிற்சி பெறுவார்கள் என்று எதிர்பார்க்கப்படுகிறது. SLCG, JCG மற்றும் JICA ஆகியவற்றுக்கு இடையேயான ஒரு கூட்டு ஒருங்கிணைப்புக் குழுக் கூட்டம் ஆகஸ்ட் 30 அன்று அதன் அடுத்த 3 ஆண்டுகளுக்கான செயல்பாட்டுத் திட்டம் உட்பட திட்ட அணுகுமுறையை இறுதி செய்தது.",
        "“JICA வழங்கிய கப்பல்கள் மற்றும் உபகரணங்களை முறையான சூழ்நிலையில் பராமரித்த SLCGக்கு நாங்கள் மிகவும் நன்றியுள்ளவர்களாக இருக்கிறோம். எண்ணெய் கசிவை எதிர்த்துப் போராடுவதற்கான அதன் திறனை மேலும் வலுப்படுத்தவும் மற்றும் SLCG க்குள் அறிவைப் பாதுகாக்க ஒரு நிலையான பொறிமுறையை நிறுவவும் SLCG இந்த வாய்ப்பைப் பயன்படுத்திக்கொள்ளும் என்பது எங்கள் எதிர்பார்ப்பு. JICA மற்றும் JCG குழு அடுத்த 3 ஆண்டுகளில் எங்களின் சிறந்த ஆதரவை வழங்க எதிர்நோக்குகிறோம்\" என்று TSUCHIYA Koji JICA மூத்த ஆலோசகர் கூறினார்.",
        "NSB தொடர்ந்து இரண்டாவது ஆண்டாக மிகவும் பிரபலமான வங்கி மற்றும் நிதி இணையதளம் ஆகும்",
        "பாக்கிஸ்தான் நிதித் தலைவர் தேசம் அதன் எல்லைக்குள் வாழ வேண்டும் என்று விரும்புகிறார்",
        "ஒரு பதிலை விடுங்கள் பதிலை ரத்துசெய் உங்கள் மின்னஞ்சல் முகவரி வெளியிடப்படாது. தேவையான புலங்கள் குறிக்கப்பட்டுள்ளன *கருத்து பெயர் *",
        "அடுத்த முறை நான் கருத்து தெரிவிக்க, எனது பெயர், மின்னஞ்சல் மற்றும் இணையதளத்தை இந்த உலாவியில் சேமிக்கவும்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "JICA",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "மூன்று ஆண்டுகள்",
          "label": "DATE"
        },
        {
          "text": "எஸ்.எல்.சி.ஜி",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ஜப்பான் சர்வதேச ஒத்துழைப்பு நிறுவனம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "JICA",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "மூன்று வருடம்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜப்பான் கடலோர காவல்படை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜே.சி.ஜி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை கடற்கரை",
            "label": "LOC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆசியா",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "எஸ்.எல்.சி.ஜி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "JICA",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "எஸ்.எல்.சி.ஜி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "2014",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இரண்டு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "2",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜப்பான்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "எஸ்.எல்.சி.ஜி",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "கிக்ஆஃப்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜூலை 2022",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "JICA",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை கடலோர காவல்படை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆகஸ்ட் 29 முதல் செப்டம்பர் 2 வரை",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "மூன்று",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "3",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "மொபைல் ஒத்துழைப்பு குழு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "எஸ்.எல்.சி.ஜி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "501",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "502",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆண்டு 2018",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "22",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜப்பான்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜே.சி.ஜி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜப்பான்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "கூட்டு ஒருங்கிணைப்புக் குழு கூட்டம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "எஸ்.எல்.சி.ஜி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜே.சி.ஜி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "JICA",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆகஸ்ட் 30",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "அடுத்த 3 ஆண்டுகள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "JICA",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "எஸ்.எல்.சி.ஜி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "JICA",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜே.சி.ஜி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "அடுத்த 3 ஆண்டுகள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "என்.எஸ்.பி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "பிரபலமான வங்கி & நிதி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "தொடர்ந்து இரண்டாவது ஆண்டு",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பாகிஸ்தான்",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [],
        []
      ]
    }
  }
}