{
  "newspaper_id": "lankadeepa-lk",
  "url": "https://www.lankadeepa.lk/news/රාජිතගේ-නැව්-අටේ-නඩුව-ඉල්ලා-අස්කර-ගනී/101-617021",
  "time_ut": 1658752723,
  "original_lang": "si",
  "original_title": "රාජිතගේ නැව් අටේ නඩුව ඉල්ලා අස්කර ගනී",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Rajitha's eight-ship case is withdrawn",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "The Criminal Investigation Department, Colombo Additional Magistrate Mr. Keminda Perera announced today (25) that the case regarding the bringing of 08 ships to Sri Lanka and the leasing of Modara fishing port during the tenure of MP Rajitha Senaratne as the Minister of Fisheries will be withdrawn.",
        "The Criminal Investigation Department informed the court that since the Bribery Commission has filed a case against Parliamentarian Mr. Rajitha Senaratne under the charge of 'corruption' in relation to this incident, the case pending in this court will be withdrawn.",
        "Accordingly, the Magistrate allowed the CID to withdraw the case.",
        "These facts were presented today (25) when the Magistrate's inquiry related to the incident was called.",
        "State Minister Sanath Nishantha Perera had submitted a complaint to the Criminal Investigation Department regarding this incident stating that these 08 ships had been brought to Sri Lanka under an agreement with a Chinese company in the name of Don Lalith Anuradha Seneviratne, who worked as a coordination secretary of former Fisheries Minister Rajitha Senaratne.",
        "Also, it has been reported to the court that the prosecution has asked the Criminal Investigation Department to start an investigation regarding the lease of Modara port to a foreign company mentioned in the complaint."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Rajitha",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "eight",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "The Criminal Investigation Department",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Colombo Additional Magistrate",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Keminda Perera",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "25",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "08",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Modara",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Rajitha Senaratne",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "The Criminal Investigation Department",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Bribery Commission",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliamentarian",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Rajitha Senaratne",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Magistrate",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "CID",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "25",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Magistrate",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sanath Nishantha",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Criminal Investigation Department",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "08",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Chinese",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Anuradha Seneviratne",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Fisheries",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Rajitha Senaratne",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the Criminal Investigation Department",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Modara",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "රාජිතගේ නැව් අටේ නඩුව ඉල්ලා අස්කර ගනී",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "පාර්ලිමේන්තු මන්ත්‍රී රාජිත සේනාරත්න මහතා ධීවර අමාත්‍යවරයා වශයෙන් කටයුතු කළ සමයේ නෞකා 08ක් මෙරටට ගෙන්වීම සහ මෝදර ධීවර වරාය බදුදීම සම්බන්ධයෙන් වන නඩුව ඉල්ලා අස්කර ගන්නා බව අපරාධ පරික්ෂණ දෙපාර්ත්මේන්තුව කොළඹ අතිරේක මහේස්ත්‍රාත් කේමින්ද පෙරේරා මහතා අද (25) ප්‍රකාශ කළේය.",
        "මෙම සිද්ධියට අදාළව ‘දූෂණය’ චෝදනාව යටතේ අල්ලස් කොමිසම පාර්ලිමේන්තු මන්ත්‍රි රාජිත සේනාරත්න මහතාට එරෙහිව නඩුවක් ගොනුකර කටයුතු කර ඇති බැවින් මෙම අධිකරණයේ පවතින නඩුව ඉල්ලා අස්කර ගන්නා බව අපරාධ පරීක්ෂණ දෙපාර්තමේන්තුව අධිකරණයට එලෙස දැනුම් දුන්නේය.",
        "ඒ අනුව, එම නඩුව ඉල්ලා අස්කර ගැනීමට මහේස්ත්‍රාත්වරයා අපරාධ පරීක්ෂණ දෙපාර්තමේන්තුවට අවසර ලබා දුන්නේය.",
        "සිද්ධියට අදාළ මහේස්ත්‍රාත් පරීක්ෂණය හමුවේ අද (25) කැදවූ අවස්ථාවේදී මෙම කරුණු ඉදිරිපත් විණී.",
        "හිටපු ධීවර අමාත්‍ය රාජිත සේනාරත්න මහතාගේ සම්බන්ධීකරණ ලේකම්වරයකු ලෙස කටයුතු කළ දොන් ලලිත් අනුරාධ සෙනෙවිරත්න යන අය නමින් මෙම නැව් 08 චීන සමාගමක් සමඟ ගිවිසුමකින් මෙරටට ගෙන්වා ඇතැයි සදහන් කරමින් මෙම සිද්ධිය සම්බන්ධයෙන් අපරාධ පරික්ෂණ දෙපාර්තමේන්තුවට පැමිණීල්ලක් ඉදිරිපත් කර තිබුණේ රාජ්‍ය අමාත්‍ය සනත් නිශාන්ත පෙරේරා මහතා විසිනි.",
        "එමෙන්ම, අසාදුලේඛනයේ සදහන් විදෙස් සමාගමකට මෝදර වරාය බදුදී තිබීම සම්බන්ධයෙන් ද පරීක්ෂණයක් අරම්භ කරන ලෙසට පැමිණීල්ල අපරාධ පරීක්ෂණ දෙපාර්තමේන්තුවෙන් ඉල්ලා ඇතැයි අධිකරණයට කරුණු වාර්තා වී ඇත."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "රාජිත",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "අට",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "අපරාධ පරීක්ෂණ දෙපාර්තමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "කොළඹ අතිරේක මහේස්ත්‍රාත්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "කේමින්ද පෙරේරා",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "25",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "08",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මෝදර",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "රාජිත සේනාරත්න",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "අපරාධ පරීක්ෂණ දෙපාර්තමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "අල්ලස් කොමිසම",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තු මන්ත්‍රී",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "රාජිත සේනාරත්න",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "මහේස්ත්රාත්වරයා",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "CID",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "25",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "මහේස්ත්රාත්වරයා",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "සනත් නිශාන්ත",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "අපරාධ පරීක්ෂණ දෙපාර්තමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "08",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "චීන",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "අනුරාධ සෙනෙවිරත්න",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ධීවර",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "රාජිත සේනාරත්න",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "අපරාධ පරීක්ෂණ දෙපාර්තමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "මෝදර",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "ராஜிதவின் எட்டு கப்பல் வழக்கு வாபஸ்",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "பாராளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர் ராஜித சேனாரத்ன கடற்றொழில் அமைச்சராக இருந்த காலத்தில் 08 கப்பல்களை இலங்கைக்கு கொண்டு வந்தமை மற்றும் மோதர மீன்பிடி துறைமுகத்தை குத்தகைக்கு வழங்கியமை தொடர்பான வழக்கு விசாரணைக்கு எடுத்துக்கொள்ளப்படும் என குற்றப் புலனாய்வு திணைக்களம் கொழும்பு மேலதிக நீதவான் திரு.கெமிந்த பெரேரா இன்று (25) அறிவித்தார். திரும்பப் பெறப்படும்.",
        "இந்த சம்பவம் தொடர்பில் இலஞ்ச ஊழல் ஆணைக்குழு நாடாளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர் ராஜித சேனாரத்னவுக்கு எதிராக ஊழல் குற்றச்சாட்டின் கீழ் வழக்குத் தாக்கல் செய்துள்ளதால், இந்த நீதிமன்றத்தில் நிலுவையில் உள்ள வழக்கை வாபஸ் பெறுவதாக குற்றப் புலனாய்வுத் திணைக்களம் நீதிமன்றில் தெரிவித்துள்ளது.",
        "அதன்படி வழக்கை வாபஸ் பெற சிஐடிக்கு மாஜிஸ்திரேட் அனுமதி அளித்தார்.",
        "சம்பவம் தொடர்பான நீதவான் விசாரணைக்கு இன்று (25) அழைப்பு விடுக்கப்பட்ட போதே இந்த உண்மைகள் முன்வைக்கப்பட்டன.",
        "இராஜாங்க அமைச்சர் சனத் நிஷாந்த பெரேரா, இந்த சம்பவம் தொடர்பில் குற்றப் புலனாய்வு திணைக்களத்தில் முறைப்பாடு செய்திருந்த நிலையில், இந்த 08 கப்பல்களும், ஒருங்கிணைப்புச் செயலாளராகப் பணியாற்றிய டொன் லலித் அனுராத செனவிரத்னவின் பெயரில் சீன நிறுவனத்துடன் ஒப்பந்தம் செய்து கொண்டு இலங்கைக்குக் கொண்டுவரப்பட்டதாகத் தெரிவித்துள்ளார். முன்னாள் மீன்பிடி அமைச்சர் ராஜித சேனாரத்னவின்.",
        "அத்துடன், முறைப்பாட்டில் குறிப்பிடப்பட்டுள்ள மோதர துறைமுகத்தை வெளிநாட்டு நிறுவனத்திற்கு குத்தகைக்கு வழங்கியமை தொடர்பில் விசாரணைகளை ஆரம்பிக்குமாறு குற்றப் புலனாய்வுத் திணைக்களத்திடம் அரசாங்கத் தரப்பு கோரியுள்ளதாக நீதிமன்றில் தெரிவிக்கப்பட்டுள்ளது."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ராஜிதா",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "எட்டு",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "குற்றப் புலனாய்வுத் துறை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "கொழும்பு மேலதிக நீதவான்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "கெமிந்த பெரேரா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "25",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "08",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "மோதர",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ராஜித சேனாரத்ன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "குற்றப் புலனாய்வுத் துறை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலஞ்ச ஆணைக்குழு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர்",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ராஜித சேனாரத்ன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "மாஜிஸ்திரேட்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "சி.ஐ.டி",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "25",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "மாஜிஸ்திரேட்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "சனத் நிஷாந்த",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "குற்றப் புலனாய்வுத் துறை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "08",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சீன",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "அனுராதா செனவிரத்ன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "மீன்வளம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ராஜித சேனாரத்ன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "குற்றப் புலனாய்வுத் துறை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "மோதர",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}