{
  "newspaper_id": "lankadeepa-lk",
  "url": "https://www.lankadeepa.lk/news/ඉන්දියානු-මහ-කොමසාරිස්-කාර්යාලයෙන්-නිවේදනයක්/101-616741",
  "time_ut": 1658303686,
  "original_lang": "si",
  "original_title": "ඉන්දියානු මහ කොමසාරිස් කාර්යාලයෙන් නිවේදනයක්",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "An announcement from the Indian High Commission",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "The Indian High Commission in Sri Lanka has issued a statement saying that it strongly rejects the baseless and speculative media reports that India exerted pressure on Sri Lankan political leaders during the vote held in Parliament today (20) to elect the successor president of Sri Lanka.",
        "According to the statement, the Indian High Commission once again emphasizes that India will provide support at all times to achieve the aspirations of Sri Lankans in accordance with the democratic methods and values ​​as well as the constitutional provisions through the established constitutional institutions.",
        "The Indian High Commission stated that India will never interfere in the internal affairs or democratic process of another country."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "the Indian High Commission",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "The Indian High Commission",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "India",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lankan",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "20",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the Indian High Commission",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "India",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lankans",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "The Indian High Commission",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "India",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "ඉන්දියානු මහ කොමසාරිස් කාර්යාලයෙන් නිවේදනයක්",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ අනුප්‍රාප්තික ජනාධිපතිවරයා තෝරා ගැනීම සඳහා අද (20) පාර්ලිමේන්තුවේ පැවති ඡන්දයේදී ඉන්දියාව ශ්‍රී ලංකා දේශපාලන නායකයින්ට බලපෑම් එල්ල කළා යැයි පළවන පදනම් විරහිත මෙන්ම අනුමාන මත පළ වී ඇති මාධ්‍ය වාර්තා තරයේ ප්‍රතික්ෂේප කරන බව ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ ඉන්දියානු මහ කොමසාරිස් කාර්යාලය නිවේදනයක් නිකුත් කරමින් ප්‍රකාශ කළේය.",
        "ස්ථාපිත කර ඇති ව්‍යවස්ථාපිත ආයතන ඔස්සේ ප්‍රජාතන්ත්‍රවාදී ක්‍රමවේදයන් සහ වටිනාකම් මෙන්ම ආණ්ඩුක්‍රම ව්‍යවස්ථා විධිවිධාන වලට අනුකූලව ශ්‍රී ලාංකිකයන්ගේ අභිලාෂයන් සාක්ෂාත් කර ගැනීම සඳහා ඉන්දියාව සෑම අවස්ථාවකදීම සහාය ලබා දෙන බව ඉන්දියානු මහ කොමසාරිස් කාර්යාලය නැවත වරක් අවධාරණය කරන බව එම නිවේදනයේ දැක්වේ.",
        "ඉන්දියාව තවත් රටක අභ්‍යන්තර කටයුතුවලට හෝ  ප්‍රජාතන්ත්‍රවාදී ක්‍රියාවලියකට කිසිම විටකත් මැදිහත් නොවන බව ඉන්දීය මහ කොමසාරිස් කාර්යාලය ප්‍රකාශ කළේය."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ඉන්දීය මහ කොමසාරිස් කාර්යාලය",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දීය මහ කොමසාරිස් කාර්යාලය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලාංකික",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "20",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දීය මහ කොමසාරිස් කාර්යාලය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලාංකිකයන්",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දීය මහ කොමසාරිස් කාර්යාලය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "இந்திய உயர்ஸ்தானிகராலயத்தின் அறிவிப்பு",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "இலங்கையின் அதிபரை தெரிவு செய்வதற்கான வாக்கெடுப்பு இன்று (20) பாராளுமன்றத்தில் நடைபெற்ற வாக்கெடுப்பின் போது இலங்கை அரசியல் தலைவர்களுக்கு இந்தியா அழுத்தம் கொடுத்ததாக வெளியான ஆதாரமற்ற ஊக ஊடக செய்திகளை வன்மையாக நிராகரிப்பதாக இலங்கைக்கான இந்திய உயர்ஸ்தானிகராலயம் அறிக்கை ஒன்றை வெளியிட்டுள்ளது.",
        "அந்த அறிக்கையின்படி, ஸ்தாபிக்கப்பட்ட அரசியலமைப்பு நிறுவனங்களின் ஊடாக ஜனநாயக முறைகள் மற்றும் விழுமியங்கள் மற்றும் அரசியலமைப்பு ஏற்பாடுகளின்படி இலங்கையர்களின் அபிலாஷைகளை அடைவதற்கு இந்தியா எல்லா நேரங்களிலும் ஆதரவை வழங்கும் என்பதை இந்திய உயர்ஸ்தானிகராலயம் மீண்டும் வலியுறுத்துகிறது.",
        "மற்றொரு நாட்டின் உள்விவகாரங்களில் அல்லது ஜனநாயக நடைமுறைகளில் இந்தியா ஒருபோதும் தலையிடாது என இந்திய உயர்ஸ்தானிகராலயம் தெரிவித்துள்ளது."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "இந்திய உயர் ஸ்தானிகராலயம்",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "இந்திய உயர் ஸ்தானிகராலயம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்தியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "20",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இந்திய உயர் ஸ்தானிகராலயம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்தியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கையர்கள்",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இந்திய உயர் ஸ்தானிகராலயம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்தியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}