{
  "newspaper_id": "lankadeepa-lk",
  "url": "https://www.lankadeepa.lk/news/පොහොට්ටුවේ-සහාය-ඩලස්ට/101-616475",
  "time_ut": 1657887771,
  "original_lang": "si",
  "original_title": "පොහොට්ටුවේ සහාය ඩලස්ට",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Bud support to Dallas",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "Sri Lanka Podujana Peramuna President Professor GL Peiris said that since a candidate has been nominated from the Sri Lanka Podujana Peramuna, support should be given to the candidate of the party and not to an outside candidate.",
        "He also mentioned that since Sri Lanka Podujana Peramuna is the party with the largest number of members in the Parliament, it is possible for the candidate from Pudujana Peramuna to win.",
        "Professor Peiris said that Mr. Dallas Alahapperuma has already announced that he will stand for the election of the President which will be held on the 20th and that he is a very suitable candidate.",
        "He also said that Sri Lanka Podujana Peramuna as a party has not taken a decision to support any other candidate"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Dallas",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Podujana Peramuna",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "GL Peiris",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "Podujana Peramuna",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "Podujana Peramuna",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Pudujana Peramuna",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Peiris",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Dallas Alahapperuma",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the 20th",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Podujana Peramuna",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "පොහොට්ටුවේ සහාය ඩලස්ට",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකා පොදුජන පෙරමුණෙන් අපේක්ෂකයකු ඉදිරිපත් ව ඇති බැවින් සහාය  දිය යුත්තේ ,පක්ෂයේ අපේක්ෂකයාට මිස පිටස්තර අපේක්ෂකයකුට නොවන බව ශ්‍රී ලංකා පොදුජන පෙරමුණේ සභාපති මහාචාර්ය ජී එල් පීරිස් මහතා පැවසීය.",
        "පාර්ලිමේන්තුවේ වැඩිම මන්ත්‍රී සංඛ්‍යාවක් හිමි පක්ෂය ශ්‍රී ලංකා පොදුජන පෙරමුණ බැවින්,පොදුජන  පෙරමුණෙන් ඉදිරිපත් වන අපේක්ෂකයා ජයග්‍රහණය කරවීමට හැකි බව ද  ඔහු සඳහන් කළේය.",
        "ලබන විසිවැනිදා පැවැත්වෙන ජනාධිපතිවරයා තෝරාගැනීමේ ඡන්දයට ඉදිරිපත් වන බව ඩලස් අලහප්පෙරුම මහතා දැනටමත් ප්‍රකාශ කර ඇතැයි  කී මහාචාර්ය  පීරිස් මහතා ඔහු ඉතා සුදුසු අපේක්ෂකයෙකු බව සඳහන් කළේය",
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකා පොදුජන පෙරමුණ පක්ෂයක් වශයෙන් වෙනත් අපේක්ෂකයෙකුට සහාය දීමට තීරණයක් ගෙන නැතැයි ද හෙතෙම කීවේය"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ඩලස්",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "පොදුජන පෙරමුණ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජී එල් පීරිස්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "පොදුජන පෙරමුණ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "පොදුජන පෙරමුණ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "පුදුජන පෙරමුණ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "පීරිස්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඩලස් අලහප්පෙරුම",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "20 වැනි",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "පොදුජන පෙරමුණ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "டல்லாஸுக்கு மொட்டு ஆதரவு",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "ஸ்ரீலங்கா பொதுஜன பெரமுனவில் இருந்து வேட்பாளர் ஒருவர் நியமிக்கப்பட்டுள்ளதால் வெளி வேட்பாளருக்கு ஆதரவளிக்காமல் கட்சியின் வேட்பாளருக்கே ஆதரவு வழங்க வேண்டும் என ஸ்ரீலங்கா பொதுஜன பெரமுனவின் தலைவர் பேராசிரியர் ஜீ.எல்.பீரிஸ் தெரிவித்துள்ளார்.",
        "ஸ்ரீலங்கா பொதுஜன பெரமுன பாராளுமன்றத்தில் அதிக உறுப்பினர்களை கொண்ட கட்சியாக இருப்பதால், புதுஜன பெரமுனவின் வேட்பாளர் வெற்றி பெறுவது சாத்தியம் எனவும் அவர் குறிப்பிட்டுள்ளார்.",
        "எதிர்வரும் 20ஆம் திகதி நடைபெறவுள்ள ஜனாதிபதி தேர்தலில் தாம் போட்டியிடவுள்ளதாக திரு.டலஸ் அழகப்பெரும ஏற்கனவே அறிவித்துள்ளதாகவும் அவர் மிகவும் பொருத்தமான வேட்பாளர் எனவும் பேராசிரியர் பீரிஸ் தெரிவித்துள்ளார்.",
        "ஸ்ரீலங்கா பொதுஜன பெரமுன ஒரு கட்சி என்ற ரீதியில் வேறு எந்த வேட்பாளருக்கும் ஆதரவளிக்கும் முடிவை எடுக்கவில்லை என்றும் அவர் கூறினார்"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "டல்லாஸ்",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "பொதுஜன பெரமுன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜி.எல்.பீரிஸ்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "பொதுஜன பெரமுன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "பொதுஜன பெரமுன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "புதுஜன பெரமுன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பீரிஸ்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "டலஸ் அழகப்பெரும",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "20 ஆம் தேதி",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "பொதுஜன பெரமுன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}