{
  "newspaper_id": "daily-mirror-lk",
  "url": "https://www.dailymirror.lk/latest_news/Protect-the-Parliament-RW-issues-order-to-security-forces/342-241025",
  "time_ut": 1657729599,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "’Protect the Parliament’- RW issues order to security forces",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "’Protect the Parliament’- RW issues order to security forces",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "Acting President Ranil Wickremesinghe has issued orders to the security forces to protect the Parliament from protestors who were attempting to take it under control.",
        "Security force commanders had sought orders from the Party Leaders at the All Party Leaders meeting to ensure Parliament is protected but did not receive a final word from the party leaders and were told to receive the orders from the government, the Daily Mirror learns.",
        "The security force commanders had then sought orders from the acting president who said Parliament must be protected.",
        "Security forces are presently giving chase to the protestors and several have been injured from both ides."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the Party Leaders",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Daily Mirror",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        []
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "‘පාර්ලිමේන්තුව ආරක්ෂා කරන්න’- RW ආරක්ෂක අංශ වෙත නියෝගයක් නිකුත් කරයි",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව පාලනය කිරීමට උත්සාහ කරන විරෝධතාකරුවන්ගෙන් පාර්ලිමේන්තුව ආරක්ෂා කරන ලෙස වැඩබලන ජනාධිපති රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතා ආරක්ෂක අංශ වෙත නියෝග නිකුත් කර තිබේ.",
        "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව ආරක්‍ෂා කිරීම සඳහා ආරක්‍ෂක සේනා ආඥාපතිවරුන් සර්ව පාක්‍ෂ නායක රැස්වීමේදී පක්‍ෂ නායකයන්ගෙන් නියෝග ඉල්ලා ඇතත් පක්‍ෂ නායකයන්ගෙන් අවසන් වචනයක් නොලැබුණු අතර රජයෙන් නියෝග ලබා ගන්නා ලෙසට ඔවුන්ට දැනුම් දී ඇතැයි ඩේලි මිරර් වෙත වාර්තා වේ.",
        "එවිට ආරක්‍ෂක අංශ අණදෙන නිලධාරීන් වැඩබලන ජනාධිපතිවරයාගෙන් නියෝග ඉල්ලා තිබුණේ පාර්ලිමේන්තුව ආරක්‍ෂා කළ යුතු බව පවසමිනි.",
        "ආරක්ෂක අංශ මේ වන විට විරෝධතාකරුවන් හඹා යමින් සිටින අතර දෙපාර්ශ්වයේම කිහිප දෙනෙකු තුවාල ලබා ඇත."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "පක්ෂ නායකයන්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඩේලි මිරර්",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        []
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "'பாராளுமன்றத்தைப் பாதுகாக்கவும்'- RW பாதுகாப்புப் படையினருக்கு உத்தரவு பிறப்பிக்கிறது",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "பாராளுமன்றத்தை கட்டுப்பாட்டுக்குள் கொண்டு வர முற்பட்ட ஆர்ப்பாட்டக்காரர்களிடம் இருந்து பாராளுமன்றத்தை பாதுகாக்குமாறு பாதுகாப்பு தரப்பினருக்கு பதில் ஜனாதிபதி ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க உத்தரவு பிறப்பித்துள்ளார்.",
        "அனைத்துக் கட்சித் தலைவர்கள் கூட்டத்தில், அனைத்துக் கட்சித் தலைவர்கள் கூட்டத்தில், பாதுகாப்புப் படைத் தளபதிகள், கட்சித் தலைவர்களிடம் உத்தரவு கேட்டனர், ஆனால் கட்சித் தலைவர்களிடமிருந்து இறுதி வார்த்தை வரவில்லை, மேலும் அரசாங்கத்திடமிருந்து உத்தரவுகளைப் பெறுமாறு கூறப்பட்டதாக டெய்லி மிரர் அறியிறது.",
        "அப்போது, ​​பாதுகாப்புப் படைத் தளபதிகள், நாடாளுமன்றத்தைப் பாதுகாக்க வேண்டும் என்று பதில் ஜனாதிபதியிடம் உத்தரவு கேட்டனர்.",
        "பாதுகாப்புப் படையினர் தற்போது போராட்டக்காரர்களை விரட்டியடித்து வருகின்றனர், மேலும் இரு தரப்பிலும் பலர் காயமடைந்துள்ளனர்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "கட்சி தலைவர்கள்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "டெய்லி மிரர்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        []
      ]
    }
  }
}