{
  "newspaper_id": "ada-derana-lk",
  "url": "http://www.adaderana.lk/news/84630/live-update-interim-budget-speech-2022",
  "time_ut": 1661845020,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "LIVE UPDATE: Interim Budget Speech 2022",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "LIVE UPDATE: Interim Budget Speech 2022",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "President Wickremesinghe announced that the Value Added Tax (VAT) will be increased from 12% to 15% with effect from September 01, 2022.",
        "This is the basic foundation of preparing a national economic policy that suits today’s world, he said.",
        "“Hon. Speaker, today we will present to the Parliament the Interim Budget that will lay the foundation for changing the economic design which existed in our country thus far,” he said, commencing his speech.",
        "President Ranil Wickremesinghe arrives in the House to deliver the Interim Budget Speech 2022, after the Parliament sittings commenced at 01.00 p.m. today (30).",
        "The inaugural speech of the second reading of the Appropriation (Amendment) Bill will be presented by the President and Minister of Finance, Economic Stabilization and National Policies Ranil Wickremesinghe from 01.00 p.m. to 02.00 p.m.",
        "Subsequently, the house will be adjourned till tomorrow (31) 09.30 a.m."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Value Added Tax",
            "label": "LAW"
          },
          {
            "text": "12% to 15%",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "September 01, 2022",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Parliament the Interim Budget",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "House",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Interim Budget Speech 2022",
            "label": "LAW"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "01.00 p.m.",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "30",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "second",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Appropriation (Amendment) Bill",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Economic Stabilization",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "National Policies Ranil Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "01.00 p.m. to",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "02.00 p.m.",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "tomorrow",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "09.30 a.m.",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "සජීවී යාවත්කාලීන කිරීම: අතුරු අයවැය කතාව 2022",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "2022 සැප්තැම්බර් 01 වැනිදා සිට ක්‍රියාත්මක වන පරිදි එකතු කළ අගය මත බද්ද (VAT) 12% සිට 15% දක්වා වැඩි කරන බව ජනාධිපති වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතා ප්‍රකාශ කළේය.",
        "වර්තමාන ලෝකයට ගැළපෙන ජාතික ආර්ථික ප්‍රතිපත්තියක් සකස් කිරීමේ මූලික පදනම මෙය බව ද ඔහු පැවසීය.",
        "\"ගරු. කථානායකතුමනි, මෙතෙක් අපේ රටේ පැවති ආර්ථික සැලැස්ම වෙනස් කිරීමට අවශ්‍ය පදනම සකසන අතුරු අයවැය අද අපි පාර්ලිමේන්තුවට ඉදිරිපත් කරනවා.” යැයි ඔහු සිය කතාව ආරම්භ කළේය.",
        "පාර්ලිමේන්තු රැස්වීම පස්වරු 01.00 ට ආරම්භ වීමෙන් පසු 2022 අතුරු අයවැය කතාව ඉදිරිපත් කිරීම සඳහා ජනාධිපති රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතා සභාවට පැමිණේ. අද (30)",
        "විසර්ජන (සංශෝධන) පනත් කෙටුම්පත දෙවැනි වර කියවීමේ සමාරම්භක කතාව ජනාධිපති සහ මුදල්, ආර්ථික ස්ථායීකරණ සහ ජාතික ප්‍රතිපත්ති අමාත්‍ය රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතා විසින් පස්වරු 01.00 සිට ඉදිරිපත් කිරීමට නියමිතය. 02.00 දක්වා.",
        "අනතුරුව සභාව හෙට (31) පෙරවරු 09.30 දක්වා කල් තැබේ."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "එකතු කළ අගය මත බද්ද",
            "label": "LAW"
          },
          {
            "text": "12% සිට 15% දක්වා",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "සැප්තැම්බර් 01, 2022",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව අතුරු අයවැය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "නිවස",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "2022 අතුරු අයවැය කතාව",
            "label": "LAW"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "01.00 ප.ව.",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "30",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "දෙවැනි",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "විසර්ජන (සංශෝධන) පනත් කෙටුම්පත",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ආර්ථික ස්ථාවරත්වය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජාතික ප්‍රතිපත්ති රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "01.00 ප.ව. වෙත",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "02.00 ප.ව.",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "හෙට",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "09.30 පෙ.ව.",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "நேரடி அறிவிப்பு: இடைக்கால பட்ஜெட் உரை 2022",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "2022 செப்டெம்பர் 01 ஆம் திகதி முதல் அமுலுக்கு வரும் வகையில் பெறுமதி சேர் வரி (VAT) 12% இலிருந்து 15% ஆக அதிகரிக்கப்படும் என ஜனாதிபதி விக்ரமசிங்க அறிவித்துள்ளார்.",
        "இன்றைய உலகத்திற்கு ஏற்ற தேசிய பொருளாதாரக் கொள்கையை தயாரிப்பதற்கான அடிப்படை அடித்தளம் இதுதான் என்றார்.",
        "“அரசர். சபாநாயகர் அவர்களே, இதுவரையில் எமது நாட்டில் நிலவி வந்த பொருளாதார வடிவமைப்பை மாற்றுவதற்கான அடித்தளத்தை அமைக்கும் இடைக்கால வரவு செலவுத் திட்டத்தை இன்று பாராளுமன்றத்தில் சமர்ப்பிக்கவுள்ளோம்” என அவர் தனது உரையை ஆரம்பித்து வைத்தார்.",
        "2022 ஆம் ஆண்டுக்கான இடைக்கால வரவு செலவுத் திட்ட உரையை ஆற்றுவதற்காக ஜனாதிபதி ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க, பாராளுமன்ற அமர்வுகள் பிற்பகல் 01.00 மணிக்கு ஆரம்பமானதை அடுத்து சபைக்கு வருகை தந்தார். இன்று (30).",
        "ஒதுக்கீட்டு (திருத்த) சட்டமூலத்தின் இரண்டாம் வாசிப்பின் ஆரம்ப உரை பிற்பகல் 01.00 மணி முதல் ஜனாதிபதி மற்றும் நிதி, பொருளாதார ஸ்திரப்படுத்தல் மற்றும் தேசிய கொள்கைகள் அமைச்சர் ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்கவினால் சமர்ப்பிக்கப்படவுள்ளது. மதியம் 02.00 மணி வரை",
        "இதையடுத்து, அவை நாளை (31) காலை 9.30 மணி வரை ஒத்திவைக்கப்பட்டது."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "மதிப்பு கூட்டப்பட்ட வரி",
            "label": "LAW"
          },
          {
            "text": "12% முதல் 15%",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "செப்டம்பர் 01, 2022",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம் இடைக்கால பட்ஜெட்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "வீடு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இடைக்கால பட்ஜெட் உரை 2022",
            "label": "LAW"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "01.00 மணி",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "30",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இரண்டாவது",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஒதுக்கீடு (திருத்தம்) மசோதா",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "பொருளாதார ஸ்திரத்தன்மை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "தேசிய கொள்கைகள் ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "01.00 மணி செய்ய",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "பிற்பகல் 02.00",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "நாளை",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "09.30 a.m.",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}