{
  "newspaper_id": "news-first-lk",
  "url": "https://www.newsfirst.lk/2022/07/21/navy-seizes-poaching-trawler-in-mannar-seas/",
  "time_ut": 1658396700,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Navy seizes poaching trawler in Mannar seas",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Navy seizes poaching trawler in Mannar seas",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); Sri Lanka Navy seized an Indian trawler with 06 Indian fishermen aboard for poaching in the island’s waters, during a patrol carried out in the seas north of Mannar on the night of 20th July 2022.",
        "The Navy regularly conducts patrols and operations in Sri Lankan waters with a view to curbing the impact on the local fishing community as well as the damage caused to the biodiversity of the marine environment of Sri Lanka, due to illegal fishing activities carried out by foreign fishermen in the country’s waters.",
        "The apprehension was made by a Fast Attack Craft of the 4th Fast Attack Flotilla in the Northern Naval Command, during a night patrol in seas off Mannar on 20th July. Accordingly, the Indian trawler with 06 Indian fishermen were held while they were poaching in Sri Lankan waters, via the Internal Maritime Boundary Line (IMBL).",
        "The apprehended Indian fishermen and their trawler were brought to Talaimannar and arrangements are currently under way to hand over them to the Fisheries Inspector of Mannar.",
        "Including the latest apprehension, Sri Lanka Navy has seized and produced 04 Indian poaching trawlers and 29 Indian fishermen for legal proceedings, thus far in the month of July this year.",
        "Meanwhile, the Navy will continue to carry out constant operations in the waters around the island, to ensure the security of it and protect the livelihood of local fishermen."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Navy",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "Mannar",
          "label": "WORK_OF_ART"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "News 1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka Navy",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Indian",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "06",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Indian",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Mannar",
            "label": "WORK_OF_ART"
          },
          {
            "text": "the night of 20th July 2022",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Navy",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lankan",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "4th",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Fast Attack Flotilla",
            "label": "EVENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Northern Naval Command",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Mannar",
            "label": "WORK_OF_ART"
          },
          {
            "text": "20th July",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Indian",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "06",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Indian",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lankan",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Internal Maritime Boundary Line",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "IMBL",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Indian",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Talaimannar",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Fisheries Inspector of Mannar",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka Navy",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "04",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Indian",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "29",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Indian",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "the month of July this year",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Navy",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "මන්නාරම මුහුදේදී දඩයම් කළ ට්‍රෝලර් යාත්‍රාවක් නාවික හමුදා භාරයට",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); ශ්‍රී ලංකා නාවික හමුදාව විසින් 2022 ජුලි 20 වැනි දින රාත්‍රියේ මන්නාරමට උතුරින් වූ මුහුදු ප්‍රදේශයේ සිදු කළ මුර සංචාරයක් අතරතුරදී, ශ්‍රී ලංකා නාවික හමුදාව විසින් දිවයිනේ මුහුදු සීමාවේ මසුන් ඇල්ලීම සඳහා ඉන්දීය ධීවරයින් 06 දෙනෙකු සමඟ ඉන්දීය ට්‍රෝලර් යාත්‍රාවක් අත්අඩංගුවට ගෙන ඇත.",
        "විදේශීය ධීවරයින් විසින් සිදුකරන නීතිවිරෝධී ධීවර කටයුතු හේතුවෙන් දේශීය ධීවර ප්‍රජාවට සිදුවන බලපෑම මෙන්ම ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ ජෛව විවිධත්වයට සිදුවන හානිය මැඩලීමේ අරමුණින් නාවික හමුදාව ශ්‍රී ලංකා මුහුදු තීරයේ නිරන්තර මුර සංචාර සහ මෙහෙයුම් සිදු කරයි. රටේ ජලයේ.",
        "උතුරු නාවික විධානයට අයත් 4 වන වේග ප්‍රහාරක ෆ්ලෝටිලා හි වේග ප්‍රහාරක යාත්‍රාවක් විසින් ජුලි 20 වන දින මන්නාරමට ඔබ්බෙන් වූ මුහුදු ප්‍රදේශයේ රාත්‍රී මුර සංචාරයක් අතරතුරදී මෙම අත්අඩංගුවට ගැනීම සිදු කර ඇත. ඒ අනුව, ඉන්දීය ධීවරයින් 06 දෙනෙකු සමඟ ඉන්දීය ට්‍රෝලර් යාත්‍රාව අත්අඩංගුවට ගෙන ඇත්තේ ඔවුන් ශ්‍රී ලංකා මුහුදු සීමාවේ, අභ්‍යන්තර මුහුදු සීමා රේඛාව (IMBL) හරහා දඩයම් කරමින් සිටියදීය.",
        "අත්අඩංගුවට ගත් ඉන්දීය ධීවරයින් සහ යාත්‍රාව තලෙයිමන්නාරම වෙත රැගෙන ඒමට කටයුතු කර ඇති අතර ඔවුන් මන්නාරම ධීවර පරීක්ෂක වෙත භාරදීමට මේ වනවිට කටයුතු කරමින් පවතිනවා.",
        "නවතම අත් අඩංගුවට ගැනීම් ඇතුළුව, ශ්‍රී ලංකා නාවික හමුදාව විසින් මේ වසරේ ජූලි මාසයේ මේ දක්වා ඉන්දීය දඩයම් ට්‍රෝලර් යාත්‍රා 04 ක් සහ ඉන්දීය ධීවරයින් 29 දෙනෙකු අත්අඩංගුවට ගෙන නීතිමය කටයුතු සඳහා ඉදිරිපත් කර ඇත.",
        "මේ අතර, නාවික හමුදාව විසින් දිවයින වටා ඇති මුහුදු තීරයේ ආරක්ෂාව තහවුරු කිරීම සහ දේශීය ධීවරයින්ගේ ජීවනෝපාය ආරක්ෂා කිරීම සඳහා අඛණ්ඩ මෙහෙයුම් අඛණ්ඩව සිදු කරනු ඇත."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "නාවික",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "මන්නාරම",
          "label": "WORK_OF_ART"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "News 1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකා නාවික හමුදාව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දීය",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "06",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දීය",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "මන්නාරම",
            "label": "WORK_OF_ART"
          },
          {
            "text": "2022 ජූලි 20 වැනිදා රාත්‍රිය",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "නාවික",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලාංකික",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "4 වැනි",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "වේගවත් ප්‍රහාර ෆ්ලෝටිලා",
            "label": "EVENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "උතුරු නාවික විධානය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "මන්නාරම",
            "label": "WORK_OF_ART"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජූලි 20",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දීය",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "06",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දීය",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලාංකික",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "අභ්යන්තර සමුද්ර මායිම් රේඛාව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "IMBL",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දීය",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "තලෙයිමන්නාරම",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මන්නාරම ධීවර පරීක්ෂක",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකා නාවික හමුදාව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "04",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දීය",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "29",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දීය",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "මේ වසරේ ජූලි මාසය",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "නාවික",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "மன்னார் கடற்பரப்பில் வேட்டையாடிய இழுவை படகை கடற்படையினர் கைப்பற்றியுள்ளனர்",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); 2022 ஆம் ஆண்டு ஜூலை மாதம் 20 ஆம் திகதி இரவு மன்னாருக்கு வடக்கே கடற்பகுதியில் மேற்கொள்ளப்பட்ட ரோந்து நடவடிக்கையின் போது, ​​இலங்கை கடற்படையினர் தீவு கடற்பரப்பில் அத்துமீறி மீன்பிடியில் ஈடுபட்டதற்காக 06 இந்திய மீனவர்களுடன் இந்திய இழுவை படகு ஒன்றை கைப்பற்றினர்.",
        "வெளிநாட்டு மீனவர்களால் மேற்கொள்ளப்படும் சட்டவிரோத மீன்பிடி நடவடிக்கைகளினால் இலங்கையின் கடல்சார் சுற்றுச்சூழலின் பல்லுயிர் சேதம் மற்றும் உள்நாட்டு மீனவ சமூகத்திற்கு ஏற்படும் பாதிப்புகளை கட்டுப்படுத்தும் நோக்கில் கடற்படையினர் இலங்கை கடற்பரப்பில் தொடர்ந்து ரோந்து மற்றும் நடவடிக்கைகளை மேற்கொண்டு வருகின்றனர். நாட்டின் நீர்நிலைகளில்.",
        "கடந்த ஜூலை 20 ஆம் திகதி மன்னார் கடற்பகுதியில் இரவு ரோந்துப் பணியின் போது வடக்கு கடற்படை கட்டளையின் 4 ஆவது விரைவுத் தாக்குதல் புளோட்டிலாவின் விரைவுத் தாக்குதல் கைவினைப்பொருளால் இந்த அச்சம் ஏற்பட்டது. இதன்படி, 06 இந்திய மீனவர்களுடன் இந்திய இழுவை படகு, உள்நாட்டு கடல் எல்லைக் கோடு (IMBL) ஊடாக, இலங்கை கடற்பரப்பில் அத்துமீறி மீன்பிடியில் ஈடுபட்டிருந்த போதே, கைது செய்யப்பட்டுள்ளது.",
        "கைது செய்யப்பட்ட இந்திய மீனவர்களும் அவர்களது படகுகளும் தலைமன்னாருக்கு கொண்டு வரப்பட்டதுடன், அவர்களை மன்னார் கடற்றொழில் பரிசோதகரிடம் ஒப்படைப்பதற்கான ஏற்பாடுகள் தற்போது நடைபெற்று வருகின்றன.",
        "சமீபத்திய அச்சம் உட்பட, இந்த ஆண்டு ஜூலை மாதத்தில் இதுவரை 04 இந்திய வேட்டையாடும் இழுவை படகுகளையும் 29 இந்திய மீனவர்களையும் இலங்கை கடற்படை கைப்பற்றி சட்ட நடவடிக்கைகளுக்காக ஆஜர்படுத்தியுள்ளது.",
        "இதேவேளை, தீவைச் சூழவுள்ள கடற்பரப்பின் பாதுகாப்பை உறுதிப்படுத்தவும், உள்ளூர் மீனவர்களின் வாழ்வாதாரத்தைப் பாதுகாக்கவும் கடற்படையினர் தொடர்ந்தும் தொடர்ச்சியான நடவடிக்கைகளை மேற்கொள்வார்கள்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "கடற்படை",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "மன்னார்",
          "label": "WORK_OF_ART"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "News 1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை கடற்படை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்தியன்",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "06",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்தியன்",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "மன்னார்",
            "label": "WORK_OF_ART"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜூலை 20, 2022 இரவு",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "கடற்படை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "4வது",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஃபாஸ்ட் அட்டாக் ஃப்ளோட்டிலா",
            "label": "EVENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "வடக்கு கடற்படை கட்டளை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "மன்னார்",
            "label": "WORK_OF_ART"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜூலை 20",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்தியன்",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "06",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்தியன்",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "உள்நாட்டு கடல் எல்லைக் கோடு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "IMBL",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இந்தியன்",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "தலைமன்னார்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "மன்னார் கடற்றொழில் பரிசோதகர்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை கடற்படை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "04",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்தியன்",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "29",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்தியன்",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்த ஆண்டு ஜூலை மாதம்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "கடற்படை",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}