{
  "newspaper_id": "lankadeepa-lk",
  "url": "https://www.lankadeepa.lk/latest_news/ඩලස්-කණ්ඩායමෙන්-අයවැයට-සහාය-නෑ/1-619195",
  "time_ut": 1662115227,
  "original_lang": "si",
  "original_title": "ඩලස් කණ්ඩායමෙන් අයවැයට සහාය නෑ",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "No budget support from the Dallas team",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "The 13 members of the Sri Lanka Podujana Peremane, who left the government and went to the opposition, decided to refrain from voting in the interim budget vote, says Mr. G. L. Peiris, Member of Parliament.",
        "He mentioned this while attending the opening of the main office of the Free National Assembly, which was established by the 13 people who left the government and joined the opposition.",
        "Mr. G. L. Peiris also said that he took that action to express his objection to not giving any space to his group to comment in the interim budget debate."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Dallas",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "13",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "Podujana Peremane",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "G. L. Peiris",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the Free National Assembly",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "13",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "G. L. Peiris",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "ඩලස් කණ්ඩායමෙන් අයවැයට සහාය නෑ",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "ආණ්ඩුවෙන් ඉවත්වී විපක්ෂයට ගිය ශ්‍රී ලංකා පොදුජන පෙරමණේ මන්ත්‍රීවරුන් 13 දෙනා අතුරු අයවැය ඡන්දයේදී ඡන්දය දීමෙන් වැලකී සිටීමට තීරණය කළ බව  පාර්ලිමේන්තු මන්ත්‍රී මහාචාර්ය ජී.එල්.පීරිස් මහතා පවසයි.",
        "ඔහු මේ බව සඳහන් කළේ ආණ්ඩුවෙන් ඉවත්ව විපක්ෂයේ ගිය 13 දෙනා එක්ව පිහිටුවන ලද නිදහස් ජාතික සභාවේ ප්‍රධාන කාර්යාලය විවෘත කිරීමේ අවස්ථාවට එක් වෙමිනි.",
        "අතුරු අයවැය විවාදයේදි අදහස් දැක්වීමට තම කණ්ඩායමට කිසිදු ඉඩක් ලබා නොදීමට විරෝධය ප්‍රකාශ කිරීම සඳහා එම ක්‍රියාමාර්ගය ගත් බව ද ජී.එල්.පීරිස් මහතා කිය."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ඩලස්",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "13",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "පොදුජන පෙරේරා",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජී.එල්. පීරිස්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "නිදහස් ජාතික සභාව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "13",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ජී.එල්. පීරිස්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "டல்லாஸ் அணியிலிருந்து பட்ஜெட் ஆதரவு இல்லை",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "அரசாங்கத்தில் இருந்து விலகி எதிர்க்கட்சிக்கு சென்ற ஸ்ரீலங்கா பொதுஜன பெரேமனேவின் 13 உறுப்பினர்கள் இடைக்கால வரவு செலவுத் திட்ட வாக்கெடுப்பில் வாக்களிப்பதில் இருந்து விலகி இருக்க தீர்மானித்துள்ளதாக நாடாளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர் திரு.ஜி.எல்.பீரிஸ் தெரிவித்துள்ளார்.",
        "அரசாங்கத்தில் இருந்து விலகி எதிர்க்கட்சியில் இணைந்து கொண்ட 13 பேரால் ஸ்தாபிக்கப்பட்ட சுதந்திர தேசிய சபையின் பிரதான அலுவலகத்தை திறந்து வைக்கும் நிகழ்வில் கலந்து கொண்ட போது அவர் இதனைக் குறிப்பிட்டுள்ளார்.",
        "இடைக்கால வரவு செலவுத் திட்ட விவாதத்தில் கருத்து தெரிவிக்க தமது குழுவினருக்கு இடமளிக்காததற்கு ஆட்சேபனை தெரிவிக்கவே இந்த நடவடிக்கையை மேற்கொண்டதாகவும் திரு. ஜீ.எல்.பீரிஸ் தெரிவித்தார்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "டல்லாஸ்",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "13",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "பொதுஜன பெரேமானே",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜி.எல்.பீரிஸ்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "சுதந்திர தேசிய சட்டமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "13",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஜி.எல்.பீரிஸ்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}