{
  "newspaper_id": "daily-mirror-lk",
  "url": "https://www.dailymirror.lk/latest_news/Actor-Jacqueline-Fernandez-is-now-an-accused-in-INR-200-Crore-extortion-case/342-243228",
  "time_ut": 1660720015,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Actor Jacqueline Fernandez is now an accused in INR 200-Crore extortion case",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Actor Jacqueline Fernandez is now an accused in INR 200-Crore extortion case",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "Actor Jacqueline Fernandez has been named an accused in the money laundering case against conman Sukesh Chandrashekar, who faces charges of extortion amounting to a massive INR 200 crore.",
        "The actor has been named an accused in the supplementary chargesheet filed in a Delhi court by the Enforcement Directorate (ED), which is probing the money trail in the extortion case.",
        "Earlier, the ED had attached assets belonging to the actor and had also questioned her. The agency in April provisionally attached INR 7 crore assets of the actor under the Prevention of Money Laundering Act (PMLA).",
        "\"Sukesh Chandrasekhar had given various gifts worth INR 5.71 crore to Jacqueline Fernandez from the proceeds of crime generated by criminal activities including extortion. \"Chandrasekhar had put Pinky Irani, his long time associate and co-accused in this case to deliver the said gifts to her,\" the ED had then said in a statement.",
        "Among these gifts were a horse worth INR 52 lakh and a Persian cat worth INR 9 lakh, the ED has alleged. The agency has also alleged that Chandrashekar gave huge sums of money to the family members of Ms Fernandez.",
        "The ED has alleged that Chandrashekar has given gifts worth INR 5.71 crore to the actor from the INR 200 crore he allegedly swindled of the family of former Ranbaxy promoters.",
        "Ms Fernandez is a Sri Lankan national and made her debut in the Hindi film industry in 2009.",
        "The ED has arrested a total of eight people in this case. These include Chandrshekhar and his wife Leena Maria Paul.(NDTV)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Jacqueline Fernandez",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Jacqueline Fernandez",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sukesh Chandrashekar",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "INR",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Delhi",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Enforcement Directorate",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ED",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "April",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "INR 7",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Prevention of Money Laundering Act",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sukesh Chandrasekhar",
            "label": "WORK_OF_ART"
          },
          {
            "text": "Jacqueline Fernandez",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Chandrasekhar",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Pinky Irani",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ED",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Persian",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ED",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Chandrashekar",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ms Fernandez",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ED",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Chandrashekar",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Ms Fernandez",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lankan",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Hindi",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "2009",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ED",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "eight",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Leena Maria Paul.(NDTV",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "රංගන ශිල්පිනී ජැකලින් ෆර්නැන්ඩස් ඉන්දීය රුපියල් කෝටි 200 ක කප්පම් නඩුවක චූදිතයෙක්.",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "ඉන්දීය රුපියල් කෝටි 200ක දැවැන්ත කප්පම් ගැනීමේ චෝදනාවකට මුහුණ දී සිටින කොන්මන් සුකේෂ් චන්ද්‍රසේකර්ට එරෙහිව මුදල් විශුද්ධිකරණ නඩුවේ විත්තිකාරියක් ලෙස රංගන ශිල්පිනී ජැකලින් ෆර්නැන්ඩස් නම් කර තිබේ.",
        "කප්පම් නඩුවේ මුදල් සෙවීමේ විමර්ශනය කරන බලාත්මක අධ්‍යක්ෂ මණ්ඩලය (ED) විසින් දිල්ලි අධිකරණයට ගොනු කරන ලද පරිපූරක චෝදනා පත්‍රයේ මෙම නළුවා විත්තිකරුවෙකු ලෙස නම් කර ඇත.",
        "මීට පෙර, ED විසින් නළුවාට අයත් වත්කම් අනුයුක්ත කර ඇති අතර ඇයගෙන්ද ප්‍රශ්න කර තිබුණි. ඒජන්සිය අප්‍රේල් මාසයේදී මුදල් විශුද්ධිකරණය වැළැක්වීමේ පනත (PMLA) යටතේ නළුවාගේ රුපියල් කෝටි 7 වත්කම් තාවකාලිකව අනුයුක්ත කළේය.",
        "\"සුකේෂ් චන්ද්‍රසේකර් ජැකලින් ෆර්නැන්ඩස් හට කප්පම් ගැනීම් ඇතුළු අපරාධ ක්‍රියාවලින් උපයාගත් මුදලින් ඉන්දීය රුපියල් කෝටි 5.71ක් වටිනා විවිධ තෑගි ලබා දී ඇත. \"චන්ද්‍රසේකර් විසින් එම ත්‍යාග ලබාදීමට ඔහුගේ දීර්ඝ කාලීන සහකාරිය සහ සම චූදිත පිංකි ඉරානි යොදවා තිබුණි. ඇය,\" ED පසුව නිවේදනයක් නිකුත් කරමින් කියා සිටියේය.",
        "මෙම තෑගි අතර ඉන්දීය රුපියල් ලක්ෂ 52 ක් වටිනා අශ්වයෙකු සහ රුපියල් ලක්ෂ 9 ක් වටිනා පර්සියානු බළලෙකු ද සිටි බව ED චෝදනා කර ඇත. චන්ද්‍රසේකර් ෆර්නැන්ඩස් මහත්මියගේ පවුලේ සාමාජිකයින්ට විශාල මුදලක් ලබා දුන් බවට ද ඒජන්සිය චෝදනා කර ඇත.",
        "හිටපු Ranbaxy ප්‍රවර්ධකයින්ගේ පවුලට වංචා කළ බව කියන ඉන්දීය රුපියල් කෝටි 200 න් චන්ද්‍රශේකර් නළුවාට රුපියල් කෝටි 5.71 ක් වටිනා තෑගි ලබා දී ඇති බවට ED චෝදනා කර ඇත.",
        "ෆර්නැන්ඩස් මහත්මිය ශ්‍රී ලාංකික කාන්තාවක් වන අතර ඇය හින්දි චිත්‍රපට කර්මාන්තයට පිවිසියේ 2009 වසරේදීය.",
        "ED විසින් මෙම සිද්ධිය සම්බන්ධයෙන් පුද්ගලයින් අට දෙනෙකු අත්අඩංගුවට ගෙන ඇත. චන්ද්‍රසේකර් සහ ඔහුගේ බිරිඳ ලීනා මරියා පෝල් ද ඊට ඇතුළත් ය.(NDTV)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ජැකලින් ෆර්නැන්ඩස්",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ජැකලින් ෆර්නැන්ඩස්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "සුකේෂ් චන්ද්‍රසේකර්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "INR",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "දිල්ලිය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ක්රියාත්මක කිරීමේ අධ්යක්ෂ මණ්ඩලය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ED",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "අප්රේල්",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "INR 7",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "මුදල් විශුද්ධිකරණය වැළැක්වීමේ පනත",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "සුකේෂ් චන්ද්‍රසේකර්",
            "label": "WORK_OF_ART"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජැකලින් ෆර්නැන්ඩස්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "චන්ද්‍රසේකර්",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "පිංකි ඉරානි",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ED",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "පර්සියානු",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ED",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "චන්ද්‍රසේකර්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ෆර්නැන්ඩස් මහත්මිය",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ED",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "චන්ද්‍රසේකර්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ෆර්නැන්ඩස් මහත්මිය",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලාංකික",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "හින්දි",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "2009",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ED",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "අට",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ලීනා මරියා පෝල්.(NDTV",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "200 கோடி ரூபாய் மிரட்டி பணம் பறித்த வழக்கில் நடிகை ஜாக்குலின் பெர்னாண்டஸ் தற்போது குற்றம் சாட்டப்பட்டுள்ளார்.",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "200 கோடி ரூபாய் அளவுக்கு மிரட்டி பணம் பறித்த குற்றச்சாட்டை எதிர்கொண்ட கன்மேன் சுகேஷ் சந்திரசேகர் மீதான பணமோசடி வழக்கில் நடிகை ஜாக்குலின் பெர்னாண்டஸ் குற்றவாளியாக சேர்க்கப்பட்டுள்ளார்.",
        "மிரட்டி பணம் பறித்தல் வழக்கில் பணத் தடயத்தை விசாரித்து வரும் அமலாக்க இயக்குநரகம் (ED) டெல்லி நீதிமன்றத்தில் தாக்கல் செய்த துணை குற்றப்பத்திரிகையில் நடிகர் குற்றம் சாட்டப்பட்டுள்ளார்.",
        "முன்னதாக, அமலாக்கத்துறை நடிகருக்கு சொந்தமான சொத்துக்களை பறிமுதல் செய்ததுடன், அவரிடம் விசாரணையும் நடத்தியது. ஏஜென்சி ஏப்ரல் மாதம் பணமோசடி தடுப்புச் சட்டத்தின் (பிஎம்எல்ஏ) கீழ் நடிகரின் 7 கோடி ரூபாய் சொத்துக்களை தற்காலிகமாக முடக்கியது.",
        "சுகேஷ் சந்திரசேகர், ஜாக்குலின் பெர்னாண்டஸுக்கு மிரட்டி பணம் பறித்தல் உள்ளிட்ட குற்றச் செயல்களின் மூலம் கிடைத்த பணத்தில் இருந்து 5.71 கோடி ரூபாய் மதிப்பிலான பல்வேறு பரிசுகளை வழங்கியுள்ளார். அவள்,\" என்று ED ஒரு அறிக்கையில் கூறியது.",
        "இந்த பரிசுகளில் 52 லட்சம் ரூபாய் மதிப்புள்ள குதிரையும், 9 லட்சம் ரூபாய் மதிப்புள்ள பாரசீக பூனையும் அடங்கும் என்று ED குற்றம் சாட்டியுள்ளது. திருமதி பெர்னாண்டஸின் குடும்ப உறுப்பினர்களுக்கு சந்திரசேகர் பெரும் தொகையை வழங்கியதாகவும் நிறுவனம் குற்றம் சாட்டியுள்ளது.",
        "முன்னாள் ரான்பாக்ஸி விளம்பரதாரர்களின் குடும்பத்தை மோசடி செய்ததாகக் கூறப்படும் 200 கோடி ரூபாயில் இருந்து 5.71 கோடி ரூபாய் மதிப்பிலான நடிகருக்கு சந்திரசேகர் பரிசு வழங்கியதாக ED குற்றம் சாட்டியுள்ளது.",
        "திருமதி பெர்னாண்டஸ் ஒரு இலங்கை நாட்டவர் மற்றும் 2009 இல் இந்தி திரையுலகில் அறிமுகமானார்.",
        "இந்த வழக்கில் மொத்தம் 8 பேரை ED கைது செய்துள்ளது. இவர்களில் சந்திரசேகர் மற்றும் அவரது மனைவி லீனா மரியா பால் ஆகியோர் அடங்குவர்.(NDTV)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ஜாக்குலின் பெர்னாண்டஸ்",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ஜாக்குலின் பெர்னாண்டஸ்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "சுகேஷ் சந்திரசேகர்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "INR",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "டெல்லி",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "அமலாக்க இயக்குநரகம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ED",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஏப்ரல்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்திய ரூபாய் 7",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "பணமோசடி தடுப்புச் சட்டம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "சுகேஷ் சந்திரசேகர்",
            "label": "WORK_OF_ART"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜாக்குலின் பெர்னாண்டஸ்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "சந்திரசேகர்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "பிங்கி இரானி",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ED",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பாரசீக",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ED",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "சந்திரசேகர்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "திருமதி பெர்னாண்டஸ்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ED",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "சந்திரசேகர்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "திருமதி பெர்னாண்டஸ்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஹிந்தி",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "2009",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ED",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "எட்டு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "லீனா மரியா பால்.(NDTV",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}