{
  "newspaper_id": "ada-derana-lk",
  "url": "http://www.adaderana.lk/news/84601/slpp-district-leaders-summoned-to-colombo",
  "time_ut": 1661749320,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "SLPP district leaders summoned to Colombo",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "SLPP district leaders summoned to Colombo",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "The Sri Lanka Podujana Peramuna (SLPP) has decided to call all district leaders of the party to Colombo from today (29) for discussions.",
        "The party’s media spokesperson, MP Sanjeeva Edirimanna stated that the meetings have been convened to discuss the future political affairs.",
        "All the district-level leaders of the party are informed to arrive at the SLPP party office in Nelum Mawatha of Colombo.",
        "Meanwhile, another meeting of the MPs representing the government is scheduled to be held today (29), said the SLPP spokesman.",
        "The political sources state that the meeting will be held at 5.00 p.m. today.",
        "The meeting will be held at the Presidential Secretariat and will be presided over by the president."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Colombo",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "Podujana Peramuna",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Colombo",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "29",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sanjeeva Edirimanna",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Nelum Mawatha of Colombo",
            "label": "LOC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "29",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "SLPP",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "5.00 p.m.",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the Presidential Secretariat",
            "label": "FAC"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "ශ්‍රී ලංකා පොදුජන පෙරමුණේ දිස්ත්‍රික් නායකයින් කොළඹට කැඳවයි",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකා පොදුජන පෙරමුණ (SLPP) පක්ෂයේ සියලුම දිස්ත්‍රික් නායකයින් අද (29) සිට කොළඹට කැඳවා සාකච්ඡා කිරීමට තීරණය කර ඇත.",
        "එම පක්ෂයේ මාධ්‍ය ප්‍රකාශක පාර්ලිමේන්තු මන්ත්‍රී සංජීව එදිරිමාන්න කියා සිටියේ ඉදිරි දේශපාලන කටයුතු සම්බන්ධයෙන් සාකච්ඡා කිරීම සඳහා මෙම රැස්වීම් කැඳවා ඇති බවයි.",
        "එම පක්ෂයේ සියලුම දිස්ත්‍රික් මට්ටමේ නායකයින්ට කොළඹ නෙළුම් මාවතේ පිහිටි ශ්‍රී ලංකා පොදුජන පෙරමුණ පක්ෂ කාර්යාලයට පැමිණෙන ලෙස දැනුම් දෙනවා.",
        "මේ අතර රජය නියෝජනය කරන මන්ත්‍රීවරුන්ගේ තවත් රැස්වීමක් අද (29) පැවැත්වීමට නියමිත බව ශ්‍රී ලංකා පොදුජන පෙරමුණේ ප්‍රකාශකවරයා සඳහන් කළේය.",
        "5.00ට මෙම හමුව පැවැත්වෙන බව දේශපාලන ආරංචි මාර්ග සඳහන් කරයි. අද.",
        "ජනාධිපති ලේකම් කාර්යාලයේදී රැස්වීම පැවැත්වෙන අතර එය ජනාධිපතිවරයාගේ ප්‍රධානත්වයෙන් පැවැත්වේ."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "කොළඹ",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "පොදුජන පෙරමුණ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "කොළඹ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "29",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "සංජීව එදිරිමාන්න",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "කොළඹ නෙළුම් මාවත",
            "label": "LOC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "29",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "SLPP",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "5.00 ප.ව.",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ජනාධිපති ලේකම් කාර්යාලය",
            "label": "FAC"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "SLPP மாவட்ட தலைவர்கள் கொழும்புக்கு வரவழைக்கப்பட்டுள்ளனர்",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "ஸ்ரீலங்கா பொதுஜன பெரமுன (SLPP) கட்சியின் அனைத்து மாவட்டத் தலைவர்களையும் இன்று (29) முதல் கொழும்புக்கு அழைத்து கலந்துரையாடுவதற்கு தீர்மானித்துள்ளது.",
        "எதிர்கால அரசியல் விவகாரங்கள் தொடர்பில் கலந்துரையாடுவதற்காகவே இந்த சந்திப்பு நடத்தப்பட்டுள்ளதாக கட்சியின் ஊடகப் பேச்சாளர் சஞ்சீவ எதிரிமான்ன தெரிவித்துள்ளார்.",
        "கட்சியின் அனைத்து மாவட்ட மட்டத் தலைவர்களையும் கொழும்பு நெலும் மாவத்தையில் உள்ள ஸ்ரீலங்கா பொதுஜன பெரமுன கட்சியின் அலுவலகத்திற்கு வருமாறு அறிவிக்கப்பட்டுள்ளது.",
        "இதேவேளை, அரசாங்கத்தை பிரதிநிதித்துவப்படுத்தும் பாராளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர்களின் மற்றுமொரு கூட்டம் இன்று (29) நடைபெறவுள்ளதாக ஸ்ரீலங்கா பொதுஜன பெரமுனவின் பேச்சாளர் தெரிவித்துள்ளார்.",
        "5.00 மணிக்கு இந்த சந்திப்பு இடம்பெறவுள்ளதாக அரசியல் வட்டாரங்கள் தெரிவிக்கின்றன. இன்று.",
        "ஜனாதிபதியின் தலைமையில் ஜனாதிபதி செயலகத்தில் இந்தக் கூட்டம் நடைபெறவுள்ளது."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "கொழும்பு",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "பொதுஜன பெரமுன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "கொழும்பு",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "29",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "சஞ்சீவ எதிரிமான்ன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "கொழும்பு நெலும் மாவத்தை",
            "label": "LOC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "29",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "எஸ்.எல்.பி.பி",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "மாலை 5.00 மணி.",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஜனாதிபதி செயலகம்",
            "label": "FAC"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}