{
  "newspaper_id": "daily-mirror-lk",
  "url": "https://www.dailymirror.lk/latest_news/Conspiracy-to-oust-CB-Governor-Sajith/342-244198",
  "time_ut": 1662102575,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Conspiracy to oust CB Governor: Sajith",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Conspiracy to oust CB Governor: Sajith",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "A conspiracy is being hatched to oust Central Bank Governor Nandalal Weerasinge by making false allegations and appoint a new Governor loyal to certain people, Opposition Leader Sajith Premadasa alleged today.",
        "He told Parliament that certain government MPs made unfounded allegations and accused CB Governor Weerasinghe of turning the country into bankruptcy.",
        "\"He did not come to Sri Lanka looking for a job. He came here at the request of former President Gotabaya Rajapaksa. It was a good decision and we must appreciate those good moves. We noticed that he was maliciously attacked during the recent workshop by employing a certain MP. There is clear conspiracy to oust him and appoint a confidante to the position, he said and urged the government to stop such vindictive moves.",
        "He said such practices could dilute any hope of forming an all-party-government. (Ajith Siriwardana)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Sajith",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Central Bank",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Nandalal Weerasinge",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sajith Premadasa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "CB",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Weerasinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Gotabaya Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Ajith Siriwardana",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "CB ආණ්ඩුකාරවරයා එළවීමේ කුමන්ත්‍රණයක්: සජිත්",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "අසත්‍ය චෝදනා එල්ල කරමින් මහ බැංකු අධිපති නන්දලාල් වීරසිංහ මහතා ඉවත් කර ඇතැම් පුද්ගලයන්ට හිතවත් නව අධිපතිවරයකු පත් කිරීමේ කුමන්ත්‍රණයක් ක්‍රියාත්මක වෙමින් පවතින බව විපක්ෂ නායක සජිත් ප්‍රේමදාස මහතා අද (25) චෝදනා කළේය.",
        "ආණ්ඩුවේ ඇතැම් මන්ත්‍රීවරුන් පදනම් විරහිත චෝදනා එල්ල කරන බවත්, රට බංකොලොත් භාවයට පත් කළ බවට මහ බැංකු අධිපති වීරසිංහට චෝදනා කරන බවත් ඔහු පාර්ලිමේන්තුවට පැවසීය.",
        "\"ඔහු ශ්‍රී ලංකාවට පැමිණියේ රැකියාවක් බලාපොරොත්තුවෙන් නොවේ. ඔහු මෙහි පැමිණියේ හිටපු ජනාධිපති ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ මහතාගේ ඉල්ලීමකට අනුවය. එය හොඳ තීරණයක්. එම යහපත් ක්‍රියාමාර්ග අප අගය කළ යුතුයි. පසුගියදා පැවති වැඩමුළුවේදී ඔහුට ද්වේශසහගත ප්‍රහාරයක් එල්ල වූ බව අපි දුටුවෙමු. යම් මන්ත්‍රීවරයෙකු යොදවා ගනිමින් ඔහුව එලවා විශ්වාසවන්තයෙකු එම තනතුරට පත්කිරීමේ පැහැදිලි කුමන්ත්‍රණයක් පවතින බවත් එවැනි පළිගැනීම් ක්‍රියා නතර කරන ලෙසත් ඔහු රජයෙන් ඉල්ලා සිටියේය.",
        "සර්ව පාක්ෂික ආණ්ඩුවක් පිහිටුවීමේ ඕනෑම බලාපොරොත්තුවක් දියාරු කිරීමට මෙවැනි ක්‍රියාවලින් හැකි බව ඔහු පැවසීය. (අජිත් සිරිවර්ධන)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "සජිත්",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "මහ බැංකුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "නන්දලාල් වීරසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "සජිත් ප්‍රේමදාස",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "CB",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "වීරසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "අජිත් සිරිවර්ධන",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "சிபி ஆளுநரை வெளியேற்ற சதி: சஜித்",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "பொய்யான குற்றச்சாட்டுக்களை முன்வைத்து மத்திய வங்கி ஆளுநர் நந்தலால் வீரசிங்கவை பதவி நீக்கம் செய்து புதிய ஆளுநரை நியமிக்க சதி செய்யப்படுவதாக எதிர்க்கட்சித் தலைவர் சஜித் பிரேமதாச தெரிவித்துள்ளார்.",
        "சில அரசாங்க எம்.பி.க்கள் ஆதாரமற்ற குற்றச்சாட்டுகளை முன்வைத்ததாகவும், மத்திய ஆளுநர் வீரசிங்க நாட்டை திவாலான நிலைக்கு மாற்றியதாகவும் அவர் பாராளுமன்றத்தில் தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "\"அவர் வேலை தேடி இலங்கைக்கு வரவில்லை. முன்னாள் ஜனாதிபதி கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்சவின் வேண்டுகோளுக்கு இணங்க அவர் இங்கு வந்துள்ளார். இது ஒரு நல்ல முடிவு மற்றும் அந்த நல்ல நகர்வுகளை நாம் பாராட்ட வேண்டும். சமீபத்தில் நடந்த பட்டறையின் போது அவர் தீங்கிழைக்கும் வகையில் தாக்கப்பட்டதை நாங்கள் கவனித்தோம். ஒரு குறிப்பிட்ட எம்.பி.யை பணியில் அமர்த்தி, அவரை பதவி நீக்கம் செய்து, நம்பிக்கைக்குரிய ஒருவரை அந்த பதவிக்கு நியமிக்க, தெளிவான சதி உள்ளது என்றும், இதுபோன்ற பழிவாங்கும் நடவடிக்கையை அரசு நிறுத்த வேண்டும் என்றும் அவர் வலியுறுத்தினார்.",
        "இத்தகைய நடைமுறைகள் அனைத்துக் கட்சி-அரசாங்கம் அமைக்கும் எந்த நம்பிக்கையையும் நீர்த்துப்போகச் செய்யும் என்றார். (அஜித் சிறிவர்தன)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "சஜித்",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "மத்திய வங்கி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "நந்தலால் வீரசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "சஜித் பிரேமதாச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "சிபி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "வீரசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "அஜித் சிறிவர்தன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}