{
  "newspaper_id": "economy-next-com",
  "url": "https://economynext.com/sri-lanka-ex-president-kumaratunga-declares-open-new-lanka-freedom-party-hq-99450/",
  "time_ut": 1662357480,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Sri Lanka ex president Kumaratunga declares open New Lanka Freedom Party HQ",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Sri Lanka ex president Kumaratunga declares open New Lanka Freedom Party HQ",
      "author": "",
      "body_lines": [
        "ECONOMYNEXT – Sri Lanka former President and former leader of the Sri Lanka Freedom Party (SLFP) Chandrika Bandaranaike Kumaratunga has ceremoniously opened the headquarters of a new political party named the New Lanka Freedom Party (NLFP).",
        "The NLFP, an offshoot of the SLFP, is headed by former SLFP stalwart and Kalutara district MP Kumara Welgama. The party headquarters, located in Battaramulla, Colombo, was declared open by former President Kumaratunga on Monday September 05.",
        "Welgama contested the 2020 parliamentary election on the Samagi Jana Balawegaya (SJB) ticket but has since been functioning independently in parliament.",
        "He voted for the interim budget for 2022 presented by President and Finance Minister Ranil Wickremesinghe. The SJB abstained from voting.",
        "Welgama has long been known as a vocal critic of former President Gotabaya Rajapaksa, whose candidacy at the 2019 presidential election he had opposed from the start. However, the MP was one of the politicians subject to retaliatory mob violence on May 09, 2022, after supporters of the government launched an unprovoked attack on peaceful anti-government protestors.",
        "Welgama is also known for his close relations with former President Kumaratunga, whose father’s party, the SLFP, has significantly weakened in recent years, and the MP had vowed to establish a new political force.",
        "The MP recently told a TV interview that he is also keen to bring in Kumaratunga’s son, Vimukthi Kumaratunga, to active politics. (Colombo/Sep05/2022)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Sri Lanka",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "Kumaratunga",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "New Lanka Freedom Party",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Sri Lanka Freedom Party",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kumaratunga",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the New Lanka Freedom Party",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "SLFP",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "SLFP",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kalutara",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kumara Welgama",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Battaramulla, Colombo",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kumaratunga",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Monday September 05",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "2020",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Samagi",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Jana Balawegaya",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "SJB",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "2022",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Finance",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "SJB",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Welgama",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Gotabaya Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "2019",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "one",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "May 09, 2022",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Kumaratunga",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "SLFP",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "recent years",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Kumaratunga",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Vimukthi Kumaratunga",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "ශ්‍රී ලංකා හිටපු ජනාධිපති කුමාරතුංග මහතා නව ලංකා නිදහස් පක්ෂ මූලස්ථානය විවෘත කරයි",
      "author": "",
      "body_lines": [
        "ECONOMYNEXT - ශ්‍රී ලංකා හිටපු ජනාධිපතිනි සහ ශ්‍රී ලංකා නිදහස් පක්ෂයේ (ශ්‍රීලනිප) හිටපු නායිකා චන්ද්‍රිකා බණ්ඩාරනායක කුමාරතුංග මහත්මිය විසින් නව ලංකා නිදහස් පක්ෂය (NLFP) නමින් නව දේශපාලන පක්ෂයක මූලස්ථානය උත්සවාකාරයෙන් විවෘත කරන ලදී.",
        "ශ්‍රීලනිපයේ ශාඛාවක් වන NLFP නායකත්වය දරන්නේ හිටපු ශ්‍රීලනිප ප්‍රබලයෙකු සහ කළුතර දිස්ත්‍රික් පාර්ලිමේන්තු මන්ත්‍රී කුමාර වෙල්ගම විසිනි. කොළඹ බත්තරමුල්ලේ පිහිටි පක්ෂ මූලස්ථානය සැප්තැම්බර් 05 සඳුදා හිටපු ජනාධිපති කුමාරතුංග මහතා අතින් විවෘත විය.",
        "වෙල්ගම 2020 පාර්ලිමේන්තු මැතිවරණයට සමගි ජන බලවේගයෙන් (SJB) තරග කළ නමුත් එතැන් සිට පාර්ලිමේන්තුවේ ස්වාධීනව කටයුතු කරයි.",
        "ජනාධිපතිවරයා සහ මුදල් අමාත්‍ය රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතා විසින් ඉදිරිපත් කරන ලද 2022 සඳහා වූ අතුරු අයවැයට පක්ෂව ඡන්දය ප්‍රකාශ කළේය. SJB ඡන්දය දීමෙන් වැළකී සිටියේය.",
        "2019 ජනාධිපතිවරණයේ අපේක්ෂකත්වයට මුල සිටම විරුද්ධ වූ හිටපු ජනාධිපති ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂගේ දැඩි විවේචකයෙකු ලෙස වෙල්ගම බොහෝ කලක සිට ප්‍රසිද්ධියට පත්ව ඇත. කෙසේ වෙතත්, 2022 මැයි 09 වන දින සාමකාමී රාජ්‍ය විරෝධී විරෝධතාකරුවන්ට රජයේ ආධාරකරුවන් විසින් ප්‍රකෝපකාරී නොවන ප්‍රහාරයක් දියත් කිරීමෙන් පසු, පළිගැනීමේ මැර ප්‍රචණ්ඩත්වයට ලක් වූ දේශපාලනඥයින් අතර මන්ත්‍රීවරයා ද විය.",
        "වෙල්ගම හිටපු ජනාධිපති කුමාරතුංග සමඟ ඇති සමීප සබඳතා සඳහා ද ප්‍රසිද්ධය, ඔහුගේ පියාගේ පක්ෂය වන ශ්‍රීලනිපය මෑත වසරවලදී සැලකිය යුතු ලෙස දුර්වල වී ඇති අතර නව දේශපාලන බලවේගයක් පිහිටුවීමට මන්ත්‍රීවරයා සපථ කර තිබුණි.",
        "මන්ත්‍රීවරයා පසුගියදා රූපවාහිනී සාකච්ඡාවකට එක්වෙමින් කියා සිටියේ කුමාරතුංගගේ පුත් විමුක්ති කුමාරතුංගද ක්‍රියාකාරී දේශපාලනයට ගෙන ඒමට තමන් උනන්දු වන බවයි. (කොළඹ/සැප්.05/2022)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "කුමාරතුංග ය",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "නව ලංකා නිදහස් පක්ෂය",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකා නිදහස් පක්ෂය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "කුමාරතුංග ය",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "නව ලංකා නිදහස් පක්ෂය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රීලනිප",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රීලනිප",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "කළුතර",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "කුමාර වෙල්ගම",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "බත්තරමුල්ල, කොළඹ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "කුමාරතුංග ය",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "සැප්තැම්බර් 05 සඳුදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "2020",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "සමගි",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජන බලවේගය",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "එස්.ජේ.බී",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "2022",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මූල්ය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "එස්.ජේ.බී",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "වෙල්ගම",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "2019",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "එක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "2022 මැයි 09",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "කුමාරතුංග ය",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රීලනිප",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "පසුගිය වසරවල",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "කුමාරතුංග ය",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "විමුක්ති කුමාරතුංග",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "இலங்கையின் முன்னாள் ஜனாதிபதி குமாரதுங்க புதிய லங்கா சுதந்திரக் கட்சியின் தலைமையகத்தை திறந்து வைத்தார்",
      "author": "",
      "body_lines": [
        "பொருளாதாரம் - இலங்கையின் முன்னாள் ஜனாதிபதியும் ஸ்ரீலங்கா சுதந்திரக் கட்சியின் (SLFP) முன்னாள் தலைவருமான சந்திரிக்கா பண்டாரநாயக்க குமாரதுங்க புதிய லங்கா சுதந்திரக் கட்சி (NLFP) என்ற புதிய அரசியல் கட்சியின் தலைமையகத்தை வைபவ ரீதியாக திறந்து வைத்தார்.",
        "ஸ்ரீ.ல.சு.க.வின் கிளையான என்.எல்.எப்.பி, முன்னாள் ஸ்ரீ.ல.சு.க. முக்கியஸ்தரும் களுத்துறை மாவட்ட எம்.பி.யுமான குமார வெல்கம தலைமையில் இயங்குகிறது. கொழும்பு பத்தரமுல்லையில் அமைந்துள்ள கட்சியின் தலைமையகம் முன்னாள் ஜனாதிபதி குமாரதுங்கவினால் செப்டம்பர் 05 திங்கட்கிழமை திறந்து வைக்கப்பட்டது.",
        "வெல்கம 2020 நாடாளுமன்றத் தேர்தலில் சமகி ஜன பலவேகய (SJB) சீட்டில் போட்டியிட்டார், ஆனால் அதன் பின்னர் நாடாளுமன்றத்தில் சுயேச்சையாகச் செயல்பட்டு வருகிறார்.",
        "ஜனாதிபதியும் நிதியமைச்சருமான ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்கவினால் முன்வைக்கப்பட்ட 2022ஆம் ஆண்டுக்கான இடைக்கால வரவு செலவுத் திட்டத்திற்கு அவர் வாக்களித்துள்ளார். SJB வாக்களிப்பதில் இருந்து விலகியிருந்தது.",
        "வெல்கம நீண்டகாலமாக முன்னாள் ஜனாதிபதி கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ஷவை கடுமையாக விமர்சிப்பவராக அறியப்பட்டவர், 2019 ஜனாதிபதித் தேர்தலில் அவரது வேட்புமனுவை ஆரம்பத்தில் இருந்தே அவர் எதிர்த்தார். எவ்வாறாயினும், 2022 மே 09 அன்று அமைதியான அரசாங்க எதிர்ப்பு ஆர்ப்பாட்டக்காரர்கள் மீது அரசாங்கத்தின் ஆதரவாளர்கள் தூண்டுதலற்ற தாக்குதலைத் தொடங்கிய பின்னர், பழிவாங்கும் கும்பல் வன்முறைக்கு உட்பட்ட அரசியல்வாதிகளில் ஒருவரான எம்.பி.",
        "வெல்கம முன்னாள் ஜனாதிபதி குமாரதுங்கவுடனான அவரது நெருங்கிய உறவுகளுக்காகவும் அறியப்படுகிறார், அவரது தந்தையின் கட்சியான ஸ்ரீ.ல.சு.க சமீப ஆண்டுகளில் கணிசமாக பலவீனமடைந்துள்ளது, மேலும் புதிய அரசியல் சக்தியை ஸ்தாபிப்பதாக பாராளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர் சபதம் செய்திருந்தார்.",
        "குமாரதுங்கவின் மகன் விமுக்தி குமாரதுங்கவையும் தீவிர அரசியலுக்குக் கொண்டு வர ஆர்வமாக உள்ளதாக எம்.பி சமீபத்தில் ஒரு தொலைக்காட்சி நேர்காணலுக்குத் தெரிவித்தார். (கொழும்பு/செப்05/2022)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "இலங்கை",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "குமாரதுங்க",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "புதிய லங்கா சுதந்திரக் கட்சி",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஸ்ரீலங்கா சுதந்திரக் கட்சி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "குமாரதுங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "புதிய லங்கா சுதந்திரக் கட்சி",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஸ்ரீ.ல.சு.க",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஸ்ரீ.ல.சு.க",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "களுத்துறை",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "குமார வெல்கம",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "பத்தரமுல்ல, கொழும்பு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "குமாரதுங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "செப்டம்பர் 05 திங்கட்கிழமை",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "2020",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சமகி",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜன பலவேகயா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "எஸ்.ஜே.பி",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "2022",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "நிதி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "எஸ்.ஜே.பி",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "வெல்கம",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "2019",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஒன்று",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "மே 09, 2022",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "குமாரதுங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஸ்ரீ.ல.சு.க",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "சமீபத்திய ஆண்டுகளில்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "குமாரதுங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "விமுக்தி குமாரதுங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}