{
  "newspaper_id": "ada-lk",
  "url": "https://www.ada.lk/breaking_news/ජුලි-මාසයේදී-සංචාරකයන්-28000ක්-ඇවිත්/11-395670",
  "time_ut": 1658558721,
  "original_lang": "si",
  "original_title": "ජුලි මාසයේදී සංචාරකයන් 28000ක් ඇවිත්",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "28000 tourists came in July",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "According to the Tourism Development Authority, 28 733 tourists have come to Sri Lanka in the first 19 days of July. Along with that number, the number of tourists who have come to Sri Lanka so far this year is 440110, said the authority.",
        "England, India and Germany have become the three countries where the largest number of tourists have visited Sri Lanka this month.",
        "However, since the state of emergency is currently in force in the country, this will cause some hindrance to tourist arrivals in the future, according to representatives of the tourism industry."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "28000",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "July",
          "label": "DATE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "the Tourism Development Authority",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "28",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "the first 19 days of July",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "440110",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "England",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "India",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Germany",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "three",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "this month",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        []
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "ජුලි මාසයේදී සංචාරකයන් 28000ක් ඇවිත්",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "ජුලි මාසයේ පළමු දින 19 තුළ ශ්‍රී ලංකාවට සංචාරකයන් 28 733ක් පැමිණ ඇති බව සංචාරක සංවර්ධන අධිකාරිය පවසයි. එම සංඛ්‍යාවද සමගන් මේ වසරේදී මේ දක්වා ශ්‍රි ලංකාවට පැමිණ ඇති සංචාරකයන් සංඛ්‍යාව 440110 ක් බවද එම අධිකාරිය පවසයි.",
        "මේ මසයේදී ශ්‍රී ලංකාවට වැඩිම සංචාරකයන් පිරිසක් පැමිණි රටවල් තුන බවට මේ දක්වා පත්ව ඇත්තේ එංගලන්තය, ඉන්දියාව හා ජර්මනියයි.",
        "කෙසේ වෙතත් මේ වන විට රට තුළ හදිසි නීතිය ක්‍රියාත්මක බැවින් ඉදිරියේදී සංචාරක පැමිණීම්වලට මෙය තරමක බාධාවක් ඇතිකරනු ඇතැයි සංචාරක ක්ෂේත්‍ර යේ නියෝජිතයෝ පවසති."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "28000",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "ජුලි",
          "label": "DATE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "සංචාරක සංවර්ධන අධිකාරිය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "28",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජූලි පළමු දින 19",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "440110",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "එංගලන්තය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජර්මනිය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "තුන්",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මේ මාසයේ",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        []
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "ஜூலை மாதத்தில் 28000 சுற்றுலாப் பயணிகள் வந்தனர்",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "சுற்றுலா அபிவிருத்தி அதிகார சபையின் கூற்றுப்படி, ஜூலை மாதம் முதல் 19 நாட்களில் 28 ஆயிரத்து 733 சுற்றுலாப் பயணிகள் இலங்கைக்கு வந்துள்ளனர். அந்த எண்ணிக்கையுடன் இந்த வருடத்தின் இதுவரையான காலப்பகுதியில் இலங்கைக்கு வந்துள்ள சுற்றுலாப் பயணிகளின் எண்ணிக்கை 440110 என அதிகார சபை தெரிவித்துள்ளது.",
        "இம்மாதம் இலங்கைக்கு அதிகளவான சுற்றுலாப் பயணிகள் வருகை தந்த மூன்று நாடுகளாக இங்கிலாந்து, இந்தியா மற்றும் ஜேர்மனி ஆகிய மூன்று நாடுகளும் மாறியுள்ளன.",
        "எவ்வாறாயினும், நாட்டில் தற்போது அவசரகாலச் சட்டம் அமுலில் உள்ளதால், இது எதிர்காலத்தில் சுற்றுலாப் பயணிகளின் வருகைக்கு சில இடையூறுகளை ஏற்படுத்தும் என சுற்றுலாத்துறை பிரதிநிதிகள் தெரிவிக்கின்றனர்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "28000",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "ஜூலை",
          "label": "DATE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "சுற்றுலா வளர்ச்சி ஆணையம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "28",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜூலை முதல் 19 நாட்கள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "440110",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இங்கிலாந்து",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்தியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜெர்மனி",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "மூன்று",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்த மாதம்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        []
      ]
    }
  }
}