{
  "newspaper_id": "lankadeepa-lk",
  "url": "https://www.lankadeepa.lk/news/කළමනාකරණ-නිලධාරීන්-පාස්පෝට්-කන්තෝරුවට/101-616019",
  "time_ut": 1657197453,
  "original_lang": "si",
  "original_title": "කළමනාකරණ නිලධාරීන් පාස්පෝට් කන්තෝරුවට",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Management Officers to Passport Office",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "The Ministry of Public Administration has informed all heads of institutions to assign Management Service Officers to the Immigration Department for a period of three months.",
        "This decision has been taken as per the request of the Comptroller General of Immigration, paying attention to the current congestion in the Battaramulla head office of the Immigration Department, and accordingly, management service officers residing within 10 km of the Immigration Department office are to be assigned to that office."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Management Officers to",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "Passport Office",
          "label": "FAC"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "The Ministry of Public Administration",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Management Service Officers",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Immigration Department",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "three months",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the Comptroller General of Immigration",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Battaramulla",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Immigration Department",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "10 km",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Immigration Department",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "කළමනාකරණ නිලධාරීන් පාස්පෝට් කන්තෝරුවට",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "කළමනාකරණ සේවා නිලධාරීන් මාස තුනක කාලයක් සඳහා ආගමන විගමන දෙපාර්තමේන්තුවට අනුයුක්ත කරන ලෙස රාජ්‍ය පරිපාලන අමාත්‍යංශය සියලුම ආයතන ප්‍රධානීන්ට දැනුම් දී තිබේ.",
        "ආගමන විගමන දෙපාර්තමේන්තුවේ බත්තරමුල්ල ප්‍රධාන කාර්යාලය තුළ මේ වන විට පවතින තදබදය පිළිබඳව අවධානය යොමු කර ආගමන විගමන පාලක ජනරාල්වරයාගේ ඉල්ලීමකට අනුව මෙම තීරණය ගෙන ඇති අතර ඒ අනුව ආගමන විගමන දෙපාර්තමේන්තු කාර්යාලයට කිලෝමීටර 10 ක දුර තුළ පදිංචි කළමනාකරණ සේවා නිලධාරීන් මෙසේ එම කාර්යාලයට අනුයුක්ත කිරීමට නියමිතය."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "කළමනාකරණ නිලධාරීන් වෙත",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "ගමන් බලපත්ර කාර්යාලය",
          "label": "FAC"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "රාජ්ය පරිපාලන අමාත්යාංශය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "කළමනාකරණ සේවා නිලධාරීන්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ආගමන දෙපාර්තමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "මාස තුනක්",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ආගමන විගමන පාලක ජනරාල්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "බත්තරමුල්ල",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ආගමන දෙපාර්තමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "10 කි.මී",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "ආගමන දෙපාර්තමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "பாஸ்போர்ட் அலுவலகத்திற்கு நிர்வாக அதிகாரிகள்",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "மூன்று மாத காலத்திற்கு குடிவரவு திணைக்களத்திற்கு முகாமைத்துவ சேவை அதிகாரிகளை நியமிக்குமாறு பொது நிர்வாக அமைச்சு அனைத்து நிறுவனங்களின் தலைவர்களுக்கும் அறிவித்துள்ளது.",
        "குடிவரவு குடியகழ்வு திணைக்களத்தின் பத்தரமுல்ல பிரதான காரியாலயத்தில் தற்போது காணப்படும் நெரிசல் குறித்து அவதானம் செலுத்தி குடிவரவு குடியகழ்வு திணைக்களத்தின் 10 கிலோமீற்றர் தூரத்திற்குள் வசிக்கும் முகாமைத்துவ சேவை உத்தியோகத்தர்களின் வேண்டுகோளுக்கு இணங்க இந்த தீர்மானம் எடுக்கப்பட்டுள்ளது. அந்த அலுவலகத்திற்கு ஒதுக்கப்பட்டுள்ளது."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "நிர்வாக அதிகாரிகளுக்கு",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "பாஸ்போர்ட் அலுவலகம்",
          "label": "FAC"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "பொது நிர்வாக அமைச்சகம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "மேலாண்மை சேவை அதிகாரிகள்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "குடிவரவுத் துறை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "மூன்று மாதங்கள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "குடியேற்றத்தின் பொதுக் கட்டுப்பாட்டாளர்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "பத்தரமுல்ல",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "குடிவரவுத் துறை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "10 கி.மீ",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "குடிவரவுத் துறை",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}