{
  "newspaper_id": "economy-next-com",
  "url": "https://economynext.com/move-to-pay-117-mn-in-compensation-to-victimised-sri-lanka-officials-report-98511/",
  "time_ut": 1660456680,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Move to pay 117 mn in compensation to “victimised” Sri Lanka officials: report",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Move to pay 117 mn in compensation to “victimised” Sri Lanka officials: report",
      "author": "",
      "body_lines": [
        "ECONOMYNEXT – A section of the ruling Sri Lanka Podujana Peramuna (SLPP) is attempting to push a cabinet paper through the office of Prime Minister Dinesh Gunawardena recommending over 117 million rupees in compensation to state official who were allegedly “victimised” from 2015 to 2019, the weekly English newspaper The Sunday Times reported.",
        "According to a report on The Sunday Times that appeared on Sunday August 14, the paper, which had originally been drafted by former Prime Minister Mahinda Rajapaksa before his resignation on May 09, has now resurfaced and pressure is being brought on Prime Minister Gunawardena’s office by SLPP “higher-ups” to submit the paper to the cabinet and secure the recommended compensation.",
        "A total of 27 officials are due to receive monetary compensation, according to documents reportedly seen by The Sunday Times, with compensation ranging from 700,000 to 25 million rupees. (Colombo/Aug14/2022)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "117",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "Sri Lanka",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "Podujana Peramuna",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Dinesh Gunawardena",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "over 117 million",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "2015 to 2019",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "weekly",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "English",
            "label": "LANGUAGE"
          },
          {
            "text": "The Sunday Times",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "The Sunday Times",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sunday August 14",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Mahinda Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "May 09",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Gunawardena",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "27",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "The Sunday Times",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "700,000 to 25 million",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "“වින්දිත” ශ්‍රී ලංකා නිලධාරීන්ට වන්දි වශයෙන් මිලියන 117ක් ගෙවීමට පියවර: වාර්තාව",
      "author": "",
      "body_lines": [
        "ECONOMYNEXT – පාලක ශ්‍රී ලංකා පොදුජන පෙරමුණේ (SLPP) කොටසක් 2015 සිට 2019 දක්වා “ගොදුරක්” වූ බව කියන රාජ්‍ය නිලධාරින්ට රුපියල් මිලියන 117කට අධික වන්දි මුදලක් නිර්දේශ කරමින් අගමැති දිනේෂ් ගුණවර්ධනගේ කාර්යාලය හරහා කැබිනට් පත්‍රිකාවක් තල්ලු කිරීමට උත්සාහ කරයි. සතිපතා ඉංග්‍රීසි පුවත්පතක් වන ද සන්ඩේ ටයිම්ස් වාර්තා කළේය.",
        "අගෝස්තු 14 ඉරිදා පළ වූ The Sunday Times පුවත්පතේ වාර්තාවකට අනුව, මැයි 09 වැනිදා ඉල්ලා අස්වීමට පෙර හිටපු අගමැති මහින්ද රාජපක්ෂ මහතා විසින් මුලින් කෙටුම්පත් කර තිබූ පත්‍රය මේ වන විට යළි කරළියට පැමිණ ඇති අතර අගමැති ගුණවර්ධනගේ කාර්යාලයට බලපෑම් එල්ල කරන්නේ කැබිනට් මණ්ඩලයට පත්‍රිකාව ඉදිරිපත් කර නිර්දේශිත වන්දි ලබා ගැනීමට ශ්‍රී ලංකා පොදුජන පෙරමුණේ “ඉහළින්”.",
        "සන්ඩේ ටයිම්ස් විසින් වාර්තා කරන ලද ලේඛනවලට අනුව, රුපියල් ලක්ෂ 7 සිට මිලියන 25 දක්වා වන්දි මුදලක් සහිතව නිලධාරීන් 27 දෙනෙකුට මුල්‍ය වන්දි ගෙවීමට නියමිතය. (කොළඹ/අගෝ.14/2022)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "117",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "පොදුජන පෙරමුණ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "දිනේෂ් ගුණවර්ධන",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "මිලියන 117 ඉක්මවයි",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "2015 සිට 2019 දක්වා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "සතිපතා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉංග්රීසි",
            "label": "LANGUAGE"
          },
          {
            "text": "සන්ඩේ ටයිම්ස්",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "සන්ඩේ ටයිම්ස්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "අගෝස්තු 14 ඉරිදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මහින්ද රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "මැයි 09",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගුණවර්ධන ය",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "27",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "සන්ඩේ ටයිම්ස්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "700,000 සිට මිලියන 25 දක්වා",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "\"பாதிக்கப்பட்ட\" இலங்கை அதிகாரிகளுக்கு 117 மில்லியன் இழப்பீடு வழங்க நடவடிக்கை: அறிக்கை",
      "author": "",
      "body_lines": [
        "பொருளாதாரம் - ஆளும் ஸ்ரீலங்கா பொதுஜன பெரமுனவின் (SLPP) ஒரு பகுதி, 2015 முதல் 2019 வரை \"பாதிக்கப்பட்ட\"தாகக் கூறப்படும் அரச அதிகாரிகளுக்கு 117 மில்லியன் ரூபா நட்டஈடாகப் பரிந்துரைக்கும் அமைச்சரவைப் பத்திரத்தை பிரதமர் தினேஷ் குணவர்தனவின் அலுவலகத்தின் ஊடாக முன்வைக்க முயற்சிக்கிறது. தி சண்டே டைம்ஸ் வார ஆங்கில நாளிதழ் செய்தி வெளியிட்டுள்ளது.",
        "ஆகஸ்ட் 14 ஞாயிற்றுக்கிழமை வெளிவந்த த சண்டே டைம்ஸ் செய்தியின்படி, முன்னாள் பிரதமர் மஹிந்த ராஜபக்ஷ மே 09 அன்று ராஜினாமா செய்வதற்கு முன்னர் முதலில் வரையப்பட்ட பத்திரிகை இப்போது மீண்டும் வெளிவந்துள்ளது மற்றும் பிரதமர் குணவர்தனவின் அலுவலகத்திற்கு அழுத்தம் கொடுக்கப்பட்டுள்ளது. SLPP \"உயர்-அப்கள்\" அமைச்சரவைக்கு பத்திரத்தை சமர்ப்பித்து பரிந்துரைக்கப்பட்ட இழப்பீட்டைப் பெற வேண்டும்.",
        "700,000 முதல் 25 மில்லியன் ரூபாய் வரையிலான இழப்பீடுகளுடன், தி சண்டே டைம்ஸ் பார்த்த ஆவணங்களின்படி, மொத்தம் 27 அதிகாரிகள் பண இழப்பீடு பெற உள்ளனர். (கொழும்பு/ஆகஸ்ட்14/2022)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "117",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "இலங்கை",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "பொதுஜன பெரமுன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "தினேஷ் குணவர்தன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "117 மில்லியனுக்கு மேல்",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "2015 முதல் 2019 வரை",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "வாரந்தோறும்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆங்கிலம்",
            "label": "LANGUAGE"
          },
          {
            "text": "தி சண்டே டைம்ஸ்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "தி சண்டே டைம்ஸ்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆகஸ்ட் 14 ஞாயிறு",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "மஹிந்த ராஜபக்ஷ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "மே 09",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "குணவர்தன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "27",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "தி சண்டே டைம்ஸ்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "700,000 முதல் 25 மில்லியன் வரை",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}