{
  "newspaper_id": "ada-lk",
  "url": "https://www.ada.lk/breaking_news/මහ-බැංකුව-ගැනත්-හොයලා-බලන්න---ණය-ගෙවීම-පැහැර-හැරියේ-ඇයි-/11-396811",
  "time_ut": 1662015174,
  "original_lang": "si",
  "original_title": "මහ බැංකුව ගැනත් හොයලා බලන්න - ණය ගෙවීම පැහැර හැරියේ ඇයි?",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Also find out about the Central Bank - Why did the loan default?",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "Member of Parliament Mr. Vajira Abeywardena says that if we look into Sri Lanka's Water Supply Board, Electricity Board and Petroleum Corporation, we should also look into the Central Bank of Sri Lanka.",
        "Joining the budget debate in Parliament, he said that it should be inquired as to who approved Sri Lanka's debt default.",
        "He also stated that there is no responsibility of the MPs for this. \"Whoever asked, who did this, the Parliament should approve,\" he said."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "the Central Bank - Why",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Vajira Abeywardena",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka's",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Water Supply Board",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Electricity Board",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Petroleum Corporation",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Central Bank of Sri Lanka",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka's",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "මහ බැංකුව ගැනත් හොයලා බලන්න - ණය ගෙවීම පැහැර හැරියේ ඇයි?",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ ජල සම්පාදන මණ්ඩලය, විදුලි බල මණ්ඩලය හා ඛණිජ තෙල් සංස්ථාව පිළිබඳව සොයා බලනවානම් ශ්‍රී ලංකා මහ බැංකුව පිළිබඳවද සොයා බැලිය යුතු බව පාර්ලිමේ්නතු මන්ත්‍රී වජිර අබේවර්ධන මහතා පවසයි.",
        "පාර්ලිමේන්තුවේදී අයවැය විවාදයට එක්වෙමින් ඔහු ප්‍රකාශ කළේ ශ්‍රී ලංකාව ණය පැහැර හරින බවට ප්‍රකාශ කළේ කවුරුන් අනුමැතිය ඇතිවද යන්න පිළිබඳව විමසා බැලිය යුතු බවයි.",
        "මේ සඳහා මන්ත්‍රීවරුන්ගේ වගකීමක් නොමැති බවද ඔහු ප්‍රකාශ කළේය. \" කාගෙන්ද ඇහුවේ, කවුද මෙහෙම කළේ, පාර්ලිමේන්තුවයි අනුමැතිය දිය යුත්තේ \" යැයි ඔහු පැවැසීය."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "මහ බැංකුව - ඇයි?",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "වජිර අබේවර්ධන",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජල සම්පාදන මණ්ඩලය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "විදුලිබල මණ්ඩලය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඛනිජ තෙල් සංස්ථාව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකා මහ බැංකුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "மத்திய வங்கியைப் பற்றியும் தெரிந்து கொள்ளுங்கள் - கடன் ஏன் தவறியது?",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "இலங்கையின் நீர்வழங்கல் சபை, மின்சார சபை, பெற்றோலியக் கூட்டுத்தாபனம் ஆகியவற்றைப் பார்த்தால் இலங்கை மத்திய வங்கியையும் பார்க்க வேண்டும் என நாடாளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர் திரு வஜிர அபேவர்தன தெரிவித்துள்ளார்.",
        "நாடாளுமன்றத்தில் வரவு செலவுத் திட்ட விவாதத்தில் கலந்துகொண்டு உரையாற்றிய அவர், இலங்கையின் கடனைத் திருப்பிச் செலுத்துவதற்கு யார் அங்கீகாரம் வழங்கினர் என்பது குறித்து விசாரிக்கப்பட வேண்டும் என்றார்.",
        "இதற்கு எம்.பி.க்களுக்கு எந்தப் பொறுப்பும் இல்லை என்றும் அவர் குறிப்பிட்டார். இதை யார் கேட்டாலும், யார் செய்தாலும் நாடாளுமன்றம் அங்கீகரிக்க வேண்டும் என்றார்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "மத்திய வங்கி - ஏன்",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "வஜிர அபேவர்தன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கையின்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "நீர் வழங்கல் வாரியம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "மின்சார வாரியம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "பெட்ரோலியம் கார்ப்பரேஷன்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை மத்திய வங்கி",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கையின்",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}