{
  "newspaper_id": "ada-derana-lk",
  "url": "http://www.adaderana.lk/news/84696/assets-of-sri-lankans-with-ltte-links-seized-in-india-over-money-laundering-charges",
  "time_ut": 1662060720,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Assets of Sri Lankans with LTTE links seized in India over money laundering charges",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Assets of Sri Lankans with LTTE links seized in India over money laundering charges",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "India’s Enforcement Directorate (ED) on Thursday said that they have attached three immovable properties worth INR 337 million belonging to Sri Lankan nationals, linked to the banned LTTE in connection with a Prevention of Money Laundering case.",
        "The official said that a bungalow on the ECR and two agricultural lands in Thiruvannamalai district, owned by Gunasekaran alias Perama Kumar, and his son Dileep alias Thileep were attached.",
        "Kumar was reportedly charged over the bomb attack targeting former Sri Lankan President Chandrika Bandaranaike Kumaratunga.",
        "The Enforcement Directorate initiated money laundering probes on the basis of FIR registered by CID, Kancheepuram in 2020.",
        "It is alleged that Kumar, his son, and others committed offences covered under the Foreigners Act, the Passports Act, the NDPS Act, and the Indian Penal Code.",
        "The accused individuals had created and used fake identity cards such as PAN, Aadhar, and driving licenses over a period and stayed illegally in India.",
        "During the course of investigation, it was found out that Kumar, Suresh Raj, Mohamed Sherif, and Raja Medura Gedara alias Gamini were involved in buying and selling of drugs, and were convicted by court for the crime in 2011.",
        "After the completion of their jail term, they changed their identity and generated proceeds of crime. The properties attached in the instant case are all purchased after 2011 and the accused were not able to explain the source of funds used in their purchase.",
        "It was learnt that the market value of the said immovable properties are much higher than the value mentioned in the documents."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Sri Lankans",
          "label": "NORP"
        },
        {
          "text": "LTTE",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "India",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "India",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Enforcement Directorate",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Thursday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "three",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "INR 337 million",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lankan",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "LTTE",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "a Prevention of Money Laundering",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ECR",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "two",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Thiruvannamalai",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Gunasekaran",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Perama Kumar",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Kumar",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lankan",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Chandrika Bandaranaike",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kumaratunga",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "The Enforcement Directorate",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "FIR",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "CID",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kancheepuram",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "2020",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Kumar",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Foreigners Act",
            "label": "LAW"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Passports Act",
            "label": "LAW"
          },
          {
            "text": "the NDPS Act",
            "label": "PRODUCT"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Indian Penal Code",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "PAN",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Aadhar",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "India",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Kumar",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Mohamed Sherif",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Medura Gedara",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Gamini",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "2011",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "2011",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        []
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "මුදල් විශුද්ධිකරණ චෝදනා මත එල්ටීටීඊ සබඳතා ඇති ශ්‍රී ලාංකිකයන්ගේ වත්කම් ඉන්දියාවේදී අත්අඩංගුවට ගැනේ",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "මුදල් විශුද්ධිකරණය වැලැක්වීමේ නඩුවකට අදාළව තහනම් එල්ටීටීඊ සංවිධානයට සම්බන්ධ ශ්‍රී ලාංකික පුරවැසියන්ට අයත් රුපියල් මිලියන 337 ක් වටිනා නිශ්චල දේපල තුනක් තමන් භාරයට ගෙන ඇති බව ඉන්දියාවේ බලාත්මක කිරීමේ අධ්‍යක්ෂ මණ්ඩලය (ED) බ්‍රහස්පතින්දා ප්‍රකාශ කළේය.",
        "ගුණසේකරන් හෙවත් පෙරම කුමාර් සහ ඔහුගේ පුත් දිලීප් හෙවත් තිලීප්ට අයත් ECR හි බංගලාවක් සහ තිරුවානාමලෙයි දිස්ත්‍රික්කයේ කෘෂිකාර්මික ඉඩම් දෙකක් අනුයුක්ත කර ඇති බව නිලධාරියා පැවසීය.",
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකා හිටපු ජනාධිපතිනි චන්ද්‍රිකා බණ්ඩාරනායක කුමාරතුංග මහත්මිය ඉලක්ක කර එල්ල කළ බෝම්බ ප්‍රහාරය සම්බන්ධයෙන් කුමාර්ට චෝදනා එල්ල වී ඇති බව වාර්තා වේ.",
        "2020 දී CID, Kancheepuram විසින් ලියාපදිංචි කරන ලද FIR පදනම මත බලාත්මක කිරීමේ අධ්‍යක්ෂ මණ්ඩලය මුදල් විශුද්ධිකරණය පිළිබඳ විමර්ශන ආරම්භ කරන ලදී.",
        "කුමාර්, ඔහුගේ පුතා සහ තවත් අය විදේශිකයන්ගේ පනත, විදේශ ගමන් බලපත්‍ර පනත, NDPS පනත සහ ඉන්දීය දණ්ඩ නීති සංග්‍රහය යටතේ ආවරණය වන වැරදි සිදු කළ බවට චෝදනා එල්ල වේ.",
        "චූදිතයන් විසින් PAN, Aadhar සහ රියදුරු බලපත්‍ර වැනි ව්‍යාජ හැඳුනුම්පත් නිර්මාණය කර භාවිත කර කාලාන්තරයක් තිස්සේ නීතිවිරෝධී ලෙස ඉන්දියාවේ රැඳී සිට ඇත.",
        "විමර්ශනයේදී කුමාර්, සුරේෂ් රාජ්, මොහොමඩ් ෂෙරීෆ් සහ රාජ මැදුර ගෙදර නොහොත් ගාමිණී මත්ද්‍රව්‍ය මිලදී ගැනීමට සහ විකිණීමට සම්බන්ධ බවට අනාවරණය වී ඇති අතර, 2011 වසරේ එම අපරාධයට අධිකරණයෙන් වරදකරුවන් විය.",
        "ඔවුන්ගේ සිර දඬුවම අවසන් වූ පසු, ඔවුන් ඔවුන්ගේ අනන්‍යතාවය වෙනස් කර අපරාධවලින් මුදල් උපයා ගත්හ. ක්ෂණික නඩුවේ අමුණා ඇති දේපල සියල්ලම 2011 න් පසුව මිලදී ගත් ඒවා වන අතර විත්තිකරුවන්ට ඔවුන් මිලදී ගැනීමට භාවිතා කළ මුදල් මූලාශ්‍රය පැහැදිලි කිරීමට නොහැකි විය.",
        "එම නිශ්චල දේපලවල වෙළඳපල වටිනාකම ලේඛනවල සඳහන් වටිනාකමට වඩා බෙහෙවින් වැඩි බව දැනගන්නට ලැබිණි."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ශ්‍රී ලාංකිකයන්",
          "label": "NORP"
        },
        {
          "text": "එල්ටීටීඊය",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "ඉන්දියාව",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "බලාත්මක කිරීමේ අධ්යක්ෂ මණ්ඩලය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "බ්රහස්පතින්දා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "තුන්",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දීය රුපියල් මිලියන 337 කි",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලාංකික",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "එල්ටීටීඊය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "මුදල් විශුද්ධිකරණය වැළැක්වීම",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ECR",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "දෙක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "තිරුවන්නමලෙයි",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගුණසේකරන්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "පෙරම කුමාර",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "කුමාර",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලාංකික",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "චන්ද්‍රිකා බණ්ඩාරනායක",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "කුමාරතුංග ය",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "බලාත්මක කිරීමේ අධ්යක්ෂ මණ්ඩලය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "FIR",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "CID",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "කාංචීපුරම්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "2020",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "කුමාර",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "විදේශිකයන්ගේ පනත",
            "label": "LAW"
          },
          {
            "text": "විදේශ ගමන් බලපත්ර පනත",
            "label": "LAW"
          },
          {
            "text": "NDPS පනත",
            "label": "PRODUCT"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දියානු දණ්ඩ නීති සංග්‍රහය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "පෑන්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ආධාර්",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "කුමාර",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මොහොමඩ් ෂෙරිෆ්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "මැදුර ගෙදර",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගාමිණී",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "2011",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "2011",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        []
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "இந்தியாவில் பணமோசடி குற்றச்சாட்டின் பேரில் விடுதலைப் புலிகளுடன் தொடர்புடைய இலங்கையர்களின் சொத்துக்கள் கைப்பற்றப்பட்டுள்ளன",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "பணமோசடி தடுப்பு வழக்கு தொடர்பாக தடை செய்யப்பட்ட விடுதலைப் புலிகளுடன் தொடர்புடைய இலங்கை பிரஜைகளின் 337 மில்லியன் ரூபாய் மதிப்புள்ள மூன்று அசையா சொத்துக்களை பறிமுதல் செய்துள்ளதாக இந்தியாவின் அமலாக்க இயக்குநரகம் (ED) வியாழக்கிழமை தெரிவித்துள்ளது.",
        "இசிஆரில் உள்ள ஒரு பங்களாவும், திருவண்ணாமலை மாவட்டத்தில் பெரம குமார் என்கிற குணசேகரனுக்கு சொந்தமான இரண்டு விவசாய நிலங்களும், அவரது மகன் திலீப் என்கிற திலீப்பும் இணைக்கப்பட்டதாக அந்த அதிகாரி தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "இலங்கையின் முன்னாள் ஜனாதிபதி சந்திரிகா பண்டாரநாயக்க குமாரதுங்காவை இலக்கு வைத்து நடத்தப்பட்ட வெடிகுண்டுத் தாக்குதல் தொடர்பாக குமார் மீது குற்றம் சுமத்தப்பட்டுள்ளதாக தெரிவிக்கப்படுகிறது.",
        "2020 ஆம் ஆண்டு காஞ்சிபுரம் சிஐடி பதிவு செய்த எப்ஐஆர் அடிப்படையில் அமலாக்க இயக்குனரகம் பணமோசடி விசாரணையைத் தொடங்கியது.",
        "குமார், அவரது மகன் மற்றும் பலர் வெளிநாட்டினர் சட்டம், பாஸ்போர்ட் சட்டம், என்டிபிஎஸ் சட்டம் மற்றும் இந்திய தண்டனைச் சட்டம் ஆகியவற்றின் கீழ் உள்ள குற்றங்களைச் செய்ததாகக் கூறப்படுகிறது.",
        "குற்றம் சாட்டப்பட்ட நபர்கள் பான், ஆதார் மற்றும் ஓட்டுநர் உரிமம் போன்ற போலி அடையாள அட்டைகளை உருவாக்கி பயன்படுத்தியுள்ளனர் மற்றும் இந்தியாவில் சட்டவிரோதமாக தங்கியுள்ளனர்.",
        "விசாரணையில், குமார், சுரேஷ் ராஜ், முகமது ஷெரீப், காமினி என்ற ராஜா மெதுரா கெடரா ஆகியோர் போதைப்பொருள் கொள்முதல் மற்றும் விற்பனையில் ஈடுபட்டது தெரியவந்தது, மேலும் அவர்கள் 2011 ஆம் ஆண்டு குற்றத்திற்காக நீதிமன்றத்தால் தண்டிக்கப்பட்டனர்.",
        "சிறைத்தண்டனை முடிந்த பிறகு, அவர்கள் தங்கள் அடையாளத்தை மாற்றி, குற்றத்தின் வருமானத்தை உருவாக்கினர். உடனடி வழக்கில் இணைக்கப்பட்ட சொத்துக்கள் அனைத்தும் 2011 ஆம் ஆண்டுக்குப் பிறகு வாங்கப்பட்டவை மற்றும் குற்றம் சாட்டப்பட்டவர்களால் அவர்கள் வாங்கப்பட்ட நிதி ஆதாரத்தை விளக்க முடியவில்லை.",
        "ஆவணங்களில் குறிப்பிடப்பட்டுள்ள அசையா சொத்துகளின் சந்தை மதிப்பை விட சந்தை மதிப்பு அதிகம் என தெரிய வந்தது."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "இலங்கையர்கள்",
          "label": "NORP"
        },
        {
          "text": "விடுதலைப் புலிகள்",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "இந்தியா",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "இந்தியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "அமலாக்க இயக்குநரகம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "வியாழன்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "மூன்று",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "INR 337 மில்லியன்",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "விடுதலைப் புலிகள்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "பணமோசடி தடுப்பு",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ECR",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இரண்டு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "திருவண்ணாமலை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "குணசேகரன்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "பெரம குமார்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "குமார்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "சந்திரிகா பண்டாரநாயக்கா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "குமாரதுங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "அமலாக்க இயக்குநரகம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "FIR",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "சி.ஐ.டி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "காஞ்சிபுரம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "2020",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "குமார்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "வெளிநாட்டினர் சட்டம்",
            "label": "LAW"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாஸ்போர்ட் சட்டம்",
            "label": "LAW"
          },
          {
            "text": "NDPS சட்டம்",
            "label": "PRODUCT"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்திய தண்டனைச் சட்டம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "PAN",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆதார்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்தியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "குமார்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "முகமது ஷெரீப்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "மெதுரா கெடரா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "காமினி",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "2011",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "2011",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        []
      ]
    }
  }
}