{
  "newspaper_id": "daily-mirror-lk",
  "url": "https://www.dailymirror.lk/breaking_news/Pregnant-mother-daughter-die-and-4-injured-in-train-accident/108-241297",
  "time_ut": 1658135653,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Pregnant mother, daughter die and 4 injured in train accident",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Pregnant mother, daughter die and 4 injured in train accident",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "An expectant mother and her 10-year old daughter had died and four others were seriously injured when a motorcar hit a moving train at Magalla Gangarama road railway level crossing in Galle in the the Southern coastal line this morning.",
        "Six members of one family from Godakanda area were on board the ill-fated car, were heading to Galle to attend a wedding reception when they met with the tragedy.",
        "Police said the driver had attempted to drive through the railway crossing ignoring the colour light signals and the alarm siren when the Vavuniya bound Rajarata Ragina express train from Beliatta was approaching and subsequently slammed against the car. ( D.G.Sugathapala and Sirangika Lokukravita)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "4",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "10-year old",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "four",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Magalla Gangarama",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Galle",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Southern",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "this morning",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Six",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "one",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Godakanda",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Galle",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Vavuniya",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Beliatta",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sirangika Lokukravita",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "දුම්රිය අනතුරකින් ගැබිණි මව, දියණිය මිය ගොස් 4 දෙනෙකුට තුවාල",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "දකුණු මුහුදුබඩ මාර්ගයේ ගාල්ල මාගල්ල ගංගාරාම මාර්ගයේ දුම්රිය හරස් මාර්ගයේදී මෝටර් රථයක් ධාවනය වෙමින් තිබූ දුම්රියක ගැටීමෙන් ගැබිණි මවක් සහ ඇගේ 10 හැවිරිදි දියණිය අද උදෑසන මිය ගොස් තවත් සිව් දෙනෙකු බරපතල තුවාල ලබා තිබේ.",
        "ගොඩකන්ද ප්‍රදේශයේ එකම පවුලක සාමාජිකයින් 6 දෙනෙකු මෙම අවාසනාවන්ත මෝටර් රථයේ නැගී මංගල භෝජන සංග්‍රහයකට සහභාගී වීම සඳහා ගාල්ල බලා යමින් සිටියදී මෙම ඛේදවාචකයට මුහුණ පා ඇත.",
        "බෙලිඅත්තේ සිට වව්නියාව බලා ධාවනය වූ රජරට රගින ශීඝ්‍රගාමී දුම්රිය ආසන්නයේදී රියදුරු වර්ණ ආලෝක සංඥා සහ අනතුරු ඇඟවීමේ සයිරන් නාද නොතකා දුම්රිය හරස් මාර්ගය හරහා ධාවනය කිරීමට උත්සාහ කර ඇති අතර පසුව මෝටර් රථයේ ගැටී ඇති බව පොලීසිය සඳහන් කළේය. (ඩී.ජී.සුගතපාල සහ සිරංගිකා ලොකුක්‍රාවිට)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "4",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "අවුරුදු 10 යි",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "හතර",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "මාගල්ල ගංගාරාමය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගාල්ල",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "දකුණු",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "මේ උදෑසන",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "හය",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "එක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගොඩකන්ද",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගාල්ල",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "වවුනියාව",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "බෙලිඅත්ත",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "සිරංගිකා ලොකුක්‍රවිට",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "ரயில் விபத்தில் கர்ப்பிணி தாய், மகள் பலி, 4 பேர் படுகாயம்",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "இன்று காலை தெற்கு கரையோரப் பாதையில் காலி, மாகல்ல கங்காராம வீதி புகையிரத கடவையில் மோட்டார் கார் ஒன்று ஓடும் ரயிலில் மோதியதில் கர்ப்பிணித் தாய் மற்றும் அவரது 10 வயது மகளும் உயிரிழந்துள்ளதுடன் மேலும் நால்வர் படுகாயமடைந்துள்ளனர்.",
        "கொடகந்த பிரதேசத்தைச் சேர்ந்த ஒரே குடும்பத்தைச் சேர்ந்த 6 பேர், திருமண வரவேற்பு நிகழ்வில் கலந்துகொள்வதற்காக காலி நோக்கிச் சென்ற காரில் பயணித்த போதே இந்த அனர்த்தம் ஏற்பட்டுள்ளது.",
        "பெலியத்தவிலிருந்து வவுனியா நோக்கிச் சென்ற ரஜரட்ட ரகிண விரைவு ரயில் வரும்போது வண்ண ஒளி சமிக்ஞைகள் மற்றும் எச்சரிக்கை சைரனைப் பொருட்படுத்தாமல் புகையிரத கடவையின் ஊடாக சாரதி வாகனத்தை செலுத்த முற்பட்டதாக பொலிஸார் தெரிவித்தனர். (டி.ஜி.சுகதபால மற்றும் சீரங்கிகா லோகுக்ரவிதா)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "4",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "10 வயது",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "நான்கு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "மாகல்ல கங்காராம",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "காலி",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "தெற்கு",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று காலை",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஆறு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஒன்று",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "கொடகந்த",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "காலி",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "வவுனியா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "பெலியட்டா",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "சீரங்கிகா லோகுக்ரவிதா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}