{
  "newspaper_id": "economy-next-com",
  "url": "https://economynext.com/sri-lanka-state-run-rupavahini-itn-off-air-amid-protests-97337/",
  "time_ut": 1657701480,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Sri Lanka state run Rupavahini, ITN off air amid protests",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Sri Lanka state run Rupavahini, ITN off air amid protests",
      "author": "",
      "body_lines": [
        "ECONOMYNEXT – Sri Lanka’s state-run Rupavahini went off air for a time after two protestors were interviewed live on air and suspended programs, while Independent Television Network another state broadcaster is also displaying colour bars.",
        "The headquarters of the Sri Lanka Rupahavini Corporation (SLRC), the state-owned television network, was given heavy security from morning with authorities expecting protestors expected lay siege to the station.",
        "Two spokesmen who said they represented ‘Aragala Protestors’ said they have taken over the station on behalf of the people and exhorted on the workers to be independent.",
        "“We have not even aimed a stone at Rupavahini,” the representative said. “We only made a request",
        "to change the broadcast and  join the aragala and not to join any leader than comes but be independent.”",
        "“Now as aragala we took this over for the people we thank the staff for accepting us.",
        "Separately state-run Independent Television Network has also suspended normal programming as is displaying colour bars. (Colombo/Jul13/2022)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Sri Lanka",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "Rupavahini",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "ITN",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka’s",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Rupavahini",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "two",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Independent Television Network",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the Sri Lanka Rupahavini Corporation",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "morning",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Two",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Rupavahini",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "Independent Television Network",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Colombo/Jul13/2022",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "විරෝධතා මධ්‍යයේ ශ්‍රී ලංකා රාජ්‍ය රූපවාහිනිය, අයිටීඑන් විකාශනය අක්‍රියයි",
      "author": "",
      "body_lines": [
        "ECONOMYNEXT - විරෝධතාකරුවන් දෙදෙනෙකු ගුවන් මගින් සජීවීව සම්මුඛ සාකච්ඡා කර වැඩසටහන් අත්හිටුවීමෙන් පසු ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ රාජ්‍ය රූපවාහිනිය ටික වේලාවකට විකාශනය නොවීය, ස්වාධීන රූපවාහිනියේ තවත් රාජ්‍ය විකාශකයෙකු ද වර්ණ තීරු ප්‍රදර්ශනය කරයි.",
        "රජය සතු රූපවාහිනී ජාලය වන ශ්‍රී ලංකා රූපවාහිනි සංස්ථාවේ (SLRC) මූලස්ථානයට උදෑසන සිට දැඩි ආරක්ෂාවක් යොදවා තිබූ අතර විරෝධතාකරුවන් දුම්රිය ස්ථානය වටලනු ඇතැයි බලධාරීහු අපේක්ෂා කළහ.",
        "තමන් ‘අරගල විරෝධතාකරුවන්’ නියෝජනය කරන බව පැවසූ ප්‍රකාශකයින් දෙදෙනෙක් කියා සිටියේ තමන් ජනතාව වෙනුවෙන් දුම්රිය ස්ථානය පවරාගෙන කම්කරුවන්ට ස්වාධීන වන ලෙස උපදෙස් දුන් බවයි.",
        "“අපි රූපවාහිනියට ගලක්වත් එල්ල කළේ නැහැ,” නියෝජිතයා පැවසීය. “අපි කළේ ඉල්ලීමක් විතරයි",
        "විකාශනය වෙනස් කර අරගලට එක්වීමට සහ පැමිණෙනවාට වඩා කිසිදු නායකයෙකු සමඟ එකතු නොවී ස්වාධීන වන්න.",
        "“දැන් අරගල විදියට අපි මේක භාර ගත්තේ ජනතාව වෙනුවෙන් අපිව පිළිගත්තට කාර්ය මණ්ඩලයට ස්තුතිවන්ත වෙනවා.",
        "වෙනමම රජය විසින් පවත්වාගෙන යනු ලබන ස්වාධීන රූපවාහිනී ජාලය වර්ණ තීරු ප්‍රදර්ශනය කරන පරිදි සාමාන්‍ය වැඩසටහන් ද අත්හිටුවා ඇත. (කොළඹ/ජූලි13/2022)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "රූපවාහිනිය",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "ITN",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "රූපවාහිනිය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "දෙක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ස්වාධීන රූපවාහිනී ජාලය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකා රූපවාහිනි සංස්ථාව",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "උදෑසන",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "දෙක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "රූපවාහිනිය",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "ස්වාධීන රූපවාහිනී ජාලය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "කොළඹ/ජූලි13/2022",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "எதிர்ப்புகளுக்கு மத்தியில் இலங்கை அரசு நடத்தும் ரூபவாஹினி, ITN ஒளிபரப்பானது",
      "author": "",
      "body_lines": [
        "ECONOMYNEXT - இலங்கையின் அரசால் நடத்தப்படும் ரூபவாஹினி இரண்டு எதிர்ப்பாளர்களை நேரலையில் நேர்காணல் செய்து நிகழ்ச்சிகளை இடைநிறுத்தியதையடுத்து சிறிது நேரம் ஒளிபரப்பானது",
        "அரசுக்கு சொந்தமான தொலைக்காட்சி வலையமைப்பான இலங்கை ரூபஹாவினி கூட்டுத்தாபனத்தின் (SLRC) தலைமையகத்திற்கு காலை முதல் பலத்த பாதுகாப்பு வழங்கப்பட்டுள்ளது, எதிர்ப்பாளர்கள் நிலையத்தை முற்றுகையிடுவார்கள் என்று எதிர்பார்க்கப்படுகிறது.",
        "தாம் ‘அறகல எதிர்ப்பாளர்களை’ பிரதிநிதித்துவப்படுத்துவதாக தெரிவித்த இரண்டு பேச்சாளர்கள், மக்கள் சார்பாக நிலையத்தை கையகப்படுத்தியதாகவும், தொழிலாளர்கள் சுதந்திரமாக இருக்குமாறு அறிவுறுத்தியதாகவும் தெரிவித்தனர்.",
        "நாங்கள் ரூபவாஹினியை நோக்கி ஒரு கல்லைக் கூட குறிவைக்கவில்லை என பிரதிநிதி கூறினார். “நாங்கள் ஒரு கோரிக்கையை மட்டுமே வைத்தோம்",
        "ஒளிபரப்பை மாற்றி அரகலையில் சேரவும், வருவதை விட எந்தத் தலைவருடனும் சேராமல் சுதந்திரமாக இருங்கள்.",
        "\"இப்போது அரகலாவாக நாங்கள் இதை மக்களுக்காக எடுத்துக்கொள்கிறோம், எங்களை ஏற்றுக்கொண்ட ஊழியர்களுக்கு நாங்கள் நன்றி கூறுகிறோம்.",
        "தனித்தனியாக அரசு நடத்தும் சுயாதீன தொலைக்காட்சி வலையமைப்பும் வண்ணப் பட்டைகளைக் காட்டுவது போல் சாதாரண நிரலாக்கத்தையும் நிறுத்தி வைத்துள்ளது. (கொழும்பு/ஜூலை13/2022)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "இலங்கை",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "ரூபவாஹினி",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "ஐ.டி.என்",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கையின்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரூபவாஹினி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இரண்டு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "சுயாதீன தொலைக்காட்சி நெட்வொர்க்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை ரூபாஹாவினி கூட்டுத்தாபனம்",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "காலை",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இரண்டு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ரூபவாஹினி",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "சுயாதீன தொலைக்காட்சி நெட்வொர்க்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "கொழும்பு/ஜூலை13/2022",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}