{
  "newspaper_id": "economy-next-com",
  "url": "https://economynext.com/sri-lanka-crisis-would-deepen-if-creditors-disagree-imf-says-amid-china-concerns-99329/",
  "time_ut": 1662021000,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Sri Lanka crisis would deepen if creditors disagree, IMF says amid China concerns",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Sri Lanka crisis would deepen if creditors disagree, IMF says amid China concerns",
      "author": "",
      "body_lines": [
        "ECONOMYNEXT – Sri Lanka’s ongoing economic crisis would deepen if one creditors disagrees, a senior International Monetary Fund (IMF) official said after announcing a US$2.9 billion reform package amid concerns that China would not go along with Western creditors on debt restructuring on an equal footing.",
        "All Sri Lankan creditors including China have to agree to restructure their existing lending to the island nation before the IMF starts the loan disbursement. Delay in debt restructuring would drag the IMF loan disbursement, Sri Lankan officials who are familiar with the IMF discussions have told the EconomyNext.",
        "China has so far not agreed for debt restructuring which also includes a haircut or writing off some debts. Instead, China has expressed its willingness to refinance Sri Lanka to repay its past loans without any changes, Sri Lankan officials say.",
        "“If one creditor or creditors are not willing to provide these assurances, that would indeed deepen the crisis here in Sri Lanka and would undermine the repayment capacity,” Peter Breuer, senior IMF mission chief told reporters in Colombo when asked what if China does not agree on a debt restructuring plan.",
        "“So a deepening crisis means that essentially the resources available to service the debt would become less,” he said at the media briefing after concluding a nine-day visit to finalize the staff-level agreement and possible loan package for Sri Lanka’s reforms.",
        "“So it is actually in the interest of all creditors to collaborate together and with Sri Lanka so that Sri Lanka can emerge from this crisis as quickly as possible and regain its repayment capacity and service this new debt that will come out of these debt negotiations.”",
        "Sri Lanka has already hired leading financial and legal advisory firms Lazard and Clifford Chance LLP to support its debt restructuring as the country is on the brink of bankruptcy. Lazard has been the legal advisor in Zambia’s debt restructuring with the South African nation’s creditor’s including China.",
        "Unlike with members in Paris Club, the IMF is unable to deal with China as it is not in the Paris Club, which formed by a group of creditors who provide debt treatments to debtor countries in the form of rescheduling, by postponement or, in the case of concessional rescheduling, reduction in debt service obligations during a defined period.",
        "“Sri Lanka is in a special situation that much of its official debt is outside of Paris Club creditors,” Breuer said.",
        "“In the case of Sri Lanka, it owed to creditors that are not owed to Paris Club. It is important to move expeditiously. We want to avoid the crisis from becoming worse.” (Colombo/Sept01/2022)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Sri Lanka",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "IMF",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "China",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka’s",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "one",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "International Monetary Fund",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "US$2.9 billion",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "China",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lankan",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "China",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "IMF",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "IMF",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lankan",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "EconomyNext",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "China",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "China",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lankan",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "one",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Peter Breuer",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Colombo",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "China",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "nine-day",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka’s",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Lazard",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Clifford Chance LLP",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Lazard",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Zambia",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "South African",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "China",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Paris Club",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "China",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Paris Club",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "Paris Club",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Paris Club",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "ණයහිමියන් එකඟ නොවන්නේ නම් ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ අර්බුදය ගැඹුරු වනු ඇතැයි චීනයේ උත්සුකයන් මධ්‍යයේ IMF පවසයි",
      "author": "",
      "body_lines": [
        "ECONOMYNEXT - එක් ණයහිමියෙකු එකඟ නොවන්නේ නම් ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ පවතින ආර්ථික අර්බුදය ගැඹුරු වනු ඇති බව ජාත්‍යන්තර මූල්‍ය අරමුදලේ (IMF) ජ්‍යෙෂ්ඨ නිලධාරියෙක් එක්සත් ජනපද ඩොලර් බිලියන 2.9 ක ප්‍රතිසංස්කරණ පැකේජයක් ප්‍රකාශයට පත් කිරීමෙන් පසු ප්‍රකාශ කළේ චීනය සමාන පදනමක් මත ණය ප්‍රතිව්‍යුහගත කිරීම සම්බන්ධයෙන් බටහිර ණය හිමියන් සමඟ නොයනු ඇතැයි යන කනස්සල්ල මධ්‍යයේ ය. .",
        "ජාත්‍යන්තර මූල්‍ය අරමුදල විසින් ණය ලබා දීම ආරම්භ කිරීමට පෙර, චීනය ඇතුළු සියලුම ශ්‍රී ලංකා ණයහිමියන් දිවයිනේ ජාතියට දැනට ලබා දී ඇති ණය ප්‍රතිව්‍යුහගත කිරීමට එකඟ විය යුතුය. ණය ප්‍රතිව්‍යුහගත කිරීම ප්‍රමාද වීම ජාත්‍යන්තර මූල්‍ය අරමුදලේ ණය ලබා දීම ඇදගෙන යනු ඇති බව ජාත්‍යන්තර මූල්‍ය අරමුදලේ සාකච්ඡා ගැන දන්නා ශ්‍රී ලංකා නිලධාරීන් EconomyNext වෙත පවසා ඇත.",
        "කොණ්ඩය කැපීම හෝ සමහර ණය කපා හැරීම ද ඇතුළත් ණය ප්‍රතිව්‍යුහගත කිරීම සඳහා චීනය මෙතෙක් එකඟ වී නැත. ඒ වෙනුවට චීනය ශ්‍රී ලංකාවට ලබාදුන් අතීත ණය කිසිදු වෙනසක් නොමැතිව ආපසු ගෙවීමට ප්‍රතිමූල්‍යකරණය කිරීමට කැමැත්ත පළ කර ඇතැයි ශ්‍රී ලංකා බලධාරීහු පවසති.",
        "\"එක් ණයහිමියෙකු හෝ ණයහිමියන් මෙම සහතික ලබා දීමට අකමැති නම්, එය සැබවින්ම ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ අර්බුදය ගැඹුරු කරන අතර ආපසු ගෙවීමේ හැකියාව අඩපණ කරනු ඇත\" යනුවෙන් ජාමූඅ ජ්‍යෙෂ්ඨ දූත මණ්ඩල ප්‍රධානී පීටර් බෲවර් කොළඹදී මාධ්‍යවේදීන් අමතා ප්‍රශ්න කළ විට චීනය එසේ නොකරන්නේ නම් ණය ප්රතිව්යුහගත කිරීමේ සැලැස්මකට එකඟ වේ.",
        "“එබැවින් ගැඹුරු වන අර්බුදයක් යනු අත්‍යවශ්‍යයෙන්ම ණය ගෙවීම සඳහා පවතින සම්පත් අඩු වනු ඇත,” ඔහු ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ ප්‍රතිසංස්කරණ සඳහා කාර්ය මණ්ඩල මට්ටමේ ගිවිසුම සහ හැකි ණය පැකේජය අවසන් කිරීම සඳහා දින නවයක සංචාරයක් අවසන් කිරීමෙන් පසු මාධ්‍ය හමුවේදී පැවසීය.",
        "“එබැවින් ශ්‍රී ලංකාවට හැකි ඉක්මනින් මෙම අර්බුදයෙන් මිදීමටත්, ආපසු ගෙවීමේ හැකියාව නැවත ලබා ගැනීමටත්, මෙම ණය සාකච්ඡාවලින් එළියට එන මෙම නව ණයට සේවය කිරීමටත් හැකි වන පරිදි එක්ව සහ ශ්‍රී ලංකාව සමඟ සහයෝගයෙන් කටයුතු කිරීම ඇත්ත වශයෙන්ම සියලුම ණය හිමියන්ගේ අවශ්‍යතාවයයි. ”",
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකාව බංකොලොත් භාවයේ අද්දර සිටින බැවින් සිය ණය ප්‍රතිව්‍යුහගත කිරීමට සහාය වීම සඳහා ශ්‍රී ලංකාව දැනටමත් ප්‍රමුඛ පෙළේ මූල්‍ය සහ නීති උපදේශක සමාගම් වන Lazard සහ Clifford Chance LLP බඳවා ගෙන ඇත. ලාසාර්ඩ් චීනය ඇතුළු දකුණු අප්‍රිකානු ජාතියේ ණයහිමියන් සමඟ සැම්බියාවේ ණය ප්‍රතිව්‍යුහගත කිරීමේ නීති උපදේශකයා වී ඇත.",
        "පැරිස් සමාජයේ සාමාජිකයන් මෙන් නොව, IMF ට චීනය සමඟ ගනුදෙනු කිරීමට නොහැකි වන්නේ එය පැරිස් සමාජයේ නොමැති නිසා, ණයගැති රටවලට ණයගැති රටවලට ණය ප්‍රතිකාර නැවත කාලසටහන් කිරීම, කල් දැමීම හෝ, සහනදායී නැවත කාලසටහන් කිරීම, නිශ්චිත කාල සීමාවක් තුළ ණය සේවා වගකීම් අඩු කිරීම.",
        "\"ශ්‍රී ලංකාව විශේෂ තත්වයක සිටින අතර එහි නිල නය බොහෝමයක් පැරිස් ක්ලබ් ණය හිමියන්ට පිටතින් පවතී,\" Breuer පැවසීය.",
        "“ශ්‍රී ලංකාව සම්බන්ධයෙන් ගත් කල, එය පැරිස් සමාජයට ණය නැති ණය හිමියන්ට ණයගැතියි. වේගයෙන් ගමන් කිරීම වැදගත් වේ. අර්බුදය නරක අතට හැරීම වළක්වා ගැනීමට අපට අවශ්‍යයි. ” (කොළඹ/සැප්තැම්බර්01/2022)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "IMF",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "චීනය",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "එක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජාත්යන්තර මූල්ය අරමුදල",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඇමෙරිකානු ඩොලර් බිලියන 2.9 කි",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "චීනය",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලාංකික",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "චීනය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "IMF",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "IMF",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලාංකික",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "EconomyNext",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "චීනය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "චීනය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලාංකික",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "එක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "පීටර් බෲවර්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "කොළඹ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "චීනය",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "දින නවය",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Lazard",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ක්ලිෆර්ඩ් චාන්ස් එල්එල්පී",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Lazard",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "සැම්බියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "දකුණු අප්රිකානු",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "චීනය",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "පැරිස් සමාජය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "චීනය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "පැරිස් සමාජය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "පැරිස් සමාජය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "පැරිස් සමාජය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "கடனாளிகள் உடன்படாவிட்டால் இலங்கை நெருக்கடி ஆழமடையும் என சீனாவின் கவலைகளுக்கு மத்தியில் சர்வதேச நாணய நிதியம் தெரிவித்துள்ளது",
      "author": "",
      "body_lines": [
        "ECONOMYNEXT – கடனளிப்பவர்களில் ஒருவர் உடன்படவில்லை என்றால் இலங்கையின் தற்போதைய பொருளாதார நெருக்கடி ஆழமடையும் என்று ஒரு மூத்த சர்வதேச நாணய நிதியத்தின் (IMF) அதிகாரி ஒருவர் 2.9 பில்லியன் அமெரிக்க டாலர் சீர்திருத்தப் பொதியை அறிவித்த பின்னர், மேற்கத்திய கடனாளிகளுடன் சமமான நிலையில் கடன் மறுசீரமைப்புக்கு சீனா செல்லாது என்ற கவலைகளுக்கு மத்தியில் தெரிவித்தார். .",
        "சர்வதேச நாணய நிதியம் கடனை வழங்கத் தொடங்குவதற்கு முன்னர், சீனா உட்பட அனைத்து இலங்கைக் கடன் வழங்குநர்களும் தீவு நாட்டிற்கு தற்போதுள்ள கடனை மறுசீரமைக்க ஒப்புக் கொள்ள வேண்டும். கடன் மறுசீரமைப்பில் தாமதம் IMF கடன் வழங்கலை இழுத்துச் செல்லும் என்று IMF விவாதங்களை நன்கு அறிந்த இலங்கை அதிகாரிகள் EconomyNext இடம் கூறியுள்ளனர்.",
        "சீனா இதுவரை கடன் மறுசீரமைப்புக்கு உடன்படவில்லை, அதில் முடி வெட்டுதல் அல்லது சில கடன்களை தள்ளுபடி செய்வதும் அடங்கும். அதற்குப் பதிலாக, இலங்கையின் கடந்த கால கடன்களை எந்தவித மாற்றமும் இன்றி திருப்பிச் செலுத்துவதற்கு மறுநிதியளிப்பதற்கு சீனா விருப்பம் தெரிவித்துள்ளதாக இலங்கை அதிகாரிகள் தெரிவித்துள்ளனர்.",
        "\"ஒரு கடனாளி அல்லது கடனாளி இந்த உத்தரவாதங்களை வழங்க தயாராக இல்லை என்றால், அது உண்மையில் இலங்கையில் நெருக்கடியை ஆழமாக்கும் மற்றும் திருப்பிச் செலுத்தும் திறனைக் குறைமதிப்பிற்கு உட்படுத்தும்\" என்று IMF பணியின் மூத்த தலைவர் பீட்டர் ப்ரூயர் கொழும்பில் செய்தியாளர்களிடம் கேட்டபோது, ​​சீனா அவ்வாறு செய்யவில்லை என்றால் என்ன என்று கூறினார். கடன் மறுசீரமைப்பு திட்டத்தை ஒப்புக்கொள்கிறேன்.",
        "\"எனவே ஆழமாகிவரும் நெருக்கடியானது, கடனைச் செலுத்துவதற்கான ஆதாரங்கள் குறைவாகவே இருக்கும்,\" என்று இலங்கையின் சீர்திருத்தங்களுக்கான பணியாளர் மட்ட ஒப்பந்தம் மற்றும் சாத்தியமான கடன் பொதியை இறுதி செய்வதற்கான ஒன்பது நாள் விஜயத்தை முடித்த பின்னர் ஊடகவியலாளர் சந்திப்பில் அவர் கூறினார்.",
        "\"எனவே, அனைத்து கடன் வழங்குநர்களும் ஒன்றிணைந்து இலங்கையுடன் ஒத்துழைப்பது உண்மையில் ஆர்வமாக உள்ளது, இதன்மூலம் இலங்கை இந்த நெருக்கடியிலிருந்து விரைவாக மீள்வதற்கும் அதன் திருப்பிச் செலுத்தும் திறனை மீட்டெடுப்பதற்கும் இந்த கடன் பேச்சுவார்த்தைகளில் இருந்து வெளிவரும் இந்த புதிய கடனுக்கு சேவை செய்வதற்கும் ஆகும். ”",
        "நாடு திவால்நிலையின் விளிம்பில் இருப்பதால், கடன் மறுசீரமைப்பிற்கு ஆதரவளிக்க, இலங்கை ஏற்கனவே முன்னணி நிதி மற்றும் சட்ட ஆலோசனை நிறுவனங்களான Lazard மற்றும் Clifford Chance LLP ஐ பணியமர்த்தியுள்ளது. சீனா உட்பட தென்னாப்பிரிக்க நாட்டின் கடனாளிகளுடன் ஜாம்பியாவின் கடன் மறுசீரமைப்பில் லாசார்ட் சட்ட ஆலோசகராக இருந்துள்ளார்.",
        "பாரிஸ் கிளப்பில் உள்ள உறுப்பினர்களைப் போலல்லாமல், IMF ஆனது பாரிஸ் கிளப்பில் இல்லாததால், சீனாவை சமாளிக்க முடியவில்லை, இது கடனாளி நாடுகளுக்கு கடன் சிகிச்சைகளை மறு திட்டமிடல், ஒத்திவைத்தல் அல்லது, சலுகை மறு திட்டமிடல் வழக்கு, வரையறுக்கப்பட்ட காலத்தில் கடன் சேவை கடமைகளை குறைத்தல்.",
        "\"இலங்கை ஒரு சிறப்பு சூழ்நிலையில் உள்ளது, அதன் உத்தியோகபூர்வ கடனில் பெரும்பகுதி Paris Club கடனாளர்களுக்கு வெளியே உள்ளது,\" என்று ப்ரூயர் கூறினார்.",
        "“இலங்கையைப் பொறுத்தவரை, அது பாரிஸ் கிளப்பிற்குக் கொடுக்கப்படாத கடனாளிகளுக்குக் கடன்பட்டிருக்கிறது. விரைவாக நகர்த்துவது முக்கியம். நெருக்கடி மோசமடைவதைத் தவிர்க்க விரும்புகிறோம். (கொழும்பு/செப்டம்பர்01/2022)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "இலங்கை",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "IMF",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "சீனா",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கையின்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஒன்று",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "சர்வதேச நாணய நிதியம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "US$2.9 பில்லியன்",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "சீனா",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "சீனா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "IMF",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "IMF",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "EconomyNext",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "சீனா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சீனா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஒன்று",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "பீட்டர் ப்ரூயர்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "கொழும்பு",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "சீனா",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஒன்பது நாள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கையின்",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "லசார்ட்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "கிளிஃபோர்ட் சான்ஸ் LLP",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "லசார்ட்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜாம்பியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "தென்னாப்பிரிக்கா",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "சீனா",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பாரிஸ் கிளப்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "சீனா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாரிஸ் கிளப்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாரிஸ் கிளப்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாரிஸ் கிளப்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}