{
  "newspaper_id": "economy-next-com",
  "url": "https://economynext.com/three-shipments-of-fuel-to-arrive-in-sri-lanka-by-mid-end-july-august-lanka-ioc-96783/",
  "time_ut": 1656744600,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Three shipments of fuel to arrive in Sri Lanka by mid, end July, August: Lanka IOC",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Three shipments of fuel to arrive in Sri Lanka by mid, end July, August: Lanka IOC",
      "author": "Chanka Jayasinghe",
      "body_lines": [
        "ECONOMYNEXT – Two consignments of both petrol and diesel are expected to arrive in Sri Lanka by mid and end of July, with another consignment scheduled to arrive in August, Lanka Indian Oil Corporation (Lanka IOC) officials said.",
        "Lanka IOC Chairman Manoj Gupta told EconomyNext on Saturday July 02 that all three shipments will consist of both diesel and petrol with each vessel carrying 30,000 metric tons of fuel.",
        "Two consignments are expected to arrive on July 13 or 14 and on July 28-30 and another consignment is scheduled to arrive between August 10 and 15.",
        "Gupta said the ships will be arriving either from Singapore or Fujairah, UAE.",
        "The ongoing fuel crisis in the country due to lack of forex has worsened over time, forcing the state run Ceylon Petroleum Corporation (CPC) to shut down most filling stations due to the inability to supply fuel.",
        "Due to the high demand for fuel in the country, Lanka IOC, a local unit of the Indian Oil Corporation (IOC), also distributes fuel under restrictions of maximum value fuel that can be obtained.",
        "Accordingly, two-wheelers can get fuel value up to a maximum of 1,500 rupees, threewheelers up to 2,500 rupees and four-wheelers up to 7,000 rupees from Lanka IOC fuel stations. (Colombo/Jul02/2022)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Three",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "Sri Lanka",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "mid, end July, August",
          "label": "DATE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Two",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "mid and end of July",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "August",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Lanka Indian Oil Corporation",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "IOC",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Manoj Gupta",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Saturday July 02",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "three",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "30,000 metric tons",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Two",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "July 13",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "14",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "July 28-30",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "between August 10 and 15",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Gupta",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Singapore",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Fujairah",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "UAE",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Ceylon Petroleum Corporation",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "CPC",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Lanka IOC",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Indian Oil Corporation",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "IOC",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "two",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "1,500",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "up to",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "four",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "up to 7,000",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Colombo/Jul02/2022",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "ජූලි, අගෝස්තු මැද භාගය වන විට ඉන්ධන තොග තුනක් ශ්‍රී ලංකාවට පැමිණීමට නියමිතය: ලංකා IOC",
      "author": "චංක ජයසිංහ",
      "body_lines": [
        "ECONOMYNEXT - පෙට්‍රල් සහ ඩීසල් දෙකේම තොග දෙකක් ජූලි මස මැද සහ අග වන විට ශ්‍රී ලංකාවට පැමිණීමට අපේක්ෂා කරන අතර තවත් තොගයක් අගෝස්තු මාසයේදී පැමිණීමට නියමිත බව ලංකා ඉන්දියන් ඔයිල් කෝපරේෂන් (ලංකා IOC) නිලධාරීහු පවසති.",
        "ලංකා IOC සභාපති මනෝජ් ගුප්තා ජූලි 02 සෙනසුරාදා EconomyNext වෙත පැවසුවේ මෙම නැව්ගත කිරීම් තුනම ඩීසල් සහ පෙට්‍රල් යන දෙකින්ම සමන්විත වන අතර සෑම නෞකාවක්ම ඉන්ධන මෙට්‍රික් ටොන් 30,000ක් රැගෙන යන බවයි.",
        "ජූලි 13 හෝ 14 සහ ජූලි 28-30 යන දිනවල තොග දෙකක් පැමිණීමට අපේක්ෂා කරන අතර අගෝස්තු 10 සහ 15 අතර තවත් තොගයක් පැමිණීමට නියමිතය.",
        "ගුප්තා පැවසුවේ මෙම නැව් සිංගප්පූරුවෙන් හෝ එක්සත් අරාබි එමීර් රාජ්‍යයේ ෆුජයිරා සිට පැමිණෙන බවයි.",
        "විදේශ විනිමය නොමැතිකම හේතුවෙන් රට තුළ පවතින ඉන්ධන අර්බුදය කාලයාගේ ඇවෑමෙන් උග්‍ර වී ඇති අතර, ඉන්ධන සැපයීමට නොහැකි වීම හේතුවෙන් බොහෝ ඉන්ධන පිරවුම්හල් වසා දැමීමට රජය විසින් පාලනය කරන ලංකා ඛනිජ තෙල් නීතිගත සංස්ථාවට (CPC) සිදු විය.",
        "මෙරට ඉන්ධන සඳහා පවතින ඉහළ ඉල්ලුම හේතුවෙන් ඉන්දීය තෙල් සංස්ථාවේ (IOC) දේශීය ඒකකයක් වන ලංකා IOC ද ඉන්ධන ලබා ගත හැකි උපරිම වටිනාකමින් යුත් ඉන්ධන සීමා කිරීම් යටතේ ඉන්ධන බෙදා හැරීම සිදු කරයි.",
        "ඒ අනුව ලංකා IOC ඉන්ධන පිරවුම්හල්වලින් ත්‍රිරෝද රථ සඳහා රුපියල් 1500ක් දක්වාත්, ත්‍රිරෝද රථ සඳහා රුපියල් 2500ක් දක්වාත්, රෝද හතරේ වාහන සඳහා රුපියල් 7000ක් දක්වාත් ඉන්ධන වටිනාකමක් ලබාගත හැකියි. (කොළඹ/ජූලි 02/2022)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "තුන්",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "මැද, ජූලි, අගෝස්තු අවසානය",
          "label": "DATE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "දෙක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජූලි මැද සහ අවසානයේ",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "අගෝස්තු",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ලංකා ඉන්දියන් ඔයිල් කෝපරේෂන්",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "අයි.ඕ.සී",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "මනෝජ් ගුප්තා",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජූලි 02 සෙනසුරාදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "තුන්",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "මෙට්‍රික් ටොන් 30,000 කි",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "දෙක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජූලි 13",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "14",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජූලි 28-30",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "අගෝස්තු 10 සහ 15 අතර",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ගුප්ත",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "සිංගප්පූරුව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ෆුජයිරා",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "UAE",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ලංකා ඛනිජ තෙල් නීතිගත සංස්ථාව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "CPC",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ලංකා IOC",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දියානු තෙල් සංස්ථාව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "අයි.ඕ.සී",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "දෙක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "1,500 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "දක්වා",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "හතර",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "7,000 දක්වා",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ලංකා",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "කොළඹ/ජූලි 02/2022",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "ஜூலை, ஆகஸ்ட் நடுப்பகுதிக்குள் மூன்று எரிபொருள் ஏற்றுமதி இலங்கைக்கு வரும்: லங்கா ஐ.ஓ.சி",
      "author": "சங்க ஜெயசிங்க",
      "body_lines": [
        "ECONOMYNEXT - பெட்ரோல் மற்றும் டீசல் இரண்டின் இரண்டு சரக்குகள் ஜூலை நடுப்பகுதி மற்றும் இறுதிக்குள் இலங்கைக்கு வரும் என எதிர்பார்க்கப்படுகிறது, மற்றொரு சரக்கு ஆகஸ்ட் மாதம் வரவுள்ளதாக லங்கா இந்தியன் ஆயில் கார்ப்பரேஷன் (லங்கா ஐஓசி) அதிகாரிகள் தெரிவித்தனர்.",
        "லங்கா IOC தலைவர் மனோஜ் குப்தா EconomyNext க்கு சனிக்கிழமை ஜூலை 02 அன்று தெரிவித்தார், மூன்று ஏற்றுமதிகளும் டீசல் மற்றும் பெற்றோல் இரண்டையும் கொண்டிருக்கும் ஒவ்வொரு கப்பலும் 30,000 மெட்ரிக் தொன் எரிபொருளைக் கொண்டு செல்லும்.",
        "ஜூலை 13 அல்லது 14 மற்றும் ஜூலை 28-30 ஆகிய தேதிகளில் இரண்டு சரக்குகள் வரும் என்று எதிர்பார்க்கப்படுகிறது மற்றும் ஆகஸ்ட் 10 மற்றும் 15 க்கு இடையில் மற்றொரு சரக்கு வர திட்டமிடப்பட்டுள்ளது.",
        "கப்பல்கள் சிங்கப்பூர் அல்லது ஐக்கிய அரபு எமிரேட்ஸின் புஜைராவிலிருந்து வரும் என்று குப்தா கூறினார்.",
        "அந்நிய செலாவணி பற்றாக்குறையால் நாட்டில் நிலவும் எரிபொருள் நெருக்கடி காலப்போக்கில் மோசமாகி, எரிபொருள் விநியோகம் செய்ய இயலாமையால் பெரும்பாலான எரிபொருள் நிரப்பு நிலையங்களை அரசு நடத்தும் இலங்கை பெற்றோலியக் கூட்டுத்தாபனம் (CPC) மூட வேண்டியதாயிற்று.",
        "நாட்டில் எரிபொருளுக்கான அதிக தேவை காரணமாக, இந்தியன் ஆயில் கார்ப்பரேஷனின் (IOC) உள்ளூர் பிரிவான லங்கா ஐஓசி, பெறக்கூடிய அதிகபட்ச மதிப்பு எரிபொருளின் கட்டுப்பாடுகளின் கீழ் எரிபொருளை விநியோகிக்கிறது.",
        "இதன்படி, லங்கா ஐஓசி எரிபொருள் நிரப்பு நிலையங்களில் இரு சக்கர வாகனங்கள் அதிகபட்சமாக 1,500 ரூபா வரையிலும், முச்சக்கர வண்டிகள் 2,500 ரூபா வரையிலும், நான்கு சக்கர வாகனங்கள் 7,000 ரூபா வரையிலும் எரிபொருள் பெறுமதியைப் பெற முடியும். (கொழும்பு/ஜூலை02/2022)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "மூன்று",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "இலங்கை",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "நடுப்பகுதி, ஜூலை இறுதி, ஆகஸ்ட்",
          "label": "DATE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "இரண்டு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜூலை நடுப்பகுதி மற்றும் இறுதியில்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆகஸ்ட்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "லங்கா இந்தியன் ஆயில் கார்ப்பரேஷன்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஐஓசி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "மனோஜ் குப்தா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜூலை 02 சனிக்கிழமை",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "மூன்று",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "30,000 மெட்ரிக் டன்",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இரண்டு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜூலை 13",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "14",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜூலை 28-30",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆகஸ்ட் 10 மற்றும் 15 க்கு இடையில்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "குப்தா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "சிங்கப்பூர்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "புஜைரா",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஐக்கிய அரபு எமிரேட்ஸ்",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை பெற்றோலியக் கூட்டுத்தாபனம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "CPC",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "லங்கா ஐ.ஓ.சி",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்தியன் ஆயில் கார்ப்பரேஷன்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஐஓசி",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இரண்டு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "1,500",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "அது வரை",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "நான்கு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "7,000 வரை",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "கொழும்பு/ஜூலை02/2022",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}