{
  "newspaper_id": "news-first-lk",
  "url": "https://www.newsfirst.lk/2022/08/23/sl-navy-seizes-poaching-trawler-in-sri-lanka%e2%80%99s-waters-off-mullaitivu/",
  "time_ut": 1661229660,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "SL Navy seizes poaching trawler in Sri Lanka’s waters off Mullaitivu",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "SL Navy seizes poaching trawler in Sri Lanka’s waters off Mullaitivu",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); Sri Lanka Navy on Monday (22) conducted a special operation to chase away Indian trawlers poaching in the island’s waters.",
        "The operation led to the seizure of an Indian trawler with 10 Indian fishermen while poaching in Sri Lanka’s waters off Mullaitivu, via the International Maritime Boundary Line (IMBL).",
        "The Navy continues to carry out regular patrols in the island’s waters to prevent illegal fishing practices by foreign fishermen, intending to protect the fishery resources of the country and the livelihood of local fishermen.",
        "Accordingly, the Navy deployed a Fast Attack Craft of the 4th Fast Attack Flotilla (4 FAF), attached to the Eastern Naval Command to chase away Indian trawlers poaching in Sri Lanka’s waters, via the IMBL on 22nd August.",
        "In this operation, the Navy seized an Indian poaching trawler remaining off Mullaitivu, with 10 Indian fishermen and their fishing gear.",
        "The Indian trawler and 10 Indian fishermen held by the Navy are being brought to the Trincomalee harbour as of now and they will be handed over to the Fisheries Inspector of Trincomalee for onward legal action.",
        "Meanwhile, the Sri Lanka Navy continues to carry out regular operations to protect the country’s fishery resources and the livelihood of the local fishing community.",
        "SL Navy seizes poaching trawler in Sri Lanka’s waters off Mullaitivu",
        "Sri Lanka Govt must permit the safe return of Gotabaya & Family – HRCSL"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Navy",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "Sri Lanka’s",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "Mullaitivu",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "News 1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka Navy",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Monday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "22",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Indian",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Indian",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "10",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Indian",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka’s",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Mullaitivu",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the International Maritime Boundary Line",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "IMBL",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Navy",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Navy",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "4th",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Fast Attack Flotilla",
            "label": "EVENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "FAF",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Eastern Naval Command",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Indian",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka’s",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "IMBL",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "22nd August",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Navy",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Indian",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Mullaitivu",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "10",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Indian",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Indian",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "10",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Indian",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Navy",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Trincomalee",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Fisheries Inspector",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Trincomalee",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the Sri Lanka Navy",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Navy",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka’s",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Mullaitivu",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Gotabaya & Family",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "ශ්‍රී ලංකා නාවික හමුදාව විසින් මුලතිව් මුහුදු තීරයේදී දඩයම් කළ ට්‍රෝලර් යාත්‍රාවක් අත්අඩංගුවට ගෙන ඇත",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); ශ්‍රී ලංකා නාවික හමුදාව විසින් සඳුදා (22) දිවයිනේ මුහුදු සීමාවේ දඩයම් කරන ඉන්දීය ට්‍රෝලර් යාත්‍රා පලවා හැරීම සඳහා විශේෂ මෙහෙයුමක් ක්‍රියාත්මක කරන ලදී.",
        "ජාත්‍යන්තර සමුද්‍ර සීමා රේඛාව (IMBL) හරහා මුලතිව් ඔබ්බෙන් වූ ශ්‍රී ලංකා මුහුදු තීරයේ දඩයම් කරමින් සිටියදී ඉන්දීය ධීවරයින් 10 දෙනෙකු සමඟ ඉන්දීය ට්‍රෝලර් යාත්‍රාවක් අත්අඩංගුවට ගැනීමට මෙම මෙහෙයුම හේතු විය.",
        "මෙරට ධීවර සම්පත සහ දේශීය ධීවරයින්ගේ ජීවනෝපාය ආරක්‍ෂා කිරීමේ අරමුණින් විදේශීය ධීවරයින් විසින් සිදුකරන නීතිවිරෝධී ධීවර කටයුතු වැළැක්වීම සඳහා නාවික හමුදාව දිවයිනේ මුහුදු සීමාවේ නිරන්තර මුර සංචාර අඛණ්ඩව සිදු කරයි.",
        "ඒ අනුව, නාවික හමුදාව විසින් ශ්‍රී ලංකා මුහුදු සීමාවේ දඩයම් කරන ඉන්දීය ට්‍රෝලර් යාත්‍රා පලවා හැරීම සඳහා නැගෙනහිර නාවික විධානයට අනුයුක්ත 4 වන වේග ප්‍රහාරක ෆ්ලෝටිලා (4 FAF) හි වේග ප්‍රහාරක යාත්‍රාවක් IMBL හරහා අගෝස්තු 22 වන දින යෙදවිය.",
        "මෙම මෙහෙයුමේදී ඉන්දීය ධීවරයින් 10 දෙනෙකු සහ ඔවුන්ගේ ධීවර ආම්පන්න සමඟ මුලතිව් ඔබ්බෙන් ඉතිරිව තිබූ ඉන්දීය දඩයම් ට්‍රෝලර් යාත්‍රාවක් නාවික හමුදාව භාරයට ගෙන ඇත.",
        "නාවික හමුදාව භාරයේ සිටින ඉන්දීය ට්‍රෝලර් යාත්‍රාව සහ ඉන්දීය ධීවරයින් 10 දෙනෙකු මේ වන විට ත්‍රිකුණාමලය වරායට රැගෙන ඒමට නියමිත අතර ඉදිරි නීතිමය කටයුතු සඳහා ඔවුන් ත්‍රිකුණාමලය ධීවර පරීක්ෂක වෙත භාරදීමට නියමිතයි.",
        "මේ අතර, ශ්‍රී ලංකා නාවික හමුදාව රටේ ධීවර සම්පත සහ දේශීය ධීවර ප්‍රජාවගේ ජීවනෝපාය ආරක්ෂා කිරීම සඳහා නිරන්තර මෙහෙයුම් අඛණ්ඩව සිදු කරයි.",
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකා නාවික හමුදාව විසින් මුලතිව් මුහුදු තීරයේදී දඩයම් කළ ට්‍රෝලර් යාත්‍රාවක් අත්අඩංගුවට ගෙන ඇත",
        "ගෝඨාභය සහ පවුලේ අය ආරක්ෂිතව නැවත පැමිණීමට ශ්‍රී ලංකා රජය අවසර දිය යුතුය - HRCSL"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "නාවික",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "මුලතිව්",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "News 1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකා නාවික හමුදාව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "සඳුදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "22",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දීය",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දීය",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "10",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දීය",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මුලතිව්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජාත්‍යන්තර සමුද්‍ර මායිම් රේඛාව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "IMBL",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "නාවික",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "නාවික",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "4 වැනි",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "වේගවත් ප්‍රහාර ෆ්ලෝටිලා",
            "label": "EVENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "FAF",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "නැගෙනහිර නාවික විධානය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දීය",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "IMBL",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "අගෝස්තු 22",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "නාවික",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දීය",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "මුලතිව්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "10",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දීය",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දීය",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "10",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දීය",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "නාවික",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ත්රිකුණාමලය",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ධීවර පරීක්ෂක",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ත්රිකුණාමලය",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකා නාවික හමුදාව",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "නාවික",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මුලතිව්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ගෝඨාභය සහ පවුල",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "இலங்கை கடற்படையினர் முல்லைத்தீவு கடற்பரப்பில் வேட்டையாடிய இழுவை படகை கைப்பற்றியுள்ளனர்",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); இலங்கை கடற்பரப்பில் வேட்டையாடும் இந்திய இழுவை படகுகளை விரட்டுவதற்கான விசேட நடவடிக்கையை இலங்கை கடற்படையினர் திங்கட்கிழமை (22) மேற்கொண்டுள்ளனர்.",
        "இந்த நடவடிக்கையானது சர்வதேச கடல் எல்லைக் கோடு (IMBL) வழியாக முல்லைத்தீவுக்கு அப்பால் இலங்கையின் கடற்பரப்பில் வேட்டையாடும்போது 10 இந்திய மீனவர்களுடன் இந்திய இழுவை படகு கைப்பற்றப்பட்டது.",
        "வெளிநாட்டு மீனவர்களின் சட்டவிரோத மீன்பிடி நடைமுறைகளைத் தடுக்கவும், நாட்டின் மீன்வளத்தையும் உள்நாட்டு மீனவர்களின் வாழ்வாதாரத்தையும் பாதுகாக்கும் நோக்கில் கடற்படையினர் தீவுக் கடற்பரப்பில் தொடர்ந்து ரோந்துப் பணிகளை மேற்கொண்டு வருகின்றனர்.",
        "அதன்படி, இலங்கை கடற்பரப்பில் வேட்டையாடும் இந்திய இழுவை படகுகளை விரட்டுவதற்காக கிழக்கு கடற்படை கட்டளையுடன் இணைக்கப்பட்ட 4வது ஃபாஸ்ட் அட்டாக் ஃப்ளோட்டிலாவின் (4 FAF) ஃபாஸ்ட் அட்டாக் கிராஃப்டை கடற்படை ஆகஸ்ட் 22 அன்று IMBL வழியாக அனுப்பியது.",
        "இந்த நடவடிக்கையில், முல்லைத்தீவில் எஞ்சியிருந்த 10 இந்திய மீனவர்கள் மற்றும் அவர்களது மீன்பிடி உபகரணங்களுடன் எஞ்சியிருந்த இந்திய வேட்டையாடும் இழுவை படகு ஒன்றை கடற்படையினர் கைப்பற்றியுள்ளனர்.",
        "கடற்படையினரால் கைது செய்யப்பட்ட இந்திய இழுவை படகு மற்றும் 10 இந்திய மீனவர்கள் தற்போது திருகோணமலை துறைமுகத்திற்கு கொண்டு வரப்பட்டு, அவர்கள் திருகோணமலை கடற்றொழில் பரிசோதகரிடம் மேலதிக சட்ட நடவடிக்கைகளுக்காக ஒப்படைக்கப்படவுள்ளனர்.",
        "இதற்கிடையில், இலங்கை கடற்படையினர் நாட்டின் மீன்பிடி வளங்களையும் உள்ளூர் மீனவ மக்களின் வாழ்வாதாரத்தையும் பாதுகாப்பதற்கான வழக்கமான நடவடிக்கைகளை தொடர்ந்து மேற்கொண்டு வருகின்றனர்.",
        "இலங்கை கடற்படையினர் முல்லைத்தீவு கடற்பரப்பில் வேட்டையாடிய இழுவை படகை கைப்பற்றியுள்ளனர்",
        "கோட்டாபய மற்றும் குடும்பத்தினர் பாதுகாப்பாக திரும்புவதற்கு இலங்கை அரசாங்கம் அனுமதிக்க வேண்டும் - HRCSL"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "கடற்படை",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "இலங்கையின்",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "முல்லைத்தீவு",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "News 1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை கடற்படை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "திங்கட்கிழமை",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "22",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்தியன்",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இந்தியன்",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "10",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்தியன்",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கையின்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "முல்லைத்தீவு",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "சர்வதேச கடல் எல்லைக் கோடு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "IMBL",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "கடற்படை",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "கடற்படை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "4வது",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஃபாஸ்ட் அட்டாக் ஃப்ளோட்டிலா",
            "label": "EVENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "FAF",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "கிழக்கு கடற்படை கட்டளை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்தியன்",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கையின்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "IMBL",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆகஸ்ட் 22",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "கடற்படை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்தியன்",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "முல்லைத்தீவு",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "10",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்தியன்",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இந்தியன்",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "10",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்தியன்",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "கடற்படை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "திருகோணமலை",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "மீன்வள ஆய்வாளர்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "திருகோணமலை",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை கடற்படை",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "கடற்படை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கையின்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "முல்லைத்தீவு",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "கோட்டாபய & குடும்பம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}