{
  "newspaper_id": "daily-mirror-lk",
  "url": "https://www.dailymirror.lk/latest_news/Parliament-has-constitutional-obligation-to-elect-Prez-capable-of-repairing-collapsed-economy-Church-of-Ceylon/342-241298",
  "time_ut": 1658135945,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Parliament has constitutional obligation to elect Prez, capable of repairing collapsed economy: Church of Ceylon",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Parliament has constitutional obligation to elect Prez, capable of repairing collapsed economy: Church of Ceylon",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "Parliament has the constitutional obligation to elect a President who will commence the challenging task of restoring constitutionalism and accountability, repairing the collapsed economy and restoring a semblance of normalcy in the lives of the citizens of the country, the Church of Ceylon said.",
        "They said in a statement that the People’s Movement/Aragalaya has achieved its primary objective, after a long period of struggle-the resignation of Gotabaya Rajapakse as the President of Sri Lanka. \"We welcome this significant milestone in the campaign for democracy, accountability and justice,\" the statement said.",
        "\"This was achieved despite setbacks and the cynical political maneuvering of President Rajapakse when he appointed Ranil Wickremesinghe as his Prime Minister.",
        "The next phase of the struggle is extremely important if the campaign for democracy, accountability and justice is to continue. Parliament has to elect a person from among its members to serve the remainder of the presidential term,\" the statement added.",
        "\"The present Parliament, also discredited in the eyes of the People for its inability to check the corruption and mismanagement of the executive and ensure public accountability, has the constitutional obligation to elect a President who will commence the challenging task of restoring constitutionalism and accountability, repairing the collapsed economy and restoring a semblance of normalcy in the lives of the citizens of the country.",
        "Will Parliament be able to redeem itself, at least somewhat, next week? Will Parliament heed the voices of the People clearly articulated through the Aragalaya and the numerous statements made in recent weeks by civil society? A rejection of politics as usual; a demand for radical political change where partisan politics that places individual and party interests above the national interest is repudiated; a new beginning, even in an old discredited Parliament, that promises further change ahead. The signs of the past couple of days has been disappointing with each party and its leaders demonstrating deafness to the voices of the People and making claims for the presidency based on the old discredited politics as usual,",
        "Sri Lanka needs an inclusive, interim government with a respected and unifying person as the new President so that genuine constitutional reform and the challenging task of restoring the economy can begin forthwith,",
        "We call upon every Member of Parliament to remember that she/he is primarily a representative of the People, rather than a party or a party leader, and in electing a new President and Government next week, is performing a special constitutional function in extraordinary circumstances. Those who have in the past few months led the struggle for change, the people of Sri Lanka and the international community will watch to see whether members of the Parliament of Sri Lanka have the capacity, courage and wisdom to perform this extraordinary responsibility. The future of constitutionalism, democracy and the Sri Lankan economy could very well depend on it,\" the statement further added."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Parliament",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "Church of Ceylon",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Church of Ceylon",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the People’s Movement/Aragalaya",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Gotabaya Rajapakse",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Rajapakse",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "next week",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "recent weeks",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the past couple of days",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Government",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "next week",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the past few months",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Parliament of Sri Lanka",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lankan",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "කඩා වැටුණු ආර්ථිකය යථා තත්ත්වයට පත් කළ හැකි ජනාධිපතිවරයා තෝරා ගැනීමට පාර්ලිමේන්තුවට ව්‍යවස්ථාපිත වගකීමක් ඇත: ලංකා පල්ලිය",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "ව්‍යවස්ථානුකූලභාවය සහ වගවීම ප්‍රතිෂ්ඨාපනය කිරීම, කඩා වැටුණු ආර්ථිකය යථා තත්ත්වයට පත් කිරීම සහ රටේ පුරවැසියන්ගේ ජන ජීවිතය සාමාන්‍ය තත්ත්වයට පත් කිරීම යන අභියෝගාත්මක කාර්යය ආරම්භ කරන ජනාධිපතිවරයකු තෝරා පත් කර ගැනීමට පාර්ලිමේන්තුවට ව්‍යවස්ථාපිත වගකීමක් ඇති බව ලංකා පල්ලිය පවසයි.",
        "මහජන ව්‍යාපාරය/අරගලය දීර්ඝ කාලීන අරගලයකින් පසු ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ ජනාධිපති ධූරයෙන් ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ ඉල්ලා අස්වීම එහි මූලික අරමුණ ඉටුකරගෙන ඇති බව ඔවුන් නිවේදනයක් නිකුත් කරමින් කියා සිටියේය. \"ප්‍රජාතන්ත්‍රවාදය, වගවීම සහ යුක්තිය සඳහා වන ව්‍යාපාරයේ මෙම වැදගත් සන්ධිස්ථානය අපි සාදරයෙන් පිළිගනිමු\" යනුවෙන් එම නිවේදනයේ සඳහන් වේ.",
        "“මෙය සාක්ෂාත් කරගනු ලැබුවේ රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ අගමැති ලෙස පත්කිරීමේදී ජනාධිපති රාජපක්ෂගේ නරුම දේශපාලන උපාමාරු සහ පසුබෑම් මධ්‍යයේ ය.",
        "ප‍්‍රජාතන්ත‍්‍රවාදය, වගවීම සහ යුක්තිය සඳහා වන ව්‍යාපාරය ඉදිරියට ගෙන යාමට නම් අරගලයේ මීළඟ අදියර අතිශයින් වැදගත් වේ. ජනාධිපතිවරයාගේ ධූර කාලයේ ඉතිරි කාලය සඳහා පාර්ලිමේන්තුවට සිය මන්ත්‍රීවරුන් අතරින් පුද්ගලයකු තෝරා පත් කර ගත යුතු බව එම නිවේදනයේ වැඩිදුරටත් සඳහන් වේ.",
        "\"විධායකයේ දූෂණ හා අවපාලනය පාලනය කිරීමට සහ මහජන වගවීම සහතික කිරීමට නොහැකි වීම නිසා ජනතාව ඉදිරියේ අපකීර්තියට පත් වත්මන් පාර්ලිමේන්තුවට, ව්‍යවස්ථානුකූලභාවය සහ වගවීම ප්‍රතිෂ්ඨාපනය කිරීමේ අභියෝගාත්මක කර්තව්‍යය ආරම්භ කරන ජනාධිපතිවරයෙකු තෝරා පත් කර ගැනීමේ ව්‍යවස්ථාපිත වගකීමක් ඇත. කඩා වැටුණු ආර්ථිකය යථා තත්ත්වයට පත් කිරීම සහ රටේ පුරවැසියන්ගේ ජීවිතවල සාමාන්‍ය ස්වරූපයක් ඇති කිරීම.",
        "ලබන සතියේදී පාර්ලිමේන්තුවට අවම වශයෙන් යම් ප්‍රමාණයකට හෝ මුදවා ගැනීමට හැකිවේද? අරගලය හරහා පැහැදිලිවම ප්‍රකාශ කරන ලද ජනතා හඬට සහ සිවිල් සමාජය විසින් පසුගිය සති කිහිපය තුළ කරන ලද ප්‍රකාශ ගණනාවකට පාර්ලිමේන්තුව අවනත වේද? සුපුරුදු පරිදි දේශපාලනය ප්‍රතික්ෂේප කිරීම; ජාතික අවශ්‍යතාවයට වඩා පුද්ගල සහ පක්ෂ අවශ්‍යතා ඉහළින් තබන පක්ෂග්‍රාහී දේශපාලනය ප්‍රතික්ෂේප කරන රැඩිකල් දේශපාලන වෙනසක් සඳහා වූ ඉල්ලීමක්; නව ආරම්භයක්, පැරණි අපකීර්තිමත් පාර්ලිමේන්තුවක වුවද, ඉදිරියේදී තවත් වෙනසක් පොරොන්දු වේ. සෑම පක්‍ෂයක්ම සහ එහි නායකයන් ජනතාවගේ හඬට බිහිරි බව පෙන්වමින් සුපුරුදු පරිදි පැරණි අපකීර්තිමත් දේශපාලනය මත පදනම්ව ජනාධිපතිකමට හිමිකම් කීම පසුගිය දින දෙකේ ලකුණු බලාපොරොත්තු සුන් කරවන සුළුය.",
        "සැබෑ ආණ්ඩුක්‍රම ව්‍යවස්ථා ප්‍රතිසංස්කරණ සහ ආර්ථිකය ප්‍රතිෂ්ඨාපනය කිරීමේ අභියෝගාත්මක කර්තව්‍යය වහාම ආරම්භ කිරීමට හැකිවන පරිදි, නව ජනාධිපතිවරයා ලෙස ගෞරවනීය සහ ඒකරාශී කරන පුද්ගලයකු සහිත, ඇතුළත්, අන්තර්වාර රජයක් ශ්‍රී ලංකාවට අවශ්‍ය වේ.",
        "අපි සෑම මන්ත්‍රීවරයෙකුගෙන්ම ඉල්ලා සිටින්නේ ඇය/ඔහු මූලිකවම පක්ෂයකට හෝ පක්ෂ නායකයෙකුට වඩා මහජන නියෝජිතයෙකු බවත් ලබන සතියේ නව ජනාධිපතිවරයෙකු සහ රජයක් තෝරා පත් කර ගැනීමේදී අසාමාන්‍ය තත්වයන් යටතේ විශේෂ ව්‍යවස්ථාපිත කාර්යයක් ඉටු කරන බවත් මතක තබා ගන්නා ලෙසයි. . පසුගිය මාස කිහිපය තුළ වෙනසක් සඳහා අරගලයට නායකත්වය දුන් අය, ශ්‍රී ලංකා මහජනතාව සහ ජාත්‍යන්තර ප්‍රජාව මෙම අසාමාන්‍ය වගකීම ඉටු කිරීමට ශ්‍රී ලංකා පාර්ලිමේන්තුවේ මන්ත්‍රීවරුන්ට හැකියාවක්, ධෛර්යයක් සහ ප්‍රඥාවක් තිබේදැයි බලා සිටිනු ඇත. ව්‍යවස්ථානුකූලවාදයේ, ප්‍රජාතන්ත්‍රවාදයේ සහ ශ්‍රී ලංකා ආර්ථිකයේ අනාගතය ඒ මත ඉතා හොඳින් රඳා පවතිනු ඇත."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "ලංකා පල්ලිය",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ලංකා පල්ලිය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ජනතා ව්‍යාපාරය/අරගලය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඊළඟ සතිය",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "මෑත සති",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "පසුගිය දින කිහිපය",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ආණ්ඩුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඊළඟ සතිය",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "පසුගිය මාස කිහිපය",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකා පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලාංකික",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "சீர்குலைந்த பொருளாதாரத்தை சீர்செய்யும் திறன் கொண்ட ஜனாதிபதியை தெரிவு செய்ய பாராளுமன்றத்திற்கு அரசியலமைப்பு கடமை உள்ளது: சர்ச் ஆஃப் சிலோன்",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "அரசியலமைப்பு மற்றும் பொறுப்புக்கூறலை மீளமைத்தல், வீழ்ச்சியடைந்த பொருளாதாரத்தை சீர்செய்தல் மற்றும் நாட்டின் குடிமக்களின் வாழ்வில் இயல்பு நிலையை மீட்டெடுக்கும் சவாலான பணியை ஆரம்பிக்கும் ஜனாதிபதி ஒருவரை தெரிவு செய்ய பாராளுமன்றத்திற்கு அரசியலமைப்பு கடமை உள்ளது என இலங்கை திருச்சபை தெரிவித்துள்ளது.",
        "இலங்கையின் ஜனாதிபதி பதவியில் இருந்து கோத்தபய ராஜபக்ச ராஜினாமா செய்த நீண்ட கால போராட்டத்திற்குப் பிறகு, மக்கள் இயக்கம்/அறகலயா தனது முதன்மை நோக்கத்தை அடைந்துள்ளதாக அவர்கள் ஒரு அறிக்கையில் தெரிவித்துள்ளனர். \"ஜனநாயகம், பொறுப்புக்கூறல் மற்றும் நீதிக்கான பிரச்சாரத்தில் இந்த குறிப்பிடத்தக்க மைல்கல்லை நாங்கள் வரவேற்கிறோம்\" என்று அந்த அறிக்கையில் கூறப்பட்டுள்ளது.",
        "ஜனாதிபதி இராஜபக்ஷ தனது பிரதமராக ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்கவை நியமித்தபோது பின்னடைவுகள் மற்றும் இழிந்த அரசியல் சூழ்ச்சிகளுக்கு மத்தியிலும் இது சாதிக்கப்பட்டது.",
        "ஜனநாயகம், பொறுப்புக்கூறல் மற்றும் நீதிக்கான பிரச்சாரம் தொடர வேண்டுமானால் போராட்டத்தின் அடுத்த கட்டம் மிகவும் முக்கியமானது. ஜனாதிபதி பதவிக் காலத்தின் எஞ்சிய காலத்திற்கு பணியாற்றுவதற்கு பாராளுமன்றம் அதன் உறுப்பினர்களில் இருந்து ஒருவரைத் தேர்ந்தெடுக்க வேண்டும்” என்று அந்த அறிக்கையில் மேலும் தெரிவிக்கப்பட்டுள்ளது.",
        "தற்போதைய பாராளுமன்றம், நிறைவேற்று அதிகாரத்தின் ஊழல் மற்றும் முறைகேடுகளை சரிபார்த்து, பொதுப் பொறுப்புக்கூறலை உறுதிப்படுத்த முடியாமல் மக்களின் பார்வையில் மதிப்பிழந்துள்ளது. சரிந்த பொருளாதாரத்தை சரிசெய்தல் மற்றும் நாட்டின் குடிமக்களின் வாழ்வில் இயல்பு நிலையை மீட்டெடுப்பது.",
        "அடுத்த வாரமாவது பாராளுமன்றம் தன்னை மீட்டுக்கொள்ளுமா? அரகலயாவின் மூலம் தெளிவாக வெளிப்படுத்தப்பட்ட மக்களின் குரல்களுக்கும், சிவில் சமூகத்தினால் அண்மைய வாரங்களில் வெளியிடப்பட்ட பல அறிக்கைகளுக்கும் பாராளுமன்றம் செவிசாய்க்குமா? வழக்கம் போல் அரசியலை நிராகரித்தல்; தேசிய நலனுக்கு மேல் தனிநபர் மற்றும் கட்சி நலன்களை வைக்கும் பாகுபாடான அரசியல் நிராகரிக்கப்படும் தீவிர அரசியல் மாற்றத்திற்கான கோரிக்கை; ஒரு புதிய ஆரம்பம், பழைய மதிப்பிழந்த பாராளுமன்றத்தில் கூட, இது மேலும் மாற்றத்தை உறுதியளிக்கிறது. கடந்த இரண்டு நாட்களாக ஒவ்வொரு கட்சியும் அதன் தலைவர்களும் மக்களின் குரலுக்கு செவிடாமையை வெளிப்படுத்தி வழமை போன்று பழைய இழிவான அரசியலை முன்னிறுத்தி ஜனாதிபதி பதவிக்கான கோரிக்கைகளை முன்வைத்து வருவது ஏமாற்றமளிக்கிறது.",
        "உண்மையான அரசியலமைப்பு சீர்திருத்தம் மற்றும் பொருளாதாரத்தை மீட்டெடுக்கும் சவாலான பணியை உடனடியாக ஆரம்பிக்கும் வகையில், புதிய ஜனாதிபதியாக மதிப்பிற்குரிய மற்றும் ஒன்றிணைக்கும் நபரைக் கொண்ட உள்ளடக்கிய இடைக்கால அரசாங்கம் இலங்கைக்கு தேவைப்படுகிறது.",
        "ஒவ்வொரு பாராளுமன்ற உறுப்பினரும் அவர்/அவர் ஒரு கட்சி அல்லது கட்சித் தலைவர் என்பதை விட முதன்மையாக மக்களின் பிரதிநிதி என்பதை நினைவில் கொள்ள வேண்டும் என்று நாங்கள் கேட்டுக்கொள்கிறோம், மேலும் அடுத்த வாரம் புதிய ஜனாதிபதி மற்றும் அரசாங்கத்தைத் தேர்ந்தெடுப்பதில், அசாதாரண சூழ்நிலையில் ஒரு சிறப்பு அரசியலமைப்புச் செயல்பாட்டைச் செய்கிறார். . கடந்த சில மாதங்களாக மாற்றத்திற்கான போராட்டத்தை முன்னெடுத்தவர்கள், இலங்கை நாடாளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர்களுக்கு இந்த அசாதாரண பொறுப்பை நிறைவேற்றும் திறன், தைரியம் மற்றும் விவேகம் உள்ளதா என்பதை இலங்கை மக்களும் சர்வதேச சமூகமும் உற்று நோக்கும். அரசியலமைப்பு, ஜனநாயகம் மற்றும் இலங்கைப் பொருளாதாரத்தின் எதிர்காலம் அதைச் சார்ந்தே இருக்க முடியும்” என்று அந்த அறிக்கையில் மேலும் தெரிவிக்கப்பட்டுள்ளது."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "சிலோன் தேவாலயம்",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "சிலோன் தேவாலயம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "மக்கள் இயக்கம்/அரகலயா",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ஷ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ராஜபக்சே",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "அடுத்த வாரம்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "சமீபத்திய வாரங்கள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "கடந்த இரண்டு நாட்களாக",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "அரசாங்கம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "அடுத்த வாரம்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "கடந்த சில மாதங்களாக",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}