{
  "newspaper_id": "ada-lk",
  "url": "https://www.ada.lk/breaking_news/ලංකාව-පතුලටම-ඇද-දමා-ජනපති-රටින්-යයි/11-395369",
  "time_ut": 1657678830,
  "original_lang": "si",
  "original_title": "ලංකාව පතුලටම ඇද දමා ජනපති රටින් යයි",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Sri Lanka will be dragged to the bottom and the President will leave the country",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "BBC reports that President Gotabaya Rajapaksa has left for Malé, the capital of the Maldives in an air force jet. The news service reports the information.",
        "The news service reports that the 73-year-old Gotabaya Rajapaksa has reached the capital city of Male today at around 3:00 am Maldives time.",
        "President Gotabaya Rajapaksa is going to resign from his position today and before that he has gone to Maldives.",
        "The President has signed his resignation letter. It was reported earlier that he had planned to leave the country after that."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Sri Lanka",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "BBC",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Gotabaya Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Malé",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "73-year-old",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Gotabaya Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "around 3:00 am",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Gotabaya Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Maldives",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        []
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "ලංකාව පතුලටම ඇද දමා ජනපති රටින් යයි",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "ජනපති ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ මහතා ගුවන් හමුදා ජෙට් යානයකින් මාලදිවයිනේ මාලේ අගනුවර වෙත පිටත්ව ගොස් ඇති බව බී.බී.සී. පුවත් සේවය තොරතුරු වාර්තා කරයි.",
        "73 හැවැරිදි ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ මහතා මාලදිවයිනේ වේලාවෙන් අද පෙරවරු 3.00ට පමණ එරට මාලේ අගනුවර වෙත ළඟා වී ඇති බව එම පුවත් සේවය වාර්තා කරයි.",
        "ජනපති ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ මහතා අද දිනයේදී සිය ධුරයෙන් ඉල්ලා අස්වීමට නියමිත අතර ඊට පෙර ඔහු මෙසේ මාලදිවයිනට ගොස් තිබේ.",
        "ජනපතිවරයා සිය ඉල්ලා අස්විමේ ලිපියට අත්සත් තබා තිබේ. ඉන් අනතුරුව ඔහු රටින් පිටත්වීමට සැලසුම් කර තිබුණ බව මිට පෙර තොරතුරු වාර්තා විය."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "බීබීසී",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "මාලේ",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "73 හැවිරිදිය",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "3:00 පමණ",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මාලදිවයින",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        []
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "இலங்கையை அதளபாதாளத்திற்கு இழுத்து ஜனாதிபதி நாட்டை விட்டு வெளியேறுவார்",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "ஜனாதிபதி கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ஷ மாலைதீவு தலைநகர் மாலே நோக்கி விமானப்படை ஜெட் விமானத்தில் சென்றுள்ளதாக பிபிசி தெரிவித்துள்ளது. செய்தி சேவை தகவல் தெரிவிக்கிறது.",
        "73 வயதான கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ச மாலைதீவு நேரப்படி இன்று அதிகாலை 3 மணியளவில் தலைநகர் மாலேயை சென்றடைந்ததாக செய்தி சேவை தெரிவித்துள்ளது.",
        "ஜனாதிபதி கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ஷ இன்று தனது பதவியை இராஜினாமா செய்யவுள்ளதாகவும் அதற்கு முன்னதாக மாலைதீவு சென்றுள்ளார்.",
        "அவரது ராஜினாமா கடிதத்தில் ஜனாதிபதி கையெழுத்திட்டுள்ளார். அதன் பின்னர் அவர் நாட்டை விட்டு வெளியேற திட்டமிட்டுள்ளதாக முன்னர் தெரிவிக்கப்பட்டது."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "இலங்கை",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "பிபிசி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆண்",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "73 வயதானவர்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "சுமார் 3:00 மணி",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "மாலத்தீவுகள்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        []
      ]
    }
  }
}