{
  "newspaper_id": "economy-next-com",
  "url": "https://economynext.com/sri-lanka-to-revise-water-tariffs-to-reflect-operational-costs-98386/",
  "time_ut": 1660039560,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Sri Lanka to revise water tariffs to reflect operational costs",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Sri Lanka to revise water tariffs to reflect operational costs",
      "author": "",
      "body_lines": [
        "ECONOMYNEXT – Sri Lanka’s cabinet of ministers has approved a proposal to revise water and sewage charges to reflect the Water Supply and Drainage Board’s recurring operational costs and working capital loan obligations.",
        "A statement from the government information department said on Tuesday August 09 that a tariff revision was deemed necessary to ensure an interrupted supply of water.",
        "Cabinet spokesman Minister Bandula Gunawardena called it a cost-reflective price formula.",
        "According to the Central Bank annual report, in 2021, the water board recorded an operating loss of 3.1 billion rupees compared to the loss of 370.5 million rupees recorded in the previous year, owing to increases in operation and maintenance costs during the period under review.",
        "Sri Lanka is going through its worst economic crisis since Independence, with high inflation adding to public woes. (Colombo/Aug09/2022)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Sri Lanka",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka’s",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Water Supply and Drainage Board’s",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Tuesday August 09",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Cabinet",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Bandula Gunawardena",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Central Bank",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "annual",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "2021",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "3.1 billion",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "370.5 million",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "the previous year",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Independence",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "මෙහෙයුම් පිරිවැය පිළිබිඹු කිරීම සඳහා ජල ගාස්තු සංශෝධනය කිරීමට ශ්‍රී ලංකාව",
      "author": "",
      "body_lines": [
        "ECONOMYNEXT - ජල සම්පාදන හා ජලාපවහන මණ්ඩලයේ පුනරාවර්තන මෙහෙයුම් වියදම් සහ කාරක ප්‍රාග්ධන ණය බැඳීම් පිළිබිඹු වන පරිදි ජල හා අපද්‍රව්‍ය ගාස්තු සංශෝධනය කිරීමේ යෝජනාවක් ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ අමාත්‍ය මණ්ඩලය විසින් අනුමත කර ඇත.",
        "ජල සැපයුම අත්හිටුවීම සහතික කිරීම සඳහා ගාස්තු සංශෝධනයක් අවශ්‍ය යැයි සලකන බව රජයේ ප්‍රවෘත්ති දෙපාර්තමේන්තුවේ ප්‍රකාශයක් අගෝස්තු 09 අඟහරුවාදා ප්‍රකාශ කළේය.",
        "කැබිනට් ප්‍රකාශක අමාත්‍ය බන්දුල ගුණවර්ධන එය හැඳින්වූයේ පිරිවැය පරාවර්තක මිල සූත්‍රයක් ලෙසයි.",
        "මහ බැංකු වාර්ෂික වාර්තාවට අනුව, සමාලෝචිත කාලසීමාව තුළ මෙහෙයුම් සහ නඩත්තු වියදම් ඉහළ යාම හේතුවෙන්, 2021 වසරේදී ජල මණ්ඩලයට පෙර වසරේ වාර්තා වූ රුපියල් මිලියන 370.5 ක අලාභයට සාපේක්ෂව රුපියල් බිලියන 3.1 ක මෙහෙයුම් අලාභයක් වාර්තා විය.",
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකාව නිදහසින් පසු එහි දරුණුතම ආර්ථික අර්බුදය හරහා ගමන් කරමින් සිටින අතර, ඉහළ උද්ධමනය මහජන දුක්ඛිත තත්ත්වයන්ට එකතු වේ. (කොළඹ/අගෝස්තු 09/2022)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජල සම්පාදන හා ජලාපවහන මණ්ඩලයේ",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "අගෝස්තු 09 අඟහරුවාදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "මණ්ඩල",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "බන්දුල ගුණවර්ධන",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "මහ බැංකුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "වාර්ෂික",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "2021",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "බිලියන 3.1 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "මිලියන 370.5 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "පෙර වසරේ",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "නිදහස",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "செயற்பாட்டுச் செலவுகளை பிரதிபலிக்கும் வகையில் இலங்கை நீர் கட்டணங்களை திருத்தியமைக்கவுள்ளது",
      "author": "",
      "body_lines": [
        "பொருளாதாரம் - நீர் வழங்கல் மற்றும் வடிகாலமைப்புச் சபையின் தொடர்ச்சியான செயற்பாட்டுச் செலவுகள் மற்றும் செயற்பாட்டு மூலதனக் கடன் கடமைகளைப் பிரதிபலிக்கும் வகையில் நீர் மற்றும் கழிவுநீர் கட்டணங்களைத் திருத்துவதற்கான முன்மொழிவுக்கு இலங்கையின் அமைச்சர்கள் அமைச்சரவை அங்கீகாரம் வழங்கியுள்ளது.",
        "செவ்வாய்க்கிழமை ஆகஸ்ட் 09 அன்று அரசாங்க தகவல் திணைக்களத்தின் அறிக்கையொன்றில், நீர் விநியோகம் தடைப்படுவதை உறுதிசெய்ய கட்டண திருத்தம் அவசியமானதாகக் கருதப்படுகிறது.",
        "அமைச்சரவைப் பேச்சாளர் அமைச்சர் பந்துல குணவர்தன இதனை செலவு பிரதிபலிப்பு விலை சூத்திரம் என தெரிவித்துள்ளார்.",
        "மத்திய வங்கியின் வருடாந்த அறிக்கையின்படி, 2021 ஆம் ஆண்டில், மீளாய்வுக்குட்பட்ட காலப்பகுதியில் செயற்பாடு மற்றும் பராமரிப்புச் செலவுகள் அதிகரித்ததன் காரணமாக, கடந்த வருடத்தில் பதிவான 370.5 மில்லியன் ரூபா நட்டத்துடன் ஒப்பிடுகையில், 3.1 பில்லியன் ரூபா செயற்பாட்டு நட்டத்தை நீர் சபை பதிவு செய்துள்ளது.",
        "இலங்கை சுதந்திரத்திற்குப் பின்னர் மிக மோசமான பொருளாதார நெருக்கடியை எதிர்கொண்டுள்ளது, உயர் பணவீக்கம் பொது துயரங்களைச் சேர்க்கிறது. (கொழும்பு/ஆகஸ்ட்09/2022)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "இலங்கை",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கையின்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "நீர் வழங்கல் மற்றும் வடிகால் வாரியம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஆகஸ்ட் 09 செவ்வாய்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "மந்திரி சபை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "பந்துல குணவர்தன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "மத்திய வங்கி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆண்டு",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "2021",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "3.1 பில்லியன்",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "370.5 மில்லியன்",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "முந்தைய ஆண்டு",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சுதந்திரம்",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}