{
  "newspaper_id": "news-first-lk",
  "url": "https://www.newsfirst.lk/2022/09/04/president-extends-condolences-to-family-of-gorbachev/",
  "time_ut": 1662276000,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "President extends condolences to family of Gorbachev",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "President extends condolences to family of Gorbachev",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); President Ranil Wickremesinghe has extended his heartfelt condolences to the family of the late Leader of the Soviet Union Mikhail Gorbachev and the people of Russia.",
        "The Presidential Media Division stated that the President had extended the condolence message to Russian President Vladimir Putin on the passing of the late Soviet Union Leader Gorbachev.",
        "He had noted that the late Soviet Union Leader will be remembered as a preeminent world leader whose commitment to forging partnerships with other nations changed the course of history and paved the way for a new era in global relations."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Gorbachev",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "News 1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Soviet Union",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Mikhail Gorbachev",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Russia",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "The Presidential Media Division",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Russian",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Vladimir Putin",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Soviet Union",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Gorbachev",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Soviet Union",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "ගොර්බචෙව්ගේ පවුලේ අයට ජනාධිපතිතුමා ශෝකය පළ කරයි",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); අභාවප්‍රාප්ත සෝවියට් සංගමයේ නායක මිහායිල් ගොර්බචෙව්ගේ පවුලේ අයට සහ රුසියානු ජනතාවට ජනාධිපති රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතා සිය හෘදයාංගම ශෝකය ප්‍රකාශ කර තිබේ.",
        "අභාවප්‍රාප්ත සෝවියට් සංගමයේ නායක ගොර්බචෙව්ගේ අභාවය වෙනුවෙන් ජනාධිපතිවරයා රුසියානු ජනාධිපති ව්ලැඩිමීර් පුටින් වෙත ශෝක පණිවුඩය යොමු කළ බවයි ජනාධිපති මාධ්‍ය අංශය සඳහන් කළේ.",
        "අභාවප්‍රාප්ත සෝවියට් සංගමයේ නායකයා අනෙකුත් ජාතීන් සමඟ හවුල්කාරිත්වයන් ඇති කර ගැනීමට කැපවීම ඉතිහාසයේ ගමන් මග වෙනස් කළ සහ ගෝලීය සබඳතාවල නව යුගයකට මග පෑදූ ප්‍රමුඛතම ලෝක නායකයෙකු ලෙස සිහිපත් කරනු ඇතැයි ඔහු සඳහන් කර තිබුණි."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ගොර්බචෙව්",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "News 1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "සෝවියට් සංගමය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මිහායිල් ගොර්බචෙව්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "රුසියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ජනාධිපති මාධ්‍ය අංශය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "රුසියානු",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ව්ලැඩිමීර් පුටින්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "සෝවියට් සංගමය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගොර්බචෙව්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "සෝවියට් සංගමය",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "கோர்பச்சேவ் குடும்பத்தினருக்கு ஜனாதிபதி இரங்கல் தெரிவித்துள்ளார்",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); சோவியத் யூனியனின் மறைந்த தலைவர் மிகைல் கொர்பச்சேவ் அவர்களின் குடும்பத்தினருக்கும் ரஷ்ய மக்களுக்கும் ஜனாதிபதி ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க தனது ஆழ்ந்த அனுதாபங்களை தெரிவித்துள்ளார்.",
        "மறைந்த சோவியத் யூனியன் தலைவர் கொர்பச்சேவின் மறைவு குறித்து ரஷ்ய ஜனாதிபதி விளாடிமிர் புட்டினுக்கு ஜனாதிபதி இரங்கல் செய்தியை வெளியிட்டதாக ஜனாதிபதி ஊடகப் பிரிவு தெரிவித்துள்ளது.",
        "மறைந்த சோவியத் யூனியன் தலைவர் ஒரு தலைசிறந்த உலகத் தலைவராக நினைவுகூரப்படுவார் என்று அவர் குறிப்பிட்டார், மற்ற நாடுகளுடன் கூட்டுறவை உருவாக்குவதற்கான அர்ப்பணிப்பு வரலாற்றின் போக்கை மாற்றியது மற்றும் உலகளாவிய உறவுகளில் ஒரு புதிய சகாப்தத்திற்கு வழி வகுத்தது."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "கோர்பச்சேவ்",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "News 1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "சோவியத் ஒன்றியம்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "மிகைல் கோர்பச்சேவ்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரஷ்யா",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஜனாதிபதி ஊடகப் பிரிவு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரஷ்யன்",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "விளாடிமிர் புடின்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "சோவியத் ஒன்றியம்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "கோர்பச்சேவ்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "சோவியத் ஒன்றியம்",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}