{
  "newspaper_id": "lankadeepa-lk",
  "url": "https://www.lankadeepa.lk/news/සැර-කොරෝනාව-තවත්-ප්‍රදේශ-හතරකින්/101-618493",
  "time_ut": 1661099595,
  "original_lang": "si",
  "original_title": "සැර කොරෝනාව තවත් ප්‍රදේශ හතරකින්",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Severe Corona from four other areas",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "Dr. Chandima Jeewandara, Head of the Department of Allergy Immunology and Cell Biology, University of Sri Jayawardenepura, said that the BA 5 sub-type of Covid, which is spreading rapidly in the world, has been found in four other areas of the island.",
        "He said that sixty-seven biofilm samples taken from those areas were tested and 60 of them were found to contain this severe corona sub-variety.",
        "He also mentioned that other Omicron subtypes were found in the other seven samples.",
        "The biofilm samples of people infected with Covid-19 taken from the areas of Colombo, Gampaha, Kurunegala and Puttalam have been tested.",
        "The fast-spreading BA5 subtype of Covid was previously found in several areas.",
        "A group of researchers including Professor Chandima Jeevandara conducted genetic analysis tests on these biofilm samples received by the health departments."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Corona",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "four",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Chandima Jeewandara",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Department of Allergy Immunology",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Cell Biology",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "University of Sri Jayawardenepura",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the BA 5 sub-type of",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Covid",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "four",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "sixty-seven",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "60",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Omicron",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "seven",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Colombo",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Gampaha",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kurunegala",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Puttalam",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Covid",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Chandima Jeevandara",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "සැර කොරෝනාව තවත් ප්‍රදේශ හතරකින්",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "ලෝකයේ වේගවත් පැතිරීමක් සහිත බී.ඒ 5 කොවිඩ් අනු ප්‍රභේදය දිවයිනේ තවත් ප්‍රදේශ හතරකින් සොයාගෙන ඇතැයි ශ්‍රී ජයවර්ධනපුර විශ්වවිද්‍යාලයේ ආසාත්මිකතා ප්‍රතිශක්තිවේද සහ සෛල ජෛව විද්‍යා අධ්‍යයන අංශයේ ප්‍රධානී ආචාර්ය චන්දිම ජීවන්දර මහතා පැවසීය.",
        "එම ප්‍රදේශවලින් ලබාගත් ජෛව පටල සාම්පල හැට හතක් පරීක්ෂාවට ලක් කෙරුණු අතර ඉන් 60 කම මෙම සැර කොරෝනා අනු ප්‍රභේදය තිබි හමුවූ බවද හෙතෙම සඳහන් කළේය.",
        "අනෙකුත් ඔමික්‍රෝන් අනු ප්‍රභේද අනෙක් සාම්පල හතේ තිබී සොයාගත් බවද හෙතෙම සඳහන් කළේය.",
        "මෙසේ පරීක්ෂාවට ලක් කර ඇත්තේ කොළඹ ගම්පහ කුරුණෑගල සහ පුත්තලම යන ප්‍රදේශවලින් ලබාගත් කොවිඩ් ආසාදිතයන්ගේ ජෛව පටල සාම්පලයන්ය.",
        "වේගවත් පැතිරීමක් සහිත බී.ඒ 5 කොවිඩ් අනු ප්‍රභේදය ප්‍රදේශ කිහිපයකින් මීට පෙරද සොයා ගැනිණ.",
        "සෞඛ්‍ය අංශ විසින් බාරදෙනු ලැබූ මෙම ජෛව පටල සාම්පල සම්බන්ධයෙන් ජාන විශ්ලේෂණ පරීක්ෂණ කරනු ලැබුවේ මහාචාර්ය චන්දිම ජීවන්දර මහතා ඇතුළු පර්යේෂකයන් පිරිසක් විසිනි."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "කොරෝනා",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "හතර",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "චන්දිම ජීවන්දර",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "අසාත්මිකතා ප්රතිශක්තිකරණ දෙපාර්තමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "සෛල ජීව විද්යාව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ජයවර්ධනපුර විශ්වවිද්‍යාලය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "BA 5 උප වර්ගය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "කොවිඩ්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "හතර",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "හැට හත",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "60",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Omicron",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "හත",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "කොළඹ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගම්පහ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "කුරුණෑගල",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "පුත්තලම",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "කොවිඩ්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "චන්දිම ජීවන්දර",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "மற்ற நான்கு பகுதிகளில் இருந்து கடுமையான கொரோனா",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "ஸ்ரீ ஜயவர்தனபுர பல்கலைக்கழகத்தின் ஒவ்வாமை நோயெதிர்ப்பு மற்றும் உயிரியல் துறையின் தலைவர் டாக்டர் சந்திம ஜீவந்தர, உலகில் வேகமாக பரவி வரும் கோவிட் BA 5 துணை வகை, தீவின் மற்ற நான்கு பகுதிகளில் கண்டறியப்பட்டுள்ளது. .",
        "அந்த பகுதிகளில் இருந்து எடுக்கப்பட்ட அறுபத்தேழு உயிரிப்படலம் மாதிரிகள் பரிசோதிக்கப்பட்டதாகவும், அவற்றில் 60 வகைகளில் இந்த கடுமையான கொரோனா துணை வகை இருப்பது கண்டறியப்பட்டதாகவும் அவர் கூறினார்.",
        "மற்ற ஏழு மாதிரிகளில் மற்ற ஓமிக்ரான் துணை வகைகள் காணப்பட்டதாகவும் அவர் குறிப்பிட்டார்.",
        "கொழும்பு, கம்பஹா, குருநாகல் மற்றும் புத்தளம் ஆகிய பகுதிகளில் இருந்து எடுக்கப்பட்ட கொவிட்-19 தொற்றுக்குள்ளானவர்களின் உயிரிப்படலம் மாதிரிகள் பரிசோதிக்கப்பட்டுள்ளன.",
        "வேகமாகப் பரவும் BA5 துணை வகை கோவிட் முன்பு பல பகுதிகளில் கண்டறியப்பட்டது.",
        "பேராசிரியர் சந்திம ஜீவந்தர உள்ளிட்ட ஆராய்ச்சியாளர்கள் குழு, சுகாதாரத் துறைகளால் பெறப்பட்ட இந்த உயிரிப்படலம் மாதிரிகளில் மரபணு பகுப்பாய்வு சோதனைகளை நடத்தியது."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "கொரோனா",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "நான்கு",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "சந்திம ஜீவந்தர",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஒவ்வாமை நோய்த்தடுப்பு துறை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "உயிரணு உயிரியல்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஸ்ரீ ஜயவர்தனபுர பல்கலைக்கழகம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "பிஏ 5 துணை வகை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "கோவிட்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "நான்கு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "அறுபத்து ஏழு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "60",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஓமிக்ரான்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஏழு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "கொழும்பு",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "கம்பஹா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "குருநாகல்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "புத்தளம்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "கோவிட்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "சந்திம ஜீவந்தர",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}