{
  "newspaper_id": "virakesari-lk",
  "url": "http://www.virakesari.lk/article/130423",
  "time_ut": 1656498505,
  "original_lang": "ta",
  "original_title": "இலங்கைக்கான நன்கொடையினை சீனா கௌரவமாக கருதுகிறது - தூதுவர் கீ சென்ஹொங்",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "China considers donation to Sri Lanka as an honor - Ambassador Kei Senhong",
      "author": "T. Saranya",
      "body_lines": [
        "The 5,000 metric tons of rice donated by China will be used to feed students in all nine provinces. In response, the Minister of Education told the Chinese Ambassador to Sri Lanka that the Chinese government was welcome to co-operate with China in the face of the crisis.",
        "Sri Lankans are facing an economic crisis. We have decided to provide nutritious food to children from low income families who have been severely affected economically.",
        "Chinese Ambassador to Sri Lanka Kei Senhong said that China considers the donation as an honor.",
        "China has decided to donate 10,000 metric tons of rice to Sri Lanka on the occasion of the 70th anniversary of the signing of the Sri Lanka Rubber-Rice Agreement.",
        "Chinese Ambassador to Sri Lanka Ki-Senhong handed over 5,000 metric tons of rice to Education Minister Bandula Gunawardena yesterday.",
        "Commenting on this, Transport, Highways and Media Minister Bandula Gunawardena welcomed China's cooperation in the face of the worst economic crisis.",
        "The historic good relations between China and Sri Lanka have further strengthened the cooperation and good relations between the two countries.",
        "The 5,000 metric tons of rice available will be used to feed millions of students in 7,900 schools in 9 provinces. On behalf of Sri Lanka, I would like to thank the Chinese Government.",
        "Chinese Ambassador to Sri Lanka Xi Hong Kong, who attended on behalf of the Chinese Government, said China has co-operated with Sri Lanka on all occasions in the face of the crisis situation in Sri Lanka.",
        "Minister Bandula Gunawardena stated that all necessary assistance will be provided for the nutrition of the school children.",
        "China is honored to donate during an emergency. The surplus 5,000 metric tons of rice will be delivered soon.",
        "The Sri Lankan brothers are facing the current economic crisis. Most families in the total population face this problem.",
        "We decided to provide nutritious food to children from low-income families who have been severely affected economically. He said Sri Lankans would face the current crisis together and make rapid progress."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "China",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "Sri Lanka",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "Kei Senhong",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "The 5,000 metric tons",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "China",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "nine",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Chinese",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Chinese",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "China",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lankans",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Chinese",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka Kei Senhong",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "China",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "China",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "10,000 metric tons",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "70th",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Sri Lanka Rubber-Rice Agreement",
            "label": "LOC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Chinese",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka Ki-Senhong",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "over 5,000 metric tons",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "Bandula Gunawardena",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "yesterday",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Bandula Gunawardena",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "China",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "China",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "two",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "The 5,000 metric tons",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "millions",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "7,900",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "9",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Chinese",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Chinese",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka Xi",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Hong Kong",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Chinese Government",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "China",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Bandula Gunawardena",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "China",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "5,000 metric tons",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lankan",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lankans",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "චීනය ශ්‍රී ලංකාවට පරිත්‍යාග කිරීම ගෞරවයක් ලෙස සලකයි - තානාපති කී සෙන්හොං",
      "author": "T. Saranya",
      "body_lines": [
        "චීනය විසින් පරිත්‍යාග කරන ලද සහල් මෙට්‍රික් ටොන් 5000 පළාත් නවයේම සිසුන්ගේ ආහාර සඳහා යොදා ගැනේ. ඊට ප්‍රතිචාර දක්වමින් අධ්‍යාපන අමාත්‍යවරයා ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ චීන තානාපතිවරයාට කියා සිටියේ අර්බුදය හමුවේ චීනය සමඟ සහයෝගයෙන් කටයුතු කිරීමට චීන රජය සාදරයෙන් පිළිගන්නා බවයි.",
        "ශ්‍රී ලාංකිකයෝ ආර්ථික අර්බුදයකට මුහුණ දී සිටිති. ආර්ථික වශයෙන් දැඩි ලෙස පීඩාවට පත්ව සිටින අඩු ආදායම්ලාභී පවුල්වල දරුවන්ට පෝෂ්‍යදායී ආහාර ලබාදීමට අපි තීරණය කර තිබෙනවා.",
        "මෙම පරිත්‍යාගය ගෞරවයක් ලෙස චීනය සලකන බව ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ චීන තානාපති Kei Senhong මහතා පැවසීය.",
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකා රබර් සහල් ගිවිසුම අත්සන් කර වසර 70ක් සපිරීම නිමිත්තෙන් සහල් මෙට්‍රික් ටොන් 10,000ක් ශ්‍රී ලංකාවට පරිත්‍යාග කිරීමට චීනය තීරණය කර තිබේ.",
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ චීන තානාපති Ki-Senhong මහතා විසින් සහල් මෙට්‍රික් ටොන් 5000ක් අධ්‍යාපන අමාත්‍ය බන්දුල ගුණවර්ධන මහතා වෙත ඊයේ භාර දෙනු ලැබීය.",
        "මේ පිළිබඳව අදහස් දැක්වූ ප්‍රවාහන, මහාමාර්ග හා ජනමාධ්‍ය අමාත්‍ය බන්දුල ගුණවර්ධන මහතා, දරුණුතම ආර්ථික අර්බුදය හමුවේ චීනයේ සහයෝගීතාව පිළිගත්තේය.",
        "චීනය සහ ශ්‍රී ලංකාව අතර ඓතිහාසික යහපත් සබඳතා දෙරට අතර සහයෝගීතාව සහ යහපත් සබඳතා තවදුරටත් ශක්තිමත් කර ඇත.",
        "පවතින සහල් මෙට්‍රික් ටොන් 5,000 පළාත් 9ක පාසල් 7,900ක මිලියන සංඛ්‍යාත සිසුන්ගේ පෝෂණය සඳහා යොදා ගැනේ. ශ්‍රී ලංකාව වෙනුවෙන් මම චීන රජයට ස්තූතිවන්ත වෙනවා.",
        "චීන රජය වෙනුවෙන් සහභාගී වූ ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ චීන තානාපති ෂී හොංකොං මහතා පැවසුවේ ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ අර්බුදකාරී තත්ත්වය හමුවේ චීනය සෑම අවස්ථාවකදීම ශ්‍රී ලංකාව සමඟ සහයෝගයෙන් කටයුතු කළ බවයි.",
        "පාසල් දරුවන්ගේ පෝෂණය වෙනුවෙන් අවශ්‍ය සියලු සහය ලබාදෙන බව අමාත්‍ය බන්දුල ගුණවර්ධන ප්‍රකාශ කළා.",
        "හදිසි අවස්ථාවකදී පරිත්‍යාග කිරීම චීනයට ගෞරවයක්.අතිරික්ත සහල් මෙට්‍රික් ටොන් 5,000 ඉක්මනින් ලබා දෙනවා.",
        "වත්මන් ආර්ථික අර්බුදයට ශ්‍රී ලාංකීය සහෝදරයෝ මුහුණ දී සිටිති. මුළු ජනගහනයෙන් බොහෝ පවුල් මෙම ගැටලුවට මුහුණ දෙති.",
        "ආර්ථික වශයෙන් දැඩි ලෙස පීඩාවට පත්ව සිටින අඩු ආදායම්ලාභී පවුල්වල දරුවන්ට පෝෂණීය ආහාර ලබාදීමට අපි තීරණය කළා. වත්මන් අර්බුදයට ශ්‍රී ලාංකිකයන් එක්ව මුහුණ දී ශීඝ්‍ර ප්‍රගතියක් අත්කර ගනු ඇතැයි ඔහු පැවසීය."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "චීනය",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "Kei Senhong",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "මෙට්‍රික් ටොන් 5000 කි",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "චීනය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "නවය",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "චීන",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "චීන",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "චීනය",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලාංකිකයන්",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "චීන",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකාව කී සෙන්හොං",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "චීනය",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "චීනය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මෙට්‍රික් ටොන් 10,000 කි",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "70 වැනි",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකා රබර් සහල් ගිවිසුම",
            "label": "LOC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "චීන",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකා කි-සෙන්හොං",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මෙට්‍රික් ටොන් 5,000කට වැඩි",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "බන්දුල ගුණවර්ධන",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඊයේ",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "බන්දුල ගුණවර්ධන",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "චීනය",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "චීනය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "දෙක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "මෙට්‍රික් ටොන් 5000 කි",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "මිලියන",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "7,900 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "9",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "චීන",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "චීන",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකා ෂී",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "හොංකොං",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "චීන රජය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "චීනය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "බන්දුල ගුණවර්ධන",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "චීනය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මෙට්‍රික් ටොන් 5000 කි",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලාංකික",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලාංකිකයන්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "இலங்கைக்கான நன்கொடையினை சீனா கௌரவமாக கருதுகிறது - தூதுவர் கீ சென்ஹொங்",
      "author": "T. Saranya",
      "body_lines": [
        "சீனாவின் நன்கொடையினால் கிடைக்கப்பெற்ற 5,000 மெற்றிக்தொன் அரிசி 9 மாகாணங்களிலும் உள்ள மாணவர்களின் போசனை உணவிற்காக வழங்கப்படும். நெருக்கடியான நிலைமையினை எதிர்கொண்டுள்ள போது சீனாவின் ஒத்துழைப்பு வரவேற்கத்தக்கது என பதில் கல்வி அமைச்சர் சீன அரசாங்கத்தின் பிரதிநிதியான இலங்கைக்கான சீன தூதுவரிடம் குறிப்பிட்டார்.",
        "இலங்கையர்கள் பொருளாதார நெருக்கடியினை எதிர்கொண்டுள்ளார்கள். பொருளாதார ரீதியில் பெருமளவில் பாதிக்கப்பட்டுள்ள குறைந்த வருமானம் பெறும் குடும்பங்களில் உள்ள பிள்ளைகளுக்கு போசனையான உணவினை வழங்க தீர்மானித்துள்ளோம்.",
        "வழங்கப்பட்ட நன்கொடையினை சீனா கௌரவமாக கருதுகிறது என இலங்கைக்கான சீன தூதுவர் கீ சென்ஹொங் தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "சீனா இலங்கை இறப்பர் - அரிசி ஒப்பந்தம் கைச்சாத்திடப்பட்டு 70 ஆண்டுகள் பூரணமடைந்துள்ளதை முன்னிட்டு இலங்கைக்கு 10,000 மெற்றிக்தொன் அரிசியை நன்கொடையாக வழங்க சீனா தீர்மானித்தது.",
        "அதற்கமைய முதற்கட்டமாக 5,000 மெற்றிக்தொன் அரிசி தொகையை இலங்கைக்கான சீன தூதுவர் கீ-சென்ஹொங் பதில் கல்வி அமைச்சர் பந்துல குணவர்தனவிடம் நேற்று கையளித்தார்.",
        "இதன்போது கருத்துரைத்த போக்குவரத்து, நெடுஞ்சாலைகள் மற்றும் ஊடகத்துறை அமைச்சர் பந்துல குணவர்தன மிக மோசமான பொருளாதார நெருக்கடியினை எதிர்கொண்டுள்ள வேளையில் சீனாவினால் வழங்கப்படும் ஒத்துழைப்பு வரவேற்கத்தக்கது.",
        "சீனாவிற்கும் இலங்கைக்கும் இடையில் வரலாற்று ரீதியில் காணப்படும் நல்லுறவு இரு நாடுகளின் ஒத்துழைப்பு மற்றும் நல்லுறவை மேலும் பலப்படுத்தியுள்ளது.",
        "கிடைக்கப்பெற்றுள்ள 5,000 மெற்றிக்தொன் அரிசி 9 மாகாணங்களிலும் உள்ள 7,900 பாடசாலைகளில் கல்வி பயிலும் மில்லியன் கணக்கிலான மாணவர்களுக்கு உணவு வழங்குவதற்காக பயன்படுத்தப்படும். இலங்கை சார்பில் சீன அரசாங்கத்திற்கு நன்றியினை தெரிவித்துக்கொள்கிறேன் என்றார்.",
        "சீன அரசாங்கம் சார்பில் கலந்துக்கொண்ட இலங்கைக்கான சீன தூதுவர் சி சென்ஹொங் இலங்கை நெருக்கடியான சூழலை எதிர்க்கொண்ட அனைத்து சந்தர்ப்பங்களிலும் சீனா இலங்கைக்கு ஒத்துழைப்பு வழங்கியுள்ளது.",
        "அமைச்சர் பந்துல குணவர்தன குறிப்பிட்டதற்கமைய பாடசாலை மாணவர்களின் போசனைக்கு தேவையான சகல ஒத்துழைப்புக்களும் வழங்கப்படும்.",
        "அத்தியாவசியமான சந்தர்ப்பத்தின் போது வழங்கப்பட்ட நன்கொடையினை சீனா கௌரவமாக கருதுகிறது.மிகுதி 5000 மெற்றிக்தொன் அரிசி விரைவாக வழங்கப்படும்.",
        "இலங்கை சகோதரர்கள் தற்போதைய பொருளாதார நெருக்கடியினை எதிர்கொண்டுள்ளார்கள். மொத்த சனத்தொகையில் பெரும்பாலான குடும்பத்தினர் இப்பிரச்சினையை எதிர்கொண்டுள்ளனர்.",
        "பொருளாதார ரீதியில் பெருமளவில் பாதிக்கப்பட்டுள்ள குறைந்த வருமானம் பெறும் குடும்பங்களில் உள்ள பிள்ளைகளுக்கு போசனையான உணவினை வழங்க தீர்மானித்தோம். தற்போதைய நெருக்கடியான சூழலை இலங்கையர்கள் ஒன்றாக எதிர்கொண்டு விரைவாக முன்னேற்றமடைவார்கள் என்றார்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "சீனா",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "இலங்கை",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "Kei Senhong",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "5,000 மெட்ரிக் டன்",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "சீனா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஒன்பது",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "சீன",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சீன",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "சீனா",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கையர்கள்",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "சீன",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை கீ சென்ஹோங்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சீனா",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "சீனா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "10,000 மெட்ரிக் டன்",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "70வது",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை ரப்பர்-அரிசி ஒப்பந்தம்",
            "label": "LOC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "சீன",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை கி-சென்ஹாங்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "5,000 மெட்ரிக் டன்களுக்கு மேல்",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "பந்துல குணவர்தன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "நேற்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பந்துல குணவர்தன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "சீனா",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "சீனா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இரண்டு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "5,000 மெட்ரிக் டன்",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "மில்லியன்கள்",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "7,900",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "9",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சீன",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "சீன",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை Xi",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஹாங்காங்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சீன அரசாங்கம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "சீனா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பந்துல குணவர்தன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "சீனா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "5,000 மெட்ரிக் டன்",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கையர்கள்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}