{
  "newspaper_id": "d-b-s-jeyaraj-com",
  "url": "https://dbsjeyaraj.com/dbsj/archives/79189",
  "time_ut": 1661453820,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Former MP and State Minister Ranjan Ramanayake walks out a free man after being released from a 4 year rigorous imprisonment sentence; President Wickremesinghe grants conditional  pardon stipulating that Ramanayake should not make any statement critical or derogatory of the entire judiciary in future.",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Former MP and State Minister Ranjan Ramanayake walks out a free man after being released from a 4 year rigorous imprisonment sentence; President Wickremesinghe grants conditional  pardon stipulating that Ramanayake should not make any statement critical or derogatory of the entire judiciary in future.",
      "author": "Administrator",
      "body_lines": [
        "Former MP and State Minister Ranjan Ramanayake was freed yesterday from prison after a conditional pardon by President Ranil Wickremesinghe.",
        "Opposition Leader Sajith Premadasa, Labour and Foreign Employment Minister Manusha Nanayakkara, MPs Nalin Bandara and Harshana Rajakaruna were present outside the Welikada prison along with supporters to welcome him.",
        "Ramanayake who was serving a four-year rigorous imprisonment since January 2021 for contempt of court.",
        "The release follows President Wickremesinghe yesterday signing the document granting pardon on the condition that Ramanayake should not make any statement critical or derogatory of the entire judiciary in future.",
        "The conditional pardon however saw Premadasa expressing regret. Taking to Twitter, he expressed his disappointment that Ramanayake was released under 34 (1) (d) of the Constitution and not under 34 (2).",
        "“Disappointed to learn that he was released under 34 (1) (d) of the constitution which is merely a remission of his sentence rather than a full pardon with his civic and political rights intact under 34 (2),” Premadasa tweeted. “This means he is disqualified from holding political office. Utterly disappointed!” he said.",
        "Ramanayake had made statements insulting the Judiciary primarily outside Temple Trees on 21 August 2017. He alleged that the majority of judges and lawyers in the country were corrupt.",
        "The Supreme Court delivered its judgement on 12 January 2021, convicting him for the offence of contempt of court and sentenced him to four years’ rigorous imprisonment.",
        "Submitting an affidavit to court on Thursday, Ranjan Ramanayake had stated that having reflected deeply on the statement made by him outside Temple Trees on 21 August 2017, he admits that the statement he made is completely and utterly false and derogatory and contemptuous of the entire Judiciary and humbly and profoundly apologised and sought the forgiveness of the entire Judiciary.",
        "Further, Ramanayake also sought forgiveness for the derogatory statement he made outside the Supreme Court premises claiming that he would not withdraw the statement he made on 21 August 2017.",
        "He also gave an assurance that he would never again, in his entire lifetime, make any statement critical or derogatory of the entire Judiciary."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "State",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "Ranjan Ramanayake",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "4 year",
          "label": "DATE"
        },
        {
          "text": "Wickremesinghe",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "Ramanayake",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "State",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ranjan Ramanayake",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "yesterday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sajith Premadasa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Labour",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Manusha Nanayakkara",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Nalin Bandara",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Harshana Rajakaruna",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "Welikada",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "four-year",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "January 2021",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "yesterday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ramanayake",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Premadasa",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Twitter",
            "label": "PRODUCT"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ramanayake",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "under 34",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "1",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Constitution",
            "label": "LAW"
          },
          {
            "text": "34",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "2",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "under 34",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "1",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "34",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "2",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Premadasa",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Temple Trees",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "21 August 2017",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "The Supreme Court",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "12 January 2021",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "four years",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Thursday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ranjan Ramanayake",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "21 August 2017",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Judiciary",
            "label": "LOC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Ramanayake",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Supreme Court",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "21 August 2017",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Judiciary",
            "label": "LOC"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "හිටපු පාර්ලිමේන්තු මන්ත්‍රී සහ රාජ්‍ය අමාත්‍ය රන්ජන් රාමනායක වසර 4ක සිරදඬුවම් විඳීමෙන් නිදහස් වූ පසු නිදහස් පුද්ගලයෙකු පිටව යයි. මින් ඉදිරියට රාමනායක මහතා සමස්ත අධිකරණයම විවේචනාත්මක හෝ අවමන් සහගත ප්‍රකාශයක් නොකළ යුතු බවට කොන්දේසි සහිතව ජනාධිපති වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතා කොන්දේසි සහිත සමාව ලබා දෙයි.",
      "author": "පරිපාලක",
      "body_lines": [
        "හිටපු පාර්ලිමේන්තු මන්ත්‍රී සහ රාජ්‍ය අමාත්‍ය රන්ජන් රාමනායක මහතා ජනාධිපති රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතාගේ කොන්දේසි සහිත සමාවකින් පසු ඊයේ සිරෙන් නිදහස් විය.",
        "විපක්ෂ නායක සජිත් ප්‍රේමදාස, කම්කරු හා විදේශ රැකියා අමාත්‍ය මනූෂ නානායක්කාර, පාර්ලිමේන්තු මන්ත්‍රීවරුන් වන නලින් බණ්ඩාර සහ හර්ෂණ රාජකරුණා ඇතුළු පිරිසක් ඔහු පිළිගැනීමට ආධාරකරුවන් සමඟ වැලිකඩ බන්ධනාගාරයෙන් පිටත පැමිණ සිටියහ.",
        "රාමනායක මහතා අධිකරණයට අපහාස කිරීම සම්බන්ධයෙන් 2021 ජනවාරි මාසයේ සිට වසර හතරක සිරදඬුවමක් විඳිමින් සිටියේය.",
        "මින් ඉදිරියට රාමනායක මහතා සමස්ත අධිකරණයම විවේචනාත්මක හෝ අවමන් සහගත ප්‍රකාශයක් නොකළ යුතුය යන කොන්දේසිය මත ජනාධිපති වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතා සමාව ලබා දීමේ ලේඛනයට ඊයේ අත්සන් තැබීමෙන් අනතුරුව මෙම නිදහස් කිරීම සිදු විය.",
        "කෙසේ වෙතත් කොන්දේසි සහිත සමාව ප්‍රේමදාස මහතා කනගාටුව ප්‍රකාශ කළේය. ට්විටර් පණිවුඩයක් නිකුත් කරමින් ඔහු රාමනායක මහතා නිදහස් කර ඇත්තේ ආණ්ඩුක්‍රම ව්‍යවස්ථාවේ 34 (1) (d) යටතේ මිස 34 (2) යටතේ නොවන බව සිය කණගාටුව ප්‍රකාශ කළේය.",
        "“ව්‍යවස්ථාවේ 34 (1) (ඈ) යටතේ ඔහුව නිදහස් කර ඇති බව දැනගැනීමෙන් කලකිරීමක් ඇති වන අතර එය හුදෙක් 34 (2) යටතේ ඔහුගේ ප්‍රජා සහ දේශපාලන අයිතිවාසිකම්වලට පූර්ණ සමාවක් ලබා දෙනවාට වඩා ඔහුගේ දඬුවම ලිහිල් කිරීමක් පමණි,” ප්‍රේමදාස ට්වීට් කළේය. “මෙයින් අදහස් කරන්නේ ඔහු දේශපාලන තනතුරු දැරීමට නුසුදුසු බවයි. සම්පූර්ණයෙන්ම කලකිරුණා! ” ඔහු කිව්වා.",
        "රාමනායක මහතා 2017 අගෝස්තු 21 වැනි දින මූලික වශයෙන් අරලියගහ මන්දිරයෙන් පිටතදී අධිකරණයට අපහාස වන ආකාරයේ ප්‍රකාශයන් කර තිබුණි. රටේ බහුතර විනිසුරුවරුන් සහ නීතිඥයන් දූෂිතයන් බවට ඔහු චෝදනා කළේය.",
        "2021 ජනවාරි 12 වැනි දින ශ්‍රේෂ්ඨාධිකරණය සිය තීන්දුව ප්‍රකාශයට පත් කළ අතර, අධිකරණයට අපහාස කිරීමේ වරදට ඔහු වරදකරු කරමින් ඔහුට වසර හතරක බරපතළ වැඩ සහිත සිර දඬුවමක් නියම කළේය.",
        "බ්‍රහස්පතින්දා අධිකරණයට දිවුරුම් ප්‍රකාශයක් ඉදිරිපත් කරමින් රන්ජන් රාමනායක ප්‍රකාශ කර ඇත්තේ 2017 අගෝස්තු 21 වැනිදා අරලියගහ මන්දිරයෙන් පිටතදී තමන් කළ ප්‍රකාශය ගැඹුරින් කල්පනා කර බලන විට තමන් කළ ප්‍රකාශය සම්පූර්ණයෙන් සහ සම්පූර්ණයෙන් අසත්‍ය, අවමන් සහගත සහ සමස්‌ත අධිකරණයට අපහාස කරන බව පිළිගන්නා බවයි. සහ නිහතමානීව සහ ගැඹුරින් සමාව අයැද සිටි අතර සමස්ත අධිකරණයෙන් සමාව ඉල්ලා සිටියේය.",
        "තවද, 2017 අගෝස්තු 21 දින තමන් කළ ප්‍රකාශය ඉල්ලා අස්කර නොගන්නා බවට පවසමින් ශ්‍රේෂ්ඨාධිකරණ පරිශ්‍රයෙන් පිටතදී කළ අපහාසාත්මක ප්‍රකාශය සම්බන්ධයෙන් ද රාමනායක මහතා සමාව ඉල්ලා සිටියේය.",
        "තම මුළු ජීවිත කාලය තුළම නැවත කිසි දිනෙක සමස්ත අධිකරණයට විවේචනාත්මක හෝ අවමන් සහගත ප්‍රකාශයක් නොකරන බවටද ඔහු සහතික විය."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "රජයේ",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "රන්ජන් රාමනායක",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "අවුරුදු 4 යි",
          "label": "DATE"
        },
        {
          "text": "වික්‍රමසිංහ",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "රාමනායක",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "රජයේ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "රන්ජන් රාමනායක",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඊයේ",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "සජිත් ප්‍රේමදාස",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "කම්කරු",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "මනූෂ නානායක්කාර",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "නලින් බණ්ඩාර",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "හර්ෂණ රාජකරුණා",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "වැලිකඩ",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "අවුරුදු හතරක්",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "2021 ජනවාරි",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඊයේ",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "රාමනායක",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ප්‍රේමදාස ය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ට්විටර්",
            "label": "PRODUCT"
          },
          {
            "text": "රාමනායක",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "34 ට අඩු",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "1",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ආණ්ඩුක්රම ව්යවස්ථාව",
            "label": "LAW"
          },
          {
            "text": "34",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "2",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "34 ට අඩු",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "1",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "34",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "2",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ප්‍රේමදාස ය",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "අරලියගහ මන්දිරය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "2017 අගෝස්තු 21",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රේෂ්ඨාධිකරණය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "2021 ජනවාරි 12",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "අවුරුදු හතරක්",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "බ්රහස්පතින්දා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "රන්ජන් රාමනායක",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "2017 අගෝස්තු 21",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "අධිකරණය",
            "label": "LOC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "රාමනායක",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රේෂ්ඨාධිකරණය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "2017 අගෝස්තු 21",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "අධිකරණය",
            "label": "LOC"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "முன்னாள் பாராளுமன்ற உறுப்பினரும் இராஜாங்க அமைச்சருமான ரஞ்சன் ராமநாயக்க 4 வருட கடூழிய சிறைத்தண்டனையிலிருந்து விடுவிக்கப்பட்ட பின்னர் விடுவிக்கப்பட்ட மனிதரை வெளியேற்றினார். எதிர்காலத்தில் முழு நீதித்துறையையும் விமர்சிக்கும் அல்லது இழிவுபடுத்தும் வகையில் எந்தவொரு அறிக்கையையும் ராமநாயக்க வெளியிடக்கூடாது என்ற நிபந்தனையுடன் ஜனாதிபதி விக்கிரமசிங்க நிபந்தனையுடன் மன்னிப்பு வழங்குகிறார்.",
      "author": "நிர்வாகி",
      "body_lines": [
        "முன்னாள் பாராளுமன்ற உறுப்பினரும் இராஜாங்க அமைச்சருமான ரஞ்சன் ராமநாயக்க, ஜனாதிபதி ரணில் விக்ரமசிங்கவின் நிபந்தனையுடன் கூடிய மன்னிப்பின் பின்னர் நேற்று சிறையிலிருந்து விடுவிக்கப்பட்டார்.",
        "அவரை வரவேற்க எதிர்க்கட்சித் தலைவர் சஜித் பிரேமதாச, தொழில் மற்றும் வெளிநாட்டு வேலைவாய்ப்பு அமைச்சர் மனுஷ நாணயக்கார, பாராளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர்களான நளின் பண்டார மற்றும் ஹர்ஷன ராஜகருணா ஆகியோர் வெலிக்கடை சிறைச்சாலைக்கு வெளியே ஆதரவாளர்களுடன் பிரசன்னமாகியிருந்தனர்.",
        "நீதிமன்றத்தை அவமதித்ததற்காக 2021 ஜனவரி முதல் நான்கு ஆண்டுகள் கடுங்காவல் சிறைத்தண்டனை அனுபவித்து வருபவர் ராமநாயக்க.",
        "எதிர்காலத்தில் முழு நீதித்துறையையும் விமர்சிக்கும் அல்லது இழிவுபடுத்தும் எந்தவொரு அறிக்கையையும் ராமநாயக்க வெளியிடக்கூடாது என்ற நிபந்தனையுடன் மன்னிப்பு வழங்கும் ஆவணத்தில் ஜனாதிபதி விக்ரமசிங்க நேற்று கையொப்பமிட்டதைத் தொடர்ந்து இந்த வெளியீடு வெளியிடப்பட்டுள்ளது.",
        "எனினும் நிபந்தனையுடன் கூடிய மன்னிப்பு பிரேமதாச வருத்தம் தெரிவித்தது. ட்விட்டரில் பதிவிட்டுள்ள அவர், அரசியலமைப்பின் 34 (1) (d) இன் கீழ் ராமநாயக்க விடுவிக்கப்பட்டார் என்றும் 34 (2) இன் கீழ் அல்ல என்றும் தனது ஏமாற்றத்தை வெளிப்படுத்தினார்.",
        "\"அரசியலமைப்பின் 34 (1) (d) இன் கீழ் அவர் விடுவிக்கப்பட்டார் என்பதை அறிந்து ஏமாற்றம் அடைந்தார், இது 34 (2) இன் கீழ் அவரது குடியுரிமை மற்றும் அரசியல் உரிமைகளுடன் முழுமையான மன்னிப்பைக் காட்டிலும் அவரது தண்டனையை நீக்குவதாகும்\" என்று பிரேமதாசா ட்வீட் செய்துள்ளார். “அதன் பொருள் அவர் அரசியல் பதவியை வகிக்க தகுதியற்றவர். முற்றிலும் ஏமாற்றம்! ” அவன் சொன்னான்.",
        "ராமநாயக்க 21 ஆகஸ்ட் 2017 அன்று அலரிமாளிகைக்கு வெளியே நீதித்துறையை அவமதிக்கும் வகையில் அறிக்கைகளை வெளியிட்டார். நாட்டில் உள்ள பெரும்பான்மையான நீதிபதிகள் மற்றும் வழக்கறிஞர்கள் ஊழல்வாதிகள் என்று அவர் குற்றம் சாட்டினார்.",
        "உச்ச நீதிமன்றம் 12 ஜனவரி 2021 அன்று தீர்ப்பை வழங்கியது, நீதிமன்ற அவமதிப்பு குற்றத்திற்காக அவருக்கு நான்கு ஆண்டுகள் கடுங்காவல் சிறைத்தண்டனை விதித்தது.",
        "வியாழன் அன்று நீதிமன்றத்தில் வாக்குமூலம் சமர்ப்பித்த ரஞ்சன் ராமநாயக்க, 2017 ஆகஸ்ட் 21 அன்று அலரிமாளிகைக்கு வெளியே தாம் கூறிய கூற்றை ஆழ்ந்து சிந்தித்துப் பார்க்கையில், தாம் கூறிய கருத்து முற்றிலும் பொய்யானதும், ஒட்டுமொத்த நீதித்துறையையும் அவமதிக்கும் வகையிலானது என்பதை ஒப்புக்கொள்கிறேன். மேலும் பணிவாகவும் ஆழமாகவும் மன்னிப்புக் கேட்டு ஒட்டுமொத்த நீதித்துறையின் மன்னிப்பையும் கோரினார்.",
        "மேலும், 2017 ஆகஸ்ட் 21 அன்று தான் வெளியிட்ட அறிக்கையை வாபஸ் பெறப் போவதில்லை எனக் கூறி உச்ச நீதிமன்ற வளாகத்திற்கு வெளியே தாம் கூறிய இழிவான அறிக்கைக்காகவும் ராமநாயக்க மன்னிப்பு கோரினார்.",
        "மேலும், தனது வாழ்நாளில், ஒட்டுமொத்த நீதித்துறையை விமர்சிக்கும் வகையில் அல்லது இழிவுபடுத்தும் வகையில் எந்த ஒரு அறிக்கையும் வெளியிடமாட்டேன் என்றும் அவர் உறுதியளித்தார்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "நிலை",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "ரஞ்சன் ராமநாயக்க",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "4 வருடம்",
          "label": "DATE"
        },
        {
          "text": "விக்கிரமசிங்க",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "ராமநாயக்க",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "நிலை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரஞ்சன் ராமநாயக்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "நேற்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "சஜித் பிரேமதாச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "தொழிலாளர்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "மனுஷ நாணயக்கார",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "நளின் பண்டார",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஹர்ஷன ராஜகருணா",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "வெலிக்கடை",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "நான்கு ஆண்டுகள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜனவரி 2021",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "நேற்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ராமநாயக்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பிரேமதாச",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ட்விட்டர்",
            "label": "PRODUCT"
          },
          {
            "text": "ராமநாயக்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "34 கீழ்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "1",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "அரசியலமைப்பு",
            "label": "LAW"
          },
          {
            "text": "34",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "2",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "34 கீழ்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "1",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "34",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "2",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "பிரேமதாச",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "கோவில் மரங்கள்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "21 ஆகஸ்ட் 2017",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "உச்ச நீதிமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "12 ஜனவரி 2021",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "நான்கு வருடங்கள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "வியாழன்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரஞ்சன் ராமநாயக்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "21 ஆகஸ்ட் 2017",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "நீதித்துறை",
            "label": "LOC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ராமநாயக்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "உச்ச நீதிமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "21 ஆகஸ்ட் 2017",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "நீதித்துறை",
            "label": "LOC"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}