{
  "newspaper_id": "daily-mirror-lk",
  "url": "https://www.dailymirror.lk/front_page/Sri-Lanka-to-use-another-US-70-M-from-Indian-credit-line-to-import-food/238-239743",
  "time_ut": 1656089762,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Sri Lanka to use another US $ 70 M  from Indian credit line to import food",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Sri Lanka to use another US $ 70 M  from Indian credit line to import food",
      "author": "",
      "body_lines": [
        "The recent economic, financial and humanitarian assistance  of over US$ 3.5 billion was guided by  ‘Neighbourhood First’ policy and Security and Growth for All in the  Region (SAGAR) vision of PM Narendra Modi",
        "The government has given approval to make use of another US $ 70 million from the US $ 1 billion Indian line of credit to import essential food items, a minister said.  Trade Minister Nalin Fernando told Daily Mirror that this would be in addition to US $ 180 million worth food commodities already imported from India under the same facility.",
        "Rice, sugar, onions and wheat (whole grain) are among the items already ordered to be delivered to the country.",
        "“Once we get these items, we will have food required for at least another couple of months. Besides, we got approval to use another US $ 70 million from the same credit facility to import food commodities in the near future,” he said.",
        "India has offered the US $ 1 billion credit facility to import food, pharmaceuticals and raw materials. Of the credit line, US $ 200 million was also released earlier to import fuel for the country.",
        "A delegation of senior Government of India officials led by Foreign Secretary Vinay Kwatra visited Sri Lanka on June 23. They held talks with President Gotabaya Rajapaksa and Prime Minister Ranil Wickremesinghe .   “The Indian delegation underscored that the unprecedented recent economic, financial and humanitarian assistance of over US$ 3.5 billion to the people of Sri Lanka was guided by ‘Neighbourhood First’ policy and Security and Growth for All in the Region (SAGAR) vision of Prime Minister Narendra Modi.",
        "During the call on President Gotabaya Rajapaksa, the Indian side thanked the President of Sri Lanka for his commitment to the development of India-Sri Lanka bilateral relations. Both sides had a productive exchange of views on the current economic situation in Sri Lanka as well as India’s ongoing support. In the meeting with Prime Minister Ranil Wickremesinghe, the two sides had an in-depth discussion on the Sri Lankan economy and efforts undertaken by the Government of Sri Lanka towards achieving economic recovery. In this context, both sides highlighted the importance of promoting India-Sri Lanka investment partnership including in the fields of infrastructure, connectivity, renewable energy and deepening economic linkages between the two countries.",
        "It may be recalled that development assistance extended by India stands at over USD 5 billion with more than USD 600 million being in grants, which include the Sri Lanka Unique Digital Identity Project. India continues to be the largest source of tourism for Sri Lanka,” the statement from the High Commission said."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Sri Lanka",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "US",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "Indian",
          "label": "NORP"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "US$ 3.5 billion",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "First",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "SAGAR",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Narendra",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "US",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "$ 70 million",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "$ 1 billion",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "Indian",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Nalin Fernando",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Daily Mirror",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "US",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "$ 180 million",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "India",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "at least another couple of months",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "US",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "$ 70 million",
            "label": "MONEY"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "India",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "US",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "$ 1 billion",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "US",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "$ 200 million",
            "label": "MONEY"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "India",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Vinay Kwatra",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "June 23",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Gotabaya Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Indian",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "US$ 3.5 billion",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "First",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "SAGAR",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Narendra Modi",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Gotabaya Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Indian",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "India",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "India",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "two",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lankan",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Government of Sri Lanka",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "India",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "two",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "India",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "over USD 5 billion",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Sri Lanka Unique Digital Identity Project",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "India",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the High Commission",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "ශ්‍රී ලංකාව ආහාර ආනයනය කිරීම සඳහා ඉන්දීය ණය මාර්ගයෙන් තවත් ඇමෙරිකානු ඩොලර් මිලියන 70ක් භාවිතා කරයි",
      "author": "",
      "body_lines": [
        "ඇමරිකානු ඩොලර් බිලියන 3.5කට අධික මෑතකාලීන ආර්ථික, මූල්‍ය සහ මානුෂීය ආධාර  මෙහෙයවනු ලැබුවේ  'අසල්වැසි ප්‍රථම' ප්‍රතිපත්තිය සහ අගමැති නරේන්ද්‍ර මෝදිගේ කලාපයේ සැමට ආරක්ෂාව සහ වර්ධනය (සාගර්) දැක්ම මගිනි.",
        "අත්‍යාවශ්‍ය ආහාර ද්‍රව්‍ය ආනයනය කිරීම සඳහා ඇමෙරිකානු ඩොලර් බිලියන 1ක ඉන්දීය ණය මාර්ගයෙන් තවත් ඇමෙරිකානු ඩොලර් මිලියන 70ක් භාවිතා කිරීමට රජය අනුමැතිය ලබා දී ඇති බව අමාත්‍යවරයෙක් පැවසීය. වෙළඳ අමාත්‍ය නලින් ප්‍රනාන්දු ඩේලි මිරර් වෙත කියා සිටියේ මෙම පහසුකම යටතේ දැනටමත් ඉන්දියාවෙන් ආනයනය කර ඇති ඇමරිකානු ඩොලර් මිලියන 180 ක් වටිනා ආහාර ද්‍රව්‍යවලට අමතරව මෙය වන බවයි.",
        "සහල්, සීනි, ළූණු සහ තිරිඟු (සම්පූර්ණ ධාන්‍ය) දැනටමත් රට වෙත ලබා දීමට ඇණවුම් කර ඇති භාණ්ඩ අතර වේ.",
        "“මේ බඩු ටික ගත්තම තව මාස දෙකකටවත් අවශ්‍ය කෑම අපිට ලැබෙනවා. ඊට අමතරව නුදුරු අනාගතයේ දී ආහාර ද්‍රව්‍ය ආනයනය කිරීම සඳහා එම ණය පහසුකමෙන් තවත් ඇමෙරිකානු ඩොලර් මිලියන 70ක් භාවිතා කිරීමට අපට අනුමැතිය ලැබුණා,” ඔහු පැවසීය.",
        "ආහාර, ඖෂධ සහ අමුද්‍රව්‍ය ආනයනය කිරීම සඳහා ඉන්දියාව ඇමෙරිකානු ඩොලර් බිලියනයක ණය පහසුකම ලබා දී ඇත. ණය මාර්ගයෙන් ඇමරිකානු ඩොලර් මිලියන 200ක් ද මීට පෙර රට සඳහා ඉන්ධන ආනයනය කිරීමට නිදහස් කරන ලදී.",
        "විදේශ ලේකම් විනේ ක්වාත්‍රා ප්‍රමුඛ ඉන්දීය රජයේ ජ්‍යෙෂ්ඨ නිලධාරීන් පිරිසක් ජූනි 23 වැනි දින ශ්‍රී ලංකාවට පැමිණි අතර ඔවුහු ජනාධිපති ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ මහතා සහ අගමැති රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතා සමඟ සාකච්ඡා කළහ. “ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ ජනතාවට පෙර නොවූ විරූ ලෙස මෑත කාලීනව ඇමරිකානු ඩොලර් බිලියන 3.5කට අධික ආර්ථික, මූල්‍ය සහ මානුෂීය ආධාර 'අසල්වැසි ප්‍රථම' ප්‍රතිපත්තිය සහ ප්‍රයිම්ගේ කලාපයේ සැමට ආරක්ෂාව සහ වර්ධනය (සාගර්) දැක්ම මගින් මඟ පෙන්වනු ලැබූ බව ඉන්දීය නියෝජිත පිරිස අවධාරනය කළහ. අමාත්‍ය නරේන්ද්‍ර මෝදි.",
        "ජනාධිපති ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ මහතා හමුවූ අවස්ථාවේදී ඉන්දීය පාර්ශවය ඉන්දීය ශ්‍රී ලංකා ද්විපාර්ශ්වික සබඳතා වර්ධනය කර ගැනීම සඳහා ශ්‍රී ලංකා ජනාධිපතිවරයා දක්වන කැපවීම පිළිබඳව ස්තුතිය පුද කළේය. ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ වත්මන් ආර්ථික තත්ත්වය මෙන්ම ඉන්දියාවේ අඛණ්ඩ සහයෝගය පිළිබඳව දෙපාර්ශවයම ඵලදායී අදහස් හුවමාරු කර ගත්හ. අග්‍රාමාත්‍ය රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතා සමඟ පැවති සාකච්ඡාවේදී දෙපාර්ශවය අතර ශ්‍රී ලංකා ආර්ථිකය සහ ආර්ථික ප්‍රකෘතිය සඳහා ශ්‍රී ලංකා රජය ගෙන ඇති ප්‍රයත්නයන් පිළිබඳව ගැඹුරින් සාකච්ඡා කර තිබේ. මෙම සන්දර්භය තුළ, යටිතල පහසුකම්, සම්බන්ධතා, පුනර්ජනනීය බලශක්ති සහ දෙරට අතර ආර්ථික සබඳතා ගැඹුරු කිරීම යන ක්ෂේත්‍ර ඇතුළුව ඉන්දියා-ශ්‍රී ලංකා ආයෝජන හවුල්කාරිත්වය ප්‍රවර්ධනය කිරීමේ වැදගත්කම දෙපාර්ශ්වයම අවධාරණය කළහ.",
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකා අනන්‍ය ඩිජිටල් අනන්‍යතා ව්‍යාපෘතිය ඇතුළුව ඩොලර් මිලියන 600 කට වැඩි ප්‍රදානයන් සමඟ ඉන්දියාව විසින් ලබා දෙන සංවර්ධන ආධාර ඩොලර් බිලියන 5 කට වඩා වැඩි බව සිහිපත් කළ හැකිය. ශ්‍රී ලංකාව සඳහා විශාලතම සංචාරක ප්‍රභවය ලෙස ඉන්දියාව දිගටම පවතිනවා,” මහ කොමසාරිස් කාර්යාලයේ ප්‍රකාශයේ සඳහන් වේ."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "එක්සත් ජනපදය",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "ඉන්දීය",
          "label": "NORP"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ඇමෙරිකානු ඩොලර් බිලියන 3.5 කි",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "පළමුවන",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "සාගර්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "නරේන්ද්‍ර",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "එක්සත් ජනපදය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඩොලර් මිලියන 70 කි",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඩොලර් බිලියන 1",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දීය",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "නලින් ප්‍රනාන්දු",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඩේලි මිරර්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "එක්සත් ජනපදය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඩොලර් මිලියන 180 කි",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "අවම වශයෙන් තවත් මාස කිහිපයක්",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "එක්සත් ජනපදය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඩොලර් මිලියන 70 කි",
            "label": "MONEY"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "එක්සත් ජනපදය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඩොලර් බිලියන 1",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "එක්සත් ජනපදය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඩොලර් මිලියන 200 කි",
            "label": "MONEY"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "විනේ ක්වාත්‍රා",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජූනි 23",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දීය",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඇමෙරිකානු ඩොලර් බිලියන 3.5 කි",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "පළමුවන",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "සාගර්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "නරේන්ද්‍ර මෝදි",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දීය",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "දෙක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලාංකික",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකා රජය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "දෙක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "USD බිලියන 5 කට වඩා",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකා අනන්‍ය ඩිජිටල් අනන්‍යතා ව්‍යාපෘතිය",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මහ කොමසාරිස්",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "உணவு இறக்குமதிக்கு இந்திய கடன் வரியிலிருந்து மேலும் 70 மில்லியன் அமெரிக்க டாலர்களை இலங்கை பயன்படுத்த உள்ளது",
      "author": "",
      "body_lines": [
        "சமீபத்திய பொருளாதார, நிதி மற்றும் மனிதாபிமான உதவி  3.5 பில்லியனுக்கும் அதிகமான அமெரிக்க டாலர்கள்  ‘அருகில் முதலில்’ கொள்கை மற்றும் பிரதமர் நரேந்திர மோடியின்  பிராந்தியத்தில் உள்ள அனைவருக்கும் பாதுகாப்பு மற்றும் வளர்ச்சி (SAGAR) பார்வையால் வழிநடத்தப்பட்டது.",
        "அத்தியாவசிய உணவுப் பொருட்களை இறக்குமதி செய்வதற்காக 1 பில்லியன் அமெரிக்க டாலர் இந்தியக் கடனிலிருந்து மேலும் 70 மில்லியன் அமெரிக்க டாலர்களைப் பயன்படுத்த அரசாங்கம் ஒப்புதல் அளித்துள்ளது என்று அமைச்சர் ஒருவர் தெரிவித்தார். இதே வசதியின் கீழ் ஏற்கனவே இந்தியாவில் இருந்து இறக்குமதி செய்யப்பட்ட 180 மில்லியன் அமெரிக்க டொலர் பெறுமதியான உணவுப் பொருட்களுக்கு மேலதிகமாக இது இருக்கும் என வர்த்தக அமைச்சர் நளின் பெர்னாண்டோ டெய்லி மிரருக்கு தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "அரிசி, சர்க்கரை, வெங்காயம் மற்றும் கோதுமை (முழு தானியங்கள்) ஆகியவை ஏற்கனவே நாட்டிற்கு வழங்க ஆர்டர் செய்யப்பட்ட பொருட்களில் அடங்கும்.",
        "“இந்தப் பொருட்கள் கிடைத்தவுடன், இன்னும் இரண்டு மாதங்களுக்குத் தேவையான உணவு எங்களிடம் இருக்கும். மேலும், அதே கடன் வசதியில் இருந்து மேலும் 70 மில்லியன் அமெரிக்க டாலர்களை உணவுப் பொருட்களை இறக்குமதி செய்வதற்குப் பயன்படுத்த அனுமதி கிடைத்துள்ளது,” என்றார்.",
        "உணவு, மருந்துகள் மற்றும் மூலப்பொருட்களை இறக்குமதி செய்ய 1 பில்லியன் டாலர் கடன் வசதியை இந்தியா வழங்கியுள்ளது. கடன் வரிசையில், நாட்டிற்கு எரிபொருளை இறக்குமதி செய்வதற்காக 200 மில்லியன் அமெரிக்க டாலர்களும் முன்னதாக வெளியிடப்பட்டது.",
        "வெளியுறவுச் செயலர் வினய் குவாத்ரா தலைமையிலான இந்திய அரசின் மூத்த அதிகாரிகளைக் கொண்ட குழு ஜூன் 23 அன்று இலங்கைக்கு விஜயம் செய்தது. அவர்கள் ஜனாதிபதி கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ஷ மற்றும் பிரதமர் ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க ஆகியோருடன் பேச்சுவார்த்தை நடத்தினர். \"இலங்கை மக்களுக்கு முன்னெப்போதும் இல்லாத வகையில் அண்மைக்காலமாக 3.5 பில்லியன் அமெரிக்க டொலர்கள் பொருளாதார, நிதி மற்றும் மனிதாபிமான உதவிகள் வழங்கப்பட்டுள்ளமை, 'அருகில் முதலில்' கொள்கை மற்றும் பிரதேசத்தில் உள்ள அனைவருக்கும் பாதுகாப்பு மற்றும் வளர்ச்சி (SAGAR) பார்வையால் வழிநடத்தப்பட்டது என்பதை இந்திய பிரதிநிதிகள் அடிக்கோடிட்டுக் காட்டினர். அமைச்சர் நரேந்திர மோடி.",
        "ஜனாதிபதி கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ஷவுடனான சந்திப்பின் போது, ​​இந்திய-இலங்கை இருதரப்பு உறவுகளை மேம்படுத்துவதற்கான அர்ப்பணிப்புக்காக இலங்கை ஜனாதிபதிக்கு இந்தியத் தரப்பு நன்றி தெரிவித்தது. இலங்கையின் தற்போதைய பொருளாதார நிலை மற்றும் இந்தியாவின் தற்போதைய ஆதரவு குறித்து இரு தரப்பினரும் ஆக்கப்பூர்வமான கருத்துக்களை பரிமாறிக் கொண்டனர். பிரதமர் ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்கவுடனான சந்திப்பில், இலங்கையின் பொருளாதாரம் மற்றும் பொருளாதார மீட்சியை அடைவதற்காக இலங்கை அரசாங்கம் மேற்கொண்டுள்ள முயற்சிகள் குறித்து இரு தரப்பினரும் ஆழமாக கலந்துரையாடினர். இந்தச் சூழலில், உள்கட்டமைப்பு, இணைப்பு, புதுப்பிக்கத்தக்க எரிசக்தி மற்றும் இரு நாடுகளுக்கு இடையேயான ஆழமான பொருளாதாரத் தொடர்புகள் உள்ளிட்ட துறைகளில் இந்தியா-இலங்கை முதலீட்டுப் பங்காளித்துவத்தை மேம்படுத்துவதன் முக்கியத்துவத்தை இரு தரப்பினரும் எடுத்துரைத்தனர்.",
        "இந்தியாவினால் வழங்கப்பட்ட அபிவிருத்தி உதவியானது 5 பில்லியன் அமெரிக்க டொலர்களுக்கு மேல் உள்ளதுடன், 600 மில்லியன் அமெரிக்க டொலர்களுக்கும் அதிகமான மானியங்கள் வழங்கப்பட்டுள்ளன. இலங்கைக்கான மிகப்பெரிய சுற்றுலா ஆதாரமாக இந்தியா தொடர்ந்தும் இருந்து வருகிறது” என உயர்ஸ்தானிகராலயத்தின் அறிக்கையில் தெரிவிக்கப்பட்டுள்ளது."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "இலங்கை",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "எங்களுக்கு",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "இந்தியன்",
          "label": "NORP"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "3.5 பில்லியன் அமெரிக்க டாலர்கள்",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "முதலில்",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "சாகர்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "நரேந்திரன்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "எங்களுக்கு",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "$ 70 மில்லியன்",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "$ 1 பில்லியன்",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்தியன்",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "நளின் பெர்னாண்டோ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "டெய்லி மிரர்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "எங்களுக்கு",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "$ 180 மில்லியன்",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்தியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "குறைந்தது இன்னும் இரண்டு மாதங்கள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "எங்களுக்கு",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "$ 70 மில்லியன்",
            "label": "MONEY"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இந்தியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "எங்களுக்கு",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "$ 1 பில்லியன்",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "எங்களுக்கு",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "$ 200 மில்லியன்",
            "label": "MONEY"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இந்தியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "வினய் குவாத்ரா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜூன் 23",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்தியன்",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "3.5 பில்லியன் அமெரிக்க டாலர்கள்",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "முதலில்",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "சாகர்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "நரேந்திர மோடி",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்தியன்",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்தியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்தியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இரண்டு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை அரசாங்கம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்தியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இரண்டு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இந்தியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "5 பில்லியன் அமெரிக்க டாலர்களுக்கு மேல்",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை தனித்துவ டிஜிட்டல் அடையாள திட்டம்",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்தியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "உயர் ஆணையம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  },
  "title": "Sri Lanka to use another US $ 70 M  from Indian credit line to import food",
  "body_lines": [
    "The recent economic, financial and humanitarian assistance  of over US$ 3.5 billion was guided by  ‘Neighbourhood First’ policy and Security and Growth for All in the  Region (SAGAR) vision of PM Narendra Modi",
    "The government has given approval to make use of another US $ 70 million from the US $ 1 billion Indian line of credit to import essential food items, a minister said.  Trade Minister Nalin Fernando told Daily Mirror that this would be in addition to US $ 180 million worth food commodities already imported from India under the same facility.",
    "Rice, sugar, onions and wheat (whole grain) are among the items already ordered to be delivered to the country.",
    "“Once we get these items, we will have food required for at least another couple of months. Besides, we got approval to use another US $ 70 million from the same credit facility to import food commodities in the near future,” he said.",
    "India has offered the US $ 1 billion credit facility to import food, pharmaceuticals and raw materials. Of the credit line, US $ 200 million was also released earlier to import fuel for the country.",
    "A delegation of senior Government of India officials led by Foreign Secretary Vinay Kwatra visited Sri Lanka on June 23. They held talks with President Gotabaya Rajapaksa and Prime Minister Ranil Wickremesinghe .   “The Indian delegation underscored that the unprecedented recent economic, financial and humanitarian assistance of over US$ 3.5 billion to the people of Sri Lanka was guided by ‘Neighbourhood First’ policy and Security and Growth for All in the Region (SAGAR) vision of Prime Minister Narendra Modi.",
    "During the call on President Gotabaya Rajapaksa, the Indian side thanked the President of Sri Lanka for his commitment to the development of India-Sri Lanka bilateral relations. Both sides had a productive exchange of views on the current economic situation in Sri Lanka as well as India’s ongoing support. In the meeting with Prime Minister Ranil Wickremesinghe, the two sides had an in-depth discussion on the Sri Lankan economy and efforts undertaken by the Government of Sri Lanka towards achieving economic recovery. In this context, both sides highlighted the importance of promoting India-Sri Lanka investment partnership including in the fields of infrastructure, connectivity, renewable energy and deepening economic linkages between the two countries.",
    "It may be recalled that development assistance extended by India stands at over USD 5 billion with more than USD 600 million being in grants, which include the Sri Lanka Unique Digital Identity Project. India continues to be the largest source of tourism for Sri Lanka,” the statement from the High Commission said."
  ],
  "translate": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Sri Lanka to use another US $ 70 M  from Indian credit line to import food",
      "author": "",
      "body_lines": [
        "The recent economic, financial and humanitarian assistance  of over US$ 3.5 billion was guided by  ‘Neighbourhood First’ policy and Security and Growth for All in the  Region (SAGAR) vision of PM Narendra Modi",
        "The government has given approval to make use of another US $ 70 million from the US $ 1 billion Indian line of credit to import essential food items, a minister said.  Trade Minister Nalin Fernando told Daily Mirror that this would be in addition to US $ 180 million worth food commodities already imported from India under the same facility.",
        "Rice, sugar, onions and wheat (whole grain) are among the items already ordered to be delivered to the country.",
        "“Once we get these items, we will have food required for at least another couple of months. Besides, we got approval to use another US $ 70 million from the same credit facility to import food commodities in the near future,” he said.",
        "India has offered the US $ 1 billion credit facility to import food, pharmaceuticals and raw materials. Of the credit line, US $ 200 million was also released earlier to import fuel for the country.",
        "A delegation of senior Government of India officials led by Foreign Secretary Vinay Kwatra visited Sri Lanka on June 23. They held talks with President Gotabaya Rajapaksa and Prime Minister Ranil Wickremesinghe .   “The Indian delegation underscored that the unprecedented recent economic, financial and humanitarian assistance of over US$ 3.5 billion to the people of Sri Lanka was guided by ‘Neighbourhood First’ policy and Security and Growth for All in the Region (SAGAR) vision of Prime Minister Narendra Modi.",
        "During the call on President Gotabaya Rajapaksa, the Indian side thanked the President of Sri Lanka for his commitment to the development of India-Sri Lanka bilateral relations. Both sides had a productive exchange of views on the current economic situation in Sri Lanka as well as India’s ongoing support. In the meeting with Prime Minister Ranil Wickremesinghe, the two sides had an in-depth discussion on the Sri Lankan economy and efforts undertaken by the Government of Sri Lanka towards achieving economic recovery. In this context, both sides highlighted the importance of promoting India-Sri Lanka investment partnership including in the fields of infrastructure, connectivity, renewable energy and deepening economic linkages between the two countries.",
        "It may be recalled that development assistance extended by India stands at over USD 5 billion with more than USD 600 million being in grants, which include the Sri Lanka Unique Digital Identity Project. India continues to be the largest source of tourism for Sri Lanka,” the statement from the High Commission said."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Sri Lanka",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "US",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "Indian",
          "label": "NORP"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "US$ 3.5 billion",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "First",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "SAGAR",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Narendra",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "US",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "$ 70 million",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "$ 1 billion",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "Indian",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Nalin Fernando",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Daily Mirror",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "US",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "$ 180 million",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "India",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "at least another couple of months",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "US",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "$ 70 million",
            "label": "MONEY"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "India",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "US",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "$ 1 billion",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "US",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "$ 200 million",
            "label": "MONEY"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "India",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Vinay Kwatra",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "June 23",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Gotabaya Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Indian",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "US$ 3.5 billion",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "First",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "SAGAR",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Narendra Modi",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Gotabaya Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Indian",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "India",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "India",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "two",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lankan",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Government of Sri Lanka",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "India",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "two",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "India",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "over USD 5 billion",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Sri Lanka Unique Digital Identity Project",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "India",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the High Commission",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "ශ්‍රී ලංකාව ආහාර ආනයනය කිරීම සඳහා ඉන්දීය ණය මාර්ගයෙන් තවත් ඇමෙරිකානු ඩොලර් මිලියන 70ක් භාවිතා කරයි",
      "author": "",
      "body_lines": [
        "ඇමරිකානු ඩොලර් බිලියන 3.5කට අධික මෑතකාලීන ආර්ථික, මූල්‍ය සහ මානුෂීය ආධාර  මෙහෙයවනු ලැබුවේ  'අසල්වැසි ප්‍රථම' ප්‍රතිපත්තිය සහ අගමැති නරේන්ද්‍ර මෝදිගේ කලාපයේ සැමට ආරක්ෂාව සහ වර්ධනය (සාගර්) දැක්ම මගිනි.",
        "අත්‍යාවශ්‍ය ආහාර ද්‍රව්‍ය ආනයනය කිරීම සඳහා ඇමෙරිකානු ඩොලර් බිලියන 1ක ඉන්දීය ණය මාර්ගයෙන් තවත් ඇමෙරිකානු ඩොලර් මිලියන 70ක් භාවිතා කිරීමට රජය අනුමැතිය ලබා දී ඇති බව අමාත්‍යවරයෙක් පැවසීය. වෙළඳ අමාත්‍ය නලින් ප්‍රනාන්දු ඩේලි මිරර් වෙත කියා සිටියේ මෙම පහසුකම යටතේ දැනටමත් ඉන්දියාවෙන් ආනයනය කර ඇති ඇමරිකානු ඩොලර් මිලියන 180 ක් වටිනා ආහාර ද්‍රව්‍යවලට අමතරව මෙය වන බවයි.",
        "සහල්, සීනි, ළූණු සහ තිරිඟු (සම්පූර්ණ ධාන්‍ය) දැනටමත් රට වෙත ලබා දීමට ඇණවුම් කර ඇති භාණ්ඩ අතර වේ.",
        "“මේ බඩු ටික ගත්තම තව මාස දෙකකටවත් අවශ්‍ය කෑම අපිට ලැබෙනවා. ඊට අමතරව නුදුරු අනාගතයේ දී ආහාර ද්‍රව්‍ය ආනයනය කිරීම සඳහා එම ණය පහසුකමෙන් තවත් ඇමෙරිකානු ඩොලර් මිලියන 70ක් භාවිතා කිරීමට අපට අනුමැතිය ලැබුණා,” ඔහු පැවසීය.",
        "ආහාර, ඖෂධ සහ අමුද්‍රව්‍ය ආනයනය කිරීම සඳහා ඉන්දියාව ඇමෙරිකානු ඩොලර් බිලියනයක ණය පහසුකම ලබා දී ඇත. ණය මාර්ගයෙන් ඇමරිකානු ඩොලර් මිලියන 200ක් ද මීට පෙර රට සඳහා ඉන්ධන ආනයනය කිරීමට නිදහස් කරන ලදී.",
        "විදේශ ලේකම් විනේ ක්වාත්‍රා ප්‍රමුඛ ඉන්දීය රජයේ ජ්‍යෙෂ්ඨ නිලධාරීන් පිරිසක් ජූනි 23 වැනි දින ශ්‍රී ලංකාවට පැමිණි අතර ඔවුහු ජනාධිපති ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ මහතා සහ අගමැති රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතා සමඟ සාකච්ඡා කළහ. “ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ ජනතාවට පෙර නොවූ විරූ ලෙස මෑත කාලීනව ඇමරිකානු ඩොලර් බිලියන 3.5කට අධික ආර්ථික, මූල්‍ය සහ මානුෂීය ආධාර 'අසල්වැසි ප්‍රථම' ප්‍රතිපත්තිය සහ ප්‍රයිම්ගේ කලාපයේ සැමට ආරක්ෂාව සහ වර්ධනය (සාගර්) දැක්ම මගින් මඟ පෙන්වනු ලැබූ බව ඉන්දීය නියෝජිත පිරිස අවධාරනය කළහ. අමාත්‍ය නරේන්ද්‍ර මෝදි.",
        "ජනාධිපති ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ මහතා හමුවූ අවස්ථාවේදී ඉන්දීය පාර්ශවය ඉන්දීය ශ්‍රී ලංකා ද්විපාර්ශ්වික සබඳතා වර්ධනය කර ගැනීම සඳහා ශ්‍රී ලංකා ජනාධිපතිවරයා දක්වන කැපවීම පිළිබඳව ස්තුතිය පුද කළේය. ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ වත්මන් ආර්ථික තත්ත්වය මෙන්ම ඉන්දියාවේ අඛණ්ඩ සහයෝගය පිළිබඳව දෙපාර්ශවයම ඵලදායී අදහස් හුවමාරු කර ගත්හ. අග්‍රාමාත්‍ය රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතා සමඟ පැවති සාකච්ඡාවේදී දෙපාර්ශවය අතර ශ්‍රී ලංකා ආර්ථිකය සහ ආර්ථික ප්‍රකෘතිය සඳහා ශ්‍රී ලංකා රජය ගෙන ඇති ප්‍රයත්නයන් පිළිබඳව ගැඹුරින් සාකච්ඡා කර තිබේ. මෙම සන්දර්භය තුළ, යටිතල පහසුකම්, සම්බන්ධතා, පුනර්ජනනීය බලශක්ති සහ දෙරට අතර ආර්ථික සබඳතා ගැඹුරු කිරීම යන ක්ෂේත්‍ර ඇතුළුව ඉන්දියා-ශ්‍රී ලංකා ආයෝජන හවුල්කාරිත්වය ප්‍රවර්ධනය කිරීමේ වැදගත්කම දෙපාර්ශ්වයම අවධාරණය කළහ.",
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකා අනන්‍ය ඩිජිටල් අනන්‍යතා ව්‍යාපෘතිය ඇතුළුව ඩොලර් මිලියන 600 කට වැඩි ප්‍රදානයන් සමඟ ඉන්දියාව විසින් ලබා දෙන සංවර්ධන ආධාර ඩොලර් බිලියන 5 කට වඩා වැඩි බව සිහිපත් කළ හැකිය. ශ්‍රී ලංකාව සඳහා විශාලතම සංචාරක ප්‍රභවය ලෙස ඉන්දියාව දිගටම පවතිනවා,” මහ කොමසාරිස් කාර්යාලයේ ප්‍රකාශයේ සඳහන් වේ."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "එක්සත් ජනපදය",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "ඉන්දීය",
          "label": "NORP"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ඇමෙරිකානු ඩොලර් බිලියන 3.5 කි",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "පළමුවන",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "සාගර්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "නරේන්ද්‍ර",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "එක්සත් ජනපදය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඩොලර් මිලියන 70 කි",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඩොලර් බිලියන 1",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දීය",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "නලින් ප්‍රනාන්දු",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඩේලි මිරර්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "එක්සත් ජනපදය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඩොලර් මිලියන 180 කි",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "අවම වශයෙන් තවත් මාස කිහිපයක්",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "එක්සත් ජනපදය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඩොලර් මිලියන 70 කි",
            "label": "MONEY"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "එක්සත් ජනපදය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඩොලර් බිලියන 1",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "එක්සත් ජනපදය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඩොලර් මිලියන 200 කි",
            "label": "MONEY"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "විනේ ක්වාත්‍රා",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජූනි 23",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දීය",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඇමෙරිකානු ඩොලර් බිලියන 3.5 කි",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "පළමුවන",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "සාගර්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "නරේන්ද්‍ර මෝදි",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දීය",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "දෙක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලාංකික",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකා රජය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "දෙක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "USD බිලියන 5 කට වඩා",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකා අනන්‍ය ඩිජිටල් අනන්‍යතා ව්‍යාපෘතිය",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මහ කොමසාරිස්",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "உணவு இறக்குமதிக்கு இந்திய கடன் வரியிலிருந்து மேலும் 70 மில்லியன் அமெரிக்க டாலர்களை இலங்கை பயன்படுத்த உள்ளது",
      "author": "",
      "body_lines": [
        "சமீபத்திய பொருளாதார, நிதி மற்றும் மனிதாபிமான உதவி  3.5 பில்லியனுக்கும் அதிகமான அமெரிக்க டாலர்கள்  ‘அருகில் முதலில்’ கொள்கை மற்றும் பிரதமர் நரேந்திர மோடியின்  பிராந்தியத்தில் உள்ள அனைவருக்கும் பாதுகாப்பு மற்றும் வளர்ச்சி (SAGAR) பார்வையால் வழிநடத்தப்பட்டது.",
        "அத்தியாவசிய உணவுப் பொருட்களை இறக்குமதி செய்வதற்காக 1 பில்லியன் அமெரிக்க டாலர் இந்தியக் கடனிலிருந்து மேலும் 70 மில்லியன் அமெரிக்க டாலர்களைப் பயன்படுத்த அரசாங்கம் ஒப்புதல் அளித்துள்ளது என்று அமைச்சர் ஒருவர் தெரிவித்தார். இதே வசதியின் கீழ் ஏற்கனவே இந்தியாவில் இருந்து இறக்குமதி செய்யப்பட்ட 180 மில்லியன் அமெரிக்க டொலர் பெறுமதியான உணவுப் பொருட்களுக்கு மேலதிகமாக இது இருக்கும் என வர்த்தக அமைச்சர் நளின் பெர்னாண்டோ டெய்லி மிரருக்கு தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "அரிசி, சர்க்கரை, வெங்காயம் மற்றும் கோதுமை (முழு தானியங்கள்) ஆகியவை ஏற்கனவே நாட்டிற்கு வழங்க ஆர்டர் செய்யப்பட்ட பொருட்களில் அடங்கும்.",
        "“இந்தப் பொருட்கள் கிடைத்தவுடன், இன்னும் இரண்டு மாதங்களுக்குத் தேவையான உணவு எங்களிடம் இருக்கும். மேலும், அதே கடன் வசதியில் இருந்து மேலும் 70 மில்லியன் அமெரிக்க டாலர்களை உணவுப் பொருட்களை இறக்குமதி செய்வதற்குப் பயன்படுத்த அனுமதி கிடைத்துள்ளது,” என்றார்.",
        "உணவு, மருந்துகள் மற்றும் மூலப்பொருட்களை இறக்குமதி செய்ய 1 பில்லியன் டாலர் கடன் வசதியை இந்தியா வழங்கியுள்ளது. கடன் வரிசையில், நாட்டிற்கு எரிபொருளை இறக்குமதி செய்வதற்காக 200 மில்லியன் அமெரிக்க டாலர்களும் முன்னதாக வெளியிடப்பட்டது.",
        "வெளியுறவுச் செயலர் வினய் குவாத்ரா தலைமையிலான இந்திய அரசின் மூத்த அதிகாரிகளைக் கொண்ட குழு ஜூன் 23 அன்று இலங்கைக்கு விஜயம் செய்தது. அவர்கள் ஜனாதிபதி கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ஷ மற்றும் பிரதமர் ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க ஆகியோருடன் பேச்சுவார்த்தை நடத்தினர். \"இலங்கை மக்களுக்கு முன்னெப்போதும் இல்லாத வகையில் அண்மைக்காலமாக 3.5 பில்லியன் அமெரிக்க டொலர்கள் பொருளாதார, நிதி மற்றும் மனிதாபிமான உதவிகள் வழங்கப்பட்டுள்ளமை, 'அருகில் முதலில்' கொள்கை மற்றும் பிரதேசத்தில் உள்ள அனைவருக்கும் பாதுகாப்பு மற்றும் வளர்ச்சி (SAGAR) பார்வையால் வழிநடத்தப்பட்டது என்பதை இந்திய பிரதிநிதிகள் அடிக்கோடிட்டுக் காட்டினர். அமைச்சர் நரேந்திர மோடி.",
