{
  "newspaper_id": "virakesari-lk",
  "url": "http://www.virakesari.lk/article/131811",
  "time_ut": 1658226791,
  "original_lang": "ta",
  "original_title": "பொதுஜன பெரமுனவின் இளைஞர் அணியின் ஆதரவு ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்கவிற்கு - டி.வி.சானக",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Podujana Peramuna's youth team support for Ranil Wickramasinghe - TV Chanaka",
      "author": "T. Saranya",
      "body_lines": [
        "The youth wing of Sri Lanka Podujana Peramuna has decided to vote for the candidate nominated by Podujana Peramuna during the new presidential election.",
        "Member of Parliament T.V. Sanaka said that this decision was taken during the Central Executive Committee meeting of the Youth League of Sri Lanka Podujana Peramuna.",
        "He also mentioned that all the members of the youth team have agreed to the decision of Sri Lanka Podujana Peramuna to support Ranil Wickremesinghe.",
        "Podujana Peramuna General Secretary Sagara Kariyawasam has announced that he will support the nomination of President Ranil Wickremesinghe for the post of President.",
        "Meanwhile, while Dines Gunawardena, the Speaker of the House, Ranil Wickramasinghe was nominated for the post of President, Member of Parliament Manusha Nanayakkara confirmed it. However, it is noteworthy that the other side of the Podujana Peramuna has declared its support for the Dallas beauty."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Podujana Peramuna's",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "Ranil Wickramasinghe - TV Chanaka",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "Podujana Peramuna",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Podujana Peramuna",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Parliament T.V. Sanaka",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Central Executive Committee",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Youth League of Sri",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Podujana Peramuna",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "Podujana Peramuna",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Podujana Peramuna",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sagara Kariyawasam",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Dines Gunawardena",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "House",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickramasinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament Manusha Nanayakkara",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Podujana Peramuna",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "Dallas",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "පොදුජන පෙරමුණේ තරුණ කණ්ඩායමේ සහය රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහට - ටීවී චානක",
      "author": "T. Saranya",
      "body_lines": [
        "නව ජනාධිපතිවරණයේදී ශ්‍රී ලංකා පොදුජන පෙරමුණ විසින් නම් කරන අපේක්ෂකයාට ඡන්දය ප්‍රකාශ කිරීමට ශ්‍රී ලංකා පොදුජන පෙරමුණේ තරුණ සංවිධානය තීරණය කර තිබේ.",
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකා පොදුජන පෙරමුණේ තරුණ සංගමයේ මධ්‍යම විධායක කමිටු රැස්වීමේදී මෙම තීරණය ගත් බවයි පාර්ලිමේන්තු මන්ත්‍රී ටීවී සනක කියා සිටියේ.",
        "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතාට සහය දැක්වීමට ශ්‍රී ලංකා පොදුජන පෙරමුණ ගත් තීරණයට තරුණ කණ්ඩායමේ සියලු දෙනා එකඟ වී ඇති බවද ඔහු සඳහන් කළේය.",
        "පොදුජන පෙරමුණේ ප්‍රධාන ලේකම් සාගර කාරියවසම් මහතා ජනාධිපති ධූරයට රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතා නම් කිරීමට සහාය දෙන බව ප්‍රකාශ කළේය.",
        "මේ අතර, සභාපති ධූරය සඳහා පාර්ලිමේන්තුවේ කථානායක දිනේස් ගුණවර්ධන, රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහගේ නම යෝජනා වූ අතර, පාර්ලිමේන්තු මන්ත්‍රී මනූෂ නානායක්කාර එය තහවුරු කළා. කෙසේ වෙතත් ඩලස් සුරූපිනියට පොදුජන පෙරමුණේ අනෙක් පාර්ශ්වය සහය පළ කර තිබීම විශේෂත්වයක්."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "පොදුජන පෙරමුණේ",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ - ටීවී චානක",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "පොදුජන පෙරමුණ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "පොදුජන පෙරමුණ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තු ටී.වී.සනක",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "මධ්යම විධායක කමිටුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී තරුණ සංගමය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "පොදුජන පෙරමුණ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "පොදුජන පෙරමුණ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "පොදුජන පෙරමුණ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "සාගර කාරියවසම්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ඩයිනස් ගුණවර්ධන",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "නිවස",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තු මනූෂ නානායක්කාර",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "පොදුජන පෙරමුණ",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඩලස්",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "பொதுஜன பெரமுனவின் இளைஞர் அணியின் ஆதரவு ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்கவிற்கு - டி.வி.சானக",
      "author": "T. Saranya",
      "body_lines": [
        "ஸ்ரீலங்கா பொதுஜன பெரமுனவின் இளைஞர் அணி புதிய ஜனாதிபதி தேர்தலின் போது பொதுஜன பெரமுனவால் பரிந்துரைக்கப்படும் வேட்பாளருக்கு வாக்களிக்க தீர்மானித்துள்ளது.",
        "ஸ்ரீலங்கா பொதுஜன பெரமுனவின் இளைஞர் அணி மத்திய செயற்குழு கூட்டத்தின் போது இந்த தீர்மானம் எடுக்கப்பட்டதாக , பாராளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர் டி.வி.சானக தெரிவித்துள்ளார்.",
        "அதற்கமைய ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்கவுக்கு ஆதரவளிக்கும் ஸ்ரீலங்கா பொதுஜன பெரமுனவின் தீர்மானத்திற்கு இளைஞர் அணி உறுப்பினர்கள் அனைவரும் இணக்கம் தெரிவித்துள்ளதாகவும் அவர் குறிப்பிட்டுள்ளார்.",
        "ஜனாதிபதி பதவிக்கு பதில் ஜனாதிபதி ரணில் விக்ரமசிங்கவை முன்னிறுத்துவதற்கு ஆதரவு வழங்குவதாக பொதுஜன பெரமுனவின் பொதுச் செயலாளர் சாகர காரியவசம்  அறிவித்துள்ளார்.",
        "அதற்கமைய நேற்றைய தினம் சபை முதல்வரான தினேஸ் குணவர்தன ரணில் விக்ரமசிங்கவை ஜனாதிபதி பதவிக்கு முன்மொழிந்த அதேவேளை, பாராளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர் மனுஷ நாணயக்கார அதனை உறுதிப்படுத்தினார். எவ்வாறாயினும், பொதுஜன பெரமுனவின் மற்றைய தரப்பு டலஸ் அழகப்பெருமவை ஆதரிப்பதாக அறிவித்துள்ளமை குறிப்பிடத்தக்கது."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "பொதுஜன பெரமுனவின்",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க - டி.வி.சானக்க",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "பொதுஜன பெரமுன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "பொதுஜன பெரமுன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம் டி.வி.சானக",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "மத்திய செயற்குழு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஸ்ரீ இளைஞர் கழகம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "பொதுஜன பெரமுன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "பொதுஜன பெரமுன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பொதுஜன பெரமுன",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "சாகர காரியவசம்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "டைன்ஸ் குணவர்தன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "வீடு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்ற மனுஷ நாணயக்கார",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "பொதுஜன பெரமுனா",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "டல்லாஸ்",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}