{
  "newspaper_id": "daily-mirror-lk",
  "url": "https://www.dailymirror.lk/breaking_news/China-asks-India-to-stop-disturbing-its-exchange-with-SL/108-242645",
  "time_ut": 1659970653,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "China asks India to ’’stop disturbing’’ its exchange with SL",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "China asks India to ’’stop disturbing’’ its exchange with SL",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "Riled by Sri Lanka's request to defer the planned docking of a high-tech Chinese research vessel at the strategic Hambantota Port, China on Monday took a dig at India, saying it was \"senseless to pressure\" Colombo by citing the issue of security concerns.",
        "According to reports from Colombo, Sri Lanka has asked Beijing to defer the arrival of the Chinese space and satellite tracking research vessel 'Yuan Wang 5' which was scheduled to dock at the Hambantota Port from August 11 to 17 due to security concerns expressed by India.",
        "Responding to the reports, Chinese Foreign Ministry spokesman Wang Wenbin told a media briefing here that Beijing has taken note of the reports and asserted that \"the cooperation between China and Sri Lanka is independently chosen by the two countries and meets common interests. It does not target any third party\".",
        "It is \"senseless to pressure Sri Lanka\" by citing the issue of security concerns, he said, in reference to the reports that Sri Lanka's move was attributed to concerns expressed by India.",
        "\"Sri Lanka is a sovereign state. It can develop relations with other countries in the light of its own development interests,\" he said.",
        "\"China urges relevant parties to see China's scientific explorations in a reasonable and sensible way and stop disturbing the normal exchange between China and Sri Lanka,\" Mr Wang said.",
        "Sri Lanka is a transport hub in the Indian Ocean. Many scientific exploration ships including those from China have stopped at the port of Sri Lanka for resupplies, he said. \"China has always exercised the freedom of navigation in the high seas and fully respects the jurisdiction of coastal states for the scientific exploration activities within their waters,\" he said.",
        "According to media reports, India informed Sri Lanka that the docking of the high-tech Chinese research vessel could pose a threat to its national security.",
        "Sri Lanka received strong messages of protests from India as the ship was said to have the capability to track satellites and intercontinental ballistic missiles, the reports said.",
        "India has said it carefully monitors any development having a bearing on its security and economic interests.",
        "\"We are aware of reports of a proposed visit by this vessel to Hambantota in August,\" External Affairs Ministry Spokesperson Arindam Bagchi said in New Delhi when asked about the reports of a proposed visit by the Chinese vessel.",
        "\"The government carefully monitors any development having a bearing on India's security and economic interests and takes all necessary measures to safeguard them,\" he said last month.",
        "Reports from Colombo on Sunday said China's embassy in the country sought an urgent meeting with senior Sri Lankan authorities after Colombo sought deferment in the planned docking of the research vessel.",
        "Some Sri Lankan news portals also reported that the country's President Ranil Wickremesinghe held a closed-door meeting with China's Ambassador Qi Zhenhong after Colombo sought the deferment of the planned docking.",
        "On July 12, amidst the political turmoil in Sri Lanka, the previous government approved the Chinese vessel's docking at the Hambantota port.(Agencies)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "China",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "India",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka's",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Chinese",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Hambantota Port",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "China",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Monday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "India",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Colombo",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Beijing",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Chinese",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Yuan Wang",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Hambantota Port",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "August 11 to 17",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "India",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Chinese Foreign Ministry",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Wang Wenbin",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Beijing",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "China",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "two",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "third",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka's",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "India",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "LOC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "China",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "China",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "China",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Wang",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Indian Ocean",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "China",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "China",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "India",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Chinese",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "India",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "India",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Hambantota",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "August",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "External Affairs Ministry",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Spokesperson Arindam Bagchi",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "New Delhi",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Chinese",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "India",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "last month",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sunday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "China",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lankan",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "Colombo",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "China",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Qi Zhenhong",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Colombo",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "July 12",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Chinese",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Hambantota",
            "label": "LOC"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "චීනය ඉන්දියාවෙන් ඉල්ලා සිටින්නේ ශ්‍රී ලංකාව සමඟ තම හුවමාරුව \"අවුල් කිරීම නවත්වන ලෙස\" ය",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "චීනයේ උපායමාර්ගික හම්බන්තොට වරායේ අධි තාක්‍ෂණික චීන පර්යේෂණ යාත්‍රාවක් නැව්ගත කිරීම කල් දැමීමට ශ්‍රී ලංකාව කළ ඉල්ලීමෙන් කෝපයට පත් චීනය සඳුදා ඉන්දියාවට හාස්‍යයක් ඇති කරමින් කියා සිටියේ ආරක්ෂාව පිළිබඳ ප්‍රශ්නය සඳහන් කරමින් කොළඹට බලපෑම් කිරීම තේරුමක් නැති බවය.",
        "කොළඹින් ලැබෙන වාර්තාවලට අනුව, ඉන්දියාව විසින් ප්‍රකාශ කරන ලද ආරක්ෂක ගැටළු හේතුවෙන් අගෝස්තු 11 සිට 17 දක්වා හම්බන්තොට වරායේ නැව්ගත කිරීමට නියමිතව තිබූ චීන අභ්‍යවකාශ සහ චන්ද්‍රිකා ලුහුබැඳීමේ පර්යේෂණ යාත්‍රාව වන 'යුවාන් වැන්ග් 5' පැමිණීම කල් දමන ලෙස ශ්‍රී ලංකාව බීජිං වෙතින් ඉල්ලා තිබේ. .",
        "මෙම වාර්තාවලට ප්‍රතිචාර දක්වමින් චීන විදේශ අමාත්‍යාංශයේ ප්‍රකාශක වැන්ග් වෙන්බින් මෙහි පැවති මාධ්‍ය හමුවකදී කියා සිටියේ බීජිං එම වාර්තා සැලකිල්ලට ගෙන ඇති අතර \"චීනය සහ ශ්‍රී ලංකාව අතර සහයෝගීතාවය දෙරට විසින් ස්වාධීනව තෝරාගෙන ඇති අතර පොදු අවශ්‍යතා සපුරාලන බවයි. එය එසේ නොවේ. ඕනෑම තෙවන පාර්ශවයක් ඉලක්ක කරන්න\"",
        "ආරක්‍ෂාව පිළිබඳ ප්‍රශ්නය උපුටා දක්වමින් ශ්‍රී ලංකාවට බලපෑම් කිරීම තේරුමක් නැති ක්‍රියාවක් බවත්, ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ මෙම පියවර ඉන්දියාව විසින් ප්‍රකාශ කරන ලද කනස්සල්ලට හේතු වූ බවට පළ වූ වාර්තා ගැන සඳහන් කරමින් ඔහු පැවසීය.",
        "\"ශ්‍රී ලංකාව ස්වෛරී රාජ්‍යයක්. එයට තම සංවර්ධන අවශ්‍යතා අනුව අනෙකුත් රටවල් සමඟ සබඳතා වර්ධනය කර ගත හැකිය,\" ඔහු පැවසීය.",
        "\"චීනයේ විද්‍යාත්මක ගවේෂණ සාධාරණ හා සංවේදී ආකාරයෙන් දැකීමටත් චීනය සහ ශ්‍රී ලංකාව අතර සාමාන්‍ය හුවමාරුවට බාධා කිරීම නවත්වන ලෙසත් චීනය අදාළ පාර්ශවයන්ගෙන් ඉල්ලා සිටී,\" වැන්ග් මහතා පැවසීය.",
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකාව ඉන්දියන් සාගරයේ ප්‍රවාහන මධ්‍යස්ථානයකි. චීනය ඇතුළු බොහෝ විද්‍යාත්මක ගවේෂණ නෞකා නැවත සැපයුම් සඳහා ශ්‍රී ලංකා වරායේ නතර කර ඇති බව ඔහු පැවසීය. \"චීනය සෑම විටම මහ මුහුදේ යාත්‍රා කිරීමේ නිදහස භාවිතා කර ඇති අතර වෙරළබඩ රාජ්‍යයන් ඔවුන්ගේ ජලය තුළ විද්‍යාත්මක ගවේෂණ කටයුතු සඳහා අධිකරණ බලයට සම්පූර්ණයෙන්ම ගරු කරයි,\" ඔහු පැවසීය.",
        "මාධ්‍ය වාර්තාවලට අනුව, අධි තාක්‍ෂණික චීන පර්යේෂණ යාත්‍රාව නැව්ගත කිරීම තම ජාතික ආරක්ෂාවට තර්ජනයක් විය හැකි බව ඉන්දියාව ශ්‍රී ලංකාවට දන්වා සිටියේය.",
        "චන්ද්‍රිකා සහ අන්තර් මහද්වීපික බැලස්ටික් මිසයිල නිරීක්ෂණය කිරීමේ හැකියාව මෙම නෞකාවට ඇති බව පැවසීම නිසා ඉන්දියාවෙන් ශ්‍රී ලංකාවට දැඩි විරෝධතා පණිවිඩයක් ලැබුණු බව වාර්තාවේ.",
        "ඉන්දියාව පවසා ඇත්තේ තම ආරක්‍ෂාව සහ ආර්ථික අවශ්‍යතා කෙරෙහි බලපාන ඕනෑම වර්ධනයක් පරෙස්සමින් නිරීක්‍ෂණය කරන බවයි.",
        "\"මෙම යාත්‍රාව අගෝස්තු මාසයේදී හම්බන්තොටට යෝජිත සංචාරයක් පිළිබඳ වාර්තා පිළිබඳව අපි දනිමු,\" විදේශ කටයුතු අමාත්‍යාංශයේ ප්‍රකාශක Arindam Bagchi නවදිල්ලියේ දී පැවසුවේ චීන යාත්‍රාවේ යෝජිත සංචාරයක වාර්තා පිළිබඳව විමසූ විට ය.",
        "“ඉන්දියාවේ ආරක්‍ෂාව සහ ආර්ථික අවශ්‍යතා කෙරෙහි බලපාන ඕනෑම සංවර්ධනයක් රජය පරෙස්සමින් නිරීක්‍ෂණය කරන අතර ඒවා ආරක්‍ෂා කිරීමට අවශ්‍ය සියලු පියවර ගනී,” ඔහු පසුගිය මාසයේ පැවසීය.",
        "පර්යේෂන යාත්‍රාව සැලසුම්ගත නැව්ගත කිරීම කල්දැමීමට කොළඹ ඉල්ලා සිටීමෙන් පසු, රටේ චීන තානාපති කාර්යාලය ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ ජ්‍යෙෂ්ඨ බලධාරීන් සමඟ හදිසි සාකච්ඡාවක් ඉල්ලා ඇති බව ඉරිදා කොළඹින් වාර්තා විය.",
        "ඇතැම් ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ ප්‍රවෘත්ති ද්වාර ද වාර්තා කළේ, කොළඹ සැලසුම් කර ඇති නැව්ගත කිරීම කල් දැමීමෙන් පසුව, රටේ ජනාධිපති රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ, චීන තානාපති Qi Zhenhong සමඟ සංවෘත දොරේ රැස්වීමක් පැවැත්වූ බව ය.",
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ දේශපාලන ව්‍යාකූලත්වය මධ්‍යයේ ජුලි 12 දා, පසුගිය රජය චීන යාත්‍රාව හම්බන්තොට වරායේ නැව්ගත කිරීම අනුමත කළේය.(ඒජන්සි)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "චීනය",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "ඉන්දියාව",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "චීන",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "හම්බන්තොට වරාය",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "චීනය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "සඳුදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "කොළඹ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "බීජිං",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "චීන",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Yuan Wang",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "හම්බන්තොට වරාය",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "අගෝස්තු 11 සිට 17 දක්වා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "චීන විදේශ අමාත්‍යාංශය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Wang Wenbin",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "බීජිං",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "චීනය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "දෙක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "තෙවන",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "LOC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "චීනය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "චීනය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "චීනය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "වැන්ග්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දියන් සාගරය",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "චීනය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "චීනය",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "චීන",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "හම්බන්තොට",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "අගෝස්තු",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "විදේශ කටයුතු අමාත්‍යාංශය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ප්‍රකාශක Arindam Bagchi",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "නව දිල්ලි",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "චීන",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "පසුගිය මාසයේ",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ඉරිදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "චීනය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලාංකික",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "කොළඹ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "චීනය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Qi Zhenhong",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "කොළඹ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ජූලි 12",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "චීන",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "හම්බන්තොට",
            "label": "LOC"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "இலங்கையுடனான தனது பரிமாற்றத்தை ''தொந்தரவு செய்வதை நிறுத்துங்கள்'' என்று இந்தியாவை சீனா கேட்டுக்கொள்கிறது",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "மூலோபாய அம்பாந்தோட்டை துறைமுகத்தில் உயர் தொழில்நுட்ப சீன ஆராய்ச்சிக் கப்பலை நிறுத்துவதற்குத் திட்டமிடப்பட்டுள்ள இலங்கையின் கோரிக்கையால் கோபமடைந்த சீனா, திங்களன்று இந்தியாவைக் கடுமையாக விமர்சித்தது.",
        "கொழும்பில் இருந்து வரும் செய்திகளின்படி, ஆகஸ்ட் 11 முதல் 17 வரை அம்பாந்தோட்டை துறைமுகத்தில் நிறுத்தப்படவிருந்த சீன விண்வெளி மற்றும் செயற்கைக்கோள் கண்காணிப்பு ஆய்வுக் கப்பலான 'யுவான் வாங் 5' வருவதை ஒத்திவைக்குமாறு பெய்ஜிங்கை இலங்கை கேட்டுக் கொண்டுள்ளது. .",
        "இந்தச் செய்திகளுக்குப் பதிலளித்த சீன வெளியுறவு அமைச்சகத்தின் செய்தித் தொடர்பாளர் வாங் வென்பின் இங்கு நடைபெற்ற ஊடகவியலாளர் சந்திப்பில், பெய்ஜிங் இந்த அறிக்கைகளை கவனத்தில் கொண்டு, \"சீனாவுக்கும் இலங்கைக்கும் இடையிலான ஒத்துழைப்பை இரு நாடுகளும் சுதந்திரமாகத் தேர்ந்தெடுத்து பொதுவான நலன்களைப் பூர்த்தி செய்கின்றன. அது இல்லை. எந்த மூன்றாம் தரப்பினரையும் குறிவைக்கவும்.",
        "பாதுகாப்பு பிரச்சினைகளை மேற்கோள்காட்டி இலங்கைக்கு அழுத்தம் கொடுப்பது அர்த்தமற்றது என்று அவர் கூறினார், இலங்கையின் இந்த நடவடிக்கை இந்தியா வெளிப்படுத்திய கவலைகளுக்கு காரணம் என்று அறிக்கைகள் குறிப்பிடுகின்றன.",
        "\"இலங்கை ஒரு இறையாண்மை கொண்ட நாடு. அது தனது சொந்த வளர்ச்சி நலன்களின் வெளிச்சத்தில் மற்ற நாடுகளுடன் உறவுகளை வளர்க்க முடியும்,\" என்று அவர் கூறினார்.",
        "\"சீனாவின் அறிவியல் ஆய்வுகளை நியாயமான மற்றும் விவேகமான முறையில் பார்க்கவும், சீனாவுக்கும் இலங்கைக்கும் இடையிலான இயல்பான பரிமாற்றத்தை சீர்குலைப்பதை நிறுத்தவும் சீனா சம்பந்தப்பட்ட தரப்பினரை வலியுறுத்துகிறது\" என்று திரு வாங் கூறினார்.",
        "இலங்கை இந்தியப் பெருங்கடலில் போக்குவரத்து மையமாக உள்ளது. சீனா உள்ளிட்ட பல அறிவியல் ஆய்வுக் கப்பல்கள் இலங்கை துறைமுகத்தில் மறுவிநியோகத்திற்காக நிறுத்தப்பட்டுள்ளன. \"சீனா எப்பொழுதும் உயர் கடல்களில் வழிசெலுத்துவதற்கான சுதந்திரத்தைப் பயன்படுத்துகிறது மற்றும் கடலோர மாநிலங்களின் அதிகார வரம்பிற்கு அவர்களின் கடல்களுக்குள் அறிவியல் ஆய்வு நடவடிக்கைகளுக்கு முழுமையாக மதிப்பளிக்கிறது,\" என்று அவர் கூறினார்.",
        "உயர்தொழில்நுட்ப சீன ஆராய்ச்சிக் கப்பலை நிறுத்துவது அதன் தேசிய பாதுகாப்பிற்கு அச்சுறுத்தலாக அமையும் என இந்தியா இலங்கைக்கு தெரிவித்ததாக ஊடகச் செய்திகள் தெரிவிக்கின்றன.",
        "இந்த கப்பல் செயற்கைக்கோள்கள் மற்றும் கண்டம் விட்டு கண்டம் பாயும் ஏவுகணைகளை கண்காணிக்கும் திறன் கொண்டதாக கூறப்பட்டதால், இந்தியாவிடம் இருந்து இலங்கைக்கு கடும் எதிர்ப்புகள் வந்ததாக தகவல்கள் தெரிவிக்கின்றன.",
        "இந்தியா தனது பாதுகாப்பு மற்றும் பொருளாதார நலன்களில் தாக்கத்தை ஏற்படுத்தும் எந்தவொரு வளர்ச்சியையும் கவனமாகக் கண்காணித்து வருவதாகக் கூறியுள்ளது.",
        "சீனக் கப்பலின் முன்மொழியப்பட்ட பயணத்தின் அறிக்கைகள் குறித்து புதுதில்லியில் கேட்டபோது, ​​வெளியுறவு அமைச்சகத்தின் செய்தித் தொடர்பாளர் அரிந்தம் பாக்சி, “இந்தக் கப்பல் ஆகஸ்ட் மாதம் ஹம்பாந்தோட்டைக்கு விஜயம் செய்ய முன்மொழியப்பட்ட செய்திகளை நாங்கள் அறிவோம்.",
        "\"இந்தியாவின் பாதுகாப்பு மற்றும் பொருளாதார நலன்களை பாதிக்கும் எந்தவொரு வளர்ச்சியையும் அரசாங்கம் கவனமாகக் கண்காணித்து, அவற்றைப் பாதுகாக்க தேவையான அனைத்து நடவடிக்கைகளையும் எடுக்கிறது,\" என்று அவர் கடந்த மாதம் கூறினார்.",
        "ஞாயிற்றுக்கிழமை கொழும்பில் இருந்து வரும் செய்திகள், ஆராய்ச்சிக் கப்பலைத் திட்டமிட்டு நறுக்குவதில் கொழும்பு தள்ளிவைக்கக் கோரியதை அடுத்து, நாட்டிலுள்ள சீனத் தூதரகம் இலங்கையின் மூத்த அதிகாரிகளுடன் அவசரச் சந்திப்பை நாடியதாகக் கூறியது.",
        "திட்டமிட்ட கப்பல்துறையை ஒத்திவைக்க கொழும்பு கோரியதை அடுத்து, நாட்டின் ஜனாதிபதி ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க, சீனத் தூதுவர் Qi Zhenhong உடன் மூடிய கதவு சந்திப்பை நடத்தியதாகவும் சில இலங்கை செய்தி இணையதளங்கள் தெரிவித்துள்ளன.",
        "ஜூலை 12 அன்று, இலங்கையில் நிலவும் அரசியல் குழப்பங்களுக்கு மத்தியில், அம்பாந்தோட்டை துறைமுகத்தில் சீனக் கப்பலை நிறுத்துவதற்கு முந்தைய அரசாங்கம் ஒப்புதல் அளித்தது.(ஏஜென்சிகள்)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "சீனா",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "இந்தியா",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கையின்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சீன",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "அம்பாந்தோட்டை துறைமுகம்",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "சீனா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "திங்கட்கிழமை",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்தியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "கொழும்பு",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "பெய்ஜிங்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சீன",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Yuan Wang",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "அம்பாந்தோட்டை துறைமுகம்",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆகஸ்ட் 11 முதல் 17 வரை",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்தியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "சீன வெளியுறவு அமைச்சகம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Wang Wenbin",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "பெய்ஜிங்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சீனா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இரண்டு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "மூன்றாவது",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கையின்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்தியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "LOC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "சீனா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சீனா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சீனா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "வாங்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்தியப் பெருங்கடல்",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "சீனா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சீனா",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இந்தியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சீன",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்தியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இந்தியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஹம்பாந்தோட்டை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆகஸ்ட்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "வெளியுறவு அமைச்சகம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "செய்தி தொடர்பாளர் அரிந்தம் பாக்சி",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "புது தில்லி",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சீன",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இந்தியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "கடந்த மாதம்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஞாயிற்றுக்கிழமை",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சீனா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "கொழும்பு",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "சீனா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Qi Zhenhong",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "கொழும்பு",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஜூலை 12",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சீன",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஹம்பாந்தோட்டை",
            "label": "LOC"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}