{
  "newspaper_id": "ada-lk",
  "url": "https://www.ada.lk/international/ට්‍රම්ප්ගේ-හිටපු-උපදේශක-යුක්රේන-අනාගතය-දකියි/3-395209",
  "time_ut": 1657217313,
  "original_lang": "si",
  "original_title": "ට්‍රම්ප්ගේ හිටපු උපදේශක යුක්රේන අනාගතය දකියි",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Trump's former adviser sees the future of Ukraine",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "Former Trump military advisor Colonel Douglas McGregor said in an interview with Sky News Australia that Ukraine could disappear from the map if the conflict with Russia is not resolved peacefully.",
        "Asked what more could be done to help Ukraine in the ongoing military conflict, McGregor stated, \"The longer this goes on, the more people will be needlessly killed. The more damage Ukraine will certainly suffer. Effectively a failure situation, it can be completely wiped off the map.\" .\" Namely.",
        "\"We need a ceasefire,\" MacGregor argued, noting that Ukraine's forces have suffered massive losses during the conflict, and that Russian forces have not suffered any significant losses or injuries at this point. He also mentioned that countries like Australia should not stand against it and force it.",
        "\"We cannot fight this until there are no more Ukrainians left,\" he stressed, adding that he had heard from people in Berlin, Paris and London that there was growing support for a ceasefire between Moscow and Kiev's rulers."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Trump",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "Ukraine",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Trump",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Douglas McGregor",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sky News",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Australia",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ukraine",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Russia",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Ukraine",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "McGregor",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ukraine",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "MacGregor",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ukraine",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Russian",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Australia",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Ukrainians",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Berlin",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Paris",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "London",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Moscow",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kiev",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "ට්‍රම්ප්ගේ හිටපු උපදේශක යුක්රේන අනාගතය දකියි",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "රුසියාව සමග ගැටුම සාමකාමීව විසඳා නොගතහොත් යුක්රේනය සිතියමෙන් අතුරුදන් විය හැකි බව හිටපු ට්‍රම්ප් හමුදා උපදේශක කර්නල් ඩග්ලස් මැක්ග්‍රෙගර් ස්කයි නිව්ස් ඔස්ට්‍රේලියාව සමග සම්මුඛ සාකච්ඡාවකට එක්වෙමින් පැවසීය.",
        "දැනට පවතින හමුදා ගැටුමේදී යුක්රේනයට උපකාර කිරීම සඳහා තවත් කුමක් කළ හැකිදැයි ඇසූ විට, මැක්ග්‍රෙගෝර් ප්‍රකාශ කළේ, \"මෙය තවදුරටත් පවතින විට, වැඩි වැඩියෙන් මිනිසුන් අනවශ්‍ය ලෙස ඝාතනය වේවි. යුක්‍රේනයට වැඩි හානියක් සිදුවීම ඒකාන්තයි. ඵලදායී ලෙස අසාර්ථක තත්වයක්, එය සිතියමෙන් සම්පූර්ණයෙන්ම මකා දැමිය හැකියි.\" යනුවෙනි.",
        "ගැටුම අතරතුර යුක්රේනයේ හමුදාවන්ට දැවැන්ත පාඩු සිදුවී ඇති බවත්, රුසියානු හමුදාවන්ට මේ අවස්ථාවේ දී කිසි ලෙසකින්වත් දැනෙන පාඩුවක් හෝ රිදවීමක් සිදුවී නැති බවත් සඳහන් කරමින් මැක්ග්‍රෙගෝර් තර්ක කළේ \"අපට සටන් විරාමයක් අවශ්‍යයි\" යනුවෙනි. විශේෂයෙන්ම ඔස්ට්‍රේලියාව වැනි රටවල් ඊට විරුද්ධව නොසිට, ඒ සඳහා බල කළ යුතු බවත් හෙතෙම සඳහන් කළේය.",
        "\"තවදුරටත් යුක්රේන ජාතිකයන් ඉතිරි නොවන තුරු අපට මෙයට එරෙහිව සටන් කිරීමට හැකියාවක් නැහැ\" ඔහු අවධාරණයය කළේ, මොස්කව් සහ කියෙව් පාලකයන් අතර සටන් විරාමයක් සඳහා වැඩෙන සහයෝගයක් හෝ යම් ආකාරයකට පැමිණිය යුතු බවට බර්ලින්, පැරිස් සහ ලන්ඩනයේ ජනතාවගෙන් තමා අසා ඇති බවයි."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ට්රම්ප්",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "යුක්රේනය",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ට්රම්ප්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඩග්ලස් මැක්ග්‍රෙගර්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ස්කයි නිව්ස්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඕස්ට්රේලියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "යුක්රේනය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "රුසියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "යුක්රේනය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මැක්ග්රෙගර්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "යුක්රේනය",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "මැක්ග්‍රෙගර්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "යුක්රේනය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "රුසියානු",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඕස්ට්රේලියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "යුක්රේනියානුවන්",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "බර්ලින්",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "පැරිස්",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ලන්ඩන්",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මොස්කව්",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "කියෙව්",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "டிரம்பின் முன்னாள் ஆலோசகர் உக்ரைனின் எதிர்காலத்தைப் பார்க்கிறார்",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "ரஷ்யாவுடனான மோதலை அமைதியான முறையில் தீர்க்காவிட்டால் உக்ரைன் வரைபடத்தில் இருந்து மறைந்துவிடும் என்று டிரம்ப் முன்னாள் ராணுவ ஆலோசகர் கர்னல் டக்ளஸ் மெக்ரிகோர் ஸ்கை நியூஸ் ஆஸ்திரேலியாவுக்கு அளித்த பேட்டியில் கூறினார்.",
        "தற்போதைய இராணுவ மோதலில் உக்ரைனுக்கு உதவ இன்னும் என்ன செய்ய முடியும் என்று கேட்டதற்கு, மெக்ரிகோர் கூறினார், \"இது எவ்வளவு காலம் நீடிக்கும், அதிகமான மக்கள் தேவையில்லாமல் கொல்லப்படுவார்கள். உக்ரைன் நிச்சயமாக பாதிக்கப்படும். உக்ரைன் நிச்சயமாக தோல்வியடையும். வரைபடத்தை துடைத்துவிட்டார்.\" .\" அதாவது.",
        "\"எங்களுக்கு ஒரு போர்நிறுத்தம் தேவை,\" என்று MacGregor வாதிட்டார், மோதலின் போது உக்ரைனின் படைகள் பாரிய இழப்புகளை சந்தித்துள்ளன, மேலும் ரஷ்ய படைகள் இந்த கட்டத்தில் குறிப்பிடத்தக்க இழப்புகள் அல்லது காயங்களை சந்திக்கவில்லை. அவுஸ்திரேலியா போன்ற நாடுகள் அதற்கு எதிராக நின்று கட்டாயப்படுத்தக் கூடாது எனவும் அவர் குறிப்பிட்டுள்ளார்.",
        "\"இன்னும் உக்ரேனியர்கள் எஞ்சியிருக்கும் வரை நாங்கள் இதை எதிர்த்துப் போராட முடியாது,\" என்று அவர் வலியுறுத்தினார், மாஸ்கோவிற்கும் கியேவின் ஆட்சியாளர்களுக்கும் இடையில் போர்நிறுத்தத்திற்கு வளர்ந்து வரும் ஆதரவு இருப்பதாக பெர்லின், பாரிஸ் மற்றும் லண்டனில் உள்ள மக்களிடம் இருந்து தான் கேள்விப்பட்டேன்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "டிரம்ப்",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "உக்ரைன்",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "டிரம்ப்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "டக்ளஸ் மெக்ரிகோர்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஸ்கை நியூஸ்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆஸ்திரேலியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "உக்ரைன்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரஷ்யா",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "உக்ரைன்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "மெக்ரிகோர்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "உக்ரைன்",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "மேக்கிரிகோர்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "உக்ரைன்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரஷ்யன்",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆஸ்திரேலியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "உக்ரேனியர்கள்",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "பெர்லின்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாரிஸ்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "லண்டன்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "மாஸ்கோ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "கியேவ்",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}