{
  "newspaper_id": "daily-ft-lk",
  "url": "https://www.ft.lk/business/Lankan-envoy-in-India-visits-Amul-Headquarters-in-Gujarat/34-737889",
  "time_ut": 1658774950,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Lankan envoy in India visits Amul Headquarters in Gujarat",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Lankan envoy in India visits Amul Headquarters in Gujarat",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "High Commissioner Moragoda (right) with Amul Managing Director Dr. R.S. Sodhi",
        "The High Commissioner visiting Amul’s Kaira Milk Union dairy plant",
        "The High Commissioner and his delegation with the officials of Amul",
        "Sri Lanka sought ways and means to develop its dairy industry with the cooperation of India, when an official delegation led by Sri Lanka’s High Commissioner to New Delhi, Milinda Moragoda held discussions last week with the Gujarat Cooperative Milk Marketing Federation Ltd. (GCMMF), popularly known as Amul.",
        "High Commissioner Moragoda met Amul Managing Director Dr. R.S. Sodhi for discussions at the Federation’s headquarters in Anand, during the former’s first official visit to the State of Gujarat since assuming office in India. He met with state officials and potential investors.",
        "The discussion with the delegation led by Amul Managing Director focussed on dairy sector cooperation between Sri Lanka and India with special attention on importing Amul dairy products through the existing Indian credit line and replicating the Amul cooperative model in Sri Lanka with a view to ensuring self-sufficiency in milk. The possibility of introducing buffalo farming to Sri Lanka as a source of milk with the technical assistance of Amul was also discussed. In India, buffalo milk accounts for 45% of the total milk production of the country, while 55% of Amul’s total milk production comes from buffaloes.",
        "Following the discussion, the High Commissioner and the delegation visited Kaira Milk Union dairy plant in Anand where packaging of milk and production of other dairy foods take place.",
        "Formed in 1946 as a cooperative society in response to the exploitation of marginal milk producers by traders and agents in small cities, Amul was closely associated with anti-colonial sentiments and India’s independence movement. Today, Amul is jointly controlled by 3.6 million milk producers in 18,565 villages in Gujarat. These village cooperatives form thirteen milk unions and the GCMMF functions as the apex body of those milk unions and manages the cooperative. The Federation is the largest food products marketing organisation in India.",
        "Amul spurred India’s ‘White Revolution’ or achieving self-sufficiency in milk, transforming India from a milk-deficient nation into the world’s largest milk producer, surpassing the United States of America in 1998. This was done through replicating the Amul model throughout India.",
        "Under the guidance of freedom fighter and unifier of India, Sardar Vallabhbhai Patel, Tribhuvandas Kishibhai Patel became the founding chairman of the organisation and led it until his retirement in the 70s. Dr. Verghese Kurien, who is considered to be the man behind the enormous success of Amul, joined the organisation in 1949 as its General Manager, and later became the founder Chairman of the GCMMF in 1973, a post that he held until 2006.",
        "During his visit to Amul headquarters, High Commissioner Moragoda paid floral tributes to the statues of Sardar Vallabhbhai Patel, Tribhuvandas Kishibhai Patel and Dr. Verghese Kurien."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "India",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "Amul Headquarters",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "Gujarat",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Moragoda",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "R.S. Sodhi",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Amul",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Amul",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "India",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka’s",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "New Delhi",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Milinda Moragoda",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "last week",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Gujarat Cooperative Milk Marketing Federation Ltd.",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Amul",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Moragoda",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Amul",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "R.S. Sodhi",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Federation",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Anand",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "first",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "India",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "India",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Amul",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Indian",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Amul",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Amul",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "India",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "45%",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "55%",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "Amul",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Kaira Milk Union",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Anand",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "1946",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Amul",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "India",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Today",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Amul",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "3.6 million",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "18,565",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Gujarat",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "thirteen",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Federation",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "India",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "India",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "India",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the United States of America",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "1998",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Amul",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "India",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "India",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sardar Vallabhbhai Patel",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Tribhuvandas Kishibhai Patel",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the 70s",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Verghese Kurien",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Amul",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "1949",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "1973",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "2006",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Amul",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sardar Vallabhbhai Patel",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Tribhuvandas Kishibhai Patel",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Verghese Kurien",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "ඉන්දියාවේ ලංකා තානාපති ගුජරාටයේ අමුල් මූලස්ථානයට",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "මහ කොමසාරිස් මොරගොඩ (දකුණ) සමඟ අමුල් කළමනාකාර අධ්‍යක්ෂ ආචාර්ය ආර්. සෝදි",
        "මහ කොමසාරිස් අමුල් කයිරා කිරි සංගමයේ කිරි නිෂ්පාදනාගාරයේ නිරීක්ෂණ චාරිකාවක",
        "මහ කොමසාරිස්වරයා සහ ඔහුගේ දූත පිරිස අමුල් සමාගමේ නිලධාරීන් සමඟ",
        "නවදිල්ලියේ ශ්‍රී ලංකා මහ කොමසාරිස් මිලින්ද මොරගොඩ ප්‍රමුඛ නිල නියෝජිත පිරිසක් පසුගිය සතියේ සීමාසහිත ගුජරාට් සමුපකාර කිරි අලෙවි සම්මේලනය (GCMMF) සමඟ සාකච්ඡා පැවැත්වූ විට, ශ්‍රී ලංකාව ඉන්දියාවේ සහයෝගීතාවයෙන් කිරි කර්මාන්තය දියුණු කිරීමට ක්‍රම සහ ක්‍රම සෙව්වේය. අමුල් ලෙස ජනප්‍රියයි.",
        "මහ කොමසාරිස් මොරගොඩ මහතා අමුල් කළමනාකාර අධ්‍යක්ෂ ආචාර්ය ආර්. සෝදි ඉන්දියාවේ බලයට පත්වීමෙන් පසු ගුජරාට් ප්‍රාන්තයේ හිටපු පළමු නිල සංචාරය අතරතුර, ආනන්ද් හි පිහිටි සම්මේලනයේ මූලස්ථානයේ සාකච්ඡා සඳහා. ඔහු රාජ්‍ය නිලධාරීන් සහ අනාගත ආයෝජකයින් හමුවිය.",
        "Amul කළමනාකාර අධ්‍යක්ෂ ප්‍රමුඛ දූත පිරිස සමඟ පැවති සාකච්ඡාවේදී ශ්‍රී ලංකාව සහ ඉන්දියාව අතර කිරි නිෂ්පාදන අංශයේ සහයෝගීතාව කෙරෙහි අවධානය යොමු කරන ලද අතර, දැනට පවතින ඉන්දීය ණය මාර්ගය හරහා අමුල් කිරි නිෂ්පාදන ආනයනය කිරීම සහ ස්වයංක්‍රීයත්වය සහතික කිරීමේ අරමුණින් ශ්‍රී ලංකාව තුළ අමුල් සමුපකාර ආකෘතිය ප්‍රතිනිර්මාණය කිරීම කෙරෙහි විශේෂ අවධානය යොමු විය. කිරි වල ප්රමාණවත් වීම. අමුල් සමාගමේ තාක්ෂණික සහය ඇතිව මී ගව වගාව කිරි ප්‍රභවයක් ලෙස ශ්‍රී ලංකාවට හඳුන්වා දීමේ හැකියාව පිළිබඳව ද මෙහිදී සාකච්ඡා කෙරිණි. ඉන්දියාවේ, රටේ මුළු කිරි නිෂ්පාදනයෙන් 45%ක් මී කිරි නියෝජනය කරන අතර, අමුල්ගේ මුළු කිරි නිෂ්පාදනයෙන් 55%ක් පැමිණෙන්නේ මී ගවයින්ගෙනි.",
        "සාකච්ඡාවෙන් අනතුරුව මහ කොමසාරිස්වරයා ඇතුළු දූත පිරිස කිරි ඇසුරුම් කිරීම සහ අනෙකුත් කිරි ආහාර නිෂ්පාදනය කෙරෙන ආනන්ද් හි කයිරා මිල්ක් යූනියන් කිරි කම්හල වෙත ගියහ.",
        "කුඩා නගරවල වෙළෙන්දන් සහ නියෝජිතයින් විසින් ආන්තික කිරි නිෂ්පාදකයින් සූරාකෑමට ප්‍රතිචාර වශයෙන් සමුපකාර සමිතියක් ලෙස 1946 දී පිහිටුවන ලද අමුල් යටත් විජිත විරෝධී හැඟීම් සහ ඉන්දියාවේ නිදහස් ව්‍යාපාරය සමඟ සමීපව සම්බන්ධ විය. අද වන විට, ගුජරාටයේ ගම් 18,565 ක කිරි නිෂ්පාදකයින් මිලියන 3.6 ක් විසින් අමුල් පාලනය කරනු ලැබේ. මෙම ග්‍රාමීය සමුපකාර කිරි සංගම් දහතුනක් පිහිටුවා ගන්නා අතර GCMMF එම කිරි සංගම්වල ප්‍රධාන ආයතනය ලෙස ක්‍රියා කරන අතර සමුපකාරය කළමනාකරණය කරයි. ෆෙඩරේෂන් යනු ඉන්දියාවේ විශාලතම ආහාර නිෂ්පාදන අලෙවිකරණ සංවිධානයයි.",
        "අමුල් විසින් ඉන්දියාවේ ‘ධවල විප්ලවය’ හෙවත් කිරිවලින් ස්වයංපෝෂිත භාවයක් ලබා ගනිමින්, කිරි හිඟ රාජ්‍යයක සිට ලොව විශාලතම කිරි නිෂ්පාදකයා බවට ඉන්දියාව පරිවර්තනය කරමින්, 1998 දී ඇමරිකා එක්සත් ජනපදය අභිබවා යමින්, ඉන්දියාව පුරා අමුල් ආකෘතිය ප්‍රතිනිර්මාණය කිරීම හරහා මෙය සිදු විය.",
        "නිදහස් සටන්කාමියෙකු සහ ඉන්දියාවේ එක්සත් ජාතිකයෙකු වූ සර්දාර් වල්ලභායි පටෙල්ගේ මගපෙන්වීම යටතේ, ත්‍රිභුවන්දස් කිෂිබායි පටෙල් සංවිධානයේ ආරම්භක සභාපති බවට පත් වූ අතර 70 දශකයේ විශ්‍රාම යන තෙක් එය මෙහෙයවීය. අමුල් හි දැවැන්ත සාර්ථකත්වය පිටුපස සිටින පුද්ගලයා ලෙස සැලකෙන ආචාර්ය වර්ගීස් කුරියන් 1949 දී එහි සාමාන්‍යාධිකාරීවරයා ලෙස සංවිධානයට සම්බන්ධ වූ අතර පසුව 1973 දී GCMMF හි ආරම්භක සභාපති බවට පත් වූ අතර ඔහු 2006 දක්වා එම තනතුර දැරීය.",
        "මහ කොමසාරිස් මොරගොඩ අමුල් මූලස්ථානයට කළ සංචාරයේදී සර්දාර් වල්ලභායි පටෙල්, ත්‍රිභුවන්දස් කිෂිබායි පටෙල් සහ ආචාර්ය වර්ගීස් කුරියන් යන අයගේ ප්‍රතිමාවලට පුෂ්පෝපහාර දැක්වීය."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ඉන්දියාව",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "අමුල් මූලස්ථානය",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "ගුජරාට්",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "මොරගොඩ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "රුපියල්. සෝදි",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "අමුල්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "අමුල්",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "නව දිල්ලි",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මිලින්ද මොරගොඩ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගිය සතිය",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "සීමාසහිත ගුජරාට් සමුපකාර කිරි අලෙවි සම්මේලනය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "අමුල්",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "මොරගොඩ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "අමුල්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "රුපියල්. සෝදි",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "සම්මේලනය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ආනන්ද්",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "පළමුවන",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "අමුල්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දීය",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "අමුල්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "අමුල්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "45%",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "55%",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "අමුල්",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "කයිරා කිරි සංගමය",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ආනන්ද්",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "1946",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "අමුල්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "අමුල්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "මිලියන 3.6 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "18,565 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගුජරාට්",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "දහතුන",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "සම්මේලනය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඇමරිකා එක්සත් ජනපදය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "1998",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "අමුල්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "සර්දාර් වල්ලභායි පටෙල්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Tribhuvandas Kishibhai Patel",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "70 දශකය",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "වර්ගීස් කුරියන්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "අමුල්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "1949",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "1973",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "2006",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "අමුල්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "සර්දාර් වල්ලභායි පටෙල්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Tribhuvandas Kishibhai Patel",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "වර්ගීස් කුරියන්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "இந்தியாவிற்கான இலங்கைத் தூதுவர் குஜராத்தில் உள்ள அமுல் தலைமையகத்திற்கு வருகை தந்துள்ளார்",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "உயர் ஸ்தானிகர் மொரகொட (வலது) உடன் அமுல் முகாமைத்துவப் பணிப்பாளர் கலாநிதி ஆர்.எஸ். சோதி",
        "உயர் ஸ்தானிகர் அமுலின் கைரா பால் யூனியன் பால் ஆலைக்கு விஜயம் செய்தார்",
        "அமுல் அதிகாரிகளுடன் உயர் ஸ்தானிகர் மற்றும் அவரது குழு",
        "புதுடில்லிக்கான இலங்கை உயர்ஸ்தானிகர் மிலிந்த மொரகொட தலைமையிலான உத்தியோகபூர்வ பிரதிநிதிகள் குழு, குஜராத் கூட்டுறவு பால் சந்தைப்படுத்தல் கூட்டமைப்பு லிமிடெட் (GCMMF) உடன் கடந்த வாரம் கலந்துரையாடல்களை நடத்திய போது, ​​இந்தியாவின் ஒத்துழைப்புடன் தனது பால் தொழில்துறையை மேம்படுத்துவதற்கான வழிகளையும் வழிகளையும் இலங்கை நாடியது. அமுல் என்று பிரபலமாக அறியப்படுகிறது.",
        "உயர்ஸ்தானிகர் மொரகொட அமுல் முகாமைத்துவ பணிப்பாளர் கலாநிதி ஆர்.எஸ். சோதி, இந்தியாவில் பதவியேற்ற பிறகு குஜராத் மாநிலத்திற்கு முதல் அதிகாரப்பூர்வ விஜயத்தின் போது, ​​ஆனந்தில் உள்ள கூட்டமைப்பின் தலைமையகத்தில் கலந்துரையாடல்களுக்காக சோதி. அவர் மாநில அதிகாரிகள் மற்றும் சாத்தியமான முதலீட்டாளர்களை சந்தித்தார்.",
        "அமுல் முகாமைத்துவப் பணிப்பாளர் தலைமையிலான குழுவுடனான கலந்துரையாடல், இலங்கைக்கும் இந்தியாவிற்கும் இடையிலான பால் உற்பத்தித் துறை ஒத்துழைப்பு குறித்து கவனம் செலுத்தியதுடன், அமுல் பால் உற்பத்திகளை தற்போதுள்ள இந்திய கடன் வரிசையின் மூலம் இறக்குமதி செய்வது மற்றும் அமுல் கூட்டுறவு மாதிரியை இலங்கையில் பிரதிபலிப்பது குறித்து கவனம் செலுத்தப்பட்டது. பாலில் போதுமான அளவு. அமுல் நிறுவனத்தின் தொழிநுட்ப உதவியுடன் எருமை வளர்ப்பை பால் ஆதாரமாக இலங்கைக்கு அறிமுகப்படுத்துவது குறித்தும் கலந்துரையாடப்பட்டது. இந்தியாவில், நாட்டின் மொத்த பால் உற்பத்தியில் எருமைப் பால் 45% ஆகும், அதே சமயம் அமுலின் மொத்த பால் உற்பத்தியில் 55% எருமைகளிலிருந்து வருகிறது.",
        "கலந்துரையாடலைத் தொடர்ந்து, உயர் ஸ்தானிகர் மற்றும் தூதுக்குழுவினர் ஆனந்தில் உள்ள கைரா மில்க் யூனியன் பால் ஆலைக்கு விஜயம் செய்தனர், அங்கு பால் பேக்கேஜிங் மற்றும் பிற பால் உணவுகளின் உற்பத்தி நடைபெறுகிறது.",
        "சிறு நகரங்களில் வணிகர்கள் மற்றும் முகவர்களால் விளிம்பு நிலை பால் உற்பத்தியாளர்களை சுரண்டுவதற்கு பதில் கூட்டுறவு சங்கமாக 1946 இல் உருவாக்கப்பட்டது, அமுல் காலனித்துவ எதிர்ப்பு உணர்வுகள் மற்றும் இந்தியாவின் சுதந்திர இயக்கத்துடன் நெருக்கமாக தொடர்புடையது. இன்று, அமுல் குஜராத்தில் 18,565 கிராமங்களில் 3.6 மில்லியன் பால் உற்பத்தியாளர்களால் கூட்டாகக் கட்டுப்படுத்தப்படுகிறது. இந்த கிராம கூட்டுறவுகள் பதின்மூன்று பால் சங்கங்களை உருவாக்குகின்றன மற்றும் GCMMF அந்த பால் சங்கங்களின் உச்ச அமைப்பாக செயல்படுகிறது மற்றும் கூட்டுறவு நிர்வாகத்தை நிர்வகிக்கிறது. கூட்டமைப்பு இந்தியாவின் மிகப்பெரிய உணவுப் பொருட்களை சந்தைப்படுத்தும் அமைப்பாகும்.",
        "அமுல் இந்தியாவின் ‘வெள்ளை புரட்சியை’ அல்லது பாலில் தன்னிறைவு அடைய, பால் பற்றாக்குறை உள்ள நாடாக இருந்து இந்தியாவை உலகின் மிகப்பெரிய பால் உற்பத்தியாளராக மாற்றியது, 1998 இல் அமெரிக்காவை விஞ்சியது. இது இந்தியா முழுவதும் அமுல் மாதிரியைப் பிரதியெடுப்பதன் மூலம் செய்யப்பட்டது.",
        "சுதந்திரப் போராட்ட வீரரும், இந்தியாவை ஒருங்கிணைத்தவருமான சர்தார் வல்லபாய் படேலின் வழிகாட்டுதலின் கீழ், திரிபுவன்தாஸ் கிஷிபாய் படேல் இந்த அமைப்பின் நிறுவனத் தலைவராக ஆனார் மற்றும் 70 களில் ஓய்வு பெறும் வரை அதை வழிநடத்தினார். அமுலின் மகத்தான வெற்றிக்குப் பின்னால் இருந்த மனிதராகக் கருதப்படும் டாக்டர். வர்கீஸ் குரியன், 1949 இல் அதன் பொது மேலாளராக நிறுவனத்தில் சேர்ந்தார், பின்னர் 1973 இல் GCMMF இன் நிறுவனர் தலைவராக ஆனார், அவர் 2006 வரை பதவி வகித்தார்.",
        "அமுல் தலைமையகத்திற்கு தனது விஜயத்தின் போது, ​​உயர் ஆணையர் மொரகொடா, சர்தார் வல்லபாய் படேல், திரிபுவன்தாஸ் கிஷிபாய் படேல் மற்றும் டாக்டர் வர்கீஸ் குரியன் ஆகியோரின் சிலைகளுக்கு மலர் தூவி மரியாதை செலுத்தினார்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "இந்தியா",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "அமுல் தலைமையகம்",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "குஜராத்",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "மொரகொட",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆர்.எஸ். சோதி",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "அமுல்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "அமுல்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்தியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கையின்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "புது தில்லி",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "மிலிந்த மொரகொட",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "கடந்த வாரம்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "குஜராத் கூட்டுறவு பால் விற்பனை கூட்டமைப்பு லிமிடெட்.",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "அமுல்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "மொரகொட",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "அமுல்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆர்.எஸ். சோதி",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "கூட்டமைப்பு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆனந்த்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "முதலில்",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்தியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்தியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "அமுல்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்தியன்",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "அமுல்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "அமுல்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்தியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "45%",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "55%",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "அமுல்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "கைரா பால் ஒன்றியம்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆனந்த்",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "1946",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "அமுல்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்தியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "அமுல்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "3.6 மில்லியன்",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "18,565",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "குஜராத்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "பதின்மூன்று",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "கூட்டமைப்பு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்தியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இந்தியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்தியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஐக்கிய அமெரிக்கா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "1998",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "அமுல்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்தியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இந்தியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சர்தார் வல்லபாய் படேல்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "திரிபுவன்தாஸ் கிஷிபாய் படேல்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "70கள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "வர்கீஸ் குரியன்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "அமுல்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "1949",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "1973",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "2006",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "அமுல்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "சர்தார் வல்லபாய் படேல்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "திரிபுவன்தாஸ் கிஷிபாய் படேல்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "வர்கீஸ் குரியன்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}