{
  "newspaper_id": "news-first-lk",
  "url": "https://www.newsfirst.lk/2022/07/28/cops-chase-after-suspicious-swimmer-and-recover-stolen-money-bag-with-rs-1-5-mn/",
  "time_ut": 1659002760,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Cops chase after suspicious swimmer and recover stolen money bag with Rs. 1.5 Mn",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Cops chase after suspicious swimmer and recover stolen money bag with Rs. 1.5 Mn",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); Sri Lanka Police arrested a man who jumped into a canal close to a bridge in Wattala and started swimming suspiciously.",
        "Officers attached to the Crimes Prevention Division of the Wattala Police chased after the man, and investigations revealed that the man was running away after stealing Rs. 1.5 Million from a passenger in a bus traveling from Colombo to Negombo.",
        "Upon interrogation of the suspect, a police officer recovered the stolen money bag on the banks of the canal.",
        "The suspect had reportedly stolen the money bag and jumped off the bus before he was arrested by police officers.",
        "Cops chase after suspicious swimmer and recover stolen money bag with Rs. 1.5 Mn",
        "Court tells Police to produce Rs. 17.8 Mn found inside President’s House on 9th July"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "1.5",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "Mn",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "News 1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka Police",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Wattala",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the Crimes Prevention Division",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "1.5 Million",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Negombo",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "1.5",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Mn",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "17.8",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Mn",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "House",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "9th July",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "පොලිසිය සැකකටයුතු පිහිනුම්කරු පසුපස ලුහුබැඳ ගොස් සොරකම් කළ මුදල් බෑගය රු. මිලියන 1.5",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); වත්තල පාලමක් අසලින් ඇළකට පැන සැක කටයුතු ලෙස දියනෑමට ගිය පුද්ගලයෙකු ශ්‍රී ලංකා පොලිසිය විසින් අත්අඩංගුවට ගෙන තිබේ.",
        "වත්තල පොලිසියේ අපරාධ නිවාරණ කොට්ඨාශයේ නිළධාරීන් මෙම පුද්ගලයා පසුපස ලුහුබැඳ ගොස් ඇති අතර, විමර්ශනවලදී අනාවරණ වී ඇත්තේ මෙම පුද්ගලයා රුපියල් ලක්ෂ 10ක් සොරකම් කර පලා යන බවයි. කොළඹ සිට මීගමුව බලා ධාවනය වූ බස් රථයක මගියෙකුගෙන් රුපියල් මිලියන 1.5ක්.",
        "සැකකරුගෙන් ප්‍රශ්න කිරීමේදී ඇළ ඉවුරේ තිබී සොරාගත් මුදල් බෑගය පොලිස් නිලධාරියකු විසින් සොයා ගෙන ඇත.",
        "සැකකරු පොලිස් නිලධාරීන් විසින් අත්අඩංගුවට ගැනීමට පෙර මුදල් බෑගය සොරකම් කර බස් රථයෙන් පැන ඇති බව වාර්තා වේ.",
        "පොලිසිය සැකකටයුතු පිහිනුම්කරු පසුපස ලුහුබැඳ ගොස් සොරකම් කළ මුදල් බෑගය රු. මිලියන 1.5",
        "අධිකරණය පොලිසියට දන්වා ඇත්තේ රු. ජුලි 9 වැනිදා ජනාධිපති මන්දිරයේ තිබී මිලියන 17.8ක් සොයා ගැනේ"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "1.5",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "Mn",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "News 1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකා පොලිසිය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "වත්තල",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "අපරාධ නිවාරණ කොට්ඨාශය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "මිලියන 1.5 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "මීගමුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "1.5",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Mn",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "17.8",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Mn",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "නිවස",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජූලි 9",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "சந்தேகத்திற்கிடமான நீச்சல் வீரரை துரத்திச் சென்ற போலீஸார், திருடப்பட்ட பணப் பையை மீட்டனர். 1.5 மில்லியன்",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); வத்தளையில் பாலமொன்றுக்கு அருகில் உள்ள கால்வாயில் குதித்து சந்தேகத்திற்கிடமான முறையில் நீந்தத் தொடங்கிய நபரை இலங்கை பொலிஸார் கைது செய்துள்ளனர்.",
        "வத்தளை பொலிஸ் குற்றத்தடுப்பு பிரிவின் அதிகாரிகள் அந்த நபரை பின்தொடர்ந்து துரத்திச் சென்றதுடன், குறித்த நபர் 2000 ரூபாவை கொள்ளையடித்து விட்டு தப்பிச் சென்றுள்ளதாக விசாரணைகளில் இருந்து தெரியவந்துள்ளது. கொழும்பில் இருந்து நீர்கொழும்பு நோக்கி பயணித்த பேருந்தில் பயணித்தவரிடமிருந்து 1.5 மில்லியன்.",
        "சந்தேக நபரிடம் நடத்திய விசாரணையில், கால்வாய் கரையில் திருடப்பட்ட பணப்பையை போலீசார் மீட்டனர்.",
        "சந்தேக நபர் பொலிஸ் அதிகாரிகளால் கைது செய்யப்படுவதற்கு முன்னர் பணப் பையை திருடி பஸ்ஸில் இருந்து குதித்துள்ளார்.",
        "சந்தேகத்திற்கிடமான நீச்சல் வீரரை துரத்திச் சென்ற போலீஸார், திருடப்பட்ட பணப் பையை மீட்டனர். 1.5 மில்லியன்",
        "நீதிமன்றம் போலீசாரிடம் ரூ. ஜூலை 9 ஆம் தேதி ஜனாதிபதி மாளிகைக்குள் 17.8 மில்லியன் கண்டுபிடிக்கப்பட்டது"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "1.5",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "Mn",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "News 1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை காவல்துறை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "வத்தளை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "குற்றத் தடுப்புப் பிரிவு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "1.5 மில்லியன்",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "நீர்கொழும்பு",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "1.5",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Mn",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "17.8",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Mn",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "வீடு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜூலை 9",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}