{
  "newspaper_id": "daily-ft-lk",
  "url": "https://www.ft.lk/news/Y-s-Men-Intl-Asia-Pacific-President-Ben-Tsutomu-to-address-YM-Convention-in-Colombo-today/56-736659",
  "time_ut": 1656096323,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Y’s Men Intl. Asia Pacific President Ben Tsutomu to address YM Convention in Colombo today",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Y’s Men Intl. Asia Pacific President Ben Tsutomu to address YM Convention in Colombo today",
      "author": "",
      "body_lines": [
        "Y’s Men International movement, the premier movement oriented to serve MCAs and is also renowned for assisting communities across Sri Lanka for over 90 years, will hold its 46th national convention today at the Grand Oriental Hotel, Colombo.",
        "No less than the Y’s Men International Asia Pacific Area President YM Ohno Ben Tsutomu (of Kobe Port Y’s Men’s Club, Japan West Region) will address this year’s event as the Chief Guest. YM Tsutomu leads the large group of diverse Clubs spread across Asia Pacific Y’s Men Area that includes Sri Lanka, along with the Regions of Australia, Southeast Asia, Japan East and Japan West, Taiwan, and the Philippines.",
        "At today’s convention in Colombo, the Present Sri Lanka Regional Director Milroy Manuel will conclude his term thus opening the way for incoming 2022/’23 Sri Lanka Regional Director YM Anton Kandiah, who held the mantle of the Sri Lanka Regional Director previously on two occasions.",
        "Renowned compere, TV Presenter, show-biz personality and Sri Lanka Broadcasting Corporation former Director General Dr. Vijaya Corea will deliver the keynote address of the Convention.",
        "The global Y’s Men movement was one of the earliest global community service movements to be launched and was founded in Toledo, Ohio, USA in 1922. Despite being titled, “Y’s Men”, many women too are among its members today and family participation is widely seen in numerous service activities.",
        "The movement was introduced to Sri Lanka by the Colombo YMCA first General Secretary the late YM R.O. Buell. He launched it in Sri Lanka upon his return to the country after attending an International Y’s Men Convention in Minneapolis, USA. The first Y’s Men’s Club in Sri Lanka began its operations in 1929 in Colombo and was called Y’s Men’s Club of Colombo, which continues to function and grow to this day.",
        "The milestone event of Chartering the “Colombo Club” to be part of International Y’s Men, Geneva, took place in December 1930 with late Sir Oliver Goonetilleka, the former Governor-General of Ceylon, being the Club’s first Charter President. It was also through the Colombo Club that the Y’s Men’s movement was introduced to India.",
        "Later Sri Lanka became a separate Region of its own in 1975. The first Regional Convention of the newborn “Sri Lanka Region” was held in Kandy in September 1976, attended by a large gathering."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Y’s Men Intl",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "Asia Pacific",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "Ben Tsutomu",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "YM Convention in Colombo",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "today",
          "label": "DATE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Y’s Men International",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "over 90 years",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "46th",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Grand Oriental Hotel, Colombo",
            "label": "FAC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "YM Ohno Ben Tsutomu",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kobe Port",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "Japan",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "West Region",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "year",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Chief Guest",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Tsutomu",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Asia Pacific Y’s Men Area",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Southeast Asia",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "Japan East",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "Japan West",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Taiwan",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Philippines",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Milroy Manuel",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "2022/’23",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "YM Anton Kandiah",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "two",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka Broadcasting Corporation",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Vijaya Corea",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Convention",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "one",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Toledo",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ohio",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "USA",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "1922",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Y’s Men",
            "label": "WORK_OF_ART"
          },
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "R.O. Buell",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Minneapolis",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "USA",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "first",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "1929",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Y’s Men’s Club of Colombo",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "this day",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "International Y’s Men",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Geneva",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "December 1930",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Oliver Goonetilleka",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Club",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "first",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Colombo Club",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "India",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Later Sri Lanka",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "1975",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kandy",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "September 1976",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "Y’s Men Intl. ආසියා ශාන්තිකර කලාපීය ජනාධිපති බෙන් සුටෝමු අද කොළඹ දී YM සමුළුව ඇමතීමට නියමිතය",
      "author": "",
      "body_lines": [
        "වසර 90 කට වැඩි කාලයක් ශ්‍රී ලංකාව පුරා සිටින ප්‍රජාවන්ට උපකාර කිරීම සම්බන්ධයෙන් ද ප්‍රසිද්ධියක් උසුලන MCA සඳහා සේවය කිරීමට නැඹුරු වූ ප්‍රමුඛතම ව්‍යාපාරය වන Y’s Men International ව්‍යාපාරය සිය 46 වැනි ජාතික සමුළුව අද කොළඹ Grand Oriental හෝටලයේදී පැවැත්වේ.",
        "Y’s Men International Asia Pacific Area සභාපති YM Ohno Ben Tsutomu (Japan West Region, Kobe Port Y’s Men’s Club) මෙම වසරේ ප්‍රධාන ආරාධිත අමුත්තා ලෙස අමතනු ඇත. ඕස්ට්‍රේලියාව, අග්නිදිග ආසියාව, ජපානය නැගෙනහිර සහ ජපානය බටහිර, තායිවානය සහ පිලිපීනය යන කලාප සමඟින් ශ්‍රී ලංකාව ඇතුළු Asia Pacific Y’s Men Area පුරා පැතිරී ඇති විවිධ සමාජ ශාලා සමූහයට YM Tsutomu නායකත්වය දෙයි.",
        "අද කොළඹදී පැවැත්වෙන සමුළුවේදී වත්මන් ශ්‍රී ලංකා ප්‍රාදේශීය අධ්‍යක්ෂ මිල්රෝයි මැනුවෙල් මහතා සිය ධුර කාලය අවසන් කරන්නේ මීට පෙර අවස්ථා දෙකකදී ශ්‍රී ලංකා ප්‍රාදේශීය අධ්‍යක්ෂ ධුරය දැරූ 2022/'23 ශ්‍රී ලංකා ප්‍රාදේශීය අධ්‍යක්ෂ වයි.එම්.ඇන්ටන් කන්දියා මහතාට මාර්ගය විවෘත කරමිනි .",
        "සම්මුතියේ ප්‍රධාන දේශනය පවත්වනු ලබන්නේ සුප්‍රකට compere, TV ඉදිරිපත් කරන්නා, show-biz පෞරුෂය සහ ශ්‍රී ලංකා ගුවන්විදුලි සංස්ථාවේ හිටපු අධ්‍යක්ෂ ජනරාල් ආචාර්ය විජය කොරයා විසිනි.",
        "ගෝලීය Y's Men ව්‍යාපාරය දියත් කරන ලද මුල්ම ගෝලීය ප්‍රජා සේවා ව්‍යාපාරයක් වන අතර එය 1922 දී ඇමරිකා එක්සත් ජනපදයේ ඔහියෝ හි ටොලෙඩෝ හි ආරම්භ කරන ලදී. \"Y's Men\" ලෙස නම් කර ඇතත්, බොහෝ කාන්තාවන් ද අද එහි සාමාජිකයින් අතර සිටින අතර පවුලේ සහභාගීත්වය ද වේ. බොහෝ සේවා ක්‍රියාකාරකම්වල බහුලව දක්නට ලැබේ.",
        "මෙම ව්‍යාපාරය ශ්‍රී ලංකාවට හඳුන්වා දෙනු ලැබුවේ කොළඹ YMCA පළමු ප්‍රධාන ලේකම් දිවංගත YM R.O විසිනි. බුවෙල්. ඔහු එය ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ දියත් කළේ ඇමරිකා එක්සත් ජනපදයේ මිනියාපොලිස් හි පැවති ජාත්‍යන්තර Y’s Men සම්මුතියකට සහභාගී වී ආපසු මෙරටට පැමිණි පසුවය. ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ ප්‍රථම Y’s පිරිමි සමාජය 1929 දී කොළඹදී සිය මෙහෙයුම් ආරම්භ කළ අතර එය අද දක්වාම ක්‍රියාත්මක වෙමින් වර්ධනය වෙමින් පවතින Y’s Men’s Club of Colombo ලෙස හැඳින්විණි.",
        "ජාත්‍යන්තර Y's Men, Geneva හි කොටසක් වීමට \"Colombo Club\" වරලත් කිරීමේ සන්ධිස්ථානය 1930 දෙසැම්බර් මාසයේදී සිදු වූයේ, ලංකාවේ හිටපු ආණ්ඩුකාරවරයා වූ දිවංගත ශ්‍රීමත් ඔලිවර් ගුණතිලක සමාජයේ ප්‍රථම වරලත් සභාපතිවරයා වීමත් සමඟය. Y’s Men’s ව්‍යාපාරය ඉන්දියාවට හඳුන්වා දුන්නේද Colombo Club හරහාය.",
        "පසුව 1975 දී ශ්‍රී ලංකාව වෙනම කලාපයක් බවට පත් විය. අලුත උපන් “ශ්‍රී ලංකා කලාපයේ” ප්‍රථම ප්‍රාදේශීය සමුළුව 1976 සැප්තැම්බර් මාසයේදී මහනුවරදී පැවැත්වුණු අතර විශාල පිරිසක් සහභාගි වූහ."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Y’s Men Intl",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "ආසියා පැසිෆික්",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "Ben Tsutomu",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "කොළඹ පැවති වයි.එම්",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "අද",
          "label": "DATE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Y’s Men International",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "අවුරුදු 90 ට වැඩි",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "46 වැනි",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ග්‍රෑන්ඩ් ඔරියන්ටල් හෝටලය, කොළඹ",
            "label": "FAC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "YM Ohno Ben Tsutomu",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "කෝබේ වරාය",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජපානය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "බටහිර කලාපය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "වර්ෂය",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ප්‍රධාන ආරාධිතයා",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "සුතොමු",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ආසියා පැසිෆික් Y's පිරිමි ප්රදේශය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගිනිකොනදිග ආසියාව",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජපානය නැගෙනහිර",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "බටහිර ජපානය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "තායිවානය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "පිලිපීනය",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මිල්රෝයි මැනුවෙල්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "2022/'23",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "වයි.එම් ඇන්ටන් කන්දියා",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "දෙක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකා ගුවන් විදුලි සංස්ථාව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "විජය කොරයා",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "සම්මුතිය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "එක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ටොලිඩෝ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඔහියෝ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඇඑජ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "1922",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Y ගේ පිරිමි",
            "label": "WORK_OF_ART"
          },
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "R.O. බුවෙල්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මිනියාපොලිස්",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඇඑජ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "පළමුවන",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "1929",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Y’s පිරිමි සමාජය කොළඹ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "අද දවස",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ජාත්‍යන්තර Y’s පිරිමි",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජිනීවා",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "1930 දෙසැම්බර්",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඔලිවර් ගුණතිලක",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "සමාජය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "පළමුවන",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "කොළඹ සමාජය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "පසුව ශ්‍රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "1975",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මහනුවර",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "1976 සැප්තැම්බර්",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "Y's Men Intl. இன்று கொழும்பில் நடைபெறும் YM மாநாட்டில் ஆசிய பசுபிக் அதிபர் பென் சுடோமு உரையாற்றவுள்ளார்",
      "author": "",
      "body_lines": [
        "90 ஆண்டுகளுக்கும் மேலாக இலங்கை முழுவதிலும் உள்ள சமூகங்களுக்கு உதவுவதில் புகழ்பெற்று விளங்கும், MCA களுக்கு சேவை செய்வதில் முதன்மையான இயக்கமான Y’s Men International இயக்கம், அதன் 46வது தேசிய மாநாட்டை இன்று கொழும்பு Grand Oriental Hotel இல் நடத்தவுள்ளது.",
        "Y's Men இன்டர்நேஷனல் ஆசிய பசிபிக் பகுதியின் தலைவர் YM Ohno Ben Tsutomu (கோப் போர்ட் Y's Men's Club, Japan West Region) இந்த ஆண்டு நிகழ்வில் பிரதம விருந்தினராக கலந்து கொண்டு உரையாற்றுவார். ஆஸ்திரேலியா, தென்கிழக்கு ஆசியா, ஜப்பான் கிழக்கு மற்றும் ஜப்பான் மேற்கு, தைவான் மற்றும் பிலிப்பைன்ஸ் ஆகிய பிராந்தியங்களுடன், இலங்கையை உள்ளடக்கிய ஆசியா பசிபிக் Y's Men பகுதி முழுவதும் பரந்து விரிந்திருக்கும் பல்வேறுபட்ட கிளப்புகளின் பெரிய குழுவிற்கு YM Tsutomu தலைமை தாங்குகிறார்.",
        "கொழும்பில் இன்று நடைபெறும் மாநாட்டில், தற்போதைய இலங்கை பிராந்திய பணிப்பாளர் மில்ரோய் மானுவல் தனது பதவிக் காலத்தை நிறைவு செய்கிறார், இதன் மூலம் 2022/'23 இலங்கை பிராந்திய பணிப்பாளர் வை.எம். அன்டன் கந்தையா, முன்னர் இரண்டு தடவைகள் இலங்கை பிராந்திய பணிப்பாளராக பதவி வகித்தவர். .",
        "புகழ்பெற்ற இசையமைப்பாளர், தொலைக்காட்சி தொகுப்பாளர், நிகழ்ச்சி-பிஸ் ஆளுமை மற்றும் இலங்கை ஒலிபரப்புக் கூட்டுத்தாபனத்தின் முன்னாள் பணிப்பாளர் நாயகம் கலாநிதி விஜய கொரியா மாநாட்டின் முக்கிய உரையை ஆற்றவுள்ளார்.",
        "உலகளாவிய ஒய்ஸ் மென் இயக்கம் தொடங்கப்பட்ட ஆரம்பகால உலகளாவிய சமூக சேவை இயக்கங்களில் ஒன்றாகும், இது 1922 ஆம் ஆண்டில் அமெரிக்காவின் ஓஹியோவில் உள்ள டோலிடோவில் நிறுவப்பட்டது. \"ஒய்'ஸ் மென்\" என்று பெயரிடப்பட்டிருந்தாலும், பல பெண்களும் இன்று உறுப்பினர்களாக உள்ளனர் மற்றும் குடும்ப பங்கேற்பு உள்ளது. பல சேவை நடவடிக்கைகளில் பரவலாகக் காணப்படுகிறது.",
        "கொழும்பு ஒய்எம்சிஏ முதல் பொதுச் செயலாளர் மறைந்த ஒய்எம் ஆர் ஓ அவர்களால் இந்த இயக்கம் இலங்கைக்கு அறிமுகப்படுத்தப்பட்டது. புயல். அமெரிக்காவின் மினியாபோலிஸில் நடைபெற்ற சர்வதேச ஒய் ஆண்கள் மாநாட்டில் கலந்து கொண்டு நாடு திரும்பியதும் அவர் அதை இலங்கையில் தொடங்கினார். இலங்கையில் முதல் Y's Men's Club 1929 இல் கொழும்பில் தனது செயற்பாடுகளை ஆரம்பித்தது மற்றும் Y's Men's Club of Colombo என அழைக்கப்பட்டது, அது இன்றுவரை தொடர்ந்து செயல்பட்டு வளர்ந்து வருகிறது.",
        "ஜெனிவாவில் உள்ள சர்வதேச Y's Men இன் ஒரு பகுதியாக \"கொழும்பு கிளப்\" பட்டயப்படுத்தப்பட்ட மைல்கல் நிகழ்வு, 1930 டிசம்பரில் இலங்கையின் முன்னாள் கவர்னர் ஜெனரலாக இருந்த மறைந்த சர் ஒலிவர் குணதிலக, கிளப்பின் முதல் பட்டயத் தலைவராக இருந்தார். Y’s Men’s இயக்கம் இந்தியாவிற்கு அறிமுகப்படுத்தப்பட்டதும் கொழும்பு கிளப் மூலம் தான்.",
        "பின்னர் 1975 இல் இலங்கை தனியான பிராந்தியமாக மாறியது. புதிதாகப் பிறந்த “இலங்கை பிராந்தியத்தின்” முதல் பிராந்திய மாநாடு 1976 செப்டம்பரில் கண்டியில் நடைபெற்றது, இதில் ஏராளமானோர் கலந்து கொண்டனர்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Y's Men Intl",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "ஆசிய பசிபிக்",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "Ben Tsutomu",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "கொழும்பில் வை.எம்",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "இன்று",
          "label": "DATE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Y's Men International",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "90 ஆண்டுகளுக்கு மேல்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "46வது",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "கிராண்ட் ஓரியண்டல் ஹோட்டல், கொழும்பு",
            "label": "FAC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "YM Ohno Ben Tsutomu",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "கோபி துறைமுகம்",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜப்பான்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "மேற்கு மண்டலம்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆண்டு",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "பிரதம விருந்தினர்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "சுடோமு",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆசியா பசிபிக் ஒய் ஆண்கள் பகுதி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "தென்கிழக்கு ஆசியா",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜப்பான் கிழக்கு",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜப்பான் மேற்கு",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "தைவான்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "பிலிப்பைன்ஸ்",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "மில்ராய் மானுவல்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "2022/'23",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஒய்.எம்.அன்டன் காண்டியா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இரண்டு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை ஒலிபரப்புக் கூட்டுத்தாபனம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "விஜயா கொரியா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "மாநாடு",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஒன்று",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "டோலிடோ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஓஹியோ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "அமெரிக்கா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "1922",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Y's ஆண்கள்",
            "label": "WORK_OF_ART"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆர்.ஓ. புயல்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "மினியாபோலிஸ்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "அமெரிக்கா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "முதலில்",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "1929",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Y's Men's Club of Colombo",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்த நாள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "சர்வதேச ஒய்'ஸ் ஆண்கள்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜெனிவா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "டிசம்பர் 1930",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஒலிவர் குணதிலக",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "சங்கம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "முதலில்",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "கொழும்பு கிளப்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்தியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பின்னர் இலங்கை",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "1975",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "கண்டி",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "செப்டம்பர் 1976",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  },
  "title": "Y’s Men Intl. Asia Pacific President Ben Tsutomu to address YM Convention in Colombo today",
  "body_lines": [
    "Y’s Men International movement, the premier movement oriented to serve MCAs and is also renowned for assisting communities across Sri Lanka for over 90 years, will hold its 46th national convention today at the Grand Oriental Hotel, Colombo.",
    "No less than the Y’s Men International Asia Pacific Area President YM Ohno Ben Tsutomu (of Kobe Port Y’s Men’s Club, Japan West Region) will address this year’s event as the Chief Guest. YM Tsutomu leads the large group of diverse Clubs spread across Asia Pacific Y’s Men Area that includes Sri Lanka, along with the Regions of Australia, Southeast Asia, Japan East and Japan West, Taiwan, and the Philippines.",
    "At today’s convention in Colombo, the Present Sri Lanka Regional Director Milroy Manuel will conclude his term thus opening the way for incoming 2022/’23 Sri Lanka Regional Director YM Anton Kandiah, who held the mantle of the Sri Lanka Regional Director previously on two occasions.",
    "Renowned compere, TV Presenter, show-biz personality and Sri Lanka Broadcasting Corporation former Director General Dr. Vijaya Corea will deliver the keynote address of the Convention.",
    "The global Y’s Men movement was one of the earliest global community service movements to be launched and was founded in Toledo, Ohio, USA in 1922. Despite being titled, “Y’s Men”, many women too are among its members today and family participation is widely seen in numerous service activities.",
    "The movement was introduced to Sri Lanka by the Colombo YMCA first General Secretary the late YM R.O. Buell. He launched it in Sri Lanka upon his return to the country after attending an International Y’s Men Convention in Minneapolis, USA. The first Y’s Men’s Club in Sri Lanka began its operations in 1929 in Colombo and was called Y’s Men’s Club of Colombo, which continues to function and grow to this day.",
    "The milestone event of Chartering the “Colombo Club” to be part of International Y’s Men, Geneva, took place in December 1930 with late Sir Oliver Goonetilleka, the former Governor-General of Ceylon, being the Club’s first Charter President. It was also through the Colombo Club that the Y’s Men’s movement was introduced to India.",
    "Later Sri Lanka became a separate Region of its own in 1975. The first Regional Convention of the newborn “Sri Lanka Region” was held in Kandy in September 1976, attended by a large gathering."
  ],
  "translate": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Y’s Men Intl. Asia Pacific President Ben Tsutomu to address YM Convention in Colombo today",
      "author": "",
      "body_lines": [
        "Y’s Men International movement, the premier movement oriented to serve MCAs and is also renowned for assisting communities across Sri Lanka for over 90 years, will hold its 46th national convention today at the Grand Oriental Hotel, Colombo.",
        "No less than the Y’s Men International Asia Pacific Area President YM Ohno Ben Tsutomu (of Kobe Port Y’s Men’s Club, Japan West Region) will address this year’s event as the Chief Guest. YM Tsutomu leads the large group of diverse Clubs spread across Asia Pacific Y’s Men Area that includes Sri Lanka, along with the Regions of Australia, Southeast Asia, Japan East and Japan West, Taiwan, and the Philippines.",
        "At today’s convention in Colombo, the Present Sri Lanka Regional Director Milroy Manuel will conclude his term thus opening the way for incoming 2022/’23 Sri Lanka Regional Director YM Anton Kandiah, who held the mantle of the Sri Lanka Regional Director previously on two occasions.",
        "Renowned compere, TV Presenter, show-biz personality and Sri Lanka Broadcasting Corporation former Director General Dr. Vijaya Corea will deliver the keynote address of the Convention.",
        "The global Y’s Men movement was one of the earliest global community service movements to be launched and was founded in Toledo, Ohio, USA in 1922. Despite being titled, “Y’s Men”, many women too are among its members today and family participation is widely seen in numerous service activities.",
        "The movement was introduced to Sri Lanka by the Colombo YMCA first General Secretary the late YM R.O. Buell. He launched it in Sri Lanka upon his return to the country after attending an International Y’s Men Convention in Minneapolis, USA. The first Y’s Men’s Club in Sri Lanka began its operations in 1929 in Colombo and was called Y’s Men’s Club of Colombo, which continues to function and grow to this day.",
        "The milestone event of Chartering the “Colombo Club” to be part of International Y’s Men, Geneva, took place in December 1930 with late Sir Oliver Goonetilleka, the former Governor-General of Ceylon, being the Club’s first Charter President. It was also through the Colombo Club that the Y’s Men’s movement was introduced to India.",
        "Later Sri Lanka became a separate Region of its own in 1975. The first Regional Convention of the newborn “Sri Lanka Region” was held in Kandy in September 1976, attended by a large gathering."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Y’s Men Intl",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "Asia Pacific",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "Ben Tsutomu",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "YM Convention in Colombo",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "today",
          "label": "DATE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Y’s Men International",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "over 90 years",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "46th",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Grand Oriental Hotel, Colombo",
            "label": "FAC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "YM Ohno Ben Tsutomu",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kobe Port",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "Japan",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "West Region",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "year",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Chief Guest",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Tsutomu",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Asia Pacific Y’s Men Area",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Southeast Asia",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "Japan East",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "Japan West",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Taiwan",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Philippines",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Milroy Manuel",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "2022/’23",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "YM Anton Kandiah",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "two",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka Broadcasting Corporation",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Vijaya Corea",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Convention",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "one",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Toledo",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ohio",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "USA",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "1922",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Y’s Men",
            "label": "WORK_OF_ART"
          },
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "R.O. Buell",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Minneapolis",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "USA",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "first",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "1929",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Y’s Men’s Club of Colombo",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "this day",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "International Y’s Men",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Geneva",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "December 1930",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Oliver Goonetilleka",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Club",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "first",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Colombo Club",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "India",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Later Sri Lanka",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "1975",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kandy",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "September 1976",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "Y’s Men Intl. ආසියා ශාන්තිකර කලාපීය ජනාධිපති බෙන් සුටෝමු අද කොළඹ දී YM සමුළුව ඇමතීමට නියමිතය",
      "author": "",
      "body_lines": [
        "වසර 90 කට වැඩි කාලයක් ශ්‍රී ලංකාව පුරා සිටින ප්‍රජාවන්ට උපකාර කිරීම සම්බන්ධයෙන් ද ප්‍රසිද්ධියක් උසුලන MCA සඳහා සේවය කිරීමට නැඹුරු වූ ප්‍රමුඛතම ව්‍යාපාරය වන Y’s Men International ව්‍යාපාරය සිය 46 වැනි ජාතික සමුළුව අද කොළඹ Grand Oriental හෝටලයේදී පැවැත්වේ.",
        "Y’s Men International Asia Pacific Area සභාපති YM Ohno Ben Tsutomu (Japan West Region, Kobe Port Y’s Men’s Club) මෙම වසරේ ප්‍රධාන ආරාධිත අමුත්තා ලෙස අමතනු ඇත. ඕස්ට්‍රේලියාව, අග්නිදිග ආසියාව, ජපානය නැගෙනහිර සහ ජපානය බටහිර, තායිවානය සහ පිලිපීනය යන කලාප සමඟින් ශ්‍රී ලංකාව ඇතුළු Asia Pacific Y’s Men Area පුරා පැතිරී ඇති විවිධ සමාජ ශාලා සමූහයට YM Tsutomu නායකත්වය දෙයි.",
        "අද කොළඹදී පැවැත්වෙන සමුළුවේදී වත්මන් ශ්‍රී ලංකා ප්‍රාදේශීය අධ්‍යක්ෂ මිල්රෝයි මැනුවෙල් මහතා සිය ධුර කාලය අවසන් කරන්නේ මීට පෙර අවස්ථා දෙකකදී ශ්‍රී ලංකා ප්‍රාදේශීය අධ්‍යක්ෂ ධුරය දැරූ 2022/'23 ශ්‍රී ලංකා ප්‍රාදේශීය අධ්‍යක්ෂ වයි.එම්.ඇන්ටන් කන්දියා මහතාට මාර්ගය විවෘත කරමිනි .",
        "සම්මුතියේ ප්‍රධාන දේශනය පවත්වනු ලබන්නේ සුප්‍රකට compere, TV ඉදිරිපත් කරන්නා, show-biz පෞරුෂය සහ ශ්‍රී ලංකා ගුවන්විදුලි සංස්ථාවේ හිටපු අධ්‍යක්ෂ ජනරාල් ආචාර්ය විජය කොරයා විසිනි.",
        "ගෝලීය Y's Men ව්‍යාපාරය දියත් කරන ලද මුල්ම ගෝලීය ප්‍රජා සේවා ව්‍යාපාරයක් වන අතර එය 1922 දී ඇමරිකා එක්සත් ජනපදයේ ඔහියෝ හි ටොලෙඩෝ හි ආරම්භ කරන ලදී. \"Y's Men\" ලෙස නම් කර ඇතත්, බොහෝ කාන්තාවන් ද අද එහි සාමාජිකයින් අතර සිටින අතර පවුලේ සහභාගීත්වය ද වේ. බොහෝ සේවා ක්‍රියාකාරකම්වල බහුලව දක්නට ලැබේ.",
        "මෙම ව්‍යාපාරය ශ්‍රී ලංකාවට හඳුන්වා දෙනු ලැබුවේ කොළඹ YMCA පළමු ප්‍රධාන ලේකම් දිවංගත YM R.O විසිනි. බුවෙල්. ඔහු එය ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ දියත් කළේ ඇමරිකා එක්සත් ජනපදයේ මිනියාපොලිස් හි පැවති ජාත්‍යන්තර Y’s Men සම්මුතියකට සහභාගී වී ආපසු මෙරටට පැමිණි පසුවය. ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ ප්‍රථම Y’s පිරිමි සමාජය 1929 දී කොළඹදී සිය මෙහෙයුම් ආරම්භ කළ අතර එය අද දක්වාම ක්‍රියාත්මක වෙමින් වර්ධනය වෙමින් පවතින Y’s Men’s Club of Colombo ලෙස හැඳින්විණි.",
        "ජාත්‍යන්තර Y's Men, Geneva හි කොටසක් වීමට \"Colombo Club\" වරලත් කිරීමේ සන්ධිස්ථානය 1930 දෙසැම්බර් මාසයේදී සිදු වූයේ, ලංකාවේ හිටපු ආණ්ඩුකාරවරයා වූ දිවංගත ශ්‍රීමත් ඔලිවර් ගුණතිලක සමාජයේ ප්‍රථම වරලත් සභාපතිවරයා වීමත් සමඟය. Y’s Men’s ව්‍යාපාරය ඉන්දියාවට හඳුන්වා දුන්නේද Colombo Club හරහාය.",
        "පසුව 1975 දී ශ්‍රී ලංකාව වෙනම කලාපයක් බවට පත් විය. අලුත උපන් “ශ්‍රී ලංකා කලාපයේ” ප්‍රථම ප්‍රාදේශීය සමුළුව 1976 සැප්තැම්බර් මාසයේදී මහනුවරදී පැවැත්වුණු අතර විශාල පිරිසක් සහභාගි වූහ."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Y’s Men Intl",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "ආසියා පැසිෆික්",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "Ben Tsutomu",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "කොළඹ පැවති වයි.එම්",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "අද",
          "label": "DATE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Y’s Men International",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "අවුරුදු 90 ට වැඩි",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "46 වැනි",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ග්‍රෑන්ඩ් ඔරියන්ටල් හෝටලය, කොළඹ",
            "label": "FAC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "YM Ohno Ben Tsutomu",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "කෝබේ වරාය",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජපානය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "බටහිර කලාපය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "වර්ෂය",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ප්‍රධාන ආරාධිතයා",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "සුතොමු",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ආසියා පැසිෆික් Y's පිරිමි ප්රදේශය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගිනිකොනදිග ආසියාව",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජපානය නැගෙනහිර",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "බටහිර ජපානය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "තායිවානය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "පිලිපීනය",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මිල්රෝයි මැනුවෙල්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "2022/'23",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "වයි.එම් ඇන්ටන් කන්දියා",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "දෙක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකා ගුවන් විදුලි සංස්ථාව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "විජය කොරයා",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "සම්මුතිය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "එක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ටොලිඩෝ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඔහියෝ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඇඑජ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "1922",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Y ගේ පිරිමි",
            "label": "WORK_OF_ART"
          },
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "R.O. බුවෙල්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මිනියාපොලිස්",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඇඑජ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "පළමුවන",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "1929",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Y’s පිරිමි සමාජය කොළඹ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "අද දවස",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ජාත්‍යන්තර Y’s පිරිමි",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජිනීවා",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "1930 දෙසැම්බර්",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඔලිවර් ගුණතිලක",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "සමාජය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "පළමුවන",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "කොළඹ සමාජය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "පසුව ශ්‍රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "1975",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මහනුවර",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "1976 සැප්තැම්බර්",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "Y's Men Intl. இன்று கொழும்பில் நடைபெறும் YM மாநாட்டில் ஆசிய பசுபிக் அதிபர் பென் சுடோமு உரையாற்றவுள்ளார்",
      "author": "",
      "body_lines": [
        "90 ஆண்டுகளுக்கும் மேலாக இலங்கை முழுவதிலும் உள்ள சமூகங்களுக்கு உதவுவதில் புகழ்பெற்று விளங்கும், MCA களுக்கு சேவை செய்வதில் முதன்மையான இயக்கமான Y’s Men International இயக்கம், அதன் 46வது தேசிய மாநாட்டை இன்று கொழும்பு Grand Oriental Hotel இல் நடத்தவுள்ளது.",
        "Y's Men இன்டர்நேஷனல் ஆசிய பசிபிக் பகுதியின் தலைவர் YM Ohno Ben Tsutomu (கோப் போர்ட் Y's Men's Club, Japan West Region) இந்த ஆண்டு நிகழ்வில் பிரதம விருந்தினராக கலந்து கொண்டு உரையாற்றுவார். ஆஸ்திரேலியா, தென்கிழக்கு ஆசியா, ஜப்பான் கிழக்கு மற்றும் ஜப்பான் மேற்கு, தைவான் மற்றும் பிலிப்பைன்ஸ் ஆகிய பிராந்தியங்களுடன், இலங்கையை உள்ளடக்கிய ஆசியா பசிபிக் Y's Men பகுதி முழுவதும் பரந்து விரிந்திருக்கும் பல்வேறுபட்ட கிளப்புகளின் பெரிய குழுவிற்கு YM Tsutomu தலைமை தாங்குகிறார்.",
        "கொழும்பில் இன்று நடைபெறும் மாநாட்டில், தற்போதைய இலங்கை பிராந்திய பணிப்பாளர் மில்ரோய் மானுவல் தனது பதவிக் காலத்தை நிறைவு செய்கிறார், இதன் மூலம் 2022/'23 இலங்கை பிராந்திய பணிப்பாளர் வை.எம். அன்டன் கந்தையா, முன்னர் இரண்டு தடவைகள் இலங்கை பிராந்திய பணிப்பாளராக பதவி வகித்தவர். .",
        "புகழ்பெற்ற இசையமைப்பாளர், தொலைக்காட்சி தொகுப்பாளர், நிகழ்ச்சி-பிஸ் ஆளுமை மற்றும் இலங்கை ஒலிபரப்புக் கூட்டுத்தாபனத்தின் முன்னாள் பணிப்பாளர் நாயகம் கலாநிதி விஜய கொரியா மாநாட்டின் முக்கிய உரையை ஆற்றவுள்ளார்.",
        "உலகளாவிய ஒய்ஸ் மென் இயக்கம் தொடங்கப்பட்ட ஆரம்பகால உலகளாவிய சமூக சேவை இயக்கங்களில் ஒன்றாகும், இது 1922 ஆம் ஆண்டில் அமெரிக்காவின் ஓஹியோவில் உள்ள டோலிடோவில் நிறுவப்பட்டது. \"ஒய்'ஸ் மென்\" என்று பெயரிடப்பட்டிருந்தாலும், பல பெண்களும் இன்று உறுப்பினர்களாக உள்ளனர் மற்றும் குடும்ப பங்கேற்பு உள்ளது. பல சேவை நடவடிக்கைகளில் பரவலாகக் காணப்படுகிறது.",
        "கொழும்பு ஒய்எம்சிஏ முதல் பொதுச் செயலாளர் மறைந்த ஒய்எம் ஆர் ஓ அவர்களால் இந்த இயக்கம் இலங்கைக்கு அறிமுகப்படுத்தப்பட்டது. புயல். அமெரிக்காவின் மினியாபோலிஸில் நடைபெற்ற சர்வதேச ஒய் ஆண்கள் மாநாட்டில் கலந்து கொண்டு நாடு திரும்பியதும் அவர் அதை இலங்கையில் தொடங்கினார். இலங்கையில் முதல் Y's Men's Club 1929 இல் கொழும்பில் தனது செயற்பாடுகளை ஆரம்பித்தது மற்றும் Y's Men's Club of Colombo என அழைக்கப்பட்டது, அது இன்றுவரை தொடர்ந்து செயல்பட்டு வளர்ந்து வருகிறது.",
        "ஜெனிவாவில் உள்ள சர்வதேச Y's Men இன் ஒரு பகுதியாக \"கொழும்பு கிளப்\" பட்டயப்படுத்தப்பட்ட மைல்கல் நிகழ்வு, 1930 டிசம்பரில் இலங்கையின் முன்னாள் கவர்னர் ஜெனரலாக இருந்த மறைந்த சர் ஒலிவர் குணதிலக, கிளப்பின் முதல் பட்டயத் தலைவராக இருந்தார். Y’s Men’s இயக்கம் இந்தியாவிற்கு அறிமுகப்படுத்தப்பட்டதும் கொழும்பு கிளப் மூலம் தான்.",
        "பின்னர் 1975 இல் இலங்கை தனியான பிராந்தியமாக மாறியது. புதிதாகப் பிறந்த “இலங்கை பிராந்தியத்தின்” முதல் பிராந்திய மாநாடு 1976 செப்டம்பரில் கண்டியில் நடைபெற்றது, இதில் ஏராளமானோர் கலந்து கொண்டனர்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Y's Men Intl",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "ஆசிய பசிபிக்",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "Ben Tsutomu",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "கொழும்பில் வை.எம்",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "இன்று",
          "label": "DATE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Y's Men International",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "90 ஆண்டுகளுக்கு மேல்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "46வது",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "கிராண்ட் ஓரியண்டல் ஹோட்டல், கொழும்பு",
            "label": "FAC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "YM Ohno Ben Tsutomu",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "கோபி துறைமுகம்",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜப்பான்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "மேற்கு மண்டலம்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆண்டு",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "பிரதம விருந்தினர்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "சுடோமு",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆசியா பசிபிக் ஒய் ஆண்கள் பகுதி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "தென்கிழக்கு ஆசியா",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜப்பான் கிழக்கு",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜப்பான் மேற்கு",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "தைவான்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "பிலிப்பைன்ஸ்",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "மில்ராய் மானுவல்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "2022/'23",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஒய்.எம்.அன்டன் காண்டியா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இரண்டு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை ஒலிபரப்புக் கூட்டுத்தாபனம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "விஜயா கொரியா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "மாநாடு",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஒன்று",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "டோலிடோ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஓஹியோ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "அமெரிக்கா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "1922",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Y's ஆண்கள்",
            "label": "WORK_OF_ART"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆர்.ஓ. புயல்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "மினியாபோலிஸ்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "அமெரிக்கா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "முதலில்",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "1929",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Y's Men's Club of Colombo",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்த நாள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "சர்வதேச ஒய்'ஸ் ஆண்கள்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜெனிவா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
