{
  "newspaper_id": "lankadeepa-lk",
  "url": "https://www.lankadeepa.lk/latest_news/රන්ජන්ට-කොන්දේසි-සහිත-සමාවක්/1-618776",
  "time_ut": 1661492717,
  "original_lang": "si",
  "original_title": "රන්ජන්ට කොන්දේසි සහිත සමාවක්",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "A conditional pardon for Ranjan",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "President Ranil Wickramasinghe today (26) signed the document regarding the granting of presidential pardon to former state minister Mr. Ranjan Ramanayake, who was convicted and sentenced to prison for contempt of court.",
        "The President has arranged to grant a conditional pardon that he will not make any statement or action that insults the court from now on.",
        "Arrangements have also been made to assign the Secretary of the Ministry of Justice to carry out further work regarding the release of Mr. Ranjan Ramanayake.",
        "On 12 January 2021 he was sentenced to four years imprisonment with hard labor by the Supreme Court after filing the first case for the statement made outside the Temple House on 21 August 2017.",
        "Mr. Ranjan Ramanayake issued an affidavit and apologized for insulting the court yesterday (25).",
        "It has been mentioned in the affidavit that the statements made by him are completely wrong and he apologizes for causing disrespect to everyone in the legal field including the Chief Justice.",
        "Former State Minister Mr. Ranjan Ramanayake has further stated in the affidavit given to the court that the statements made by him are false and that he will retract those statements and will not make such statements in the future."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Ranjan",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickramasinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "26",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ranjan Ramanayake",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "the Ministry of Justice",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ranjan Ramanayake",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "12 January 2021",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "four years",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Supreme Court",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Temple House",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "21 August 2017",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Ranjan Ramanayake",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "yesterday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "25",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "State",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ranjan Ramanayake",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "රන්ජන්ට කොන්දේසි සහිත සමාවක්",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "අධිකරණයට අපහාස කිරීම සම්බන්ධයෙන් වරදකරුවී සිර දඬුවම් ලබන හිටපු රාජ්‍ය ඇමති රන්ජන් රාමනායක මහතාට ජනාධිපති සමාව ලබාදීම සම්බන්ධයෙන් වූ ලේඛනයට ජනාධිපති රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතා අද (26) අත්සන් තැබීය.",
        "මින් ඉදිරියට අධිකරණයට අපහාස වන කිසිදු ප්‍රකාශයක් හෝ ක්‍රියාවක් සිදු නොකරන ලෙස වන කොන්දේසි සහිත සමාවක් ලබාදීමට ජනාධිපතිවරයා මෙහිදී කටයුතු කර ඇත.",
        "රන්ජන් රාමනායක මහතාට නිදහස ලබාදීම සම්බන්ධයෙන් ඉදිරි කටයුතු සිදුකිරීමට අධිකරණ අමාත්‍යාංශ ලේකම්වරයාට පැවරීමට ද කටයුතු කර තිබේ.",
        "2017 අගෝස්තු 21වනදා අරලියගහ මන්දිරයෙන් පිටත සිදුකළ ප්‍රකාශයට පළමු නඩුව ගොනු කරමින් 2021 ජනවාරි 12 වන දින ඔහුට ශ්‍රේෂ්ඨාධිකරණය විසින් වසර හතරක බරපතල වැඩ සහිත සිරදඬුවමක් නියම කෙරිණි.",
        "රන්ජන් රාමනායක මහතා දිවුරුම් ප්‍රකාශයක් යොමු කරමින් අධිකරණයට අපහාස කිරීම සම්බන්ධයෙන් සමාව අයදීම ඊයේ (25) සිදු කළේය.",
        "තමන් සිදු කළ ප්‍රකාශ සම්පූර්ණයෙන් වැරදි බවත් එම ප්‍රකාශය නිසා අගවිනිසුරු ඇතුළු නීති ක්ෂේත්‍රයේ  සියලුදෙනාට අගෞරවයක් ඇතිවීම සම්බන්ධයෙන් සමාව ඉල්ලා සිටින බවත් එම දිවුරුම් ප්‍රකාශයේ සඳහන් කර ඇත.",
        "තමා විසින් සිදුකරන ලද ප්‍රකාශ අසත්‍ය බවත් එම ප්‍රකාශ ඉල්ලා අස්කර ගන්නා බවටත් ඉදිරියේදී මෙවැනි ප්‍රකාශ සිදු නොකරන බවටත් හිටපු රාජ්‍ය ඇමති රන්ජන් රාමනායක මහතා අධිකරණයට ලබාදුන් දිවුරුම් ප්‍රකාශයේ වැඩිදුරටත්  සඳහන් කර තිබේ."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "රන්ජන්",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "26",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "රන්ජන් රාමනායක",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "අධිකරණ අමාත්යාංශය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "රන්ජන් රාමනායක",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "2021 ජනවාරි 12",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "අවුරුදු හතරක්",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රේෂ්ඨාධිකරණය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "පන්සල් මන්දිරය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "2017 අගෝස්තු 21",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "රන්ජන් රාමනායක",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඊයේ",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "25",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "රජයේ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "රන්ජන් රාමනායක",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "ரஞ்சனுக்கு நிபந்தனையுடன் கூடிய மன்னிப்பு",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "நீதிமன்றத்தை அவமதித்த குற்றச்சாட்டில் குற்றவாளியாக அறிவிக்கப்பட்டு சிறைத்தண்டனை விதிக்கப்பட்ட முன்னாள் இராஜாங்க அமைச்சர் திரு.ரஞ்சன் ராமநாயக்கவுக்கு ஜனாதிபதி பொதுமன்னிப்பு வழங்குவது தொடர்பான ஆவணத்தில் ஜனாதிபதி ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க இன்று (26) கையொப்பமிட்டுள்ளார்.",
        "இனிமேல் நீதிமன்றத்தை அவமதிக்கும் வகையிலான எந்தவொரு அறிக்கையையோ அல்லது நடவடிக்கையையோ மேற்கொள்ள வேண்டாம் என ஜனாதிபதி நிபந்தனையுடன் கூடிய மன்னிப்பு வழங்க ஏற்பாடு செய்துள்ளார்.",
        "திரு.ரஞ்சன் ராமநாயக்கவின் விடுதலை தொடர்பான மேலதிக பணிகளை மேற்கொள்வதற்கு நீதி அமைச்சின் செயலாளரை நியமிக்கவும் ஏற்பாடுகள் செய்யப்பட்டுள்ளன.",
        "21 ஆகஸ்ட் 2017 அன்று டெம்பிள் ஹவுஸுக்கு வெளியே செய்யப்பட்ட அறிக்கைக்காக முதல் வழக்கைத் தாக்கல் செய்த பின்னர், 12 ஜனவரி 2021 அன்று உச்ச நீதிமன்றத்தால் அவருக்கு நான்கு ஆண்டுகள் கடுங்காவல் சிறைத்தண்டனை விதிக்கப்பட்டது.",
        "நீதிமன்றத்தை அவமதித்ததற்காக திரு.ரஞ்சன் ராமநாயக்க நேற்று (25) சத்தியக் கடதாசி ஒன்றை வெளியிட்டு மன்னிப்புக் கோரினார்.",
        "அவர் தெரிவித்த கருத்துக்கள் முற்றிலும் தவறானவை என்றும், பிரதம நீதியரசர் உட்பட சட்டத்துறையில் உள்ள அனைவருக்கும் அவமரியாதையை ஏற்படுத்தியதற்காக மன்னிப்பு கோருவதாகவும் அந்த வாக்குமூலத்தில் குறிப்பிடப்பட்டுள்ளது.",
        "முன்னாள் இராஜாங்க அமைச்சர் திரு.ரஞ்சன் ராமநாயக்க நீதிமன்றில் வழங்கிய வாக்குமூலத்தில் மேலும் தெரிவித்துள்ளதாவது, தாம் கூறிய கருத்துக்கள் பொய்யானவை எனவும், அந்த அறிக்கைகளை வாபஸ் பெறுவதாகவும், எதிர்காலத்தில் அவ்வாறான அறிக்கைகளை வெளியிடப் போவதில்லை எனவும் தெரிவித்துள்ளார்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ரஞ்சன்",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "26",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரஞ்சன் ராமநாயக்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "நீதி அமைச்சகம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரஞ்சன் ராமநாயக்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "12 ஜனவரி 2021",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "நான்கு வருடங்கள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "உச்ச நீதிமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "கோவில் வீடு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "21 ஆகஸ்ட் 2017",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ரஞ்சன் ராமநாயக்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "நேற்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "25",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "நிலை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரஞ்சன் ராமநாயக்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}