{
  "newspaper_id": "virakesari-lk",
  "url": "http://www.virakesari.lk/article/131518",
  "time_ut": 1657868179,
  "original_lang": "ta",
  "original_title": "கோட்டாபயவின் வருகையும் வெளியேற்றமும்",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Arrival and exodus of Gotabaya",
      "author": "Vishnu",
      "body_lines": [
        "Gotabaya Rajapaksa, the 7th executive president of Sri Lanka, who has a military background without direct participation in politics, has resigned due to the pressure of the people's spontaneous protests. Speaker Mahindayapa Abeywardena has announced that he has received his official letter of resignation.",
        "In the presidential election held on 16 November 2019, Gotabaya Rajapaksa won a massive victory with 69 lakh 24 thousand 255 votes. He got 52.25 percent of the preference votes. Gotabaya Rajapaksa received more votes in the 8th presidential election in 2019 than the candidates who won in the 7 presidential elections from 1982 to 2015 in the history of Sri Lanka.",
        "He held important positions in the army and was also seen as the first president of Sri Lanka with a military background. He retired from the army at an early stage and went to the United States and served as the defense secretary in 2005 when his brother Mahinda Rajapaksa was elected president. After the 2015 regime change, he had a bit of a break from active politics, but he won the 2019 presidential election by a landslide.",
        "National security and economic development were seen as the main issues in his election policy declaration.",
        "However, due to improper economic approaches and irresponsible decisions, Sri Lanka's downfall is due to his rule. He has received the support of more than 69 lakh people, but he has been forced to resign due to the hatred of the people of the entire country.",
        "Because of this, Gotabaya Rajapaksa is the first executive president to resign before the end of his term in Sri Lankan political history. Due to the decisions taken by him, all the people, starting from the farmers, have faced severe hardships without any discrimination. The people enraged by the crisis and the peaceful uprisings of the young generation hoping for a change in the Sri Lankan political system took Gotabaya Rajapaksa to the point of announcing his resignation from another country.",
        "His resignation has taught a great lesson to all politicians that a country should not be managed and how responsible the next rulers should be. Although this resignation will not immediately solve the problems in the country, it is the position of most that Gotabaya Rajapaksa has escaped from being held responsible for all these."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Arrival",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "Gotabaya",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Gotabaya Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "7th",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Mahindayapa Abeywardena",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "16 November 2019",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Gotabaya Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "69",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "24 thousand 255",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "52.25 percent",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "Gotabaya Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "8th",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "2019",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "7",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "from 1982 to 2015",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "first",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the United States",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "2005",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Mahinda Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "2015",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "2019",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka's",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "more than 69",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Gotabaya Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "first",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lankan",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lankan",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "Gotabaya Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Gotabaya Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "ගෝඨාභයගේ පැමිණීම සහ නික්මයාම",
      "author": "විෂ්ණු",
      "body_lines": [
        "දේශපාලනයේ සෘජු දායකත්වයක් නොමැති යුදමය පසුබිමක් ඇති ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ 7 වැනි විධායක ජනාධිපතිවරයා වන ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ මහතා ජනතා ස්වයංසිද්ධ විරෝධතාවල පීඩනය හේතුවෙන් ඉල්ලා අස්වී තිබේ. සිය ඉල්ලා අස්වීමේ නිල ලිපිය ලැබුණු බව කථානායක මහින්දයාපා අබේවර්ධන මහතා නිවේදනය කළේය.",
        "2019 නොවැම්බර් 16 වැනිදා පැවති ජනාධිපතිවරණයෙන් ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ මහතා ඡන්ද 69 ලක්ෂ 24,255කින් දැවැන්ත ජයග්‍රහණයක් ලබා ගත්තේය. ඔහු මනාප සියයට 52.25ක් ලබා ගත්තා. ශ්‍රී ලංකා ඉතිහාසයේ 1982 සිට 2015 දක්වා පැවති ජනාධිපතිවරණ 7 න් ජයග්‍රහණය කළ අපේක්ෂකයින්ට වඩා වැඩි ඡන්ද ප්‍රමාණයක් 2019 වසරේ 8 වැනි ජනාධිපතිවරණයේදී ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂට ලැබිණි.",
        "ඔහු හමුදාවේ වැදගත් තනතුරු දැරූ අතර හමුදා පසුබිමක් ඇති ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ පළමු ජනාධිපතිවරයා ලෙසද සැලකේ. ඔහු මුල් අවදියේදීම හමුදාවෙන් විශ්‍රාම ගෙන අමෙරිකාවට ගොස් 2005 වසරේ සිය සොහොයුරු මහින්ද රාජපක්ෂ මහතා ජනාධිපති ධුරයට පත්වන විට ආරක්ෂක ලේකම්වරයා ලෙස කටයුතු කළේය. 2015 පාලන තන්ත්‍ර වෙනසෙන් පසු ඔහුට ක්‍රියාකාරී දේශපාලනයෙන් මදක් විරාමයක් තිබුණත් 2019 ජනාධිපතිවරණයෙන් ඔහු විශිෂ්ට ලෙස ජයග්‍රහණය කළේය.",
        "ඔහුගේ මැතිවරණ ප්‍රතිපත්ති ප්‍රකාශයේ ප්‍රධාන කරුණු ලෙස සැලකුණේ ජාතික ආරක්ෂාව සහ ආර්ථික සංවර්ධනයයි.",
        "කෙසේ වෙතත්, නුසුදුසු ආර්ථික ප්‍රවේශයන් සහ වගකීම් විරහිත තීරණ හේතුවෙන් ශ්‍රී ලංකාව කඩා වැටීමට හේතුව ඔහුගේ පාලනයයි. 69 ලක්ෂයකට අධික ජනතාවගේ සහයෝගය ඔහුට ලැබී ඇතත් මුළු රටේම ජනතාවගේ වෛරය නිසා ඔහුට ඉල්ලා අස්වීමට සිදුවී ඇත.",
        "මේ නිසා ශ්‍රී ලංකා දේශපාලන ඉතිහාසයේ සිය ධුර කාලය අවසන් වීමට පෙර ඉල්ලා අස් වූ පළමු විධායක ජනාධිපතිවරයා වන්නේ ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂයි. එතුමා ගත් තීන්දු තීරණ නිසා ගොවියාගේ පටන් සියලු ජනතාව කිසිදු භේදයකින් තොරව දැඩි දුෂ්කරතාවලට මුහුණ දී තිබෙනවා. ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ දේශපාලන ක්‍රමයේ වෙනසක් බලාපොරොත්තු වූ තරුණ පරම්පරාවේ අර්බුදය සහ සාමකාමී නැගිටීම් නිසා කෝපයට පත් ජනතාව ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ වෙනත් රටක සිට ඉල්ලා අස්වන බව ප්‍රකාශ කරන තැනට ගෙන ගියහ.",
        "රටක් කළමනාකරණය නොකළ යුතු බවත්, ඊළඟට එන පාලකයන් කෙතරම් වගකීමෙන් කටයුතු කළ යුතුද යන්නත් ඔහුගේ ඉල්ලා අස්වීම සියලු දේශපාලනඥයන්ට කදිම පාඩමක් උගන්වා තිබේ. මෙම ඉල්ලා අස්වීමෙන් රටේ ප්‍රශ්නවලට ක්ෂණික විසඳුමක් නොලැබුණත් මේ සියල්ලටම වගකිව යුත්තේ ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ මහතා බව බොහෝ දෙනාගේ ස්ථාවරයයි."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "පැමිණීම",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "ගෝඨාභය",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "7 වැනි",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මහින්දයාපා අබේවර්ධන",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "2019 නොවැම්බර් 16",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "69",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "24,255 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "සියයට 52.25 කි",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "8 වැනි",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "2019",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "7",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "1982 සිට 2015 දක්වා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "පළමුවන",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "එක්සත් ජනපදය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "2005",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මහින්ද රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "2015",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "2019",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "69 ට වැඩි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "පළමුවන",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලාංකික",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලාංකික",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "கோட்டாபயவின் வருகையும் வெளியேற்றமும்",
      "author": "Vishnu",
      "body_lines": [
        "அரசியலில் நேரடி பங்கேற்பற்ற இராணுவ பின்புலத்தைக் கொண்ட இலங்கையின் 7 ஆவது நிறைவேற்றதிகார ஜனாதிபதி கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ஷ , மக்களின் தன்னெழுச்சி போராட்டங்களின் அழுத்தத்தினால் இராஜினாமா செய்துள்ளார். அவரது உத்தியோகபூர்வ பதவி விலகல் கடிதம் தனக்கு கிடைக்கப் பெற்றுள்ளதாக சபாநாயகர் மஹிந்தயாபா அபேவர்தனவால் அறிவிக்கப்பட்டுள்ளது.",
        "கடந்த 2019 ஆம் ஆண்டு நவம்பர் 16 ஆம் திகதி இடம்பெற்ற ஜனாதிபதித் தேர்தலில் கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ஷ 69 இலட்சத்து 24 ஆயிரத்து 255 விருப்பு வாக்குகளால் பாரிய வெற்றியைப் பெற்றுக் கொண்டார். இவர் பெற்றுக் கொண்ட விருப்பு வாக்குகள் நூற்றுக்கு 52.25 சதவீதமாகும். இலங்கை வரலாற்றில் 1982 முதல் 2015 வரை இடம்பெற்றுள்ள 7 ஜனாதிபதி தேர்தல்களில் வெற்றி பெற்ற வேட்பாளர்களை விட , 2019 இல் இடம்பெற்ற 8 ஆவது ஜனாதிபதித் தேர்தலில் கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ஷ பெற்றுக் கொண்ட வாக்குகளே அதிகூடிய வாக்குகளாகப் பதிவாகியுள்ளன.",
        "இராணுவத்தில் முக்கிய பதவிகளை வகித்த இவரே இலங்கையில் இராணுவ பின்புலம் கொண்ட முதலாவது ஜனாதிபதியாகவும் காணப்பட்டார். ஆரம்ப கால கட்டத்திலேயே இராணுவத்திலிருந்து ஓய்வு பெற்று அமெரிக்கா சென்ற இவர் , 2005 இல் தனது சகோதரரான மஹிந்த ராஜபக்ஷ ஜனாதிபதியாக தெரிவு செய்யப்பட்ட போது பாதுகாப்பு செயலாளராகவும் பதவி வகித்தார். 2015 ஆட்சி மாற்றத்தின் பின்னர் செயற்பாட்டு அரசியலிலிருந்து சற்று விலகிருந்த போதிலும் , 2019 ஜனாதிபதித் தேர்தலில் பாரிய வெற்றியைப் பெற்றுக் கொண்டார்.",
        "தேசிய பாதுகாப்பு மற்றும் பொருளாதார அபிவிருத்தி என்பவையே இவரின் தேர்தல் கொள்கை பிரகடனத்தில் பிரதான விடயங்களாகக் காணப்பட்டன.",
        "எவ்வாறிருப்பினும் முறையற்ற பொருளாதார அணுகுமுறைகளாலும் , பொறுத்தமற்ற தீர்மானங்களாலும் வங்குரோத்தடைந்த நாடாக இலங்கை வீழ்ச்சியடை இவரது ஆட்சி காரணமாக அமைந்துள்ளது. 69 இலட்சத்திற்கும் அதிக மக்களின் விருப்பினைப் பெற்ற இவர் , ஒட்டுமொத்த நாட்டு மக்களின் வெறுப்பிற்குள்ளாகி அவர்களின் அழுத்தத்தினால் பதவியை இராஜிநாமா செய்யும் நிலைக்கு தள்ளப்பட்டுள்ளார்.",
        "இதன் காரணமாக பதவி காலம் நிறைவடைவதற்கு முன்னரே தனது பதவியை இராஜிநாமா செய்த முதலாவது நிறைவேற்றதிகார ஜனாதிபதியாகவும் கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ஷ இலங்கை அரசியல் வரலாற்றில் இடம்பிடித்துள்ளார். இவரால் எடுக்கப்பட்ட தீர்மானங்களால் விவசாயிகள் முதற்கொண்டு எவ்வித பாரபட்சமும் இன்றி சகல மக்களும் கடும் நெருக்கடிகளை எதிர்கொண்டுள்ளனர். நெருக்கடிகளால் ஆத்திரமடைந்த மக்களினதும் , இலங்கை அரசியல் முறைமையில் மாற்றத்தினை எதிர்பார்க்கும் இளம் தலைமுறையினரின் அமைதியான தன்னெழுச்சி போராட்டங்களும் கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ஷவை பிரிதொரு நாட்டிலிருந்து பதவி விலகலை அறிவிக்கச் செய்யுமளவிற்கு கொண்டு சென்றன.",
        "ஒரு நாட்டை நிர்வகிக்கக் கூடாது என்றும் , அடுத்து வரும் ஆட்சியாளர்கள் எந்தளவிற்கு பொறுப்புடன் செயற்பட வேண்டும் என்று சகல அரசியல்வாதிகளுக்கும் இவரது பதவி விலகலானது சிறந்த பாடத்தைக் கற்பித்துக் கொடுத்திருக்கிறது. இந்த  பதவி விலகலால் நாட்டிலுள்ள பிரச்சினைகளுக்கு உடனடியாக தீர்வு கிடைக்கப் போவதில்லை என்றாலும் , இவை அனைத்திற்குமான பொறுப்பு கூறலிலிருந்து கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ஷ தப்பியுள்ளார் என்பதே பெரும்பாலானோரின் நிலைப்பாடாகவுள்ளது."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "வருகை",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "கோட்டாபய",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "7வது",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "மஹிந்தயாப அபேவர்தன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "16 நவம்பர் 2019",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "69",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "24 ஆயிரத்து 255",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "52.25 சதவீதம்",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "8வது",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "2019",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "7",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "1982 முதல் 2015 வரை",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "முதலில்",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஐக்கிய நாடுகள்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "2005",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "மஹிந்த ராஜபக்ஷ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "2015",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "2019",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கையின்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "69க்கு மேல்",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "முதலில்",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}