{
  "newspaper_id": "economy-next-com",
  "url": "https://economynext.com/sri-lankan-airlines-loses-rs248bn-in-four-months-after-soft-peg-collapse-96916/",
  "time_ut": 1656984360,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Sri Lankan Airlines loses Rs248bn in four months after soft-peg collapse",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Sri Lankan Airlines loses Rs248bn in four months after soft-peg collapse",
      "author": "",
      "body_lines": [
        "ECONOMYNEXT – Sri Lanka’s state-run SriLankan Airlines has lost 248 billion rupees up to April 2022 with most of it coming from the collapse of the currency, official data showed, amid the worst currency crisis in the history of its intermediate regime central bank.",
        "SriLankan Airlines had earned revenues of Rs71.82 billion in the first four months of 2022.",
        "The airline had lost Rs248.44 billion in the first four months with 145 billion rupees coming from a foreign exchange loss.",
        "Sri Lanka’s rupee collapsed from 200 to 341 to the US dollar by end April 2022 in an attempt to float the currency with a surrender rule.",
        "SriLankan Airlines (SLA) has Rs 618,677.61 million in liabilities, including sovereign guaranteed US$ 175 million bond, Treasury guaranteed bank loans from state banks, aircraft leases, and debt with trade creditors, primarily Ceylon Petroleum Corporation, a Finance Ministry report said.",
        "Sri Lankan has a dollar arrears to Ceylon Petroleum Corporation on fuel bought before 2019. But now it pays in US dollars in time.",
        "“In this context, the government is no longer able to finance SLA’s losses and there is an urgent requirement to restructure SLA’s balance sheet and convert its operating model into a profitable structure,” the report said.",
        "While aircraft leases relate to currently revenue earning assets, the 175 million bond and CPC arrears were taken to fund legacy losses.",
        "Prime Minister Ranil Wickremesinghe has said the airline has to be privatized.",
        "The rupee has collaped from 131 to around 370 to the US dollar after ‘flexible inflation targeting’ began where a notoriously unstable reserve collecting soft-peg was bombarded with open market operations, either to boost inflation (2015) or to boost growth (output gap targeting) from 2018.",
        "State-run Ceylon Petroleum Corporation has been hit a 628 billion loss due to the soft-pegged exchange rate regime and loans taken after printing money.",
        "Sri Lanka’s CPC in shocking Rs628bn loss on soft-pegging loans",
        "Sri Lanka has turned its back on classical economics, sound money, and has rejected single anchor regimes like a clean float or a currency board and is operating an intermediate regime.",
        "Since the intermediate regime as set up in 1950 the rupee that has been depreciated from 4.70 to 370 to the US dollar in belief that there is prosperity at the end of monetary instability and depreciation. (Colombo/June05/2022)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Sri Lankan Airlines",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "Rs248bn",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "four months",
          "label": "DATE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka’s",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "SriLankan Airlines",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "248 billion",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "April 2022",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "SriLankan Airlines",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the first four months of 2022",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the first four months",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "145 billion",
            "label": "MONEY"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka’s",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "200 to 341",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "US",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "April 2022",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "SriLankan Airlines",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "SLA",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "618,677.61 million",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "US$ 175 million",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "Treasury",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ceylon Petroleum Corporation",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Finance Ministry",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lankan",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ceylon Petroleum Corporation",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "2019",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "US",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "SLA",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "SLA",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "175 million",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "CPC",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "131",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "370",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "US",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "2015",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "2018",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Ceylon Petroleum Corporation",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "628 billion",
            "label": "MONEY"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka’s",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "CPC",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Rs628bn",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "1950",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "4.70",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "370",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "US",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Colombo/June05/2022",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "Soft-peg කඩා වැටීමෙන් පසු ශ්‍රී ලංකන් ගුවන් සමාගමට මාස හතරක් තුළ රුපියල් බිලියන 248 ක පාඩුවක්",
      "author": "",
      "body_lines": [
        "ECONOMYNEXT - ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ රජය විසින් පවත්වාගෙන යනු ලබන ශ්‍රීලංකන් ගුවන් සමාගමට 2022 අප්‍රේල් දක්වා රුපියල් බිලියන 248ක් අහිමි වී ඇති අතර එයින් වැඩි ප්‍රමාණයක් මුදල් කඩා වැටීමෙන් ලැබෙන බව නිල දත්ත පෙන්වා දෙන්නේ, එහි අතරමැදි පාලන තන්ත්‍රයේ මහ බැංකු ඉතිහාසයේ දරුණුතම මුදල් අර්බුදය මධ්‍යයේ ය.",
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකන් ගුවන් සමාගම 2022 වසරේ මුල් මාස හතර තුළ රුපියල් බිලියන 71.82 ක ආදායමක් උපයා ඇත.",
        "පළමු මාස ​​හතර තුළ ගුවන් සමාගම රුපියල් බිලියන 248.44 ක් අහිමි වී ඇති අතර විදේශ විනිමය පාඩුවෙන් රුපියල් බිලියන 145 ක් පැමිණ තිබේ.",
        "2022 අප්‍රේල් මස අවසන් වන විට ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ රුපියල එක්සත් ජනපද ඩොලරයට 200 සිට 341 දක්වා කඩා වැටුනේ යටත් වීමේ රීතියක් සමඟ මුදල් පාවෙන උත්සාහයක් ලෙසිනි.",
        "ශ්‍රීලංකන් එයාර්ලයින්ස් (SLA) සතුව රුපියල් මිලියන 618,677.61 ක වගකීම් ඇති අතර, ස්වෛරී ඇපකර ඇමරිකානු ඩොලර් මිලියන 175 ක බැඳුම්කර, රාජ්‍ය බැංකුවලින් භාණ්ඩාගාර සහතික කළ බැංකු ණය, ගුවන් යානා කල්බදු සහ වෙළඳ ණය හිමියන් සමඟ ඇති ණය, මූලික වශයෙන් ලංකා ඛනිජ තෙල් නීතිගත සංස්ථාව ඇතුළුව බව මුදල් අමාත්‍යාංශයේ වාර්තාවක් පවසයි.",
        "2019 ට පෙර මිලදී ගත් ඉන්ධන සඳහා ලංකා ඛනිජ තෙල් සංස්ථාවට ඩොලර් හිඟ මුදලක් ඇත. නමුත් දැන් එය නියමිත වේලාවට ඩොලර් වලින් ගෙවයි.",
        "\"මෙම සන්දර්භය තුළ, රජයට තවදුරටත් SLA හි පාඩු සඳහා මුදල් යෙදවීමට නොහැකි වන අතර SLA හි ශේෂ පත්‍රය ප්‍රතිව්‍යුහගත කිරීම සහ එහි මෙහෙයුම් ආකෘතිය ලාභදායී ව්‍යුහයක් බවට පරිවර්තනය කිරීමේ හදිසි අවශ්‍යතාවයක් පවතී\" යනුවෙන් වාර්තාව පවසයි.",
        "ගුවන් යානා කල්බදු දැනට ආදායම් උපයන වත්කම්වලට අදාළ වන අතර, මිලියන 175 ක බැඳුම්කර සහ CPC හි හිඟ මුදල් ලබාගෙන ඇත්තේ උරුම පාඩු සඳහා අරමුදල් සැපයීම සඳහා ය.",
        "ගුවන් සේවය පෞද්ගලීකරණය කළ යුතු බව අගමැති රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතා පවසයි.",
        "උද්ධමනය (2015) ඉහළ නැංවීමට හෝ වර්ධනය ඉහළ නැංවීමට (නිමැවුම් පරතරය) විවෘත වෙලඳපොල මෙහෙයුම් සමඟ කුප්‍රකට අස්ථායී සංචිතයක් රැස්කිරීමේ සුප‍්‍රකට අස්ථාවර සංචිතයක් බෝම්බ හෙලීමෙන් පසු ‘නම්‍යශීලී උද්ධමන ඉලක්ක කිරීම’ ආරම්භ වීමෙන් පසු රුපියල එක්සත් ජනපද ඩොලරයට 131 සිට 370 දක්වා පහත වැටී ඇත. ඉලක්කගත කිරීම) 2018 සිට.",
        "විනිමය අනුපාත පාලනය සහ මුදල් මුද්‍රණය කිරීමෙන් පසු ලබාගත් ණය හේතුවෙන් රජය විසින් පවත්වාගෙන යනු ලබන ලංකා ඛනිජ තෙල් නීතිගත සංස්ථාවට බිලියන 628 ක පාඩුවක් සිදුව තිබේ.",
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකා ඛනිජ තෙල් නීතිගත සංස්ථාවට සහනදායී ණය මත රුපියල් බිලියන 628 ක කම්පන සහගත පාඩුවක්",
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකාව සම්භාව්‍ය ආර්ථික විද්‍යාවට, හොඳ මුදල්වලට පිටුපා ඇති අතර, පිරිසිදු පාවෙන හෝ මුදල් මණ්ඩලයක් වැනි තනි නැංගුරම් පාලන තන්ත්‍රයන් ප්‍රතික්ෂේප කර අතරමැදි පාලනයක් ක්‍රියාත්මක කරයි.",
        "1950 දී පිහිටුවන ලද අතරමැදි පාලන තන්ත්‍රයේ සිට එක්සත් ජනපද ඩොලරයට රුපියල 4.70 සිට 370 දක්වා අවප්‍රමාණය වී ඇත්තේ මුදල් අස්ථාවරත්වය සහ ක්ෂයවීම් අවසානයේ සමෘද්ධිය ඇති බව විශ්වාස කිරීමෙනි. (කොළඹ/ජුනි05/2022)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකන් ගුවන් සේවය",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "රුපියල් බිලියන 248",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "සිව් මාස",
          "label": "DATE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකන් ගුවන් සේවය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "බිලියන 248 කි",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "අප්රේල් 2022",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකන් ගුවන් සේවය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "2022 පළමු මාස ​​හතර",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "පළමු මාස ​​හතර",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "බිලියන 145 කි",
            "label": "MONEY"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "200 සිට 341 දක්වා",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "එක්සත් ජනපදය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "අප්රේල් 2022",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකන් ගුවන් සේවය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "එස්.එල්.ඒ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "මිලියන 618,677.61 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඇමෙරිකානු ඩොලර් මිලියන 175 කි",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "භාණ්ඩාගාර",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ලංකා ඛනිජ තෙල් නීතිගත සංස්ථාව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "මුදල් අමාත්යාංශය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලාංකික",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ලංකා ඛනිජ තෙල් නීතිගත සංස්ථාව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "2019",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "එක්සත් ජනපදය",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "එස්.එල්.ඒ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "එස්.එල්.ඒ",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "මිලියන 175 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "CPC",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "131",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "370",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "එක්සත් ජනපදය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "2015",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "2018",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ලංකා ඛනිජ තෙල් නීතිගත සංස්ථාව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "බිලියන 628 කි",
            "label": "MONEY"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "CPC",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "රුපියල් බිලියන 628 කි",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "1950",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "4.70 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "370",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "එක්සත් ජනපදය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "කොළඹ/ජුනි05/2022",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "ஸ்ரீலங்கன் ஏர்லைன்ஸ் நான்கு மாதங்களில் 248 பில்லியன் ரூபாயை இழந்துள்ளது",
      "author": "",
      "body_lines": [
        "ECONOMYNEXT - இலங்கையின் அரச நிறுவனமான ஸ்ரீலங்கன் ஏர்லைன்ஸ் 2022 ஏப்ரல் வரை 248 பில்லியன் ரூபாவை இழந்துள்ளதுடன், பெரும்பாலான நாணயச் சரிவு காரணமாக அதன் இடைநிலை ஆட்சி மத்திய வங்கியின் வரலாற்றில் மிக மோசமான நாணய நெருக்கடிக்கு மத்தியில் உத்தியோகபூர்வ தரவுகள் தெரிவிக்கின்றன.",
        "2022 ஆம் ஆண்டின் முதல் நான்கு மாதங்களில் ஸ்ரீலங்கன் எயார்லைன்ஸ் ரிம71.82 பில்லியன் வருமானத்தை ஈட்டியுள்ளது.",
        "முதல் நான்கு மாதங்களில் 145 பில்லியன் ரூபாய் அந்நிய செலாவணி இழப்பின் மூலம் விமான நிறுவனம் ரூ248.44 பில்லியனை இழந்துள்ளது.",
        "சரணடைதல் விதியுடன் நாணயத்தை மிதக்கும் முயற்சியில் 2022 ஏப்ரல் இறுதிக்குள் அமெரிக்க டாலருக்கு இலங்கையின் ரூபாய் 200ல் இருந்து 341 ஆக சரிந்தது.",
        "ஸ்ரீலங்கன் எயார்லைன்ஸ் (SLA) ரூ.618,677.61 மில்லியன் பொறுப்புகளில் உள்ளது, இதில் இறைமை உத்தரவாதம் அளிக்கப்பட்ட 175 மில்லியன் அமெரிக்க டாலர் பத்திரம், அரச வங்கிகளிடமிருந்து திறைசேரி உத்தரவாதம் அளிக்கப்பட்ட வங்கிக் கடன்கள், விமானக் குத்தகைகள் மற்றும் வர்த்தகக் கடனாளர்களுடனான கடன், முதன்மையாக சிலோன் பெட்ரோலியம் கூட்டுத்தாபனம் ஆகியவை அடங்கும்.",
        "இலங்கை பெற்றோலியக் கூட்டுத்தாபனத்திற்கு 2019 ஆம் ஆண்டுக்கு முன்னர் கொள்வனவு செய்யப்பட்ட எரிபொருளுக்காக ஒரு டொலர் பாக்கி வைத்துள்ளது.",
        "\"இந்தச் சூழலில், SLA இன் இழப்புகளுக்கு அரசாங்கத்தால் நிதியளிக்க முடியாது, மேலும் SLA இன் இருப்புநிலைக் குறிப்பை மறுசீரமைத்து அதன் செயல்பாட்டு மாதிரியை லாபகரமான கட்டமைப்பாக மாற்றுவதற்கான அவசரத் தேவை உள்ளது\" என்று அறிக்கை கூறியது.",
        "விமானக் குத்தகைகள் தற்போது வருவாய் ஈட்டும் சொத்துக்களுடன் தொடர்புடையதாக இருந்தாலும், 175 மில்லியன் பத்திரங்கள் மற்றும் CPC நிலுவைத் தொகை மரபு இழப்புகளுக்கு நிதியளிக்க எடுக்கப்பட்டது.",
        "விமான சேவையை தனியார் மயமாக்க வேண்டும் என பிரதமர் ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க தெரிவித்துள்ளார்.",
        "பணவீக்கத்தை (2015) அதிகரிக்க அல்லது வளர்ச்சியை (வெளியீட்டு இடைவெளியை அதிகரிக்க) திறந்த சந்தை நடவடிக்கைகளின் மூலம் ஒரு மோசமான நிலையற்ற இருப்பு சேகரிப்பு சாஃப்ட்-பெக் வெடித்ததால், 'நெகிழ்வான பணவீக்க இலக்கு' தொடங்கிய பின்னர், அமெரிக்க டாலருக்கு ரூபாய் 131ல் இருந்து சுமார் 370 ஆக சரிந்துள்ளது. இலக்கு) 2018 முதல்.",
        "அரசாங்கத்தால் நடத்தப்படும் இலங்கை பெற்றோலியக் கூட்டுத்தாபனமானது 628 பில்லியன் நட்டத்தைச் சந்தித்துள்ளது. இதன்மூலம் மென்மையான நாணய மாற்று விகித ஆட்சி மற்றும் பணத்தை அச்சடித்த பின்னர் எடுக்கப்பட்ட கடன்கள் காரணமாகும்.",
        "இலங்கையின் CPC க்கு அதிர்ச்சியளிக்கும் வகையில் 628 பில்லியன் ரூபாய் நஷ்டம்",
        "இலங்கை பாரம்பரிய பொருளாதாரம், நல்ல பணம் ஆகியவற்றுக்குப் பின்வாங்கி, சுத்தமான மிதவை அல்லது நாணயப் பலகை போன்ற ஒற்றை நங்கூர ஆட்சிகளை நிராகரித்து இடைநிலை ஆட்சியை நடத்தி வருகிறது.",
        "1950 ஆம் ஆண்டு அமைக்கப்பட்ட இடைக்கால ஆட்சியில் இருந்து, அமெரிக்க டாலருக்கு நிகரான ரூபாய் மதிப்பு 4.70 லிருந்து 370 ஆக குறைந்துள்ளது. (கொழும்பு/ஜூன்05/2022)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ஸ்ரீலங்கன் ஏர்லைன்ஸ்",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "ரூ248 பில்லியன்",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "நான்கு மாதங்கள்",
          "label": "DATE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கையின்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஸ்ரீலங்கன் ஏர்லைன்ஸ்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "248 பில்லியன்",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஏப்ரல் 2022",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஸ்ரீலங்கன் ஏர்லைன்ஸ்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "2022 இன் முதல் நான்கு மாதங்கள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "முதல் நான்கு மாதங்கள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "145 பில்லியன்",
            "label": "MONEY"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கையின்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "200 முதல் 341 வரை",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "எங்களுக்கு",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஏப்ரல் 2022",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஸ்ரீலங்கன் ஏர்லைன்ஸ்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "SLA",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "618,677.61 மில்லியன்",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "175 மில்லியன் அமெரிக்க டாலர்கள்",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "கருவூலம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை பெற்றோலியக் கூட்டுத்தாபனம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "நிதி அமைச்சகம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை பெற்றோலியக் கூட்டுத்தாபனம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "2019",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "எங்களுக்கு",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "SLA",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "SLA",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "175 மில்லியன்",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "CPC",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "131",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "370",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "எங்களுக்கு",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "2015",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "2018",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை பெற்றோலியக் கூட்டுத்தாபனம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "628 பில்லியன்",
            "label": "MONEY"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கையின்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "CPC",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரூ628 பில்லியன்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "1950",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "4.70",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "370",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "எங்களுக்கு",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "கொழும்பு/ஜூன்05/2022",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}