{
  "newspaper_id": "lankadeepa-lk",
  "url": "https://www.lankadeepa.lk/world_news/රිෂී-සුනාක්ට-අගමැති-ධුරය-හිමිවන-ලකුණු/14-616666",
  "time_ut": 1658209124,
  "original_lang": "si",
  "original_title": "රිෂී සුනාක්ට අගමැති ධුරය හිමිවන ලකුණු",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Rishi Sunak gets the Prime Ministership",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "According to foreign media, Rishi Sunak, the former Finance Minister (Chancellor) of the country, will get the vacant post of British Prime Minister.",
        "The foreign media said that Rishi Sunak, the former Finance Minister (Chancellor) of the country, will get the vacant post of British Prime Minister.",
        "With the 42-year-old Sunak of Indian origin succeeding in the leadership battle of the ruling party 'Kovsavertiv'. The British Prime Minister is held by the leader of the ruling party. The current ruling party is the 'Conservative' party.",
        "A poll to select candidates for party leadership was held yesterday (18), where Rishi Sunak received the majority of the votes, the poll was held within the 'Conservative' party.",
        "There are 358 members of the Conservative Party in the British Parliament, and the candidate who wins the consent and trust of the largest group of members will be the leader of the Conservative Party and the British Prime Minister.",
        "Several polls will be held among the 'Conservative' party MPs regarding the selection of a suitable party leader. That leaves two candidates. When a poll was held yesterday (18), there were five candidates for the party leadership and the post of Prime Minister.",
        "The five are former Finance Minister Rishi Sunak, Foreign Affairs Minister Liz Truss, Minister of State for Trade Penny Mordaunt, MP Kemi Bednock and MP Tom Tugendart.",
        "In yesterday's (18) poll, former Finance Minister (Chancellor) Rishi Sunak received the support of 115 Conservative Party MPs. The number of MPs supported by State Minister for Trade Penny Mordont is 82.",
        "The number of people who supported Foreign Affairs Minister Liz Truss was 71. Member of Parliament Kemi Bednok received the support of 58 members and Tom Tugendat received the support of 31 members. Tom Tugendart, who received the support of the least number of MPs, withdrew from the party leadership battle. In the end, polls are held within the party until two candidates are left.",
        "Boris Johnson, who was in the position of Prime Minister, had to leave the party leadership as well as the position of Prime Minister due to opposition from the 'Conservative' party. The reason for the protest was Johnson, the violation of the Covid laws and the offer of a high government position to an MP who was accused of sex. Johnson will act as acting Prime Minister until a new party leader and Prime Minister is chosen."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Rishi Sunak",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Rishi Sunak",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Finance",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "British",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Rishi Sunak",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Finance",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "British",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "42-year-old",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Indian",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kovsavertiv",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "British",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "yesterday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "18",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Rishi Sunak",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "358",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Conservative Party",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "British",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Conservative Party",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "British",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "two",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "yesterday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "18",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "five",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "five",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Finance",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Rishi Sunak",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Liz Truss",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Tom Tugendart",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "yesterday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "18",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Finance",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Rishi Sunak",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "115",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Conservative Party",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "State",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Trade Penny",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Mordont",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "82",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Liz Truss",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "71",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament Kemi Bednok",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "58",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Tom Tugendat",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "31",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Tom Tugendart",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "two",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Boris Johnson",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Johnson",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Covid",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Johnson",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "රිෂී සුනාක්ට අගමැති ධුරය හිමිවන ලකුණු",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "පුරප්පාඩු වූ බ්‍රිතාන්‍ය අග්‍රාමාත්‍ය ධුරය එරට හිටපු මුදල් අමාත්‍ය (චාන්සලර්) රිෂී සුනාක් ට හිමිවනු ඇතැයි විදෙස් මාධ්‍ය පවසයි.",
        "විදෙස් මාධ්‍ය මෙසේ පැවැසුවේ පුරප්පාඩු වූ බ්‍රිතාන්‍ය අග්‍රාමාත්‍ය ධුරය එරට හිටපු මුදල් අමාත්‍ය (චාන්සලර්) රිෂී සුනාක් ට හිමිවනු ඇතැයි විදෙස් මාධ්‍ය පවසයි.",
        "පාලක පක්ෂය වන ‘කොව්සවර්ටිව්’ පක්ෂයේ නායකත්ව සටනේ ඉදිරියට පැමිණීමට ඉන්දීය සම්භවයක් ඇති 42 හැවිරිදි සුනාක් සමත් වීමත් සමඟය. බ්‍රිතාන්‍ය අග්‍රාමාත්‍ය ධුරය හිමිවන්නේ පාලක පක්ෂයේ නායකයාටය. වත්මන් පාලක පක්ෂය ලෙස කටයුතු කරන්නේ ‘කොන්සවර්ටිව්’ පක්ෂයයි.",
        "පක්ෂ නායකත්වය සඳහා අපේක්ෂකයන් තෝරා ගැනීමේ ඡන්ද විමසුමක් ඊයේ (18) පැවැත්වුණු අතර, එහිදී වැඩි දෙනාගේ මනාපය රිෂී සුනාක්ට හිමිවියත ඡන්ද විමසුම පැවැත්වූයේ ‘කොන්සවර්ටිව්’ පක්ෂ අභ්‍යන්තරයේය.",
        "බ්‍රිතාන්‍ය පාර්ලිමේන්තුවේ කොන්සර්වර්ටිව් පක්ෂය මන්ත්‍රීවරු 358 දෙනකු සිටින අතර, එයින් වැඩිම මන්ත්‍රීවරුන් පිරිසකගේ කැමැත්ත සහ විශ්වාසය දිනාගන්නා අපේක්ෂකයා ‘කොන්සවර්ටිව්’ පක්ෂ නායකයා මෙන්ම බ්‍රිතාන්‍ය අග්‍රාමාත්‍යවරයා ද වනු ඇත.",
        "පක්ෂ නායකත්වයට සුදුස්සකු තෝරා ගැනීම සම්බන්ධයෙන් ‘කොන්සවර්ටිව්’ පක්ෂ මන්ත්‍රීවරුන් අතරේ ඡන්ද විමසීම් කීපයක් පැවැත්වෙයි. ඒ, අපේක්ෂකයන් දෙදෙනකු ඉතිරි වන පරිදිය. ඊයේ (18) ඡන්ද විමසුමක් පැවැත්වෙද්දී පක්ෂ නායකත්වය සහ අග්‍රාමාත්‍ය ධුරය අපේක්ෂාවෙන් අපේක්ෂකයෝ පස් දෙනෙක් ඉදිරිපත් වී සිටියහ.",
        "හිටපු මුදල් අමාත්‍ය රිෂී සුනාක්, විදේශ කටයුතු අමාත්‍යවරිය ලිස් ට්‍රස්, වෙළඳ රාජ්‍ය අමාත්‍ය පෙනී මොර්ඩෝන්ට්, පාර්ලිමේන්තු මන්ත්‍රී කෙමී බෙඩ්නොක් සහ පාර්ලිමේන්තු මන්ත්‍රී ටොම් ටුගෙන්ඩාට් එම පස්දෙනාය.",
        "ඊයේ (18) ඡන්ද විමසුමේ දී, හිටපු මුදල් අමාත්‍ය (චාන්සලර්) රිෂී සුනාක් ට කොන්සර්වර්ටිව් පක්ෂ මන්ත්‍රීවරු 115 දෙනකුගේ සහාය හිමිවිය. වෙළෙඳ රාජ්‍ය අමාත්‍ය පෙනී මොර්ඩෝන්ට් සහාය ලබා දුන් මන්ත්‍රීවරුන් ගණන 82 කි.",
        "විදේශ කටයුතු අමාත්‍ය ලිස් ට්‍රස් ට සහාය ලබා දුන් ගණන 71 කි. පාර්ලිමේන්තු මන්ත්‍රී කෙමී බෙඩ්නොක් ට 58 දෙනකුගේ සහාය මෙන්ම ටොම් ටුගෙන්ඩාට් මන්ත්‍රීවරුන් 31 දෙනෙකගේ සහාය හිමිවිය. අඩුම මන්ත්‍රීවරුන් ගණනකගේ සහාය හිමිවුණු ටොම් ටුගෙන්ඩාට් පක්ෂ නායකත්වය සටනෙන් ඒ අනුව ඉවත් වූයේය. අවසානයේ අපේක්ෂකයන් දෙදෙනකු ඉතිරි වනතුරු මෙසේ ඡන්ද විමසීම් පක්ෂ අභ්‍යන්තරයේ පැවැත්වෙයි.",
        "අග්‍රාමාත්‍ය ධුරයේ සිටි බොරිස් ජොන්සන් ට පක්ෂ නායකත්වයෙන් මෙන්ම අග්‍රාමාත්‍ය ධුරයෙන් ද ඉවත් වීමට සිදුවූයේ ‘කොන්සවර්ටිව්’ පක්ෂය තුළින් එල්ල වුණු විරෝධයක් හේතුවෙනි. එම විරෝධයට හේතුව වූයේ ජොන්සන්, කොවිඩ් නීති උල්ලංඝනය සහ ලිංගික චෝදනා එල්ල වුණු මන්ත්‍රීවරයකුට රජයේ ඉහළ තනතුරක් පිරිනැමීමය. නව පක්ෂ නායකයකු මෙන්ම අග්‍රාමාත්‍යවරයකු තෝරා ගන්නා තුරු වැඩබලන අග්‍රාමාත්‍ය ලෙස කටයුතු කරන්නේ ජොන්සන්ය."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "රිෂි සුනක්",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "රිෂි සුනක්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "මූල්ය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "බ්රිතාන්ය",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "රිෂි සුනක්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "මූල්ය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "බ්රිතාන්ය",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "42 හැවිරිදිය",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දීය",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "කොව්සවර්ටිව්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "බ්රිතාන්ය",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ඊයේ",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "18",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "රිෂි සුනක්",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "358",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "කොන්සර්වේටිව් පක්ෂය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "බ්රිතාන්ය",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "කොන්සර්වේටිව් පක්ෂය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "බ්රිතාන්ය",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "දෙක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඊයේ",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "18",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "පහ",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "පහ",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "මූල්ය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "රිෂි සුනක්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ලිස් ට්‍රස්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Tom Tugendart",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ඊයේ",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "18",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "මූල්ය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "රිෂි සුනක්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "115",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "කොන්සර්වේටිව් පක්ෂය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "රජයේ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "වෙළඳාම පෙනි",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "මොර්ඩොන්ට්",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "82",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ලිස් ට්‍රස්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "71",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව Kemi Bednok",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "58",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Tom Tugendat",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "31",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Tom Tugendart",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "දෙක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "බොරිස් ජොන්සන්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජොන්සන්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "කොවිඩ්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජොන්සන්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "ரிஷி சுனக் பிரதமர் பதவியைப் பெறுகிறார்",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "காலியாக உள்ள பிரித்தானிய பிரதமர் பதவியை அந்நாட்டின் முன்னாள் நிதியமைச்சர் (அதிபர்) ரிஷி சுனக் பெறுவார் என வெளிநாட்டு ஊடகங்கள் தெரிவிக்கின்றன.",
        "காலியாக உள்ள பிரித்தானிய பிரதமர் பதவியை அந்நாட்டின் முன்னாள் நிதியமைச்சர் (வேந்தர்) ரிஷி சுனக் பெறுவார் என வெளிநாட்டு ஊடகங்கள் தெரிவித்துள்ளன.",
        "இந்திய வம்சாவளியைச் சேர்ந்த 42 வயதான சுனக் ஆளும் கட்சியான 'கோவ்சாவெர்டிவ்' தலைமைப் போரில் வெற்றி பெற்றார். பிரிட்டிஷ் பிரதம மந்திரி ஆளும் கட்சியின் தலைவரால் நடத்தப்படுகிறார். தற்போதைய ஆளும் கட்சி 'கன்சர்வேடிவ்' கட்சி.",
        "கட்சித் தலைமைக்கான வேட்பாளர்களைத் தெரிவு செய்வதற்கான வாக்கெடுப்பு நேற்று (18) இடம்பெற்றது, அங்கு ரிஷி சுனக் அதிக வாக்குகளைப் பெற்றுள்ள நிலையில், 'கன்சர்வேடிவ்' கட்சிக்குள் வாக்கெடுப்பு நடத்தப்பட்டது.",
        "பிரிட்டிஷ் பாராளுமன்றத்தில் கன்சர்வேடிவ் கட்சியின் 358 உறுப்பினர்கள் உள்ளனர், மேலும் மிகப்பெரிய குழு உறுப்பினர்களின் ஒப்புதல் மற்றும் நம்பிக்கையை வென்ற வேட்பாளர் கன்சர்வேடிவ் கட்சியின் தலைவராகவும் பிரிட்டிஷ் பிரதமராகவும் இருப்பார்.",
        "'கன்சர்வேடிவ்' கட்சி எம்.பி.க்கள் மத்தியில் பொருத்தமான கட்சித் தலைவரை தேர்ந்தெடுப்பது குறித்து பல கருத்துக் கணிப்புகள் நடத்தப்படும். அது இரண்டு வேட்பாளர்களை விட்டுவிடுகிறது. நேற்று (18) வாக்கெடுப்பு நடத்தப்பட்ட போது கட்சியின் தலைமை மற்றும் பிரதமர் பதவிக்கு ஐந்து பேர் போட்டியிட்டனர்.",
        "முன்னாள் நிதியமைச்சர் ரிஷி சுனக், வெளியுறவு அமைச்சர் லிஸ் ட்ரஸ், வர்த்தக அமைச்சர் பென்னி மோர்டான்ட், எம்.பி. கெமி பெட்னாக் மற்றும் எம்.பி டாம் டுகென்டார்ட் ஆகியோர் ஐந்து பேர்.",
        "நேற்று (18) நடைபெற்ற வாக்கெடுப்பில், முன்னாள் நிதியமைச்சர் (அதிபர்) ரிஷி சுனக் 115 கன்சர்வேட்டிவ் கட்சி எம்.பி.க்களின் ஆதரவைப் பெற்றுள்ளார். மாநில வர்த்தக அமைச்சர் பென்னி மோர்டோன்ட்டின் ஆதரவு எம்.பி.க்களின் எண்ணிக்கை 82 ஆகும்.",
        "வெளியுறவு அமைச்சர் லிஸ் டிரஸ்ஸுக்கு ஆதரவளித்தவர்களின் எண்ணிக்கை 71 ஆகும். நாடாளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர் Kemi Bednok 58 உறுப்பினர்களின் ஆதரவையும், Tom Tugendat 31 உறுப்பினர்களின் ஆதரவையும் பெற்றனர். குறைந்த எண்ணிக்கையிலான எம்.பி.க்களின் ஆதரவைப் பெற்ற டாம் டுகென்டார்ட், கட்சித் தலைமைப் போரில் இருந்து விலகினார். இறுதியில், இரண்டு வேட்பாளர்கள் எஞ்சியிருக்கும் வரை கட்சிக்குள் கருத்துக் கணிப்புகள் நடத்தப்படுகின்றன.",
        "பிரதமர் பதவியில் இருந்த போரிஸ் ஜான்சன், 'கன்சர்வேடிவ்' கட்சியின் எதிர்ப்பால், கட்சித் தலைமையிலிருந்தும், பிரதமர் பதவியிலிருந்தும் விலக நேரிட்டது. எதிர்ப்புக்கு காரணம் ஜான்சன், கோவிட் சட்டங்களை மீறியது மற்றும் பாலியல் குற்றச்சாட்டுக்கு உள்ளான ஒரு எம்.பி.க்கு உயர் அரசாங்க பதவியை வழங்கியது. புதிய கட்சித் தலைவர் மற்றும் பிரதமர் தேர்ந்தெடுக்கப்படும் வரை ஜான்சன் தற்காலிக பிரதமராக செயல்படுவார்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ரிஷி சுனக்",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ரிஷி சுனக்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "நிதி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "பிரிட்டிஷ்",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ரிஷி சுனக்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "நிதி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "பிரிட்டிஷ்",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "42 வயது",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்தியன்",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "கோவ்சாவெர்டிவ்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "பிரிட்டிஷ்",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "நேற்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "18",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரிஷி சுனக்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "358",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "கன்சர்வேடிவ் கட்சி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "பிரிட்டிஷ்",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "கன்சர்வேடிவ் கட்சி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "பிரிட்டிஷ்",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இரண்டு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "நேற்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "18",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஐந்து",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஐந்து",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "நிதி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரிஷி சுனக்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "லிஸ் டிரஸ்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "டாம் டுகென்டார்ட்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "நேற்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "18",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "நிதி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரிஷி சுனக்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "115",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "கன்சர்வேடிவ் கட்சி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "நிலை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "வர்த்தக பென்னி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "மோர்டோன்ட்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "82",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "லிஸ் டிரஸ்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "71",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம் கெமி பெட்னோக்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "58",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "டாம் துகெண்டாட்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "31",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "டாம் டுகென்டார்ட்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இரண்டு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "போரிஸ் ஜான்சன்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜான்சன்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "கோவிட்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜான்சன்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}