{
  "newspaper_id": "news-first-lk",
  "url": "https://www.newsfirst.lk/2022/08/31/one-month-old-infant-abandoned-at-a-motor-garage-with-a-letter/",
  "time_ut": 1661962860,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "One-month-old infant abandoned at a motor garage with a letter",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "One-month-old infant abandoned at a motor garage with a letter",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); A one month-old infant was found abandoned near a vehicle garage in Bandarawela on Wednesday, with a letter.",
        "A Police investigation is underway after one month-old infant was found abandoned near a vehicle garade in Bandarawela on Wednesday (31).",
        "Interestingly, the infant the vehicle garage is located close to a Child Care Center in the Ambewala area in Bandarawela.",
        "Investigations revealed that this infant was left at the premises at noon on Wednesday (31).",
        "Mechanics who were employed at the garage heard the cried of this infant and informed the police, who and then had handed over the infant to a Child Care Center.",
        "A female Police Officer also volunteered to take care and feed the infant.",
        "A letter was also found along with the infant, and the letter states that the person who left the child at the garage will be back to take infant in a short time and to take care of the child until then.",
        "The infant was then hospitalized at he Diyathalawa hospital for examination purposes, and Police investigations are underway to locate the suspect who abandoned the infant.",
        "One-month-old infant abandoned at a motor garage with a letter",
        "Are you a victim of Cyber Crime? Police Unit ready to crackdown crime in the cyberspace"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "One-month-old",
          "label": "DATE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "News 1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "one month-old",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Bandarawela",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Wednesday",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "one month-old",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Bandarawela",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Wednesday (31",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "a Child Care Center",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ambewala",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Bandarawela",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "noon",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "a Child Care Center",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "Diyathalawa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "One-month-old",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Cyber Crime",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "ලිපියක් සමඟ මෝටර් රථ ගරාජයක දමා ගිය මාසයක් වයසැති ළදරුවා",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); බදාදා බණ්ඩාරවෙල නගරයේ වාහන ගරාජයක් අසල දමා ගොස් සිටියදී ලිපියක් සමඟ මාසයක් වයසැති බිළිඳකු සොයා ගෙන ඇත.",
        "බදාදා (31) බණ්ඩාරවෙල ප්‍රදේශයේ වාහන ගාලක් අසල දමා ගොස් සිටි මාසයක් වයසැති බිළිඳකු හමුවීමෙන් පසු පොලිස් විමර්ශනයක් ආරම්භ කර ඇත.",
        "මෙම ළදරු වාහන ගරාජය බණ්ඩාරවෙල අඹේවල ප්‍රදේශයේ ළමා සුරැකුම් මධ්‍යස්ථානයක් ආසන්නයේ පිහිටා තිබීම සිත්ගන්නා කරුණකි.",
        "බදාදා (31) දහවල් මෙම බිළිඳා එම පරිශ්‍රයේ දමා ගොස් ඇති බව විමර්ශනවලදී අනාවරණය විය.",
        "ගරාජයේ සේවයේ නියුතු කාර්මිකයන් මෙම බිළිඳාගේ කෑගැසීම ඇසී පොලිසියට දන්වා ඇති අතර පසුව පොලිසිය විසින් බිළිඳා ළමා සුරැකුම් මධ්‍යස්ථානයකට භාර දී ඇත.",
        "ළදරුවා රැකබලා ගැනීමට සහ පෝෂණය කිරීමට කාන්තා පොලිස් නිලධාරිනියක් ද ඉදිරිපත් විය.",
        "බිළිඳා සමඟ ලිපියක් ද හමුවී ඇති අතර, දරුවා ගරාජයට දමා ගිය පුද්ගලයා කෙටි කාලයකින් නැවත පැමිණ දරුවා රැගෙන එන බවත් එතෙක් දරුවා බලා ගන්නා ලෙසත් එම ලිපියේ සඳහන් වේ.",
        "අනතුරුව පරීක්ෂණ කටයුතු සඳහා බිළිඳා දියතලාව රෝහලට ඇතුළත් කර ඇති අතර, බිළිඳා දමා ගිය සැකකරු සොයා පොලිස් පරීක්ෂණ ක්‍රියාත්මකයි.",
        "ලිපියක් සමඟ මෝටර් රථ ගරාජයක දමා ගිය මාසයක් වයසැති ළදරුවා",
        "ඔබ සයිබර් අපරාධයට ගොදුරු වූවෙක්ද? සයිබර් අවකාශයේ සිදුවන අපරාධ මර්දනයට පොලිස් ඒකකය සූදානම්"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "මාසයක් වයසැති",
          "label": "DATE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "News 1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මාසයක් වයසැති",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "බණ්ඩාරවෙල",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "බදාදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "මාසයක් වයසැති",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "බණ්ඩාරවෙල",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "බදාදා (31",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ළමා සුරැකුම් මධ්යස්ථානයක්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "අඹේවල",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "බණ්ඩාරවෙල",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "දහවල්",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ළමා සුරැකුම් මධ්යස්ථානයක්",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "දියතලාව",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "මාසයක් වයසැති",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "සයිබර් අපරාධ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "கடிதத்துடன் மோட்டார் கேரேஜில் கைவிடப்பட்ட ஒரு மாத கைக்குழந்தை",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); பண்டாரவளையில் உள்ள வாகனக் களஞ்சியசாலைக்கு அருகில் புதன்கிழமை ஒரு மாத கைக்குழந்தை கைவிடப்பட்ட நிலையில் கடிதத்துடன் கண்டெடுக்கப்பட்டுள்ளது.",
        "புதன்கிழமை (31) பண்டாரவளையில் வாகனத் தரிப்பிடத்தில் கைவிடப்பட்ட நிலையில் ஒரு மாத கைக்குழந்தை கண்டுபிடிக்கப்பட்டதை அடுத்து பொலிஸார் விசாரணைகளை மேற்கொண்டு வருகின்றனர்.",
        "சுவாரஸ்யமாக, பண்டாரவளை அம்பேவல பிரதேசத்தில் உள்ள சிறுவர் பராமரிப்பு நிலையத்திற்கு அருகில் இந்த சிசு வாகன கேரேஜ் அமைந்துள்ளது.",
        "புதன்கிழமை (31) நண்பகல் இந்த சிசு வளாகத்தில் விடப்பட்டதாக விசாரணைகளில் தெரியவந்துள்ளது.",
        "கேரேஜில் பணிபுரிந்த மெக்கானிக்குகள் குழந்தையின் அலறல் சத்தம் கேட்டு பொலிசாருக்கு தகவல் கொடுத்ததையடுத்து, அவர்கள் குழந்தையை குழந்தைகள் பராமரிப்பு மையத்தில் ஒப்படைத்தனர்.",
        "ஒரு பெண் போலீஸ் அதிகாரியும் குழந்தையை கவனித்துக் கொள்ளவும், உணவளிக்கவும் முன்வந்தார்.",
        "கைக்குழந்தையுடன் ஒரு கடிதமும் கிடைத்துள்ளது, மேலும் குழந்தையை கேரேஜில் விட்டுச் சென்றவர் சிறிது நேரத்தில் மீண்டும் குழந்தையை எடுத்துச் செல்வதாகவும் அதுவரை குழந்தையைப் பார்த்துக் கொள்வதாகவும் அந்தக் கடிதத்தில் குறிப்பிடப்பட்டுள்ளது.",
        "பின்னர் பரீட்சை நோக்கங்களுக்காக சிசு தியத்தலாவ வைத்தியசாலையில் அனுமதிக்கப்பட்டதுடன், சிசுவை கைவிட்டுச் சென்ற சந்தேக நபரைக் கண்டறிய பொலிஸார் விசாரணைகளை மேற்கொண்டு வருகின்றனர்.",
        "கடிதத்துடன் மோட்டார் கேரேஜில் கைவிடப்பட்ட ஒரு மாத கைக்குழந்தை",
        "நீங்கள் சைபர் கிரைம் பாதிக்கப்பட்டவரா? சைபர்ஸ்பேஸ் குற்றங்களை ஒடுக்க போலீஸ் பிரிவு தயார்"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ஒரு மாத வயது",
          "label": "DATE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "News 1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஒரு மாத வயது",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "பண்டாரவளை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "புதன்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஒரு மாத வயது",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "பண்டாரவளை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "புதன்கிழமை (31",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஒரு குழந்தை பராமரிப்பு மையம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "அம்பேவாலா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "பண்டாரவளை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "நண்பகல்",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஒரு குழந்தை பராமரிப்பு மையம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "தியத்தலாவ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஒரு மாத வயது",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "சைபர்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}