{
  "newspaper_id": "daily-mirror-lk",
  "url": "https://www.dailymirror.lk/breaking_news/500-workforce-instead-of-4-200-at-CPC-CPSTL-CEB-can-do-the-job-efficiently-Minister/108-243862",
  "time_ut": 1661601919,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "500 workforce instead of 4,200 at CPC, CPSTL, CEB can do the job efficiently: Minister",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "500 workforce instead of 4,200 at CPC, CPSTL, CEB can do the job efficiently: Minister",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "A good 500 workforce instead of the 4,200 could do the job efficiently at Ceylon Petroleum Coporation (CPC), Ceylon Petroleum Storage Terminals Limited (CPSTL) and half of the 26,000 workforce at the Ceylon Electricity Board (CEB), power and energy minister Kanchana Wijesekera said.",
        "He said all state-owned enterprises (SOEs) need to be restructured. \"There are capable and efficient workers at CEB, CPC and CPSTL. The majority are inefficient and incompetent,\" the Minister said.",
        "Meanwhile, the political decisions, political appointments, maladministration and incompetence have led to the downfall of these entities, he said.",
        "\"I don’t think the majority of the public workforce will survive in the private sector or be recruited at all. Performance based remuneration is a must,\" Minister Wijesekera said. (Chaturanga Samarawickrama)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "500",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "4,200",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "CPC",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "CPSTL",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "CEB",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "500",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "4,200",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ceylon Petroleum Coporation",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "CPC",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ceylon Petroleum Storage Terminals Limited",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "half",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "26,000",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Ceylon Electricity Board",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kanchana Wijesekera",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "CEB",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "CPC",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "Wijesekera",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Chaturanga Samarawickrama",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "CPC, CPSTL, CEB හි 4,200ක් වෙනුවට 500ක් ශ්‍රම බලකායට කාර්යක්‍ෂමව කාර්යය කළ හැකියි: ඇමති",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "ලංකා ඛනිජ තෙල් සංස්ථාවේ (CPC), Ceylon Petroleum Storage Terminals Limited (CPSTL) සහ ලංකා විදුලිබල මණ්ඩලයේ (CEB) ශ්‍රම බලකායේ 26,000 න් අඩක් පමණ කාර්යක්‍ෂමව වැඩ කිරීමට 4,200 වෙනුවට හොඳ ශ්‍රම බළකාය 500කට හැකි බව විදුලිබල හා බලශක්ති අමාත්‍ය Kangana Wijes. කිව්වා.",
        "රජය සතු සියලුම ව්‍යවසායන් (SOEs) ප්‍රතිව්‍යුහගත කළ යුතු බව ඔහු පැවසීය. \"CEB, CPC සහ CPSTL යන ආයතනවල දක්‍ෂ සහ කාර්යක්‍ෂම සේවකයන් සිටිනවා. බහුතරයක් අකාර්යක්ෂම සහ අදක්ෂ,\" අමාත්‍යවරයා පැවසීය.",
        "මේ අතර දේශපාලන තීන්දු තීරණ, දේශපාලන පත්වීම්, පරිපාලනයේ නොගැලපීම සහ නොහැකියාව මෙම ආයතනවල කඩා වැටීමට හේතු වී ඇති බවද ඔහු පැවසීය.",
        "\"රාජ්‍ය ශ්‍රම බලකායෙන් බහුතරයක් පෞද්ගලික අංශයේ නොනැසී පවතිනු ඇතැයි හෝ කිසිසේත්ම බඳවා ගනු ඇතැයි මම නොසිතමි. කාර්ය සාධනය පදනම් කරගත් වේතනයක් අත්‍යවශ්‍ය වේ\" යනුවෙන් විජේසේකර අමාත්‍යවරයා පැවසීය. (චතුරංග සමරවික්‍රම)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "500",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "4,200 කි",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "CPC",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "CPSTL",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "ලංවිම",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "500",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "4,200 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ලංකා ඛනිජ තෙල් සංස්ථාව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "CPC",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "සිලෝන් පෙට්‍රෝලියම් ස්ටෝරේජ් ටර්මිනල්ස් ලිමිටඩ්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "අඩක්",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "26,000 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ලංකා විදුලිබල මණ්ඩලය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "කාංචන විජේසේකර",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ලංවිම",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "CPC",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "විජේසේකර",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "චතුරංග සමරවික්‍රම",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "CPC, CPSTL, CEB ஆகியவற்றில் 4,200 பணியாளர்களுக்கு பதிலாக 500 பணியாளர்கள் பணியை திறமையாக செய்ய முடியும்: அமைச்சர்",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "இலங்கை பெற்றோலியக் கூட்டுத்தாபனம் (CPC), சிலோன் பெட்ரோலியம் சேமிப்பு முனையங்கள் லிமிடெட் (CPSTL) மற்றும் இலங்கை மின்சார சபையில் (CEB) உள்ள 26,000 பணியாளர்களில் பாதிப் பேரில் 4,200 பணியாளர்களுக்குப் பதிலாக ஒரு நல்ல 500 பணியாளர்கள் இந்தப் பணியை திறமையாகச் செய்ய முடியும். கூறினார்.",
        "அனைத்து அரசுக்கு சொந்தமான நிறுவனங்களும் (SOEs) மறுசீரமைக்கப்பட வேண்டும் என்றார். \"CEB, CPC மற்றும் CPSTL ஆகியவற்றில் திறமையான மற்றும் திறமையான தொழிலாளர்கள் உள்ளனர். பெரும்பான்மையானவர்கள் திறமையற்றவர்கள் மற்றும் திறமையற்றவர்கள்\" என்று அமைச்சர் கூறினார்.",
        "இதற்கிடையில், அரசியல் முடிவுகள், அரசியல் நியமனங்கள், முறைகேடு மற்றும் திறமையின்மை ஆகியவை இந்த நிறுவனங்களின் வீழ்ச்சிக்கு வழிவகுத்தன, என்றார்.",
        "\"பெரும்பாலான அரச பணியாளர்கள் தனியார் துறையில் வாழ்வார்கள் அல்லது ஆட்சேர்ப்பு செய்யப்படுவார்கள் என்று நான் நினைக்கவில்லை. செயல்திறன் அடிப்படையிலான ஊதியம் அவசியம்\" என்று அமைச்சர் விஜேசேகர கூறினார். (சதுரங்க சமரவிக்ரம)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "500",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "4,200",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "CPC",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "CPSTL",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "CEB",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "500",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "4,200",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை பெற்றோலியக் கூட்டுத்தாபனம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "CPC",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "சிலோன் பெட்ரோலியம் சேமிப்பு டெர்மினல்ஸ் லிமிடெட்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாதி",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "26,000",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை மின்சார சபை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "காஞ்சனா விஜேசேகர",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "CEB",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "CPC",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "விஜேசேகர",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "சதுரங்க சமரவிக்ரம",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}