{
  "newspaper_id": "ada-lk",
  "url": "https://www.ada.lk/breaking_news/කටාරයේ-බලශක්ති-රාජ්‍ය-ඇමති-හා-කංචන-අතර-හමුවක්/11-394929",
  "time_ut": 1656415996,
  "original_lang": "si",
  "original_title": "කටාරයේ බලශක්ති රාජ්‍ය ඇමති හා කංචන අතර හමුවක්",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Meeting between Minister of State for Energy of Qatar and Kanchana",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "Kanchana Wijesekera, Minister of Power and Energy, who is on a visit to Qatar to discuss a number of issues, including the availability of fuel to Sri Lanka, has held discussions with the Minister of State for Energy and the Chief Executive of Qatar Energy, Saad Sheridan Al Kabi.",
        "With the support of Qatar Energy and the Qatar Development Fund to help ease the energy crisis in Sri Lanka, Petroleum Products, LPG And LNG. Obtained is discussed here."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Qatar",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "Kanchana",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Kanchana Wijesekera",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Qatar",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Qatar Energy",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Saad Sheridan Al Kabi",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Qatar Energy",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Qatar Development Fund",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Petroleum Products",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "LPG",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "LNG",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "කටාරයේ බලශක්ති රාජ්‍ය ඇමති හා කංචන අතර හමුවක්",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "ලංකාවට ඉන්ධන ලබා ගැනීම ඇතුළුව තවත් කරුණු කිහිපයක්  පිළිබ﻿ඳව සාකච්ඡා කිරීම වෙනුවෙන් කටාර් බලා පිටත්ව ගිය විදුලි බල හා බලශක්ති අමාත්‍ය කංචන විජේසේකර මහතා එරට බලශක්ති කටයුතු පිළිබඳ රාජ්‍ය අමාත්‍ය මෙන්ම කටාර් එනර්ජිහි ප්‍රධාන විධායක නිලධාරී සාඩ් ශෙරීඩා අල් කාබි මහතා හා සාකච්ඡා පවත්වා තිබේ.",
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ බලශක්ති අර්බුදයෙන් මිදීම සඳහා කටාර් එනර්ජි සමාගමේ සහාය හා කටාර් සංවර්ධන අරමුදලේ සහාය ඇතිව ඛනිජ තෙල් නිශ්පාදන, එල්.පී.ජී. හා එල්.එන්.ජී. ලබාගැනීම පිළිබඳව මෙහිදී සාකච්ඡ කර තිබේ."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "කටාර්",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "කාංචනා",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "කාංචන විජේසේකර",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "කටාර්",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "කටාර් බලශක්ති",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Saad Sheridan Al Kabi",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "කටාර් බලශක්ති",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "කටාර් සංවර්ධන අරමුදල",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඛනිජ තෙල් නිෂ්පාදන",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "එල්.පී.ජී",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "එල්එන්ජී",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "கத்தார் எரிசக்தி துறை அமைச்சர் காஞ்சனா இடையே சந்திப்பு",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "இலங்கைக்கு எரிபொருள் கிடைப்பது உட்பட பல விடயங்கள் தொடர்பில் கலந்துரையாடுவதற்காக கட்டாருக்கு விஜயம் மேற்கொண்டுள்ள மின்வலு மற்றும் எரிசக்தி அமைச்சர் காஞ்சன விஜேசேகர, எரிசக்தி இராஜாங்க அமைச்சர் மற்றும் கட்டார் எரிசக்தியின் பிரதம நிறைவேற்று அதிகாரிகளுடன் கலந்துரையாடியுள்ளார். சாத் ஷெரிடன் அல் கபி.",
        "கத்தார் எரிசக்தி மற்றும் கட்டார் அபிவிருத்தி நிதியத்தின் ஆதரவுடன் இலங்கையின் எரிசக்தி நெருக்கடியைத் தணிக்க, பெற்றோலியப் பொருட்கள், எல்.பி.ஜி. மற்றும் எல்.என்.ஜி. பெறப்பட்டது இங்கு விவாதிக்கப்படுகிறது."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "கத்தார்",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "காஞ்சனா",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "காஞ்சனா விஜேசேகர",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "கத்தார்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "கத்தார் ஆற்றல்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "சாத் ஷெரிடன் அல் கபி",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "கத்தார் ஆற்றல்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "கத்தார் மேம்பாட்டு நிதி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "பெட்ரோலிய பொருட்கள்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "எல்.பி.ஜி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "எல்என்ஜி",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}