{
  "newspaper_id": "daily-mirror-lk",
  "url": "https://www.dailymirror.lk/front_page/All-Party-interim-Government-SLFP-to-hold-talks-again-with-President/238-242154",
  "time_ut": 1659324061,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "All Party interim Government SLFP to hold talks again with President",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "All Party interim Government SLFP to hold talks again with President",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "Maithripala Sirisena is expected to return home after a visit to Korea to address a global conference, ‘World Summit For Peace 2022’ and a date would be decided for bilateral talks between the President and the SLFP after that",
        "It was the SLFP that first proposed an all-party government to bail out the country from the current economic, political and social mess as far back as April, this year",
        "The Sri Lanka Freedom Party (SLFP) wants to hold another round of talks with President Ranil Wickremesinghe next week in a bid to come to a consensus with the government and form an all-party interim government until a general election is held, General Secretary of the SLFP, former Minister Dayasiri Jayasekara said yesterday.",
        "Jayasekara said party chief and former President Maithripala Sirisena is expected to return home after a visit to Korea to address a global conference, ‘World Summit For Peace 2022’ and a date would be decided for bilateral talks between the President and the SLFP after that.",
        "“I hope, we can meet during the course of next week,”  Jayasekara added.",
        "Commenting on the reported invitation to all 224 MPs by President Wickremesinghe individually to join an interim government,  Jayasekara said most appropriate and transparent way for such an invitation would have been to invite via the party leadership.",
        "“It was the SLFP that first proposed an all-party government to bail out the country from the current economic, political and social mess as far back as April, this year. In that proposal, we said President must consult party leaders and invite the political parties that represent Parliament to participate in an all-party interim government. However, I expect, President Wickremesinghe will invite the party leadership also to join the all-party interim government,” Jayasekara said.",
        "Jayasekara told Daily Mirror that the first discussion the SLFP leadership held  last Friday at the Finance Ministry with President Wickremesinghe was a success.",
        "“We submitted a 9 point strategic plan that highlighted the necessity to hold a general election soon after the country returns to normalcy by putting an end to fuel and gas queues, ensuring steady supply of food, drugs and other essentials and restoring stability in the country which was agreed by the both,” Jayasekara noted.",
        "The first discussion the SLFP leadership held  last Friday at the Finance Ministry with President Wickremesinghe was a success"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "All Party interim Government SLFP",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Maithripala Sirisena",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Korea",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "April",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "this year",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "next week",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "SLFP",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Dayasiri Jayasekara",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "yesterday",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Jayasekara",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Maithripala Sirisena",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Korea",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "next week",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "224",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Jayasekara",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "April",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "this year",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Jayasekara",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Jayasekara",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Daily Mirror",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "first",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "SLFP",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "last Friday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Finance Ministry",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "9",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Jayasekara",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "first",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "SLFP",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "last Friday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Finance Ministry",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "සර්ව පාක්ෂික අන්තර්වාර ආණ්ඩුව ශ්‍රීලනිපය ජනපති සමඟ යළි සාකච්ඡා කිරීමට",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "‘සාමය සඳහා වූ ලෝක සමුළුව 2022’ යන ගෝලීය සමුළුව ඇමතීමට කොරියාවේ සංචාරයක නිරතවීමෙන් අනතුරුව මෛත්‍රීපාල සිරිසේන මහතා සිය රටට පැමිණීමට නියමිත අතර ජනාධිපතිවරයා සහ ශ්‍රීලනිපය අතර ද්වීපාර්ශ්වික සාකච්ඡා පැවැත්වීමේ දිනයක් ඉන් අනතුරුව තීරණය කිරීමට නියමිතයි.",
        "මේ වසරේ අපේ‍්‍රල් මාසය තරම් ඈත කාලයකදී පවතින ආර්ථික, දේශපාලන හා සමාජීය අවුලෙන් රට ගොඩගැනීමට සර්ව පාක්ෂික ආණ්ඩුවක් මුලින්ම යෝජනා කළේ ශ‍්‍රීලනිපයයි.",
        "මහ මැතිවරණයක් පැවැත්වෙන තෙක් රජය සමඟ එකඟතාවකට පැමිණ සර්ව පාක්ෂික අන්තර්වාර ආණ්ඩුවක් පිහිටුවීම සඳහා ශ්‍රී ලංකා නිදහස් පක්ෂයට ලබන සතියේ තවත් සාකච්ඡා වටයක් ජනාධිපති රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතා සමඟ පැවැත්වීමට අවශ්‍ය බව ශ්‍රී ලංකා නිදහස් පක්ෂය ප්‍රකාශ කරයි. ශ්‍රීලනිප හිටපු අමාත්‍ය දයාසිරි ජයසේකර මහතා ඊයේ ප්‍රකාශ කළේය.",
        "‘සාමය සඳහා වූ ලෝක සමුළුව 2022’ යන ගෝලීය සමුළුව ඇමතීමට කොරියාවේ සංචාරයක නිරතව සිටින පක්ෂ ප්‍රධානී සහ හිටපු ජනාධිපති මෛත්‍රීපාල සිරිසේන මහතා සිය රටට පැමිණීමට බලාපොරොත්තු වන බවත් ඉන් අනතුරුව ජනාධිපතිවරයා සහ ශ්‍රීලනිපය අතර ද්විපාර්ශ්වික සාකච්ඡා පැවැත්වීමට දිනයක් තීරණය කරන බවත් ජයසේකර මහතා පැවසීය.",
        "\"මම බලාපොරොත්තු වෙනවා, අපට ලබන සතියේ දී හමුවිය හැකියි\"  ජයසේකර වැඩිදුරටත් පැවසීය.",
        "ජනාධිපති වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතා විසින් තනි තනිව මන්ත්‍රීවරුන් 224 දෙනාටම අන්තර්වාර ආණ්ඩුවකට එක්වන ලෙස වාර්තා කළ ආරාධනය පිළිබඳව අදහස් දක්වමින් ජයසේකර පැවසුවේ එවැනි ආරාධනයක් සඳහා වඩාත් උචිත සහ විනිවිද පෙනෙන ක්‍රමය පක්ෂ නායකත්වය හරහා ආරාධනා කිරීම බවයි.",
        "“දැනට පවතින ආර්ථික, දේශපාලන හා සමාජීය අවුලෙන් රට ගොඩගැනීම සඳහා සර්ව පාක්ෂික ආණ්ඩුවක් මුලින්ම යෝජනා කළේ මේ වසරේ අප්‍රේල් තරම් ඈත කාලයකදී ශ්‍රීලනිපයයි. එම යෝජනාවේදී අපි කියා සිටියේ ජනාධිපතිවරයා පක්ෂ නායකයන්ගෙන් අදහස් විමසා පාර්ලිමේන්තුව නියෝජනය කරන දේශපාලන පක්ෂවලට සර්ව පාක්ෂික අන්තර්වාර ආණ්ඩුවකට සහභාගි වන ලෙස ආරාධනා කළ යුතු බවයි. කෙසේ වෙතත්, සර්ව පාක්ෂික අන්තර්වාර ආණ්ඩුවට එක්වන ලෙස ජනාධිපති වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතා පක්ෂ නායකත්වයට ද ආරාධනා කරනු ඇතැයි මම අපේක්ෂා කරමි.” ජයසේකර මහතා පැවසීය.",
        "ජයසේකර ඩේලි මිරර් වෙත පැවසුවේ ශ්‍රීලනිප නායකත්වය පසුගිය සිකුරාදා මුදල් අමාත්‍යාංශයේදී ජනාධිපති වික්‍රමසිංහ සමඟ පැවැත්වූ පළමු සාකච්ඡාව සාර්ථක වූ බවයි.",
        "“ඉන්ධන සහ ගෑස් පෝලිම්වලට තිත තබමින්, ආහාර, ඖෂධ සහ අනෙකුත් අත්‍යවශ්‍ය ද්‍රව්‍යවල ස්ථාවර සැපයුමක් සහතික කරමින් සහ රට තුළ ස්ථාවරත්වය ඇති කරමින් රට යථා තත්ත්වයට පත් වූ වහාම මහ මැතිවරණයක් පැවැත්වීමේ අවශ්‍යතාවය ඉස්මතු කරන කරුණු 9 කින් යුත් උපායමාර්ගික සැලැස්මක් අපි ඉදිරිපත් කළා. එය දෙදෙනාගේම එකඟතාවයකට පැමිණියා” යැයි ජයසේකර සඳහන් කළේය.",
        "ශ්‍රීලනිප නායකත්වය පසුගිය සිකුරාදා මුදල් අමාත්‍යාංශයේදී ජනාධිපති වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතා සමඟ පැවැත්වූ පළමු සාකච්ඡාව සාර්ථක විය."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "සර්ව පාක්ෂික අන්තර්වාර ආණ්ඩුව ශ්‍රීලනිප",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "මෛත්‍රීපාල සිරිසේන",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "කොරියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "අප්රේල්",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මේ වසරේ",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඊළඟ සතිය",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රීලනිප",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "දයාසිරි ජයසේකර",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඊයේ",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ජයසේකර",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මෛත්‍රීපාල සිරිසේන",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "කොරියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ඊළඟ සතිය",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "224",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජයසේකර",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "අප්රේල්",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මේ වසරේ",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජයසේකර",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ජයසේකර",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඩේලි මිරර්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "පළමුවන",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රීලනිප",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "පසුගිය සිකුරාදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මුදල් අමාත්යාංශය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "9",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජයසේකර",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "පළමුවන",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රීලනිප",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "පසුගිය සිකුරාදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මුදල් අමාත්යාංශය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "ஜனாதிபதியுடன் மீண்டும் பேச்சுவார்த்தை நடத்த அனைத்துக் கட்சி இடைக்கால அரசாங்கம் ஸ்ரீலங்கா சுதந்திரக் கட்சி",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "‘சமாதானத்திற்கான உலக உச்சி மாநாடு 2022’ என்ற உலகளாவிய மாநாட்டில் உரையாற்றுவதற்காக மைத்திரிபால சிறிசேன கொரியாவுக்கு விஜயம் செய்து நாடு திரும்புவார் என எதிர்பார்க்கப்படுகிறது, அதன் பின்னர் ஜனாதிபதிக்கும் ஸ்ரீலங்கா சுதந்திரக் கட்சிக்கும் இடையிலான இருதரப்பு பேச்சுவார்த்தைக்கான திகதி தீர்மானிக்கப்படும்.",
        "இந்த ஆண்டு ஏப்ரல் மாதம் வரை தற்போதைய பொருளாதார, அரசியல் மற்றும் சமூக குழப்பத்தில் இருந்து நாட்டை மீட்டெடுக்க சர்வகட்சி அரசாங்கத்தை முதன்முதலில் முன்மொழிந்தது SLFP தான்.",
        "பொதுத் தேர்தல் நடத்தப்படும் வரை சர்வகட்சி இடைக்கால அரசாங்கத்தை அமைப்பதற்கும், அரசாங்கத்துடன் இணக்கப்பாட்டுக்கு வருவதற்கும் ஸ்ரீலங்கா சுதந்திரக் கட்சி அடுத்த வாரம் ஜனாதிபதி ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்கவுடன் மீண்டும் ஒரு சுற்றுப் பேச்சுவார்த்தையை நடத்த விரும்புகிறது. ஸ்ரீலங்கா சுதந்திரக் கட்சியின் முன்னாள் அமைச்சர் தயாசிறி ஜயசேகர நேற்று தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "‘சமாதானத்திற்கான உலக உச்சி மாநாடு 2022’ என்ற உலகளாவிய மாநாட்டில் உரையாற்றுவதற்காக கட்சியின் தலைவரும் முன்னாள் ஜனாதிபதியுமான மைத்திரிபால சிறிசேன கொரியாவுக்கு விஜயம் செய்து நாடு திரும்புவார் என எதிர்பார்க்கப்படுவதாகவும் அதன் பின்னர் ஜனாதிபதிக்கும் ஸ்ரீலங்கா சுதந்திரக் கட்சிக்கும் இடையிலான இருதரப்பு பேச்சுவார்த்தைக்கான திகதி தீர்மானிக்கப்படும் என்றும் ஜயசேகர தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "\"அடுத்த வாரத்தில் சந்திப்போம் என்று நம்புகிறேன்,\"  ஜெயசேகர மேலும் கூறினார்.",
        "இடைக்கால அரசாங்கத்தில் இணையுமாறு ஜனாதிபதி விக்கிரமசிங்க அனைத்து 224 எம்.பி.க்களுக்கும் தனித்தனியாக அழைப்பு விடுத்திருப்பது குறித்து கருத்து தெரிவித்த ஜெயசேகர, அத்தகைய அழைப்பிற்கு மிகவும் பொருத்தமான மற்றும் வெளிப்படையான வழி கட்சித் தலைமையின் ஊடாக அழைப்பதாக இருக்கும் என்றார்.",
        "“தற்போதைய பொருளாதார, அரசியல் மற்றும் சமூகச் சீர்கேட்டில் இருந்து நாட்டை மீட்டெடுக்க அனைத்துக் கட்சி அரசாங்கத்தை முதன்முதலில் முன்மொழிந்தது ஸ்ரீலங்கா சுதந்திரக் கட்சிதான். அந்த பிரேரணையில், ஜனாதிபதி கட்சித் தலைவர்களுடன் கலந்தாலோசிக்க வேண்டும் மற்றும் அனைத்துக் கட்சிகளின் இடைக்கால அரசாங்கத்தில் பங்கேற்க பாராளுமன்றத்தை பிரதிநிதித்துவப்படுத்தும் அரசியல் கட்சிகளை அழைக்க வேண்டும் என்று நாங்கள் கூறினோம். எவ்வாறாயினும், அனைத்துக் கட்சிகளின் இடைக்கால அரசாங்கத்தில் இணையுமாறு கட்சித் தலைமையையும் ஜனாதிபதி விக்கிரமசிங்க அழைப்பார் என்று நான் எதிர்பார்க்கிறேன், ”என்று ஜெயசேகர கூறினார்.",
        "ஜனாதிபதி விக்கிரமசிங்கவுடன் நிதி அமைச்சில் கடந்த வெள்ளிக்கிழமை ஸ்ரீலங்கா சுதந்திரக் கட்சியின் தலைமை நடத்திய முதல் கலந்துரையாடல் வெற்றியடைந்ததாக ஜயசேகர டெய்லி மிரருக்கு தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "\"எரிபொருள் மற்றும் எரிவாயு வரிசைகளுக்கு முற்றுப்புள்ளி வைத்து, உணவு, மருந்துகள் மற்றும் பிற அத்தியாவசியப் பொருட்களின் நிலையான விநியோகத்தை உறுதிசெய்து, நாட்டில் ஸ்திரத்தன்மையை மீட்டெடுப்பதன் மூலம் நாடு இயல்பு நிலைக்குத் திரும்பியவுடன் பொதுத் தேர்தலை நடத்த வேண்டியதன் அவசியத்தை எடுத்துக்காட்டும் 9 அம்ச மூலோபாய திட்டத்தை நாங்கள் சமர்ப்பித்தோம். இருவராலும் ஒப்புக் கொள்ளப்பட்டது” என்று ஜெயசேகர குறிப்பிட்டார்.",
        "ஜனாதிபதி விக்கிரமசிங்கவுடன் நிதி அமைச்சில் ஸ்ரீலங்கா சுதந்திரக் கட்சியின் தலைமைத்துவம் கடந்த வெள்ளிக்கிழமை நடத்திய முதலாவது கலந்துரையாடல் வெற்றியளித்தது."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "அனைத்துக் கட்சி இடைக்கால அரசு ஸ்ரீ.ல.சு.க",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "மைத்திரிபால சிறிசேன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "கொரியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஏப்ரல்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்த வருடம்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "அடுத்த வாரம்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஸ்ரீ.ல.சு.க",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "தயாசிறி ஜயசேகர",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "நேற்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஜெயசேகர",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "மைத்திரிபால சிறிசேன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "கொரியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "அடுத்த வாரம்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "224",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜெயசேகர",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஏப்ரல்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்த வருடம்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜெயசேகர",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஜெயசேகர",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "டெய்லி மிரர்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "முதலில்",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஸ்ரீ.ல.சு.க",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "கடந்த வெள்ளிக்கிழமை",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "நிதி அமைச்சகம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "9",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜெயசேகர",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "முதலில்",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஸ்ரீ.ல.சு.க",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "கடந்த வெள்ளிக்கிழமை",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "நிதி அமைச்சகம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}