{
  "newspaper_id": "ada-derana-lk",
  "url": "http://www.adaderana.lk/news/84471/president-and-opposition-leader-hold-talks",
  "time_ut": 1661194920,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "President and Opposition Leader hold talks",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "President and Opposition Leader hold talks",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "A discussion between President Ranil Wickremesinghe and Opposition Leader Sajith Premadasa was reportedly held at the Presidential Secretariat in Colombo on Monday.",
        "The general secretary of the ‘Samagi Jana Balawegaya’, MP Ranjith Madduma Bandara had also participated in the meeting, according to sources.",
        "It is reported that the discussion focused on the formation of the proposed all-party government."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sajith Premadasa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Presidential Secretariat in Colombo",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "Monday",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the ‘Samagi Jana Balawegaya’",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ranjith Madduma Bandara",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        []
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "ජනපති සහ විපක්ෂ නායක සාකච්ඡාවක්",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "ජනාධිපති රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතා සහ විපක්ෂ නායක සජිත් ප්‍රේමදාස මහතා අතර සාකච්ඡාවක් සඳුදා කොළඹ ජනාධිපති ලේකම් කාර්යාලයේදී පැවති බව වාර්තා වේ.",
        "මෙම රැස්වීමට සමගි ජන බලවේගයේ ප්‍රධාන ලේකම් පාර්ලිමේන්තු මන්ත්‍රී රංජිත් මද්දුමබණ්ඩාර මහතාද සහභාගී වී සිටි බව ආරංචි මාර්ග පවසයි.",
        "යෝජිත සර්ව පාක්ෂික ආණ්ඩුව පිහිටුවීම සම්බන්ධයෙන් මෙම සාකච්ඡාවේදී අවධානය යොමු වූ බව වාර්තා වේ."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "සජිත් ප්‍රේමදාස",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "කොළඹ ජනාධිපති ලේකම් කාර්යාලයේදී",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "සඳුදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "සමගි ජන බලවේගය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "රංජිත් මද්දුම බණ්ඩාර",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        []
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "ஜனாதிபதியும் எதிர்க்கட்சித் தலைவரும் பேச்சுவார்த்தை நடத்துகின்றனர்",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "ஜனாதிபதி ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்கவிற்கும் எதிர்க்கட்சித் தலைவர் சஜித் பிரேமதாசவிற்கும் இடையில் இன்று திங்கட்கிழமை கொழும்பில் உள்ள ஜனாதிபதி செயலகத்தில் கலந்துரையாடல் இடம்பெற்றதாக தெரிவிக்கப்படுகிறது.",
        "சமகி ஜன பலவேகயவின் பொதுச் செயலாளர், பாராளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர் ரஞ்சித் மத்தும பண்டாரவும் இந்த சந்திப்பில் கலந்து கொண்டதாக தகவல்கள் தெரிவிக்கின்றன.",
        "உத்தேச சர்வகட்சி அரசாங்கத்தை அமைப்பது தொடர்பில் கலந்துரையாடப்பட்டதாகத் தெரிவிக்கப்படுகிறது."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "சஜித் பிரேமதாச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "கொழும்பில் உள்ள ஜனாதிபதி செயலகம்",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "திங்கட்கிழமை",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "‘சமகி ஜன பலவேகயா’",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரஞ்சித் மத்தும பண்டார",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        []
      ]
    }
  }
}