{
  "newspaper_id": "news-first-lk",
  "url": "https://www.newsfirst.lk/2022/06/25/welgama-assault-one-more-arrested/",
  "time_ut": 1656134400,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Welgama Assault : One more arrested",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Welgama Assault : One more arrested",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); The Criminal Investigations Department (CID) has arrested another suspect in connection with the assault on MP Kumara Welgama in Makumbura, Kottawa, on the 9th May.",
        "The suspect was identified as a 36-year-old resident of Magammana, Homagama.",
        "Police stated that seven suspects have been arrested so far in connection with the assault on MP Welgama.",
        "MP Kumara Welgama, his security guard and driver came under attack near the Makumbura Southern Expressway entrance in Kottawa, during the unrest which took place on 9th of May.",
        "Parliamentarian Welgama’s vehicle was also set on fire during the incident."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Welgama Assault",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "One",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "The Criminal Investigations Department",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "CID",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kumara Welgama",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Makumbura",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kottawa",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the 9th May",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "36-year-old",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Magammana",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Homagama",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "seven",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Welgama",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Kumara Welgama",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Makumbura Southern Expressway",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kottawa",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "9th of May",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        []
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "වෙල්ගමට පහරදීමක්: තවත් අයෙක් අත්අඩංගුවට",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); පාර්ලිමේන්තු මන්ත්‍රී කුමාර වෙල්ගම මහතාට කොට්ටාව, මාකුඹුර ප්‍රදේශයේදී පහරදීමේ සිද්ධියට සම්බන්ධ තවත් සැකකරුවෙකු අපරාධ පරීක්ෂණ දෙපාර්තමේන්තුව (CID) විසින් පසුගිය 09 වනදා අත්අඩංගුවට ගෙන තිබේ.",
        "සැකකරු හෝමාගම, මාගම්මන ප්‍රදේශයේ පදිංචි 36 හැවිරිදි පුද්ගලයෙකි.",
        "පාර්ලිමේන්තු මන්ත්‍රී වෙල්ගම මහතාට පහරදීමේ සිද්ධිය සම්බන්ධයෙන් මේ වන විට සැකකරුවන් හත් දෙනෙකු අත්අඩංගුවට ගෙන ඇති බව පොලීසිය ප්‍රකාශ කළා.",
        "කොට්ටාව, මාකුඹුර දක්ෂිණ අධිවේගී පිවිසුම අසලදී පසුගිය මැයි 9 වැනිදා ඇති වූ නොසන්සුන්තාව අතරතුර පාර්ලිමේන්තු මන්ත්‍රී කුමාර වෙල්ගම, ඔහුගේ ආරක්ෂක නිලධාරියා සහ රියදුරු ප්‍රහාරයට ලක්වුණා.",
        "සිද්ධිය අතරතුර පාර්ලිමේන්තු මන්ත්‍රී වෙල්ගමගේ වාහනයටද ගිනි තබා ඇත."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "වෙල්ගමට පහරදීම",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "එක",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "අපරාධ පරීක්ෂණ දෙපාර්තමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "CID",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "කුමාර වෙල්ගම",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "මාකුඹුර",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kottawa",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මැයි 9",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "36 හැවිරිදිය",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මාගම්මන",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Homagama",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "හත",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "වෙල්ගම",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "කුමාර වෙල්ගම",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "මාකුඹුර දක්ෂිණ අධිවේගී මාර්ගය",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kottawa",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මැයි 9 වෙනිදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        []
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "வெல்கம தாக்குதல்: மேலும் ஒருவர் கைது",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); கடந்த மே மாதம் 9 ஆம் திகதி கொட்டாவ, மகும்புர பிரதேசத்தில் பாராளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர் குமார வெல்கம தாக்கப்பட்டமை தொடர்பில் குற்றப் புலனாய்வு திணைக்களம் (CID) மேலும் ஒரு சந்தேக நபரை கைது செய்துள்ளது.",
        "சந்தேக நபர் ஹோமாகம, மாகம்மன பிரதேசத்தில் வசிக்கும் 36 வயதுடையவர் என அடையாளம் காணப்பட்டுள்ளார்.",
        "பாராளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர் வெல்கம தாக்கப்பட்டமை தொடர்பில் இதுவரை ஏழு சந்தேகநபர்கள் கைது செய்யப்பட்டுள்ளதாக பொலிஸார் தெரிவித்துள்ளனர்.",
        "கடந்த மே மாதம் 9 ஆம் திகதி இடம்பெற்ற அமைதியின்மையின் போது, ​​கொட்டாவ, மகும்புர தெற்கு அதிவேக நெடுஞ்சாலை நுழைவாயிலுக்கு அருகில் பாராளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர் குமார வெல்கம, அவரது பாதுகாப்பு உத்தியோகத்தர் மற்றும் சாரதி ஆகியோர் தாக்குதலுக்கு உள்ளாகினர்.",
        "இந்த சம்பவத்தின் போது நாடாளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர் வெல்கமவின் வாகனமும் தீ வைத்து எரிக்கப்பட்டது."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "வெல்கம தாக்குதல்",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "ஒன்று",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "குற்றப் புலனாய்வுத் திணைக்களம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "சி.ஐ.டி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "குமார வெல்கம",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "மகும்புரா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kottawa",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "மே 9",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "36 வயது",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "மகம்மன",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Homagama",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஏழு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "வெல்கம",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "குமார வெல்கம",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "மகும்புரா தெற்கு அதிவேக நெடுஞ்சாலை",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kottawa",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "மே 9 ஆம் தேதி",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        []
      ]
    }
  }
}