{
  "newspaper_id": "island-lk",
  "url": "http://island.lk/developing-cultural-and-historical-ties-between-india-and-sri-lanka-through-the-murugan-trail/",
  "time_ut": 1661878740,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Developing cultural and historical ties between India and Sri Lanka through the “Murugan Trail”",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Developing cultural and historical ties between India and Sri Lanka through the “Murugan Trail”",
      "author": "Sahan Weerasooriya",
      "body_lines": [
        "Sri Lanka was further able to strengthen its cultural and historical friendship with its Indian counterparts by organizing the first ever ‘’Murugan Trail ‘’ from South India, which was a Media FAM Tour organized by the Sri Lanka Tourism Promotion Bureau, in collaboration with the Sri Lanka Deputy High commission in Chennai, from 3rd to 13th August 2022.",
        "This was seen as a good initiative as the country is recovering slowly from its economic crisis, where the Tourism sector also suffered a considerable setback, with several countries issuing travel advisories. Sri Lanka Tourism is back on track with the hope of bringing one million tourists this year, where tourist arrivals are on the rise with the gradual relaxation of travel advisories at the same time. India has been exceptionally helpful towards its neighbor during this crucial period, by bringing the most number of tourist arrivals to the destination, recorded as 74,792 for the month of July 2022.",
        "The main purpose of organizing this FAM Tour was to promote the ‘’Murugan Trail’’ to South Indian tourists, who have a deep connection with Lord Murugan and the festivals as Hindu devotees. Nallur festival in Jaffna and Kataragama Esala Festival are held annually to pay homage to Lord Murugan. Nallur Kandaswamy Kovil or Nallur Murugan Kovil is one of the of the most significant Hindu temples in the Nallur, Jaffna. The Nallur Festival in Jaffna in August is the island’s longest festival. Spanning 25 days of vibrant chariot processions, drumming, dancing and acts of self-mortification, held in honor of the war god Skanda.",
        "Kataragama temple is mostly worshipped by Sinhalese and Hindu devotees. Kataragama plays a very pivotal role as it is a religious place of worship by both Sri Lankans and South Indians alike. Murugan, is the Hindu god of war, the son of Parvati and Shiva, the brother of Ganesha and a god whose legends have many versions in Hinduism. Skanda has been an important deity in the Indian subcontinent since ancient times, worshipped as Mahasena and Kumara in North India and is and predominantly worshipped in the state of Tamil Nadu and other parts of South India, Sri Lanka, Singapore, and Malaysia as Murugan. He is also known as the God of the Tamil people’’. Therefore, the Kataragama Esala Festival is also a crucial part of the Murugan Trail.",
        "In this regard, the Kataragama Esala Festival is a crucial celebration where Kataragama temple is dedicated to lord Murugan and is also known as ‘’Skandha’’ who is known among the Sinhalese as the “Kataragama Deviyo”. The Kataragama Esala Festival also holds an important place in the ‘’Murugan Trail ‘’ because of its historic connection. Due to this reason, many South Indians come to Sri Lanka as Pilgrims to worship.",
        "Bourse’s fortunes pick-up in the wake of IMF deal speculation",
        "Sampath Bank hands over Pubbiliya Wewa, the 12th successful restoration project in its Wewata Jeewayak program",
        "Leave a Reply Cancel replyYour email address will not be published. Required fields are marked *Comment Name *",
        "Save my name, email, and website in this browser for the next time I comment."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "India",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "Sri Lanka",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "the “Murugan Trail",
          "label": "FAC"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Indian",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "first",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "South India",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Sri Lanka Tourism Promotion Bureau",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "Chennai",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "3rd to 13th",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "August 2022",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Tourism",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "one million",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "this year",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "India",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "as 74,792",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "the month of July 2022",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the ‘’Murugan Trail",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "South Indian",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Murugan",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Hindu",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Jaffna",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kataragama Esala",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "annually",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Murugan",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Nallur Kandaswamy Kovil",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Nallur Murugan Kovil",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "one",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Hindu",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Nallur",
            "label": "PRODUCT"
          },
          {
            "text": "Jaffna",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "The Nallur Festival",
            "label": "EVENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "Jaffna",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "August",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "25 days",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Skanda",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sinhalese",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Hindu",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kataragama",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lankans",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "South Indians",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Murugan",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Hindu",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Shiva",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Hinduism",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Skanda",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Indian",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Mahasena",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kumara",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "North India",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "Tamil Nadu",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "South India",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Singapore",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Malaysia",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Murugan",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Tamil",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Murugan Trail",
            "label": "FAC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Kataragama",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Murugan",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sinhalese",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "the ‘’Murugan Trail ‘’",
            "label": "EVENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "South Indians",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Pilgrims",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Bourse’s",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "IMF",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sampath Bank",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Pubbiliya Wewa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the 12th",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Wewata Jeewayak",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [],
        []
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "\"මුරුගන් මාවත\" හරහා ඉන්දියාව සහ ශ්‍රී ලංකාව අතර සංස්කෘතික හා ඓතිහාසික සබඳතා වර්ධනය කිරීම",
      "author": "සහන් වීරසූරිය",
      "body_lines": [
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකා සංචාරක ප්‍රවර්ධන කාර්යාංශය විසින් සංවිධානය කරන ලද මාධ්‍ය FAM චාරිකාවක් වූ දකුණු ඉන්දියාවෙන් ප්‍රථම වරට සංවිධානය කරන ලද \"මුරුගන් ට්‍රේල්\" සංවිධානය කිරීම තුළින් ශ්‍රී ලංකාව සිය ඉන්දියානු සගයන් සමඟ ඇති සංස්කෘතික හා ඓතිහාසික මිත්‍රත්වය තවදුරටත් ශක්තිමත් කර ගැනීමට සමත් විය. චෙන්නායි හි ශ්‍රී ලංකා නියෝජ්‍ය මහ කොමසාරිස් කාර්යාලය, 2022 අගෝස්තු 3 සිට 13 දක්වා.",
        "රටවල් කිහිපයක් සංචාරක උපදේශන නිකුත් කිරීමත් සමඟ සංචාරක ක්ෂේත්‍රය ද සැලකිය යුතු පසුබෑමකට ලක්ව ඇති ආර්ථික අර්බුදයෙන් රට සෙමෙන් යථා තත්ත්වයට පත්වෙමින් පවතින බැවින් මෙය හොඳ මුලපිරීමක් ලෙස සැලකේ. සංචාරක උපදේශන ක්‍රමයෙන් ලිහිල් කිරීමත් සමඟ සංචාරක පැමිණීම් ඉහළ යන මේ වසරේ සංචාරකයින් දස ලක්ෂයක් ගෙන්වා ගැනීමේ අපේක්ෂාවෙන් ශ්‍රී ලංකා සංචාරක ව්‍යාපාරය යළිත් යථා තත්ත්වයට පත්ව ඇත. 2022 ජූලි මාසය සඳහා 74,792 ක් ලෙස වාර්තා වූ වැඩිම සංචාරකයින් සංඛ්‍යාවක් ගමනාන්තයට ගෙන ඒමෙන් ඉන්දියාව මෙම තීරණාත්මක කාල පරිච්ෙඡ්දය තුළ තම අසල්වැසියාට සුවිශේෂී ලෙස උපකාරී වී ඇත.",
        "මෙම FAM චාරිකාව සංවිධානය කිරීමේ ප්‍රධාන අරමුණ වූයේ හින්දු බැතිමතුන් ලෙස මුරුගන් දෙවියන් හා උත්සව සමඟ ගැඹුරු සම්බන්ධයක් ඇති දකුණු ඉන්දීය සංචාරකයින් වෙත ‘‘මුරුගන් මාවත’’ ප්‍රවර්ධනය කිරීමයි. යාපනයේ නල්ලූර් උත්සවය සහ කතරගම ඇසළ මංගල්‍යය වාර්ෂිකව මුරුගන් දෙවියන්ට ගෞරව දැක්වීම සඳහා පැවැත්වේ. නල්ලූර් කන්දස්වාමි කෝවිල නොහොත් නල්ලූර් මුරුගන් කෝවිල යාපනයේ නල්ලූර් හි පිහිටි හින්දු කෝවිල් අතුරින් ඉතා වැදගත් එකක් වේ. අගෝස්තු මාසයේ යාපනයේ පැවැත්වෙන නල්ලූර් උත්සවය දිවයිනේ දීර්ඝතම උත්සවය වේ. ස්කන්ධ යුධ දෙවියන්ට ගෞරව කිරීම සඳහා දින 25ක් පුරා විචිත්‍රවත් රථ පෙරහැර, බෙර වාදනය, නැටුම් සහ ස්වයං මරණ ක්‍රියාවන් පැවැත්විණි.",
        "කතරගම දේවාලය වැඩි වශයෙන් වන්දනා කරන්නේ සිංහල හා හින්දු බැතිමතුන්ය. කතරගම ශ්‍රී ලාංකිකයන් මෙන්ම දකුණු ඉන්දියානුවන්ද යන දෙඅංශයෙන්ම ආගමික සිද්ධස්ථානයක් වන බැවින් එය ඉතා වැදගත් කාර්යභාරයක් ඉටු කරයි. මුරුගන් යනු හින්දු යුද්ධ දෙවියාය, පාර්වතී සහ ශිව ගේ  පුත්‍රයා  ගණේෂා                                                                ినిల్ని  හින්දු ආගමේ  පවතින දෙවියෙක් වේ. ස්කන්ධ, පුරාණ කාලයේ සිට ඉන්දියානු උපමහාද්වීපයේ වැදගත් දෙවියෙක් වූ අතර, උතුරු ඉන්දියාවේ මහාසේන සහ කුමාර ලෙස වන්දනාමාන කරනු ලබන අතර, තමිල්නාඩු ප්‍රාන්තයේ සහ දකුණු ඉන්දියාව, ශ්‍රී ලංකාව, සිංගප්පූරුව සහ මැලේසියාවේ අනෙකුත් ප්‍රදේශවල ප්‍රධාන වශයෙන් මුරුගන් ලෙස වන්දනාමාන කරනු ලැබේ. ඔහු දෙමළ ජනතාවගේ දෙවියා ලෙසද හැඳින්වේ. එබැවින් කතරගම ඇසළ මංගල්‍යය ද මුරුගන් මාවතේ තීරණාත්මක අංගයකි.",
        "මේ සම්බන්ධයෙන් ගත් කල, කතරගම ඇසළ මංගල්‍යය තීරණාත්මක උත්සවයක් වන අතර එහිදී කතරගම දේවාලය මුරුගන් දෙවියන්ට කැප කර ඇති අතර සිංහලයන් අතර “කතරගම දෙවියෝ” ලෙස හඳුන්වන “ස්කන්ධ” ලෙසද හැඳින්වේ. කතරගම ඇසළ මංගල්‍යය ද ‛‛මුරුගන් මංපෙත’’ තුළ වැදගත් ස්ථානයක් හිමිකර ගන්නේ එහි ඇති ඓතිහාසික සම්බන්ධය නිසාය. මේ හේතුව නිසා බොහෝ දකුණු ඉන්දියානුවන් වන්දනාකරුවන් ලෙස ශ්‍රී ලංකාවට පැමිණේ.",
        "IMF ගණුදෙණු සමපේක්ෂනය ඉක්බිති Bourse හි වාසනාව ඉහල යයි",
        "සම්පත් බැංකුව සිය වැවට ජීවයක් වැඩසටහනේ 12 වැනි සාර්ථක ප්‍රතිසංස්කරණ ව්‍යාපෘතිය වන පුබ්බිලිය වැව භාර දෙයි",
        "පිළිතුරක් දෙන්න පිළිතුර අවලංගු කරන්න ඔබගේ විද්‍යුත් තැපැල් ලිපිනය ප්‍රකාශයට පත් නොකෙරේ. අවශ්‍ය ක්ෂේත්‍ර සලකුණු කර ඇත *අදහස් නම *",
        "මම ඊළඟ වතාවේ අදහස් දැක්වීම සඳහා මගේ නම, විද්‍යුත් තැපෑල සහ වෙබ් අඩවිය මෙම බ්‍රවුසරයේ සුරකින්න."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ඉන්දියාව",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "\"මුරුගන් මාවත",
          "label": "FAC"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දීය",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "පළමුවන",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "දකුණු ඉන්දියාව",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකා සංචාරක ප්‍රවර්ධන කාර්යාංශය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "චෙන්නායි",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "3 සිට 13 දක්වා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "2022 අගෝස්තු",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "සංචාරක",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "මිලියනයක්",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "මේ වසරේ",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "74,792 ක් ලෙසිනි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "2022 ජූලි මාසය",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "මුරුගන් මාවත",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "දකුණු ඉන්දියානු",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "මුරුගන්",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "හින්දු",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "යාපනය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "කතරගම ඇසළ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "වාර්ෂිකව",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මුරුගන්",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "නල්ලූර් කන්දස්වාමි කෝවිල",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "නල්ලූර් මුරුගන් කෝවිල",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "එක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "හින්දු",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "නල්ලුර්",
            "label": "PRODUCT"
          },
          {
            "text": "යාපනය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "නල්ලූර් උත්සවය",
            "label": "EVENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "යාපනය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "අගෝස්තු",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "දින 25 යි",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ස්කන්ධ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "සිංහල",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "හින්දු",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "කතරගම",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලාංකිකයන්",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "දකුණු ඉන්දියානුවන්",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "මුරුගන්",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "හින්දු",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශිව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "හින්දු ආගම",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ස්කන්ධ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දීය",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "මහසේන",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "කුමාර",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "උතුරු ඉන්දියාව",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "තමිල්නාඩුව",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "දකුණු ඉන්දියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "සිංගප්පූරුව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මැලේසියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මුරුගන්",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "දෙමළ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "මුරුගන් මාවත",
            "label": "FAC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "කතරගම",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මුරුගන්",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "සිංහල",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "‘‘මුරුගන් මාවත’’",
            "label": "EVENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "දකුණු ඉන්දියානුවන්",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "වන්දනාකරුවන්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Bourse ගේ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "IMF",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "සම්පත් බැංකුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Pubbiliya Wewa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "12 වැනි",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "වැවට ජීවයක්",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [],
        []
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "\"முருகன் பாதை\" மூலம் இந்தியாவிற்கும் இலங்கைக்கும் இடையிலான கலாச்சார மற்றும் வரலாற்று உறவுகளை மேம்படுத்துதல்",
      "author": "சஹான் வீரசூரிய",
      "body_lines": [
        "இலங்கை சுற்றுலா ஊக்குவிப்பு பணியகத்தால் ஏற்பாடு செய்யப்பட்ட ஊடக FAM சுற்றுலாவான தென்னிந்தியாவிலிருந்து முதன்முதலில் \"முருகன் பாதையை\" ஏற்பாடு செய்ததன் மூலம் இலங்கை தனது இந்திய சகாக்களுடன் தனது கலாச்சார மற்றும் வரலாற்று நட்பை மேலும் வலுப்படுத்த முடிந்தது. 2022 ஆகஸ்ட் 3 முதல் 13 வரை சென்னையில் உள்ள இலங்கை துணை உயர் ஸ்தானிகராலயம்.",
        "நாடு தனது பொருளாதார நெருக்கடியிலிருந்து மெதுவாக மீண்டு வருவதால், சுற்றுலாத் துறையும் கணிசமான பின்னடைவைச் சந்தித்ததால், பல நாடுகள் பயண ஆலோசனைகளை வழங்குவதால், இது ஒரு நல்ல முயற்சியாகக் காணப்பட்டது. இந்த ஆண்டு ஒரு மில்லியன் சுற்றுலாப் பயணிகளை வரவழைக்கும் நம்பிக்கையுடன் இலங்கை சுற்றுலாத் துறை மீண்டும் பாதைக்கு திரும்பியுள்ளது, அதே நேரத்தில் பயண ஆலோசனைகள் படிப்படியாக தளர்த்தப்பட்டதன் மூலம் சுற்றுலாப் பயணிகளின் வருகை அதிகரித்து வருகிறது. 2022 ஜூலை மாதத்தில் 74,792 சுற்றுலாப் பயணிகளின் வருகையைப் பதிவு செய்ததன் மூலம், இந்த முக்கியமான காலகட்டத்தில், இந்தியா தனது அண்டை நாடுகளுக்கு விதிவிலக்காக உதவிகரமாக இருந்தது.",
        "இந்த FAM சுற்றுப்பயணத்தை ஏற்பாடு செய்ததன் முக்கிய நோக்கம், முருகன் மற்றும் திருவிழாக்களுடன் இந்து பக்தர்களுடன் ஆழமான தொடர்பைக் கொண்ட தென்னிந்திய சுற்றுலாப் பயணிகளுக்கு ‘‘முருகன் பாதை’’யை ஊக்குவிப்பதாகும். யாழ்ப்பாணத்தில் நல்லூர் திருவிழாவும், கதிர்காமம் எசல திருவிழாவும் ஆண்டுதோறும் முருகப் பெருமானை வழிபடும் வகையில் நடைபெற்று வருகிறது. நல்லூர் கந்தசுவாமி கோவில் அல்லது நல்லூர் முருகன் கோவில் யாழ்ப்பாணம் நல்லூரில் உள்ள இந்துக் கோவில்களில் முக்கியமான ஒன்றாகும். ஆகஸ்ட் மாதம் யாழ்ப்பாணத்தில் நடைபெறும் நல்லூர் திருவிழா தீவின் மிக நீண்ட திருவிழாவாகும். போர்க் கடவுளான ஸ்கந்தாவின் நினைவாக 25 நாட்கள் துடிப்பான ரத ஊர்வலங்கள், மேளம், நடனம் மற்றும் சுயமரியாதைச் செயல்கள் நடைபெற்றன.",
        "கதிர்காமம் கோவில் பெரும்பாலும் சிங்கள மற்றும் இந்து பக்தர்களால் வழிபடப்படுகிறது. கதிர்காமம் இலங்கை மற்றும் தென்னிந்தியர்களின் மத வழிபாட்டுத் தலமாக இருப்பதால் இது மிகவும் முக்கிய பங்கு வகிக்கிறது. முருகன், இந்து போர் கடவுள், பார்வதி மற்றும் சிவன் மகன், விநாயகரின் சகோதரர் மற்றும் இந்து மதத்தில் பல புராணக்கதைகளைக் கொண்ட கடவுள். பழங்காலத்திலிருந்தே இந்தியத் துணைக்கண்டத்தில் ஒரு முக்கியமான தெய்வமாக ஸ்கந்தன் இருந்துள்ளார், வட இந்தியாவில் மகாசேனா மற்றும் குமாரனாக வழிபடப்படுகிறார், மேலும் தமிழ்நாடு மாநிலத்திலும் தென்னிந்தியா, இலங்கை, சிங்கப்பூர் மற்றும் மலேசியாவின் பிற பகுதிகளிலும் முருகனாக வழிபடப்படுகிறார். அவர் தமிழ் மக்களின் கடவுள் என்றும் அழைக்கப்படுகிறார். எனவே, கதிர்காமம் எசல திருவிழாவும் முருகன் பாதையில் ஒரு முக்கிய பகுதியாகும்.",
        "இது சம்பந்தமாக, கதிர்காமம் முருகனுக்கு அர்ப்பணிக்கப்பட்ட கதிர்காம ஆலயம் ஒரு முக்கியமான கொண்டாட்டமாகும், மேலும் இது சிங்களவர்களிடையே \"கத்தரகமா தேவியோ\" என்று அழைக்கப்படும் \"ஸ்கந்தா\" என்றும் அழைக்கப்படுகிறது. கதிர்காமம் எசல திருவிழாவும் அதன் வரலாற்றுத் தொடர்பு காரணமாக ‘முருகன் பாதையில்’ ஒரு முக்கிய இடத்தைப் பிடித்துள்ளது. இதன் காரணமாக தென்னிந்தியர்கள் பலர் இலங்கைக்கு யாத்ரீகர்களாக வந்து வழிபடுகின்றனர்.",
        "IMF ஒப்பந்த ஊகங்களை அடுத்து Bourse இன் அதிர்ஷ்டம் பிக்-அப்",
        "சம்பத் வங்கி தனது வேவட ஜீவாயக் திட்டத்தில் 12வது வெற்றிகரமான மறுசீரமைப்பு திட்டமான பப்பிலிய வெவாவை கையளிக்கிறது",
        "ஒரு பதிலை விடுங்கள் பதிலை ரத்துசெய் உங்கள் மின்னஞ்சல் முகவரி வெளியிடப்படாது. தேவையான புலங்கள் குறிக்கப்பட்டுள்ளன *கருத்து பெயர் *",
        "அடுத்த முறை நான் கருத்து தெரிவிக்க, எனது பெயர், மின்னஞ்சல் மற்றும் இணையதளத்தை இந்த உலாவியில் சேமிக்கவும்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "இந்தியா",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "இலங்கை",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "\"முருகன் பாதை",
          "label": "FAC"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்தியன்",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "முதலில்",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "தென் இந்தியா",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை சுற்றுலா ஊக்குவிப்பு பணியகம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "சென்னை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "3 முதல் 13 வரை",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆகஸ்ட் 2022",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "சுற்றுலா",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஒரு மில்லியன்",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்த வருடம்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்தியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "74,792 ஆக உள்ளது",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜூலை 2022 மாதம்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "முருகன் பாதை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "தென்னிந்தியா",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "முருகன்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்து",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "யாழ்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "கதிர்கம எசல",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆண்டுதோறும்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "முருகன்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "நல்லூர் கந்தசுவாமி கோவில்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "நல்லூர் முருகன் கோவில்",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஒன்று",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்து",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "நல்லூர்",
            "label": "PRODUCT"
          },
          {
            "text": "யாழ்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "நல்லூர் திருவிழா",
            "label": "EVENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "யாழ்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆகஸ்ட்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "25 நாட்கள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஸ்கந்தா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "சிங்களவர்கள்",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்து",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "கதிர்காமம்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கையர்கள்",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "தென் இந்தியர்கள்",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "முருகன்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்து",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "சிவன்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்து மதம்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஸ்கந்தா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்தியன்",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "மகாசேனா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "குமார",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "வட இந்தியா",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "தமிழ்நாடு",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "தென் இந்தியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சிங்கப்பூர்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "மலேசியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "முருகன்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "தமிழ்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "முருகன் பாதை",
            "label": "FAC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "கதிர்காமம்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "முருகன்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சிங்களவர்கள்",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "''முருகன் பாதை''",
            "label": "EVENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "தென் இந்தியர்கள்",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "யாத்ரீகர்கள்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "போர்ஸின்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "IMF",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "சம்பத் வங்கி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Pubbiliya Wewa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "12வது",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "வெவத ஜீவாயக்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [],
        []
      ]
    }
  }
}