{
  "newspaper_id": "ada-lk",
  "url": "https://www.ada.lk/breaking_news/ගෑස්-පෝලිමේ-සිටි-අයෙකුගේ-හිසට-පොල්-ගෙඩියක්-වැටී-රෝහලට/11-395616",
  "time_ut": 1658386970,
  "original_lang": "si",
  "original_title": "ගෑස් පෝලිමේ සිටි අයෙකුගේ හිසට පොල් ගෙඩියක් වැටී රෝහලට",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "A coconut fell on the head of a person who was in the gas queue and went to the hospital",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "The Pitigala police said that a coconut fell on the head of a person standing in the gas queue in the Pitigala area today (21st) and he was taken to the hospital with serious injuries.",
        "The police say that a father of three residing in Pitigala Idipalagoda area has been hospitalized.",
        "This coconut has fallen on the head of a person who was standing in the gas queue at Pitigala Idipalegoda school grounds for five days now.",
        "Elpitiya hospital sources say that the condition of the person whose head the coconut fell on is serious. Pitigala Police is conducting further investigations in this regard."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Pitigala",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Pitigala",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "21st",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "three",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Pitigala Idipalagoda",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Pitigala Idipalegoda",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "five days",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Pitigala Police",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "ගෑස් පෝලිමේ සිටි අයෙකුගේ හිසට පොල් ගෙඩියක් වැටී රෝහලට",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "පිටිගල ප්‍රදේශයේ ගෑස්  පෝලිමේ සිටි අයකුගේ හිසට අද (21දා)පොල් ගෙඩියක් වැටි බරපතල තුවාල ලබා රෝහල් ගත කල බව පිටිගල පොලිසිය පවසයි .",
        "මෙසේ රෝහල්ගත කොට ඇත්තේ පිටිගල ඉදිපලගොඩ ප්‍රදේශයේම පදිංචි තිදරු පියෙක් බවද පොලිසිය කියයි.",
        "දැනට දින පහක් තිස්සේ පිටිගල ඉදිපලේගොඩ විදුහල් පිටියේ ගෑස් පෝලිමේ සිටි අයෙකුගේ හිසට මේ පොල් ගෙඩිය වැටි තිබේ.",
        "හිසට පොල් ගෙඩිය වැටුණු තැනැත්තාගේ තත්ත්වය බරපතල බව ඇල්පිටිය රෝහල් ආරංචි මාර්ග කියයි . පිටිගල පොලිසිය මේ පිලිබදව වැඩිදුර පරීක්ෂණ පවත්වයි ."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "පිටිගල",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "පිටිගල",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "21 වැනි",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "තුන්",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "පිටිගල ඉදිපලාගොඩ",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "පිටිගල ඉදිපලේගොඩ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "දින පහක්",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "පිටිගල පොලිසිය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "காஸ் கியூவில் இருந்தவரின் தலையில் தேங்காய் விழுந்து மருத்துவமனை சென்றது",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "இன்று (21) பிடிகல பிரதேசத்தில் எரிவாயு வரிசையில் நின்றிருந்த நபரின் தலையில் தேங்காய் விழுந்து பலத்த காயங்களுக்குள்ளான நிலையில் வைத்தியசாலைக்கு கொண்டு செல்லப்பட்டதாக பிடிகல பொலிஸார் தெரிவித்தனர்.",
        "பிடிகல இடிபாலகொட பிரதேசத்தில் வசிக்கும் மூன்று பிள்ளைகளின் தந்தையொருவரே வைத்தியசாலையில் அனுமதிக்கப்பட்டுள்ளதாக பொலிஸார் தெரிவிக்கின்றனர்.",
        "பிடிகல இடிபலேகொட பாடசாலை மைதானத்தில் காஸ் வரிசையில் நின்ற ஒருவரின் தலையில் இந்த தேங்காய் விழுந்து ஐந்து நாட்களாகின்றன.",
        "தலையில் தேங்காய் விழுந்த நபரின் நிலைமை கவலைக்கிடமாக உள்ளதாக எல்பிட்டிய வைத்தியசாலை வட்டாரங்கள் தெரிவிக்கின்றன. இது தொடர்பான மேலதிக விசாரணைகளை பிடிகல பொலிஸார் மேற்கொண்டு வருகின்றனர்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "பிடிகல",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "பிடிகல",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "21 ஆம் தேதி",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "மூன்று",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "பிடிகல இடிபாலகொட",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பிடிகல இடிபலேகொட",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஐந்து நாட்கள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பிடிகல பொலிஸ்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}