{
  "newspaper_id": "island-lk",
  "url": "http://island.lk/mas-joins-sri-lanka-athletics-as-official-clothing-partner/",
  "time_ut": 1659176700,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "MAS joins Sri Lanka Athletics as official clothing partner",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "MAS joins Sri Lanka Athletics as official clothing partner",
      "author": "Thilina Walpola",
      "body_lines": [
        "Sri Lanka Athletics has an official clothing partner for the first time after Bodyline (Pvt.) Ltd, a subsidiary of MAS Holdings pledged its support to provide kits for national athletes until the Paris Olympics, at a function held in Colombo on Thursday.",
        "Speaking at the function Major Gen. Palitha Fernando, the President of Sri Lanka Athletics marked it as a historic moment for the sport which celebrates its centenary this year.",
        "“Through this partnership, MAS will provide Sri Lankan athletes with kits designed using the latest in apparel technology, to support their training and performance at international events leading up to the Paris Olympics in 2024. A contingent of 20 athletes who toured India in June this year was the first group to receive game day and training kits designed by MAS,” a statement from the sponsor said.",
        "Dinesh de Silva, Chief Executive Officer of Bodyline, officially handed over the athletic kits designed by MAS to the President of the SLA and future prospect Medhani Jayamanne, who was one of the first athletes to get MAS’ support.",
        "Former national champion Umanga Surendra who trains Jayamanne had negotiated with MAS on behalf of SLA after his trainee became a beneficiary of MAS’ support for clothing.",
        "Despite not winning international medals, the premier Olympic sport has things to celebrate in the centenary year with one of its athletes reaching phenomenal highs to be rated among the top athletes in the world.",
        "Sprinter Yupun Abeykoon who became the first South Asian to produce a sub 10 seconds feat in the 100 metres dash recently is among the top sprinters in Asia and will carry the country’s hopes at several future international events including the ongoing Commonwealth Games.",
        "Sri Lanka Athletics is set to send athletes for a number of junior and senior events during the next two years where they will be clad in kits provided by MAS.The agreement between SLA and MAS was signed by the President of Sri Lanka Athletics, Palitha Fernando, and Dinesh de Silva, Chief Executive Officer of Bodyline Trading (Pvt) Ltd respectively.",
        "Nine Gateway Griffins receive Golden Eagle Awards for representing Sri Lanka",
        "Leave a Reply Cancel replyYour email address will not be published. Required fields are marked *Comment Name *",
        "Save my name, email, and website in this browser for the next time I comment."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Sri Lanka Athletics",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka Athletics",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "first",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Bodyline (Pvt.) Ltd",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "MAS Holdings",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Paris Olympics",
            "label": "EVENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "Colombo",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Thursday",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Palitha Fernando",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka Athletics",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "this year",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "MAS",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lankan",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Paris Olympics",
            "label": "EVENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "2024",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "20",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "India",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "June this year",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "first",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "MAS",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Dinesh de Silva",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Bodyline",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "MAS",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "SLA",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Medhani Jayamanne",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "one",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "first",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Jayamanne",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "MAS",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the centenary year",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "one",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sprinter Yupun Abeykoon",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "first",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "South Asian",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "a sub 10 seconds",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "100 metres",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "Asia",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "Commonwealth Games",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka Athletics",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the next two years",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "MAS",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka Athletics",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Palitha Fernando",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Dinesh de Silva",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Bodyline Trading (Pvt) Ltd",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Nine Gateway Griffins",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Golden Eagle Awards",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [],
        []
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "MAS නිල ඇඳුම් සහකරු ලෙස ශ්‍රී ලංකා මලල ක්‍රීඩා හා සම්බන්ධ වේ",
      "author": "තිළිණ වල්පොල",
      "body_lines": [
        "MAS Holdings හි අනුබද්ධිත Bodyline (Pvt.) Ltd, පැරිස් ඔලිම්පික් උළෙල දක්වා ජාතික මලල ක්‍රීඩක ක්‍රීඩිකාවන් සඳහා ඇඳුම් කට්ටල ලබාදීමට සිය සහය ලබා දීමෙන් පසු ප්‍රථම වරට ශ්‍රී ලංකා මලල ක්‍රීඩා සඳහා නිල ඇඳුම් සහකරුවෙකු සිටී.",
        "උත්සවය අමතමින් ශ්‍රී ලංකා මලල ක්‍රීඩා සභාපති මේජර් ජෙනරාල් පාලිත ප්‍රනාන්දු මහතා එය සනිටුහන් කළේ මෙවර සිය සංවත්සරය සමරන ක්‍රීඩාවේ ඓතිහාසික අවස්ථාවක් ලෙසයි.",
        "2024 පැරිස් ඔලිම්පික් උළෙල දක්වා ජාත්‍යන්තර ඉසව්වලදී ඔවුන්ගේ පුහුණුවීම් සහ දස්කම් සඳහා සහාය වීම සඳහා නවීනතම ඇඟලුම් තාක්ෂණය යොදා ගනිමින් නිර්මාණය කරන ලද ඇඳුම් කට්ටල මෙම හවුල්කාරිත්වය හරහා MAS විසින් ශ්‍රී ලාංකික ක්‍රීඩක ක්‍රීඩිකාවන්ට ලබා දෙනු ඇත. මේ ජුනි මාසයේදී ඉන්දියාවේ සංචාරය කළ ක්‍රීඩක ක්‍රීඩිකාවන් 20 දෙනෙකුගෙන් යුත් කණ්ඩායමක්. MAS විසින් නිර්මාණය කරන ලද ක්‍රීඩා දින සහ පුහුණු කට්ටල ලබාගත් පළමු කණ්ඩායම වසරයි.",
        "බොඩිලයින් හි ප්‍රධාන විධායක නිලධාරී දිනේෂ් ද සිල්වා මහතා විසින් MAS විසින් නිර්මාණය කරන ලද මලල ක්‍රීඩා කට්ටල SLA හි සභාපතිනිය සහ MAS හි සහය ලැබූ ප්‍රථම ක්‍රීඩිකාවන් අතර අනාගත අපේක්‍ෂක මේධානි ජයමාන්න වෙත නිල වශයෙන් භාර දෙන ලදී.",
        "ජයමාන්න පුහුණු කරන හිටපු ජාතික ශූර උමංග සුරේන්ද්‍ර SLA වෙනුවෙන් MAS සමඟ සාකච්ඡා කර ඇත්තේ ඔහුගේ අභ්‍යාසලාභියා MAS හි ඇඳුම් සඳහා සහය ලැබීමෙන් පසුවය.",
        "ජාත්‍යන්තර පදක්කම් දිනා නොගත්තද, ප්‍රමුඛ ඔලිම්පික් ක්‍රීඩාවට ශත සංවත්සරයේ සැමරීමට දේවල් තිබේ, එහි එක් ක්‍රීඩකයෙක් ලෝකයේ ඉහළම ක්‍රීඩක ක්‍රීඩිකාවන් අතර ශ්‍රේණිගත කිරීම සඳහා අතිවිශිෂ්ට ඉහළ මට්ටම් කරා ළඟා වේ.",
        "පසුගියදා මීටර් 100 ඉසව්වෙන් තත්පර 10ට අඩු දක්ෂතාවක් දැක්වූ දකුණු ආසියාවේ ප්‍රථම ස්ප්‍රින්ටර් ක්‍රීඩක යූපුන් අබේකෝන් ආසියාවේ ප්‍රමුඛතම ධාවන ශූරයන් අතරට එක්වන අතර දැනට පැවැත්වෙන පොදුරාජ්‍ය මණ්ඩලීය ක්‍රීඩා උළෙල ඇතුළු අනාගත ජාත්‍යන්තර ඉසව් කිහිපයකදී රටේ බලාපොරොත්තු රැගෙන යනු ඇත.",
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකා මලල ක්‍රීඩා උළෙල ඉදිරි වසර දෙක තුළදී කනිෂ්ඨ සහ ජ්‍යෙෂ්ඨ ඉසව් රැසක් සඳහා ක්‍රීඩක ක්‍රීඩිකාවන් යැවීමට නියමිත අතර එහිදී ඔවුන් MAS විසින් ලබාදෙන ඇඳුම් කට්ටලවලින් සැරසීමට නියමිතය. SLA සහ MAS අතර ගිවිසුමට ශ්‍රී ලංකා මලල ක්‍රීඩා සභාපති පාලිත ප්‍රනාන්දු මහතා විසින් අත්සන් තබන ලදී. , සහ Bodyline Trading (Pvt) Ltd හි ප්‍රධාන විධායක නිලධාරී දිනේෂ් ද සිල්වා පිළිවෙලින්.",
        "Gateway Griffins නවයක් ශ්‍රී ලංකාව නියෝජනය කිරීම වෙනුවෙන් ගෝල්ඩන් ඊගල් සම්මාන ලබයි",
        "පිළිතුරක් දෙන්න පිළිතුර අවලංගු කරන්න ඔබගේ විද්‍යුත් තැපැල් ලිපිනය ප්‍රකාශයට පත් නොකෙරේ. අවශ්‍ය ක්ෂේත්‍ර සලකුණු කර ඇත *අදහස් නම *",
        "මම ඊළඟ වතාවේ අදහස් දැක්වීම සඳහා මගේ නම, විද්‍යුත් තැපෑල සහ වෙබ් අඩවිය මෙම බ්‍රවුසරයේ සුරකින්න."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකා මලල ක්‍රීඩා",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකා මලල ක්‍රීඩා",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "පළමුවන",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Bodyline (Pvt.) Ltd",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "MAS Holdings",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "පැරිස් ඔලිම්පික්",
            "label": "EVENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "කොළඹ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "බ්රහස්පතින්දා",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "පාලිත ප්‍රනාන්දු",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකා මලල ක්‍රීඩා",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "මේ වසරේ",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "MAS",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලාංකික",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "පැරිස් ඔලිම්පික්",
            "label": "EVENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "2024",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "20",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මේ වසරේ ජූනි",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "පළමුවන",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "MAS",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "දිනේෂ් ද සිල්වා",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශරීර රේඛාව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "MAS",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "එස්.එල්.ඒ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "මේධානි ජයමාන්න",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "එක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "පළමුවන",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ජයමාන්න",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "MAS",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "සියවස් වසර",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "එක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "කෙටි දුර ධාවන ශූර යුපුන් අබේකෝන්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "පළමුවන",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "දකුණු ආසියානු",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "තත්පර 10 උප",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "මීටර් 100 යි",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "ආසියාව",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "පොදුරාජ්‍ය මණ්ඩලීය ක්‍රීඩා උළෙල",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකා මලල ක්‍රීඩා",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉදිරි වසර දෙක",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "MAS",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකා මලල ක්‍රීඩා",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාලිත ප්‍රනාන්දු",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "දිනේෂ් ද සිල්වා",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Bodyline Trading (Pvt) Ltd",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Gateway Griffins නවයක්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගෝල්ඩන් ඊගල් සම්මාන",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [],
        []
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "MAS உத்தியோகபூர்வ ஆடை பங்காளியாக இலங்கை தடகளத்துடன் இணைந்துள்ளது",
      "author": "திலின வல்பொல",
      "body_lines": [
        "வியாழன் அன்று கொழும்பில் நடைபெற்ற விழாவில், MAS ஹோல்டிங்ஸின் துணை நிறுவனமான Bodyline (Pvt.) Ltd, பாரீஸ் ஒலிம்பிக் வரை தேசிய விளையாட்டு வீரர்களுக்கு கிட் வழங்குவதற்கு தனது ஆதரவை உறுதியளித்ததை அடுத்து, இலங்கை தடகளம் முதல் முறையாக உத்தியோகபூர்வ ஆடை பங்காளியாக உள்ளது.",
        "இந்நிகழ்வில் கலந்து கொண்டு உரையாற்றிய இலங்கை தடகளத் தலைவர் மேஜர் ஜெனரல் பாலித பெர்னாண்டோ, இந்த ஆண்டு தனது நூற்றாண்டைக் கொண்டாடும் விளையாட்டுக்கு இது ஒரு வரலாற்றுத் தருணம் என்று குறிப்பிட்டார்.",
        "2024 ஆம் ஆண்டு பாரிஸ் ஒலிம்பிக்கிற்கு முன்னோடியாகவுள்ள சர்வதேச நிகழ்வுகளில் அவர்களின் பயிற்சி மற்றும் செயல்திறனை ஆதரிக்கும் வகையில், இலங்கை விளையாட்டு வீரர்களுக்கு நவீன ஆடைத் தொழில்நுட்பத்தைப் பயன்படுத்தி வடிவமைக்கப்பட்ட கருவிகளை MAS வழங்கும். MAS ஆல் வடிவமைக்கப்பட்ட விளையாட்டு நாள் மற்றும் பயிற்சிக் கருவிகளைப் பெற்ற முதல் குழு ஆண்டு,\" என்று ஸ்பான்சரின் அறிக்கை கூறியது.",
        "Bodyline இன் பிரதம நிறைவேற்று அதிகாரி தினேஷ் டி சில்வா, MAS ஆல் வடிவமைக்கப்பட்ட தடகள உபகரணங்களை SLA இன் தலைவரும் எதிர்கால எதிர்பார்ப்புமான மேதானி ஜெயமான்னவிடம் உத்தியோகபூர்வமாக கையளித்தார்.",
        "ஜயமான்னேவை பயிற்றுவிக்கும் முன்னாள் தேசிய சாம்பியனான உமங்கா சுரேந்திரா SLA சார்பாக MAS உடன் பேச்சுவார்த்தை நடத்தினார்.",
        "சர்வதேசப் பதக்கங்களை வெல்லாத போதிலும், முதன்மையான ஒலிம்பிக் விளையாட்டானது நூற்றாண்டு ஆண்டில் கொண்டாட வேண்டிய விஷயங்களைக் கொண்டுள்ளது, அதன் விளையாட்டு வீரர்களில் ஒருவர் உலகின் தலைசிறந்த விளையாட்டு வீரர்களில் ஒருவரான தனிச்சிறப்புமிக்க உயரங்களை எட்டினார்.",
        "அண்மையில் 100 மீற்றர் ஓட்டத்தில் 10 வினாடிகளுக்குள் சாதனை படைத்த முதல் தெற்காசிய வீரரான யுபுன் அபேகோன், ஆசியாவின் சிறந்த ஓட்டப்பந்தய வீரர்களில் ஒருவராவார், மேலும் தற்போது நடைபெற்று வரும் காமன்வெல்த் விளையாட்டுப் போட்டிகள் உட்பட பல எதிர்கால சர்வதேச நிகழ்வுகளில் நாட்டின் நம்பிக்கையை சுமந்து செல்வார்.",
        "ஸ்ரீலங்கா தடகள விளையாட்டு வீரர்களை அடுத்த இரண்டு ஆண்டுகளில் பல கனிஷ்ட மற்றும் சிரேஷ்ட போட்டிகளுக்கு அனுப்ப உள்ளது. அங்கு அவர்கள் MAS வழங்கும் கிட்களை அணிவார்கள். SLA மற்றும் MAS இடையேயான ஒப்பந்தத்தில் இலங்கை தடகளத் தலைவர் பாலித பெர்னாண்டோ கையெழுத்திட்டார். , மற்றும் தினேஷ் டி சில்வா, முறையே Bodyline Trading (Pvt) Ltd இன் பிரதம நிறைவேற்று அதிகாரி.",
        "ஒன்பது கேட்வே கிரிஃபின்ஸ் இலங்கையைப் பிரதிநிதித்துவப்படுத்தியதற்காக கோல்டன் ஈகிள் விருதுகளைப் பெறுகின்றனர்",
        "ஒரு பதிலை விடுங்கள் பதிலை ரத்துசெய் உங்கள் மின்னஞ்சல் முகவரி வெளியிடப்படாது. தேவையான புலங்கள் குறிக்கப்பட்டுள்ளன *கருத்து பெயர் *",
        "அடுத்த முறை நான் கருத்து தெரிவிக்க, எனது பெயர், மின்னஞ்சல் மற்றும் இணையதளத்தை இந்த உலாவியில் சேமிக்கவும்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "இலங்கை தடகள",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை தடகள",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "முதலில்",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Bodyline (Pvt.) Ltd",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "MAS ஹோல்டிங்ஸ்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாரிஸ் ஒலிம்பிக்",
            "label": "EVENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "கொழும்பு",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "வியாழன்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பாலித பெர்னாண்டோ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை தடகள",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்த வருடம்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "MAS",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாரிஸ் ஒலிம்பிக்",
            "label": "EVENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "2024",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "20",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்தியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்த ஆண்டு ஜூன்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "முதலில்",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "MAS",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "தினேஷ் டி சில்வா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாடிலைன்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "MAS",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "SLA",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "மேதானி ஜெயமான்னே",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஒன்று",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "முதலில்",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஜெயமான்னே",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "MAS",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "நூற்றாண்டு ஆண்டு",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஒன்று",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஓட்டப்பந்தய வீரர் யுபுன் அபேகோன்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "முதலில்",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "தெற்காசிய",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஒரு துணை 10 வினாடிகள்",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "100 மீட்டர்",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆசியா",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "காமன்வெல்த் விளையாட்டு",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை தடகள",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "அடுத்த இரண்டு ஆண்டுகள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "MAS",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை தடகள",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாலித பெர்னாண்டோ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "தினேஷ் டி சில்வா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Bodyline Trading (Pvt) Ltd",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஒன்பது கேட்வே கிரிஃபின்ஸ்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "கோல்டன் ஈகிள் விருதுகள்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [],
        []
      ]
    }
  }
}