{
  "newspaper_id": "economy-next-com",
  "url": "https://economynext.com/sri-lanka-navy-seizes-kerala-cannabis-worth-65-mn-rupees-in-jaffna-98826/",
  "time_ut": 1661059380,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Sri Lanka Navy seizes Kerala cannabis worth 65 mn rupees in Jaffna",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Sri Lanka Navy seizes Kerala cannabis worth 65 mn rupees in Jaffna",
      "author": "Chanka Jayasinghe",
      "body_lines": [
        "ECONOMYNEXT – Sri Lanka Navy (SLN) has seized Kerala cannabis worth a total of 65 million rupees in Jaffna in 20 days, the navy said.",
        "The latest haul was cannabis with a street value of 27 million rupees that was seized on Saturday August 19 in the northern peninsula. Over 93kg of it was found on the beach at Saukkadi, Madagal in Jaffna, stuffed in 40 packs kept in a shrimp weir.",
        "The navy said it suspects that smugglers might have left behind the consignment in the shrimp weir, being unable to bring it ashore, due to naval operations in the area.",
        "On August 03, 49kg and 380g (wet weight) of Kerala cannabis was seized during a search operation conducted near the Mannar sandbanks. The cannabis was in 20 packs that were found buried in the area by smugglers. The gross street value of the seized cannabis is believed to be about 14 million rupees, the navy said.",
        "Another operation conducted by the Navy at Mannar Sand Banks on the evening of 02nd August 2022, led to the seizure of about 47kg and 240g (wet weight) of Kerala cannabis. The gross street value of seized Kerala cannabis is believed to be around 14 million rupees.",
        "On August 04, SLN had fished out 34kg and 38g (wet weight) of Kerala cannabis floating in the seas between Kayts and Punguduthive Islands in Jaffna, stuffed in eight packs. The gross street value of seized cannabis is believed to be about 10 million rupees.",
        "Navy Spokesman Captain Indika Silva told EconomyNext that most of the cannabis being arrested is suspected to be smuggled into the country for the consumption of locals while Sri Lanka is sometimes used as an exchange point for other narcotics circulating in the region.",
        "“We have arrested about one ton of heroin this year. However, the smuggling of heroin seems to have reduced these days,” said Silva.",
        "“However, cannabis seems to be coming in because there are no reports of arrests while it’s smuggled out of the country.”",
        "Police Spokesman SSP Nihal Thalduwa was unavailable for comment. (Colombo/Aug20/2022)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Sri Lanka Navy",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "Kerala",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "65",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "Jaffna",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Navy",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "SLN",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kerala",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "65 million",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "Jaffna",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "20 days",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "navy",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "27 million",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Saturday August 19",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "93kg",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "Saukkadi",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Jaffna",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "40",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "August 03",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "49kg",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "380",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kerala",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Mannar",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "20",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "about 14 million",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "navy",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Navy",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Mannar Sand Banks",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "August 2022",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "about 47kg",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kerala",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kerala",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "14 million",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "August 04",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "SLN",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "34kg",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kerala",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kayts",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Punguduthive Islands",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "Jaffna",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "eight",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "about 10 million",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Navy",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Indika Silva",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "this year",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "these days",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Silva",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "SSP Nihal",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "රුපියල් මිලියන 65ක් වටිනා කේරළ ගංජා තොගයක් ශ්‍රී ලංකා නාවික හමුදාව විසින් යාපනයේදී අත්අඩංගුවට ගෙන තිබේ",
      "author": "චංක ජයසිංහ",
      "body_lines": [
        "ECONOMYNEXT – ශ්‍රී ලංකා නාවික හමුදාව දින 20ක් තුළ යාපනයේදී රුපියල් මිලියන 65ක් වටිනා කේරළ ගංජා අත්අඩංගුවට ගත් බව නාවික හමුදාව පවසයි.",
        "නවතම තොගය වූයේ අගෝස්තු 19 වැනි සෙනසුරාදා උතුරු අර්ධද්වීපයේ දී අත්අඩංගුවට ගත් රුපියල් මිලියන 27 ක වීදි වටිනාකමකින් යුත් ගංජා ය. ඉන් කිලෝග්‍රෑම් 93කට අධික ප්‍රමාණයක් යාපනයේ මාඩගල් ප්‍රදේශයේ සෞක්කඩි වෙරළ තීරයේ තිබී ඉස්සන් වත්තක තබා තිබූ ඇසුරුම් 40ක පුරවා තිබී හමුවී ඇත.",
        "නාවික හමුදාව ප්‍රදේශයේ සිදුකරනු ලබන මෙහෙයුම් හේතුවෙන් මෙම තොගය ගොඩබිමට ගෙන ඒමට නොහැකිව ජාවාරම්කරුවන් විසින් මෙම ඉස්සන් වැල්ලේ දමා යන්නට ඇති බවට සැකකරන බව නාවික හමුදාව ප්‍රකාශ කළේය.",
        "අගෝස්තු 03 වැනි දින මන්නාරම වැලි ඉවුර ආසන්නයේ සිදුකළ සෝදිසි මෙහෙයුමකදී කේරළ ගංජා කිලෝග්‍රෑම් 49යි ග්‍රෑම් 380ක් (තෙත් බර) අත්අඩංගුවට ගෙන ඇත. ජාවාරම්කරුවන් විසින් එම ප්‍රදේශයේ වළදමා තිබියදී සොයාගත් ගංජා ඇසුරුම් 20ක තිබී ඇත. අත්අඩංගුවට ගත් ගංජා තොගයේ දළ වීථි වටිනාකම රුපියල් මිලියන 14ක් පමණ වන බව නාවික හමුදාව පවසයි.",
        "නාවික හමුදාව විසින් 2022 අගෝස්තු මස 02 වන දින සවස මන්නාරම වැලි ඉවුරේදී සිදුකළ තවත් මෙහෙයුමකින් කේරළ ගංජා කිලෝග්‍රෑම් 47 යි ග්‍රෑම් 240 ක් පමණ (තෙත් බර) අත්අඩංගුවට ගැනීමට හැකි විය. අත්අඩංගුවට ගත් කේරළ ගංජාවල දළ වීදි වටිනාකම රුපියල් මිලියන 14ක් පමණ වනු ඇතැයි විශ්වාස කෙරේ.",
        "අගෝස්තු 04 වැනි දින යාපනයේ කයිට්ස් සහ පුංගුඩුතිව් දූපත් අතර මුහුදේ පාවෙමින් තිබූ කේරළ ගංජා කිලෝ ග්‍රෑම් 34යි ග්‍රෑම් 38 (තෙත් බර) ප්‍රමාණයක් ඇසුරුම් අටක පුරවා ශ්‍රී ලංකා නාවික හමුදාව විසින් මසුන් ඇල්ලීමට සමත් විය. අත්අඩංගුවට ගත් ගංජා තොගයේ දළ වටිනාකම රුපියල් මිලියන 10ක් පමණ වෙතැයි සැලකේ.",
        "නාවික හමුදා මාධ්‍ය ප්‍රකාශක කපිතාන් ඉන්දික සිල්වා මහතා EconomyNext වෙත ප්‍රකාශ කළේ අත්අඩංගුවට ගන්නා ගංජා තොගයෙන් වැඩි ප්‍රමාණයක් ප්‍රදේශවාසීන්ගේ පරිභෝජනය සඳහා මෙරටට රැගෙන එන බවට සැක කෙරෙන අතර ශ්‍රී ලංකාව ඇතැම් විට කලාපයේ සංසරණය වන අනෙකුත් මත්ද්‍රව්‍ය හුවමාරු මධ්‍යස්ථානයක් ලෙස භාවිත කරන බවයි.",
        "“අපි මේ වසරේ හෙරොයින් ටොන් එකක් පමණ අත්අඩංගුවට ගෙන තිබෙනවා. හැබැයි මේ දවස්වල හෙරොයින් ජාවාරම අඩුවෙලා වගේ.” සිල්වා කීවේය.",
        "\"කෙසේ වෙතත්, ගංජා රටින් පිටතට ගෙන යන අතරතුර අත්අඩංගුවට ගැනීම් පිළිබඳ වාර්තා නොමැති නිසා එය පැමිණෙන බව පෙනේ.\"",
        "පොලිස් මාධ්‍ය ප්‍රකාශක ජ්‍යෙෂ්ඨ පොලිස් අධිකාරී නිහාල් තල්දූව මහතා ප්‍රකාශයක් ලබා ගැනීමට නොහැකි විය. (කොළඹ/අගෝස්තු 20/2022)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකා නාවික හමුදාව",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "කේරල",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "65",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "යාපනය",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "නාවික",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "SLN",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "කේරල",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මිලියන 65 කි",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "යාපනය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "දින 20 යි",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "නාවික",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "මිලියන 27 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "අගෝස්තු 19 සෙනසුරාදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "93kg",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "සෞක්කාඩි",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "යාපනය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "40",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "අගෝස්තු 03",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "49kg",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "380",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "කේරල",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මන්නාරම",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "20",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "මිලියන 14 ක් පමණ වේ",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "නාවික",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "නාවික",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "මන්නාරම වැලි ඉවුරු",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "2022 අගෝස්තු",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "47kg පමණ",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "කේරල",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "කේරල",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මිලියන 14 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "අගෝස්තු 04",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "SLN",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "34kg",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "කේරල",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "කයිට්ස්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "පුංගුඩුතිව් දූපත්",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "යාපනය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "අට",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "මිලියන 10 ක් පමණ වේ",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "නාවික",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දික සිල්වා",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "මේ වසරේ",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මෙම දිනවල",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "සිල්වා",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "ජ්‍යෙෂ්ඨ පොලිස් අධිකාරී නිහාල්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "யாழ்ப்பாணத்தில் 65 மில்லியன் ரூபா பெறுமதியான கேரள கஞ்சாவை இலங்கை கடற்படையினர் கைப்பற்றியுள்ளனர்",
      "author": "சங்க ஜெயசிங்க",
      "body_lines": [
        "பொருளாதாரம் – யாழ்ப்பாணத்தில் 20 நாட்களில் மொத்தம் 65 மில்லியன் ரூபா பெறுமதியான கேரள கஞ்சாவை இலங்கை கடற்படை (SLN) கைப்பற்றியுள்ளதாக கடற்படை தெரிவித்துள்ளது.",
        "வடக்கு குடாநாட்டில் கடந்த சனிக்கிழமை ஆகஸ்ட் 19 ஆம் திகதி கைப்பற்றப்பட்ட 27 மில்லியன் ரூபா வீதி பெறுமதியான கஞ்சாவாகும். யாழ்ப்பாணம் சௌக்கடி, மடகல் கடற்கரையில் 93 கிலோவுக்கும் அதிகமான எடையுள்ள இறால் வேரில் வைக்கப்பட்டிருந்த 40 பொதிகளில் அடைக்கப்பட்டிருந்தன.",
        "அப்பகுதியில் கடற்படையின் நடவடிக்கைகள் காரணமாக கடத்தல்காரர்கள் இறால்களை கரைக்கு கொண்டு வர முடியாமல் இறால் தோப்பில் விட்டுச் சென்றிருக்கலாம் என சந்தேகிக்கப்படுவதாக கடற்படையினர் தெரிவித்தனர்.",
        "ஓகஸ்ட் 03ஆம் திகதி மன்னார் மணற் கரைக்கு அருகில் மேற்கொள்ளப்பட்ட சோதனை நடவடிக்கையின் போது 49 கிலோ 380 கிராம் (ஈரமான எடை) கேரள கஞ்சா கைப்பற்றப்பட்டது. கடத்தல்காரர்களால் அப்பகுதியில் புதைத்து வைக்கப்பட்டிருந்த 20 பொதிகளில் கஞ்சா இருந்தது. கைப்பற்றப்பட்ட கஞ்சாவின் மொத்த பெறுமதி சுமார் 14 மில்லியன் ரூபா என கடற்படை தெரிவித்துள்ளது.",
        "2022 ஆம் ஆண்டு ஆகஸ்ட் மாதம் 02 ஆம் திகதி மாலை மன்னார் மணல் கரையில் கடற்படையினரால் மேற்கொள்ளப்பட்ட மற்றுமொரு நடவடிக்கையில் சுமார் 47 கிலோ 240 கிராம் (ஈரமான எடை) கேரள கஞ்சா கைப்பற்றப்பட்டது. கைப்பற்றப்பட்ட கேரள கஞ்சாவின் மொத்த தெரு மதிப்பு சுமார் 14 மில்லியன் ரூபா என நம்பப்படுகிறது.",
        "யாழ்ப்பாணம் ஊர்காவற்துறை மற்றும் புங்குடுதீவு தீவுகளுக்கு இடைப்பட்ட கடற்பரப்பில் மிதந்து கொண்டிருந்த 34கிலோ 38கிலோ (ஈரமான எடை) கேரள கஞ்சாவை ஆகஸ்ட் 04 ஆம் திகதி SLN மீன்பிடித்துள்ளது. கைப்பற்றப்பட்ட கஞ்சாவின் மொத்த மதிப்பு சுமார் 10 மில்லியன் ரூபா என நம்பப்படுகிறது.",
        "கைதுசெய்யப்படும் கஞ்சாவில் பெரும்பாலானவர்கள் உள்ளூர் மக்களின் நுகர்வுக்காக நாட்டிற்குள் கடத்தப்படுவதாக சந்தேகிக்கப்படுவதாக கடற்படைப் பேச்சாளர் கப்டன் இந்திக சில்வா EconomyNext இடம் தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "“இந்த ஆண்டு சுமார் ஒரு டன் ஹெராயின் கைது செய்துள்ளோம். எவ்வாறாயினும், இந்த நாட்களில் ஹெரோயின் கடத்தல் குறைந்துள்ளதாகத் தெரிகிறது” என்று சில்வா கூறினார்.",
        "\"இருப்பினும், கஞ்சா நாட்டிற்கு வெளியே கடத்தப்படும்போது கைது செய்யப்பட்டதாக எந்த அறிக்கையும் இல்லாததால் கஞ்சா உள்ளே வருவதாகத் தெரிகிறது.\"",
        "பொலிஸ் பேச்சாளர் எஸ்.எஸ்.பி நிஹால் தல்துவா கருத்துக்கு கிடைக்கவில்லை. (கொழும்பு/ஆகஸ்ட்20/2022)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "இலங்கை கடற்படை",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "கேரளா",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "65",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "யாழ்",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "கடற்படை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "எஸ்.எல்.என்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "கேரளா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "65 மில்லியன்",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "யாழ்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "20 நாட்கள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "கடற்படை",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "27 மில்லியன்",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆகஸ்ட் 19 சனிக்கிழமை",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "93 கிலோ",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "சவுக்கடி",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "யாழ்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "40",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஆகஸ்ட் 03",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "49 கிலோ",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "380",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "கேரளா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "மன்னார்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "20",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "சுமார் 14 மில்லியன்",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "கடற்படை",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "கடற்படை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "மன்னார் மணல் கரைகள்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆகஸ்ட் 2022",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சுமார் 47 கிலோ",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "கேரளா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "கேரளா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "14 மில்லியன்",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஆகஸ்ட் 04",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "எஸ்.எல்.என்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "34 கிலோ",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "கேரளா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஊர்காவற்துறை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "புங்குடுதீவு தீவுகள்",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "யாழ்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "எட்டு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "சுமார் 10 மில்லியன்",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "கடற்படை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்திக்க சில்வா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இந்த வருடம்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்த நாட்களில்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சில்வா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "எஸ்எஸ்பி நிஹால்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}