{
  "newspaper_id": "lankadeepa-lk",
  "url": "https://www.lankadeepa.lk/news/දෙවෙනි-පර්යන්තයේ-ඉදිකිරීමට-ඉන්ධන-ඇමතිගෙන්/101-615686",
  "time_ut": 1656654915,
  "original_lang": "si",
  "original_title": "දෙවෙනි පර්යන්තයේ ඉදිකිරීමට ඉන්ධන ඇමතිගෙන්",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "From the minister of fuel to build the second terminal",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "Oil bunkerers in this country have agreed to supply fuel to the Japanese company that is working on the construction of the second terminal in Katunayake.",
        "The warehouses have agreed to supply fuel following a special request made by Ports, Shipping and Aviation Minister Nimal Siripala de Silva.",
        "Japan's Taisei Corporation, which is engaged in the construction of the second terminal of Katunayake Airport, is facing the crisis of obtaining fuel, so the construction work has been slow for some time.",
        "Sumio Takahashi, Senior Administrative Manager, Taisei, told the Minister that he needed 13,000 liters of fuel per day.",
        "Commenting on this, the Minister of Ports, Shipping and Aviation Services Mr. Nimal Siripala de Silva stated that he had recently discussed with the Japanese Ambassador to Sri Lanka about the serious delay in the construction of the terminal due to the Corona epidemic and the current fuel crisis.",
        "The minister also said that he would like to express his thanks and gratitude to the fuel stockists in Sri Lanka who promised to supply fuel.",
        "Accordingly, the minister requested the representatives of the Japanese company to take necessary steps to complete the construction of the second terminal as soon as possible.",
        "Secretary to the Ministry KD H Ruwan Chandra, Chairman, Airport and Aviation Retired Major General GA Chandrasiri, representatives of Taisei Corporation of Japan and representatives of local IOC warehousing companies including IOC."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "second",
          "label": "ORDINAL"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Japanese",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "second",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Katunayake",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Ports, Shipping and Aviation",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Nimal Siripala de Silva",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Japan",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Taisei Corporation",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "second",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Katunayake Airport",
            "label": "FAC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sumio Takahashi",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Taisei",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "13,000",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Ports",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Nimal Siripala de Silva",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Japanese",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Corona",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Japanese",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "second",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the Ministry KD H Ruwan Chandra",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Aviation Retired Major",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "GA Chandrasiri",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Taisei Corporation",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Japan",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "IOC",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "IOC",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "දෙවෙනි පර්යන්තයේ ඉදිකිරීමට ඉන්ධන ඇමතිගෙන්",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "කටුනායක දෙවන පර්යන්තයේ ඉදිකිරීම්  කටයුතු කරන  ජපන් සමාගමට ඉන්ධන සැපයිමට මෙරට  ඉන්ධන   තොග ගබඩාකරුවන් (Oil bunkering) එකඟතාව  පළ කර ඇත.",
        "ගබඩාකරුවන්  ඉන්ධන සැපයීමට මෙසේ   එකඟවී ඇත්තේ  වරාය නාවික සහ ගුවන් සේවා අමාත්‍ය නිමල් සිරිපාල ද සිල්වා මහතා ඒ  සම්බන්ධයෙන් කළ විශේෂ ඉල්ලීමක් අනුවය.",
        "කටුනායක ගුවන් තොටුපොළ දෙවන පර්යන්තය ඉදි කිරීමේ නිරත ජපානයේ ටායිසෙයි කෝපරේෂන්  සමාගම  ඉන්ධන  ලබා ගැනීමේ අර්බුදයට මුහුණදී සිටින හෙයින් එම ඉදිකිරීම් කටයුතු කාලයක් තිස්සේ  මන්දගාමීව  පැවතිණ.",
        "තමන්ට දෛනිකව ඉන්ධන  ලීටර් 13,000 අවශ්‍ය බව ටායිසෙයි සමාගමේ ජ්‍යෙෂ්ඨ   පරිපාලන කළමනාකරු සුමියෝ තකහාෂි ( Sumio Takahashi) මහතා  ඇමැතිවරයාට පෙන්වා දුන්නේය.",
        "මේ සම්බන්ධයෙන් අදහස් දැක්වූ  වරාය, නාවික හා ගුවන් සේවා අමාත්‍ය නිමල් සිරිපාල ද සිල්වා මහතා ප්‍රකාශ කළේ  කොරෝනා වසංගතය හා වර්තමාන ඉන්ධන අර්බුදය හේතුවෙන් එම පර්යන්තයේ  ඉදිකිරීම් කටයුතු බරපතළ ලෙස ප්‍රමාදවීම පිළිබඳව   ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ ජපාන තානාපතිවරයා  සමග පසුගියදා සාකච්ඡා කළ බවයි.",
        "ඉන්ධන සැපයීමට පොරොන්දුවූ මෙරට ඉන්ධන තොග ගබඩාකරුවන්ට ස්තූතිය හා  ප්‍රණාමය පුද කරන බවද අමාත්‍යවරයා පැවසීය.",
        "ඒ අනුව  දෙවැනි පර්යන්තයේ   ඉදිකිරීම් කඩිනමින්  නිම කිරීමට අවශ්‍ය පියවර ගන්නා ලෙස අමාත්‍යවරයා ජපාන සමාගමේ නියෝජිතයන්ගෙන් ඉල්ලීමක් කළේය.",
        "මෙම සාකච්ඡාවට  අමාත්‍යංශයේ ලේකම් කේ.ඩී. එච් රුවන්චන්ද්‍ර ,ගුවන් තොටුපොළ හා ගුවන් සේවා සමාගමේ සභාපති විශ්‍රාමික මේජර් ජනරාල් ජී.ඒ.චන්ද්‍රසිරි, ජපානයේ ටායිසෙයි කෝපරේෂන් සමාගමේ  නියෝජිතයන් ද අයි.ඕ.සී.සමාගම ඇතුළු මෙරට ඉන්ධන තොග ගබඩා සමාගම් නියෝජිතයන්  ඇතුළු පිරිසක්ද   සහභාගිවූහ."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "දෙවැනි",
          "label": "ORDINAL"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ජපන්",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "දෙවැනි",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "කටුනායක",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "වරාය, නාවික සහ ගුවන් සේවා",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "නිමල් සිරිපාල ද සිල්වා",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ජපානය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Taisei සංස්ථාව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "දෙවැනි",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "කටුනායක ගුවන් තොටුපළ",
            "label": "FAC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sumio Takahashi",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Taisei",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "13,000 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "වරායන්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "නිමල් සිරිපාල ද සිල්වා",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජපන්",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "කොරෝනා",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ජපන්",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "දෙවැනි",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "අමාත්‍යාංශය KD H රුවන්චන්ද්‍ර",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගුවන් සේවා විශ්‍රාමික මේජර්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජීඒ චන්ද්‍රසිරි",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Taisei සංස්ථාව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජපානය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "අයි.ඕ.සී",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "අයි.ඕ.සී",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "இரண்டாவது முனையத்தை அமைக்க எரிபொருள் துறை அமைச்சரிடம் இருந்து",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "கட்டுநாயக்கவில் இரண்டாவது முனையத்தை நிர்மாணிக்கும் பணியில் ஈடுபட்டுள்ள ஜப்பானிய நிறுவனத்திற்கு எரிபொருளை வழங்குவதற்கு இந்நாட்டில் உள்ள எண்ணெய் பதுங்குகுழிகள் இணக்கம் தெரிவித்துள்ளன.",
        "துறைமுகங்கள், கப்பல் போக்குவரத்து மற்றும் விமானப் போக்குவரத்து அமைச்சர் நிமல் சிறிபால டி சில்வாவினால் விடுக்கப்பட்ட விசேட கோரிக்கைக்கு அமைய எரிபொருள் விநியோகம் செய்வதற்கு களஞ்சியசாலைகள் இணக்கம் தெரிவித்துள்ளன.",
        "ஜப்பானின் Taisei கூட்டுத்தாபனம் எரிபொருள் நெருக்கடியை எதிர்கொண்டுள்ளதால் கட்டுநாயக்க சர்வதேச விமான நிலையத்தின் இரண்டாவது முனையத்தின் நிர்மாணப் பணிகள் சில காலமாக மந்தகதியில் இடம்பெற்று வருகின்றன.",
        "நாளொன்றுக்கு 13,000 லீற்றர் எரிபொருள் தேவைப்படுவதாக தைசேயின் சிரேஷ்ட நிர்வாக முகாமையாளர் சுமியோ தகாஹாஷி அமைச்சரிடம் தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "கொரோனா தொற்று மற்றும் தற்போதைய எரிபொருள் நெருக்கடி காரணமாக முனையத்தின் நிர்மாணப் பணிகளில் ஏற்பட்டுள்ள பாரிய தாமதம் தொடர்பில் அண்மையில் இலங்கைக்கான ஜப்பானிய தூதுவருடன் கலந்துரையாடியதாக துறைமுகங்கள், கப்பல் போக்குவரத்து மற்றும் விமான சேவைகள் அமைச்சர் நிமல் சிறிபால டி சில்வா தெரிவித்துள்ளார்.",
        "எரிபொருளை வழங்குவதாக உறுதியளித்த இலங்கை எரிபொருள் கையிருப்பு நிறுவனங்களுக்கும் அவர் நன்றி தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "இதன்படி, இரண்டாவது முனையத்தின் நிர்மாணப் பணிகளை விரைவாக முடிக்க தேவையான நடவடிக்கைகளை மேற்கொள்ளுமாறு ஜப்பானிய நிறுவனத்தின் பிரதிநிதிகளிடம் அமைச்சர் கோரிக்கை விடுத்தார்.",
        "இந்த கலந்துரையாடலில் அமைச்சின் செயலாளர் கே.டி. விமான நிலையம் மற்றும் விமான சேவைகள் நிறுவனத்தின் தலைவர் எச்.ருவன்சந்திர, ஓய்வுபெற்ற மேஜர் ஜெனரல் ஜி.ஏ.சந்திரசிறி, ஜப்பானின் Taisei கூட்டுத்தாபனம் மற்றும் IOC நிறுவனத்தின் பிரதிநிதிகள் மற்றும் இலங்கை எரிபொருள் களஞ்சிய நிறுவனங்களின் பிரதிநிதிகள் கலந்துகொண்டனர்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "இரண்டாவது",
          "label": "ORDINAL"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ஜப்பானியர்",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "இரண்டாவது",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "கட்டுநாயக்கா",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "துறைமுகங்கள், கப்பல் போக்குவரத்து மற்றும் விமான போக்குவரத்து",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "நிமல் சிறிபால டி சில்வா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஜப்பான்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Taisei கார்ப்பரேஷன்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இரண்டாவது",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "கட்டுநாயக்க விமான நிலையம்",
            "label": "FAC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sumio Takahashi",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "தைசி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "13,000",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "துறைமுகங்கள்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "நிமல் சிறிபால டி சில்வா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜப்பானியர்",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "கொரோனா",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஜப்பானியர்",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "இரண்டாவது",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "அமைச்சு KD H ருவன் சந்திரா",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஏவியேஷன் ஓய்வு பெற்ற மேஜர்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜிஏ சந்திரசிறி",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Taisei கார்ப்பரேஷன்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜப்பான்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஐஓசி",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஐஓசி",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}