{
  "newspaper_id": "ada-lk",
  "url": "https://www.ada.lk/breaking_news/22වැනි-ව්‍යාවස්ථා-සංශෝධනය-නොපමාව-පාර්ලිමේන්තුවට/11-394925",
  "time_ut": 1656412452,
  "original_lang": "si",
  "original_title": "22වැනි ව්‍යාවස්ථා සංශෝධනය නොපමාව පාර්ලිමේන්තුවට",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "22nd Amendment to the Constitution to Parliament immediately",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "The 22nd Amendment to the Constitution, which has been approved by the Cabinet of Ministers, will be gazetted and presented to Parliament in the next few days, Minister of Justice, Prisons and Constitutional Reform said at a media briefing held at the Government Information Department today (28). Seven days after the bill was gazetted, it will be placed on the agenda of Parliament and further action will be taken, the Minister said.",
        "The Minister said that the people have a problem with the number of amendments to the Constitution. Explaining this, the Minister said, “After the Samagi Janabalawegaya presented the 21st Amendment Bill to Parliament, I introduced the 22nd Amendment to the Constitution as a private member's motion. When I was appointed as a Minister, I presented the same constitutional amendment to the Cabinet as a draft constitutional amendment to the government.",
        "The Minister said that there is dancing. At the same time, the 22nd Amendment to the Constitution, which I personally tabled, was withdrawn from Parliament. As a government proposal it will publish the 22nd Amendment to the Constitution in the Gazette and present it to Parliament.",
        "Considering the original Amendment Bill to be taken up in the process of this in Parliament, it will be renamed as No. 21. Accordingly, when the 22nd Amendment is first debated in Parliament, it will be named as the 21st Amendment to the Constitution.",
        "The 21st Amendment to the Constitution tabled by the Opposition is unworkable. The Supreme Court has ruled that a referendum is required for every clause to become law. ”"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "22nd Amendment",
          "label": "LAW"
        },
        {
          "text": "Constitution",
          "label": "LAW"
        },
        {
          "text": "Parliament",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "The 22nd Amendment",
            "label": "LAW"
          },
          {
            "text": "Constitution",
            "label": "LAW"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Cabinet of Ministers",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the next few days",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Government Information Department",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "28",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Seven days",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Constitution",
            "label": "LAW"
          },
          {
            "text": "After the Samagi Janabalawegaya",
            "label": "WORK_OF_ART"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the 22nd Amendment",
            "label": "LAW"
          },
          {
            "text": "Constitution",
            "label": "LAW"
          },
          {
            "text": "Cabinet",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the 22nd Amendment",
            "label": "LAW"
          },
          {
            "text": "Constitution",
            "label": "LAW"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the 22nd Amendment",
            "label": "LAW"
          },
          {
            "text": "Constitution",
            "label": "LAW"
          },
          {
            "text": "Gazette",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Amendment Bill",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "21",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "the 22nd Amendment",
            "label": "LAW"
          },
          {
            "text": "first",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Constitution",
            "label": "LAW"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "The 21st Amendment",
            "label": "EVENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "Constitution",
            "label": "LAW"
          },
          {
            "text": "Opposition",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "The Supreme Court",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "22වැනි ව්‍යාවස්ථා සංශෝධනය නොපමාව පාර්ලිමේන්තුවට",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "අමාත්‍ය මණ්ඩල අනුමැතිය ලද  22වන අණ්ඩුක්‍රම ව්‍යවස්ථා සංශෝධනය ගැසට් පත්‍රයක් මගින්  ප්‍රසිද්ධියට පත් කර ඉදිරි දින කිහිපය තුළ ව්‍යාවස්ථානුකුලව පාර්ලිමේන්තුවට  ඉදිරිපත් කරන බව අද (28) රජයේ ප්‍රවෘත්ති දෙපාර්තමේන්තුවේ දී පැවති මාධ්‍ය සාකච්ඡාවකට එක් වෙමින් අධිකරණ, බන්ධනාගාර හා ආණ්ඩුක්‍රම ව්‍යවස්ථා ප්‍රතිස්සංකරණ අමාත්‍යආචාර්ය විජයදාස රජපක්ෂ මහතා පැවසීය.  පනත් කෙටුම් පත ගැසට් පත්‍රයක්මගින් ප්‍රසිද්ධියට පත් කර දින හතක් ගිය පසු පාර්ලිමේන්තුවේ න්‍යාය පත්‍රයට ඇතුළත් කොට ඉදිරි ක්‍රියාමාර්ග  ගන්නා බවද අමාත්‍යවරයා  පැවැසීය",
        "ව්‍යවස්ථා සංශෝධනයේ අංකය පිළිබඳව ජනතාවට යම් ගැටලුවක් ඇති බව දක්නට ඇතැයි අමාත්‍යවරයා පැවසීය. එය නිරවුල් කරමින් අමාත්‍යවරයා පැවසුවේ, “සමගි ජනබලවේගය පාර්ලිමේන්තුවට 21 වන ව්‍යාවස්ථා සංශෝධන කොටුම්පත ඉදිරිපත් කිරීමෙන් අනතුරුව  මම පෞද්ගලික  මන්ත්‍රී යෝජනාවක් ලෙස  22 වන ආණ්ඩුක්‍රම ව්‍යවස්ථා සංශෝධනය ඉදිරිපත් කළ කළා. මම අමාත්‍යවරයෙක් ලෙස පත් වු පසු  එම ව්‍යවස්ථා සංශෝධනයම  ආණ්ඩුවේ ව්‍යාවස්ථා සංශෝධන කෙටුම්පතක් ලෙස අමාත්‍ය මණ්ඩලයට ඉදිරිපත් කළා.",
        "නට ඇතැයි අමාත්‍යවරයා පැවසීය. මෙඒ සමඟම මම පෞද්ගලිකව ඉදිරිපත් කළ  22 වන ආණ්ඩුක්‍රව ව්‍යවස්ථා සංශෝධනය පාර්ලිමේන්තුවෙන් ඉල්ලා අස්කර ගත්තා. එය රජයේ යෝජනාවක් ලෙස   22වන ආණ්ඩුක්‍රම  ව්‍යවස්ථා සංශෝධනය ගැසට් පත්‍රයේ  පළ කර පාර්ලිමේන්තුවට ඉදිරිපත් කරනවා.",
        "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව තුළ  මේ පිළිබඳ ක්‍රියාදාමයේදී මුලින් ගනු ලබන සංශෝධන කොටුම්පත  කුමක්ද යන්න සලකා බලා  එය නැවත වතාවක් අංක 21 ලෙස නම් කරනවා. ඒ අනුව 22 වන සංශෝධනය  මුලින් පාර්ලිමේන්තුවේ සාකච්ඡාවට ගන්නා අවස්ථාව වන විට  එය 21 වන ආණ්ඩුක්‍රම ව්‍යාවස්ථා සංශෝධනය  ලෙස නම් කරනවා.",
        "විපක්ෂය ඉදිරිපත් කළ 21 වන ආණ්ඩුක්‍රම ව්‍යවස්ථා සංශෝධනය  එළිදැක්විමට නොහැකි  එකක්. එහි සැම වගන්තියක්ම  නීතියක් බවට පත් වන්නට  ජනමත විචාරණයක් අවශ්‍යය යන්න තීරණය  ශ්‍රේෂ්ඨාධිකරණය දීලා තියෙනවා.”"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "22 වැනි සංශෝධනය",
          "label": "LAW"
        },
        {
          "text": "ආණ්ඩුක්රම ව්යවස්ථාව",
          "label": "LAW"
        },
        {
          "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "22 වැනි සංශෝධනය",
            "label": "LAW"
          },
          {
            "text": "ආණ්ඩුක්රම ව්යවස්ථාව",
            "label": "LAW"
          },
          {
            "text": "අමාත්ය මණ්ඩලය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉදිරි දින කිහිපය",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "රජයේ ප්‍රවෘත්ති දෙපාර්තමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "28",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "දින හතක්",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ආණ්ඩුක්රම ව්යවස්ථාව",
            "label": "LAW"
          },
          {
            "text": "සමගි ජනබලවේගයෙන් පසුව",
            "label": "WORK_OF_ART"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "22 වැනි සංශෝධනය",
            "label": "LAW"
          },
          {
            "text": "ආණ්ඩුක්රම ව්යවස්ථාව",
            "label": "LAW"
          },
          {
            "text": "මණ්ඩල",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "22 වැනි සංශෝධනය",
            "label": "LAW"
          },
          {
            "text": "ආණ්ඩුක්රම ව්යවස්ථාව",
            "label": "LAW"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "22 වැනි සංශෝධනය",
            "label": "LAW"
          },
          {
            "text": "ආණ්ඩුක්රම ව්යවස්ථාව",
            "label": "LAW"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගැසට්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "සංශෝධන පනත් කෙටුම්පත",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "21",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "22 වැනි සංශෝධනය",
            "label": "LAW"
          },
          {
            "text": "පළමුවන",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ආණ්ඩුක්රම ව්යවස්ථාව",
            "label": "LAW"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "21 වැනි සංශෝධනය",
            "label": "EVENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "ආණ්ඩුක්රම ව්යවස්ථාව",
            "label": "LAW"
          },
          {
            "text": "විපක්ෂ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රේෂ්ඨාධිකරණය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "அரசியலமைப்பின் 22வது திருத்தம் உடனடியாக பாராளுமன்றத்திற்கு",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "அமைச்சரவையினால் அங்கீகரிக்கப்பட்ட அரசியலமைப்பின் 22வது திருத்தம் எதிர்வரும் சில தினங்களில் வர்த்தமானியாக வெளியிடப்பட்டு பாராளுமன்றத்தில் சமர்ப்பிக்கப்படும் என நீதி, சிறைச்சாலைகள் மற்றும் அரசியலமைப்பு மறுசீரமைப்பு அமைச்சர் இன்று அரசாங்க தகவல் திணைக்களத்தில் நடைபெற்ற ஊடகவியலாளர் சந்திப்பில் தெரிவித்தார். (28) இந்த சட்டமூலம் வர்த்தமானியாக வெளியிடப்பட்டு ஏழு நாட்களுக்குப் பின்னர், அது நாடாளுமன்றத்தின் நிகழ்ச்சி நிரலில் வைக்கப்பட்டு, அடுத்தகட்ட நடவடிக்கை எடுக்கப்படும் என்று அமைச்சர் கூறினார்.",
        "அரசியலமைப்புச் சட்டத்தில் திருத்தங்கள் மேற்கொள்ளப்படுவதில் மக்களுக்குப் பிரச்சினை இருப்பதாக அமைச்சர் கூறினார். இதற்கு விளக்கமளித்த அமைச்சர், “சமகி ஜனபலவேகய 21ஆவது திருத்தச் சட்டமூலத்தை நாடாளுமன்றத்தில் சமர்ப்பித்ததன் பின்னர், அரசியலமைப்பின் 22ஆவது திருத்தச் சட்டத்தை தனிப்பட்ட உறுப்பினர் பிரேரணையாக நான் முன்வைத்தேன். நான் அமைச்சராக பதவியேற்றதும் அதே அரசியலமைப்பு திருத்தத்தை அரசமைப்பு சட்ட திருத்த வரைவாக அமைச்சரவையில் முன்வைத்தேன்.",
        "நடனம் உள்ளது என்றார் அமைச்சர். அதேநேரம், நான் தனிப்பட்ட முறையில் முன்வைத்த அரசியலமைப்பின் 22வது திருத்தம் பாராளுமன்றத்தில் இருந்து வாபஸ் பெறப்பட்டது. அரச பிரேரணையாக அரசியலமைப்பின் 22வது திருத்தத்தை வர்த்தமானியில் வெளியிட்டு பாராளுமன்றத்தில் சமர்ப்பிக்கவுள்ளது.",
        "இச்செயற்பாட்டின் போது பாராளுமன்றத்தில் எடுக்கப்படும் அசல் திருத்தச் சட்டமூலத்தை கருத்தில் கொண்டு, அது எண் 21 என பெயர் மாற்றப்படும். இதன்படி, 22வது திருத்தம் தொடர்பில் பாராளுமன்றத்தில் முதலில் விவாதம் நடத்தப்படும் போது, ​​அது அரசியலமைப்பின் 21வது திருத்தம் என பெயரிடப்படும்.",
        "எதிர்க்கட்சிகளால் முன்வைக்கப்பட்ட அரசியலமைப்பின் 21வது திருத்தம் நடைமுறைப்படுத்த முடியாதது. ஒவ்வொரு ஷரத்தும் சட்டமாக மாறுவதற்கு பொதுவாக்கெடுப்பு அவசியம் என்று உச்ச நீதிமன்றம் தீர்ப்பளித்துள்ளது."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "22வது திருத்தம்",
          "label": "LAW"
        },
        {
          "text": "அரசியலமைப்பு",
          "label": "LAW"
        },
        {
          "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "22வது திருத்தம்",
            "label": "LAW"
          },
          {
            "text": "அரசியலமைப்பு",
            "label": "LAW"
          },
          {
            "text": "மந்திரிசபை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "அடுத்த சில நாட்கள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "அரசாங்க தகவல் திணைக்களம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "28",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஏழு நாட்கள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "அரசியலமைப்பு",
            "label": "LAW"
          },
          {
            "text": "சமகி ஜனபலவேகய பிறகு",
            "label": "WORK_OF_ART"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "22 வது திருத்தம்",
            "label": "LAW"
          },
          {
            "text": "அரசியலமைப்பு",
            "label": "LAW"
          },
          {
            "text": "மந்திரி சபை",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "22 வது திருத்தம்",
            "label": "LAW"
          },
          {
            "text": "அரசியலமைப்பு",
            "label": "LAW"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "22 வது திருத்தம்",
            "label": "LAW"
          },
          {
            "text": "அரசியலமைப்பு",
            "label": "LAW"
          },
          {
            "text": "அரசிதழ்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "திருத்த மசோதா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "21",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "22 வது திருத்தம்",
            "label": "LAW"
          },
          {
            "text": "முதலில்",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "அரசியலமைப்பு",
            "label": "LAW"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "21வது திருத்தம்",
            "label": "EVENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "அரசியலமைப்பு",
            "label": "LAW"
          },
          {
            "text": "எதிர்ப்பு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "உச்ச நீதிமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}