{
  "newspaper_id": "island-lk",
  "url": "http://island.lk/boi-showcases-singing-skills-of-employees-at-katunayake-epz/",
  "time_ut": 1660493700,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "BOI showcases singing skills of employees at Katunayake EPZ",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "BOI showcases singing skills of employees at Katunayake EPZ",
      "author": "Thilina Walpola",
      "body_lines": [
        "Niranjala Sarojini from the UTP factory in Katunayake, emerged as the winner at the grand finale of ‘The Voice Range’ hosted by the Board of Investment (BOI) with the objective of showcasing singing skills of employees at Free Zones. Sarojini won the first place in the competition organised for Katunayake Export Processing Zone, which was held at the BOI Ground in Katunayake on Saturday, August 13. The event was held under the patronage of BOI Director General Renuka M Weerakone. The founder of ‘The Voice Range’ was also present at the event. Niranjala was awarded Rs. 100,000. She will get an opportunity to sing at a musical show in Dubai. Music band ‘Sakura Flash’ will compose a song for her for which she will get complete ownership. Also, Rupavahini will feature her in a musical programme.",
        "Digital Marketing Association of Sri Lanka hosts its 1st AGM",
        "SPC embraces biggest technological shift in school book printing arena",
        "Leave a Reply Cancel replyYour email address will not be published. Required fields are marked *Comment Name *",
        "Save my name, email, and website in this browser for the next time I comment."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "BOI",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "Katunayake EPZ",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Niranjala Sarojini",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "UTP",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Katunayake",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Board of Investment",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "BOI",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Free Zones",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "first",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Katunayake Export Processing Zone",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the BOI Ground",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "Katunayake",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Saturday, August 13",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "BOI",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Renuka M Weerakone",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Niranjala",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Rs",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "100,000",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Dubai",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Rupavahini",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Digital Marketing Association of Sri Lanka",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [],
        []
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "BOI කටුනායක EPZ හි සේවකයින්ගේ ගායන කුසලතා ප්‍රදර්ශනය කරයි",
      "author": "තිළිණ වල්පොල",
      "body_lines": [
        "ෆ්‍රී සෝන්ස් හි සේවකයින්ගේ ගායන කුසලතා ප්‍රදර්ශනය කිරීමේ අරමුණින් ආයෝජන මණ්ඩලය (BOI) විසින් පවත්වන ලද ‘ද වොයිස් රේන්ජ්’ අවසන් මහා තරගයේ ජයග්‍රාහකයා ලෙස කටුනායක UTP කර්මාන්ත ශාලාවේ නිරංජලා සරෝජිනී සමත් වූවාය. අගෝස්තු 13 වැනි සෙනසුරාදා කටුනායක ශ්‍රී ලංකා ආයෝජන මණ්ඩලයේ ක්‍රීඩාංගණයේ පැවැති කටුනායක අපනයන සැකසුම් කලාපය සඳහා සංවිධානය කළ තරගයේ ප්‍රථම ස්ථානය සරෝජිනී දිනා ගත්තාය. මෙම උත්සවය ආයෝජන මණ්ඩලයේ අධ්‍යක්ෂ ජනරාල් රේණුකා එම් වීරකෝන් මහත්මියගේ ප්‍රධානත්වයෙන් පැවැත්විණි. ‘ද වොයිස් රේන්ජ්’ නිර්මාතෘවරයා ද මෙම අවස්ථාවට එක්ව සිටියේය. නිරංජලාට රු. 100,000 කි. ඩුබායිවල පැවැත්වෙන සංගීත සංදර්ශනයක ගායනයට අවස්ථාවක් ලැබෙනවා. ‘සකුරා ෆ්ලෑෂ්’ සංගීත කණ්ඩායම ඇය වෙනුවෙන් ගීතයක් රචනා කරන අතර එහි සම්පූර්ණ අයිතිය ඇයට හිමි වේ. ඒ වගේම රූපවාහිනියේ සංගීත වැඩසටහනකට ඇයව ඉදිරිපත් කරනවා.",
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකා ඩිජිටල් අලෙවිකරණ සංගමය එහි පළමු මහා සම්මේලනය පවත්වනු ලබයි",
        "SPC පාසල් පොත් මුද්‍රණ ක්ෂේත්‍රයේ විශාලතම තාක්‍ෂණික වෙනසක් වැළඳ ගනී",
        "පිළිතුරක් දෙන්න පිළිතුර අවලංගු කරන්න ඔබගේ විද්‍යුත් තැපැල් ලිපිනය ප්‍රකාශයට පත් නොකෙරේ. අවශ්‍ය ක්ෂේත්‍ර සලකුණු කර ඇත *අදහස් නම *",
        "මම ඊළඟ වතාවේ අදහස් දැක්වීම සඳහා මගේ නම, විද්‍යුත් තැපෑල සහ වෙබ් අඩවිය මෙම බ්‍රවුසරයේ සුරකින්න."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "BOI",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "කටුනායක EPZ",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Niranjala Sarojini",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "UTP",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "කටුනායක",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ආයෝජන මණ්ඩලය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "BOI",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "නිදහස් කලාප",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "පළමුවන",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "කටුනායක අපනයන සැකසුම් කලාපය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "BOI පිටිය",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "කටුනායක",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "අගෝස්තු 13 සෙනසුරාදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "BOI",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "රේණුකා එම් වීරකෝන්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "නිරංජලා",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "රුපියල්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "100,000 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඩුබායි",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "රූපවාහිනිය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකා ඩිජිටල් අලෙවිකරණ සංගමය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "1 වැනි",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [],
        []
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "BOI கட்டுநாயக்க EPZ இல் ஊழியர்களின் பாடும் திறன்களை வெளிப்படுத்துகிறது",
      "author": "திலின வல்பொல",
      "body_lines": [
        "கட்டுநாயக்காவில் உள்ள UTP தொழிற்சாலையைச் சேர்ந்த நிரஞ்சலா சரோஜினி, Free Zoneகளில் ஊழியர்களின் பாடும் திறமையை வெளிப்படுத்தும் நோக்கத்துடன் முதலீட்டுச் சபை (BOI) நடத்திய ‘The Voice Range’ இன் மாபெரும் இறுதிப்போட்டியில் வெற்றியாளராக வெளிப்பட்டார். கட்டுநாயக்க ஏற்றுமதி செயலாக்க வலயத்திற்காக ஏற்பாடு செய்யப்பட்ட போட்டியில் சரோஜினி முதலாம் இடத்தைப் பெற்றுக்கொண்டார். ஆகஸ்ட் 13 ஆம் திகதி சனிக்கிழமை கட்டுநாயக்க BOI மைதானத்தில் நடைபெற்ற இந்நிகழ்வு BOI பணிப்பாளர் நாயகம் ரேணுகா எம் வீரகோன் தலைமையில் நடைபெற்றது. இந்நிகழ்ச்சியில் ‘தி வாய்ஸ் ரேஞ்ச்’ நிறுவனரும் கலந்து கொண்டார். நிரஞ்சலாவுக்கு ரூ. 100,000. துபாயில் நடக்கும் இசை நிகழ்ச்சியில் பாட வாய்ப்பு கிடைக்கும். ‘சகுரா ஃப்ளாஷ்’ என்ற மியூசிக் பேண்ட் அவருக்காக ஒரு பாடலை உருவாக்கவுள்ளது, அதற்கான முழு உரிமையை அவர் பெறுவார். மேலும், ரூபவாஹினி ஒரு இசை நிகழ்ச்சியிலும் அவரை இடம்பெறச் செய்யும்.",
        "இலங்கையின் டிஜிட்டல் சந்தைப்படுத்தல் சங்கம் அதன் 1வது AGM ஐ நடத்துகிறது",
        "பள்ளி புத்தக அச்சிடும் அரங்கில் SPC மிகப்பெரிய தொழில்நுட்ப மாற்றத்தை தழுவியுள்ளது",
        "ஒரு பதிலை விடுங்கள் பதிலை ரத்துசெய் உங்கள் மின்னஞ்சல் முகவரி வெளியிடப்படாது. தேவையான புலங்கள் குறிக்கப்பட்டுள்ளன *கருத்து பெயர் *",
        "அடுத்த முறை நான் கருத்து தெரிவிக்க, எனது பெயர், மின்னஞ்சல் மற்றும் இணையதளத்தை இந்த உலாவியில் சேமிக்கவும்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "BOI",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "கட்டுநாயக்க EPZ",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Niranjala Sarojini",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "யுடிபி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "கட்டுநாயக்கா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "முதலீட்டு வாரியம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "BOI",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலவச மண்டலங்கள்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "முதலில்",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "கட்டுநாயக்க ஏற்றுமதி செயலாக்க வலயம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "BOI மைதானம்",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "கட்டுநாயக்கா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சனிக்கிழமை, ஆகஸ்ட் 13",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "BOI",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரேணுகா எம் வீரகோன்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "நிரஞ்சலா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரூ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "100,000",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "துபாய்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரூபவாஹினி",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை டிஜிட்டல் சந்தைப்படுத்தல் சங்கம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "1வது",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [],
        []
      ]
    }
  }
}