{
  "newspaper_id": "economy-next-com",
  "url": "https://economynext.com/sri-lanka-president-should-form-stable-govt-with-slpp-mp-namal-rajapaksa-99352/",
  "time_ut": 1662031980,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Sri Lanka president should form stable govt with SLPP: MP Namal Rajapaksa",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Sri Lanka president should form stable govt with SLPP: MP Namal Rajapaksa",
      "author": "",
      "body_lines": [
        "ECONOMYNEXT – Sri Lanka President Ranil Wickremesinghe ought to form a stable administration with the 134 ruling party MPs who elected him rather than pin his hopes on an all-party government, according to Sri Lanka Podujana Peramuna (SLPP) Namal Rajapaksa.",
        "Rajapaksa told reporters on Thursday September 01 that the very parties that had demanded an all-party government now appear to have abandoned their call.",
        "“Rather than approach all 225 members, what President Wickremesinghe ought to do now is realise that there are 134 MPs who voted for him and form a stable government with those 134 MPs and solve the problems of the people,” he said.",
        "Rajapaksa also called for the appointment of district committees and state ministries with a view to providing relief to the public hit by Sri Lanka’s worst economic crisis since independence.",
        "However, President Wickremesinghe has not yet given up on his repeatedly stated goal of establishing an all-party government. Delivering the interim budget speech in parliament on Tuesday August 30, he reiterated the call, highlighting the importance of bipartisan consensus in seeing Sri Lanka through much needed economic reforms.",
        "The main opposition Samagi Jana Balawegaya (SJB) has officially said it is agreeable to supporting the government’s reform efforts through parliamentary committees without joining the cabinet. But analysts say SJB seniors have been blowing hot and cold on the matter, with some apparently more eager than others to play a more hands-on role.",
        "The SLPP and the Rajapaksa family, meanwhile, are at their lowest in terms of popularity, but opposition lawmakers have claimed that President Wickremesinghe is at the mercy of the SLPP, with some going as far as to call him a prisoner of the party of the Rajapaksas.",
        "However, the SLPP and the coalition it leads has splintered and factionalised in the wake of Sri Lanka’s youth-led protests, with the latest defection being from 13 party members including the party’s chairman.",
        "Former Prime Minister Mahinda Rajapaksa, who has been maintaining a low profile in the wake of the protests, was also seen at an SLPP meeting where party seniors were discussing where the once unstoppable party had “gone wrong”.",
        "Reports over recent weeks have speculated that the main Rajapaksa-led faction has been canvassing for more power and position in the government, with demands reportedly made for state ministries with the attended perks in tact.",
        "The United National Party (UNP), which Wickremesinghe leads, is represented in parliament by just one MP: Vajira Abeywardena, a staunch Wickremesinghe loyalist. (Colombo/Sep01/2022)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Sri Lanka",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "Namal Rajapaksa",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "134",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "Podujana Peramuna",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Namal Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Thursday September 01",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "225",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "134",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "134",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka’s",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Tuesday August 30",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Samagi",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Jana Balawegaya",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "SJB",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "SJB",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Rajapaksas",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "13",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Mahinda Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "recent weeks",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Rajapaksa",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "The United National Party",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "UNP",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Vajira Abeywardena",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "ශ්‍රී ලංකා ජනාධිපතිවරයා ශ්‍රී ලංකා පොදුජන පෙරමුණ සමඟ ස්ථාවර ආණ්ඩුවක් පිහිටුවිය යුතුයි: පාර්ලිමේන්තු මන්ත්‍රී නාමල් රාජපක්ෂ",
      "author": "",
      "body_lines": [
        "ආර්ථිකය - ශ්‍රී ලංකා පොදුජන පෙරමුණ (SLPP) නාමල් රාජපක්ෂට අනුව, ශ්‍රී ලංකා ජනාධිපති රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතා සර්ව පාක්ෂික ආණ්ඩුවක් කෙරෙහි බලාපොරොත්තු තබා නොගෙන තමන් පත් කළ ආණ්ඩු පක්ෂයේ මන්ත්‍රීවරුන් 134 දෙනා සමඟ ස්ථාවර පාලනයක් ගොඩනැගිය යුතුය.",
        "රාජපක්ෂ සැප්තැම්බර් 01 බ්‍රහස්පතින්දා මාධ්‍යවේදීන් අමතමින් කියා සිටියේ සර්ව පාක්ෂික ආණ්ඩුවක් ඉල්ලා සිටි පාර්ශවයන්ම දැන් ඔවුන්ගේ කැඳවීම අත්හැර ඇති බවක් පෙනෙන බවයි.",
        "මන්ත්‍රීවරුන් 225 දෙනාටම ළං වෙනවාට වඩා වික්‍රමසිංහ ජනාධිපතිතුමා දැන් කළ යුත්තේ තමන්ට ඡන්දය දුන් මන්ත්‍රීවරුන් 134ක් සිටින බව තේරුම් ගෙන එම මන්ත්‍රීවරුන් 134 දෙනා සමඟ ස්ථාවර ආණ්ඩුවක් පිහිටුවා ජනතාවගේ ප්‍රශ්න විසඳීමයි.",
        "නිදහසින් පසු ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ දරුණුතම ආර්ථික අර්බුදයෙන් පීඩාවට පත් මහජනතාවට සහන සැලසීමේ අරමුණින් දිස්ත්‍රික් කමිටු සහ රාජ්‍ය අමාත්‍යාංශ පත් කරන ලෙස ද රාජපක්ෂ ඉල්ලා සිටියේය.",
        "කෙසේ වෙතත්, ජනාධිපති වික්‍රමසිංහ සර්ව පාක්ෂික ආණ්ඩුවක් පිහිටුවීමේ තම අරමුණ පුන පුනා ප්‍රකාශ කිරීම තවමත් අත්හැර නැත. අගෝස්තු 30 වැනි අඟහරුවාදා පාර්ලිමේන්තුවේ අතුරු අයවැය කතාව ඉදිරිපත් කරමින් ඔහු නැවත නැවතත් කැඳවීම කළේ, ශ්‍රී ලංකාව අත්‍යවශ්‍ය ආර්ථික ප්‍රතිසංස්කරණ හරහා දැකීමට ද්විපාර්ශ්වික එකඟතාවයේ වැදගත්කම අවධාරණය කරමිනි.",
        "ප්‍රධාන විපක්ෂය වන සමගි ජන බලවේගය (SJB) කැබිනට් මණ්ඩලයට සම්බන්ධ නොවී පාර්ලිමේන්තු කමිටු හරහා ආණ්ඩුවේ ප්‍රතිසංස්කරණ ප්‍රයත්නයන්ට සහාය දැක්වීමට එකඟ බව නිල වශයෙන් පවසා තිබේ. නමුත් විශ්ලේෂකයින් පවසන්නේ SJB ජ්‍යෙෂ්ඨයින් මෙම කාරණය සම්බන්ධයෙන් උණුසුම් හා සීතලක් ඇති කර ඇති අතර සමහරුන් අනෙක් අයට වඩා වැඩි කාර්යභාරයක් ඉටු කිරීමට උනන්දු වන බවයි.",
        "මේ අතර ශ්‍රී ලංකා පොදුජන පෙරමුණ සහ රාජපක්ෂ පවුල ජනප්‍රියත්වය අතින් පහළම තැනක සිටින නමුත් විපක්ෂයේ මන්ත්‍රීවරුන් ප්‍රකාශ කළේ වික්‍රමසිංහ ජනාධිපතිවරයා ශ්‍රී ලංකා පොදුජන පෙරමුණේ අනුකම්පාව යටතේ සිටින බව ය. රාජපක්ෂලා.",
        "කෙසේ වෙතත්, ශ්‍රී ලංකා පොදුජන පෙරමුණ සහ එය නායකත්වය දෙන සභාගය ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ තරුණයන් විසින් මෙහෙයවන ලද විරෝධතා හමුවේ දෙකඩ වී කණ්ඩායම්ගත වී ඇති අතර, අලුත්ම ඉවත්වීම පක්ෂයේ සභාපතිවරයා ඇතුළු පක්ෂ සාමාජිකයින් 13 දෙනෙකුගෙන් විය.",
        "විරෝධතා හමුවේ පහත් තත්ත්වයක සිටින හිටපු අගමැති මහින්ද රාජපක්ෂ ද ශ්‍රී ලංකා පොදුජන පෙරමුණේ රැස්වීමක දී ද, කලක් නතර කළ නොහැකි වූ පක්ෂයට වැරදුණේ කොතැනදැයි පක්ෂයේ ජ්‍යෙෂ්ඨයන් සාකච්ඡා කරමින් සිටිනු දක්නට ලැබිණි.",
        "පසුගිය සතිවල වාර්තා අනුමාන කර ඇත්තේ රාජපක්ෂ ප්‍රමුඛ ප්‍රධාන කන්ඩායම ආණ්ඩුවේ වැඩි බලයක් සහ තනතුරක් සඳහා කැන්වසින් කරමින් සිටින බවත්, රාජ්‍ය අමාත්‍යාංශ සඳහා උපක්‍රමශීලීව සහභාගි වූ වරප්‍රසාද සමඟ ඉල්ලීම් ඉදිරිපත් කර ඇති බවත්ය.",
        "වික්‍රමසිංහ නායකත්වය දෙන එක්සත් ජාතික පක්ෂය (එජාප) පාර්ලිමේන්තුව නියෝජනය කරන්නේ එක් මන්ත්‍රීවරයෙකු පමණි: දැඩි වික්‍රමසිංහ හිතවාදියෙකු වන වජිර අබේවර්ධන. (කොළඹ/සැප්.01/2022)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "නාමල් රාජපක්ෂ",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "134",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "පොදුජන පෙරමුණ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "නාමල් රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "සැප්තැම්බර් 01 බ්‍රහස්පතින්දා",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "225",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "134",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "134",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "අගෝස්තු 30 අඟහරුවාදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "සමගි",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජන බලවේගය",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "එස්.ජේ.බී",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "එස්.ජේ.බී",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "රාජපක්ෂලා",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "13",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "මහින්ද රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "මෑත සති",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "එක්සත් ජාතික පක්ෂයයි",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "එජාප",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "වජිර අබේවර්ධන",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "இலங்கை ஜனாதிபதி SLPP உடன் இணைந்து நிலையான அரசாங்கத்தை அமைக்க வேண்டும்: பாராளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர் நாமல் ராஜபக்ஷ",
      "author": "",
      "body_lines": [
        "பொருளாதாரம் - ஸ்ரீலங்கா பொதுஜன பெரமுன (SLPP) நாமல் ராஜபக்ஷவின் கருத்துப்படி, ஸ்ரீலங்கா ஜனாதிபதி ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க அனைத்துக் கட்சி அரசாங்கத்தின் மீது நம்பிக்கை வைப்பதை விட, தன்னைத் தேர்ந்தெடுத்த 134 ஆளும் கட்சி எம்.பி.க்களுடன் நிலையான நிர்வாகத்தை உருவாக்க வேண்டும்.",
        "செப்டம்பர் 01 வியாழன் அன்று செய்தியாளர்களிடம் ராஜபக்ச, அனைத்துக் கட்சி அரசாங்கத்தைக் கோரிய கட்சிகளே இப்போது தங்கள் அழைப்பைக் கைவிட்டதாகத் தெரிகிறது.",
        "“225 உறுப்பினர்களையும் அணுகுவதற்குப் பதிலாக, ஜனாதிபதி விக்கிரமசிங்க இப்போது செய்ய வேண்டியது, தமக்கு வாக்களித்த 134 எம்.பி.க்கள் இருப்பதை உணர்ந்து அந்த 134 எம்.பி.க்களுடன் நிலையான அரசாங்கத்தை உருவாக்கி மக்களின் பிரச்சினைகளைத் தீர்ப்பதுதான்,” என்று அவர் கூறினார்.",
        "சுதந்திரத்திற்குப் பிறகு இலங்கையின் மோசமான பொருளாதார நெருக்கடியால் பாதிக்கப்பட்டுள்ள பொதுமக்களுக்கு நிவாரணம் வழங்கும் நோக்கில் மாவட்டக் குழுக்கள் மற்றும் மாநில அமைச்சகங்களை நியமிக்கவும் ராஜபக்ச அழைப்பு விடுத்தார்.",
        "எவ்வாறாயினும், ஜனாதிபதி விக்கிரமசிங்க, சர்வகட்சி அரசாங்கமொன்றை ஸ்தாபிக்க வேண்டும் என்ற தனது தொடர்ச்சியான இலக்கை இன்னும் கைவிடவில்லை. ஆகஸ்ட் 30 செவ்வாய்கிழமை பாராளுமன்றத்தில் இடைக்கால வரவு செலவுத் திட்ட உரையை ஆற்றிய அவர், இலங்கையை மிகவும் தேவையான பொருளாதார சீர்திருத்தங்கள் மூலம் பார்ப்பதில் இரு கட்சிகளின் ஒருமித்த முக்கியத்துவத்தை எடுத்துரைத்து மீண்டும் அழைப்பு விடுத்தார்.",
        "பிரதான எதிர்க்கட்சியான சமகி ஜன பலவேகய (SJB) அமைச்சரவையில் இணையாமல் நாடாளுமன்றக் குழுக்கள் மூலம் அரசாங்கத்தின் சீர்திருத்த முயற்சிகளுக்கு ஆதரவளிப்பது உடன்படுவதாக உத்தியோகபூர்வமாக தெரிவித்துள்ளது. ஆனால் ஆய்வாளர்கள் கூறுகையில், SJB மூத்தவர்கள் இந்த விஷயத்தில் சூடாகவும் குளிராகவும் உள்ளனர், சிலர் வெளிப்படையாக மற்றவர்களை விட அதிக பங்கு வகிக்க ஆர்வமாக உள்ளனர்.",
        "இதற்கிடையில், SLPP மற்றும் ராஜபக்ச குடும்பம் பிரபல்யத்தின் அடிப்படையில் மிகக் குறைந்த நிலையில் உள்ளன, ஆனால் எதிர்க்கட்சி சட்டமன்ற உறுப்பினர்கள் ஜனாதிபதி விக்கிரமசிங்க SLPP யின் தயவில் இருப்பதாகக் கூறினர், சிலர் அவரைக் கட்சியின் கைதி என்று அழைக்கிறார்கள். ராஜபக்சேக்கள்.",
        "எவ்வாறாயினும், SLPP மற்றும் அது வழிநடத்தும் கூட்டணியானது, இலங்கையின் இளைஞர்கள் தலைமையிலான போராட்டங்களை அடுத்து பிளவுபட்டு பிரிவுகளாக மாறியுள்ளது, கட்சியின் தலைவர் உட்பட 13 கட்சி உறுப்பினர்களின் சமீபத்திய விலகல்.",
        "எதிர்ப்புக்களை அடுத்து மந்தமான நிலையைக் கடைப்பிடித்து வரும் முன்னாள் பிரதமர் மஹிந்த ராஜபக்ஷ, SLPP கூட்டத்தில் ஒரு காலத்தில் தடுத்து நிறுத்த முடியாத கட்சி \"தவறானது\" என்று கட்சியின் மூத்தவர்கள் விவாதித்ததையும் காணமுடிந்தது.",
        "ராஜபக்ச தலைமையிலான பிரதான பிரிவு அரசாங்கத்தில் அதிக அதிகாரம் மற்றும் பதவிக்காக பிரச்சாரம் செய்து வருவதாக சமீபத்திய வாரங்களில் செய்திகள் ஊகிக்கின்றன.",
        "விக்கிரமசிங்க தலைமையிலான ஐக்கிய தேசியக் கட்சி (UNP) பாராளுமன்றத்தில் ஒரு எம்.பி. மட்டுமே பிரதிநிதித்துவப்படுத்துகிறது: வஜிர அபேவர்தன, ஒரு தீவிர விக்கிரமசிங்க விசுவாசி. (கொழும்பு/செப்01/2022)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "இலங்கை",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "நாமல் ராஜபக்ச",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "134",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "பொதுஜன பெரமுன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "நாமல் ராஜபக்ச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ராஜபக்சே",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "செப்டம்பர் 01 வியாழன்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "225",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "134",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "134",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ராஜபக்சே",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கையின்",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆகஸ்ட் 30 செவ்வாய்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "சமகி",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜன பலவேகயா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "எஸ்.ஜே.பி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "எஸ்.ஜே.பி",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ராஜபக்சே",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ராஜபக்சேக்கள்",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "13",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "மஹிந்த ராஜபக்ஷ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "சமீபத்திய வாரங்கள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ராஜபக்சே",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஐக்கிய தேசியக் கட்சி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஐ.தே.க",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "வஜிர அபேவர்தன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}