{
  "newspaper_id": "ada-lk",
  "url": "https://www.ada.lk/breaking_news/හිස-කපා-ගඟට-දමලා/11-394887",
  "time_ut": 1656325428,
  "original_lang": "si",
  "original_title": "හිස කපා ගඟට දමලා",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "The head was cut off and thrown into the river",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "The Akuressa Police have launched an investigation into the search for a man who had cut his head off his neck and dumped it in the Nilwala River in the Thibbatuwa area in Akuressa, Matara this morning (27).",
        "The deceased has been identified as Vellalathanthrige Sumanapala (70), a disabled father of two, a resident of Ralakadawatta, Thibbatuwa, Akuressa.",
        "The homes of the deceased and the man suspected of beheading are adjacent and an argument broke out between the two parties this morning (27th) claiming that the deceased had flagged his house.",
        "It then escalated into a confrontation and the suspect went home and took a sword and tried to attack the disabled man. Although the wife and child of the disabled person had tried to prevent it, the suspect had cut off the head of the disabled person and run away. It is reported that the head was later thrown into the Nilwala river. Police have launched an investigation to find the head.",
        "The wife and child of the disabled person who managed to escape the dispute have been admitted to the Akuressa Hospital with minor injuries. The suspect Samarasinghe Thilanna has fled the area and a special police team has been deployed to arrest him and the Akuressa Police are conducting further investigations."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "the Nilwala River",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Thibbatuwa",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Akuressa",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Matara",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "this morning",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "27",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Vellalathanthrige Sumanapala",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "70",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "two",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ralakadawatta",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Thibbatuwa",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Akuressa",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "two",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "this morning",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Nilwala",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the Akuressa Hospital",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Samarasinghe Thilanna",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "හිස කපා ගඟට දමලා",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "මාතර, අකුරැස්ස, තිබ්බටුවාව ප්‍රදේශයේ අද (27දා) උදැසන පුද්ගලයෙකුගේ ගෙල ලගින් හිස පෙදෙස කපා නිල්වලා ගගට දැමු පුද්ගලයෙක් සොයා විමර්ශණයක් ආරම්භකොට ඇති බව අකුරැස්ස පොලිසිය පවසයි.",
        "මෙසේ ජිවිතක්ෂයට පත්ව ඇත්තේ අකුරැස්ස, තිබ්බටුවාව,රළකඩවත්ත ප්‍රදේශයේ පදිංචි වෙල්ලාලතන්ත්‍රිගේ සුමනපාල (70) නම් ආබාධිත , දෙදරු පියෙකි.",
        "මියගිය තැනැත්තාගේ සහ ගෙල කපාදැමු බවට සැකකෙරෙන පුද්ගලයාගේ නිවෙස් එකලග පවතින අතර  මියගිය පුද්ගලයා විසින් තම නිවසට කොඩිනයක් කර ඇති බවට පවසමින් දෙපාර්ශවය අතර අද (27දා) උදැසන බහින්බස්විමක් අතිව තිබේ.",
        "පසුව එය එය ගැටුමක් දක්වා දුරදිග ගොස් තිබෙන අතර සැකකරු නිවසට ගොස් කඩුවක් රැගෙනවිත් ආබාධිත පුද්ගලයාට පහරදිමට තැත්කොට තිබේ. මෙහිදි ආබාධිත පුද්ගලයාගේ බිරිද හා දරුවා එය වැළක්විමට උත්සහගෙන තිබුනද සැකකරු ආබාධිත පුද්ගලයාගේ ගෙල ලගින් හිස කොටස කපාගෙන දිවගොස් ඇත. පසුව හිස කොටස නිල්වලා ගගට විසිකොට ඇති බවටද වාර්තා වෙයි. එම හිස කොටස සොයා පොලිසිය විමර්ශණයක් ආරමිභකොට තිබේ.",
        "එසේම මෙම ආරවුල බේරීම සඳහා කටයුතු කල ආබාධිත පුද්ගලයාගේ බිරිඳ හා දරුවා සුලු තුවාල ලබා අකුරැස්ස රෝහල වෙත ප්‍රතිකාර සදහා ඇතුලත් කොට තිබේ. සමරසිංහ තිලන්න යන සැකකරු ප්‍රදේශයෙන් පලාගොස් ඇති අතර ඔහුව අත්අඩංගුවට ගැනිම සදහා විශේෂ පොලිස් කණ්ඩායමක් යොදවා ඇති අතර අකුරැස්ස පොලිසිය ඉදිරි පරික්ෂණ මෙහෙයවනු ලබයි."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "නිල්වලා ගඟ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "තිබ්බටුවාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Akuressa",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මාතර",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මේ උදෑසන",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "27",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "වෙල්ලාලතන්ත්‍රිගේ සුමනපාල",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "70",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "දෙක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "රලකඩවත්ත",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "තිබ්බටුවාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Akuressa",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "දෙක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "මේ උදෑසන",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "නිල්වලා",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "අකුරැස්ස රෝහල",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "සමරසිංහ තිලන්න",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "தலை துண்டிக்கப்பட்டு ஆற்றில் வீசப்பட்டது",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "இன்று (27) காலை மாத்தறை, அக்குரஸ்ஸ திப்பட்டுவ பிரதேசத்தில் கழுத்தில் தலையை வெட்டி நில்வலா ஆற்றில் வீசிய நபரை தேடும் நடவடிக்கையில் அக்குரஸ்ஸ பொலிஸார் விசாரணைகளை ஆரம்பித்துள்ளனர்.",
        "உயிரிழந்தவர் அக்குரஸ்ஸ, திபதுவ, ரலகடவத்த பகுதியைச் சேர்ந்த, இரண்டு பிள்ளைகளின் தந்தையான ஊனமுற்ற வெள்ளாளதந்திரிகே சுமனபால (வயது 70) என அடையாளம் காணப்பட்டுள்ளார்.",
        "இறந்தவர் மற்றும் தலை துண்டிக்கப்பட்டதாக சந்தேகிக்கப்படும் நபரின் வீடுகள் அருகருகே உள்ளதால், இறந்தவர் தனது வீட்டில் கொடியேற்றியதாக கூறி இரு தரப்பினருக்கும் இடையே இன்று (27ம் தேதி) காலை வாக்குவாதம் ஏற்பட்டது.",
        "பின்னர் அது மோதலாக மாறியதுடன் சந்தேக நபர் வீட்டுக்குச் சென்று வாளை எடுத்து அங்கவீனமான நபரை தாக்க முயற்சித்துள்ளார். அங்கவீனமுற்ற நபரின் மனைவியும் பிள்ளையும் அதனைத் தடுக்க முற்பட்ட போதும் சந்தேக நபர் அங்கவீனமானவரின் தலையை வெட்டிவிட்டு தப்பிச் சென்றுள்ளார். பின்னர் தலை நில்வலா ஆற்றில் வீசப்பட்டதாகத் தெரிவிக்கப்படுகிறது. தலையை கண்டுபிடிக்க போலீசார் விசாரணையை துவக்கியுள்ளனர்.",
        "தகராறில் இருந்து தப்பிச் சென்ற ஊனமுற்ற நபரின் மனைவி மற்றும் குழந்தை சிறு காயங்களுடன் அக்குரஸ்ஸ வைத்தியசாலையில் அனுமதிக்கப்பட்டுள்ளனர். சந்தேக நபர் சமரசிங்க திலன்ன பிரதேசத்தில் இருந்து தப்பிச் சென்றுள்ளதுடன், அவரை கைது செய்ய விசேட பொலிஸ் குழுவொன்று நியமிக்கப்பட்டுள்ளதுடன், அக்குரஸ்ஸ பொலிஸார் மேலதிக விசாரணைகளை மேற்கொண்டு வருகின்றனர்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "நில்வலா நதி",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "திப்பட்டுவா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Akuressa",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "மாத்தறை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று காலை",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "27",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "வெள்ளாளதந்திரிகே சுமனபால",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "70",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "இரண்டு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரலகடவத்த",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "திப்பட்டுவா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Akuressa",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இரண்டு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று காலை",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "நில்வாலா",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "அக்குரஸ்ஸ வைத்தியசாலை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "சமரசிங்க திலன்ன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}