{
  "newspaper_id": "virakesari-lk",
  "url": "http://www.virakesari.lk/article/130481",
  "time_ut": 1656579148,
  "original_lang": "ta",
  "original_title": "ஒரு இலட்சம் மெட்ரிக் தொன் எரிவாயுவை கொள்முதல் செய்துள்ள லிட்ரோ நிறுவனம்",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Litro has purchased one lakh metric tons of gas",
      "author": "T Yuwaraj",
      "body_lines": [
        "Litro Gas Company under the Ministry of Finance has successfully procured 100,000 MT lb of gas, the Prime Minister's Office said in a statement.",
        "The total cost of the gas is estimated at $ 90 million, of which $ 70 million will be provided by the World Bank and the remaining $ 20 million by Litro.",
        "In this case, it has been reported that the said gas will be enough to supply the country for four months, 70% of the gas will be supplied to domestic consumers. Out of this, 5 million 12.5 kg cylinders, 1 million 5 kg cylinders and 1 million 2.5 kg cylinders will be procured and the remaining 30% of the gas will be supplied for commercial use.",
        "It is noteworthy that it has been reported that 33,000 tons of LPG gas purchased by Litro at a cost of $ 20 million will arrive in Sri Lanka in the first week of July."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "one lakh metric tons",
          "label": "QUANTITY"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Litro Gas Company",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Ministry of Finance",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "100,000",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Prime Minister's Office",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "$ 90 million",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "$ 70 million",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "the World Bank",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the remaining $ 20 million",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "Litro",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "four months",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "70%",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "5 million",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "12.5 kg",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "1 million",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "1 million",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "2.5 kg",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "the remaining 30%",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "33,000 tons",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "LPG",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Litro",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "$ 20 million",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the first week of July",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "ලිට්‍රෝ සමාගම ගෑස් මෙට්‍රික් ටොන් ලක්ෂයක් මිලදී ගෙන තිබෙනවා",
      "author": "ටී යුවරාජ්",
      "body_lines": [
        "මුදල් අමාත්‍යාංශය යටතේ පවතින ලිට්‍රෝ ගෑස් සමාගම LP ගෑස් මෙට්‍රික් ටොන් ලක්ෂයක් සාර්ථකව මිලදී ගෙන ඇති බව අග්‍රාමාත්‍ය කාර්යාලය නිවේදනයක් නිකුත් කරමින් පවසයි.",
        "ගෑස් සඳහා වන මුළු පිරිවැය ඩොලර් මිලියන 90 ක් ලෙස ඇස්තමේන්තු කර ඇති අතර, එයින් ඩොලර් මිලියන 70 ක් ලෝක බැංකුවෙන් ද ඉතිරි ඩොලර් මිලියන 20 ක් ලිට්‍රෝ සමාගමෙන් ද ලබා දෙනු ඇත.",
        "මෙහිදී ගෑස්වලින් 70%ක් ගෘහස්ත පාරිභෝගිකයන් වෙත සපයනු ලබන අතර, එය මාස හතරකට රටට සැපයීමට ප්‍රමාණවත් බව වාර්තා වේ. මෙයින් කිලෝග්‍රෑම් 12.5 සිලින්ඩර මිලියන 5 ක්, කිලෝග්‍රෑම් 5 සිලින්ඩර මිලියන 1 ක් සහ කිලෝග්‍රෑම් 2.5 සිලින්ඩර මිලියන 1 ක් මිලදී ගන්නා අතර ඉතිරි 30% ගෑස් වාණිජ භාවිතය සඳහා සපයනු ලැබේ.",
        "ලිට්‍රෝ සමාගම ඩොලර් මිලියන 20ක් වැයකර මිලදී ගත් LPG ගෑස් ටොන් 33,000ක් ජූලි මස මුල් සතියේදී ශ්‍රී ලංකාවට පැමිණෙනු ඇති බව සඳහන් කිරීම වටී."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "මෙට්‍රික් ටොන් ලක්ෂයක්",
          "label": "QUANTITY"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ලිට්‍රෝ ගෑස් සමාගම",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "මුදල් අමාත්යාංශය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "100,000 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "අගමැති කාර්යාලය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ඩොලර් මිලියන 90 කි",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඩොලර් මිලියන 70 කි",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "ලෝක බැංකුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉතිරි ඩොලර් මිලියන 20",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "ලිට්රෝ",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "සිව් මාස",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "70%",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "මිලියන 5 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "කිලෝ ග්රෑම් 12.5 කි",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "මිලියන 1 ක්",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "මිලියන 1 ක්",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "කිලෝ ග්රෑම් 2.5 කි",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉතිරි 30%",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ටොන් 33,000 කි",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "එල්.පී.ජී",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ලිට්රෝ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඩොලර් මිලියන 20 කි",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජූලි පළමු සතිය",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "ஒரு இலட்சம் மெட்ரிக் தொன் எரிவாயுவை கொள்முதல் செய்துள்ள லிட்ரோ நிறுவனம்",
      "author": "T Yuwaraj",
      "body_lines": [
        "நிதி அமைச்சகத்தின் கீழ் உள்ள லிட்ரோ எரிவாயு நிறுவனம், 100,000 மெட்ரிக் தொன் எல்பி எரிவாயுவை வெற்றிகரமாக கொள்முதல் செய்துள்ளதாக பிரதமர் அலுவலகம் அறிக்கை ஒன்றில் தெரிவித்துள்ளது.",
        "இந்நிலையில் குறித்த மொத்த எரிவாயுவிற்கு 90 மில்லியன் செலவாகவுள்ள நிலையில், அதில் 70 மில்லியன் டொலரை உலக வங்கி  நிதியுதவியாக  வழங்கவுள்ளதோடு, மீதமுள்ள 20 மில்லியன்  டொலரை லிட்ரோ நிறுவனத்தால் வழங்கப்பட்டுள்ளதாக தெரிவிக்கப்பட்டள்ளது.",
        "இந்நிலையில் குறித்த எரிவாயு நான்கு மாதங்களுக்கு நாட்டிற்கு வழங்க போதுமானதாக இருக்குமென தெரிவிக்கப்பட்டள்ள நிலையில், 70% எரிவாயு உள்நாட்டு நுகர்வோருக்கு வழங்கப்படும். இதன் மூலம் 5 மில்லியன் 12.5 கிலோ சிலிண்டர்கள், 1 மில்லியன் 5 கிலோ சிலிண்டர்கள் மற்றும் 1 மில்லியன் 2.5 கிலோ சிலிண்டர்கள் பெறப்படவதோடு, மீதமுள்ள 30% எரிவாயு வணிக பயன்பாட்டிற்கு வழங்கப்படவுள்ளதாக தெரிவிக்கப்பட்டள்ளது.",
        "இதன்போது லிட்ரோ நிறுவனத்தால் 20 மில்லியன் டொலர்கள் செலவில் கொள்வனவு செய்யப்பட்ட 33,000 தொன் எல்பிஜி எரிவாயு ஜூலை முதல் வாரத்தில் இலங்கையை வந்தடையவுள்ளதாக தெரிவிக்கப்பட்டுள்ளமை குறித்தப்பிடத்தக்கது."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ஒரு லட்சம் மெட்ரிக் டன்",
          "label": "QUANTITY"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "லிட்ரோ எரிவாயு நிறுவனம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "நிதி அமைச்சகம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "100,000",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "பிரதமர் அலுவலகம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "$ 90 மில்லியன்",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "$ 70 மில்லியன்",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "உலக வங்கி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "மீதமுள்ள $ 20 மில்லியன்",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "லிட்ரோ",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "நான்கு மாதங்கள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "70%",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "5 மில்லியன்",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "12.5 கி.கி",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "1 மில்லியன்",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "1 மில்லியன்",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "2.5 கி.கி",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "மீதமுள்ள 30%",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "33,000 டன்",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "எல்.பி.ஜி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "லிட்ரோ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "$ 20 மில்லியன்",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜூலை முதல் வாரம்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}