{
  "newspaper_id": "lankadeepa-lk",
  "url": "https://www.lankadeepa.lk/latest_news/මුදල්ගෙන-ටිකට්-නොදුන්-ලංගම-කොන්දොස්තරවරු-3කට-වැඩවරදී/1-617230",
  "time_ut": 1659074745,
  "original_lang": "si",
  "original_title": "මුදල්ගෙන ටිකට් නොදුන් ලංගම කොන්දොස්තරවරු 3කට වැඩවරදී",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "On duty for 3 Langama conductors who did not take money and give tickets",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "A senior official of the Ceylon Transportation Board said that the services of three conductors of the Ceylon Traffic Board (Langama) who did not issue tickets after taking money from passengers are to be suspended.",
        "The officer mentioned that three conductors of two buses on the expressway from Monaragala to Makumbura and Galle to Kadawata and a regular service bus from Tangalle to Embilipitiya have been accused of taking money and not issuing tickets. did",
        "The official said that during the operation, it was found that tickets worth 2,190 rupees on the bus from Monaragala to Makumbura, 9 tickets worth 1,190 rupees on the bus from Galle to Kadawata and 5 tickets on the bus from Tangalle to Ambilipitiya had not been given. He also mentioned that legal proceedings are being taken against the conductors of the buses.",
        "A team led by Mr. Washington Rajapaksa, chief mobile inspector of the Ceylon Transport Board, implemented this operation."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "3",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "the Ceylon Transportation Board",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "three",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Ceylon Traffic Board",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "three",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "two",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Monaragala",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Makumbura",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Galle",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kadawata",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "2,190",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Monaragala",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Makumbura",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "9",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "1,190",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Galle",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kadawata",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "5",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Tangalle",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Washington Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Ceylon Transport Board",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "මුදල්ගෙන ටිකට් නොදුන් ලංගම කොන්දොස්තරවරු 3කට වැඩවරදී",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "මගීන්ගෙන් මුදල් ලබාගෙන ප්‍රවේශපත් නිකුත් නොකළ ලංකා ගමනා ගමන මණ්ඩලයේ (ලංගම) කොන්දොස්තර මහත්වරු තිදෙනකුගේ සේවය අත්හිටුවීමට නියමිත බව ලංකා ගමනා ගමන මණ්ඩලයේ උසස් නිලධාරියකු පැවසීය.",
        "මොනරාගල සිට මාකුඹුර සහ ගාල්ල සිට කඩවත දක්වා අධිවේගී මාර්ගයේ බස් රථ දෙකක සහ තංගල්ල සිට ඇඹිලිපිටිය දක්වා සාමාන්‍ය සේවා බස් රථයක කොන්දෝසතර මහත්වරු තිදෙනකුට මුදල් ලබාගෙන ප්‍රවේශපත් නිකුත් නොකළ බවට චෝදනා එල්ල වී ඇති බවත් ජංගම පරීක්‍ෂණ නිලධාරීන් කළ විශේෂ වැටලීමකදී එම කොන්දොස්තර මහත්වරු හදුනාගත් බවත් එම නිලධාරියා සඳහන් කළේය.",
        "මොනරාගල සිට මාකුඹුර දක්වා බස් රථයේ රුපියල් 2,190 ක ප්‍රවේශපතක්, ගාල්ල සිට කඩවත දක්වා බස් රථයේ රුපියල් 1,190 ක් වටිනා ප්‍රවේශපත් 9 ක් සහ තංගල්ල සිට ඇඹිලිපිටිය දක්වා බස් රථයේ ප්‍රවේශපත් 5 ක් සඳහා මුදල් ලබාගෙන ප්‍රවේශපත් දී නොමැති යැයි මෙහෙයුමේදී සොයගත හැකි වූ බව කී එම නිලධාරියා අදාල බස් රථවල කොන්දොස්තර මහතුන් පිළිබඳව නීතිමය කටයුතු කරමින් සිටින බව ද සඳහන් කළේය.",
        "ලංකා ගමනා ගමන මණ්ඩලයේ ප්‍රධාන ජංගම පරීක්‍ෂක වොෂින්ටන් රාජපක්‍ෂ මහතා ප්‍රමුඛ කණ්ඩායමක් මෙම මෙහෙයමු ක්‍රියාත්මක කළේය."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "3",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ලංකා ගමනාගමන මණ්ඩලය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "තුන්",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ලංකා ගමනාගමන මණ්ඩලය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "තුන්",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "දෙක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "මොනරාගල",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මාකුඹුර",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගාල්ල",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "කඩවත",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "2,190 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "මොනරාගල",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මාකුඹුර",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "9",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "1,190 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගාල්ල",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "කඩවත",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "5",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "තංගල්ල",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "වොෂින්ටන් රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ලංකා ගමනාගමන මණ්ඩලය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "பணம் வாங்கி டிக்கெட் கொடுக்காத 3 லங்காமா கண்டக்டர்களுக்கு பணியில்",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "பயணிகளிடம் பணம் பெற்றுக்கொண்டு பயணச்சீட்டு வழங்காத இலங்கை போக்குவரத்து சபையின் (லங்காம) நடத்துனர்கள் மூவரின் சேவைகள் இடைநிறுத்தப்பட உள்ளதாக இலங்கை போக்குவரத்து சபையின் உயர் அதிகாரி ஒருவர் தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "மொனராகலையில் இருந்து மகும்புர மற்றும் காலிக்கு கடவத்தை வரையிலான அதிவேக நெடுஞ்சாலையில் இயங்கும் இரண்டு பஸ்களின் மூன்று நடத்துனர்கள் மற்றும் தங்காலையிலிருந்து எம்பிலிப்பிட்டிய வரையிலான வழக்கமான சேவை பஸ்ஸில் பணம் பெற்றுக்கொண்டு டிக்கெட் வழங்கவில்லை என குற்றம் சுமத்தப்பட்டுள்ளதாக அந்த அதிகாரி குறிப்பிட்டார்.",
        "இந்த நடவடிக்கையின் போது மொனராகலையில் இருந்து மகும்புர செல்லும் பேருந்தில் 2,190 ரூபா பெறுமதியான பயணச்சீட்டுகளும், காலியிலிருந்து கடவத்தை செல்லும் பேருந்தில் 1,190 ரூபா பெறுமதியான 9 டிக்கெட்டுகளும், தங்காலையில் இருந்து அம்பிலிபிட்டிய செல்லும் பேருந்தில் 5 டிக்கெட்டுகளும் வழங்கப்படவில்லை என அந்த அதிகாரி தெரிவித்தார். பேருந்து நடத்துனர்களுக்கு எதிராக சட்ட நடவடிக்கை எடுக்கப்பட்டு வருவதாகவும் அவர் குறிப்பிட்டுள்ளார்.",
        "இலங்கை போக்குவரத்து சபையின் பிரதம நடமாடும் பரிசோதகர் திரு.வொஷிங்டன் ராஜபக்ஷ தலைமையிலான குழுவினர் இந்த நடவடிக்கையை மேற்கொண்டனர்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "3",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை போக்குவரத்து சபை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "மூன்று",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை போக்குவரத்து சபை",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "மூன்று",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "இரண்டு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "மொனராகலை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "மகும்புரா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "காலி",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "கடவட",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "2,190",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "மொனராகலை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "மகும்புரா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "9",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "1,190",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "காலி",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "கடவட",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "5",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "தங்கல்லை",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "வாஷிங்டன் ராஜபக்சே",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை போக்குவரத்து சபை",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}