{
  "newspaper_id": "news-first-lk",
  "url": "https://www.newsfirst.lk/2022/07/25/droupadi-murmu-takes-oath-as-india-s-15th-president/",
  "time_ut": 1658731920,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Droupadi Murmu takes oath as India’s 15th President",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Droupadi Murmu takes oath as India’s 15th President",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "Droupadi Murmu took oath as the 15th President of India today, as she became the first tribal woman to hold the highest constitutional post in the country.",
        "Indian Chief Justice of India N V Ramana administered the oath to Murmu in the presence of Prime Minister Narendra Modi, Union Ministers Rajnath Singh, S Jaishankar, Amit Shah, among others.",
        "ddressing the nation after being sworn in as the 15th President of India, Droupadi Murmu Monday stated that she was honoured to take charge at a time India is completing 75 years of Independence. She added that she’s the first President to be born in independent India.",
        "Following her swearing-in ceremony, President Droupadi Murmu took charge of her responsibilities from former president Ram Nath Kovind at the Rashtrapati Bhavan.",
        "Three men nabbed while trying to sell loot from President’s Office"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Droupadi Murmu",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "India",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "15th",
          "label": "ORDINAL"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Droupadi Murmu",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "15th",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "India",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "first",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Indian",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Justice of India",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Murmu",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Narendra Modi",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "S Jaishankar",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "15th",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "India",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Monday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "India",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "75 years",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Independence",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "first",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "India",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Droupadi Murmu",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ram Nath Kovind",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Three",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "Droupadi Murmu ඉන්දියාවේ 15 වැනි ජනාධිපතිවරයා ලෙස දිවුරුම් දෙයි",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "ඉන්දියාවේ 15 වැනි ජනාධිපතිනිය ලෙස ද්‍රෞපදී මුර්මු අද දිවුරුම් දුන්නේ ඇය රටේ ඉහළම ව්‍යවස්ථාපිත තනතුර දැරූ පළමු ගෝත්‍රික කාන්තාව බවට පත් වෙමිනි.",
        "ඉන්දීය අග්‍රාමාත්‍ය නරේන්ද්‍ර මෝදි, මධ්‍යම අමාත්‍යවරුන් වන රාජ්නාත් සිං, එස් ජයශංකර්, අමිත් ෂා ඇතුළු පිරිසක් ඉදිරියේ ඉන්දීය අගවිනිසුරු එන් වී රාමනා මුර්මුට දිවුරුම් දුන්නේය.",
        "ඉන්දියාවේ 15 වැනි ජනාධිපතිවරයා ලෙස දිවුරුම් දීමෙන් අනතුරුව ජාතිය අමතමින් ද්‍රෞපදී මුර්මු සඳුදා ප්‍රකාශ කළේ ඉන්දියාව නිදහස ලබා වසර 75ක් සම්පූර්ණ වන අවස්ථාවක එම ධුරයේ කටයුතු කිරීමට ලැබීම තමාට ගෞරවයක් බවයි. නිදහස් ඉන්දියාවේ උපත ලැබූ පළමු ජනාධිපතිවරයා ඇය බවද ඇය පැවසුවාය.",
        "ඇයගේ දිවුරුම් දීමේ උත්සවයෙන් පසුව, ජනාධිපති Droupadi Murmu, Rashtrapati Bhavan හි හිටපු ජනාධිපති රාම් නාත් කෝවින්ද්ගෙන් ඇයගේ වගකීම් භාර ගත්තාය.",
        "ජනාධිපති කාර්යාලයෙන් කොල්ලකෑමට ගිය තිදෙනෙකු මාට්ටු"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ද්‍රෞපදී මුර්මු",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "ඉන්දියාව",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "15 වැනි",
          "label": "ORDINAL"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ද්‍රෞපදී මුර්මු",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "15 වැනි",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "පළමුවන",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දීය",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දියාවේ විනිසුරු",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "මුර්මු",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "නරේන්ද්‍ර මෝදි",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "එස් ජයශංකර්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "15 වැනි",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "සඳුදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "අවුරුදු 75 යි",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "නිදහස",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "පළමුවන",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ද්‍රෞපදී මුර්මු",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "රාම් නාත් කෝවින්ද්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "තුන්",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "இந்தியாவின் 15வது ஜனாதிபதியாக திரௌபதி முர்மு பதவியேற்றார்",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "இந்தியாவின் 15வது குடியரசுத் தலைவராக திரௌபதி முர்மு இன்று பதவியேற்றார், நாட்டின் மிக உயரிய அரசியலமைப்புப் பதவியை வகிக்கும் முதல் பழங்குடிப் பெண் என்ற பெருமையைப் பெற்றார்.",
        "பிரதமர் நரேந்திர மோடி, மத்திய அமைச்சர்கள் ராஜ்நாத் சிங், எஸ் ஜெய்சங்கர், அமித் ஷா உள்ளிட்டோர் முன்னிலையில் இந்திய தலைமை நீதிபதி என்வி ரமணா முர்முவுக்கு பதவிப் பிரமாணம் செய்து வைத்தார்.",
        "இந்தியாவின் 15வது ஜனாதிபதியாக பதவியேற்ற பின்னர் நாட்டு மக்களுக்கு உரையாற்றிய திரௌபதி முர்மு திங்கள்கிழமை, இந்தியா சுதந்திரம் அடைந்து 75 ஆண்டுகள் நிறைவடையும் இவ்வேளையில் பொறுப்பேற்றதை பெருமையாக கருதுவதாக தெரிவித்தார். சுதந்திர இந்தியாவில் பிறந்த முதல் குடியரசுத் தலைவர் அவர் என்றும் அவர் கூறினார்.",
        "பதவியேற்பு விழாவைத் தொடர்ந்து, குடியரசுத் தலைவர் திரௌபதி முர்மு, ராஷ்டிரபதி பவனில் முன்னாள் குடியரசுத் தலைவர் ராம்நாத் கோவிந்திடம் இருந்து தனது பொறுப்புகளை ஏற்றுக்கொண்டார்.",
        "ஜனாதிபதி அலுவலகத்தில் கொள்ளையடிக்க முயன்ற மூவர் கைது செய்யப்பட்டுள்ளனர்"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "திரௌபதி முர்மு",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "இந்தியா",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "15வது",
          "label": "ORDINAL"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "திரௌபதி முர்மு",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "15வது",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்தியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "முதலில்",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இந்தியன்",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்திய நீதியரசர்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "முர்மு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "நரேந்திர மோடி",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "எஸ் ஜெய்சங்கர்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "15வது",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்தியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "திங்கட்கிழமை",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்தியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "75 ஆண்டுகள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சுதந்திரம்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "முதலில்",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்தியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "திரௌபதி முர்மு",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ராம் நாத் கோவிந்த்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "மூன்று",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}