{
  "newspaper_id": "economy-next-com",
  "url": "https://economynext.com/sri-lanka-podujana-peramuna-dullas-group-to-be-independent-99244/",
  "time_ut": 1661920800,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Sri Lanka Podujana Peramuna Dullas group to be independent",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Sri Lanka Podujana Peramuna Dullas group to be independent",
      "author": "",
      "body_lines": [
        "ECONOMYNEXT – Several legislators representing the ruling Sri Lanka Podujana Peramuna (SLPP) who had been functioning independently in parliament have now officially crossed over to the opposition.",
        "The MPs are former Foreign Minister and SLPP chairman G L Peiris, Matara district MP Dullas Alahapperuma who ran for president against incumbent President Ranil Wickremesinghe, former chairman of the Committee on Public Enterprises (COPE) Charitha Herath, former State Minister Channa Jayasumana,  former minister Nalaka Godahewa, and MPs Gunapala Rathnasekara, Upul Galappaththi, Thilak Rajapakse, Dilan Perera, Udayana Kirindigoda, Wasantha Yapa Bandara and K P S Kumarasiri.",
        "Announcing the decision, MP Peiris told parliament on Wednesday August 31 that the group the SLPP’s policies, which secured a two-thirds mandate in parliament in 2020, were no longer being carried out.",
        "Peiris also called for a parliamentary election at the end of an interim administration, adding that the absence of elections was undemocratic.",
        "“Universal franchise is the means of practically exercising people’s sovereignty. No one can take that away from the public. After a programme for an interim period, we must allow the people to elect a new parliament,” said Peiris.(Colombo/Aug31/2022)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Podujana Peramuna Dullas",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "Podujana Peramuna",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "SLPP",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "G L Peiris",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Matara",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Dullas Alahapperuma",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Committee on Public Enterprises",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Charitha Herath",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "State",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Channa Jayasumana",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Nalaka Godahewa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Gunapala Rathnasekara",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Upul Galappaththi",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Thilak Rajapakse",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Dilan Perera",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Udayana Kirindigoda",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Wasantha Yapa Bandara",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "K P S Kumarasiri",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Peiris",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Wednesday August 31",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "two-thirds",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "2020",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Peiris",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        []
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "ශ්‍රී ලංකා පොදුජන පෙරමුණ ඩලස් කණ්ඩායම ස්වාධීන වෙයි",
      "author": "",
      "body_lines": [
        "ආර්ථිකය - පාර්ලිමේන්තුවේ ස්වාධීනව කටයුතු කළ පාලක ශ්‍රී ලංකා පොදුජන පෙරමුණ (SLPP) නියෝජනය කරන නීති සම්පාදකයින් කිහිප දෙනෙකු මේ වන විට නිල වශයෙන් විපක්ෂයට ගොස් තිබේ.",
        "එම මන්ත්‍රීවරුන් වන්නේ හිටපු විදේශ අමාත්‍ය සහ ශ්‍රී ලංකා පොදුජන පෙරමුණේ සභාපති ජී එල් පීරිස්, වත්මන් ජනාධිපති රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහට එරෙහිව ජනාධිපතිවරණයට ඉදිරිපත් වූ මාතර දිස්ත්‍රික් පාර්ලිමේන්තු මන්ත්‍රී ඩලස් අලහප්පෙරුම, පොදු ව්‍යාපාර පිළිබඳ කාරක සභාවේ (කෝප්) හිටපු සභාපති චරිත හේරත්, හිටපු රාජ්‍ය අමාත්‍ය චන්න ජයසුමන, හිටපු අමාත්‍ය නාලක ය. ගොඩහේවා, සහ පාර්ලිමේන්තු මන්ත්‍රීවරුන් වන ගුණපාල රත්නසේකර, උපුල් ගලප්පත්ති, තිලක් රාජපක්ෂ, ඩිලාන් පෙරේරා, උදයන කිරිඳිගොඩ, වසන්ත යාපා බණ්ඩාර සහ කේ.පී.එස්. කුමාරසිරි.",
        "මෙම තීරණය ප්‍රකාශයට පත් කරමින් පාර්ලිමේන්තු මන්ත්‍රී පීරිස් අගෝස්තු 31 බදාදා පාර්ලිමේන්තුවට පැවසුවේ 2020 දී පාර්ලිමේන්තුවේ තුනෙන් දෙකක ජනවරමක් ලබාගත් ශ්‍රී ලංකා පොදුජන පෙරමුණේ ප්‍රතිපත්ති කණ්ඩායම තවදුරටත් ක්‍රියාත්මක නොකරන බවයි.",
        "අතුරු පාලනයක් අවසානයේ පාර්ලිමේන්තු මැතිවරණයක් පැවැත්විය යුතු බව ද පීරිස් කියා සිටියේ මැතිවරණ නොපැවැත්වීම ප්‍රජාතන්ත්‍ර විරෝධී බවයි.",
        "“විශ්ව ඡන්ද බලය යනු ජනතා පරමාධිපත්‍යය ප්‍රායෝගිකව ක්‍රියාත්මක කිරීමේ මාධ්‍යයයි. ඒක මහජනතාවගෙන් උදුරා ගන්න කාටවත් බෑ. අතුරු කාලසීමාවක් සඳහා වූ වැඩපිළිවෙළකින් පසු නව පාර්ලිමේන්තුවක් තෝරා පත් කර ගැනීමට අපි ජනතාවට ඉඩ දිය යුතුයි.” පීරිස් මහතා පැවසීය."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "පොදුජන පෙරමුණ ඩලස්",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "පොදුජන පෙරමුණ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "SLPP",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජී එල් පීරිස්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "මාතර",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඩලස් අලහප්පෙරුම",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "පොදු ව්‍යාපාර පිළිබඳ කාරක සභාව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "චරිත හේරත්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "රජයේ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "චන්න ජයසුමන",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "නාලක ගොඩහේවා",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගුණපාල රත්නසේකර",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "උපුල් ගලප්පත්ති",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "තිලක් රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඩිලාන් පෙරේරා",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "උදයන කිරිඳිගොඩ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "වසන්ත යාපා බණ්ඩාර",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "කේ පී එස් කුමාරසිරි",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "පීරිස්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "අගෝස්තු 31 බදාදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "තුනෙන් දෙකක්",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "2020",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "පීරිස්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        []
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "ஸ்ரீலங்கா பொதுஜன பெரமுன டலஸ் குழு சுயேட்சை",
      "author": "",
      "body_lines": [
        "பொருளாதாரம் – பாராளுமன்றத்தில் சுதந்திரமாக செயற்பட்டு வந்த ஆளும் ஸ்ரீலங்கா பொதுஜன பெரமுனவை (SLPP) பிரதிநிதித்துவப்படுத்தும் பல சட்டமன்ற உறுப்பினர்கள் தற்போது உத்தியோகபூர்வமாக எதிர்க்கட்சிக்கு சென்றுள்ளனர்.",
        "முன்னாள் வெளிவிவகார அமைச்சரும் ஸ்ரீலங்கா பொதுஜன பெரமுனவின் தலைவருமான ஜி.எல்.பீரிஸ், தற்போதைய ஜனாதிபதி ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்கவுக்கு எதிராக ஜனாதிபதி தேர்தலில் போட்டியிட்ட மாத்தறை மாவட்ட பாராளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர் டலஸ் அழகப்பெரும, பொது நிறுவனங்கள் தொடர்பான குழுவின் (கோப்) முன்னாள் தலைவர் சரித ஹேரத், முன்னாள் இராஜாங்க அமைச்சர் சன்ன ஜயசுமன,  முன்னாள் அமைச்சர் நாலக ஆகியோர் எம்.பி.க்கள் ஆவர். கொடஹேவா, மற்றும் பாராளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர்களான குணபால ரத்னசேகர, உபுல் கலப்பத்தி, திலக் ராஜபக்ஷ, டிலான் பெரேரா, உதயண கிரிந்திகொட, வசந்த யாப்பா பண்டார மற்றும் கே.பி.எஸ் குமாரசிறி ஆகியோர் கலந்துகொண்டனர்.",
        "முடிவை அறிவித்த பாராளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர் பீரிஸ், 2020 ஆம் ஆண்டு பாராளுமன்றத்தில் மூன்றில் இரண்டு பங்கைப் பெற்ற SLPP இன் கொள்கைகள் இனிமேலும் நிறைவேற்றப்படவில்லை என்று ஆகஸ்ட் 31 புதன்கிழமை பாராளுமன்றத்தில் தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "பீரிஸ் இடைக்கால நிர்வாகத்தின் முடிவில் பாராளுமன்றத் தேர்தலுக்கு அழைப்பு விடுத்தார், தேர்தல்கள் இல்லாதது ஜனநாயக விரோதமானது என்றும் கூறினார்.",
        "“உலகளாவிய உரிமை என்பது நடைமுறையில் மக்களின் இறையாண்மையைப் பயன்படுத்துவதற்கான வழிமுறையாகும். இதை மக்களிடம் இருந்து யாரும் பறிக்க முடியாது. ஒரு இடைக்கால வேலைத்திட்டத்தின் பின்னர், புதிய பாராளுமன்றத்தை தெரிவு செய்வதற்கு மக்களை அனுமதிக்க வேண்டும்” என பீரிஸ் கூறினார்.(கொழும்பு/ஆகஸ்ட்31/2022)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "பொதுஜன பெரமுன டலஸ்",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "பொதுஜன பெரமுன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "எஸ்.எல்.பி.பி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜி எல் பீரிஸ்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "மாத்தறை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "டலஸ் அழகப்பெரும",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "பொது நிறுவனங்களுக்கான குழு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "சரித ஹேரத்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "நிலை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "சன்ன ஜெயசுமண",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "நாலக கொடஹேவா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "குணபால ரத்னசேகர",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "உபுல் கலப்பத்தி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "திலக் ராஜபக்ஷ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "திலான் பெரேரா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "உதயன கிரிந்திகொட",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "வசந்த யாப்பா பண்டார",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "கே பி எஸ் குமாரசிறி",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பீரிஸ்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆகஸ்ட் 31 புதன்கிழமை",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "மூன்றில் இரண்டு பங்கு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "2020",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பீரிஸ்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        []
      ]
    }
  }
}