{
  "newspaper_id": "ada-derana-lk",
  "url": "http://www.adaderana.lk/news/84516/caa-continues-raids-on-vendors-selling-eggs-at-higher-prices",
  "time_ut": 1661344740,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "CAA continues raids on vendors selling eggs at higher prices",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "CAA continues raids on vendors selling eggs at higher prices",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "The Consumer Affairs Authority (CAA) has initiated raids in search of the vendors selling eggs beyond the maximum retail price.",
        "The officials said that the raids, which were carried out in several areas of the country yesterday (23), were continued today (24) as well.",
        "Six such places where eggs were sold at prices exceeding the maximum retail price have been identified in the Gampaha District, according to the officers of the Gampaha District Consumer Affairs Authority.",
        "The apprehensions were made in the areas of Udugampola and Negombo.",
        "Further, it is reported that 10 shops that have been selling eggs at high prices were sued during the raids conducted in the Balangoda and Kahawatta areas. Among these was a shop attached to Balangoda cooperative service.",
        "Associations of egg producers claimed that due to the high cost of production, they are unable to sell eggs at the price rates stipulated by the government.",
        "Meanwhile, the members of the All-Ceylon Egg Producers’ Association met Opposition Leader Sajith Premadasa this morning (24) to discuss the problems they are facing at the moment due to the new price controls.",
        "They have informed the opposition leader that they find it difficult to sell eggs at the maximum retail prices announced in a recent gazette."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "The Consumer Affairs Authority",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "yesterday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "23",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "24",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Six",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Gampaha District",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Gampaha District Consumer Affairs Authority",
            "label": "FAC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Udugampola",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Negombo",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "10",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Balangoda",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kahawatta",
            "label": "LOC"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "the All-Ceylon Egg Producers’ Association met Opposition",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sajith Premadasa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "this morning",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "24",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        []
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "වැඩි මිලට බිත්තර අලෙවි කරන වෙළෙන්දන් වෙත CAA වැටලීම් දිගටම කරගෙන යයි",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "උපරිම සිල්ලර මිලට වඩා බිත්තර අලෙවි කරන වෙළෙඳුන් සොයා පාරිභෝගික කටයුතු පිළිබඳ අධිකාරිය වැටලීම් ආරම්භ කර තිබේ.",
        "ඊයේ (23) දිවයිනේ ප්‍රදේශ කිහිපයක සිදු කළ වැටලීම් අද (24) දින ද අඛණ්ඩව ක්‍රියාත්මක කළ බව එම නිලධාරීහු පැවසූහ.",
        "ගම්පහ දිස්ත්‍රික්කයේ එවැනි උපරිම සිල්ලර මිලට වඩා වැඩි මිලට බිත්තර අලෙවි කළ ස්ථාන 6ක් හඳුනාගෙන ඇති බව ගම්පහ දිස්ත්‍රික් පාරිභෝගික සේවා අධිකාරියේ නිලධාරීහු පවසති.",
        "උඩුගම්පොල සහ මීගමුව යන ප්‍රදේශවලදී මෙම අත්අඩංගුවට ගැනීම් සිදු කර ඇත.",
        "තවද බලංගොඩ සහ කහවත්ත ප්‍රදේශවල සිදුකළ වැටලීම්වලදී අධික මිලට බිත්තර අලෙවි කළ වෙළෙඳසැල් 10කට එරෙහිව නඩු පවරා ඇති බවද වාර්තා වේ. මේ අතර බලංගොඩ සමුපකාර සේවයට අනුබද්ධ වෙළෙඳසලක් ද විය.",
        "නිෂ්පාදන පිරිවැය අධික වීම හේතුවෙන් රජය විසින් නියම කර ඇති මිලට බිත්තර අලෙවි කිරීමට නොහැකි වී ඇති බව බිත්තර නිෂ්පාදකයින්ගේ සංගම් ප්‍රකාශ කළා.",
        "මේ අතර, නව මිල පාලනය හේතුවෙන් මේ වන විට තමන් මුහුණ දී සිටින ගැටලු පිළිබඳව සාකච්ඡා කිරීම සඳහා සමස්ත ලංකා බිත්තර නිෂ්පාදකයින්ගේ සංගමයේ සාමාජිකයින් අද (24) පෙරවරුවේ විපක්ෂ නායක සජිත් ප්‍රේමදාස මහතා හමුවිය.",
        "පසුගියදා ගැසට් මගින් ප්‍රකාශයට පත් කරන ලද උපරිම සිල්ලර මිලට බිත්තර අලෙවි කිරීමට අපහසු බව ඔවුන් විපක්ෂ නායකවරයාට දන්වා ඇත."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "පාරිභෝගික කටයුතු අධිකාරිය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ඊයේ",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "23",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "24",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "හය",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගම්පහ දිස්ත්‍රික්කය",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගම්පහ දිස්ත්‍රික් පාරිභෝගික සේවා අධිකාරිය",
            "label": "FAC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "උඩුගම්පොල",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "මීගමුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "10",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "බලන්ගොඩ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "කහවත්ත",
            "label": "LOC"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "සමස්ත ලංකා බිත්තර නිෂ්පාදකයින්ගේ සංගමය විරෝධය දැක්වීය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "සජිත් ප්‍රේමදාස",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "මේ උදෑසන",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "24",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        []
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "அதிக விலைக்கு முட்டை விற்கும் விற்பனையாளர்கள் மீது CAA தொடர்ந்து சோதனை நடத்தி வருகிறது",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "அதிகபட்ச சில்லறை விலைக்கு மேல் முட்டைகளை விற்பனை செய்யும் விற்பனையாளர்களை தேடி நுகர்வோர் விவகார ஆணையம் (சிஏஏ) சோதனையை தொடங்கியுள்ளது.",
        "நேற்று (23) நாட்டின் பல பகுதிகளில் மேற்கொள்ளப்பட்ட இந்த சோதனை நடவடிக்கைகள் இன்றும் (24) தொடர்ந்ததாக அதிகாரிகள் தெரிவித்தனர்.",
        "கம்பஹா மாவட்டத்தில் அதிகபட்ச சில்லறை விலையை விட அதிக விலைக்கு முட்டைகள் விற்பனை செய்யப்பட்ட ஆறு இடங்கள் அடையாளம் காணப்பட்டுள்ளதாக கம்பஹா மாவட்ட நுகர்வோர் அதிகார சபையின் அதிகாரிகள் தெரிவித்துள்ளனர்.",
        "உடுகம்பொல மற்றும் நீர்கொழும்பு ஆகிய பகுதிகளில் இந்த அச்சம் ஏற்பட்டுள்ளது.",
        "மேலும், பலாங்கொடை மற்றும் கஹவத்தை பிரதேசங்களில் மேற்கொள்ளப்பட்ட சுற்றிவளைப்பின் போது அதிக விலைக்கு முட்டை விற்பனை செய்த 10 கடைகளுக்கு எதிராக வழக்குத் தாக்கல் செய்யப்பட்டுள்ளதாக தெரிவிக்கப்படுகின்றது. இவற்றில் பலாங்கொடை கூட்டுறவு சேவையுடன் இணைந்த கடை ஒன்றும் இருந்தது.",
        "உற்பத்தி செலவு அதிகமாக உள்ளதால், அரசு நிர்ணயித்த விலைக்கு முட்டையை விற்க முடியவில்லை என முட்டை உற்பத்தியாளர்கள் சங்கத்தினர் தெரிவித்தனர்.",
        "இதேவேளை, புதிய விலைக் கட்டுப்பாட்டினால் தாம் எதிர்நோக்கும் பிரச்சினைகள் தொடர்பில் கலந்துரையாடுவதற்காக அகில இலங்கை முட்டை உற்பத்தியாளர் சங்க உறுப்பினர்கள் இன்று (24) காலை எதிர்க்கட்சித் தலைவர் சஜித் பிரேமதாசவைச் சந்தித்துள்ளனர்.",
        "அண்மையில் வர்த்தமானியில் அறிவிக்கப்பட்ட அதிகபட்ச சில்லறை விலையில் முட்டையை விற்பனை செய்வதில் சிரமம் இருப்பதாக எதிர்க்கட்சித் தலைவரிடம் தெரிவித்துள்ளனர்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "நுகர்வோர் விவகார ஆணையம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "நேற்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "23",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "24",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஆறு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "கம்பஹா மாவட்டம்",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "கம்பஹா மாவட்ட நுகர்வோர் விவகார அதிகாரசபை",
            "label": "FAC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "உடுகம்பொல",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "நீர்கொழும்பு",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "10",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "பலாங்கொடை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "கஹவத்த",
            "label": "LOC"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "அகில இலங்கை முட்டை உற்பத்தியாளர்கள் சங்கம் எதிர்ப்பை சந்தித்தது",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "சஜித் பிரேமதாச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று காலை",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "24",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        []
      ]
    }
  }
}