{
  "newspaper_id": "virakesari-lk",
  "url": "http://www.virakesari.lk/article/131776",
  "time_ut": 1658238157,
  "original_lang": "ta",
  "original_title": "மும்முனைப் போட்டி ! வெல்லப்போவது யார் ? இடைக்கால ஜனாதிபதி தெரிவிற்கான வாக்கெடுப்பு இன்று",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Three-way competition! Who will win? Voting for the interim president is today",
      "author": "T. Saranya",
      "body_lines": [
        "Ranil Wickramasinghe, Dallas Alagaperuma and Anura Kumara Dissanayake are going to contest for the vacant post of President.",
        "Leader of Opposition Sajith Premadasa proposed the name of Dulles Alagaperuma, which was confirmed by Podujana Peramuna's General Secretary GL Peiris.",
        "The parliamentary session was convened on Tuesday under the chairmanship of Speaker Mahinda Yappa Abeywardhana.",
        "Speaker Mahinda Yappa Abeywardena informed the House that the Parliamentary Secretary General will proceed from the responsibility of the Electoral Officer to the Constitution to elect a new President for the vacant position of President announced to the House on Saturday 16th July.",
        "Parliamentary Secretary General Tammika Dasanayake's Special Statement According to Article 06 of Presidential Election (Special Provisions) Article No. 02 of 1981, all members shall rise from their seats and call upon the Parliamentary Secretary (Visual Officer) to nominate the name of a candidate for the vacant presidential seat and second him. .",
        "A nominated member must first obtain consent to serve in the presidency.",
        "A copy of the same should be handed over to me.",
        "Opposition leader Sajith Premadasa, who presented the nomination first, said 'I recommend Dulles Alagaperuma to be nominated for the new presidency of the Democratic Socialist Republic of Sri Lanka'.",
        "During this, the General Secretary of the Podujana Peramuna Professor G. L. Peiris said 'I confirm the name of Dulles Alagaperuma nominated in the nomination for the new President'.",
        "Secondly, Chief Minister Dinesh Gunawardena said 'I am recommending the name of Ranil Wickramasinghe to elect the new president'.",
        "During this, the opposite party shouted. The main duty is being fulfilled, so the Speaker insisted that everyone should act calmly in the House.",
        "Thirdly, Vijitha Herath said, \"I recommend the leader of the People's Liberation Front, Anura Kumara Dissanayake, for the election of the new president.\"",
        "The Visibility Officer mentioned that there is an opportunity to suggest names of members. As no other name has been recommended, the Secretary General of the Parliament said that he would like to inform the House that the receiving of nominations through the Parliament for the position of Interim President for the posts mentioned in Article No. 02 of 1981 Presidential Selection (Special Arrangements) has been completed.",
        "I also inform the House that I accept the nominations of Member of Parliament Dalus Alagaperuma, Member of Parliament Ranil Wickramasinghe and Member of Parliament Anura Kumara Dissanayake.",
        "02 Presidential Election (Special Provisions) of 1981 as per articles 4 and 6, except for one member has been nominated and confirmed for the currently vacant position of the President, and as the date and time of the election must be notified to the House in accordance with Sections 2 and 3 of the Act, the meeting of the Parliamentary Party Leaders, and The Secretary General of the Parliament announced that the Parliament will convene tomorrow (today) at 10.00 a.m. for the decision taken in the Parliamentary Affairs Committee meeting on the 11th."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Three",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "today",
          "label": "DATE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickramasinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Dallas Alagaperuma",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Anura",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kumara Dissanayake",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Opposition Sajith Premadasa",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Dulles Alagaperuma",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Podujana Peramuna's",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "GL Peiris",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Tuesday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Mahinda Yappa Abeywardhana",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Mahinda Yappa Abeywardena",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "House",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Constitution",
            "label": "LAW"
          },
          {
            "text": "House",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Saturday 16th July",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Tammika Dasanayake's",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Article 06 of Presidential Election (Special Provisions",
            "label": "LAW"
          },
          {
            "text": "Article No. 02 of 1981",
            "label": "LAW"
          },
          {
            "text": "second",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "first",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sajith Premadasa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "first",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Dulles Alagaperuma",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Democratic Socialist Republic of Sri Lanka'",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "G. L. Peiris",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Dulles Alagaperuma",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Secondly",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Dinesh Gunawardena",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickramasinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "House",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Vijitha Herath",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the People's Liberation Front",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kumara Dissanayake",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "House",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Article No. 02 of 1981",
            "label": "LAW"
          },
          {
            "text": "Presidential Selection (Special Arrangements",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "House",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament Dalus Alagaperuma",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament Ranil Wickramasinghe",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kumara Dissanayake",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "02",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "1981",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "4",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "one",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "House",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sections 2 and 3 of the Act",
            "label": "LAW"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Parliamentary Party Leaders",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "tomorrow",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "10.00 a.m.",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Parliamentary Affairs Committee",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the 11th",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "තුන්කොන් තරඟයක්! කවුරු දිනයිද? අන්තර්වාර ජනාධිපතිවරයා සඳහා වන ඡන්ද විමසීම අදයි",
      "author": "T. Saranya",
      "body_lines": [
        "පුරප්පාඩු වූ ජනාධිපති ධූරයට රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ, ඩලස් අලගපෙරුම සහ අනුර කුමාර දිසානායක තරඟ වැදීමට නියමිතයි.",
        "විපක්ෂ නායක සජිත් ප්‍රේමදාස මහතා විසින් ඩලස් අලගපෙරුම මහතාගේ නම යෝජනා කළ අතර එය ස්ථිර කළේ පොදුජන පෙරමුණේ ප්‍රධාන ලේකම් ජී.එල්.",
        "කථානායක මහින්ද යාප්පා අබේවර්ධන මහතාගේ ප්‍රධානත්වයෙන් පාර්ලිමේන්තු සැසිවාරය අඟහරුවාදා කැදවා තිබුණි.",
        "ජූලි 16 වැනි සෙනසුරාදා සභාවට ප්‍රකාශයට පත් කළ පුරප්පාඩු වූ ජනාධිපති ධුරය සඳහා නව ජනාධිපතිවරයකු තෝරා පත් කර ගැනීම සඳහා පාර්ලිමේන්තු මහලේකම්වරයා මැතිවරණ නිලධාරියාගේ වගකීමෙන් ආණ්ඩුක්‍රම ව්‍යවස්ථාව දක්වා කටයුතු කරන බව කථානායක මහින්ද යාප්පා අබේවර්ධන මහතා සභාවට දැනුම් දුන්නේය.",
        "පාර්ලිමේන්තු මහලේකම් තම්මික දසනායකගේ විශේෂ ප්‍රකාශය 1981 අංක 02 දරන ජනාධිපතිවරණ (විශේෂ විධිවිධාන) වගන්තියේ 06 වැනි වගන්තිය අනුව සියලුම මන්ත්‍රීවරුන් තම අසුන්වලින් නැගිට පාර්ලිමේන්තු ලේකම් (දෘශ්‍ය නිලධාරි) ගෙන් අපේක්ෂකයකුගේ නම නම් කළ යුතුය. පුරප්පාඩු වූ ජනාධිපති අසුන සහ ඔහු දෙවනුව.",
        "නම් කරන ලද සාමාජිකයෙකු ජනාධිපති ධුරයේ කටයුතු කිරීමට පළමුව කැමැත්ත ලබා ගත යුතුය.",
        "එහි පිටපතක් මා වෙත භාර දිය යුතුය.",
        "මුලින්ම නාමයෝජනා ඉදිරිපත් කළ විපක්ෂ නායක සජිත් ප්‍රේමදාස මහතා පැවසුවේ ‘ශ්‍රී ලංකා ප්‍රජාතාන්ත්‍රික සමාජවාදී ජනරජයේ නව ජනාධිපති ධුරයට ඩලස් අලගපෙරුම මහතා නම් කරන ලෙස මම නිර්දේශ කරමි’ යනුවෙනි.",
        "මේ අතරවාරයේ පොදුජන පෙරමුණේ ප්‍රධාන ලේකම් මහාචාර්ය ජී.එල්.පීරිස් මහතා ප්‍රකාශ කළේ ‘නව ජනාධිපතිවරයාට නාමයෝජනා දී ඇති ඩලස් අලගපෙරුම මහතාගේ නම මම තහවුරු කරනවා’ යනුවෙනි.",
        "දෙවනුව ප්‍රධාන අමාත්‍ය දිනේෂ් ගුණවර්ධන මහතා පැවසුවේ ‘නව ජනාධිපතිවරයා තෝරා ගැනීමට මම රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතාගේ නම නිර්දේශ කරනවා’ යනුවෙනි.",
        "මේ අතරතුර ප්‍රතිවිරුද්ධ පාර්ශ්වය කෑ ගැසුවේය.ප්‍රධාන රාජකාරිය ඉටුවෙමින් පවතින බැවින් සියලු දෙනාම සන්සුන්ව සභාව තුළ කටයුතු කළ යුතු බව කථානායකවරයා අවධාරණය කළේය.",
        "තෙවනුව විජිත හේරත් කීවේ “නව ජනාධිපතිවරයා තෝරා පත් කර ගැනීම සඳහා මම නිර්දේශ කරන්නේ මහජන විමුක්ති පෙරමුණේ නායක අනුර කුමාර දිසානායක” යනුවෙනි.",
        "සාමාජිකයින්ගේ නම් යෝජනා කිරීමට අවස්ථාව පවතින බව දෘෂ්‍යතා නිලධාරියා සඳහන් කළේය. වෙනත් නමක් නිර්දේශ වී නොමැති බැවින් 1981 ජනාධිපති තේරීම් අංක 02 වගන්තියේ සඳහන් තනතුරු සඳහා අන්තර්වාර ජනාධිපති ධුරය සඳහා පාර්ලිමේන්තුව හරහා නාමයෝජනා භාර ගැනීම සභාවට දන්වන බව පාර්ලිමේන්තු මහලේකම්වරයා පැවසීය. (විශේෂ කටයුතු) අවසන් කර ඇත.",
        "පාර්ලිමේන්තු මන්ත්‍රී ඩලස් අලගපෙරුම, පාර්ලිමේන්තු මන්ත්‍රී රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ සහ පාර්ලිමේන්තු මන්ත්‍රී අනුර කුමාර දිසානායක යන මහත්වරුන්ගේ නාමයෝජනා මා පිළිගන්නා බවද සභාවට දන්වා සිටිමි.",
        "02 1981 ජනාධිපතිවරණය (විශේෂ විධිවිධාන) 4 සහ 6 වගන්තිවලට අනුව දැනට පුරප්පාඩු වී ඇති ජනාධිපති ධුරය සඳහා එක් මන්ත්‍රීවරයකු හැර නම් කර ස්ථිර කර ඇති අතර මැතිවරණය පැවැත්වෙන දිනය සහ වේලාව සභාවට දැනුම් දිය යුතුය. පනතේ 2 සහ 3 වගන්තිවලට අනුව පාර්ලිමේන්තු කටයුතු පිළිබඳ කාරක සභා රැස්වීමේදී ගන්නා තීරණය සඳහා පාර්ලිමේන්තුව හෙට (අද) පෙරවරු 10.00 ට රැස්වන බව පාර්ලිමේන්තු පක්ෂ නායක රැස්වීමේදී සහ පාර්ලිමේන්තු මහලේකම්වරයා නිවේදනය කළේය. 11 වැනි."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "තුන්",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "අද",
          "label": "DATE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඩලස් අලගපෙරුම",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "අනුර",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "කුමාර දිසානායක",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "විපක්ෂයේ සජිත් ප්‍රේමදාස",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඩලස් අලගපෙරුම",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "පොදුජන පෙරමුණේ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජී එල් පීරිස්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "අඟහරුවාදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මහින්ද යාප්පා අබේවර්ධන",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "මහින්ද යාප්පා අබේවර්ධන",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "නිවස",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ආණ්ඩුක්රම ව්යවස්ථාව",
            "label": "LAW"
          },
          {
            "text": "නිවස",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජූලි 16 සෙනසුරාදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "තම්මික දසනායකගේ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජනාධිපතිවරණයේ 06 වැනි වගන්තිය (විශේෂ විධිවිධාන",
            "label": "LAW"
          },
          {
            "text": "1981 අංක 02 වගන්තිය",
            "label": "LAW"
          },
          {
            "text": "දෙවැනි",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "පළමුවන",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "සජිත් ප්‍රේමදාස",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "පළමුවන",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඩලස් අලගපෙරුම",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකා ප්‍රජාතන්ත්‍රවාදී සමාජවාදී ජනරජය'",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ජී.එල්. පීරිස්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඩලස් අලගපෙරුම",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "දෙවනුව",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "දිනේෂ් ගුණවර්ධන",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "නිවස",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "විජිත හේරත්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "මහජන විමුක්ති පෙරමුණ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "කුමාර දිසානායක",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "නිවස",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "1981 අංක 02 වගන්තිය",
            "label": "LAW"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජනාධිපති තේරීම (විශේෂ විධිවිධාන",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "නිවස",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව දලස් අලගපෙරුම",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "කුමාර දිසානායක",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "02",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "1981",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "4",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "එක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "නිවස",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "පනතේ 2 සහ 3 වගන්ති",
            "label": "LAW"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තු පක්ෂ නායකයින්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "හෙට",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "10.00 පෙ.ව.",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තු කටයුතු කාරක සභාව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "11 වැනි",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "மும்முனைப் போட்டி ! வெல்லப்போவது யார் ? இடைக்கால ஜனாதிபதி தெரிவிற்கான வாக்கெடுப்பு இன்று",
      "author": "T. Saranya",
      "body_lines": [
        "வெற்றிடமாகியுள்ள ஜனாதிபதி  பதவி தெரிவிற்காக ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க, டலஸ் அழகபெரும, அனுர குமார திஸாநாயக்க போட்டியிடவுள்ளார்ககள்.",
        "டலஸ் அழகபெருமவின் பெயரை எதிர்க்கட்சி தலைவர் சஜித் பிரேமதாஸ முன்மொழிய, அதனை  பொதுஜன பெரமுனவின் தவிசாளர் ஜி.எல் பீரிஸ் உறுதிப்படுத்தினார்.",
        "சபாநாயகர் மஹிந்த யாப்பா அபேவர்தன தலைமையில் நேற்று செவ்வாய்க்கிழமை பாராளுமன்ற அமர்வு கூடியது.",
        "ஜூலை மாதம் 16 ஆம் திகதி சனிக்கிழமை சபைக்கு அறிவிக்கப்பட்டதற்கமைய வெற்றிடமாகியுள்ள ஜனாதிபதி பதவிக்கு புதிய ஜனாதிபதியை தெரிவு செய்வதற்கு அரசியமைப்பின் பிரகாரம் வேட்பு மனுக்களை பெற்றுக்கொள்வதை பாராளுமன்ற செயலாளர் நாயகம் தெரிவத்தாட்சி அலுவலரின் பொறுப்பில் இருந்து அரசியலமைப்பிற்கமைய முன்னெடுப்பார் என சபாநாயகர் மஹிந்த யாப்பா அபேவர்தன சபைக்கு அறிவிவித்தார்.",
        "பாராளுமன்ற செயலாளர் நாயகம் தம்மிக தஸநாயக்கவின் விசேட கூற்று 1981ஆம் ஆண்டு 02ஆம் இலக்கம் ஜனாதிபதி தெரிவு (சிறப்பு ஏற்பாடுகள்) உறுப்புரையின் 06 ஆவது உறுப்பின் பிரகாரம் சகல உறுப்பினர்களும் தங்களின் ஆசனங்களில் இருந்து எழுந்து பாராளுமன்ற செயலாளர் நாயகத்தை (தெரிவத்தாட்சி அலுவலர்)அழைத்து வெற்றிடமாகியுள்ள ஜனாதிபதி பதிவிக்கு தற்போது சபைக்கு சமுகமளித்துள்ள ஒருவரின் பெயரை பரிந்துரைத்து,அதனை பிறிதொருவர் உறுதிப்படுத்த வேண்டும்.",
        "பரிந்துரை செய்யப்பட்ட உறுப்பினர் ஜனாதிபதி பதவியில் சேவையாற்ற இணக்கம் என்பதை ஆரம்பத்தில் பெற்றுக்கொள்ள வேண்டும்.",
        "அதன் பிரதி என்னிடம் ஒப்படைக்க வேண்டும்.வேட்பு மனுத்தாக்கலுக்காக தற்போது வாய்ப்பு வழங்கப்படும் என்பதை சபைக்கு தெரிவித்துக்கொள்கிறேன்.",
        "முதலாவதாக பரிந்துரையை முன்வைத்த எதிர்க்கட்சி தலைவர் சஜித் பிரேமதாஸ 'இலங்கை ஜனநாயக சோசலிஷ குடியரசின் புதிய ஜனாதிபதி பதவிக்கான வேட்பு மனுத்தாக்கலுக்கு டலஸ் அழகப்பெருமவை பரிந்துரைக்கிறேன்' என்றார்.",
        "இதன்போது  பொதுஜன பெரமுனவின் தவிசாளர் பேராசிரியர் ஜி.எல் பீரிஸ் ' புதிய ஜனாதிபதி தெரிவிற்கான வேட்பு மனுவில் பரிந்துரைக்கப்பட்டுள்ள டலஸ் அழகபெருமவின் பெயரை உறுதிப்படுத்துகிறேன்' என்றார்.",
        "இரண்டாவதாக  சபை முதல்வர் தினேஷ் குணவர்தன ' புதிய ஜனாதிபதியை தெரிவு செய்துக்கொள்வதற்காக ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்கவின் பெயரை பரிந்துரைக்கிறேன்' என்றார்.",
        "இதன்போது எதிர்தரப்பினர் கூச்சலிட்டனர்.முக்கிய கடமை நிறைவேற்றப்படுகிறது ஆகவே சபையில் அனைவரும் அமைதியாக செயற்பட வேண்டும் என சபாநாயகர் வலியுறுத்தினார்.",
        "மூன்றாவதாக ' புதிய ஜனாதிபதி தெரிவிற்காக மக்கள் விடுதலை முன்னணியின் தலைவர் அனுர குமார திஸாநாயக்கவை விஜித ஹேரத் பரிந்துரைக்கிறேன்'என்றார்.",
        "மேலும் உறுப்பினர்களின் பெயர் பரிந்துரை செய்ய  சந்தர்ப்பம் உள்ளது  என தெரிவத்தாட்சி அலுவலர் குறிப்பிட்டார். பிற பெயர் பரிந்துரை செய்யப்படாததால் 1981 ஆம் ஆண்டு 02ஆம் இலக்கம் ஜனாதிபதி தெரிவு (சிறப்பு ஏற்பாடுகள் ) உறுப்புரையில் குறிப்பிட்டப்பட்டுள்ள விடயதானங்களுக்கமைய இடைக்கால ஜனாதிபதி பதவிக்காக பாராளுமன்றத்தின் ஊடாக வேட்பு மனுக்கலை பெற்றுக்கொள்வது நிறைவடைந்துள்ளது என்பதை சபைக்கு அறிவிக்கிறேன்  என பாராளுமன்ற செயலாளர் நாயகம் குறிப்பிட்டார்.",
        "பாராளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர் டலஸ் அழகபெரும,பாராளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர் ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க மற்றும் பாராளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர் அனுர குமார திஸாநாயக்க ஆகியோரது வேட்புமனுக்கலை ஏற்றுக்கொள்கிறேன் என்பதையும்  சபைக்கு அறிவிக்கிறேன்.",
        "1981ஆம் ஆண்டு 02ஆம் இலக்க ஜனாதிபதி தெரிவு (சிறப்பு ஏற்பாடுகள்) 4,6 ஆகிய உறுப்புரைகளின் பிரகாரம் தற்போது வெற்றிடமாகியுள்ள ஜனாதிபதி பதவிக்காக ஒரு உறுப்பினரை தவிர பலரது பெயர் பரிந்துரைக்கப்பட்டு, உறுதிப்படுத்தப்பட்டுள்ளதால் அச்சட்டத்தில் 2,3 பிரிவுகளின் பிரகாரம் வாக்கெடுபிபினை நடத்தும் திகதி மற்றும் நேரம் சபைக்கு அறிவிக்கப்பட வேண்டும் என்பதால் ,பாராளுமன்ற கட்சி தலைவர் கூட்டம்,மற்றும் பாராளுமன்ற அலுவல்கள் குழு கூட்;டத்தில் கடந்த 11ஆம் திகதி முன்னெடுக்கப்பட்ட தீர்மானத்திற்கமைய பாராளுமன்றம் நாளை (இன்று) காலை 10.00 மணிக்கு கூடும் என்பதை  சபை முதல்வர் சபைக்கு அறிவிப்பார் என பாராளுமன்ற செயலாளர் நாயகம் அறிவித்தார்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "மூன்று",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "இன்று",
          "label": "DATE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "டலஸ் அழகப்பெரும",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "அனுர",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "குமார திஸாநாயக்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "எதிர்க்கட்சியான சஜித் பிரேமதாச",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "டல்லஸ் அழகப்பெரும",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "பொதுஜன பெரமுனவின்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜி.எல்.பீரிஸ்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "செவ்வாய்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "மஹிந்த யாப்பா அபேவர்தன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "மஹிந்த யாப்பா அபேவர்தன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "வீடு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "அரசியலமைப்பு",
            "label": "LAW"
          },
          {
            "text": "வீடு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜூலை 16 சனிக்கிழமை",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "தம்மிக்க தசநாயக்கவின்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜனாதிபதித் தேர்தலின் பிரிவு 06 (சிறப்பு ஏற்பாடுகள்",
            "label": "LAW"
          },
          {
            "text": "1981 இன் கட்டுரை எண். 02",
            "label": "LAW"
          },
          {
            "text": "இரண்டாவது",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "முதலில்",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "சஜித் பிரேமதாச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "முதலில்",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "டல்லஸ் அழகப்பெரும",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை ஜனநாயக சோசலிச குடியரசு'",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஜி.எல்.பீரிஸ்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "டல்லஸ் அழகப்பெரும",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இரண்டாவதாக",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "தினேஷ் குணவர்தன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "வீடு",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "விஜித ஹேரத்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "மக்கள் விடுதலை முன்னணி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "குமார திஸாநாயக்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "வீடு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "1981 இன் கட்டுரை எண். 02",
            "label": "LAW"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜனாதிபதித் தேர்வு (சிறப்பு ஏற்பாடுகள்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "வீடு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம் டலஸ் அழகப்பெரும",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம் ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "குமார திஸாநாயக்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "02",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "1981",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "4",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஒன்று",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "வீடு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "சட்டத்தின் பிரிவு 2 மற்றும் 3",
            "label": "LAW"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்ற கட்சி தலைவர்கள்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "நாளை",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "காலை 10.00 மணி",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்ற விவகாரக் குழு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "11வது",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}