{
  "newspaper_id": "economy-next-com",
  "url": "https://economynext.com/sri-lanka-president-meets-high-powered-imf-mission-96429/",
  "time_ut": 1656120720,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Sri Lanka President meets high powered IMF mission",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Sri Lanka President meets high powered IMF mission",
      "author": "",
      "body_lines": [
        "ECONOMYNEXT – Sri Lanka’s President Gotabaya Rajapaksa has met a team from the International Monetary Fund who are in the island to negotiate a bailout involving tighter monetary and fiscal policies and a debt re-structuring.",
        "The IMF mission was led Deputy Director of IMF’s Asia Pacific Department Anne-Marie Gulde. The IMF has also appointed senior mission chief Peter Breuer, who is Chief of the Debt Capital Markets Division, Monetary and Capital Market Department of the IMF.",
        "IMF’s Mission Chief for Sri Lanka Masahiro Nozaki, Resident Representative for Sri Lanka Tubagus Feridhanusetyawan had also met President Rajapaksa.",
        "“IMF representatives briefed the President regarding the preliminary round of discussions heldwith the Prime Minister, the Ministry of Finance, the Central Bank and other economic authorities and experts as well as regarding the current situation,” his office said in a statement.",
        "“The delegation reaffirmed their commitment to support Sri Lanka at this difficult time, in line with the IMF’s policies.",
        "“The President elaborated on the current economic situation and expressed his gratitude to the delegation for their support to Sri Lanka during difficult times.”",
        "The IMF was invited to Sri Lanka at the request of President Gotabaya Rajapaksa at a time when state economists were still supporting ‘stimulus’.",
        "Stimulus or money pritning became a fad during the Coronavirus crisis and was endorsed by the IMF and major reserve currency central banks also engaged in the practice creating a ‘hangover’ in the form of high inflation.",
        "After the Fed fired a massive commodity bubble food prices are high around the world and Mercantilists are now claiming there is a ‘food crisis’ s just as they claimed at the height of the Greenspan-Bernanke bubble in 2008.",
        "Sri Lanka defaulted on the its foreign debt after 7 years of aggressive monetary stimulus, involving call money rate targeting, real effective exchange rate targeting and output gap targeting, including with fiscal stimulus (tax cuts) which led to monetary instability and higher foreign borrowings.",
        "The country is now trying to re-structure its foreign debt but is also attempting to borrow a whopping 6.0 billion dollars in 2022 amid enhanced monetary instability. (Colombo/June24/2022)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Sri Lanka",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Gotabaya Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the International Monetary Fund",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "IMF",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Asia Pacific Department",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Anne-Marie Gulde",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "IMF",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Peter Breuer",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Debt Capital Markets Division",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Monetary and Capital Market Department of the IMF",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Masahiro Nozaki",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "IMF",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Ministry of Finance",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Central Bank",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "IMF",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "IMF",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Gotabaya Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Coronavirus",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "IMF",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Fed",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Greenspan",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "2008",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "7 years",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "6.0 billion dollars",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "2022",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Colombo/June24/2022",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "ශ්‍රී ලංකා ජනපති ඉහළ බලැති IMF මෙහෙයුම හමුවෙයි",
      "author": "",
      "body_lines": [
        "ECONOMYNEXT - දැඩි මූල්‍ය හා මූල්‍ය ප්‍රතිපත්ති සහ ණය ප්‍රතිව්‍යුහගත කිරීම සම්බන්ධ ඇපදීමක් පිළිබඳ සාකච්ඡා කිරීම සඳහා ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ ජනාධිපති ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ මහතා දිවයිනට පැමිණ සිටින ජාත්‍යන්තර මූල්‍ය අරමුදලේ කණ්ඩායමක් හමුවී ඇත.",
        "IMF මෙහෙයුම මෙහෙයවනු ලැබුවේ IMF හි ආසියා පැසිෆික් දෙපාර්තමේන්තුවේ නියෝජ්‍ය අධ්‍යක්ෂ Anne-Marie Gulde විසිනි. ජාත්‍යන්තර මූල්‍ය අරමුදලේ ණය ප්‍රාග්ධන වෙළෙඳපොළ අංශය, මූල්‍ය හා ප්‍රාග්ධන වෙළෙඳපොළ දෙපාර්තමේන්තුවේ ප්‍රධානියා වන ජ්‍යෙෂ්ඨ මෙහෙවර ප්‍රධානී පීටර් බෲවර් ද පත් කර ඇත.",
        "ජාත්‍යන්තර මූල්‍ය අරමුදලේ ශ්‍රී ලංකාව සඳහා වූ දූත මණ්ඩල ප්‍රධානී Masahiro Nozaki, ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ නේවාසික නියෝජිත Tubagus Feridhanusetyawan ද ජනාධිපති රාජපක්ෂ හමුවී ඇත.",
        "අග්‍රාමාත්‍යවරයා, මුදල් අමාත්‍යාංශය, මහ බැංකුව සහ අනෙකුත් ආර්ථික බලධාරීන් සහ විශේෂඥයින් සමඟ පැවති මූලික වටයේ සාකච්ඡා පිළිබඳව මෙන්ම වත්මන් තත්ත්වය පිළිබඳව IMF නියෝජිතයින් ජනාධිපතිවරයා දැනුවත් කළ බව ඔහුගේ කාර්යාලය නිවේදනයක් නිකුත් කරමින් කියා සිටියේය.",
        "“IMF හි ප්‍රතිපත්තිවලට අනුකූලව, මෙම දුෂ්කර අවස්ථාවේ ශ්‍රී ලංකාවට සහාය දැක්වීමට ඔවුන්ගේ කැපවීම නියෝජිත පිරිස යළිත් තහවුරු කළහ.",
        "\"ජනාධිපතිවරයා වත්මන් ආර්ථික තත්ත්වය පිළිබඳව විස්තර කළ අතර දුෂ්කර කාලවලදී ශ්‍රී ලංකාවට ලබා දුන් සහයෝගය පිළිබඳව නියෝජිත පිරිසට සිය කෘතඥතාව පළ කළේය.\"",
        "ජනාධිපති ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂගේ ඉල්ලීම පරිදි IMF ශ්‍රී ලංකාවට ආරාධනා කරනු ලැබුවේ රාජ්‍ය ආර්ථික විද්‍යාඥයින් තවමත් ‘උත්තේජනයට’ සහාය දෙන අවස්ථාවක ය.",
        "කොරොන වයිරස් අර්බුදය තුළ උත්තේජක හෝ මුදල් මුද්‍රණය කිරීම විලාසිතාවක් බවට පත් වූ අතර එය IMF විසින් අනුමත කරන ලද අතර ප්‍රධාන සංචිත මුදල් මහ බැංකු ද ඉහළ උද්ධමනයේ ස්වරූපයෙන් 'හැන්ගෝවර්' නිර්මාණය කිරීමේ පරිචයේ නිරත විය.",
        "ෆෙඩරල් මහ බැංකුව විසින් දැවැන්ත භාණ්ඩ බුබුලකින් ආහාර මිල ලොව පුරා ඉහළ මට්ටමක පවතින අතර වෙළඳවාදීන් දැන් කියා සිටින්නේ 2008 දී Greenspan-Bernanke බුබුලේ උච්චතම අවස්ථාවට ප්‍රකාශ කළ ආකාරයටම 'ආහාර අර්බුදයක්' පවතින බවයි.",
        "මුදල් අස්ථාවරත්වයට සහ ඉහළ විදේශ ණය ගැනීම්වලට තුඩු දුන් මූල්‍ය උත්තේජක (බදු කප්පාදු) ඇතුළුව ඇමතුම් මුදල් අනුපාත ඉලක්ක කිරීම, සැබෑ ඵලදායී විනිමය අනුපාත ඉලක්ක කිරීම සහ ප්‍රතිදාන පරතරය ඉලක්ක කිරීම ඇතුළුව වසර 7ක ආක්‍රමණශීලී මූල්‍ය උත්තේජකවලින් පසු ශ්‍රී ලංකාව සිය විදේශ ණය පැහැර හැරියේය.",
        "රට දැන් එහි විදේශ ණය ප්‍රතිව්‍යුහගත කිරීමට උත්සාහ කරමින් සිටින නමුත් වැඩිදියුණු කළ මුදල් අස්ථාවරත්වය මධ්‍යයේ 2022 දී ඩොලර් බිලියන 6.0 ක දැවැන්ත ණයක් ගැනීමට ද උත්සාහ කරයි. (කොළඹ/ජුනි24/2022)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජාත්‍යන්තර මුල්‍ය අරමුදල",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "IMF",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ආසියා පැසිෆික් දෙපාර්තමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඈන්-මාරි ගුල්ඩ්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "IMF",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "පීටර් බෲවර්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ණය ප්රාග්ධන වෙළෙඳපොළ අංශය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "IMF හි මුදල් හා ප්‍රාග්ධන වෙළෙඳපොළ දෙපාර්තමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Masahiro Nozaki",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "IMF",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "මුදල් අමාත්යාංශය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "මහ බැංකුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "IMF",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "IMF",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "කොරෝනාවයිරසය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "IMF",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ෆෙඩරල්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ග්රීන්ස්පන්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "2008",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "අවුරුදු 7 යි",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ඩොලර් බිලියන 6.0 කි",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "2022",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "කොළඹ/ජුනි24/2022",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "இலங்கை ஜனாதிபதி உயர் அதிகாரம் கொண்ட IMF பணியை சந்தித்தார்",
      "author": "",
      "body_lines": [
        "பொருளாதாரம் - இலங்கையின் ஜனாதிபதி கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ஷ, கடுமையான நாணய மற்றும் நிதிக் கொள்கைகள் மற்றும் கடன் மறுசீரமைப்பு ஆகியவற்றை உள்ளடக்கிய பிணை எடுப்பு தொடர்பாக பேச்சுவார்த்தை நடத்துவதற்காக தீவு வந்துள்ள சர்வதேச நாணய நிதியத்தின் குழுவைச் சந்தித்துள்ளார்.",
        "IMF பணியானது IMFன் ஆசிய பசிபிக் துறையின் துணை இயக்குனர் Anne-Marie Gulde தலைமையில் இருந்தது. IMF இன் கடன் மூலதனச் சந்தைப் பிரிவு, நாணயம் மற்றும் மூலதனச் சந்தைத் துறையின் தலைவராக இருக்கும் மூத்த பணித் தலைவர் பீட்டர் ப்ரூயரையும் IMF நியமித்துள்ளது.",
        "சர்வதேச நாணய நிதியத்தின் இலங்கைக்கான தூதரகத் தலைவர் மசாஹிரோ நோசாகி, இலங்கைக்கான வதிவிடப் பிரதிநிதி டுபாகஸ் பெரிதானுசெட்யவான் ஆகியோரும் ஜனாதிபதி ராஜபக்ஷவைச் சந்தித்துள்ளனர்.",
        "பிரதமர், நிதியமைச்சு, மத்திய வங்கி மற்றும் ஏனைய பொருளாதார அதிகாரிகள் மற்றும் நிபுணர்களுடன் நடத்தப்பட்ட ஆரம்ப கட்ட கலந்துரையாடல்கள் மற்றும் தற்போதைய நிலைமை தொடர்பாக சர்வதேச நாணய நிதியத்தின் பிரதிநிதிகள் ஜனாதிபதிக்கு விளக்கமளித்ததாக அவரது அலுவலகம் அறிக்கை ஒன்றில் தெரிவித்துள்ளது.",
        "“இந்த இக்கட்டான நேரத்தில், சர்வதேச நாணய நிதியத்தின் கொள்கைகளுக்கு இணங்க இலங்கைக்கு ஆதரவளிப்பதற்கான தமது உறுதிப்பாட்டை பிரதிநிதிகள் மீண்டும் உறுதிப்படுத்தினர்.",
        "\"தற்போதைய பொருளாதார நிலைமையை ஜனாதிபதி விரிவாக எடுத்துரைத்ததுடன், கடினமான காலங்களில் இலங்கைக்கு வழங்கிய ஆதரவிற்காக தூதுக்குழுவினருக்கு தனது நன்றியைத் தெரிவித்தார்.\"",
        "அரச பொருளாதார நிபுணர்கள் இன்னும் ‘தூண்டலுக்கு’ ஆதரவளித்துக்கொண்டிருந்த நேரத்தில் ஜனாதிபதி கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ஷவின் வேண்டுகோளின் பேரில் IMF இலங்கைக்கு அழைக்கப்பட்டது.",
        "கொரோனா வைரஸ் நெருக்கடியின் போது தூண்டுதல் அல்லது பணம் அச்சிடுதல் ஒரு ஃபேஷனாக மாறியது மற்றும் IMF மற்றும் முக்கிய ரிசர்வ் கரன்சி மத்திய வங்கிகளால் அங்கீகரிக்கப்பட்டது மேலும் அதிக பணவீக்கத்தின் வடிவத்தில் 'ஹேங்ஓவர்' உருவாக்கும் நடைமுறையில் ஈடுபட்டுள்ளது.",
        "மத்திய வங்கி ஒரு பெரிய சரக்கு குமிழியை வெளியேற்றிய பிறகு, உலகம் முழுவதும் உணவு விலைகள் அதிகமாக உள்ளன, மேலும் வணிகவாதிகள் 2008 இல் கிரீன்ஸ்பான்-பெர்னான்கே குமிழியின் உச்சத்தில் கூறியது போல் இப்போது 'உணவு நெருக்கடி' இருப்பதாகக் கூறுகின்றனர்.",
        "7 வருட ஆக்கிரமிப்பு பண ஊக்குவிப்புக்குப் பிறகு இலங்கை தனது வெளிநாட்டுக் கடனைத் திருப்பிச் செலுத்தவில்லை, இதில் அழைப்புப் பண விகித இலக்கு, உண்மையான பயனுள்ள மாற்று விகித இலக்கு மற்றும் வெளியீட்டு இடைவெளி இலக்கு, நிதி ஊக்கம் (வரி குறைப்பு) உட்பட பண ஸ்திரமின்மை மற்றும் அதிக வெளிநாட்டு கடன் வாங்குதல் ஆகியவை அடங்கும்.",
        "நாடு இப்போது அதன் வெளிநாட்டுக் கடனை மீண்டும் கட்டமைக்க முயற்சிக்கிறது, ஆனால் மேம்பட்ட பண ஸ்திரமின்மைக்கு மத்தியில் 2022 இல் 6.0 பில்லியன் டாலர்களை கடனாகப் பெற முயற்சிக்கிறது. (கொழும்பு/ஜூன்24/2022)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "இலங்கை",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "சர்வதேச நாணய நிதியம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "IMF",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆசிய பசிபிக் துறை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "அன்னே-மேரி குல்டே",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "IMF",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "பீட்டர் ப்ரூயர்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "கடன் மூலதன சந்தை பிரிவு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "IMF இன் நாணய மற்றும் மூலதன சந்தை துறை",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Masahiro Nozaki",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ராஜபக்சே",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "IMF",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "நிதி அமைச்சகம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "மத்திய வங்கி",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "IMF",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "IMF",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "கொரோனா வைரஸ்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "IMF",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஊட்டி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "கிரீன்ஸ்பான்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "2008",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "7 ஆண்டுகள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "6.0 பில்லியன் டாலர்கள்",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "2022",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "கொழும்பு/ஜூன்24/2022",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  },
  "title": "Sri Lanka President meets high powered IMF mission",
  "body_lines": [
    "ECONOMYNEXT – Sri Lanka’s President Gotabaya Rajapaksa has met a team from the International Monetary Fund who are in the island to negotiate a bailout involving tighter monetary and fiscal policies and a debt re-structuring.",
    "The IMF mission was led Deputy Director of IMF’s Asia Pacific Department Anne-Marie Gulde. The IMF has also appointed senior mission chief Peter Breuer, who is Chief of the Debt Capital Markets Division, Monetary and Capital Market Department of the IMF.",
    "IMF’s Mission Chief for Sri Lanka Masahiro Nozaki, Resident Representative for Sri Lanka Tubagus Feridhanusetyawan had also met President Rajapaksa.",
    "“IMF representatives briefed the President regarding the preliminary round of discussions heldwith the Prime Minister, the Ministry of Finance, the Central Bank and other economic authorities and experts as well as regarding the current situation,” his office said in a statement.",
    "“The delegation reaffirmed their commitment to support Sri Lanka at this difficult time, in line with the IMF’s policies.",
    "“The President elaborated on the current economic situation and expressed his gratitude to the delegation for their support to Sri Lanka during difficult times.”",
    "The IMF was invited to Sri Lanka at the request of President Gotabaya Rajapaksa at a time when state economists were still supporting ‘stimulus’.",
    "Stimulus or money pritning became a fad during the Coronavirus crisis and was endorsed by the IMF and major reserve currency central banks also engaged in the practice creating a ‘hangover’ in the form of high inflation.",
    "After the Fed fired a massive commodity bubble food prices are high around the world and Mercantilists are now claiming there is a ‘food crisis’ s just as they claimed at the height of the Greenspan-Bernanke bubble in 2008.",
    "Sri Lanka defaulted on the its foreign debt after 7 years of aggressive monetary stimulus, involving call money rate targeting, real effective exchange rate targeting and output gap targeting, including with fiscal stimulus (tax cuts) which led to monetary instability and higher foreign borrowings.",
    "The country is now trying to re-structure its foreign debt but is also attempting to borrow a whopping 6.0 billion dollars in 2022 amid enhanced monetary instability. (Colombo/June24/2022)"
  ],
  "translate": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Sri Lanka President meets high powered IMF mission",
      "author": "",
      "body_lines": [
        "ECONOMYNEXT – Sri Lanka’s President Gotabaya Rajapaksa has met a team from the International Monetary Fund who are in the island to negotiate a bailout involving tighter monetary and fiscal policies and a debt re-structuring.",
        "The IMF mission was led Deputy Director of IMF’s Asia Pacific Department Anne-Marie Gulde. The IMF has also appointed senior mission chief Peter Breuer, who is Chief of the Debt Capital Markets Division, Monetary and Capital Market Department of the IMF.",
        "IMF’s Mission Chief for Sri Lanka Masahiro Nozaki, Resident Representative for Sri Lanka Tubagus Feridhanusetyawan had also met President Rajapaksa.",
        "“IMF representatives briefed the President regarding the preliminary round of discussions heldwith the Prime Minister, the Ministry of Finance, the Central Bank and other economic authorities and experts as well as regarding the current situation,” his office said in a statement.",
        "“The delegation reaffirmed their commitment to support Sri Lanka at this difficult time, in line with the IMF’s policies.",
        "“The President elaborated on the current economic situation and expressed his gratitude to the delegation for their support to Sri Lanka during difficult times.”",
        "The IMF was invited to Sri Lanka at the request of President Gotabaya Rajapaksa at a time when state economists were still supporting ‘stimulus’.",
        "Stimulus or money pritning became a fad during the Coronavirus crisis and was endorsed by the IMF and major reserve currency central banks also engaged in the practice creating a ‘hangover’ in the form of high inflation.",
        "After the Fed fired a massive commodity bubble food prices are high around the world and Mercantilists are now claiming there is a ‘food crisis’ s just as they claimed at the height of the Greenspan-Bernanke bubble in 2008.",
        "Sri Lanka defaulted on the its foreign debt after 7 years of aggressive monetary stimulus, involving call money rate targeting, real effective exchange rate targeting and output gap targeting, including with fiscal stimulus (tax cuts) which led to monetary instability and higher foreign borrowings.",
        "The country is now trying to re-structure its foreign debt but is also attempting to borrow a whopping 6.0 billion dollars in 2022 amid enhanced monetary instability. (Colombo/June24/2022)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Sri Lanka",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Gotabaya Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the International Monetary Fund",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "IMF",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Asia Pacific Department",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Anne-Marie Gulde",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "IMF",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Peter Breuer",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Debt Capital Markets Division",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Monetary and Capital Market Department of the IMF",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Masahiro Nozaki",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "IMF",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Ministry of Finance",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Central Bank",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "IMF",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "IMF",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Gotabaya Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Coronavirus",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "IMF",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Fed",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Greenspan",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "2008",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "7 years",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "6.0 billion dollars",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "2022",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Colombo/June24/2022",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "ශ්‍රී ලංකා ජනපති ඉහළ බලැති IMF මෙහෙයුම හමුවෙයි",
      "author": "",
      "body_lines": [
        "ECONOMYNEXT - දැඩි මූල්‍ය හා මූල්‍ය ප්‍රතිපත්ති සහ ණය ප්‍රතිව්‍යුහගත කිරීම සම්බන්ධ ඇපදීමක් පිළිබඳ සාකච්ඡා කිරීම සඳහා ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ ජනාධිපති ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ මහතා දිවයිනට පැමිණ සිටින ජාත්‍යන්තර මූල්‍ය අරමුදලේ කණ්ඩායමක් හමුවී ඇත.",
        "IMF මෙහෙයුම මෙහෙයවනු ලැබුවේ IMF හි ආසියා පැසිෆික් දෙපාර්තමේන්තුවේ නියෝජ්‍ය අධ්‍යක්ෂ Anne-Marie Gulde විසිනි. ජාත්‍යන්තර මූල්‍ය අරමුදලේ ණය ප්‍රාග්ධන වෙළෙඳපොළ අංශය, මූල්‍ය හා ප්‍රාග්ධන වෙළෙඳපොළ දෙපාර්තමේන්තුවේ ප්‍රධානියා වන ජ්‍යෙෂ්ඨ මෙහෙවර ප්‍රධානී පීටර් බෲවර් ද පත් කර ඇත.",
        "ජාත්‍යන්තර මූල්‍ය අරමුදලේ ශ්‍රී ලංකාව සඳහා වූ දූත මණ්ඩල ප්‍රධානී Masahiro Nozaki, ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ නේවාසික නියෝජිත Tubagus Feridhanusetyawan ද ජනාධිපති රාජපක්ෂ හමුවී ඇත.",
        "අග්‍රාමාත්‍යවරයා, මුදල් අමාත්‍යාංශය, මහ බැංකුව සහ අනෙකුත් ආර්ථික බලධාරීන් සහ විශේෂඥයින් සමඟ පැවති මූලික වටයේ සාකච්ඡා පිළිබඳව මෙන්ම වත්මන් තත්ත්වය පිළිබඳව IMF නියෝජිතයින් ජනාධිපතිවරයා දැනුවත් කළ බව ඔහුගේ කාර්යාලය නිවේදනයක් නිකුත් කරමින් කියා සිටියේය.",
        "“IMF හි ප්‍රතිපත්තිවලට අනුකූලව, මෙම දුෂ්කර අවස්ථාවේ ශ්‍රී ලංකාවට සහාය දැක්වීමට ඔවුන්ගේ කැපවීම නියෝජිත පිරිස යළිත් තහවුරු කළහ.",
        "\"ජනාධිපතිවරයා වත්මන් ආර්ථික තත්ත්වය පිළිබඳව විස්තර කළ අතර දුෂ්කර කාලවලදී ශ්‍රී ලංකාවට ලබා දුන් සහයෝගය පිළිබඳව නියෝජිත පිරිසට සිය කෘතඥතාව පළ කළේය.\"",
        "ජනාධිපති ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂගේ ඉල්ලීම පරිදි IMF ශ්‍රී ලංකාවට ආරාධනා කරනු ලැබුවේ රාජ්‍ය ආර්ථික විද්‍යාඥයින් තවමත් ‘උත්තේජනයට’ සහාය දෙන අවස්ථාවක ය.",
        "කොරොන වයිරස් අර්බුදය තුළ උත්තේජක හෝ මුදල් මුද්‍රණය කිරීම විලාසිතාවක් බවට පත් වූ අතර එය IMF විසින් අනුමත කරන ලද අතර ප්‍රධාන සංචිත මුදල් මහ බැංකු ද ඉහළ උද්ධමනයේ ස්වරූපයෙන් 'හැන්ගෝවර්' නිර්මාණය කිරීමේ පරිචයේ නිරත විය.",
        "ෆෙඩරල් මහ බැංකුව විසින් දැවැන්ත භාණ්ඩ බුබුලකින් ආහාර මිල ලොව පුරා ඉහළ මට්ටමක පවතින අතර වෙළඳවාදීන් දැන් කියා සිටින්නේ 2008 දී Greenspan-Bernanke බුබුලේ උච්චතම අවස්ථාවට ප්‍රකාශ කළ ආකාරයටම 'ආහාර අර්බුදයක්' පවතින බවයි.",
        "මුදල් අස්ථාවරත්වයට සහ ඉහළ විදේශ ණය ගැනීම්වලට තුඩු දුන් මූල්‍ය උත්තේජක (බදු කප්පාදු) ඇතුළුව ඇමතුම් මුදල් අනුපාත ඉලක්ක කිරීම, සැබෑ ඵලදායී විනිමය අනුපාත ඉලක්ක කිරීම සහ ප්‍රතිදාන පරතරය ඉලක්ක කිරීම ඇතුළුව වසර 7ක ආක්‍රමණශීලී මූල්‍ය උත්තේජකවලින් පසු ශ්‍රී ලංකාව සිය විදේශ ණය පැහැර හැරියේය.",
        "රට දැන් එහි විදේශ ණය ප්‍රතිව්‍යුහගත කිරීමට උත්සාහ කරමින් සිටින නමුත් වැඩිදියුණු කළ මුදල් අස්ථාවරත්වය මධ්‍යයේ 2022 දී ඩොලර් බිලියන 6.0 ක දැවැන්ත ණයක් ගැනීමට ද උත්සාහ කරයි. (කොළඹ/ජුනි24/2022)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජාත්‍යන්තර මුල්‍ය අරමුදල",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "IMF",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ආසියා පැසිෆික් දෙපාර්තමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඈන්-මාරි ගුල්ඩ්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "IMF",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "පීටර් බෲවර්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ණය ප්රාග්ධන වෙළෙඳපොළ අංශය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "IMF හි මුදල් හා ප්‍රාග්ධන වෙළෙඳපොළ දෙපාර්තමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Masahiro Nozaki",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "IMF",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "මුදල් අමාත්යාංශය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "මහ බැංකුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "IMF",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "IMF",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "කොරෝනාවයිරසය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "IMF",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ෆෙඩරල්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ග්රීන්ස්පන්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "2008",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "අවුරුදු 7 යි",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ඩොලර් බිලියන 6.0 කි",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "2022",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "කොළඹ/ජුනි24/2022",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "இலங்கை ஜனாதிபதி உயர் அதிகாரம் கொண்ட IMF பணியை சந்தித்தார்",
      "author": "",
      "body_lines": [
        "பொருளாதாரம் - இலங்கையின் ஜனாதிபதி கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ஷ, கடுமையான நாணய மற்றும் நிதிக் கொள்கைகள் மற்றும் கடன் மறுசீரமைப்பு ஆகியவற்றை உள்ளடக்கிய பிணை எடுப்பு தொடர்பாக பேச்சுவார்த்தை நடத்துவதற்காக தீவு வந்துள்ள சர்வதேச நாணய நிதியத்தின் குழுவைச் சந்தித்துள்ளார்.",
        "IMF பணியானது IMFன் ஆசிய பசிபிக் துறையின் துணை இயக்குனர் Anne-Marie Gulde தலைமையில் இருந்தது. IMF இன் கடன் மூலதனச் சந்தைப் பிரிவு, நாணயம் மற்றும் மூலதனச் சந்தைத் துறையின் தலைவராக இருக்கும் மூத்த பணித் தலைவர் பீட்டர் ப்ரூயரையும் IMF நியமித்துள்ளது.",
        "சர்வதேச நாணய நிதியத்தின் இலங்கைக்கான தூதரகத் தலைவர் மசாஹிரோ நோசாகி, இலங்கைக்கான வதிவிடப் பிரதிநிதி டுபாகஸ் பெரிதானுசெட்யவான் ஆகியோரும் ஜனாதிபதி ராஜபக்ஷவைச் சந்தித்துள்ளனர்.",
        "பிரதமர், நிதியமைச்சு, மத்திய வங்கி மற்றும் ஏனைய பொருளாதார அதிகாரிகள் மற்றும் நிபுணர்களுடன் நடத்தப்பட்ட ஆரம்ப கட்ட கலந்துரையாடல்கள் மற்றும் தற்போதைய நிலைமை தொடர்பாக சர்வதேச நாணய நிதியத்தின் பிரதிநிதிகள் ஜனாதிபதிக்கு விளக்கமளித்ததாக அவரது அலுவலகம் அறிக்கை ஒன்றில் தெரிவித்துள்ளது.",
        "“இந்த இக்கட்டான நேரத்தில், சர்வதேச நாணய நிதியத்தின் கொள்கைகளுக்கு இணங்க இலங்கைக்கு ஆதரவளிப்பதற்கான தமது உறுதிப்பாட்டை பிரதிநிதிகள் மீண்டும் உறுதிப்படுத்தினர்.",
        "\"தற்போதைய பொருளாதார நிலைமையை ஜனாதிபதி விரிவாக எடுத்துரைத்ததுடன், கடினமான காலங்களில் இலங்கைக்கு வழங்கிய ஆதரவிற்காக தூதுக்குழுவினருக்கு தனது நன்றியைத் தெரிவித்தார்.\"",
        "அரச பொருளாதார நிபுணர்கள் இன்னும் ‘தூண்டலுக்கு’ ஆதரவளித்துக்கொண்டிருந்த நேரத்தில் ஜனாதிபதி கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ஷவின் வேண்டுகோளின் பேரில் IMF இலங்கைக்கு அழைக்கப்பட்டது.",
        "கொரோனா வைரஸ் நெருக்கடியின் போது தூண்டுதல் அல்லது பணம் அச்சிடுதல் ஒரு ஃபேஷனாக மாறியது மற்றும் IMF மற்றும் முக்கிய ரிசர்வ் கரன்சி மத்திய வங்கிகளால் அங்கீகரிக்கப்பட்டது மேலும் அதிக பணவீக்கத்தின் வடிவத்தில் 'ஹேங்ஓவர்' உருவாக்கும் நடைமுறையில் ஈடுபட்டுள்ளது.",
        "மத்திய வங்கி ஒரு பெரிய சரக்கு குமிழியை வெளியேற்றிய பிறகு, உலகம் முழுவதும் உணவு விலைகள் அதிகமாக உள்ளன, மேலும் வணிகவாதிகள் 2008 இல் கிரீன்ஸ்பான்-பெர்னான்கே குமிழியின் உச்சத்தில் கூறியது போல் இப்போது 'உணவு நெருக்கடி' இருப்பதாகக் கூறுகின்றனர்.",
        "7 வருட ஆக்கிரமிப்பு பண ஊக்குவிப்புக்குப் பிறகு இலங்கை தனது வெளிநாட்டுக் கடனைத் திருப்பிச் செலுத்தவில்லை, இதில் அழைப்புப் பண விகித இலக்கு, உண்மையான பயனுள்ள மாற்று விகித இலக்கு மற்றும் வெளியீட்டு இடைவெளி இலக்கு, நிதி ஊக்கம் (வரி குறைப்பு) உட்பட பண ஸ்திரமின்மை மற்றும் அதிக வெளிநாட்டு கடன் வாங்குதல் ஆகியவை அடங்கும்.",
        "நாடு இப்போது அதன் வெளிநாட்டுக் கடனை மீண்டும் கட்டமைக்க முயற்சிக்கிறது, ஆனால் மேம்பட்ட பண ஸ்திரமின்மைக்கு மத்தியில் 2022 இல் 6.0 பில்லியன் டாலர்களை கடனாகப் பெற முயற்சிக்கிறது. (கொழும்பு/ஜூன்24/2022)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "இலங்கை",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "சர்வதேச நாணய நிதியம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "IMF",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆசிய பசிபிக் துறை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "அன்னே-மேரி குல்டே",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "IMF",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "பீட்டர் ப்ரூயர்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "கடன் மூலதன சந்தை பிரிவு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "IMF இன் நாணய மற்றும் மூலதன சந்தை துறை",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Masahiro Nozaki",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ராஜபக்சே",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "IMF",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "நிதி அமைச்சகம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "மத்திய வங்கி",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "IMF",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "IMF",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "கொரோனா வைரஸ்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "IMF",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஊட்டி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "கிரீன்ஸ்பான்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "2008",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "7 ஆண்டுகள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "6.0 பில்லியன் டாலர்கள்",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "2022",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "கொழும்பு/ஜூன்24/2022",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}