{
  "newspaper_id": "lankadeepa-lk",
  "url": "https://www.lankadeepa.lk/latest_news/කෝප්-එරාන්ට---කෝපා-කබීර්ට/1-618079",
  "time_ut": 1660491733,
  "original_lang": "si",
  "original_title": "කෝප් එරාන්ට - කෝපා කබීර්ට",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Cope Eran - Cope Kabir",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "Samagi Jana Balawegaya MP Eran Wickramaratne is to be appointed as the Chairman of the Parliamentary Committee on Public Affairs (COPE Committee) of the Third House of the Ninth Parliament and Mr. Kabir Hashim of the same party is to be appointed as the Chairman of the Parliamentary Committee on Public Accounts (COPE Committee). Parliamentary sources say.",
        "In this regard, in an inquiry made to the chief organizer of our opposition, Mr. Lakshman Kiriella, a lawyer, he said that proposals have been submitted in this regard.",
        "Professor Charita Herath, a member of parliament appointed by the Sri Lanka Podujana Peramuna, served as the chairman of the Parliamentary Committee on Public Affairs in the second chamber of the Ninth Parliament.",
        "Professor Tissa Witharana previously worked as the Chairman of the Parliamentary Committee on Public Accounts.",
        "COPE and COPA are the two main committees of the Parliament that conduct investigations and make recommendations on corruption, fraud, irregularities and abuses in public institutions.",
        "The chief organizer of the opposition, Mr. Lawyer Lakshman Kiriella, recently requested the speaker at the committee meeting on parliamentary affairs to give the chairmanship of all the committees of the parliament to the members of the opposition.",
        "At that time, it has been learned that the speaker clearly agreed to it.",
        "The Parliamentary Committee of Selection recently decided to appoint Dr. Harsha De Silva, a Member of the Opposition, as the Chairman of the Parliamentary Committee on Finance.",
        "According to parliamentary sources, some of the committees (almost seventy in number) which were abolished with the conclusion of the second session of the Ninth Parliament have been appointed and the rest of the committees will be appointed in the coming days."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Cope Eran - Cope Kabir",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Samagi",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Eran Wickramaratne",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Parliamentary Committee on Public Affairs",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "COPE Committee",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Third",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Ninth Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kabir Hashim",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Parliamentary Committee on Public Accounts",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "COPE Committee",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Lakshman Kiriella",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Charita Herath",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "Podujana Peramuna",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Parliamentary Committee on Public Affairs",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Ninth Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Tissa Witharana",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Parliamentary Committee on Public Accounts",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "COPE",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "COPA",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "two",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Lawyer Lakshman Kiriella",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "The Parliamentary Committee of Selection",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Harsha De Silva",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Opposition",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Parliamentary Committee on Finance",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "second",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Ninth Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the coming days",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "කෝප් එරාන්ට - කෝපා කබීර්ට",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "නවවෙනි පාර්ලිමේන්තුවේ තෙවැනි සභාවාරයේ පොදු ව්‍යාපාර පිළිබඳ පාර්ලිමේන්තු කාරක සභාවේ( කෝප් කමිටුව) සභාපති ධූරය සඳහා සමගි ජන බලවේගය පක්ෂයේ පාර්ලිමේන්තු මන්ත්‍රී එරාන් වික්‍රමරත්න මහතාද රාජ්‍ය ගිණුම් පිළිබඳ පාර්ලිමේන්තු කාරක සභාවේ ( කෝපා කමිටුව) සභාපති ධූරය සඳහා එම පක්ෂයේ පාර්ලිමේන්තු මන්ත්‍රී කබීර් හෂීම් මහතාද පත් කිරීමට නියමිතව ඇතැයි පාර්ලිමේන්තු ආරංචි මාර්ගවලින් පැවසේ.",
        "මේ සම්බන්ධයෙන් අප විපක්ෂයේ ප්‍රධාන සංවිධායක පාර්ලිමේන්තු මන්ත්‍රී නීතිඥ ලක්ෂ්මන් කිරිඇල්ල මහතාගෙන් කළ විමසුමකදී ඔහු පැවසුවේ ඒ සම්බන්ධයෙන් යෝජනා ඉදිරිපත්ව ඇති බවයි.",
        "නවවෙනි පාර්ලිමේන්තුවේ දෙවැනි සභාවාරයේ පොදු ව්‍යාපාර පිළිබඳ පාර්ලිමේන්තු කාරක සභාවේ සභාපතිවරයා ලෙස මෙයට පෙර කටයුතු කළේ ශ්‍රී ලංකා පොදුජන පෙරමුණේ පත්කළ පාර්ලිමේන්තු මන්ත්‍රී මහාචාර්ය චරිත හේරත් මහතාය.",
        "මහාචාර්ය තිස්ස විතාරණ මහතා රාජ්‍ය ගිණුම් පිළිබඳ පාර්ලිමේන්තු කාරක සභාවේ සභාපතිවරයා ලෙස මෙයට පෙර කටයුතු කළේය.",
        "කෝප් සහ කෝපා යනු රාජ්‍ය ආයතනවල දූෂණ වංචා අක්‍රමිකතා සහ අවභාවිතා පිළිබඳව විමර්ශන පවත්වා නිර්දේශ ඉදිරිපත් කරනු ලබන පාර්ලිමේන්තුවේ ප්‍රධාන කමිටු දෙක වෙයි.",
        "පාර්ලිමේන්තුවේ සියලු කමිටුවල සභාපති ධූර විපක්ෂයේ මන්ත්‍රීවරුන්ට ලබා දෙන්නැයි විපක්ෂයේ ප්‍රධාන සංවිධායක පාර්ලිමේන්තු මන්ත්‍රී නීතිඥ ලක්ෂ්මන් කිරිඇල්ල මහතා පාර්ලිමේන්තු කටයුතු පිළිබඳ කාරක සභා රැස්වීමේදී කතානායකවරයාගෙන් පසුගියදා ඉල්ලීමක් කළේය.",
        "ඒ අවස්ථාවේදී ඊට කතානායකවරයාගේ පැහැදිලි එකඟත්වය පළවූ බව දැනගන්නට ඇත.",
        "මුදල් පිළිබඳ පාර්ලිමේන්තු කාරක සභාවේ සභාපති ධූරයට විපක්ෂයේ මන්ත්‍රීවරයකු වන ආචාර්ය හර්ෂ ද සිල්වා මහතා පත් කිරීමට පාර්ලිමේන්තු තේරීම් කාරක සභාව ( committee of selection ) පසුගියදා තීරණය කළේය.",
        "නව වැනි පාර්ලිමේන්තුවේ දෙවැනි සභාවාරය අවසන් කිරීමත් සමග අහෝසි වූ එහි කමිටු( හැත්තෑවකට ආසන්න සංඛ්‍යාවක්) අතුරින් කිහිපයක් දැනට පත්කර ඇති අතර සෙසු කමිටුද පත් කිරීම ඉදිරි දිනවල කෙරෙනු ඇතැයි පාර්ලිමේන්තු ආරංචි මාර්ග සඳහන් කරයි."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "කෝප් එරන් - කෝප් කබීර්",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "සමගි",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "එරාන් වික්‍රමරත්න",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "මහජන කටයුතු පිළිබඳ පාර්ලිමේන්තු කාරක සභාව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "කෝප් කමිටුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "තෙවන",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "නවවැනි පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "කබීර් හෂීම්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "රජයේ ගිණුම් පිළිබඳ පාර්ලිමේන්තු කාරක සභාව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "කෝප් කමිටුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ලක්ෂ්මන් කිරිඇල්ල",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "චරිත හේරත්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "පොදුජන පෙරමුණ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "මහජන කටයුතු පිළිබඳ පාර්ලිමේන්තු කාරක සභාව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "නවවැනි පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "තිස්ස විතාරණ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "රජයේ ගිණුම් පිළිබඳ පාර්ලිමේන්තු කාරක සභාව",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "කෝප්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "COPA",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "දෙක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "නීතිඥ ලක්ෂ්මන් කිරිඇල්ල",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තු තේරීම් කාරක සභාව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "හර්ෂ ද සිල්වා",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "විපක්ෂ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "මුදල් පිළිබඳ පාර්ලිමේන්තු කාරක සභාව",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "දෙවැනි",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "නවවැනි පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉදිරි දින",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "கோப் ஏரான் - கோப் கபீர்",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "ஒன்பதாவது பாராளுமன்றத்தின் மூன்றாம் சபையின் பொது விவகாரங்களுக்கான பாராளுமன்ற குழுவின் (கோப் குழு) தலைவராக சமகி ஜன பலவேகய பாராளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர் எரான் விக்ரமரத்னவும், அதே கட்சியின் தலைவராக திரு.கபீர் ஹாஷிம் நியமிக்கப்படவுள்ளனர். பொதுக் கணக்குகளுக்கான நாடாளுமன்றக் குழு (கோப் குழு) என நாடாளுமன்ற வட்டாரங்கள் தெரிவிக்கின்றன.",
        "இது தொடர்பில் எமது எதிர்கட்சியின் பிரதம அமைப்பாளர் சட்டத்தரணி திரு.லக்ஷ்மன் கிரியெல்லவிடம் வினவிய போது இது தொடர்பான முன்மொழிவுகள் சமர்ப்பிக்கப்பட்டுள்ளதாக தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "ஸ்ரீலங்கா பொதுஜன பெரமுனவினால் நியமிக்கப்பட்ட நாடாளுமன்ற உறுப்பினரான பேராசிரியர் சரித ஹேரத், ஒன்பதாவது பாராளுமன்றத்தின் இரண்டாவது சபையில் பொது விவகாரங்களுக்கான பாராளுமன்றக் குழுவின் தலைவராக பணியாற்றினார்.",
        "பேராசிரியர் திஸ்ஸ விதாரண இதற்கு முன்னர் பாராளுமன்ற பொதுக் கணக்குக் குழுவின் தலைவராகப் பணியாற்றினார்.",
        "COPE மற்றும் COPA ஆகியவை பாராளுமன்றத்தின் இரண்டு முக்கிய குழுக்களாகும், அவை பொது நிறுவனங்களில் ஊழல், மோசடி, முறைகேடுகள் மற்றும் முறைகேடுகள் குறித்து விசாரணைகளை நடத்தி பரிந்துரைகளை வழங்குகின்றன.",
        "நாடாளுமன்றத்தின் அனைத்துக் குழுக்களின் தலைவர் பதவியையும் எதிர்க்கட்சி உறுப்பினர்களுக்கு வழங்குமாறு எதிர்க்கட்சியின் பிரதம அமைப்பாளர் சட்டத்தரணி லக்ஷ்மன் கிரியெல்ல அண்மையில் நாடாளுமன்ற விவகாரக் குழுக் கூட்டத்தில் சபாநாயகரிடம் கோரிக்கை விடுத்திருந்தார்.",
        "அப்போது, ​​சபாநாயகர் அதற்கு தெளிவாக ஒப்புக்கொண்டதாக தெரிய வந்துள்ளது.",
        "நிதி தொடர்பான பாராளுமன்றக் குழுவின் தலைவராக எதிர்க்கட்சி உறுப்பினர் கலாநிதி ஹர்ஷ டி சில்வாவை நியமிக்க நாடாளுமன்ற தெரிவுக்குழு அண்மையில் தீர்மானித்தது.",
        "ஒன்பதாவது பாராளுமன்றத்தின் இரண்டாவது அமர்வு முடிவடைந்த நிலையில் இரத்து செய்யப்பட்ட குழுக்களில் சில (கிட்டத்தட்ட எழுபது எண்ணிக்கை) நியமிக்கப்பட்டுள்ளதாகவும் எஞ்சிய குழுக்கள் எதிர்வரும் நாட்களில் நியமிக்கப்படவுள்ளதாக பாராளுமன்ற வட்டாரங்கள் தெரிவிக்கின்றன."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "கோப் ஏரான் - கோப் கபீர்",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "சமகி",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "எரான் விக்கிரமரத்ன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "பொது விவகாரங்களுக்கான நாடாளுமன்றக் குழு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "கோப் குழு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "மூன்றாவது",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஒன்பதாவது பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "கபீர் ஹாசிம்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "பொதுக் கணக்குகளுக்கான நாடாளுமன்றக் குழு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "கோப் குழு",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "லக்ஷ்மன் கிரியெல்ல",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "சரிதா ஹேரத்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "பொதுஜன பெரமுன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "பொது விவகாரங்களுக்கான நாடாளுமன்றக் குழு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஒன்பதாவது பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "திஸ்ஸ விதாரண",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "பொதுக் கணக்குகளுக்கான நாடாளுமன்றக் குழு",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "கோப்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "COPA",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இரண்டு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "சட்டத்தரணி லக்ஷ்மன் கிரியெல்ல",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "நாடாளுமன்றத் தேர்வுக் குழு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஹர்ஷ டி சில்வா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "எதிர்ப்பு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "நிதிக்கான நாடாளுமன்றக் குழு",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இரண்டாவது",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஒன்பதாவது பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "வரும் நாட்கள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}