{
  "newspaper_id": "daily-mirror-lk",
  "url": "https://www.dailymirror.lk/breaking_news/Struggle-should-go-ahead-until-new-govt-formed-with-new-mandate-JVP/108-240761",
  "time_ut": 1657452357,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Struggle should go ahead until new govt. formed with new mandate: JVP",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Struggle should go ahead until new govt. formed with new mandate: JVP",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "Claiming that the struggle should not be given up even after the resignation of the President and the Prime Minister, the Janatha Vimukthi Peramuna (JVP) said today it should continue until a new government is formed with a new mandate to reap the true benefit of the victory.",
        "JVP General Secretary Tilvin Silva told a news conference that the objective of the struggle was not only the removal of the President and the Prime Minister, but it was aimed at making a system change through a transformation of the 74-year- old failed economic, political and social system.",
        "He said the current economic, political and social crisis would not be resolved even after the resignation of the President and pointed out that a new government with a new mandate should be formed to resolve this crisis situation.",
        "\"Some factions are trying to grab power by taking the situation as an advantage.They are trying to appoint a President and Prime Minister through the current Parliament and govern the country. We urge people not to get caught in such ploys. We can achieve the final victory only after forming a new government.We cannot find solutions to the burning issues by the composition of the current Parliament, as the Sri Lanka Podujana Peramuna (SLPP) still holds the majority in parliament. We need to form an interim government for a short period of time and its first task should be to hold an election,\" he said.",
        "Mr. Silva said the President had to announce his resignation as he realised that his mandate was negated now and added that the mandate of the Parliament was also negated now.",
        "“Parliament is no longer valid now. This Parliament is not capable of resolving this crisis. It is not either ethical and democratic for this Parliament to resolve the crisis now,” he said. (Ajith Siriwardana)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "JVP",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "the Janatha Vimukthi Peramuna",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "JVP",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Tilvin Silva",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "74-year- old",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Sri Lanka Podujana Peramuna",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "first",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Silva",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "now",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ajith Siriwardana",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "නව රජයක් එනතුරු අරගලය ඉදිරියට යා යුතුයි. නව ජනවරමක් සහිතව පිහිටුවන ලදී: JVP",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "ජනාධිපතිවරයා සහ අග්‍රාමාත්‍යවරයා ඉල්ලා අස්වුවත් අරගලය අත් නොහැරිය යුතු බව පවසන ජනතා විමුක්ති පෙරමුණ අද ප්‍රකාශ කළේ එහි සැබෑ ප්‍රතිලාභය ලබා ගැනීම සඳහා නව ජනවරමක් සහිත නව රජයක් පිහිටුවන තුරු අඛණ්ඩව ඉදිරියට යා යුතු බවයි. ජයග්රහණය.",
        "ජනතා විමුක්ති පෙරමුණේ ප්‍රධාන ලේකම් ටිල්වින් සිල්වා ප්‍රවෘත්ති සාකච්ඡාවකට එක්වෙමින් කියා සිටියේ මෙම අරගලයේ අරමුණ ජනාධිපතිවරයා සහ අගමැතිවරයා ඉවත් කිරීම පමණක් නොව වසර 74ක අසාර්ථක ආර්ථික පරිවර්තනයක් හරහා ක්‍රමවේද වෙනසක් ඇති කිරීම එහි අරමුණ බවයි. දේශපාලන හා සමාජ පද්ධතිය.",
        "වත්මන් ආර්ථික, දේශපාලන හා සමාජීය අර්බුදය ජනාධිපතිවරයා ඉල්ලා අස්වීමෙන් පසුවද නොවිසඳෙන බවත් මෙම අර්බුදකාරී තත්ත්වය විසඳීමට නව ජනවරමක් සහිත නව රජයක් පිහිටුවිය යුතු බවද පෙන්වා දුන්නේය.",
        "“ඇතැම් කල්ලි මේ තත්ත්වය වාසියට අරගෙන බලය ගන්න හදනවා.ඔවුන් හදන්නේ වත්මන් පාර්ලිමේන්තුව හරහා ජනාධිපතිවරයෙක් අගමැතිවරයෙක් පත්කරගෙන රට පාලනය කරන්නයි.අපි ජනතාවගෙන් ඉල්ලා සිටින්නේ මෙවැනි කූට උපක්‍රමවලට හසු නොවන ලෙසයි.අපට ජයග්‍රහණය කළ හැකියි. අවසන් ජයග්‍රහණය නව රජයක් පිහිටුවීමෙන් පසුවයි.ශ්‍රී ලංකා පොදුජන පෙරමුණට තවමත් පාර්ලිමේන්තුවේ බහුතරය තිබෙන බැවින් දැවෙන ප්‍රශ්නවලට වත්මන් පාර්ලිමේන්තුවේ සංයුතියෙන් විසඳුම් සෙවිය නොහැක.අතුරු ආණ්ඩුවක් පිහිටුවිය යුතුයි. කෙටි කාලයක් සහ එහි පළමු කාර්යය විය යුත්තේ මැතිවරණයක් පැවැත්වීමයි,\" ඔහු පැවසීය.",
        "තමාගේ ජනවරම දැන් නිෂ්ප්‍රභ වී ඇති බව තේරුම් ගත් බැවින් ජනාධිපතිවරයාට ඉල්ලා අස්වීම ප්‍රකාශ කිරීමට සිදු වූ බව පැවසූ සිල්වා මහතා පාර්ලිමේන්තු ජනවරමද දැන් නිශේධනය වී ඇති බව පැවසීය.",
        "“දැන් පාර්ලිමේන්තුව වලංගු නැහැ. මේ අර්බුදය විසඳන්න මේ පාර්ලිමේන්තුවට හැකියාවක් නැහැ. මේ පාර්ලිමේන්තුව දැන් අර්බුදය විසඳන එක සදාචාරාත්මක සහ ප්‍රජාතන්ත්‍රවාදී නැහැ,” ඔහු පැවසීය. (අජිත් සිරිවර්ධන)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ජ.වි.පෙ",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ජනතා විමුක්ති පෙරමුණ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජ.වි.පෙ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ටිල්වින් සිල්වා",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "74 හැවිරිදිය",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකා පොදුජන පෙරමුණ",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "පළමුවන",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "සිල්වා",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "දැන්",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "අජිත් සිරිවර්ධන",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "புதிய அரசு அமையும் வரை போராட்டம் தொடர வேண்டும். புதிய ஆணையுடன் உருவாக்கப்பட்டது: ஜே.வி.பி",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "ஜனாதிபதி மற்றும் பிரதமர் பதவி விலகிய பின்னரும் போராட்டத்தை கைவிடக் கூடாது என்று கூறியுள்ள மக்கள் விடுதலை முன்னணி (ஜே.வி.பி) புதிய அரசை அமைக்கும் வரையில், அதன் உண்மையான பலனைப் பெறும் வரை போராட்டம் தொடர வேண்டும் என தெரிவித்துள்ளது. வெற்றி.",
        "ஜே.வி.பி.யின் பொதுச் செயலாளர் டில்வின் சில்வா செய்தியாளர் மாநாட்டில் பேசுகையில், இப்போராட்டத்தின் நோக்கம் ஜனாதிபதி மற்றும் பிரதமரை பதவி நீக்கம் செய்வது மாத்திரமல்ல, 74 வருடகால தோல்வியடைந்த பொருளாதாரத்தை மாற்றியமைத்து முறைமை மாற்றத்தை ஏற்படுத்துவதை நோக்கமாகக் கொண்டது. அரசியல் மற்றும் சமூக அமைப்பு.",
        "தற்போதைய பொருளாதார, அரசியல் மற்றும் சமூக நெருக்கடிக்கு ஜனாதிபதி பதவி விலகிய பின்னரும் தீர்வு காணப்படாது என தெரிவித்த அவர், இந்த நெருக்கடி நிலையை தீர்க்க புதிய அரசாணையுடன் கூடிய புதிய அரசாங்கம் உருவாக்கப்பட வேண்டுமெனவும் சுட்டிக்காட்டினார்.",
        "\"சில தரப்பினர் நிலைமையை சாதகமாகப் பயன்படுத்தி ஆட்சியைப் பிடிக்க முயற்சிக்கின்றனர். தற்போதைய நாடாளுமன்றத்தின் மூலம் ஜனாதிபதி மற்றும் பிரதமரை நியமித்து நாட்டை ஆள முயற்சிக்கின்றனர். இதுபோன்ற தந்திரங்களில் சிக்கிக் கொள்ள வேண்டாம் என்று மக்களை கேட்டுக்கொள்கிறோம். எம்மால் சாதிக்க முடியும். புதிய அரசாங்கத்தை அமைத்ததன் பின்னரே இறுதி வெற்றி.இப்போதும் ஸ்ரீலங்கா பொதுஜன பெரமுன (SLPP) பாராளுமன்றத்தில் பெரும்பான்மையைக் கொண்டிருப்பதால் தற்போதைய நாடாளுமன்றத்தின் மூலம் எரியும் பிரச்சினைகளுக்கு தீர்வு காண முடியாது.நாம் ஒரு இடைக்கால அரசாங்கத்தை அமைக்க வேண்டும். குறுகிய கால அவகாசம் மற்றும் அதன் முதல் பணி தேர்தலை நடத்துவதாக இருக்க வேண்டும்,\" என்றார்.",
        "ஜனாதிபதி தனது ஆணை தற்போது நிராகரிக்கப்பட்டிருப்பதை உணர்ந்ததன் காரணமாகவே தனது பதவி விலகலை அறிவிக்க நேரிட்டதாகத் தெரிவித்த திரு.",
        "“நாடாளுமன்றம் இப்போது செல்லாது. இந்த நெருக்கடியை தீர்க்கும் திறன் இந்த பாராளுமன்றத்திற்கு இல்லை. இந்த நாடாளுமன்றம் இப்போது நெருக்கடியைத் தீர்ப்பது நெறிமுறை மற்றும் ஜனநாயகம் அல்ல, ”என்று அவர் கூறினார். (அஜித் சிறிவர்தன)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ஜே.வி.பி",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ஜனதா விமுக்தி பெரமுனா",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜே.வி.பி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "டில்வின் சில்வா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "74 வயது",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஸ்ரீலங்கா பொதுஜன பெரமுனா",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "முதலில்",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "சில்வா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இப்போது",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "அஜித் சிறிவர்தன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}