{
  "newspaper_id": "news-first-lk",
  "url": "https://www.newsfirst.lk/2022/07/18/24-hrs-more-for-nominations-for-president/",
  "time_ut": 1658122800,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "24-hrs more for nominations for President",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "24-hrs more for nominations for President",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); There are less than 24-hours left for MPs to announce their candidacy to run for President of Sri Lanka.",
        "Acting President Ranil Wickramasinghe, Opposition Leader Sajith Premadasa, Anura Kumara Dissanayake, and Dullas Alahapperuma have already announced that they will contest for President.",
        "The Sri Lanka Podujana Peramuna (SLPP) is currently divided regarding the selection of its presidential candidate.",
        "The Leader of the Democratic Left Front Vasudeva Nanayakkara said that the support of the Democratic Left Front will be given to Dullas Alahapperuma.",
        "Meanwhile, E.P.D.P Leader Douglas Devananda announced that his party will support Acting President Ranil Wickramasinghe.",
        "The Leader of the Sri Lanka Muslim Congress Rauf Hakeem said that he agrees with any decision taken by the Samagi Jana Balawegaya in this regard."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "24",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "News 1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "24-hours",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickramasinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sajith Premadasa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Anura",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kumara Dissanayake",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Dullas Alahapperuma",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "Podujana Peramuna",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the Democratic Left Front Vasudeva Nanayakkara",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Democratic Left Front",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Dullas Alahapperuma",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "E.P.D.P",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Douglas Devananda",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickramasinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Muslim",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Rauf Hakeem",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Samagi",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "ජනපතිට නාමයෝජනා දීමට තවත් පැය 24ක්",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); පාර්ලිමේන්තු මන්ත්‍රීවරුන්ට ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ ජනාධිපති අපේක්ෂකත්වය සඳහා අපේක්ෂකත්වය ප්‍රකාශ කිරීමට ඉතිරිව ඇත්තේ පැය 24කට අඩු කාලයකි.",
        "වැඩබලන ජනාධිපති රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ, විපක්ෂ නායක සජිත් ප්‍රේමදාස, අනුර කුමාර දිසානායක, ඩලස් අලහප්පෙරුම යන මහත්වරුන් තමන් ජනාධිපතිවරණයට ඉදිරිපත් වන බව දැනටමත් ප්‍රකාශ කර තිබේ.",
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකා පොදුජන පෙරමුණ (SLPP) ජනාධිපති අපේක්ෂකයා තේරීම සම්බන්ධයෙන් මේ වන විට දෙකඩ වී ඇත.",
        "ප්‍රජාතන්ත්‍රවාදී වාමාංශික පෙරමුණේ සහය ඩලස් අලහප්පෙරුම මහතාට ලබාදෙන බව ප්‍රජාතන්ත්‍රවාදී වාමාංශික පෙරමුණේ නායක වාසුදේව නානායක්කාර මහතා පැවසීය.",
        "මේ අතර E.P.D.P නායක ඩග්ලස් දේවානන්ද ප්‍රකාශ කළේ තම පක්ෂය වැඩබලන ජනාධිපති රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතාට සහය පළ කරන බවයි.",
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකා මුස්ලිම් කොංග්‍රසයේ නායක රවුෆ් හකීම් මහතා පැවසුවේ මේ සම්බන්ධයෙන් සමගි ජන බලවේගය ගන්නා ඕනෑම තීරණයකට තමන් එකඟ වන බවයි."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "24",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "News 1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "පැය 24",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "සජිත් ප්‍රේමදාස",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "අනුර",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "කුමාර දිසානායක",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඩලස් අලහප්පෙරුම",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "පොදුජන පෙරමුණ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ප්‍රජාතන්ත්‍රවාදී වාමාංශික පෙරමුණ වාසුදේව නානායක්කාර",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ප්‍රජාතන්ත්‍රවාදී වාම පෙරමුණ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඩලස් අලහප්පෙරුම",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ඊ.පී.ඩී.පී",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඩග්ලස් දේවානන්ද",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "මුස්ලිම්",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "රවුෆ් හකීම්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "සමගි",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "ஜனாதிபதிக்கான வேட்புமனு தாக்கல் செய்ய இன்னும் 24 மணிநேரம்",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); இலங்கையின் ஜனாதிபதி தேர்தலில் போட்டியிடுவதற்கு எம்.பி.க்கள் தங்கள் வேட்புமனுவை அறிவிக்க இன்னும் 24 மணி நேரத்திற்கும் குறைவான நேரமே உள்ளது.",
        "பதில் ஜனாதிபதி ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க, எதிர்க்கட்சித் தலைவர் சஜித் பிரேமதாச, அனுரகுமார திஸாநாயக்க மற்றும் டலஸ் அழகப்பெரும ஆகியோர் ஜனாதிபதி தேர்தலில் போட்டியிடவுள்ளதாக ஏற்கனவே அறிவித்துள்ளனர்.",
        "ஸ்ரீலங்கா பொதுஜன பெரமுன (SLPP) ஜனாதிபதி வேட்பாளர் தெரிவு தொடர்பில் தற்போது பிளவுபட்டுள்ளது.",
        "ஜனநாயக இடதுசாரி முன்னணியின் ஆதரவு டலஸ் அழகப்பெருமவுக்கு வழங்கப்படும் என ஜனநாயக இடதுசாரி முன்னணியின் தலைவர் வாசுதேவ நாணயக்கார தெரிவித்துள்ளார்.",
        "இதேவேளை, ஈ.பி.டி.பியின் தலைவர் டக்ளஸ் தேவானந்தா, தமது கட்சி பதில் ஜனாதிபதி ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்கவுக்கு ஆதரவளிக்கவுள்ளதாக அறிவித்துள்ளார்.",
        "இது தொடர்பில் சமகி ஜன பலவேகய எடுக்கும் எந்தவொரு தீர்மானத்திற்கும் உடன்படுவதாக ஸ்ரீலங்கா முஸ்லிம் காங்கிரஸின் தலைவர் ரவூப் ஹக்கீம் தெரிவித்துள்ளார்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "24",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "News 1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "24 மணி நேரம்",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "சஜித் பிரேமதாச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "அனுர",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "குமார திஸாநாயக்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "டலஸ் அழகப்பெரும",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "பொதுஜன பெரமுன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஜனநாயக இடதுசாரி முன்னணி வாசுதேவ நாணயக்கார",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜனநாயக இடது முன்னணி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "டலஸ் அழகப்பெரும",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஈ.பி.டி.பி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "டக்ளஸ் தேவானந்தா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "முஸ்லிம்",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரவூப் ஹக்கீம்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "சமகி",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}