{
  "newspaper_id": "lankadeepa-lk",
  "url": "https://www.lankadeepa.lk/latest_news/මහඔය-පොහොර-වංචාවක්-ගැන-විමර්ශනක්/1-617133",
  "time_ut": 1658917060,
  "original_lang": "si",
  "original_title": "මහඔය පොහොර වංචාවක් ගැන විමර්ශනක්",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "An investigation into a Mahaoya fertilizer scam",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "The Minister of Agriculture, Mr. Mahinda Amaraweera, instructed the Secretary of the Ministry, Mr. Rohana Pushpakumara, to conduct an investigation regarding a urea fertilizer fraud that has occurred in the Ampara Mahaoya area.",
        "This investigation is being conducted regarding a case of a Mahaoya farmer's organization fraudulently selling a stock of urea fertilizer that was given to farmers for distribution to a private businessman.",
        "The Ministry of Agriculture says that the businessman who got the fertilizer has sold the fertilizer to the farmers at a higher price and the police have arrested all those involved in the fraud."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Mahaoya",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Mahinda Amaraweera",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Rohana Pushpakumara",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ampara Mahaoya",
            "label": "LOC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Mahaoya",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "The Ministry of Agriculture",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "මහඔය පොහොර වංචාවක් ගැන විමර්ශනක්",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "අම්පාර මහඔය ප්‍රදේශයේ සිදුව ඇති යුරියා පොහොර වංචාවක් සම්බන්ධයෙන් විමර්ශනයක් කරන ලෙස කෘෂිකර්ම අමාත්‍ය මහින්ද අමරවීර මහතා අමාත්‍යාංශයේ ලේකම් රෝහණ පුෂ්පකුමාර මහතාට උපදෙස් දුන්නේය.",
        "ගොවි ජනතාවට බෙදාහැරීමට ලබා දුන් යුරියා පොහොර තොගයක් මහඔය ගොවි සංවිධානයක් විසින් වංචා සහගතව පෞද්ගලික ව්‍යාපාරිකයකුට අලෙවි කිරීමෙි සිද්ධියක් සම්බන්ධයෙන් මෙම විමර්ශනය සිදු කෙරෙයි.",
        "පොහොර ලබාගත් ව්‍යාපාරිකයා අදාල පොහොර වැඩි මුදලට ගොවීන්ට අලෙවි කර ඇතැයි ද එම වංචාවට සම්බන්ධ සියලු දෙනා පොලිසිය විසින් අත් අඩංගුවට ගෙන ඇතැයි ද කෘෂිකර්ම අමාත්‍යාංශය කියයි."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Mahaoya",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "මහින්ද අමරවීර",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "රෝහණ පුෂ්පකුමාර",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "අම්පාර මහඔය",
            "label": "LOC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Mahaoya",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "කෘෂිකර්ම අමාත්‍යාංශය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "மஹாஓயா உர மோசடி தொடர்பில் விசாரணை",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "அம்பாறை மஹாஓயா பிரதேசத்தில் இடம்பெற்ற யூரியா உர மோசடி தொடர்பில் விசாரணைகளை மேற்கொள்ளுமாறு விவசாய அமைச்சர் மஹிந்த அமரவீர, அமைச்சின் செயலாளர் ரோஹன புஸ்பகுமாரவிடம் பணிப்புரை விடுத்துள்ளார்.",
        "விவசாயிகளுக்கு விநியோகிப்பதற்காக வழங்கப்பட்ட யூரியா உரத்தை தனியார் வர்த்தகர் ஒருவருக்கு மஹாஓயா விவசாய அமைப்பொன்று மோசடியான முறையில் விற்பனை செய்தமை தொடர்பிலேயே இந்த விசாரணை நடத்தப்பட்டு வருகின்றது.",
        "உரத்தைப் பெற்ற வர்த்தகர் உரத்தை அதிக விலைக்கு விவசாயிகளுக்கு விற்பனை செய்துள்ளதாகவும், மோசடியில் ஈடுபட்ட அனைவரையும் பொலிஸார் கைது செய்துள்ளதாகவும் விவசாய அமைச்சு தெரிவித்துள்ளது."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Mahaoya",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "மஹிந்த அமரவீர",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரோஹன புஷ்பகுமார",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "அம்பாறை மஹாஓயா",
            "label": "LOC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Mahaoya",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "விவசாய அமைச்சகம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}