{
  "newspaper_id": "news-first-lk",
  "url": "https://www.newsfirst.lk/2022/07/01/fuel-crisis-paper-marking-affected/",
  "time_ut": 1656661860,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Fuel Crisis: Paper Marking Affected",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Fuel Crisis: Paper Marking Affected",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); The Second Phase of Paper Marking for the G. C. E Ordinary Level Examination was suspended temporarily due to the fuel crisis in the country.",
        "Commissioner General of Examination L. M. D. Dharmasena said that Phase One of Paper Marking was completed on a successful note.",
        "2021 A/Level Practical Examinations for engineering technology is currently underway.",
        "Examinations Commissioner General said that practical examinations will be conducted until the 10th of July.",
        "Accordingly, Examinations Commissioner General L.M.D Dharmasena said that A/Level examination results will be released by the end of July or within the 1st two weeks of August."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "The Second Phase of Paper Marking",
            "label": "WORK_OF_ART"
          },
          {
            "text": "the G. C. E Ordinary Level Examination",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Examination L. M. D. Dharmasena",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Phase One",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "2021",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the 10th of July",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Examinations",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "L.M.D Dharmasena",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the end of July",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the 1st two weeks of August",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "ඉන්ධන අර්බුදය: කඩදාසි සලකුණු කිරීම බලපායි",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); දිවයිනේ පවතින ඉන්ධන අර්බුදය හේතුවෙන් අ.පො.ස සාමාන්‍ය පෙළ විභාගයේ දෙවන අදියරේ ප්‍රශ්න පත්‍ර ලකුණු කිරීම තාවකාලිකව අත්හිටුවා තිබේ.",
        "විභාග කොමසාරිස් ජනරාල් L. M. D. ධර්මසේන මහතා පැවසුවේ, ප්‍රශ්න පත්‍ර ලකුණු කිරීමේ පළමු අදියර සාර්ථක ලෙස නිම කළ බව ය.",
        "ඉංජිනේරු තාක්ෂණය සඳහා 2021 උසස් පෙළ ප්‍රායෝගික පරීක්ෂණ මේ වන විට පැවැත්වේ.",
        "ප්‍රායෝගික පරීක්ෂණ ජූලි 10 වැනිදා දක්වා පැවැත්වෙන බව විභාග කොමසාරිස් ජනරාල්වරයා පැවසීය.",
        "ඒ අනුව උසස් පෙළ විභාග ප්‍රතිඵල ජුලි මස අවසන් වන විට හෝ අගෝස්තු පළමු සති දෙක තුළ නිකුත් කරන බව විභාග කොමසාරිස් ජනරාල් L.M.D ධර්මසේන මහතා පැවසීය."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "කඩදාසි සලකුණු කිරීමේ දෙවන අදියර",
            "label": "WORK_OF_ART"
          },
          {
            "text": "G. C. E සාමාන්‍ය පෙළ විභාගය",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "විභාගය L. M. D. ධර්මසේන",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "පළමු අදියර",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "2021",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ජූලි 10 වෙනිදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "විභාග",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "L.M.D ධර්මසේන",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජූලි අග",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "අගෝස්තු පළමු සති දෙක",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "எரிபொருள் நெருக்கடி: காகிதக் குறியிடுதல் பாதிக்கப்பட்டது",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); நாட்டில் ஏற்பட்டுள்ள எரிபொருள் நெருக்கடி காரணமாக G. C. E சாதாரண தரப் பரீட்சைக்கான தாள் குறியிடல் இரண்டாம் கட்டம் தற்காலிகமாக இடைநிறுத்தப்பட்டுள்ளது.",
        "தாள் குறியிடுதலின் ஒரு கட்டம் வெற்றிகரமாக நிறைவடைந்ததாக பரீட்சை ஆணையாளர் நாயகம் எல்.எம்.டி.தர்மசேன தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "பொறியியல் தொழில்நுட்பத்திற்கான 2021 உயர்தர நடைமுறைத் தேர்வுகள் தற்போது நடைபெற்று வருகின்றன.",
        "நடைமுறைப் பரீட்சைகள் எதிர்வரும் ஜூலை மாதம் 10ஆம் திகதி வரை நடைபெறும் என பரீட்சைகள் ஆணையாளர் நாயகம் தெரிவித்துள்ளார்.",
        "அதன்படி, உயர்தரப் பரீட்சை பெறுபேறுகள் ஜூலை மாத இறுதியில் அல்லது ஆகஸ்ட் மாதம் முதலாம் திகதி இரண்டு வாரங்களுக்குள் வெளியிடப்படும் என பரீட்சைகள் ஆணையாளர் நாயகம் எல்.எம்.டி.தர்மசேன தெரிவித்துள்ளார்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "காகித குறியிடலின் இரண்டாம் கட்டம்",
            "label": "WORK_OF_ART"
          },
          {
            "text": "G. C. E சாதாரண தரப் பரீட்சை",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பரீட்சை L. M. D. தர்மசேன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "முதல் கட்டம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "2021",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஜூலை 10 ஆம் தேதி",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "தேர்வுகள்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "எல்.எம்.டி தர்மசேன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜூலை இறுதியில்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆகஸ்ட் முதல் இரண்டு வாரங்கள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}