{
  "newspaper_id": "lankadeepa-lk",
  "url": "https://www.lankadeepa.lk/news/’කොවිඩ්-19’-වෙනස්-වෙලා:-අවසන්-නෑ/101-615629",
  "time_ut": 1656554954,
  "original_lang": "si",
  "original_title": "’කොවිඩ් 19’ වෙනස් වෙලා: අවසන් නෑ",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "‘Kovid 19’ has changed: not over",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "The World Health Organization (WHO) warns that the 'Kovid 19' corona epidemic is changing but not over yet. The World Health Organization (WHO) has warned that there is an increase in the number of Kovid 19 cases in many countries.",
        "‘The epidemic is changing. But not over. It is clear that there was a sharp decline in the virus. That is, with the advent of the omicchron mutation. However, subtypes of omicron mutation should be considered. Kovid 19 Immunization programs around the world have also helped to control the epidemic. Today, there is an increase of 19 cases of Covid in 19 countries. '",
        "The head of the World Health Organization explained this at a press conference in Geneva. The United Nations Headquarters is located in Geneva, Switzerland.",
        "The head of the World Health Organization (WHO) told the media that 70 percent of the world's population has now received the required dose of the Kovid 19 vaccine. In the last 18 months, 12 billion vaccines have been delivered worldwide.",
        "'BA5' and 'BA4' are the most commonly identified subtypes of the 'Kovid 19 Omicron' mutation, and the fastest-growing of these two subtypes is the 'BA5' variant. There are. It is said that the 'BA5' variant has now spread to 63 countries."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "19",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "The World Health Organization",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the 'Kovid 19' corona",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "The World Health Organization",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "19",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Today",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "19",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "19",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the World Health Organization",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Geneva",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "The United Nations Headquarters",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Geneva",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Switzerland",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the World Health Organization",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "70 percent",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "the last 18 months",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "12 billion",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "19",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "two",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "63",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "’කොවිඩ් 19’ වෙනස් වෙලා: අවසන් නෑ",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "‘කොවිඩ් 19’ කොරෝනා වසංගතය වෙනස් වෙමින් පවතින නමුත් එය තවමත් අවසන් නැතැයි ලෝක සෞඛ්‍ය සංවිධානය අනතුරු අඟවයි. ලෝක සෞඛ්‍ය සංවිධානය මෙසේ අනතුරු ඇඟවූයේ, රටවල් රැසකින් ‘කොවිඩ් 19’ ආසාදිතයන්ගේ වැඩි වීමක් පෙන්නුම් කරන බැවිනි.",
        "‘වසංගතය වෙනස් වෙනවා. නමුත් අවසන් නැහැ. වයිරසයේ සැර බාල වීමක් සිදුවුණු බව පැහැදිලියි. ඒ, ඔමික්‍රෝන් විකෘතියේ ආගමනයත් සමඟයි. කෙසේ නමුත් ඔමික්‍රෝන් විකෘතියේ උප ප්‍රභේද ගැන විමසිල්ලෙන් සිටිය යුතුයි. කොවිඩ් 19  ප්‍රතිශක්තිකරණ එන්නත් වැඩසටහන් ලොව පුරා ක්‍රියාත්මක වීමත් වසංගතය පාලනයට උපකාරී වුණා. අද වනවිට රටවල් 110 කින් කොවිඩ්ඩ් 19 ආසාදිතයන්ගේ වැඩිවීමක් පෙන්නුම් කරනවා.’ යැයි ලෝක සෞඛ්‍ය සංවිධානයේ ප්‍රධානී ඇඩ්හොම් ටෙඩ්‍රෝස් ගෙබ්‍රියේසිස් මාධය හමුවේ පැහැදිලි කළේය.",
        "ලෝක සෞඛ්‍ය සංවිධානයේ ප්‍රධානියා මෙසේ පැහැදිලි කළේ, ජිනීවා නුවර පැවැති මාධ්‍ය හමුවකදීය. එක්සත් ජාතීන්ගේ මූලස්ථානය පිහිටා ඇත්තේ ස්විට්සර්ලන්තයේ ජිනීවා නුවරය.",
        "මේ වනවිට ලෝකවාසීන්ගෙන් සියයට 70 කට ‘කොවිඩ් 19’ ප්‍රතිශක්තිකරණ එන්නතේ නියමිත එන්නත් මාත්‍රා ලැබි ඇතැයි ද ලෝක සෞඛ්‍ය සංවිධානයේ ප්‍රධානියා මාධ්‍ය හමුවේ දී පැවැසුවේය. පසුගිය මාස 18 ඇතුළත ලොව පුරා එන්නත් බිලියන 12 ක් ලබා දීම සිදු කර තිබේ.",
        "‘බී.ඒ.5’ සහ ‘බී.ඒ.4’ යනු ‘කොවිඩ් 19 ඔමික්‍රෝන්’ විකෘතියේ මෙතෙක් හඳුනාගෙන ඇති උප ප්‍රභේද වන අතර, මෙම උප ප්‍රභේද දෙක අතරින් ද වඩාත් වේගයෙන් ව්‍යාප්තිය සිදුවන්නේ ‘බී.ඒ.5’ ප්‍රභේදය යැයි හඳුනාගෙන තිබේ. ‘බී.ඒ.5’ ප්‍රභේදය මේ වනවිට රටවල් 63 කට ව්‍යාප්ත වී අවසන් බව ද පැවැසෙයි."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "19",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ලෝක සෞඛ්‍ය සංවිධානය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "'කොවිඩ් 19' කොරෝනා",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ලෝක සෞඛ්‍ය සංවිධානය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "19",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "19",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "19",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ලෝක සෞඛ්ය සංවිධානය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජිනීවා",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "එක්සත් ජාතීන්ගේ මූලස්ථානය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජිනීවා",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ස්විට්සර්ලන්තය",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ලෝක සෞඛ්ය සංවිධානය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "සියයට 70 කි",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "පසුගිය මාස 18",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "බිලියන 12 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "19",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "දෙක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "63",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "‘கோவிட் 19’ மாறிவிட்டது: முடிந்துவிடவில்லை",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "'கோவிட்-19' கொரோனா தொற்று மாறிவருகிறது, ஆனால் அது இன்னும் முடிவுக்கு வரவில்லை என்று உலக சுகாதார நிறுவனம் எச்சரித்துள்ளது. பல நாடுகளில் 'கோவிட் 19' நோயால் பாதிக்கப்பட்டவர்களின் எண்ணிக்கை அதிகரித்து வருவதால் உலக சுகாதார நிறுவனம் எச்சரித்துள்ளது.",
        "'தொற்றுநோய் மாறி வருகிறது. ஆனால் முடிக்கவில்லை. வைரஸின் கடுமையான சரிவு ஏற்பட்டுள்ளது என்பது தெளிவாகிறது. அது ஓமிக்ரான் பிறழ்வின் வருகையுடன் இருந்தது. இருப்பினும், ஓமிக்ரான் பிறழ்வின் துணை வகைகளைக் கவனியுங்கள். உலகெங்கிலும் உள்ள கோவிட்-19 தடுப்பூசி திட்டங்களும் தொற்றுநோயைக் கட்டுப்படுத்த உதவியது. இன்றைய நிலவரப்படி, 110 நாடுகளில் கோவிட் -19 நோயால் பாதிக்கப்பட்டவர்களின் எண்ணிக்கை அதிகரித்து வருகிறது' என்று உலக சுகாதார அமைப்பின் தலைவர் அதோம் டெட்ரோஸ் ஜெப்ரீசிஸ் ஊடகங்களுக்கு முன்னால் கூறினார்.",
        "ஜெனிவாவில் நடைபெற்ற செய்தியாளர் சந்திப்பில் உலக சுகாதார அமைப்பின் தலைவர் இதனை விளக்கினார். ஐக்கிய நாடுகள் சபையின் தலைமையகம் சுவிட்சர்லாந்தின் ஜெனீவாவில் அமைந்துள்ளது.",
        "உலக சுகாதார அமைப்பின் (WHO) தலைவர் ஊடகங்களுக்குத் தெரிவிக்கையில், உலக மக்கள் தொகையில் 70 சதவீதம் பேர் இப்போது கோவிட் 19 தடுப்பூசியின் தேவையான அளவைப் பெற்றுள்ளனர். கடந்த 18 மாதங்களில், உலகம் முழுவதும் 12 பில்லியன் தடுப்பூசிகள் வழங்கப்பட்டுள்ளன.",
        "'BA5' மற்றும் 'BA4' ஆகியவை இதுவரை கண்டறியப்பட்ட 'கோவிட் 19 ஓமிக்ரான்' பிறழ்வின் துணை வகைகளாகும், மேலும் இந்த இரண்டு துணை வகைகளில், 'BA5' மாறுபாடு மிக வேகமாக பரவுகிறது. தற்போது 'பிஏ5' வகை 63 நாடுகளில் பரவியுள்ளதாகவும் கூறப்படுகிறது."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "19",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "உலக சுகாதார நிறுவனம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "'கோவிட் 19' கரோனா",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "உலக சுகாதார நிறுவனம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "19",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "19",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "19",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "உலக சுகாதார நிறுவனம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜெனிவா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஐக்கிய நாடுகளின் தலைமையகம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜெனிவா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சுவிட்சர்லாந்து",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "உலக சுகாதார நிறுவனம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "70 சதவீதம்",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "கடந்த 18 மாதங்கள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "12 பில்லியன்",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "19",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "இரண்டு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "63",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}