{
  "newspaper_id": "ada-derana-lk",
  "url": "http://www.adaderana.lk/news/84750/plans-afoot-to-set-up-permanent-office-for-ex-servicemen-defence-secretary",
  "time_ut": 1662317400,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Plans afoot to set up permanent office for ex-servicemen: Defence Secretary",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Plans afoot to set up permanent office for ex-servicemen: Defence Secretary",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "Defence Secretary General (Retd) Kamal Gunaratne says plans are afoot to set up a fully-fledged permanent office building for Sri Lanka Ex-Servicemen’s Association within the Defence Headquarters premises.",
        "“Accordingly, a plot of land comprising 175 perches has been earmarked for this purpose”, he also said mentioning “government funds will not be used for this”.",
        "Defence Secretary Kamal Gunaratne was the Chief Guest at the 78th Anniversary Celebration of the Sri Lanka Ex-Servicemen’s Association (SLESA) which was held at the Eagles’ Lakeside Banquet and Convention Hall in Attidiya, on Sunday (04).",
        "During the Chief Guest’s address, the Defence Secretary also recalled the deceased and differently-able war veterans and their noble services rendered to safeguard the motherland during the three-decade long battle.",
        "“As we practiced in the recent past, we also look forward to enriching SLESA and its services along with the guidance of the current President,” he pledged.",
        "Referring to the recent struggle and protests, he said it is saddening to see the disseminating of disgraceful video footages undermining noble service of our young servicemen, under the guise of democracy.",
        "Thus, he requested the ex-servicemen to encourage the country’s young servicemen to perform their duties and protect the motherland.",
        "The Defence Secretary pinned ‘Gavurawanvitha Sewa Medal’ (Honorary Service Medal) on several SLESA members during the programme and also handed over a few books authored by him, to SLESA as a symbolic gesture.",
        "Established in 1944, the SLESA has developed to a remarkable position as of today with over 45,000 members in the 48 affiliated Armed Forces Associations.",
        "Secretary General of SLESA Lt. Col. Ajith Siyambalapitiya (Retd) delivered the vote of thanks marking the culmination of the event.",
        "Army Commander Lt. Gen. Vikum Liyanage, Navy Commander Vice Admiral Nishantha Ulugetenne, former Tri-Forces Commanders, Military Liaison Officer of the Defence Ministry Maj. Gen. Dinesh Nanayakkara, Secretary General of SLESA Lt. Col. Ajith Siyambalapitiya (Retd), a large number of SLESA members and distinguished invitees were present at the event."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Defence",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Defence",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kamal Gunaratne",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka Ex-Servicemen’s Association",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Defence Headquarters",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "175",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Defence",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kamal Gunaratne",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "78th",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Eagles’ Lakeside Banquet and Convention Hall",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Attidiya",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sunday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "04",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Defence",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "three-decade",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "SLESA",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "SLESA",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "SLESA",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "1944",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "SLESA",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "45,000",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "48",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Armed Forces Associations",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Ajith Siyambalapitiya",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Army",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Vikum Liyanage",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Navy",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Nishantha Ulugetenne",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Tri-Forces Commanders",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Defence Ministry",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Dinesh Nanayakkara",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ajith Siyambalapitiya",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "SLESA",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "හිටපු සෙබළුන් සඳහා ස්ථිර කාර්යාලයක් පිහිටුවීමට සැලසුම් කරනවා: ආරක්ෂක ලේකම්",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "ආරක්ෂක මූලස්ථාන පරිශ්‍රය තුළ ශ්‍රී ලංකා හිටපු සෙබළුන්ගේ සංගමය සඳහා අංග සම්පූර්ණ ස්ථිර කාර්යාල ගොඩනැගිල්ලක් පිහිටුවීමට සැලසුම් කර ඇති බව ආරක්ෂක මහලේකම් (විශ්‍රාමික) කමල් ගුණරත්න මහතා පවසයි.",
        "ඒ අනුව පර්චස් 175ක ඉඩමක් මේ සඳහා වෙන් කර ඇති බවත්, ඒ සඳහා රජයේ මුදල් භාවිත නොකරන බවත් ඔහු සඳහන් කළේය.",
        "ආරක්ෂක ලේකම් කමල් ගුණරත්න මහතා ඉරිදා (04) අත්තිඩිය ඊගල්ස් ලේක්සයිඩ් භෝජන සංග්‍රහය සහ සම්මන්ත්‍රණ ශාලාවේ පැවති ශ්‍රී ලංකා හිටපු සෙබළුන්ගේ සංගමයේ (SLESA) 78 වැනි සංවත්සර උත්සවයේ ප්‍රධාන ආරාධිත අමුත්තා ලෙස සහභාගි විය.",
        "ප්‍රධාන ආරාධිත අමුත්තාගේ දේශනය අතරතුර, ආරක්ෂක ලේකම්වරයා දශක තුනක යුද්ධයේදී මියගිය සහ ආබාධිත රණවිරුවන් සහ ඔවුන්ගේ මාතෘ භූමිය සුරැකීමට සිදු කළ උදාර සේවාවන් ද සිහිපත් කළේය.",
        "\"පසුගිය කාලයේ අප පුරුදු පුහුණු වූවාක් මෙන්, වත්මන් ජනාධිපතිතුමාගේ මගපෙන්වීමත් සමඟ SLESA සහ එහි සේවාවන් පොහොසත් කිරීමට අපි බලාපොරොත්තු වෙනවා,\" ඔහු ප්‍රතිඥා දුන්නේය.",
        "මෑතකාලීන අරගලයන් සහ විරෝධතා ගැන සඳහන් කරමින් ඔහු කියා සිටියේ ප්‍රජාතන්ත්‍රවාදයේ මුවාවෙන් අපගේ තරුණ සෙබළුන්ගේ උදාර සේවය හෑල්ලු කරන නින්දිත වීඩියෝ දර්ශන ප්‍රචාරය කිරීම කණගාටුවට කරුණක් බවයි.",
        "එබැවින් රටේ තරුණ සෙබළුන් තම යුතුකම ඉටුකර මාතෘභූමිය සුරැකීමට දිරිමත් කරන ලෙස ඔහු හිටපු සෙබළුන්ගෙන් ඉල්ලා සිටියේය.",
        "මෙම වැඩසටහනේදී ආරක්ෂක ලේකම්වරයා විසින් SLESA සාමාජිකයින් කිහිප දෙනෙකුට ‘ගවුරවන්විට සේවා පදක්කම’ (ගෞරවනීය සේවා පදක්කම) පළඳවන ලද අතර ඔහු විසින් රචනා කරන ලද පොත් කිහිපයක් ද සංකේතාත්මක අභිනය ලෙස SLESA වෙත භාර දෙන ලදී.",
        "1944 දී පිහිටුවන ලද SLESA අද වන විට අනුබද්ධ සන්නද්ධ හමුදා සංගම් 48 ක සාමාජිකයින් 45,000 කට අධික සංඛ්‍යාවක් සමඟ කැපී පෙනෙන ස්ථානයක් දක්වා වර්ධනය වී ඇත.",
        "උත්සවයේ කූඨප්‍රාප්තිය සනිටුහන් කරමින් SLESA හි මහලේකම් ලුතිනන් කර්නල් අජිත් සියඹලාපිටිය (විශ්‍රාමික) විසින් ස්තුති කතාව පවත්වන ලදී.",
        "යුධ හමුදාපති ලුතිනන් ජෙනරාල් විකුම් ලියනගේ, නාවික හමුදාපති වයිස් අද්මිරාල් නිශාන්ත උළුගේතැන්න, හිටපු ත්‍රිවිධ හමුදාපතිවරුන්, ආරක්‍ෂක අමාත්‍යාංශයේ හමුදා සම්බන්ධීකරණ නිලධාරී මේජර් ජෙනරාල් දිනේෂ් නානායක්කාර, SLESA හි මහලේකම් ලුතිනන් කර්නල් අජිත් සියඹලාපිටිය (රිට්ටාල්පිටිය), මෙම අවස්ථාවට SLESA සාමාජිකයින් සහ සම්භාවනීය ආරාධිතයින් විශාල පිරිසක් එක්ව සිටියහ."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ආරක්ෂක",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ආරක්ෂක",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "කමල් ගුණරත්න",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකා හිටපු සෙබළුන්ගේ සංගමය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ආරක්ෂක මූලස්ථානය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "175",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ආරක්ෂක",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "කමල් ගුණරත්න",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "78 වැනි",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඊගල්ස් ලේක්සයිඩ් භෝජන සංග්‍රහය සහ සම්මන්ත්‍රණ ශාලාව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "අත්තිඩිය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉරිදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "04",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ආරක්ෂක",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "දශක තුනක්",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "SLESA",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "SLESA",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "SLESA",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "1944",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "SLESA",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "45,000 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "48",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "සන්නද්ධ හමුදා සංගම්",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "අජිත් සියඹලාපිටිය",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "හමුදා",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "විකුම් ලියනගේ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "නාවික",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "නිශාන්ත උළුගේතැන්න",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ත්‍රිවිධ හමුදාපතිවරු",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ආරක්ෂක අමාත්යාංශය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "දිනේෂ් නානායක්කාර",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "අජිත් සියඹලාපිටිය",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "SLESA",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "முன்னாள் ராணுவ வீரர்களுக்கு நிரந்தர அலுவலகம் அமைக்க திட்டம்: பாதுகாப்பு செயலாளர்",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "பாதுகாப்பு தலைமையக வளாகத்தினுள் இலங்கை முன்னாள் படைவீரர் சங்கத்திற்கான முழுமையான நிரந்தர அலுவலகக் கட்டிடத்தை அமைப்பதற்கு திட்டமிடப்பட்டுள்ளதாக பாதுகாப்பு செயலாளர் நாயகம் (ஓய்வு) கமல் குணரத்ன தெரிவித்துள்ளார்.",
        "அதற்கமைவாக 175 பேர்ச்சஸ் கொண்ட காணியொன்று இதற்கென ஒதுக்கப்பட்டுள்ளது” என்றும், “அரசாங்க நிதி இதற்குப் பயன்படுத்தப்பட மாட்டாது” என்றும் அவர் குறிப்பிட்டார்.",
        "ஞாயிற்றுக்கிழமை (04) அத்திடியவில் உள்ள ஈகிள்ஸ் லேக்சைட் விருந்து மற்றும் மாநாட்டு மண்டபத்தில் நடைபெற்ற இலங்கை முன்னாள் படைவீரர் சங்கத்தின் (SLESA) 78 ஆவது ஆண்டு நிறைவு விழாவில் பாதுகாப்புச் செயலாளர் கமல் குணரத்ன பிரதம அதிதியாகக் கலந்து கொண்டார்.",
        "பிரதம அதிதியின் உரையின் போது, ​​மூன்று தசாப்த கால யுத்தத்தின் போது, ​​உயிரிழந்த மற்றும் மாற்றுத்திறனாளிகள் மற்றும் அவர்களது தாய்நாட்டைப் பாதுகாப்பதற்காக ஆற்றிய உன்னத சேவைகளை பாதுகாப்புச் செயலாளர் நினைவுகூர்ந்தார்.",
        "\"சமீப காலங்களில் நாங்கள் நடைமுறைப்படுத்தியது போல், தற்போதைய ஜனாதிபதியின் வழிகாட்டுதலுடன் SLESA மற்றும் அதன் சேவைகளை வளப்படுத்தவும் நாங்கள் எதிர்நோக்குகிறோம்\" என்று அவர் உறுதியளித்தார்.",
        "சமீபத்திய போராட்டம் மற்றும் போராட்டங்கள் குறித்து அவர் குறிப்பிடுகையில், ஜனநாயகம் என்ற போர்வையில் நமது இளம் படைவீரர்களின் உன்னத சேவையை குறைமதிப்பிற்கு உட்படுத்தும் கேவலமான வீடியோ காட்சிகளை பரப்புவது வருத்தமளிக்கிறது என்றார்.",
        "எனவே, நாட்டின் இளம் படைவீரர்கள் தங்கள் கடமைகளைச் செய்து தாய்நாட்டைப் பாதுகாக்க முன்னாள் படைவீரர்களை ஊக்குவிக்க வேண்டும் என்று அவர் கேட்டுக் கொண்டார்.",
        "பாதுகாப்புச் செயலர் நிகழ்ச்சியின் போது பல SLESA உறுப்பினர்களுக்கு ‘கவுரவன்வித சேவா பதக்கம்’ (கௌரவ சேவைப் பதக்கம்) வழங்கினார் மேலும் அவர் எழுதிய சில புத்தகங்களையும் SLESA க்கு அடையாளச் சைகையாக வழங்கினார்.",
        "1944 இல் நிறுவப்பட்ட SLESA, 48 இணைந்த ஆயுதப் படை சங்கங்களில் 45,000 உறுப்பினர்களைக் கொண்டு இன்று குறிப்பிடத்தக்க நிலைக்கு வளர்ந்துள்ளது.",
        "SLESA இன் செயலாளர் நாயகம் லெப்டினன்ட் கேணல் அஜித் சியம்பலாபிட்டிய (ஓய்வு) நிகழ்வின் உச்சக்கட்டத்தை குறிக்கும் வகையில் நன்றியுரை ஆற்றினார்.",
        "இராணுவத் தளபதி லெப்டினன்ட் ஜெனரல் விக்கும் லியனகே, கடற்படைத் தளபதி வைஸ் அட்மிரல் நிஷாந்த உலுகேதென்ன, முன்னாள் முப்படைத் தளபதிகள், பாதுகாப்பு அமைச்சின் இராணுவ இணைப்பு அதிகாரி மேஜர் ஜெனரல் தினேஷ் நாணயக்கார, SLESA இன் செயலாளர் நாயகம் லெப்டினன்ட் கேணல் அஜித் சியம்பலாபிட்டிய நிகழ்ச்சியில் ஏராளமான SLESA உறுப்பினர்கள் மற்றும் சிறப்பு அழைப்பாளர்கள் கலந்து கொண்டனர்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "பாதுகாப்பு",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "பாதுகாப்பு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "கமல் குணரத்ன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை முன்னாள் படைவீரர் சங்கம்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாதுகாப்பு தலைமையகம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "175",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பாதுகாப்பு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "கமல் குணரத்ன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "78வது",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஈகிள்ஸ் ஏரிக்கரை விருந்து மற்றும் மாநாட்டு மண்டபம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "அத்திடியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஞாயிற்றுக்கிழமை",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "04",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பாதுகாப்பு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "மூன்று தசாப்தங்கள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "SLESA",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "SLESA",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "SLESA",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "1944",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "SLESA",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "45,000",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "48",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆயுதப்படை சங்கங்கள்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "அஜித் சியம்பலாபிட்டிய",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இராணுவம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "விக்கும் லியனகே",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "கடற்படை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "நிஷாந்த உலுகெதென்ன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "முப்படை தளபதிகள்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாதுகாப்பு அமைச்சகம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "தினேஷ் நாணயக்கார",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "அஜித் சியம்பலாபிட்டிய",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "SLESA",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}