{
  "newspaper_id": "news-first-lk",
  "url": "https://www.newsfirst.lk/2022/08/31/flood-warning-for-low-lying-areas-in-ratnapura/",
  "time_ut": 1661942640,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Flood warning for low-lying areas in Ratnapura",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Flood warning for low-lying areas in Ratnapura",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); The Irrigation Department says that within the next 24 hours, a significant level of flooding may occur in low-lying areas of Palamadulla, Nivithigala, Ratnapura, Kuruvita, Ayagama and Alapatha regional secretariat divisions in Ratnapura district.",
        "Accordingly, the Irrigation Department has informed that the people residing in the respective areas and the drivers traveling through those areas should be more careful.",
        "Meanwhile, the Department of Meteorology says that some places in Western, Southern, Sabaragamuwa, Central and Uva provinces may experience very heavy rains of more than 150 mm, due to the turbulent condition in the lower atmosphere.",
        "The weather forecast indicates that heavy rains of more than 100 mm may occur in other parts of the island.",
        "One-month-old infant abandoned at a motor garage with a letter",
        "Are you a victim of Cyber Crime? Police Unit ready to crackdown crime in the cyberspace"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Ratnapura",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "News 1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "The Irrigation Department",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the next 24 hours",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "Palamadulla",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Nivithigala",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ratnapura",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kuruvita",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ayagama",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Alapatha",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ratnapura",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the Irrigation Department",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the Department of Meteorology",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Western",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Southern, Sabaragamuwa, Central",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Uva",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "more than 150",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "more than 100",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "One-month-old",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Cyber Crime",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "රත්නපුර පහත් බිම් සඳහා ගංවතුර අනතුරු ඇඟවීමක්",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); ඉදිරි පැය 24 තුළ රත්නපුර දිස්ත්‍රික්කයේ පාලමඩුල්ල, නිවිතිගල, රත්නපුර, කුරුවිට, අයගම සහ අලපාත ප්‍රාදේශීය ලේකම් කොට්ඨාශවල පහත් බිම්වල සැලකිය යුතු මට්ටමේ ගංවතුර තත්ත්වයක් ඇති විය හැකි බව වාරිමාර්ග දෙපාර්තමේන්තුව පවසයි.",
        "ඒ අනුව අදාළ ප්‍රදේශවල පදිංචි ජනතාව සහ එම ප්‍රදේශ හරහා ගමන් කරන රියදුරන් වඩාත් සැළකිලිමත් විය යුතු බවයි වාරිමාර්ග දෙපාර්තමේන්තුව දැනුම් දෙන්නේ.",
        "මේ අතර, පහළ වායුගෝලයේ පවතින කැළඹිලි ස්වභාවය හේතුවෙන් බස්නාහිර, දකුණ, සබරගමුව, මධ්‍යම සහ ඌව පළාත්වල ඇතැම් ස්ථානවලට මිලිමීටර් 150ට වැඩි ඉතා තද වැසි ඇති විය හැකි බව කාලගුණ විද්‍යා දෙපාර්තමේන්තුව පවසයි.",
        "දිවයිනේ සෙසු ප්‍රදේශවලට මිලිමීටර් 100 ට වැඩි තද වැසි ඇති විය හැකි බව කාලගුණ අනාවැකිය පෙන්වා දෙයි.",
        "ලිපියක් සමඟ මෝටර් රථ ගරාජයක දමා ගිය මාසයක් වයසැති ළදරුවා",
        "ඔබ සයිබර් අපරාධයට ගොදුරු වූවෙක්ද? සයිබර් අවකාශයේ සිදුවන අපරාධ මර්දනයට පොලිස් ඒකකය සූදානම්"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "රත්නපුරය",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "News 1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "වාරිමාර්ග දෙපාර්තමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඊළඟ පැය 24",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "පලාමඩුල්ල",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "නිවිතිගල",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "රත්නපුරය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "කුරුවිට",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "අයගම",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "අලපාත",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "රත්නපුරය",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "වාරිමාර්ග දෙපාර්තමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "කාලගුණ විද්‍යා දෙපාර්තමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "බටහිර",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "දකුණ, සබරගමුව, මධ්‍යම",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඌව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "150 ට වැඩි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "100 ට වැඩි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "මාසයක් වයසැති",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "සයිබර් අපරාධ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "இரத்தினபுரியில் தாழ்வான பகுதிகளுக்கு வெள்ள அபாய எச்சரிக்கை",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); இரத்தினபுரி மாவட்டத்தில் பாலமடுல்ல, நிவித்திகல, இரத்தினபுரி, குருவிட்ட, அயகம மற்றும் அலபாத பிரதேச செயலகப் பிரிவுகளின் தாழ்நிலப் பகுதிகளில் அடுத்த 24 மணித்தியாலங்களுக்குள் கணிசமான அளவு வெள்ளம் ஏற்படக்கூடும் என நீர்ப்பாசனத் திணைக்களம் தெரிவித்துள்ளது.",
        "இதன்படி குறித்த பிரதேசங்களில் வசிக்கும் மக்களும், அவ்வழியாக பயணிக்கும் சாரதிகளும் மிகுந்த அவதானத்துடன் செயற்படுமாறு நீர்ப்பாசன திணைக்களம் அறிவித்துள்ளது.",
        "இதேவேளை, வளிமண்டலத்தின் கீழ் வளிமண்டலத்தில் ஏற்பட்டுள்ள கொந்தளிப்பான நிலை காரணமாக மேல், தெற்கு, சப்ரகமுவ, மத்திய மற்றும் ஊவா மாகாணங்களில் சில இடங்களில் 150 மில்லிமீற்றருக்கும் அதிகமான கடும் மழை பெய்யக்கூடும் என வளிமண்டலவியல் திணைக்களம் தெரிவித்துள்ளது.",
        "நாட்டின் ஏனைய பகுதிகளில் 100 மில்லிமீற்றருக்கும் அதிகமான பலத்த மழை பெய்யக்கூடும் என வானிலை முன்னறிவிப்பு தெரிவிக்கிறது.",
        "கடிதத்துடன் மோட்டார் கேரேஜில் கைவிடப்பட்ட ஒரு மாத கைக்குழந்தை",
        "நீங்கள் சைபர் கிரைம் பாதிக்கப்பட்டவரா? சைபர்ஸ்பேஸ் குற்றங்களை ஒடுக்க போலீஸ் பிரிவு தயார்"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "இரத்தினபுரி",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "News 1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "நீர்ப்பாசன திணைக்களம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "அடுத்த 24 மணி நேரம்",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "பலமடுல்லா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "நிவிதிகல",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இரத்தினபுரி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "குருவிட",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "அயகம",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "அலபத",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இரத்தினபுரி",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "நீர்ப்பாசன திணைக்களம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "வளிமண்டலவியல் திணைக்களம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "மேற்கு",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "தெற்கு, சப்ரகமுவ, மத்திய",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஊவா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "150க்கு மேல்",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "100க்கு மேல்",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஒரு மாத வயது",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "சைபர்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}