{
  "newspaper_id": "ada-lk",
  "url": "https://www.ada.lk/breaking_news/ගෝඨාට-මාලදිවයිනේ-සරණාගතභාවය-හෝ-රැකවරණය-දෙන්න-එපැයි-එරට-වැසියෝ-කියති/11-395383",
  "time_ut": 1657689206,
  "original_lang": "si",
  "original_title": "ගෝඨාට මාලදිවයිනේ සරණාගතභාවය හෝ රැකවරණය දෙන්න එපැයි එරට වැසියෝ කියති",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "The people of that country say that Gota should be given asylum or protection in the Maldives",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "It is reported that the people of that country are currently urging the government of Maldives not to give shelter or asylum to the President Gotabaya Rajapaksa who left the country after leaving Sri Lanka in the worst crisis.",
        "A video of President Gotabhaya Rajapaksa being taken from Male under high security by the country's security forces is currently circulating on social media.",
        "Commenting on this video, the people of Maldives declare that Mr. Gotabaya Rajapaksa should not be granted asylum or protection in that country.",
        "They also state that the people of Maldives stand with the people of Sri Lanka."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Maldives",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Maldives",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Gotabaya Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Gotabhaya Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Maldives",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Gotabaya Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Maldives",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "ගෝඨාට මාලදිවයිනේ සරණාගතභාවය හෝ රැකවරණය දෙන්න එපැයි එරට වැසියෝ කියති",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකාව දරුණුතම අර්බුදයකට පත්කර රටින් පිටව ගිය ජනපති ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ මහතා වෙත මාලදිවයිනේ රැකවරණය හෝ සරණාගභාවය ලබානොදෙන ලෙස එරට ජනතාව මේ වන විට මාලදිවයිනේ රජයට බලකරමින් සිටින බව වාර්තා වෙයි.",
        "ජනපති ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ මහතා එරට ආරක්ෂක අංශවල ඉහළ ආරක්ෂාවක් යටතේ මාලේ නුවරින් රැගෙන යන වීඩියෝවක් මේ වන විට සමාජ මාධ්‍ය තුළ සංසරණය වෙමින් පවතී.",
        "මේ වීඩියෝවට අදහස් දක්වමින් මාලදිවයිනේ ජනතාව ප්‍රකාශ කරන්නේ ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ මහතා වෙත එරට සරනාගතභාවය හෝ රැකවරණය ලබානොදෙන ලෙසයි.",
        "මාලදිවයිනේ ජනතාව ශ්‍රී ලංකා ජනතාව සමග රැදී සිටින බවද ඔවුන් ප්‍රකාශ කරයි."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "මාලදිවයින",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "මාලදිවයින",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "මාලදිවයින",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "මාලදිවයින",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "கோட்டாவுக்கு மாலத்தீவில் புகலிடம் அல்லது பாதுகாப்பு வழங்க வேண்டும் என்று அந்நாட்டு மக்கள் கூறுகின்றனர்",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "மிக மோசமான நெருக்கடியில் இலங்கையை விட்டு வெளியேறிய ஜனாதிபதி கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ஷவிற்கு அடைக்கலம் அல்லது புகலிடம் வழங்க வேண்டாம் என அந்த நாட்டு மக்கள் தற்போது மாலைதீவு அரசாங்கத்திடம் வலியுறுத்தி வருவதாகத் தெரிவிக்கப்படுகிறது.",
        "ஜனாதிபதி கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ஷ மாலேயில் இருந்து உயர் பாதுகாப்புடன் நாட்டின் பாதுகாப்புப் படையினரால் அழைத்துச் செல்லப்பட்ட வீடியோ ஒன்று தற்போது சமூக ஊடகங்களில் பரவி வருகிறது.",
        "இந்த காணொளி தொடர்பில் கருத்து தெரிவித்த மாலைதீவு மக்கள், திரு.கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்சவிற்கு அந்நாட்டில் புகலிடமோ, பாதுகாப்போ வழங்கக் கூடாது என அறிவிக்கின்றனர்.",
        "மாலைதீவு மக்கள் இலங்கை மக்களுடன் நிற்பதாகவும் அவர்கள் குறிப்பிடுகின்றனர்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "மாலத்தீவுகள்",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "மாலத்தீவுகள்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "கோத்தபாய ராஜபக்ச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "மாலத்தீவுகள்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "மாலத்தீவுகள்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}