{
  "newspaper_id": "ada-derana-lk",
  "url": "http://www.adaderana.lk/news/83780/ranil-to-be-sworn-in-as-new-president-today",
  "time_ut": 1658374020,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Ranil to be sworn in as new President today",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Ranil to be sworn in as new President today",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "Ranil Wickremesinghe, who was elected as the 8th Executive President of Sri Lanka in a parliamentary vote yesterday, will be sworn in this morning (July 21).",
        "The swearing-in ceremony will take place at the parliamentary complex.",
        "Following his victory, Wickremesinghe said that Sri Lanka is in a very difficult situation and that there are big challenges ahead.",
        "Sri Lanka’s 225-member parliament voted Wickremesinghe in as the new Head of State with a total of 134 votes cast in his favour. Meanwhile, his main opponent SLPP’s dissident MP Dullas Alahapperuma was polled second with 82 votes. NPP leader MP Anura Kumara Dissanayaka secured only 03 votes.",
        "Two parliamentary members had abstained from voting while four of the 223 votes cast by the members were meanwhile found invalid.",
        "To be elected for the office of succeeding president, a candidate should get 50% or more votes from the valid number of votes.",
        "Following the conclusion of the counting process, Secretary-General of Parliament, Dhammika Dasanayake announced to the House that Ranil Wickremesinghe was been elected as the 8th Executive President.",
        "Pursuant to the provisions of the Presidential Elections (Special Provisions) Act (No. 2 of 1981), Wickremesinghe’s appointment was published in a special gazette notification last evening.",
        "Wickremesinghe is thus qualified to hold the office of the President for the remaining term of the presidency, which was left vacant after his predecessor Gotabaya Rajapaksa stepped down last week.",
        "Wickremesinghe was appointed the caretaker president, Gotabaya Rajapaksa fled the country on a military plane to the Maldives and then took a commercial flight to Singapore.",
        "The 73-year-old has held the office of prime minister six times although he never completed a term. His latest and shortest term in office as the prime minister was when former President Gotabaya Rajapaksa appointed him to the position on July 13 this year, after his brother Mahinda Rajapaksa was forced to step down amidst growing public agitation over economic mismanagement and corruption allegations."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "today",
          "label": "DATE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "8th",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "yesterday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "this morning",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "July 21",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "225",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "State",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "134",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Dullas Alahapperuma",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "second",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "82",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "NPP",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Anura",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kumara Dissanayaka",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "only 03",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Two",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "four",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "223",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "50%",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Dhammika Dasanayake",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "House",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "8th",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the Presidential Elections (Special Provisions) Act",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "2",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "1981",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Wickremesinghe’s",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "last evening",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Gotabaya Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "last week",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Gotabaya Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Maldives",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Singapore",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "73-year-old",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "six",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Gotabaya Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "July 13 this year",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Mahinda Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "නව ජනපති ලෙස රනිල් අද දිවුරුම් දෙයි",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "ඊයේ පැවති පාර්ලිමේන්තු ඡන්ද විමසීමේදී ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ 8 වැනි විධායක ජනාධිපතිවරයා ලෙස තේරී පත් වූ රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතා අද (ජූලි 21) පෙරවරුවේ දිවුරුම් දීමට නියමිතය.",
        "දිවුරුම් දීමේ උත්සවය පාර්ලිමේන්තු සංකීර්ණයේදී පැවැත්වීමට නියමිතයි.",
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකාව ඉතා අසීරු තත්ත්වයක පසුවන බවත් ඉදිරියේදී විශාල අභියෝග තිබෙන බවත් වික්‍රමසිංහ සිය ජයග්‍රහණයෙන් අනතුරුව ප්‍රකාශ කළේය.",
        "මන්ත්‍රීවරුන් 225 දෙනෙකුගෙන් යුත් ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ පාර්ලිමේන්තුව නව රාජ්‍ය නායකයා ලෙස වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතාට ඡන්දය ප්‍රකාශ කළේ ඔහුට පක්ෂව ලැබුණු මුළු ඡන්ද සංඛ්‍යාව 134කි. මේ අතර, ඔහුගේ ප්‍රධාන ප්‍රතිවාදියා වූ ශ්‍රී ලංකා පොදුජන පෙරමුණේ විසම්මුතික පාර්ලිමේන්තු මන්ත්‍රී ඩලස් අලහප්පෙරුම ඡන්ද 82 ක් ලබා ගනිමින් දෙවන ස්ථානයට පත්විය. එජාප නායක පාර්ලිමේන්තු මන්ත්‍රී අනුර කුමාර දිසානායක මහතාට හිමිවූයේ ඡන්ද 03ක් පමණි.",
        "මන්ත්‍රීවරුන් දෙදෙනකු ඡන්දය ප්‍රකාශ කිරීමෙන් වැළකී සිටි අතර මන්ත්‍රීවරුන් ප්‍රකාශ කළ ඡන්ද 223 න් හතරක් බල රහිත විය.",
        "අනුප්‍රාප්තික ජනාධිපති ධුරය සඳහා තේරී පත් වීමට අපේක්ෂකයෙකු වලංගු ඡන්ද සංඛ්‍යාවෙන් 50% හෝ ඊට වැඩි ඡන්ද ප්‍රමාණයක් ලබා ගත යුතුය.",
        "ගණන් කිරීමේ ක්‍රියාවලිය අවසන් වීමෙන් පසු 8 වැනි විධායක ජනාධිපතිවරයා ලෙස රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතා තේරී පත් වූ බව පාර්ලිමේන්තු මහලේකම් ධම්මික දසනායක මහතා සභාවට නිවේදනය කළේය.",
        "ජනාධිපති මැතිවරණ (විශේෂ විධිවිධාන) පනතේ (1981 අංක 2) විධිවිධාන අනුව වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතාගේ පත්වීම ඊයේ සවස අති විශේෂ ගැසට් නිවේදනයක් මගින් ප්‍රකාශයට පත් කරන ලදී.",
        "පසුගිය සතියේ ඔහුගේ පූර්වගාමියා වූ ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ ඉල්ලා අස්වීමෙන් පසු පුරප්පාඩු වූ ජනාධිපති ධුරයේ ඉතිරි කාලය සඳහා ජනාධිපති ධුරය දැරීමට වික්‍රමසිංහ මේ අනුව සුදුසුකම් ලබයි.",
        "වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතා භාරකාර ජනාධිපතිවරයා ලෙස පත් කර, ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ මහතා හමුදා ගුවන් යානයකින් මාලදිවයිනට පලා ගොස් පසුව වාණිජ ගුවන් යානයකින් සිංගප්පූරුවට ගියේය.",
        "73 හැවිරිදි ඔහු කිසිදා ධුර කාලයක් සම්පූර්ණ නොකළද හය වතාවක් අගමැති ධූරය හොබවා ඇත. ආර්ථික අවභාවිතය සහ දූෂණ චෝදනා සම්බන්ධයෙන් වැඩෙන මහජන උද්ඝෝෂණ මධ්‍යයේ ඔහුගේ සොහොයුරු මහින්ද රාජපක්ෂ මහතාට ඉල්ලා අස්වීමට බලකිරීමෙන් පසු, හිටපු ජනාධිපති ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ මහතා මේ වසරේ ජූලි 13 වැනිදා ඔහුව අගමැති ධුරයට පත් කිරීම ඔහුගේ නවතම සහ කෙටිම ධුර කාලයයි."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "අද",
          "label": "DATE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "8 වැනි",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඊයේ",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මේ උදෑසන",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජූලි 21",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "225",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "රජයේ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "134",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඩලස් අලහප්පෙරුම",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "දෙවැනි",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "82",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "එන්පීපී",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "අනුර",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "කුමාර දිසානායක",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "03 ක් පමණි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "දෙක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "හතර",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "223",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "50%",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ධම්මික දසනායක",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "නිවස",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "8 වැනි",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ජනාධිපති මැතිවරණ (විශේෂ විධිවිධාන) පනත",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "2",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "1981",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "වික්‍රමසිංහගේ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඊයේ සවස",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගිය සතිය",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "මාලදිවයින",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "සිංගප්පූරුව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "73 හැවිරිදිය",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "හය",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "මේ වසරේ ජූලි 13",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මහින්ද රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "புதிய ஜனாதிபதியாக ரணில் இன்று பதவியேற்கவுள்ளார்",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "இலங்கையின் 8வது நிறைவேற்று ஜனாதிபதியாக நேற்று பாராளுமன்ற வாக்கெடுப்பில் தெரிவு செய்யப்பட்ட ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க இன்று (ஜூலை 21) காலை பதவிப்பிரமாணம் செய்து கொள்ளவுள்ளார்.",
        "பதவியேற்பு விழா நாடாளுமன்ற வளாகத்தில் நடைபெறவுள்ளது.",
        "தனது வெற்றியைத் தொடர்ந்து, இலங்கை மிகவும் கடினமான சூழ்நிலையில் இருப்பதாகவும், பாரிய சவால்கள் முன்னால் இருப்பதாகவும் விக்கிரமசிங்க தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "இலங்கையின் 225 உறுப்பினர்களைக் கொண்ட நாடாளுமன்றம், விக்ரமசிங்கேவுக்கு ஆதரவாக மொத்தம் 134 வாக்குகளைப் பெற்று புதிய அரச தலைவராக வாக்களித்தது. அதேவேளை, அவரது பிரதான எதிரியான ஸ்ரீலங்கா பொதுஜன பெரமுனவின் அதிருப்தி பாராளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர் டலஸ் அழகப்பெரும 82 வாக்குகளைப் பெற்று இரண்டாவது இடத்தைப் பிடித்தார். NPP தலைவர் பாராளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர் அனுரகுமார திஸாநாயக்க 03 வாக்குகளை மாத்திரமே பெற்றார்.",
        "இரண்டு பாராளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர்கள் வாக்களிப்பதில் இருந்து விலகியிருந்த நிலையில், உறுப்பினர்கள் அளித்த 223 வாக்குகளில் நான்கு வாக்குகள் செல்லாதவையாக காணப்பட்டன.",
        "அடுத்த ஜனாதிபதி பதவிக்கு தேர்ந்தெடுக்கப்பட, ஒரு வேட்பாளர் செல்லுபடியாகும் வாக்குகளில் 50% அல்லது அதற்கு மேற்பட்ட வாக்குகளைப் பெற வேண்டும்.",
        "வாக்கு எண்ணும் நடவடிக்கைகள் நிறைவடைந்ததையடுத்து, 8ஆவது நிறைவேற்று அதிகாரம் கொண்ட ஜனாதிபதியாக ரணில் விக்ரமசிங்க தெரிவு செய்யப்பட்டதாக நாடாளுமன்றத்தின் செயலாளர் நாயகம் தம்மிக்க தசநாயக்க சபைக்கு அறிவித்தார்.",
        "ஜனாதிபதித் தேர்தல்கள் (விசேட ஏற்பாடுகள்) சட்டத்தின் (1981 ஆம் ஆண்டின் இலக்கம் 2) விதிகளுக்கு இணங்க, விக்கிரமசிங்கவின் நியமனம் நேற்று மாலை விசேட வர்த்தமானி அறிவித்தலில் வெளியிடப்பட்டது.",
        "கடந்த வாரம் கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ச பதவி விலகியதை அடுத்து வெற்றிடமாக இருந்த ஜனாதிபதி பதவியின் எஞ்சிய காலத்திற்கு ஜனாதிபதி பதவியை வகிக்க விக்கிரமசிங்க தகுதி பெற்றுள்ளார்.",
        "விக்கிரமசிங்க தற்காலிக ஜனாதிபதியாக நியமிக்கப்பட்டார், கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ச நாட்டை விட்டு இராணுவ விமானத்தில் மாலைதீவுக்கு தப்பிச் சென்று பின்னர் வர்த்தக விமானத்தில் சிங்கப்பூர் சென்றார்.",
        "73 வயதான அவர் ஆறு முறை பிரதமர் பதவியை வகித்துள்ளார், ஆனால் அவர் ஒரு பதவிக்காலத்தை முடிக்கவில்லை. முன்னாள் ஜனாதிபதி கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ச இந்த ஆண்டு ஜூலை 13 ஆம் தேதி அவரை பிரதமராக நியமித்தது, அவரது சகோதரர் மகிந்த ராஜபக்ச, பொருளாதார முறைகேடு மற்றும் ஊழல் குற்றச்சாட்டுகள் காரணமாக அதிகரித்து வரும் பொது கிளர்ச்சிக்கு மத்தியில் பதவி விலக வேண்டிய கட்டாயம் ஏற்பட்டது."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "இன்று",
          "label": "DATE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "8வது",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "நேற்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று காலை",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜூலை 21",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "225",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "நிலை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "134",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "டலஸ் அழகப்பெரும",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இரண்டாவது",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "82",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "NPP",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "அனுர",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "குமார திஸாநாயக்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "03 மட்டுமே",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இரண்டு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "நான்கு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "223",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "50%",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "தம்மிக்க தசநாயக்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "வீடு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "8வது",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஜனாதிபதி தேர்தல்கள் (சிறப்பு ஏற்பாடுகள்) சட்டம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "2",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "1981",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "விக்கிரமசிங்கவின்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "நேற்று மாலை",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "கடந்த வாரம்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "மாலத்தீவுகள்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "சிங்கப்பூர்",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "73 வயதானவர்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆறு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்த ஆண்டு ஜூலை 13",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "மஹிந்த ராஜபக்ஷ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}