{
  "newspaper_id": "news-first-lk",
  "url": "https://www.newsfirst.lk/2022/06/28/cabinet-nod-to-revise-railway-transport-charges/",
  "time_ut": 1656403320,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Cabinet nod to revise railway transport charges",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Cabinet nod to revise railway transport charges",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); Sri Lanka’s Cabinet of Ministers granted approval to revise the railway charges for passenger transport, goods transport, and postal transport.",
        "Sri Lanka Railways had adopted a concessionary payment system for passenger transport in terms of state policies.",
        "However, due to the rapid price hike of fuel experienced recently, the recurrent loss of the Department is on the rise too. Therefore, it has become vital to increase the income earned by the Department in order to sustain a satisfactory railway service.",
        "Accordingly, the Cabinet of Ministers approved the proposal furnished by the Minister of Transport and Highways to revise the railway charges categorized as passenger transport charges which had not been revised for more than five (05) years, the goods transport and postal transport charges which have not been revised approximately in fourteen (14) years",
        "#Rambukkana Shooting: HR Commission tells AG to file criminal action against SSP Keerthiratne",
        "CBSL to liquidate five failed finance companies including ETI Finance Limited"
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka’s",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Cabinet of Ministers",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka Railways",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Department",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the Cabinet of Ministers",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "more than five",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "fourteen",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "14) years",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Rambukkana",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "HR Commission",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "AG",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "SSP Keerthiratne",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "five",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ETI Finance Limited",
            "label": "WORK_OF_ART"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "දුම්රිය ප්‍රවාහන ගාස්තු සංශෝධනය කිරීමට කැබිනට් අනුමැතිය",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); මගී ප්‍රවාහනය, භාණ්ඩ ප්‍රවාහනය සහ තැපැල් ප්‍රවාහනය සඳහා වන දුම්රිය ගාස්තු සංශෝධනය කිරීමට ශ්‍රී ලංකා අමාත්‍ය මණ්ඩලය අනුමැතිය ලබා දී ඇත.",
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකා දුම්රිය සේවය රාජ්‍ය ප්‍රතිපත්තිවලට අනුව මගී ප්‍රවාහනය සඳහා සහනදායී ගෙවීමේ ක්‍රමයක් අනුගමනය කර තිබුණි.",
        "කෙසේ වෙතත්, පසුගිය කාලයේ සිදුවූ ශීඝ්‍ර ඉන්ධන මිල ඉහළ යාම හේතුවෙන් දෙපාර්තමේන්තුවේ පුනරාවර්තන පාඩුව ද ඉහළ යමින් පවතී. එබැවින් සතුටුදායක දුම්රිය සේවාවක් පවත්වාගෙන යාම සඳහා දෙපාර්තමේන්තුව උපයන ආදායම ඉහළ නැංවීම අත්‍යවශ්‍ය වී ඇත.",
        "ඒ අනුව වසර පහකට වැඩි (05)කට වැඩි කාලයක් සංශෝධිත නොවූ මගී ප්‍රවාහන ගාස්තු ලෙස වර්ගීකරණය කර ඇති දුම්රිය ගාස්තු, භාණ්ඩ ප්‍රවාහන හා තැපැල් ප්‍රවාහන ගාස්තු සංශෝධනය කිරීමට ප්‍රවාහන හා මහාමාර්ග අමාත්‍යවරයා ඉදිරිපත් කළ යෝජනාවට අමාත්‍ය මණ්ඩල අනුමැතිය හිමි විය. වසර දාහතරකින් (14) ආසන්න වශයෙන් සංශෝධනය කර නොමැත",
        "#රඹුක්කන වෙඩි තැබීම: ජ්‍යෙෂ්ඨ පොලිස් අධිකාරී කීර්තිරත්නට එරෙහිව අපරාධ නඩු පවරන්නැයි මානව සම්පත් කොමිසම නීතිපතිට කියයි",
        "සීමාසහිත ETI ෆිනෑන්ස් ඇතුළු අසාර්ථක මූල්‍ය සමාගම් පහක් ඈවර කිරීමට CBSL"
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "අමාත්ය මණ්ඩලය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකා දුම්රිය සේවය",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ෙදපාර්තෙම්න්තුෙව්",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "අමාත්ය මණ්ඩලය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "පහකට වඩා",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "දහහතර",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "14) වසර",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "රඹුක්කන",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "මානව සම්පත් කොමිසම",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "AG",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජ්‍යෙෂ්ඨ පොලිස් අධිකාරී කීර්තිරත්න",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "පහ",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ETI ෆිනෑන්ස් ලිමිටඩ්",
            "label": "WORK_OF_ART"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "ரயில் போக்குவரத்து கட்டணத்தை திருத்த அமைச்சரவை ஒப்புதல்",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); பயணிகள் போக்குவரத்து, சரக்கு போக்குவரத்து மற்றும் தபால் போக்குவரத்துக்கான ரயில் கட்டணங்களை திருத்துவதற்கு இலங்கையின் அமைச்சரவை அனுமதி வழங்கியுள்ளது.",
        "இலங்கை ரயில்வே அரச கொள்கைகளின் அடிப்படையில் பயணிகள் போக்குவரத்திற்காக சலுகைக் கட்டண முறையை ஏற்றுக்கொண்டது.",
        "எவ்வாறாயினும், அண்மைக்காலமாக ஏற்பட்டுள்ள எரிபொருளின் விரைவான விலையேற்றம் காரணமாக, திணைக்களத்தின் தொடர்ச்சியான இழப்புகளும் அதிகரித்து வருகின்றன. எனவே, திருப்திகரமான ரயில் சேவையை நிலைநிறுத்துவதற்காக திணைக்களம் ஈட்டும் வருமானத்தை அதிகரிப்பது இன்றியமையாததாக உள்ளது.",
        "இதன்படி, ஐந்து (05) வருடங்களுக்கு மேலாக திருத்தப்படாத பயணிகள் போக்குவரத்து கட்டணங்கள், சரக்கு போக்குவரத்து மற்றும் தபால் போக்குவரத்து கட்டணங்கள் என வகைப்படுத்தப்பட்ட புகையிரத கட்டணங்களை திருத்துவதற்கு போக்குவரத்து மற்றும் நெடுஞ்சாலைகள் அமைச்சரினால் முன்வைக்கப்பட்ட யோசனைக்கு அமைச்சரவை அங்கீகாரம் வழங்கியுள்ளது. தோராயமாக பதினான்கு (14) ஆண்டுகளில் திருத்தப்படவில்லை",
        "#ரம்புக்கன துப்பாக்கிச் சூடு: எஸ்எஸ்பி கீர்த்திரத்ன மீது குற்றவியல் நடவடிக்கை எடுக்குமாறு மனிதவள ஆணையம் ஏஜியிடம் கூறியுள்ளது",
        "ETI ஃபைனான்ஸ் லிமிடெட் உட்பட ஐந்து தோல்வியடைந்த நிதி நிறுவனங்களை கலைக்க CBSL"
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கையின்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "மந்திரிசபை",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை ரயில்வே",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "துறை",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "மந்திரிசபை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஐந்துக்கும் மேல்",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "பதினான்கு",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "14 ஆண்டுகள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ரம்புக்கன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "மனிதவள ஆணையம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஏஜி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "எஸ்.எஸ்.பி கீர்த்திரத்ன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஐந்து",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ETI ஃபைனான்ஸ் லிமிடெட்",
            "label": "WORK_OF_ART"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}