{
  "newspaper_id": "news-first-lk",
  "url": "https://www.newsfirst.lk/2022/07/29/price-of-tea-leaves-up-by-100/",
  "time_ut": 1659072300,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Price of Tea Leaves Up by 100%",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Price of Tea Leaves Up by 100%",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); The Tea Small Holdings Development Authority says that the price of tea leaves has increased by 100%.",
        "The Chairman of the Tea Small Holdings Development Authority Thushara Priyadarshana said that a few months ago, the price of 1kg of raw tea leaves was between Rs.100 -130. However, the price of 1lk of raw tea leaves has exceeded Rs.260/- in the local market providing an extra profit to farmers.",
        "The Chairman said that the tea cultivators have profited from the rising exchange rate.",
        "The Chairman of the Tea Small Holdings Development Authority Thushara Priyadarshana said that a special program will be implemented to increase the quality of the tea leave harvest.",
        "China responds to USAID Samantha Power’s comments on debt to Sri Lanka"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Tea Leaves",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "100%",
          "label": "PERCENT"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "News 1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "The Tea Small Holdings Development Authority",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "100%",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the Tea Small Holdings Development Authority",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Priyadarshana",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "a few months ago",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "1kg",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "1lk",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "the Tea Small Holdings Development Authority",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Priyadarshana",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "China",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Samantha Power",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "තේ දළු මිල 100%කින් ඉහළට",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); තේ දළු මිල 100%කින් ඉහළ ගොස් ඇතැයි කුඩා තේ වතු සංවර්ධන අධිකාරිය පවසයි.",
        "කුඩා තේ වතු සංවර්ධන අධිකාරියේ සභාපති තුෂාර ප්‍රියදර්ශන මහතා පැවසුවේ මීට මාස කිහිපයකට පෙර අමු තේ දළු කිලෝග්‍රෑම් 1ක මිල රුපියල් 100 - 130 අතර වූ බවයි. කෙසේ වෙතත්, ගොවීන්ට අමතර ලාභයක් ලබා දෙමින් දේශීය වෙළෙඳපොළේ අමු තේ දළු 1kක මිල රුපියල් 260/- ඉක්මවා ඇත.",
        "ඉහළ යන විනිමය අනුපාතිකයෙන් තේ වගාකරුවන් ලාභ ලබා ඇති බව සභාපතිවරයා පැවසීය.",
        "කුඩා තේ වතු සංවර්ධන අධිකාරියේ සභාපති තුෂාර ප්‍රියදර්ශන මහතා පැවසුවේ තේ නිවාඩු අස්වැන්නේ ගුණාත්මක බව ඉහළ නැංවීම සඳහා විශේෂ වැඩපිළිවෙළක් ක්‍රියාත්මක කරන බවයි.",
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවට ණය ගැන USAID සමන්තා පවර් කළ ප්‍රකාශයට චීනය ප්‍රතිචාර දක්වයි"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "තේ කොළ",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "100%",
          "label": "PERCENT"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "News 1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "කුඩා තේ වතු සංවර්ධන අධිකාරිය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "100%",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "කුඩා තේ වතු සංවර්ධන අධිකාරිය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ප්‍රියදර්ශන",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "මාස කිහිපයකට පෙර",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "1kg",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "1k",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "කුඩා තේ වතු සංවර්ධන අධිකාරිය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ප්‍රියදර්ශන",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "චීනය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "සමන්තා පවර්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "தேயிலை இலைகளின் விலை 100% உயர்வு",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); தேயிலை துாள் விலை 100% அதிகரித்துள்ளதாக சிறு தேயிலை தோட்ட அபிவிருத்தி அதிகார சபை தெரிவித்துள்ளது.",
        "சில மாதங்களுக்கு முன்னர் 1 கிலோகிராம் கச்சா தேயிலையின் விலை ரூபா 100 – 130 ஆக இருந்ததாக சிறு தேயிலை தோட்ட அபிவிருத்தி அதிகார சபையின் தலைவர் துஷார பிரியதர்சன தெரிவித்துள்ளார். இருப்பினும், உள்ளூர் சந்தையில் 1 கிலோ கச்சா தேயிலையின் விலை ரூ.260/-ஐ தாண்டியுள்ளது விவசாயிகளுக்கு கூடுதல் லாபத்தை அளிக்கிறது.",
        "தேயிலை விவசாயிகள் அதிகரித்து வரும் மாற்று விகிதத்தினால் இலாபம் அடைந்துள்ளதாக தலைவர் தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "தேயிலை விடுப்பு அறுவடையின் தரத்தை அதிகரிக்க விசேட வேலைத்திட்டமொன்று அமுல்படுத்தப்படவுள்ளதாக சிறு தேயிலை தோட்ட அபிவிருத்தி அதிகார சபையின் தலைவர் துஷார பிரியதர்சன தெரிவித்துள்ளார்.",
        "இலங்கைக்கான கடன் தொடர்பில் USAID சமந்தா பவரின் கருத்துக்கு சீனா பதிலளித்துள்ளது"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "தேயிலை இலைகள்",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "100%",
          "label": "PERCENT"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "News 1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "தேயிலை சிறு தோட்டங்கள் அபிவிருத்தி அதிகாரசபை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "100%",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "தேயிலை சிறு தோட்டங்கள் அபிவிருத்தி அதிகாரசபை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "பிரியதர்ஷனா",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "சில மாதங்களுக்கு முன்பு",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "1 கிலோ",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "1 கிலோ",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "தேயிலை சிறு தோட்டங்கள் அபிவிருத்தி அதிகாரசபை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "பிரியதர்ஷனா",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "சீனா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சமந்தா பவர்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}