{
  "newspaper_id": "lankadeepa-lk",
  "url": "https://www.lankadeepa.lk/latest_news/’’ජේ-වී-පිය-ජනතාවගේ-හිත්-දිනාගනිමින්-සි‌ටියි’’/1-616256",
  "time_ut": 1657542967,
  "original_lang": "si",
  "original_title": "’’ජේ.වී.පිය ජනතාවගේ හිත් දිනාගනිමින් සි‌ටියි’’",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "\"JV Piya is winning the hearts of the people\"",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "Speaking about a meeting with Mr. Anura Kumara Dissanayake, the American Ambassador to Sri Lanka Mrs. Julie Chang said that the JVP is a party that is growing day by day in Sri Lanka with the approval of the people.",
        "Mrs. Julie Chang stated that a very effective and honest discussion was held between the American Ambassador to Sri Lanka Mrs. Julie Chang and the leader of Janata Vimukthi Peramuna Mr. Anura Kumara Dissanayake.",
        "Mrs. Julie Chung said that if there is a problem regarding the investment in the United States and the foreign policy of the United States or if she needs an explanation, she told Mr. Anura Kumara Dissanayake to give her a phone call. Mrs. Julie said that then she will have the opportunity to distance herself from the false information circulating through social media and rumours. declared.",
        "Ambassador Julie Chang said that although there have been controversial situations with the JVP in the past, she felt it was her duty to meet Mr. Anura Kumara Dissanayake as an individual and not as a representative of the United States of America.",
        "In that meeting, she said that she felt JVP was a political party that Sri Lanka needed and that JVP would socialize their ideologies and said that this was not the opinion of the United States of America but her personal opinion."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "JV Piya",
          "label": "WORK_OF_ART"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Anura Kumara Dissanayake",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "American",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Julie Chang",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Julie Chang",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "American",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Julie Chang",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Janata Vimukthi Peramuna",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Anura Kumara Dissanayake",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Julie Chung",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the United States",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the United States",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Anura Kumara Dissanayake",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Julie",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Julie Chang",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Anura Kumara Dissanayake",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the United States of America",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the United States of America",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "’’ජේ.වී.පිය ජනතාවගේ හිත් දිනාගනිමින් සි‌ටියි’’",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "ජනතා විමුක්ති පෙරමුණ ජනතා ප්‍රසාදය හිමිකර ගනිමින් දිනෙන් දින ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ වර්ධනය වන පක්ෂයක් බව අනුර කුමාර දිසානායක මහතා සමඟ පැවති හමුවක් පිළිබඳ අදහස් දක්වමින්  ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ ඇමෙරිකානු තානාපති ජුලී චන්ග් මහත්මිය ප්‍රකාශ කළාය.",
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ ඇමෙරිකානු තානාපති ජුලී චන්ග් මහත්මිය සහ ජනතා විමුක්ති පෙරමුණේ නායක අනුර කුමාර දිසානායක මහතා අතර පසුගියදා පැවති හමුවේදී ඉතා ඵලදායී අවංක සාකච්ඡාවක් සිදු කළ බව ජුලී චන්ග් මහත්මිය ප්‍රකාශ කළාය.",
        "එහිදී ඇමෙරිකාවේ ආයෝජන සම්බන්ධයෙන් සහ ඇමෙරිකාවේ විදේශ ප්‍රතිපත්තිය පිළිබඳ ගැටළුවක් ඇත්නම් හෝ පැහැදිලි කිරීමක් අවශ්‍ය නම් තමන්ට දුරකථන ඇමතුමක් ලබා දෙන ලෙස අනුර කුමාර දිසානායක මහතාට පැවසූ බව ජුලී චන්ග් මහත්මිය පැවසුවාය.එවිට සමාජ මාධ්‍ය සහ කටකතා මාර්ගයෙන් සැරිසරන අසත්‍ය තොරතුරු වලින් ඈත් වීමට අවස්ථාව ලැබෙන බව ජුලී මහත්මිය ප්‍රකාශ කළාය.",
        "අතීතයේ සිට ජනතා විමුක්ති පෙරමුණ සමඟ මතභේදාත්මක තත්ත්වයන් හට ගත්තද ඇමෙරිකා එක්සත් ජනපදයේ නියෝජිතයෙක් ලෙස නොව පුද්ගලයෙක් වශයෙන් අනුර කුමාර දිසානායක මහතා හමුවීම යුතුකමක් ලෙස හැඟුණු බව තානාපති ජුලී චන්ග් මහත්මිය ප්‍රකාශ කළාය.",
        "එම හමුවේදී ජනතා විමුක්ති පෙරමුණ ශ්‍රී ලංකාවට අවශ්‍ය දේශපාලන පක්ෂයක් ලෙස හැඟුණු බවත්  ජනතා විමුක්ති පෙරමුණ ඔවුන්ගේ මතවාද සමාජ ගත කරන බවත් ප්‍රකාශ කළ ඇය මෙය ඇමෙරිකා එක්සත් ජනපදයේ මතය නොවන බවත් තමන්ගේ පුද්ගලික මතය බවත් පැවසුවාය."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "JV පිය",
          "label": "WORK_OF_ART"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "අනුර කුමාර දිසානායක",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඇමෙරිකානු",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජූලි චෑන්ග්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ජූලි චෑන්ග්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඇමෙරිකානු",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජූලි චෑන්ග්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජනතා විමුක්ති පෙරමුණ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "අනුර කුමාර දිසානායක",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ජූලි චුන්ග්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "එක්සත් ජනපදය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "එක්සත් ජනපදය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "අනුර කුමාර දිසානායක",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජූලි",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ජූලි චෑන්ග්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "අනුර කුමාර දිසානායක",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඇමරිකා එක්සත් ජනපදය",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඇමරිකා එක්සත් ජනපදය",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "\"ஜே.வி.பியா மக்கள் மனதை வெல்கிறார்\"",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "இலங்கைக்கான அமெரிக்கத் தூதுவர் திருமதி ஜூலி சாங் திரு அனுரகுமார திஸாநாயக்கவுடனான சந்திப்பு குறித்து பேசிய ஜே.வி.பி இலங்கையில் மக்களின் அங்கீகாரத்துடன் நாளுக்கு நாள் வளர்ந்து வரும் கட்சியாகும்.",
        "இலங்கைக்கான அமெரிக்கத் தூதுவர் திருமதி ஜூலி சாங் மற்றும் ஜனதா விமுக்தி பெரமுனவின் தலைவர் அனுரகுமார திஸாநாயக்க ஆகியோருக்கு இடையில் மிகவும் பயனுள்ள மற்றும் நேர்மையான கலந்துரையாடல் இடம்பெற்றதாக திருமதி ஜூலி சாங் தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "அமெரிக்காவில் முதலீடு மற்றும் அமெரிக்காவின் வெளிவிவகாரக் கொள்கை தொடர்பில் ஏதேனும் பிரச்சினை இருப்பின் அல்லது தமக்கு விளக்கம் தேவைப்பட்டால், தமக்கு தொலைபேசியில் அழைப்பு விடுக்குமாறு அனுரகுமார திஸாநாயக்கவிடம் தெரிவித்ததாக திருமதி ஜூலி சுங் தெரிவித்தார். அப்போது சமூக வலைதளங்கள் மற்றும் வதந்திகள் மூலம் பரப்பப்படும் பொய்யான தகவல்களில் இருந்து ஒதுங்கிக் கொள்ள வாய்ப்பு கிடைக்கும் என்று கூறினார்.",
        "கடந்த காலங்களில் ஜே.வி.பி.யுடன் சர்ச்சைக்குரிய சூழ்நிலைகள் இருந்தபோதிலும், அமெரிக்காவின் பிரதிநிதியாக அல்லாமல் தனிப்பட்ட நபராக திரு அனுரகுமார திஸாநாயக்கவை சந்திப்பது தனது கடமையாக கருதுவதாக தூதுவர் ஜூலி சாங் தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "அந்த சந்திப்பில், ஜே.வி.பி இலங்கைக்கு தேவையான ஒரு அரசியல் கட்சியாக தான் கருதுவதாகவும், ஜே.வி.பி அவர்களின் சித்தாந்தங்களை சமூகமயமாக்கும் என்றும், இது அமெரிக்காவின் கருத்து அல்ல என்றும், தனது தனிப்பட்ட கருத்து என்றும் கூறினார்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ஜேவி பியா",
          "label": "WORK_OF_ART"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "அனுரகுமார திஸாநாயக்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "அமெரிக்கன்",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜூலி சாங்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஜூலி சாங்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "அமெரிக்கன்",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜூலி சாங்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜனதா விமுக்தி பெரமுனா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "அனுரகுமார திஸாநாயக்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஜூலி சுங்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஐக்கிய நாடுகள்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஐக்கிய நாடுகள்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "அனுரகுமார திஸாநாயக்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜூலி",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஜூலி சாங்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "அனுரகுமார திஸாநாயக்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஐக்கிய அமெரிக்கா",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஐக்கிய அமெரிக்கா",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}