{
  "newspaper_id": "daily-mirror-lk",
  "url": "https://www.dailymirror.lk/breaking_news/President-to-resign-on-Wednesday/108-240736",
  "time_ut": 1657386026,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "President to resign on Wednesday",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "President to resign on Wednesday",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "Speaker Mahinda Yapa Abeywardene said President Gotabaya Rajapaksa has informed him that he will resign from the Presidency on Wednesday (July 13).",
        "According to sources, the President had informed his decision to the Speaker in a private communique and had sought time till Wednesday as a transition period to hand over the pending official work.",
        "On Wednesday, if the Prime Minister also tenders his resignation, the Speaker will be made President for a period of 30 days during which the Parliament will elect a new President. (DSB)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Wednesday",
          "label": "DATE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Mahinda Yapa Abeywardene",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Gotabaya Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Wednesday (July 13",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Wednesday",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Wednesday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "30 days",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "DSB",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "ජනපති බදාදා ඉල්ලා අස්වෙයි",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "තමා බදාදා (ජුලි 13) ජනාධිපති ධූරයෙන් ඉල්ලා අස්වන බව ජනාධිපති ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ මහතා තමාට දන්වා ඇති බව කථානායක මහින්ද යාපා අබේවර්ධන මහතා පැවසීය.",
        "ආරංචි මාර්ගවලට අනුව ජනාධිපතිවරයා පෞද්ගලික නිවේදනයක් මගින් කථානායකවරයාට සිය තීරණය දන්වා ඇති අතර අපේක්ෂිත නිල කටයුතු භාරදීමට සංක්‍රාන්ති කාලයක් ලෙස බදාදා දක්වා කල් ඉල්ලා ඇත.",
        "බදාදා දිනයේ අගමැතිවරයාද ඉල්ලා අස්වියහොත් කථානායකවරයා දින 30ක කාලයක් සඳහා ජනාධිපති ධුරයට පත් කෙරෙන අතර එම කාලය තුළ පාර්ලිමේන්තුව විසින් නව ජනාධිපතිවරයෙකු තෝරා පත් කර ගනු ඇත. (DSB)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "බදාදා",
          "label": "DATE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "මහින්ද යාපා අබේවර්ධන",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "බදාදා (ජූලි 13",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "බදාදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "බදාදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "දින 30",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඩී.එස්.බී",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "ஜனாதிபதி புதன்கிழமை பதவி விலகுகிறார்",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "எதிர்வரும் புதன்கிழமை (ஜூலை 13) ஜனாதிபதி பதவியை இராஜினாமா செய்யவுள்ளதாக ஜனாதிபதி கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ஷ தெரிவித்துள்ளதாக சபாநாயகர் மஹிந்த யாப்பா அபேவர்தன தெரிவித்துள்ளார்.",
        "ஆதாரங்களின்படி, ஜனாதிபதி தனது முடிவை சபாநாயகருக்கு தனிப்பட்ட வாசகத்தின் மூலம் தெரிவித்ததாகவும், நிலுவையில் உள்ள உத்தியோகபூர்வ பணிகளை ஒப்படைப்பதற்கு புதன்கிழமை வரை கால அவகாசம் கோரியதாகவும் தகவல்கள் தெரிவிக்கின்றன.",
        "புதன்கிழமை, பிரதமரும் தனது ராஜினாமாவை சமர்ப்பித்தால், சபாநாயகர் 30 நாட்களுக்கு ஜனாதிபதியாக நியமிக்கப்படுவார், இதன் போது பாராளுமன்றம் புதிய ஜனாதிபதியைத் தேர்ந்தெடுக்கும். (டி.எஸ்.பி.)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "புதன்",
          "label": "DATE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "மஹிந்த யாப்பா அபேவர்தன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "புதன்கிழமை (ஜூலை 13",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "புதன்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "புதன்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "30 நாட்கள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "டி.எஸ்.பி",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}