{
  "newspaper_id": "virakesari-lk",
  "url": "http://www.virakesari.lk/article/130204",
  "time_ut": 1656235190,
  "original_lang": "ta",
  "original_title": "ரயில் கட்டணங்களை 50 சதவீதமாக அதிகரிக்குமாறு கோரிக்கை",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Demand for 50 per cent increase in train fares",
      "author": "T Yuwaraj",
      "body_lines": [
        "The Railway Department has requested the Cabinet to increase train fares by about 50 per cent.",
        "Gamini Seneviratne, Deputy Superintendent of Transport, spokesperson for the Railway Department, said that there was no other option but to increase fares as a train uses more than 100,000 liters of fuel per day.",
        "However, he added that the Railway Department has sufficient fuel reserves."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "50 per cent",
          "label": "MONEY"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "The Railway Department",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Cabinet",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "about 50",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Gamini Seneviratne",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Railway Department",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "more than 100,000",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the Railway Department",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "දුම්රිය ගාස්තු සියයට 50කින් වැඩි කරන්නැයි ඉල්ලීමක්",
      "author": "ටී යුවරාජ්",
      "body_lines": [
        "දුම්රිය ගාස්තු සියයට 50 කින් පමණ වැඩි කරන ලෙස දුම්රිය දෙපාර්තමේන්තුව කැබිනට් මණ්ඩලයෙන් ඉල්ලීමක් කර තිබේ.",
        "දුම්රිය දෙපාර්තමේන්තුවේ ප්‍රකාශක නියෝජ්‍ය ප්‍රවාහන අධිකාරී ගාමිණී සෙනෙවිරත්න පැවසුවේ දිනකට ඉන්ධන ලීටර් ලක්ෂයකට වඩා වැඩි ප්‍රමාණයක් දුම්රියක් භාවිත කරන බැවින් ගාස්තු වැඩි කිරීම හැර වෙනත් විකල්පයක් නොමැති බවයි.",
        "කෙසේ වෙතත්, දුම්රිය දෙපාර්තමේන්තුව සතුව ප්‍රමාණවත් ඉන්ධන සංචිත පවතින බවද ඔහු සඳහන් කළේය."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "සියයට 50 කි",
          "label": "MONEY"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "දුම්රිය දෙපාර්තමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "මණ්ඩල",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "50 ක් පමණ",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ගාමිණී සෙනෙවිරත්න",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "දුම්රිය දෙපාර්තමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "100,000 ට වැඩි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "දුම්රිය දෙපාර්තමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "ரயில் கட்டணங்களை 50 சதவீதமாக அதிகரிக்குமாறு கோரிக்கை",
      "author": "T Yuwaraj",
      "body_lines": [
        "ரயில் கட்டணங்களை சுமார் 50 சதவீதமாக அதிகரிக்குமாறு அமைச்சரவையிடம் கோரிக்கை விடுக்கப்பட்டுள்ளதாக ரயில்வே திணைக்களம் தெரிவித்துள்ளது.",
        "நாளொன்றுக்கு ரயிலொன்று 100,000 லீற்றருக்கு மேல் எரிபொருளைப் பயன்படுத்துவதால் கட்டணத்தை அதிகரிப்பதைத் தவிர வேறு வழியில்லை என ரயில்வே திணைக்களப் பேச்சாளர் பிரதிப் போக்குவரத்து அத்தியட்சகர் காமினி செனவிரத்ன தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "எவ்வாறாயினும், ரயில்வே திணைக்களத்திடம் போதியளவு எரிபொருள் கையிருப்பு உள்ளதாக அவர் மேலும் தெரிவித்தார்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "50 சதவீதம்",
          "label": "MONEY"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ரயில்வே துறை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "மந்திரி சபை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "சுமார் 50",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "காமினி செனவிரத்ன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரயில்வே துறை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "100,000க்கு மேல்",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ரயில்வே துறை",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}