{
  "newspaper_id": "economy-next-com",
  "url": "https://economynext.com/sri-lankas-litro-launches-new-gas-app-feature-orders-payable-in-dollars-99386/",
  "time_ut": 1662137580,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Sri Lanka’s Litro launches new gas app feature; orders payable in dollars",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Sri Lanka’s Litro launches new gas app feature; orders payable in dollars",
      "author": "Dulya de Silva",
      "body_lines": [
        "ECONOMYNEXT – Sri Lankans abroad will soon be able to buy cooking gas for relatives living in the country, Chairman of the state-owned Litro Gas, Muditha Pieris said, as the company prepares to launch an app feature that allows users to pay for gas in dollars.",
        "The feature will be added to Litro’s home delivery app, which was launched in August 2020, Pieris said.",
        "“We would like to invite overseas Sri Lankans to purchase for [their loved ones], as our way of contributing to overcome the country’s forex crisis.”",
        "At the current prices and exchange rate, a 12.5kg domestic gas cylinder will cost roughly 13 USD.",
        "Litro announced that they would be reducing gas prices for the second consecutive month on Monday (05).",
        "Sri Lanka had repeatedly called for expats to send in dollars to the country, but due to misgivings about the ousted ex President Gotabaya Rajapakse’s government, many resisted. (Colombo/Sep02/2022)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Sri Lanka’s",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lankans",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Litro Gas",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Muditha Pieris",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Litro’s",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "August 2020",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Pieris",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lankans",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "12.5kg",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "roughly 13 USD",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Litro",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the second consecutive month",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Monday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "05",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Gotabaya Rajapakse",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Colombo/Sep02/2022",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "Sri Lanka's Litro නව ගෑස් යෙදුම් විශේෂාංගය දියත් කරයි; ඩොලර් වලින් ගෙවිය යුතු ඇණවුම්",
      "author": "දුල්යා ද සිල්වා",
      "body_lines": [
        "ECONOMYNEXT – විදේශගත ශ්‍රී ලාංකිකයන්ට මෙරට ජීවත්වන ඥාතීන්ට ඉවුම් පිහුම් ගෑස් මිලදී ගැනීමට ළඟදීම හැකිවනු ඇතැයි රජයට අයත් ලිට්‍රෝ ගෑස් සමාගමේ සභාපති මුදිත පීරිස් මහතා ප්‍රකාශ කළේ පාරිභෝගිකයන්ට ගෑස් සඳහා ගෙවීමට හැකි යෙදුම් විශේෂාංගයක් හඳුන්වාදීමට සමාගම සූදානම් වන බැවිනි. ඩොලර්.",
        "මෙම විශේෂාංගය 2020 අගෝස්තු මාසයේදී දියත් කරන ලද Litro හි නිවසටම බෙදා හැරීමේ යෙදුමට එක් කරන බව පීරිස් පැවසීය.",
        "\"රටේ විදේශ විනිමය අර්බුදයෙන් මිදීමට දායක වීමේ අපගේ මාර්ගය ලෙස, [ඔවුන්ගේ ආදරණීයයන්] සඳහා මිලදී ගැනීමට විදේශීය ශ්‍රී ලාංකිකයින්ට ආරාධනා කිරීමට අපි කැමැත්තෙමු.\"",
        "වර්තමාන මිල ගණන් සහ විනිමය අනුපාතය අනුව, 12.5kg ගෘහස්ථ ගෑස් සිලින්ඩරයක දළ වශයෙන් ඩොලර් 13 ක් වැය වේ.",
        "ලිට්‍රෝ සමාගම සඳුදා (05) පිට පිට දෙවැනි මාසයටත් ගෑස් මිල අඩු කරන බව නිවේදනය කළේය.",
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකාව විදේශිකයන්ට ඩොලර් එවන ලෙස නැවත නැවතත් ඉල්ලා සිටි නමුත් නෙරපා හරින ලද හිටපු ජනාධිපති ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂගේ රජය පිළිබඳ අවිශ්වාසය නිසා බොහෝ දෙනෙක් එයට විරුද්ධ වූහ. (කොළඹ/සැප්.02/2022)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලාංකිකයන්",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ලිට්රෝ ගෑස්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "මුදිත පීරිස්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ලිට්රෝගේ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "2020 අගෝස්තු",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "පීරිස්",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලාංකිකයන්",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "12.5kg",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "දළ වශයෙන් 13 USD",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ලිට්රෝ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "අඛණ්ඩව දෙවන මාසය",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "සඳුදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "05",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "කොළඹ/සැප්.02/2022",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "இலங்கையின் லிட்ரோ புதிய எரிவாயு பயன்பாட்டு அம்சத்தை அறிமுகப்படுத்தியது; டாலர்களில் செலுத்த வேண்டிய ஆர்டர்கள்",
      "author": "துல்யா டி சில்வா",
      "body_lines": [
        "ECONOMYNEXT – வெளிநாடுகளில் உள்ள இலங்கையர்கள் நாட்டில் வசிக்கும் உறவினர்களுக்கு சமையல் எரிவாயுவை விரைவில் வாங்க முடியும் என அரசுக்கு சொந்தமான லிட்ரோ காஸ் நிறுவனத்தின் தலைவர் முதித பீரிஸ் தெரிவித்துள்ளார். டாலர்கள்.",
        "ஆகஸ்ட் 2020 இல் தொடங்கப்பட்ட லிட்ரோவின் ஹோம் டெலிவரி பயன்பாட்டில் இந்த அம்சம் சேர்க்கப்படும் என்று பீரிஸ் கூறினார்.",
        "\"நாட்டின் அந்நியச் செலாவணி நெருக்கடியைச் சமாளிப்பதற்கான எங்கள் பங்களிப்பாக, வெளிநாடுகளில் உள்ள இலங்கையர்களை [அவர்களின் அன்புக்குரியவர்களுக்காக] வாங்குவதற்கு நாங்கள் அழைக்க விரும்புகிறோம்.\"",
        "தற்போதைய விலை மற்றும் மாற்று விகிதத்தின்படி, 12.5 கிலோ எடையுள்ள வீட்டு எரிவாயு சிலிண்டரின் விலை சுமார் 13 அமெரிக்க டாலர்கள்.",
        "தொடர்ந்து இரண்டாவது மாதமாக எரிவாயு விலையை திங்கட்கிழமை (05) குறைக்கவுள்ளதாக லிட்ரோ நிறுவனம் அறிவித்துள்ளது.",
        "வெளிநாட்டவர்கள் நாட்டிற்கு டாலர்களை அனுப்புமாறு இலங்கை பலமுறை அழைப்பு விடுத்தது, ஆனால் பதவி நீக்கம் செய்யப்பட்ட முன்னாள் ஜனாதிபதி கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ஷவின் அரசாங்கம் குறித்த அவநம்பிக்கை காரணமாக, பலர் எதிர்த்தனர். (கொழும்பு/செப்02/2022)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "இலங்கையின்",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கையர்கள்",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "லிட்ரோ எரிவாயு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "முதிதா பீரிஸ்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "லிட்ரோவின்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆகஸ்ட் 2020",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "பீரிஸ்",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கையர்கள்",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "12.5 கிலோ",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "தோராயமாக 13 அமெரிக்க டாலர்கள்",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "லிட்ரோ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "தொடர்ந்து இரண்டாவது மாதம்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "திங்கட்கிழமை",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "05",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ஷ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "கொழும்பு/செப்02/2022",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}