{
  "newspaper_id": "news-first-lk",
  "url": "https://www.newsfirst.lk/2022/08/27/yuan-wang-5-mapping-indian-ocean-after-leaving-sri-lanka/",
  "time_ut": 1661596500,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Yuan Wang 5 mapping Indian Ocean after leaving Sri Lanka",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Yuan Wang 5 mapping Indian Ocean after leaving Sri Lanka",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "(Hindustan Times); After leaving Hambantota Port on August 22, the Chinese satellite and ballistic missile tracking ship Yuan Wang 5 is currently mapping the ocean bed 400 nautical miles (741 kilometers) south-southeast of Dondra Head, the southernmost tip of Sri Lanka.",
        "According to available information, the military ship is expected to head towards its home port Jiangyin near Shanghai as per details provided at Hambantota.",
        "However, it is not clear whether the ship will make another port call while on the way back to China.",
        "Although classified as a Chinese Research Vessel, the ballistic missile tracker ship became a bone of contention with Sri Lankan authorities allowing the ship to berth at Hambantota on August 16 after initially deferring the port call on August 11.",
        "The Hambantota port is on a 99-year lease with the Chinese after Sri Lanka under the Beijing-friendly Rajapaksa regime did a debt-equity swap with the Xi Jinping regime in 2017.",
        "According to China watchers, the berthing of Yuan Wang 5 at Hambantota was a political statement of assertion by the Xi Jinping regime on the weak Ranil Wickremesinghe government after India quietly conveyed its concerns about the military ship."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Yuan Wang",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "Indian Ocean",
          "label": "LOC"
        },
        {
          "text": "Sri Lanka",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Hindustan Times",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Hambantota Port",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "August 22",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Chinese",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Yuan Wang",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "400 nautical miles",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "741 kilometers",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "Dondra Head",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Shanghai",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Hambantota",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "China",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Chinese Research Vessel",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lankan",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Hambantota",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "August 16",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "August 11",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "99-year",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Chinese",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Rajapaksa",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Xi Jinping",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "2017",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "China",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Yuan Wang",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Xi Jinping",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "India",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "යුවාන් වැන්ග් 5 ශ්‍රී ලංකාවෙන් පිටවීමෙන් පසු ඉන්දියන් සාගරය සිතියම්ගත කිරීම",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "(හින්දුස්ථාන් ටයිම්ස්); අගෝස්තු 22 හම්බන්තොට වරායෙන් පිටත් වූ පසු, චීන චන්ද්‍රිකා සහ බැලස්ටික් මිසයිල ලුහුබැඳීමේ නෞකාවක් වන යුවාන් වැන්ග් 5 මේ වන විට ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ දකුණු කෙළවරේ පිහිටි දෙවුන්දර තුඩුවේ සිට දකුණු-ගිණිකොණ දෙසින් නාවික සැතපුම් 400 (කිලෝමීටර් 741) දුරින් සාගර පතුල සිතියම්ගත කරමින් සිටී.",
        "දැනට පවතින තොරතුරුවලට අනුව, හම්බන්තොට දී ලබා දී ඇති තොරතුරුවලට අනුව, හමුදා නෞකාව ෂැංහයි අසල පිහිටි එහි උපන් වරාය වන ජියැන්ග්යින් දෙසට ගමන් කිරීමට බලාපොරොත්තු වේ.",
        "කෙසේ වෙතත්, නෞකාව ආපසු චීනයට යන අතරමගදී තවත් වරාය ඇමතුමක් ගනීද යන්න පැහැදිලි නැත.",
        "චීන පර්යේෂණ යාත්‍රාවක් ලෙස වර්ගීකරණය කර ඇතත්, බැලිස්ටික් මිසයිල ට්‍රැකර් නෞකාව ශ්‍රී ලංකා බලධාරීන් සමඟ මතභේදයට තුඩු දී ඇති අතර, අගෝස්තු 11 වන දින වරාය ඇමතුම මුලින් කල් දැමීමෙන් පසු අගෝස්තු 16 වන දින නෞකාවට හම්බන්තොට නැංගුරම් ලෑමට ඉඩ ලබා දුන්නේය.",
        "බීජිං හිතවාදී රාජපක්ෂ පාලනය යටතේ ශ්‍රී ලංකාව 2017 දී ෂී ජින්පින් පාලනය සමඟ ණය කොටස් හුවමාරුවක් සිදු කිරීමෙන් පසු හම්බන්තොට වරාය චීන ජාතිකයන් සමඟ වසර 99 ක බදු පදනමක් මත පවතී.",
        "චීනයේ නිරීක්ෂකයින්ට අනුව, යුවාන් වැන්ග් 5 හම්බන්තොට නැංගුරම් ලෑම, මිලිටරි නෞකාව පිළිබඳ සිය කනස්සල්ල ඉන්දියාව නිහඬව ප්‍රකාශ කිරීමෙන් පසු දුර්වල රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ රජය පිළිබඳව ෂී ජින්පින් පාලනය විසින් කරන ලද දේශපාලන ප්‍රකාශයකි."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Yuan Wang",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "ඉන්දියන් සාගරය",
          "label": "LOC"
        },
        {
          "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "හින්දුස්ථාන් ටයිම්ස්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "හම්බන්තොට වරාය",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "අගෝස්තු 22",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "චීන",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Yuan Wang",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "නාවික සැතපුම් 400 කි",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "කිලෝමීටර 741 කි",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "දෙවුන්දර තුඩුව",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ෂැංහයි",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "හම්බන්තොට",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "චීනය",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "චීන පර්යේෂණ යාත්රාව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලාංකික",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "හම්බන්තොට",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "අගෝස්තු 16",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "අගෝස්තු 11",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "අවුරුදු 99",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "චීන",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Xi Jinping",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "2017",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "චීනය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Yuan Wang",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Xi Jinping",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "யுவான் வாங் 5 இலங்கையை விட்டு வெளியேறிய பிறகு இந்தியப் பெருங்கடலை வரைபடமாக்குகிறது",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "(ஹிந்துஸ்தான் டைம்ஸ்); ஆகஸ்ட் 22 அன்று ஹம்பாந்தோட்டை துறைமுகத்தை விட்டு வெளியேறிய பின்னர், சீன செயற்கைக்கோள் மற்றும் பாலிஸ்டிக் ஏவுகணை கண்காணிப்பு கப்பல் யுவான் வாங் 5 தற்போது இலங்கையின் தென்கோடி முனையான டோண்ட்ரா ஹெட்டின் தென்-தென்கிழக்கே 400 கடல் மைல் (741 கிலோமீட்டர்) தொலைவில் உள்ள கடல் படுக்கையை வரைபடமாக்குகிறது.",
        "கிடைக்கப்பெற்ற தகவல்களின்படி, ஹம்பாந்தோட்டையில் வழங்கப்பட்ட விவரங்களின்படி, இராணுவக் கப்பல் ஷாங்காய்க்கு அருகிலுள்ள அதன் சொந்த துறைமுகமான ஜியாங்யின் நோக்கிச் செல்லும் என்று எதிர்பார்க்கப்படுகிறது.",
        "இருப்பினும், சீனாவுக்குத் திரும்பும் வழியில் கப்பல் மற்றொரு துறைமுக அழைப்பைச் செய்யுமா என்பது தெளிவாகத் தெரியவில்லை.",
        "சீன ஆராய்ச்சிக் கப்பலாக வகைப்படுத்தப்பட்டாலும், பாலிஸ்டிக் ஏவுகணை கண்காணிப்புக் கப்பல், ஆகஸ்ட் 11 ஆம் தேதி துறைமுக அழைப்பை ஒத்திவைத்த பின்னர், ஆகஸ்ட் 16 ஆம் தேதி கப்பலை அம்பாந்தோட்டையில் நிறுத்த அனுமதித்த இலங்கை அதிகாரிகளுடன் சர்ச்சைக்குரியதாக மாறியது.",
        "பெய்ஜிங் நட்பு ராஜபக்ச ஆட்சியின் கீழ் இலங்கை 2017 இல் ஜி ஜின்பிங் ஆட்சியுடன் கடன் சமபங்கு மாற்றத்தை செய்த பின்னர் அம்பாந்தோட்டை துறைமுகம் சீனர்களுடன் 99 வருட குத்தகைக்கு உள்ளது.",
        "சீன கண்காணிப்பாளர்களின் கூற்றுப்படி, ஹம்பாந்தோட்டையில் யுவான் வாங் 5 நிறுத்தப்பட்டது, இராணுவக் கப்பல் குறித்த தனது கவலைகளை இந்தியா அமைதியாக தெரிவித்த பின்னர், பலவீனமான ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க அரசாங்கத்தின் மீது ஜி ஜின்பிங் ஆட்சியின் அரசியல் அறிக்கையாகும்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Yuan Wang",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "இந்திய பெருங்கடல்",
          "label": "LOC"
        },
        {
          "text": "இலங்கை",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "இந்துஸ்தான் டைம்ஸ்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "அம்பாந்தோட்டை துறைமுகம்",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆகஸ்ட் 22",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சீன",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Yuan Wang",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "400 கடல் மைல்கள்",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "741 கிலோமீட்டர்",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "டோண்ட்ரா ஹெட்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஷாங்காய்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஹம்பாந்தோட்டை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "சீனா",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "சீன ஆராய்ச்சிக் கப்பல்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஹம்பாந்தோட்டை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆகஸ்ட் 16",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆகஸ்ட் 11",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "99-ஆண்டு",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சீன",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ராஜபக்சே",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Xi Jinping",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "2017",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "சீனா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Yuan Wang",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Xi Jinping",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்தியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}