{
  "newspaper_id": "lankadeepa-lk",
  "url": "https://www.lankadeepa.lk/latest_news/ඉන්දියාවේ-නිදහස්-සැමරුමට-ඒකාබද්ධ-සමරු-මුද්දර/1-618203",
  "time_ut": 1660635118,
  "original_lang": "si",
  "original_title": "ඉන්දියාවේ නිදහස් සැමරුමට ඒකාබද්ධ සමරු මුද්දර",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Joint Commemorative Stamps for India's Independence Celebration",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "On the occasion of India's 75th Independence Day celebrations, Sri Lanka and Indian Postal Departments have jointly decided to issue two commemorative stamps each.",
        "For this purpose, a proposal presented by the Minister of Transport, Highways and Mass Media, Dr. Bandula Gunawardena to sign a memorandum of understanding between the postal departments of the two countries has also been approved by the Cabinet.",
        "Cabinet Spokesman, Minister, Dr. Bandula Gunawardena said that it has been proposed to issue these commemorative stamps to reflect the parliaments of the two countries based on the theme of 'democracy'.",
        "The minister also mentioned that 3,000 sets of stamps, 5,000 souvenir sheets and 2,000 first-day covers each are expected to be exchanged from these stamps created by the two countries.",
        "The minister said this while addressing the press conference to inform the Cabinet decisions held today (16) at the Government Information Department."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Joint Commemorative Stamps",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "India",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "India",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "75th",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Independence Day",
            "label": "EVENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Indian Postal Departments",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "two",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Mass Media",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "Bandula Gunawardena",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "two",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Cabinet",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Cabinet Spokesman",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Bandula Gunawardena",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "two",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "3,000",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "5,000",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "2,000",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "first-day",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "two",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Cabinet",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "16",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Government Information Department",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "ඉන්දියාවේ නිදහස් සැමරුමට ඒකාබද්ධ සමරු මුද්දර",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "ඉන්දියාවේ 75 වන නිදහස් දින සැමරුම නිමිත්තෙන් ශ්‍රී ලංකා සහ ඉන්දීය තැපැල් දෙපාර්තමේන්තු ඒකාබද්ධව සමරු මුද්දර දෙක බැගින් නිකුත් කිරීමට තීරණයක් ගෙනතිබේ.",
        "මේ සඳහා දෙරටේ තැපැල් දෙපාර්තමේන්තු අතර අවබෝධතා ගිවිසුමකට අත්සන් තැබීම සඳහා ප්‍රවාහන, මහාමාර්ග සහ ජනමාධ්‍ය අමාත්‍ය, ආචාර්ය බන්දුල ගුණවර්ධන මහතා ඉදිරිපත් කළ යෝජනාවකට අමාත්‍ය මණ්ඩල අනුමැතිය ද හිමිව ඇත.",
        "‘ප්‍රජාතන්ත්‍රවාදය’ යන තේමාව පදනම් කරගෙන දෙරටෙහි පාර්ලිමේන්තු පිළිබිඹු වන පරිදි මෙම සමරු මුද්දර නිකුත් කිරීමට යෝජනා වී ඇතැයි කැබිනට් ප්‍රකාශක, අමාත්‍ය, ආචාර්ය බන්දුල ගුණවර්ධන මහතා පැවසීය.",
        "දෙරට විසින් නිර්මාණය කරන මෙම මුද්දරවලින් මුද්දර කට්ටල 3,000 බැගින්, සිහිවටන පත්‍රිකා 5,000 බැගින් දහ මුල්දින කවර 2,000 බැගින් හුවමාරු කර ගැනීමට අපේක්‍ෂා කරන බව ද ඇමතිවරයා සඳහන් කළේය.",
        "අමාත්‍යවරයා මේ බව පැවසුවේ රජයේ ප්‍රවෘත්ති දෙපාර්තමේන්තුවේ දී අද (16) පැවති කැබිනට් තීරණ දැනුම්දීමේ මාධ්‍ය හමුව අමතමිනි."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ඒකාබද්ධ සමරු මුද්දර",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "ඉන්දියාව",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "75 වැනි",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "නිදහස් දිනය",
            "label": "EVENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දියානු තැපැල් දෙපාර්තමේන්තු",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "දෙක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ජන මාධ්‍ය",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "බන්දුල ගුණවර්ධන",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "දෙක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "මණ්ඩල",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "කැබිනට් ප්‍රකාශක",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "බන්දුල ගුණවර්ධන",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "දෙක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "3,000 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "5,000 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "2,000 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "පළමු දින",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "දෙක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "මණ්ඩල",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "16",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "රජයේ ප්‍රවෘත්ති දෙපාර්තමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "இந்தியாவின் சுதந்திரக் கொண்டாட்டத்திற்கான கூட்டு நினைவு முத்திரைகள்",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "இந்தியாவின் 75வது சுதந்திர தின கொண்டாட்டத்தை முன்னிட்டு, இலங்கை மற்றும் இந்திய தபால் துறைகள் இணைந்து தலா இரண்டு நினைவு முத்திரைகளை வெளியிட முடிவு செய்துள்ளன.",
        "இதற்காக இரு நாடுகளின் தபால் திணைக்களங்களுக்கு இடையில் புரிந்துணர்வு ஒப்பந்தத்தில் கைச்சாத்திடுவதற்கு போக்குவரத்து, நெடுஞ்சாலைகள் மற்றும் வெகுஜன ஊடக அமைச்சர் கலாநிதி பந்துல குணவர்தனவினால் முன்வைக்கப்பட்ட யோசனைக்கும் அமைச்சரவை அங்கீகாரம் வழங்கியுள்ளது.",
        "ஜனநாயகம் என்ற தொனிப்பொருளின் அடிப்படையில் இரு நாட்டு நாடாளுமன்றங்களையும் பிரதிபலிக்கும் வகையில் இந்த நினைவு முத்திரைகளை வெளியிடுவதற்கு முன்மொழியப்பட்டுள்ளதாக அமைச்சரவைப் பேச்சாளரும் அமைச்சருமான கலாநிதி பந்துல குணவர்தன தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "இரு நாடுகளாலும் உருவாக்கப்பட்ட இந்த முத்திரைகளிலிருந்து தலா 3,000 செட் முத்திரைகள், 5,000 நினைவுப் பரிசுத் தாள்கள் மற்றும் 2,000 முதல் நாள் அட்டைகள் பரிமாறிக்கொள்ள எதிர்பார்க்கப்படுவதாகவும் அமைச்சர் குறிப்பிட்டார்.",
        "அரசாங்க தகவல் திணைக்களத்தில் இன்று (16) நடைபெற்ற அமைச்சரவை முடிவுகளை அறிவிக்கும் ஊடகவியலாளர் சந்திப்பில் கலந்துகொண்டு கருத்து தெரிவிக்கும் போதே அமைச்சர் மேற்கண்டவாறு தெரிவித்தார்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "கூட்டு நினைவு முத்திரைகள்",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "இந்தியா",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "இந்தியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "75வது",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "சுதந்திர தினம்",
            "label": "EVENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்திய அஞ்சல் துறைகள்",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "இரண்டு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "வெகுஜன ஊடகம்",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "பந்துல குணவர்தன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இரண்டு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "மந்திரி சபை",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "அமைச்சரவை செய்தி தொடர்பாளர்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "பந்துல குணவர்தன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இரண்டு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "3,000",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "5,000",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "2,000",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "முதல் நாள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இரண்டு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "மந்திரி சபை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "16",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "அரசாங்க தகவல் திணைக்களம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}