{
  "newspaper_id": "lankadeepa-lk",
  "url": "https://www.lankadeepa.lk/latest_news/පොහොට්ටු-ආධාරකරුවන්-බේරේට-තල්ලු-කළ-අය-සොයා-මෙහෙයුම්/1-618532",
  "time_ut": 1661152551,
  "original_lang": "si",
  "original_title": "පොහොට්ටු ආධාරකරුවන් බේරේට තල්ලු කළ අය සොයයි",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Pohottu supporters are looking for those who pushed Beira",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "An operation has been started by the police to find the group that pushed a group of MPs including Pohottuwe into the Beira lake.",
        "After a group attacked the Colombo Galle Mudoora activists, a violent group dragged more than 20 people into the Beira lake and subjected them to various harassment on the 9th of May last.",
        "A person who allegedly robbed a local council member of money and pushed him into the Beira lake was recently arrested in the Wakanda area of ​​Colombo.",
        "This person, who has been arrested by the Colombo Crime Division, is a 34-year-old resident of Dematagoda area.",
        "The police said that while the MP was traveling in a bus, a group of people including the suspect dropped him and robbed him of his wallet and then pushed him into the Beira lake.",
        "The police are continuing investigations to find the other people who pushed the people into the Beira lake",
        "According to police sources, the person who was arrested will be questioned further in this regard."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Beira",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Beira",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Galle Mudoora",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "more than 20",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Beira",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "9th",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "May last",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Beira",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Wakanda",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the Colombo Crime Division",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "34-year-old",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Beira",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Beira",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        []
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "පොහොට්ටු ආධාරකරුවන් බේරේට තල්ලු කළ අය සොයයි",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "පොහොට්ටුවේ මන්ත්‍රීවරුන් ඇතුළු පිරිසක් බේරේ වැවට  තල්ලු කළ කණ්ඩායම සොයා පොලීසිය විසින් මෙහෙයුමක්  ආරම්භ කරනු ලැබ ඇත.",
        "කොළඹ ගාලු මුවදොර අරගල කරුවන්ට කණ්ඩායමක් පහර දීමෙන් අනතුරුව ප්‍රචණ්ඩවූ පිරිසක්   විසින් ඉකුත් මැයි මස නව වෙනිදා  පුද්ගලයෝ 20 කට  වැඩි සංඛ්‍යාවක් බේරේ වැවට  මෙලෙස  ඇද දමා විවිධ හිරිහැරයට පත්කරනු ලැබූහ.",
        "ප්‍රාදේශීය සභා මන්ත්‍රීවරයකුගේ මුදල් කොල්ලකා ඔහු බේරේ  වැවට තල්ලු කළ බව කියන පුද්ගලයෙක්  කොළඹ වෑකන්ද ප්‍රදේශයේදී  පසුගියදා අත්අඩංගුවට ගනු ලැබීය.",
        "කොළඹ අපරාධ කොට්ඨාසය විසින් අත්අඩංගුවට ගනු ලැබ සිටින මේ පුද්ගලයා  දෙමටගොඩ ප්‍රදේශයේ පදිංචි  වයස අවුරුදු 34ක අයෙකි.",
        "මන්ත්‍රීවරයා බස් රථයකින් ගමන් කරමින් සිටියදී සැකකරු ඇතුළු පිරිසක් ඔහු බිමට බස්සවා ඔහුගේ මුදල් පසුම්බිය කොල්ලකා අනතුරුව බේරේ වැවට තල්ලු කර ඇතැයි පොලිසිය පවසයි.",
        "පුද්ගලයන් බේරේ වැවට තල්ලු කළ සෙසු පුද්ගලයන් සොයා ගැනීමටද පොලිසිය  දිගින් දිගටම පරීක්ෂණ පවත්වාගෙන යයි",
        "අත්අඩංගුවට ගනු ලැබූ පුද්ගලයාගෙන්ද ඒ සම්බන්ධයෙන් වැඩිදුරටත් ප්‍රශ්න කරන බව පොලිස් ආරංචි මාර්ගවලින් පැවසේ."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "බේරේ",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "බේරේ",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ගාල්ල මුදූර",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "20 ට වැඩි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "බේරේ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "9 වැනි",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "පැවතිය හැක",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "බේරේ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "වකන්ඩා",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "කොළඹ අපරාධ කොට්ඨාශය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "34 හැවිරිදිය",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "බේරේ",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "බේරේ",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        []
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "பெய்ராவை தள்ளியவர்களை பொஹொட்டு ஆதரவாளர்கள் தேடி வருகின்றனர்",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "பொஹொட்டுவே உள்ளிட்ட பாராளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர்கள் குழுவை பேரா ஏரிக்குள் தள்ளிய குழுவை கண்டுபிடிக்கும் நடவடிக்கை பொலிஸாரால் ஆரம்பிக்கப்பட்டுள்ளது.",
        "கொழும்பு காலி முதூற செயற்பாட்டாளர்கள் மீது குழுவொன்று தாக்குதல் நடத்தியதையடுத்து, கடந்த மே மாதம் 9 ஆம் திகதி 20 இற்கும் மேற்பட்டவர்களை பெய்ரா ஏரிக்குள் இழுத்துச் சென்ற வன்முறைக் குழு பல்வேறு துன்புறுத்தல்களுக்கு உள்ளாக்கப்பட்டது.",
        "உள்ளூராட்சி மன்ற உறுப்பினர் ஒருவரின் பணத்தை கொள்ளையடித்து அவரை பெய்ரா ஏரியில் தள்ளிய நபர் ஒருவர் அண்மையில் கொழும்பு வகந்த பகுதியில் வைத்து கைது செய்யப்பட்டுள்ளார்.",
        "கொழும்பு குற்றத்தடுப்பு பிரிவினரால் கைது செய்யப்பட்டுள்ள இவர், தெமட்டகொட பிரதேசத்தை சேர்ந்த 34 வயதான ஒருவராவார்.",
        "பாராளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர் பேருந்தில் பயணித்துக் கொண்டிருந்த போது, ​​சந்தேக நபர் உள்ளிட்ட சிலர் அவரை இறக்கிவிட்டு பணப்பையை கொள்ளையடித்து பின்னர் அவரை பெய்ரா ஏரியில் தள்ளிவிட்டதாக பொலிஸார் தெரிவித்தனர்.",
        "பேரீரா ஏரியில் மக்களைத் தள்ளிய மற்ற நபர்களைக் கண்டுபிடிக்கும் போலீஸார் தொடர்ந்து விசாரணை நடத்தி வருகின்றனர்",
        "இது தொடர்பாக கைது செய்யப்பட்ட நபரிடம் மேலும் விசாரணை நடத்தப்படும் என பொலிஸ் வட்டாரங்கள் தெரிவிக்கின்றன."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "பெய்ரா",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "பெய்ரா",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "காலி முதூரா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "20க்கு மேல்",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "பெய்ரா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "9வது",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "நீடிக்கலாம்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பெய்ரா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "வகாண்டா",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "கொழும்பு குற்றப்பிரிவு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "34 வயது",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பெய்ரா",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பெய்ரா",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        []
      ]
    }
  }
}