{
  "newspaper_id": "virakesari-lk",
  "url": "http://www.virakesari.lk/article/131673",
  "time_ut": 1658123769,
  "original_lang": "ta",
  "original_title": "கோட்டாபயவின் நிலை ! எதிர்கால அரசியலுக்கு ஒரு படிப்பினை",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "State of fear! A lesson for future politics",
      "author": "Digital Desk 5",
      "body_lines": [
        "Former President Gotabaya Rajapaksa and the Sri Lanka Podujana Peramuna government led by him have marked turning points in the political history of Sri Lanka as a lesson for future politics.",
        "It is the first time in Sri Lankan political history that four people have prepared to compete for the vacant post of President. It is necessary to review the events that took place in history.",
        "Former President Gotabaya Rajapaksa, who announced that he had won with the support of the Sinhalese people in the holy land of Anuradhapura and took the oath of office as the 7th executive president, the people of the country brought the two and a half year term of office to an end on the 9th of last year. It is an important thing to go down in history.",
        "In the general election held in 2020, the Sri Lanka Podujana Peramuna won a two-thirds majority that no party in the political history of Sri Lanka had won and established a strong government.",
        "The attack by Budujana Peramuna supporters on Kota Ko Kama and Maina Ko Kama protest ground on May 09 turned into nationwide violence and brought down the political achievements of Mahinda Rajapaksa, who was admired by the Sinhalese people as the leader who won the war. Following the spread of violence, Mahinda Rajapaksa resigned as Prime Minister on May 09. .",
        "Bashil Rajapaksa, who was praised by the back row members of Podujina Peramuna, said that if a person with a brain takes office as the Finance Minister, he bid farewell to his political journey on 09th June.",
        "In Sri Lanka's political history, the people's struggle has not brought about such a revolutionary change in a short period of time. The overthrow of the political throne of the Rajapakses within a short period of six months should be mentioned as a great victory of the people's struggle.",
        "The race for the presidency has heated up since President Gotabaya Rajapaksa resigned with effect from the 14th. Sajith Premadasa, Ranil Wickramasinghe, Anura Kumara Dissanayake and Dalus Alagaperuma are also going to file their nominations stating that they are ready to contest.",
        "Following the assassination of former President Ranasinghe Premadasha during a procession in Colombo on May 1, 1993, Tikiri Banda Vijayatunga, who was the Prime Minister of the then government, was appointed as the Acting President within a few hours.",
        "Following this, on May 7, 1993, he was elected as the Interim President through the Parliament in accordance with the 40th Article of the Constitution and served as the President until November 12, 1994. In the critical situation at that time, only the name of DP Vijayatunga was nominated in the Parliament and all parties supported him.",
        "In the period after the impact of Covid, the country has reached a state of bankruptcy and the political crisis has intensified, and the number of presidential candidates has increased and has come under internal criticism."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Gotabaya Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "Podujana Peramuna",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "first",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lankan",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "four",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Gotabaya Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sinhalese",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "7th",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "two and a half year",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the 9th of last year",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "2020",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "Podujana Peramuna",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "two-thirds",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Budujana Peramuna",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kota Ko Kama",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Maina Ko Kama",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "May 09",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Mahinda Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sinhalese",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Mahinda Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "May 09",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Bashil Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Podujina Peramuna",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "09th June",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka's",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "six months",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Gotabaya Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the 14th",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sajith Premadasa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickramasinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Anura Kumara Dissanayake",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Dalus Alagaperuma",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Ranasinghe Premadasha",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Colombo",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "May 1, 1993",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Tikiri",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "a few hours",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "May 7, 1993",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "40th",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Article of the Constitution",
            "label": "LAW"
          },
          {
            "text": "November 12, 1994",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Vijayatunga",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Covid",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "භීතියේ තත්වය! අනාගත දේශපාලනයට පාඩමක්",
      "author": "ඩිජිටල් මේසය 5",
      "body_lines": [
        "හිටපු ජනාධිපති ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ මහතා සහ ඔහු ප්‍රමුඛ ශ්‍රී ලංකා පොදුජන පෙරමුණ රජය අනාගත දේශපාලනයට පාඩමක් ලෙස ශ්‍රී ලංකා දේශපාලන ඉතිහාසයේ හැරවුම් ලක්ෂ්‍ය සනිටුහන් කර ඇත.",
        "පුරප්පාඩු වූ ජනාධිපති ධූරයට සිව් දෙනෙකු තරග කිරීමට ශ්‍රී ලංකා දේශපාලන ඉතිහාසයේ ප්‍රථම වතාවට සුදානම් වීම ඉතිහාසයේ සිදු වූ සිදුවීම් සමාලෝචනය කිරීම අවශ්‍ය වේ.",
        "අනුරාධපුර පුණ්‍යභූමියේ සිංහල ජනතාවගේ සහයෝගයෙන් තමන් ජයග්‍රහණය කළ බව ප්‍රකාශ කළ හිටපු ජනාධිපති ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ මහතා 7 වැනි විධායක ජනාධිපතිවරයා ලෙස දිවුරුම් දුන් අවස්ථාවේදී රටේ ජනතාව වසර දෙකහමාරක ධුර කාලය ගෙන ආවේය. ඔෆිස් එක ගිය අවුරුද්දේ 9 වෙනිදා ඉවරයි.ඉතිහාසයට යන්න වැදගත් දෙයක්.",
        "2020 වසරේ පැවති මහ මැතිවරණයේදී ශ්‍රී ලංකා දේශපාලන ඉතිහාසයේ කිසිදු පක්ෂයක් දිනා නොගත් තුනෙන් දෙකක බහුතර බලයක් ශ්‍රී ලංකා පොදුජන පෙරමුණ ලබාගෙන ශක්තිමත් ආණ්ඩුවක් පිහිටුවීය.",
        "මැයි 09 වැනිදා කොට කෝ කම සහ මයිනා කෝ කම විරෝධතා බිමට බුදුජන පෙරමුණේ ආධාරකරුවන් විසින් එල්ල කළ ප්‍රහාරය රටපුරා ප්‍රචණ්ඩත්වයක් බවට පත් වූ අතර යුද්ධය ජයග්‍රහණය කළ නායකයා ලෙස සිංහල ජනතාවගේ ප්‍රසාදයට පාත්‍ර වූ මහින්ද රාජපක්ෂ මහතාගේ දේශපාලන ජයග්‍රහණ පහත හෙළුවේය. ප්‍රචණ්ඩත්වය පැතිරීම, මහින්ද රාජපක්ෂ මැයි 09 වැනිදා අගමැති ධූරයෙන් ඉල්ලා අස්විය.",
        "මොළයක් ඇති අයෙක් මුදල් අමාත්‍ය ධුරයට පත්වුවහොත් ජුනි 09 වැනිදා තම දේශපාලන ගමනට සමුදෙන බව පොදුජන පෙරමුණේ පසුපෙළ මන්ත්‍රීවරුන්ගේ ප්‍රශංසාවට ලක්වූ බැසිල් රාජපක්ෂ මහතා පැවසීය.",
        "ශ්‍රී ලාංකේය දේශපාලන ඉතිහාසය තුළ ජන අරගලය කෙටි කාලයක් තුළ මෙතරම් විප්ලවීය වෙනසක් ඇති කර නැත.මාස හයක් වැනි කෙටි කාලයක් තුළ රාජපක්ෂවරුන්ගේ දේශපාලන සිංහාසනය පෙරළා දැමීම ජනතා ජයග්‍රහණයක් ලෙස සඳහන් කළ යුතුය. අරගලය.",
        "පසුගිය 14 වැනිදා සිට ක්‍රියාත්මක වන පරිදි ජනාධිපති ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ මහතා ඉල්ලා අස්වීමත් සමඟ ජනපතිවරණ සටන උණුසුම් වී ඇත.සජිත් ප්‍රේමදාස,රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ,අනුර කුමාර දිසානායක,දලස් අලගපෙරුම යන මහත්වරුද තරග කිරීමට සූදානම් බව පවසමින් නාමයෝජනා භාරදීමට නියමිතය.",
        "1993 මැයි 01 වැනිදා කොළඹදී පැවති පෙළපාලියකදී හිටපු ජනාධිපති රණසිංහ ප්‍රේමදාස මහතා ඝාතනය කිරීමෙන් පසු පැය කිහිපයක් ඇතුළත වැඩබලන ජනාධිපතිවරයා ලෙස එවකට ආණ්ඩුවේ අග්‍රාමාත්‍යවරයා ලෙස කටයුතු කළ ටිකිරි බණ්ඩා විජයතුංග මහතා පත් විය.",
        "ඉන් අනතුරුව 1993 මැයි 07 වැනි දින ආණ්ඩුක්‍රම ව්‍යවස්ථාවේ 40 වැනි ව්‍යවස්ථාව අනුව පාර්ලිමේන්තුව හරහා අන්තර්වාර ජනාධිපතිවරයා ලෙස තේරී පත්වී 1994 නොවැම්බර් 12 වැනිදා දක්වා ජනාධිපතිවරයා ලෙස කටයුතු කළේය.එවකට තිබූ තීරණාත්මක තත්ත්වය තුළ නම පමණි. ඩී.පී. විජයතුංග මහතාගේ නම පාර්ලිමේන්තුවට යෝජනා වූ අතර ඔහුට සියලු පක්ෂ සහාය පළ කළේය.",
        "කොවිඩ් බලපෑමෙන් පසු කාලය තුළ රට බංකොලොත් තත්ත්වයකට පත්ව ඇති අතර දේශපාලන අර්බුදය උග්‍ර වී ඇති අතර ජනාධිපති අපේක්ෂකයින් සංඛ්‍යාව ඉහළ ගොස් අභ්‍යන්තර විවේචනයට ලක්ව ඇත."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "පොදුජන පෙරමුණ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "පළමුවන",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලාංකික",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "හතර",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "සිංහල",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "7 වැනි",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "අවුරුදු දෙකහමාරක්",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "පසුගිය වසරේ 9 වෙනිදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "2020",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "පොදුජන පෙරමුණ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "තුනෙන් දෙකක්",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "බුදුජන පෙරමුණ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "කොට කෝ කාමා",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "මයිනා කෝ කාමා",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "මැයි 09",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මහින්ද රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "සිංහල",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "මහින්ද රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "මැයි 09",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "බැසිල් රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "පොදුජන පෙරමුණ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජුනි 09",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මාස හයක්",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "14 වැනි",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "සජිත් ප්‍රේමදාස",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "අනුර කුමාර දිසානායක",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "දලස් අලගපෙරුම",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "රණසිංහ ප්‍රේමදාස",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "කොළඹ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "1993 මැයි 1",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ටිකිරි",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "පැය කිහිපයක්",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "1993 මැයි 7",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "40 වැනි",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ආණ්ඩුක්රම ව්යවස්ථාවේ වගන්තිය",
            "label": "LAW"
          },
          {
            "text": "නොවැම්බර් 12, 1994",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "විජයතුංග",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "කොවිඩ්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "கோட்டாபயவின் நிலை ! எதிர்கால அரசியலுக்கு ஒரு படிப்பினை",
      "author": "Digital Desk 5",
      "body_lines": [
        "முன்னாள் ஜனாதிபதி கோட்டபய ராஜபக்ஷ மற்றும் அவர் தலைமையிலான ஸ்ரீ லங்கா பொதுஜன பெரமுன அரசாங்கம் இலங்கை அரசியல் வரலாற்றில் திருப்புமுனையான சம்பவங்களை பதிவிட்டுள்ளமை எதிர்கால அரசியலுக்கு ஒரு படிப்பினையாக அமைந்துள்ளது.",
        "பதவி வெற்றிடமாகியுள்ள ஜனாதிபதி பதவிக்கு போட்டியிட இதுவரை நால்வர் தயாராகியுள்ளமை இலங்கை அரசியல் வரலாற்றில் முதல் முறையாக காணக்கூடியதொரு சம்பவமாகும்.வரலாற்றில் இடம்பெற்ற நிகழ்வுகளை மீட்டிப்பார்ப்பது அவசியமாகும்.",
        "தனி சிங்கள மக்களின் ஆதரவுடன் வெற்றிப்பெற்றேன் என புனித பூமியான அநுராதபுரத்தில் பறைசாற்றி 7ஆவது நிறைவேற்று அதிகாரம் கொண்ட ஜனாதிபதியாக பதவி பிரமானம் செய்த முன்னாள் ஜனாதிபதி கோட்டபய ராஜபக்ஷவின் இரண்டரை வருட பதவி காலத்தை நாட்டு மக்கள் கடந்த 09ஆம் திகதியுடன் நிறைவிற்கு கொண்டு வந்தார்கள்.தான் பதவி விலகுகிறேன் என்பதை நாட்டு மக்களுக்கு  அறிவிக்க முடியாத நெருக்கடியான நிலையை முன்னாள் ஜனாதிபதி கோட்டபய ராஜபக்ஷ எதிர்கொண்டுள்ளமை வரலாற்றில் பதியப்பட வேண்டிய முக்கிய விடயமாகும்.",
        "2020ஆம் ஆண்டு இடம்பெற்ற பொதுத்தேர்தலில் ஸ்ரீ லங்கா பொதுஜன பெரமுன இலங்கை அரசியல் வரலாற்றில் எக்கட்சியும் பெறாத அளவிற்கு மூன்றில் இரண்டு பெரும்பான்மையை கைப்பற்றி பலமிக்க அரசாங்கத்தை ஸ்தாபித்தது.பெரும்பான்மை பலமிக்க பொதுஜன பெரமுன தலைமையிலான அரசாங்கத்தின் பதவி காலத்தை நாட்டு மக்கள் இரண்டு வருடங்கள் நிறைவு பெறாத வகையில் கடந்த ஏப்ரல் 03ஆம் திகதி முடிவிற்கு கொண்டு வந்தார்கள்.",
        "கோட்டா கோ கம,மைனா கோ கம போராட்டக்களத்தின் மீது பொதுஜன பெரமுனவின் ஆதரவாளர்கள் கடந்த மே மாதம் 09ஆம் திகதி மேற்கொண்ட தாக்குதல் நாடு தழுவிய ரீதியில் வன்முறையாக உருவெடுத்து யுத்தத்தை வென்ற தலைவர் என சிங்கள மக்களால் போற்றப்பட்ட மஹிந்த ராஜபக்ஷவின் அரசியல் சாதனைகளை வீழ்த்தியது.வன்முறை தீ வியாபித்ததை தொடர்ந்து மஹிந்த ராஜபக்ஷ மே 09ஆம் திகதி பிரதமர் பதவியை இராஜினாமா செய்தார்.",
        "7 மூளையினை உடையவர் நிதியமைச்சராக பதவியேற்றால் நாட்டின் பொருளாதாரம் குறுகிய காலத்தில்  முன்னேற்றமடையும் என பொதுஜின பெரமுனவின் பின்வரிசை உறுப்பினர்களால் போற்றப்பட்ட பஷில் ராஜபக்ஷ நாட்டின் பொருளாதாரத்தை கேள்விக்குள்ளாக்கிய நிலையில் கடந்த ஜுன் மாதம் 09ஆம் திகதி தனது அரசியல் பயணத்திற்கு விடை கொடுத்தார்.",
        "இலங்கை அரசியல் வரலாற்றில் மக்கள் போராட்டம் குறுகிய காலத்திற்குள் இவ்வாறான எழுச்சி மிக்க மாற்றத்தை ஏற்படுத்தவில்லை.குறுகிய ஆறுமாத காலத்திற்குள் ராஜபக்ஷர்களின் அரசியல் சிம்மாசனம் வீழ்த்தப்பட்டது மக்கள் போராட்டத்தின் மாபெரும் வெற்றி என குறிப்பிட வேண்டும்.",
        "ஜனாதிபதி கோட்டபய ராஜபக்ஷ கடந்த 14ஆம் திகதி முதல் அமுலுக்கு வரும் வகையில் பதவி விலகியதை தொட்ந்து ஜனாதிபதி பதவிக்கான போட்டி தற்போது சூடு பிடித்துள்ளது.சஜித் பிரேமதாஸ,ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க,அனுர குமார திஸாநாயக்க மற்றும் டலஸ் அழகபெரும ஆகியோர் தானும் போட்டிக்கு தயார் என குறிப்பிட்டுக்கொண்டு வேட்பு மனுதாக்கல் செய்யவுள்ளார்கள்.",
        "முன்னாள் ஜனாதிபதி ரணசிங்க பிரேமதாஷ 1993ஆம் ஆண்டு மே மாதம் முதலாம் திகதி கொழும்பில் இடம்பெற்ற ஊர்வலத்தின் போது படுகொலை செய்யப்பட்டதை தொடர்ந்து,அப்போதைய அரசாங்கத்தின் பிரதமராக பதவி வகித்த  டிக்கிரி பண்டா விஜயதுங்கா ஒரு சில மணித்தியாலங்களில் பதில் ஜனாதிபதியாக நியமிக்கபட்டார்.",
        "அதனை தொடர்ந்து 1993ஆம் ஆண்டு மே மாதம் 07ஆம் திகதி அரசியலமைப்பின் 40 ஆவது உறுப்புரையின் பிரகாரம் அவர் பாராளுமன்றத்தின் ஊடாக இடைக்கால ஜனாதிபதியாக தெரிவு செய்யப்பட்டு,1994 நவம்பர் மாதம் 12ஆம் திகதி  வரை ஜனாதிபதியாக பதவி வகித்தார்.அப்போதைய நெருக்கடியான சூழ்நிலையில் பாராளுமன்றில் டி.பி விஜயதுங்கவின் பெயர் மாத்திரமே பரிந்துரை செய்யப்பட்டு சகல தரப்பினரும் அவருக்கு ஆதரவு வழங்கினார்கள்.",
        "கொவிட் தாக்கத்தின் பின்னரான காலப்பகுதியில் நாடு வங்குரோத்து நிலையை அடைந்து,அரசியல் நெருக்கடி தீவிரமடைந்துள்ள நிலையில் ஜனாதிபதி வேட்பாளரின் எண்ணிக்கை அதிகரித்த வண்ணம் உள்ளமை விமர்சனத்திற்குள்ளாகியுள்ளது."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "பொதுஜன பெரமுன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "முதலில்",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "நான்கு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "சிங்களவர்கள்",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "7வது",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "இரண்டரை வருடம்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "கடந்த 9 ஆம் தேதி",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "2020",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "பொதுஜன பெரமுன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "மூன்றில் இரண்டு பங்கு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "புதுஜன பெரமுன",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "கோட்டா கோ காமா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "மைனா கோ காமா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "மே 09",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "மஹிந்த ராஜபக்ஷ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "சிங்களவர்கள்",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "மஹிந்த ராஜபக்ஷ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "மே 09",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பஷில் ராஜபக்ச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "பொதுஜன பெரமுன",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜூன் 09",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கையின்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆறு மாதங்கள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "14வது",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சஜித் பிரேமதாச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "அனுரகுமார திஸாநாயக்க",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "டலஸ் அழகப்பெரும",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ரணசிங்க பிரேமதாச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "கொழும்பு",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "மே 1, 1993",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "திகிரி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஒரு சில மணி நேரம்",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "மே 7, 1993",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "40வது",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "அரசியலமைப்பின் கட்டுரை",
            "label": "LAW"
          },
          {
            "text": "நவம்பர் 12, 1994",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "விஜயதுங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "கோவிட்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}