{
  "newspaper_id": "economy-next-com",
  "url": "https://economynext.com/sri-lanka-to-set-up-soe-restructuring-unit-99188/",
  "time_ut": 1661849460,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Sri Lanka to set up SOE restructuring unit",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Sri Lanka to set up SOE restructuring unit",
      "author": "",
      "body_lines": [
        "ECONOMYNEXT – Sri Lanka will set up a separate agency to re-structure state enterprises which are eating up people’s taxes, President Ranil Wickremesinghe said.",
        "Sri Lanka will oversee around 60 state agencies with statements of intent which will be reviewed, he said.",
        "Sri Lanka has already set in motion steps to restructure Ceylon Petroleum Corporation."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Sri Lanka",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "60",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ceylon Petroleum Corporation",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "ශ්‍රී ලංකාව SOE ප්‍රතිව්‍යුහගත කිරීමේ ඒකකයක් පිහිටුවීමට",
      "author": "",
      "body_lines": [
        "ECONOMYNEXT - ජනතාවගේ බදු මුදල් කන රාජ්‍ය ව්‍යවසායන් ප්‍රතිව්‍යුහගත කිරීම සඳහා ශ්‍රී ලංකාව වෙනම ආයතනයක් පිහිටුවන බව ජනාධිපති රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතා පැවසීය.",
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකාව රාජ්‍ය ආයතන 60 ක් පමණ අධීක්ෂණය කරනු ඇති අතර අභිප්‍රාය ප්‍රකාශයන් සමාලෝචනය කෙරෙනු ඇති බව ඔහු පැවසීය.",
        "ලංකා ඛනිජ තෙල් නීතිගත සංස්ථාව ප්‍රතිව්‍යුහගත කිරීමට ශ්‍රී ලංකාව දැනටමත් පියවර ගෙන ඇත."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "60",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ලංකා ඛනිජ තෙල් නීතිගත සංස්ථාව",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "SOE மறுசீரமைப்பு பிரிவை அமைக்க இலங்கை",
      "author": "",
      "body_lines": [
        "பொருளாதாரம் - மக்களின் வரிப்பணத்தைச் சாப்பிடும் அரச நிறுவனங்களை மறுசீரமைப்பதற்காக இலங்கை தனியான நிறுவனமொன்றை அமைக்கும் என ஜனாதிபதி ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "இலங்கை சுமார் 60 அரச நிறுவனங்களை மேற்பார்வையிடும் நோக்கத்துடன் கூடிய அறிக்கைகள் மீளாய்வு செய்யப்படும் என்றும் அவர் கூறினார்.",
        "இலங்கை பெற்றோலியக் கூட்டுத்தாபனத்தை மறுசீரமைப்பதற்கான நடவடிக்கைகளில் இலங்கை ஏற்கனவே இறங்கியுள்ளது."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "இலங்கை",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "60",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை பெற்றோலியக் கூட்டுத்தாபனம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}