{
  "newspaper_id": "news-first-lk",
  "url": "https://www.newsfirst.lk/2022/08/26/marikkar-calls-for-probe-on-sanath-nishantha-s-statement/",
  "time_ut": 1661506020,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Marikkar calls for probe on Sanath Nishantha’s statement",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Marikkar calls for probe on Sanath Nishantha’s statement",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); The President needs to investigate the statements expressed by SLPP MP Sanath Nishantha that can be considered as contempt of court, Samagi Jana Balawegaya MP S.M. Marikkar said.",
        "Speaking to media, the MP said that while former MP Ranjan Ramanayake was imprisoned on charges of contempt of court following comments he made on the side of the road, SLPP MP Sanath Nishantha insulted the Court and judges at a media briefing.",
        "Therefore, MP Marikkar said that it is clear that MP Nishantha insulted the Court after convening a media briefing at the SLPP headquarters in Nelum Mawatha, which essentially represents the stand of the party as well.",
        "\"It's not an insult coming from the MP alone, but also from the Party,\" he said, adding that while the CID is investigating people who entered the president's house and Temple Trees, instead they need to investigate the statement made by SLPP MP Sanath Nishantha, as he represents the SLPP.",
        "Ranjan Ramanayake released from Colombo prison on ‘Conditional Presidential Pardon’",
        "U.S. Donates 3,000 metric tons of food to feed Sri Lankan school children"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Marikkar",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "Sanath Nishantha’s",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "News 1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sanath Nishantha",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Samagi",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Jana Balawegaya",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "S.M. Marikkar",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Ranjan Ramanayake",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sanath Nishantha",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Court",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Marikkar",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Nishantha",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Court",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "SLPP",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Nelum Mawatha",
            "label": "FAC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Party",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "CID",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Temple Trees",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sanath Nishantha",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Ranjan Ramanayake",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "U.S.",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "3,000 metric tons",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lankan",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "මරික්කාර් සනත් නිශාන්තගේ ප්‍රකාශය ගැන පරීක්ෂණයක් ඉල්ලයි",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); අධිකරණයට අපහාස කිරීමක් ලෙස සැලකිය හැකි ශ්‍රී ලංකා පොදුජන පෙරමුණේ පාර්ලිමේන්තු මන්ත්‍රී සනත් නිශාන්ත මහතා ප්‍රකාශ කර ඇති ප්‍රකාශ සම්බන්ධයෙන් ජනාධිපතිවරයා සොයා බැලිය යුතු බව සමගි ජන බලවේගයේ පාර්ලිමේන්තු මන්ත්‍රී එස්.එම්. මරික්කාර් පැවසීය.",
        "මාධ්‍ය වෙත අදහස් දක්වමින් මන්ත්‍රීවරයා කියා සිටියේ හිටපු පාර්ලිමේන්තු මන්ත්‍රී රන්ජන් රාමනායක මහතා පාර අයිනේ කළ ප්‍රකාශයක් හේතුවෙන් අධිකරණයට අපහාස කිරීමේ චෝදනාව මත ඔහු සිරගත කර සිටියදී ශ්‍රී ලංකා පොදුජන පෙරමුණේ පාර්ලිමේන්තු මන්ත්‍රී සනත් නිශාන්ත මාධ්‍ය හමුවකදී අධිකරණයට සහ විනිසුරුවරුන්ට අපහාස කළ බවයි.",
        "එබැවින් පක්ෂයේ ස්ථාවරයද නියෝජනය කරන නෙළුම් මාවතේ පිහිටි ශ්‍රී ලංකා පොදුජන පෙරමුණේ මූලස්ථානයේදී මාධ්‍ය හමුවක් කැදවා නිශාන්ත මන්ත්‍රීවරයා අධිකරණයට අපහාස කළ බව පැහැදිලි බවයි මරික්කාර් මන්ත්‍රීවරයා කියා සිටියේ.",
        "එය මන්ත්‍රීවරයාගෙන් පමණක් නොව පක්‍ෂයෙන්ද සිදුවන අපහාසයක් බවද ඔහු කියා සිටි අතර ජනාධිපතිවරයාගේ නිවසට සහ අරලියගහ මන්දිරයට ඇතුළු වූ පුද්ගලයන් පිළිබඳව රහස් පොලිසිය පරීක්‍ෂණ කරන අතරවාරයේදී ශ්‍රී ලංකා පොදුජන පෙරමුණේ පාර්ලිමේන්තු මන්ත්‍රී සනත් කළ ප්‍රකාශය පිළිබඳව පරීක්‍ෂණයක් කළ යුතු බවද පැවසීය. නිශාන්ත, ශ්‍රී ලංකා පොදුජන පෙරමුණ නියෝජනය කරන නිසා.",
        "‘කොන්දේසි සහිත ජනාධිපති සමාව’ මත රන්ජන් රාමනායක කොළඹ බන්ධනාගාරයෙන් නිදහස්",
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ පාසල් දරුවන් පෝෂණය කිරීම සඳහා එක්සත් ජනපදය ආහාර මෙට්‍රික් ටොන් 3000ක් පරිත්‍යාග කරයි"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "මරික්කාර්",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "සනත් නිශාන්තගේ",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "News 1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "සනත් නිශාන්ත",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "සමගි",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජන බලවේගය",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "එස්.එම්. මරික්කාර්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "රන්ජන් රාමනායක",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "සනත් නිශාන්ත",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "අධිකරණය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "මරික්කාර්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "නිශාන්ත",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "අධිකරණය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "SLPP",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "නෙළුම් මාවත",
            "label": "FAC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "පක්ෂය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "CID",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "අරලියගහ මන්දිරය",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "සනත් නිශාන්ත",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "රන්ජන් රාමනායක",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "එක්සත් ජනපදය.",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මෙට්‍රික් ටොන් 3,000 කි",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලාංකික",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "சனத் நிஷாந்தவின் அறிக்கை தொடர்பில் விசாரணை நடத்துமாறு மரிக்கார் கோரிக்கை விடுத்துள்ளார்",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); நீதிமன்ற அவமதிப்பாகக் கருதப்படும் ஸ்ரீலங்கா பொதுஜன பெரமுனவின் பாராளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர் சனத் நிஷாந்தவின் கருத்துக்கள் தொடர்பில் ஜனாதிபதி விசாரணை நடத்த வேண்டும் என சமகி ஜன பலவேகய பாராளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர் எஸ்.எம். மரிக்கார் தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "ஊடகங்களுக்கு கருத்து தெரிவித்த பாராளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர், முன்னாள் பாராளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர் ரஞ்சன் ராமநாயக்க நீதிமன்றத்தை அவமதித்த குற்றச்சாட்டின் பேரில் சிறையில் அடைக்கப்பட்டிருந்த நிலையில், SLPP பாராளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர் சனத் நிஷாந்த, ஊடகவியலாளர் சந்திப்பில் நீதிமன்றத்தையும் நீதிபதிகளையும் அவமதித்துள்ளார்.",
        "எனவே, கட்சியின் நிலைப்பாட்டைப் பிரதிநிதித்துவப்படுத்தும் ஸ்ரீலங்கா பொதுஜன பெரமுன கட்சியின் தலைமையகமான நெலும் மாவத்தையில் ஊடகவியலாளர் சந்திப்பொன்றை நடத்தியதன் பின்னர் பாராளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர் நிஷாந்த நீதிமன்றத்தை அவமதித்துள்ளார் என்பது தெளிவாகின்றது என பாராளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர் மரிக்கார் தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "“இது எம்.பி.யால் மட்டும் வரும் அவமானம் அல்ல, கட்சியில் இருந்தும் வரும் அவமானம்” என்று கூறிய அவர், ஜனாதிபதியின் வீடு மற்றும் அலரிமாளிகைக்குள் நுழைந்தவர்கள் குறித்து சிஐடி விசாரணை நடத்தி வரும் நிலையில், ஸ்ரீலங்கா பொதுஜன பெரமுனவின் எம்பி சனத்தின் அறிக்கையை விசாரிக்க வேண்டும் என்றார். நிஷாந்த, அவர் SLPP ஐ பிரதிநிதித்துவப்படுத்துகிறார்.",
        "கொழும்பு சிறையிலிருந்து ரஞ்சன் ராமநாயக்க ‘நிபந்தனைக்குட்பட்ட ஜனாதிபதி மன்னிப்பில்’ விடுதலை",
        "இலங்கையின் பாடசாலை மாணவர்களுக்கு உணவளிக்க அமெரிக்கா 3,000 மெட்ரிக் தொன் உணவை வழங்குகிறது"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "மரிக்கார்",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "சனத் நிஷாந்தவின்",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "News 1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சனத் நிஷாந்த",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "சமகி",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜன பலவேகயா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "எஸ்.எம். மரிக்கார்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ரஞ்சன் ராமநாயக்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "சனத் நிஷாந்த",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "நீதிமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "மரிக்கார்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "நிஷாந்த",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "நீதிமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "எஸ்.எல்.பி.பி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "நெலும் மாவத்தை",
            "label": "FAC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பார்ட்டி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "சி.ஐ.டி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "கோவில் மரங்கள்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "சனத் நிஷாந்த",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ரஞ்சன் ராமநாயக்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "எங்களுக்கு.",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "3,000 மெட்ரிக் டன்",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}