{
  "newspaper_id": "ada-lk",
  "url": "https://www.ada.lk/breaking_news/චීන-නැව-එයි/11-396326",
  "time_ut": 1660612090,
  "original_lang": "si",
  "original_title": "චීන නැව එයි",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "The Chinese ship arrives",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "China's experimental ship Yuan Wang 5 has arrived at Hambantota port. This ship arrived at Hambantota port to get fuel and essential services.",
        "The Chinese Embassy has also organized a ceremony at Hambantota port this morning to welcome the ship.",
        "India as well as America expressed their objection regarding the arrival of this ship to Sri Lanka, and then they failed to present reasonable reasons for it, so the government gave the required permission for the ship to arrive at Hambantota.",
        "This ship was supposed to arrive in Sri Lanka on the 11th. However, Sri Lanka made an official request to the Chinese Embassy to delay that date."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Chinese",
          "label": "NORP"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "China",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Yuan Wang",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Hambantota",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "The Chinese Embassy",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "this morning",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "India",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "America",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Hambantota",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the 11th",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Chinese",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "චීන නැව එයි",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "චීනයේ පර්යේෂණාත්මක නෞකාවක් වන යුවාන් වැංග් 5 නෞකාව හම්බන්තොට වරායට පැමිණ තිබේ. මෙම නෞකාව ඉන්ධන හා අත්‍යාවශ්‍ය සේවා ලබා ගැනිම වෙනුවෙන් මෙසේ හම්බන්තොට වරායට පැමිණියේය.",
        "නෞකාව පිළිගැනිම වෙනුවෙන් චීන තානාපති කාර්යාලය විසින් අද පෙරවරුවේ හම්බන්තොට වරායේ උත්සවයක්ද සංවිධානය කර තිබේ.",
        "මෙම නෞකාව ලංකාවට පැමිණීම සම්බන්ධයෙන් ඉන්දියාව මෙන්ම ඇමෙරිකාවද සිය විරෝධය ප්‍රකාශ කළ අතර පසුව ඔවුන්ට ඒ සඳහා සාධාරණ හේතු ඉදිරිපත් කිරීමට අපොහොසත්වූ බැවින් නෞකාවට හම්බන්තොටට පැමිණීමට අවශ්‍ය අවසරය රජය විසින් ලබා දුන්නේය.",
        "මෙම නෞකාව මුලින්ම ලංකාවට පැමිණීමට නියමිතව තිබුණේ පසුගිය 11 වැනිදායි. කෙසේ වෙතත් එම දිනය ප්‍රමාද කරන ලෙස ශ්‍රී ලංකාව චීන තානාපති කාර්යාලයෙන් නිල වශයෙන් ඉල්ලීමට කටයුතු කළේය."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "චීන",
          "label": "NORP"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "චීනය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Yuan Wang",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "හම්බන්තොට",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "චීන තානාපති කාර්යාලය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "මේ උදෑසන",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඇමරිකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "හම්බන්තොට",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "11 වැනි",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "චීන",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "சீனக் கப்பல் வருகிறது",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "சீனாவின் யுவான் வாங் 5 என்ற பரிசோதனைக் கப்பல் ஹம்பாந்தோட்டை துறைமுகத்தை வந்தடைந்துள்ளது. எரிபொருள் மற்றும் அத்தியாவசிய சேவைகளை பெற்றுக்கொள்வதற்காக இந்த கப்பல் ஹம்பாந்தோட்டை துறைமுகத்தை வந்தடைந்தது.",
        "சீன தூதரகம் இன்று காலை ஹம்பாந்தோட்டை துறைமுகத்தில் கப்பலை வரவேற்கும் விழாவிற்கு ஏற்பாடு செய்துள்ளது.",
        "இந்தக் கப்பல் இலங்கைக்கு வருவதற்கு இந்தியாவும் அமெரிக்காவும் ஆட்சேபனை தெரிவித்ததுடன், அதற்கான நியாயமான காரணங்களை முன்வைக்கத் தவறியதால், கப்பலை அம்பாந்தோட்டைக்கு வருவதற்குத் தேவையான அனுமதியை அரசாங்கம் வழங்கியது.",
        "இந்தக் கப்பல் எதிர்வரும் 11ஆம் திகதி இலங்கைக்கு வரவிருந்தது. எவ்வாறாயினும், அந்தத் திகதியை தாமதப்படுத்துமாறு சீனத் தூதரகத்திடம் இலங்கை உத்தியோகபூர்வ கோரிக்கையை விடுத்துள்ளது."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "சீன",
          "label": "NORP"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "சீனா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Yuan Wang",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஹம்பாந்தோட்டை",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "சீன தூதரகம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று காலை",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இந்தியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "அமெரிக்கா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஹம்பாந்தோட்டை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "11வது",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சீன",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}