{
  "newspaper_id": "lankadeepa-lk",
  "url": "https://www.lankadeepa.lk/latest_news/ආයුධයක්-සමඟ-අත්අඩංගුවට-ගත්-සැරයන්-15-තෙක්-රිමාන්ඩ්/1-616258",
  "time_ut": 1657546176,
  "original_lang": "si",
  "original_title": "ආයුධයක් සමඟ අත්අඩංගුවට ගත් සැරයන් 15 තෙක් රිමාන්ඩ්",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Sergeant arrested with weapon remanded until 15",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "Colombo Additional Magistrate Keminda Perera ordered today 11 to remand the Mechanical Police Sergeant of the Police Transport Division who was arrested by the Fort Police while standing in front of the Presidential Secretariat wearing a police uniform and carrying a sharp weapon.",
        "A police mechanical sergeant attached to the Police Transport Division residing at First Lane, Samagi Mawatha, Magammana, Homagama was remanded in custody.",
        "The Fort Police informed the court that this suspect police officer was arrested near the main entrance of the office today (11) at 4:10 am while he was standing near the Presidential Secretariat office with a knife in his hand which could be used to commit a crime."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "15",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "today 11",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Police Transport Division",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Fort Police",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Presidential Secretariat",
            "label": "LOC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the Police Transport Division",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "First Lane",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Samagi Mawatha",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Magammana",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Homagama",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "11",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "4:10 am",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "Presidential Secretariat",
            "label": "LOC"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "ආයුධයක් සමඟ අත්අඩංගුවට ගත් සැරයන් 15 තෙක් රිමාන්ඩ්",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "පොලිස් නිල ඇඳුමින් සැරසී තියුණු ආයුධයක් ද අතැතිව ජනාධිපති ලේකම් කාර්යාලය ඉදිරිපිට රැඳී සිටියදී කොටුව පොලීසිය අත්අඩංගුවට ගත් පොලිස් ප්‍රවාහන කොට්ඨාශයේ යාන්ත්‍රික පොලිස් සැරයන්වරයා ලබන 15 වැනි දා තෙක් රක්ෂිත බන්ධනාගාර ගතකරන ලෙස කොළඹ අතිරේක මහේස්ත්‍රාත් කේමින්ද පෙරේරා මහතා අද 11 නියෝග කළේය.",
        "මෙලෙස රක්ෂිත බන්ධනාගාර ගත කරනු ලැබුවේ පළමු පටුමග,  සමගි මාවත,  මාගම්මන , හෝමාගම පදිංචි පොලිස් ප්‍රවාහන කොට්ඨාශය ට අනුයුක්තව රාජකාරි කළ පොලිස් යාන්ත්‍රික සැරයන් වරයෙකි.",
        "සැකකටයුතු අයුරින් පොලිස් නිල ඇඳුමෙන් සැරසී අපරාධයක් කළ හැකි පිහියක් අතැතිව ජනාධිපති ලේකම් කාර්යාලය අසල රැදී සිටියදී මෙම සැකකාර පොලිස් නිලධාරියා අද  (11) පෙරවරු හතරයි දහයට එහි ප්‍රධාන දොරටුව අසලදී අත්අඩංගුවට ගත් බව කොටුව පොලිසිය කොටුව පොලිසිය අධිකරණයට දැනුම් දුන්නේය."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "15",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "අද 11",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "පොලිස් ප්‍රවාහන අංශය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "කොටුව පොලිසිය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජනාධිපති ලේකම් කාර්යාලය",
            "label": "LOC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "පොලිස් ප්‍රවාහන අංශය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "පළමු පටුමග",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "සමගි මාවත",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "මාගම්මන",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Homagama",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "11",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "4:10 පෙ.ව",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජනාධිපති ලේකම් කාර්යාලය",
            "label": "LOC"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "ஆயுதங்களுடன் கைது செய்யப்பட்ட சார்ஜன்ட் எதிர்வரும் 15ஆம் திகதி வரை விளக்கமறியலில் வைக்கப்பட்டுள்ளார்",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "பொலிஸ் சீருடை அணிந்து, கூரிய ஆயுதம் ஏந்தியவாறு ஜனாதிபதி செயலகத்திற்கு முன்பாக நின்றிருந்த போது, ​​கோட்டை பொலிஸாரால் கைது செய்யப்பட்ட பொலிஸ் போக்குவரத்து பிரிவின் இயந்திரவியல் பொலிஸ் சார்ஜனை விளக்கமறியலில் வைக்குமாறு கொழும்பு மேலதிக நீதவான் கெமிந்த பெரேரா இன்று 11 உத்தரவிட்டுள்ளார்.",
        "ஹோமாகம, மாகம்மன, சமகி மாவத்தை முதலாம் தடத்தில் வசிக்கும் பொலிஸ் போக்குவரத்துப் பிரிவில் கடமையாற்றும் பொலிஸ் மெக்கானிக்கல் சார்ஜன்ட் ஒருவரே விளக்கமறியலில் வைக்கப்பட்டுள்ளார்.",
        "இன்று (11) அதிகாலை 4.10 மணியளவில் ஜனாதிபதி செயலகத்திற்கு அருகில் கத்தியுடன் நின்று கொண்டிருந்த போதே குறித்த சந்தேகநபர் அலுவலக பிரதான நுழைவாயிலுக்கு அருகில் வைத்து கைது செய்யப்பட்டதாக கோட்டை பொலிஸார் நீதிமன்றில் தெரிவித்தனர். குற்றம்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "15",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "இன்று 11",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "பொலிஸ் போக்குவரத்து பிரிவு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "கோட்டை போலீஸ்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜனாதிபதி செயலகம்",
            "label": "LOC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பொலிஸ் போக்குவரத்து பிரிவு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "முதல் பாதை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "சமகி மாவத்தை",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "மகம்மன",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Homagama",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "11",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "காலை 4:10 மணி",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜனாதிபதி செயலகம்",
            "label": "LOC"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}