{
  "newspaper_id": "lankadeepa-lk",
  "url": "https://www.lankadeepa.lk/world_news/ඉන්දීය-ජනාධිපතිවරණය-අද/14-616576",
  "time_ut": 1658113175,
  "original_lang": "si",
  "original_title": "ඉන්දීය ජනාධිපතිවරණය අද",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Indian presidential election today",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "The Indian presidential election is scheduled to be held today (18) and the two main candidates in the presidential election are Draupadi Murmu and Yashwat Singh.",
        "Draupadi Murmu will contest the presidential election representing Prime Minister Narendra Modi's BJP-led National Democratic Alliance, while Yashwat Singh will represent opposition political groups led by the United Progressive Alliance.",
        "64-year-old Draupadi Murmu is an Indian politician as well as a teacher. She is a member of Bharatiya Janata Party. Indian Prime Minister Narendra Modi has said on many occasions that she is suitable for the presidential candidacy.",
        "Draupadi Murmu was the Governor of Jharkhand from 2015 to 2021. She is a leader representing the tribal community of the Indian state of Odisha. If Murmu is elected president, she will be the first tribal woman to hold the post.",
        "Yashwan Sinha, 84, represents the Trinamool Congress. Sinha, a former BJP leader. Sinha served as the Finance Minister of India from 1990 to 1991 and from 1998 to July 2002. It was under Prime Ministers Chandra Shekhar and Atal Bihari Vajpayee.",
        "Yashwan Sinha was the Home Minister of India from 2002 to 2004.",
        "According to the Constitution of India, the President of the country is not elected by popular vote, but by the votes of the representatives of the Parliament.",
        "The counting of votes and the release of the results of the presidential election held today (18) will take place on the 21st.",
        "Although the Prime Minister has more powers, the President of India is the head of state of the Republic of India. The President is the formative leader of the Indian Executive, Legislature and Judiciary. In addition, the President is also the Commander-in-Chief of the Indian Armed Forces. The term of office of the President of India is five years.",
        "The selection of the President is done by an electoral college which includes members of the two Houses of the Parliament of the Central Government (Lok Sabha and Raj Sabha) and representatives of the State Councils.",
        "The electorate consists of members elected by popular vote of twenty-nine Indian states and representatives of the constituent assemblies of union territories."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Indian",
          "label": "NORP"
        },
        {
          "text": "today",
          "label": "DATE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Indian",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "18",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "two",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Draupadi Murmu",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Yashwat Singh",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Draupadi Murmu",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Narendra Modi's",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "BJP",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "National Democratic Alliance",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Yashwat Singh",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the United Progressive Alliance",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "64-year-old",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Draupadi Murmu",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Indian",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Bharatiya Janata Party",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Indian",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Narendra Modi",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Draupadi Murmu",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Jharkhand",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "from 2015 to 2021",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Indian",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Odisha",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Murmu",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Yashwan Sinha",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "84",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Trinamool Congress",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "BJP",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Finance",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "India",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "1990 to 1991",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "1998 to July 2002",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Yashwan Sinha",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "India",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "2002",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "2004",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the Constitution of India",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "18",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "the 21st",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "India",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Republic of India",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Indian Executive",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Legislature",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Indian Armed Forces",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "India",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "five years",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "two",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Houses",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Parliament of the Central Government",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Lok Sabha",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Raj Sabha",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the State Councils",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "twenty-nine",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Indian",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "ඉන්දීය ජනාධිපතිවරණය අද",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "ඉන්දීය ජනාධිපතිවරණය අද (18) පැවැත්වීමට නියමිත අතර ජනාධිපතිවරණයේ ප්‍රධාන අපේක්ෂකයන් දෙදෙනා වන්නේ ද්‍රෞපදී මුර්මු සහ යෂ්වාත් සිං ය.",
        "ද්‍රෞපදී මුර්මු අග්‍රාමාත්‍ය නරේන්ද්‍ර මෝදිගේ භාරතීය ජනතා පක්ෂය ප්‍රමුඛ ජාතික ප්‍රජාතන්ත්‍රවාදී සන්ධානය නියෝජනය කරමින් ජනාධිපතිවරණයට ඉදිරිපත් වනු ඇති අතර, යෂ්වාත් සිං නියෝජනය කරන්නේ, එක්සත් ප්‍රගතශීලී සන්ධානය ප්‍රමුඛ විපක්ෂ දේශපාලන කණ්ඩායම් ය.",
        "64 හැවිරිදි ද්‍රෞපදී මුර්මු ඉන්දීය දේශපාලනඥයකු මෙන්ම ගුරුවරියකි. ඇය භාරතීය ජනතා පක්ෂ සාමාජිකාවකි. ඇය ජනාධිපති අපේක්ෂකත්වය සඳහා සුදුසු යැයි ඉන්දීය අග්‍රාමාත්‍ය නරේන්ද්‍ර මෝදි අවස්ථා ගණනාවකදී පවසා තිබුණි.",
        "2015 සිට 2021 තෙක් ජර්කාන්ද් ප්‍රාන්තයේ ආණ්ඩුකාර ධුරය හෙබවූයේ ද්‍රෞපදී මුර්මු ය. ඇය ඉන්දියාවේ ඔඩීෂා ප්‍රාන්තයේ ගෝත්‍රික ප්‍රජාව නියෝජනය කරන නායිකාවකි. මුර්මු ජනාධිපති ධුරයට පත්වුවහොත් එම ධුරයට පත් වන ප්‍රථම ගෝත්‍රික කාන්තාව වන්නේ ඇයයි.",
        "84 හැවිරිදි යෂ්වාන් සිංහා නියෝජනය කරන්නේ ත්‍රිණමූල් කොංග්‍රසයයි. සිංහා, භාරතීය ජනතා පක්ෂයේ හිටපු නායකයෙකි. 1990 සිට 1991 වසර තෙක් කාලයේත් 1998 සිට 2002 ජූලි මාසය දක්වාත් සිංහා ඉන්දියාවේ මුදල් අමාත්‍යවරයා ලෙස කටයුතු කළේය. ඒ අග්‍රාමාත්‍ය චන්ද්‍ර ෂෙකර් සහ අතල් බිහාරි වජ්පායි අග්‍රාමාත්‍යවරුන් යටතේය.",
        "2002 සිට 2004 තෙක් කාලයේ ඉන්දීය ස්වදේශ කටයුතු අමාත්‍ය ධුරය හෙබවූයේ ද යෂ්වාන් සිංහා ය.",
        "ඉන්දියානු ආණ්ඩුක්‍රම ව්‍යවස්ථාව අනුව රටේ ජනාධිපතිවරයා තෝරා පත්කර ගනු ලබන්නේ මහජන ඡන්දයෙන් නොව, පාර්ලිමේන්තු නියෝජිතයන්ගේ ඡන්දයෙනි.",
        "අද (18) පැවැත්වෙන ජනාධිපතිවරණයේ ඡන්ද ගණන් කිරීම සහ ප්‍රතිඵල නිකුත් කිරීම එලැඹෙන 21 වැනිදා සිදුවනු ඇත.",
        "අග්‍රාමාත්‍යවරයාට වැඩි බලතල ඇතත්, ඉන්දීය ජනාධිපතිවරයා යනු ඉන්දීය ජනරජයේ රාජ්‍ය නායකයා ය. ජනාධිපතිවරයා, ඉන්දීය විධායකයේ, ව්‍යවස්ථාදායකයේ සහ අධිකරණයේ ආකෘතික නායකයා වන්නේ ද ජනාධිපතිවරයාය. ඊට අමතරව, ඉන්දියානු සන්නද්ධ හමුදා සේනාධිනායකයා ද වන්නේ ජනාධිපතිවරයාය. ඉන්දීය ජනාධිපතිවරයාගේ ධුර කාලය වසර පහකි.",
        "ජනාධිපතිවරයා තෝරා ගැනීම සිදුවන්නේ මධ්‍යම ආණ්ඩුවේ පාර්ලිමේන්තුවේ මන්ත්‍රණ සභා දෙකහි (ලෝක් සභාව සහ රාජ් සභාව) මන්ත්‍රීවරුන්ගේ සහ ප්‍රාන්ත මන්ත්‍රී මණ්ඩල නියෝජිතයන් ද ඇතුළත් ඡන්ද පීඨයක් මගිනි.",
        "ඉන්දීය ප්‍රාන්ත විසි නවයක මහජන ඡන්දයෙන් තේරී පත්වූ මන්ත්‍රීවරුන් සහ සාංගමික ප්‍රදේශයන්හි ව්‍යවස්ථා සම්පාදක මණ්ඩලවල නියෝජිතයෝ එම ඡන්ද පීඨයට ඇතුළත් වෙති."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ඉන්දීය",
          "label": "NORP"
        },
        {
          "text": "අද",
          "label": "DATE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දීය",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "18",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "දෙක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ද්‍රෞපදී මුර්මු",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "යෂ්වත් සිං",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ද්‍රෞපදී මුර්මු",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "නරේන්ද්‍ර මෝදිගේ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "බී.ජේ.පී",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජාතික ප්‍රජාතන්ත්‍රවාදී සන්ධානය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "යෂ්වත් සිං",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "එක්සත් ප්‍රගතිශීලී සන්ධානය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "64 හැවිරිදිය",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ද්‍රෞපදී මුර්මු",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දීය",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "භාරතීය ජනතා පක්ෂය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දීය",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "නරේන්ද්‍ර මෝදි",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ද්‍රෞපදී මුර්මු",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජාර්කන්ඩ්",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "2015 සිට 2021 දක්වා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දීය",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඔඩිෂා",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මුර්මු",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "යෂ්වාන් සිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "84",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ත්‍රිනාමුල් කොංග්‍රසය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "බී.ජේ.පී",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "මූල්ය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "1990 සිට 1991 දක්වා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "1998 සිට 2002 ජූලි දක්වා",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "යෂ්වාන් සිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "2002",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "2004",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දීය ආණ්ඩුක්රම ව්යවස්ථාව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "18",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "21 වෙනිදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දීය ජනරජය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දියානු විධායකය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ව්යවස්ථාදායකය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දීය සන්නද්ධ හමුදා",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "අවුරුදු පහක්",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "දෙක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "නිවාස",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "මධ්‍යම රජයේ පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ලෝක් සභාව",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "රාජ් සභාව",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "රාජ්ය සභා",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "විසි නවය",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දීය",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "இந்திய ஜனாதிபதி தேர்தல் இன்று",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "இந்திய ஜனாதிபதித் தேர்தல் இன்று (18) நடைபெறவுள்ளதுடன், ஜனாதிபதித் தேர்தலில் இரு முக்கிய வேட்பாளர்கள் திரௌபதி முர்மு மற்றும் யஷ்வத் சிங்.",
        "குடியரசுத் தலைவர் தேர்தலில் பிரதமர் நரேந்திர மோடியின் பாஜக தலைமையிலான தேசிய ஜனநாயகக் கூட்டணி சார்பில் திரௌபதி முர்முவும், ஐக்கிய முற்போக்குக் கூட்டணி தலைமையிலான எதிர்க்கட்சிகள் சார்பில் யஷ்வத் சிங்கும் போட்டியிடவுள்ளனர்.",
        "64 வயதான திரௌபதி முர்மு ஒரு இந்திய அரசியல்வாதி மற்றும் ஆசிரியரும் ஆவார். அவர் பாரதிய ஜனதா கட்சியின் உறுப்பினர். இந்தியப் பிரதமர் நரேந்திர மோடி, குடியரசுத் தலைவர் வேட்பாளருக்குத் தான் பொருத்தமானவர் என்று பல சந்தர்ப்பங்களில் கூறியிருக்கிறார்.",
        "திரௌபதி முர்மு 2015 முதல் 2021 வரை ஜார்க்கண்ட் ஆளுநராக இருந்தார். அவர் இந்திய மாநிலமான ஒடிசாவின் பழங்குடி சமூகத்தை பிரதிநிதித்துவப்படுத்தும் ஒரு தலைவர். முர்மு அதிபராக தேர்ந்தெடுக்கப்பட்டால், அப்பதவியை வகிக்கும் முதல் பழங்குடியின பெண் என்ற பெருமையை அவர் பெறுவார்.",
        "84 வயதான யஷ்வன் சின்ஹா, திரிணாமுல் காங்கிரஸை பிரதிநிதித்துவப்படுத்துகிறார். சின்ஹா, முன்னாள் பாஜக தலைவர். சின்ஹா ​​1990 முதல் 1991 வரை மற்றும் 1998 முதல் ஜூலை 2002 வரை இந்தியாவின் நிதி அமைச்சராக பணியாற்றினார். இது பிரதமர்கள் சந்திரசேகர் மற்றும் அடல் பிஹாரி வாஜ்பாய் ஆட்சியில் இருந்தது.",
        "யஷ்வான் சின்ஹா ​​2002 முதல் 2004 வரை இந்தியாவின் உள்துறை அமைச்சராக இருந்தார்.",
        "இந்திய அரசியலமைப்புச் சட்டத்தின்படி, நாட்டின் குடியரசுத் தலைவர் மக்கள் வாக்குகளால் தேர்ந்தெடுக்கப்படுவதில்லை, மாறாக நாடாளுமன்றத்தின் பிரதிநிதிகளின் வாக்குகளால் தேர்ந்தெடுக்கப்படுகிறார்.",
        "இன்று (18) இடம்பெற்ற ஜனாதிபதித் தேர்தலின் வாக்கு எண்ணிக்கை மற்றும் முடிவுகள் வெளியீடு எதிர்வரும் 21ஆம் திகதி இடம்பெறவுள்ளது.",
        "பிரதமருக்கு அதிக அதிகாரங்கள் இருந்தாலும், இந்திய குடியரசுத் தலைவரே இந்தியக் குடியரசின் மாநிலத் தலைவர். குடியரசுத் தலைவர் இந்திய நிறைவேற்று, சட்டமன்றம் மற்றும் நீதித்துறையின் உருவாக்கத் தலைவர் ஆவார். மேலும், குடியரசுத் தலைவர் இந்திய ஆயுதப் படைகளின் தலைமைத் தளபதியாகவும் இருக்கிறார். இந்திய ஜனாதிபதியின் பதவிக்காலம் ஐந்து ஆண்டுகள்.",
        "மத்திய அரசின் நாடாளுமன்றத்தின் இரு அவைகளின் (லோக்சபா மற்றும் ராஜ் சபா) உறுப்பினர்கள் மற்றும் மாநில கவுன்சில்களின் பிரதிநிதிகளை உள்ளடக்கிய தேர்தல் கல்லூரியால் குடியரசுத் தலைவரைத் தேர்ந்தெடுப்பது செய்யப்படுகிறது.",
        "வாக்காளர்கள் இருபத்தி ஒன்பது இந்திய மாநிலங்களின் மக்கள் வாக்கு மூலம் தேர்ந்தெடுக்கப்பட்ட உறுப்பினர்கள் மற்றும் யூனியன் பிரதேசங்களின் தொகுதி சட்டமன்றங்களின் பிரதிநிதிகளைக் கொண்டுள்ளனர்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "இந்தியன்",
          "label": "NORP"
        },
        {
          "text": "இன்று",
          "label": "DATE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "இந்தியன்",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "18",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "இரண்டு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "திரௌபதி முர்மு",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "யஷ்வத் சிங்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "திரௌபதி முர்மு",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "நரேந்திர மோடியின்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "பா.ஜ.க",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "தேசிய ஜனநாயகக் கூட்டணி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "யஷ்வத் சிங்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஐக்கிய முற்போக்குக் கூட்டணி",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "64 வயது",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "திரௌபதி முர்மு",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்தியன்",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாரதிய ஜனதா கட்சி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்தியன்",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "நரேந்திர மோடி",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "திரௌபதி முர்மு",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜார்கண்ட்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "2015 முதல் 2021 வரை",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்தியன்",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஒடிசா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "முர்மு",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "யஷ்வான் சின்ஹா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "84",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "திரிணாமுல் காங்கிரஸ்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "பா.ஜ.க",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "நிதி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்தியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "1990 முதல் 1991 வரை",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "1998 முதல் ஜூலை 2002 வரை",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "யஷ்வான் சின்ஹா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்தியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "2002",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "2004",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இந்திய அரசியலமைப்பு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "18",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "21 ஆம் தேதி",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இந்தியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்திய குடியரசு",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்திய நிர்வாகி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "சட்டமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்திய ஆயுதப்படைகள்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்தியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஐந்து வருடம்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இரண்டு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "வீடுகள்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "மத்திய அரசின் பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "மக்களவை",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ராஜ் சபா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "மாநில கவுன்சில்கள்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இருபத்து ஒன்பது",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்தியன்",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}