{
  "newspaper_id": "news-first-lk",
  "url": "https://www.newsfirst.lk/2022/08/24/sri-lanka-president-to-present-interim-budget-on-30th-august/",
  "time_ut": 1661339760,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Sri Lanka President to present interim budget on 30th August",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Sri Lanka President to present interim budget on 30th August",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); President Ranil Wickremesinghe in his capacity of Minister of Finance, Economic Stability and National Policies is to present the inauguration speech of the second reading of the Appropriation (Amendment) Bill on August 30th.",
        "This decision was taken at the Committee on Parliamentary Business chaired by the Deputy Speaker of Parliament Ajith Rajapakse this morning (24) to discuss the business of parliament of the coming week.",
        "Accordingly, on August 30th, Parliament is scheduled to convene at 1:00 PM and the President is to present the second reading of the Appropriation (Amendment) Bill following which, the Parliament will be adjourned.",
        "The debate on the second reading of the Appropriation (Amendment) Bill will be held on August 31st and September 1st from 9.30 am to 5.30 pm without lunch break.",
        "Furthermore, on September 2nd from 9.30 am to 4.30 pm, the second reading of the Appropriation (Amendment) Bill will be debated, following which the Bill is scheduled to be passed after the committee stage and the third reading.",
        "Three Regulations under the Foreign Exchange Act, a resolution under the Customs Ordinance and Orders under the Special Commodity Levy Act are also scheduled to be approved in Parliament on the same day.",
        "On the 29th (Monday), according to a motion brought by the opposition, the adjournment debate will be held from 9.30 am to 4.30 pm on “The difficulties faced by the General Public due to increase in the electricity Tariff by a large Proportion”.",
        "The Leader of the House Minister (Dr.) Susil Premajayantha informed the committee that a special program to inform the government and opposition members about the current economic situation will be held on the 30th from 2.00 pm to 4.00 pm conducted by the Governor of the Central Bank Dr. Nandalal Weerasinghe. The Leader of the House also stated that he expects the participation of all members of the government and the opposition.",
        "Meanwhile, the Leader of the House said that by making an amendment to the Standing Orders, they will promptly appoint the Sectoral Oversight Committees. He also said that according to the President’s suggestion three more standing committees are expected to be established in order to strengthen the Parliamentary Committee system.",
        "Also, a discussion was also held regarding the need to give fair time to the Members of Parliament who left the Government party and act independently during the parliamentary debates.",
        "SL Police cites specific UN Security Council Resolution as relevant in PTA arrests",
        "President’s Head of Security at inquiry over assault on journalists",
        "Activist Senadhi Guruge arrested; Opp. Leader not allowed to see activist"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Sri Lanka",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "August",
          "label": "DATE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "News 1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Economic Stability and National Policies",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "second",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Appropriation (Amendment)",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "August 30th",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the Committee on Parliamentary Business",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ajith Rajapakse",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "this morning",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "24",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "the coming week",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "August 30th",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "1:00 PM",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "second",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Appropriation (Amendment) Bill",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "second",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Appropriation (Amendment) Bill",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "August 31st and September 1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "9.30 am to 5.30 pm",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "September 2nd",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "9.30 am to 4.30 pm",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "second",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Appropriation (Amendment) Bill",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Bill",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "third",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the Foreign Exchange Act",
            "label": "LAW"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Customs Ordinance and Orders",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the same day",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the 29th",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Monday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "9.30 am to 4.30 pm",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "the General Public",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Tariff",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Proportion",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "House",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Susil Premajayantha",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the 30th",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "2.00 pm",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "4.00 pm",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "Nandalal Weerasinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "House",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "House",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Standing Orders",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Sectoral Oversight Committees",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "three",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliamentary Committee",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "SL Police",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "UN Security Council Resolution",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "PTA",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "Opp",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "ශ්‍රී ලංකා ජනපති අතුරු අයවැය අගෝස්තු 30 වෙනිදා ඉදිරිපත් කරයි",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); මුදල්, ආර්ථික ස්ථාවරත්වය සහ ජාතික ප්‍රතිපත්ති අමාත්‍යවරයා වශයෙන් ජනාධිපති රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතා විසින් විසර්ජන (සංශෝධන) පනත් කෙටුම්පත දෙවැනි වර කියවීමේ සමාරම්භක කතාව අගෝස්තු 30 වැනිදා ඉදිරිපත් කිරීමට නියමිතය.",
        "ඉදිරි සතියේ පාර්ලිමේන්තුවේ කටයුතු පිළිබඳව සාකච්ඡා කිරීම සඳහා අද (24) පෙරවරුවේ නියෝජ්‍ය කථානායක අජිත් රාජපක්ෂ මහතාගේ ප්‍රධානත්වයෙන් පැවති පාර්ලිමේන්තු කටයුතු පිළිබඳ කාරක සභාවේදී මෙම තීරණය ගෙන ඇත.",
        "ඒ අනුව අගෝස්තු 30 වැනි දින පාර්ලිමේන්තුව පස්වරු 1.00 ට රැස්වීමට නියමිත අතර ජනාධිපතිවරයා විසින් විසර්ජන (සංශෝධන) පනත් කෙටුම්පත දෙවැනි වර කියවීම ඉදිරිපත් කිරීමට නියමිත අතර ඉන් අනතුරුව පාර්ලිමේන්තුව කල් තැබීමට නියමිතය.",
        "විසර්ජන (සංශෝධන) පනත් කෙටුම්පත දෙවැනිවර කියවීමේ විවාදය අගෝස්තු 31 සහ සැප්තැම්බර් 1 වැනි දින උදේ 9.30 සිට පස්වරු 5.30 දක්වා දිවා ආහාර විවේකයකින් තොරව පැවැත්වේ.",
        "තවද, සැප්තැම්බර් 02 වැනිදා පෙරවරු 9.30 සිට පස්වරු 4.30 දක්වා විසර්ජන (සංශෝධන) පනත් කෙටුම්පත දෙවැනි වර කියවීම විවාදයට ගැනෙන අතර, අනතුරුව කාරක සභා අවස්ථාවෙන් සහ තෙවැනි වර කියවීමෙන් අනතුරුව පනත් කෙටුම්පත සම්මත කිරීමට නියමිතය.",
        "විදේශ විනිමය පනත යටතේ රෙගුලාසි තුනක්, රේගු ආඥාපනත යටතේ යෝජනාවක් සහ විශේෂ වෙළඳ භාණ්ඩ බදු පනත යටතේ නියෝග ද එදින පාර්ලිමේන්තුවේදී අනුමත කිරීමට නියමිතය.",
        "විපක්‍ෂය විසින් ගෙන එන ලද යෝජනාවකට අනුව ලබන 29 වැනිදා (සඳුදා) “විශාල ප්‍රමාණයකින් විදුලි බිල වැඩි කිරීම නිසා සාමාන්‍ය ජනතාව මුහුණ දෙන දුෂ්කරතා” මැයෙන් සභාව කල් තැබීමේ විවාදය පෙරවරු 9.30 සිට පස්වරු 4.30 දක්වා පැවැත්වේ.",
        "වත්මන් ආර්ථික තත්ත්වය පිළිබඳව ආණ්ඩු පක්‍ෂය සහ විපක්‍ෂයේ මන්ත‍්‍රීවරුන් දැනුවත් කිරීමේ විශේෂ වැඩසටහනක් මධ්‍යම ආණ්ඩුකාරවරයාගේ ප‍්‍රධානත්වයෙන් ලබන 30 වැනිදා පස්වරු 2.00 සිට 4.00 දක්වා පැවැත්වෙන බව සභානායක අමාත්‍ය (ආචාර්ය) සුසිල් පේ‍්‍රමජයන්ත මහතා කමිටුවට දැනුම් දුන්නේය. බැංකුව ආචාර්ය නන්දලාල් වීරසිංහ. ආණ්ඩු පක්ෂයේ සහ විපක්ෂයේ සියලුම මන්ත්‍රීවරුන්ගේ සහභාගීත්වය අපේක්ෂා කරන බව ද සභානායකවරයා ප්‍රකාශ කළා.",
        "මේ අතර, ස්ථාවර නියෝගවලට සංශෝධනයක් සිදු කර කඩිනමින් ආංශික අධීක්ෂණ කාරක සභා පත් කිරීමට කටයුතු කරන බව සභානායකවරයා පැවසීය. ජනාධිපතිවරයාගේ යෝජනාවට අනුව පාර්ලිමේන්තු කාරක සභා ක්‍රමය ශක්තිමත් කිරීම සඳහා තවත් ස්ථාවර කමිටු තුනක් ස්ථාපිත කිරීමට බලාපොරොත්තු වන බවද ඔහු සඳහන් කළේය.",
        "එමෙන්ම පාර්ලිමේන්තු විවාදවලදී ආණ්ඩු පක්ෂයෙන් ඉවත් වී ස්වාධීනව කටයුතු කළ මන්ත්‍රීවරුන්ට සාධාරණ කාලයක් ලබාදීමේ අවශ්‍යතාව සම්බන්ධයෙන් ද සාකච්ඡාවක් පැවැත්වුණා.",
        "ත්‍රස්තවාදය වැළැක්වීමේ පනත අත් අඩංගුවට ගැනීමේදී ශ්‍රී ලංකා පොලිසිය අදාළ එක්සත් ජාතීන්ගේ ආරක්ෂක කවුන්සිලයේ නිශ්චිත යෝජනාව උපුටා දක්වයි",
        "මාධ්‍යවේදීන්ට පහරදීම ගැන ජනපතිගේ ආරක්ෂක ප්‍රධානියා පරීක්ෂණයට",
        "ක්‍රියාකාරි සේනධි ගුරුගේ අත්අඩංගුවට; විරුද්ධ නායකයාට ක්‍රියාකාරිකයෙකු බැලීමට අවසර නැත"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "අගෝස්තු",
          "label": "DATE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "News 1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ආර්ථික ස්ථාවරත්වය සහ ජාතික ප්‍රතිපත්ති",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "දෙවැනි",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "විසර්ජනය (සංශෝධන)",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "අගෝස්තු 30 වැනිදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තු කටයුතු පිළිබඳ කාරක සභාව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "අජිත් රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "මේ උදෑසන",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "24",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉදිරි සතිය",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "අගෝස්තු 30 වැනිදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "1:00 PM",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "දෙවැනි",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "විසර්ජන (සංශෝධන) පනත් කෙටුම්පත",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "දෙවැනි",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "විසර්ජන (සංශෝධන) පනත් කෙටුම්පත",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "අගෝස්තු 31 සහ සැප්තැම්බර් 1",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "9.30 සිට සවස 5.30 දක්වා",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "සැප්තැම්බර් 2 වැනිදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "9.30 සිට සවස 4.30 දක්වා",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "දෙවැනි",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "විසර්ජන (සංශෝධන) පනත් කෙටුම්පත",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "බිල්පත්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "තෙවන",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "විදේශ විනිමය පනත",
            "label": "LAW"
          },
          {
            "text": "රේගු ආඥාපනත සහ නියෝග",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "එදිනම",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "29 වෙනිදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "සඳුදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "9.30 සිට සවස 4.30 දක්වා",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "පොදු මහජනතාව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "තීරුබදු",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "සමානුපාතිකය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "නිවස",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "සුසිල් ප්‍රේමජයන්ත",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "30 වැනි",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "2.00 ප.ව",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "4.00 ප.ව",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "නන්දලාල් වීරසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "නිවස",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "නිවස",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ස්ථාවර නියෝග",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ආංශික අධීක්ෂණ කාරක සභා",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "තුන්",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තු කාරක සභාව",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකා පොලිසිය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "එක්සත් ජාතීන්ගේ ආරක්ෂක මණ්ඩලයේ යෝජනාව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "PTA",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "විරුද්ධ",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "இலங்கை ஜனாதிபதி இடைக்கால வரவு செலவுத் திட்டத்தை ஆகஸ்ட் 30ஆம் திகதி சமர்ப்பிக்கவுள்ளார்",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); நிதி, பொருளாதார ஸ்திரத்தன்மை மற்றும் தேசிய கொள்கைகள் அமைச்சர் என்ற வகையில் ஜனாதிபதி ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க, நிதி ஒதுக்கீட்டு (திருத்த) சட்டமூலத்தின் இரண்டாம் வாசிப்பின் ஆரம்ப உரையை ஆகஸ்ட் 30 ஆம் திகதி சமர்ப்பிக்க உள்ளார்.",
        "எதிர்வரும் வாரத்திற்கான பாராளுமன்ற அலுவல்கள் தொடர்பில் ஆலோசிப்பதற்காக இன்று (24) காலை பாராளுமன்ற பிரதி சபாநாயகர் அஜித் ராஜபக்ஷ தலைமையில் கூடிய பாராளுமன்ற அலுவல்கள் குழுவில் இந்த தீர்மானம் எடுக்கப்பட்டுள்ளது.",
        "இதன்படி, ஆகஸ்ட் 30 ஆம் திகதி, பாராளுமன்றம் பிற்பகல் 1.00 மணிக்கு கூடவுள்ளதுடன், ஒதுக்கீட்டு (திருத்த) சட்டமூலத்தின் இரண்டாம் வாசிப்பை ஜனாதிபதி சமர்பிக்கவுள்ளதைத் தொடர்ந்து, பாராளுமன்றம் ஒத்திவைக்கப்படும்.",
        "ஒதுக்கீட்டு (திருத்தம்) சட்டமூலத்தின் இரண்டாம் வாசிப்பு மீதான விவாதம் ஆகஸ்ட் 31 மற்றும் செப்டம்பர் 1 ஆம் தேதிகளில் காலை 9.30 மணி முதல் மாலை 5.30 மணி வரை மதிய உணவு இடைவேளையின்றி நடைபெறும்.",
        "மேலும், செப்டெம்பர் 2ஆம் திகதி காலை 9.30 மணி முதல் மாலை 4.30 மணி வரை ஒதுக்கீட்டு (திருத்த) சட்டமூலத்தின் இரண்டாம் வாசிப்பு விவாதம் நடத்தப்பட்டு, அதனைத் தொடர்ந்து குழு நிலை மற்றும் மூன்றாம் வாசிப்பின் பின்னர் சட்டமூலம் நிறைவேற்றப்படவுள்ளது.",
        "அந்நியச் செலாவணிச் சட்டத்தின் கீழ் மூன்று ஒழுங்குமுறைகள், சுங்கக் கட்டளைச் சட்டத்தின் கீழ் ஒரு தீர்மானம் மற்றும் சிறப்புப் பொருட்கள் வரிச் சட்டத்தின் கீழ் ஆணைகள் ஆகியவையும் அன்றைய தினம் நாடாளுமன்றத்தில் அங்கீகரிக்கப்பட உள்ளன.",
        "எதிர்வரும் 29ஆம் திகதி (திங்கட்கிழமை) எதிர்கட்சிகளால் கொண்டுவரப்பட்ட பிரேரணையின் பிரகாரம், “பெரும்பாலான மின்சாரக் கட்டண உயர்வால் பொது மக்கள் எதிர்நோக்கும் சிரமங்கள்” என்ற தலைப்பில் காலை 9.30 மணி முதல் மாலை 4.30 மணி வரை ஒத்திவைப்பு வேளை விவாதம் நடைபெறவுள்ளது.",
        "தற்போதைய பொருளாதார நிலைமை தொடர்பில் அரசாங்க மற்றும் எதிர்க்கட்சி உறுப்பினர்களுக்கு அறிவிக்கும் விசேட நிகழ்ச்சியொன்று எதிர்வரும் 30ஆம் திகதி பிற்பகல் 2.00 மணி தொடக்கம் 4.00 மணி வரை மத்திய ஆளுநரினால் நடாத்தப்படும் என சபைத் தலைவர் அமைச்சர் (டாக்டர்) சுசில் பிரேமஜயந்த குழுவிடம் தெரிவித்தார். வங்கி கலாநிதி நந்தலால் வீரசிங்க. அரசாங்க மற்றும் எதிர்க்கட்சி உறுப்பினர்கள் அனைவரினதும் பங்கேற்பை எதிர்பார்ப்பதாகவும் சபைத் தலைவர் குறிப்பிட்டார்.",
        "இதேவேளை, நிலையியற் கட்டளைகளில் திருத்தம் செய்து, துறைசார் கண்காணிப்புக் குழுக்களை உடனடியாக நியமிக்கவுள்ளதாக சபைத் தலைவர் தெரிவித்தார். ஜனாதிபதியின் ஆலோசனையின் பிரகாரம் பாராளுமன்றக் குழு அமைப்பை வலுப்படுத்துவதற்காக மேலும் மூன்று நிலைக்குழுக்கள் நிறுவப்படும் என எதிர்பார்க்கப்படுவதாகவும் அவர் கூறினார்.",
        "அத்துடன், நாடாளுமன்ற விவாதங்களின் போது அரசாங்கக் கட்சியிலிருந்து விலகி சுயாதீனமாக செயற்படும் நாடாளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர்களுக்கு நியாயமான கால அவகாசம் வழங்கப்பட வேண்டும் என்பது தொடர்பிலும் கலந்துரையாடப்பட்டது.",
        "PTA கைதுகளில் தொடர்புடையது என குறிப்பிட்ட UN பாதுகாப்பு கவுன்சில் தீர்மானத்தை SL போலீஸ் மேற்கோள் காட்டுகிறது",
        "ஊடகவியலாளர்கள் மீதான தாக்குதல் தொடர்பில் ஜனாதிபதியின் பாதுகாப்புத் தலைவர் விசாரணை",
        "செயற்பாட்டாளர் சேனாதி குருகே கைது; எதிர் செயல்பாட்டாளரைப் பார்க்க தலைவர் அனுமதிக்கப்படவில்லை"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "இலங்கை",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "ஆகஸ்ட்",
          "label": "DATE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "News 1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "பொருளாதார ஸ்திரத்தன்மை மற்றும் தேசிய கொள்கைகள்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இரண்டாவது",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஒதுக்கீடு (திருத்தம்)",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆகஸ்ட் 30",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்ற விவகாரங்களுக்கான குழு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "அஜித் ராஜபக்ஷ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று காலை",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "24",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "வரும் வாரம்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஆகஸ்ட் 30",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "பிற்பகல் 1:00 மணி",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "இரண்டாவது",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஒதுக்கீடு (திருத்தம்) மசோதா",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இரண்டாவது",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஒதுக்கீடு (திருத்தம்) மசோதா",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆகஸ்ட் 31 மற்றும் செப்டம்பர் 1",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "காலை 9.30 முதல் மாலை 5.30 வரை",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "செப்டம்பர் 2 ஆம் தேதி",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "காலை 9.30 முதல் மாலை 4.30 வரை",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "இரண்டாவது",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஒதுக்கீடு (திருத்தம்) மசோதா",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ர சி து",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "மூன்றாவது",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "அந்நிய செலாவணி சட்டம்",
            "label": "LAW"
          },
          {
            "text": "சுங்க கட்டளை மற்றும் உத்தரவுகள்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "அதே நாள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "29 ஆம் தேதி",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "திங்கட்கிழமை",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "காலை 9.30 முதல் மாலை 4.30 வரை",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "பொது மக்கள்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "சுங்கவரி",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "விகிதம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "வீடு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "சுசில் பிரேமஜயந்த",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "30 ஆம் தேதி",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "மதியம் 2.00 மணி",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "மாலை 4.00 மணி",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "நந்தலால் வீரசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "வீடு",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "வீடு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "நிலையியற் கட்டளைகள்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "துறைசார் மேற்பார்வைக் குழுக்கள்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "மூன்று",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்ற குழு",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "SL போலீஸ்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஐநா பாதுகாப்பு கவுன்சில் தீர்மானம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "PTA",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "எதிர்",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}