{
  "newspaper_id": "daily-mirror-lk",
  "url": "https://www.dailymirror.lk/breaking_news/Legendary-Trotskyist-Wije-Dias-no-more/108-242041",
  "time_ut": 1659109434,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Legendary Trotskyist Wije Dias no more",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Legendary Trotskyist Wije Dias no more",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "Socialist Equality Party’s (SEP) Chairperson Wije Dias died of a severe heart attack on Wednesday at the age of 81 . Mr. Dias was a member of the International Editorial Board of the World Socialist Web Site WSWS.org, the global publication of the ICFI.",
        "SEP is the Sri Lankan section of the International Committee of the Fourth International (ICFI), the world party of the working class and of the international socialist revolution",
        "SEP is the successor to the Revolutionary Communist League (RCL), which was founded in 1968 by a group of youth including Dias and Keerthi Balasuriya, who was its founding General Secretary. Mr Dias was elected to be the General Secretary of the Party after the untimely and tragic death of Balasuriya in December 1987. He was elected to the newly formed post of party Chairperson in the Third National Congress of the SEP that was held last May.",
        "Referring to Mr Dias, ICFI’s Chairperson David North stated, \"Wije’s life encompasses virtually the entire history of the International Committee of the Fourth International\".",
        "Issuing a statement, SEP's General Secretary, Deepal Jayasekera, stated, “His loss is particularly felt amid this unprecedented economic, political and social crisis in Sri Lanka. However, his powerful political legacy lives on in the cadre of the SEP and political work of the ICFI which continue his lifelong struggle for a socialist future for humanity\".",
        "Dias' remains lie at ‘Jayaratne Respect Home’, Kanatta Road in Borella for last respects from 9 a.m. till Saturday, 30 July. Cortege leaves ‘Jayaratne Respect Home’ at 2:30 p.m. on Saturday 30 July for Borella Cemetery. ‘Funeral gathering’ will be at 3 p.m. and cremation is scheduled at 5 p.m"
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Socialist Equality Party’s",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "SEP",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Wednesday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the age of 81",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Dias",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the International Editorial Board of the World Socialist",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Site WSWS.org",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "SEP",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lankan",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "the International Committee of the Fourth International",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "SEP",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Revolutionary Communist League",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "RCL",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "1968",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Dias",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Keerthi Balasuriya",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Dias",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Party",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "December 1987",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Chairperson",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "SEP",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "last May",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "David North",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the International Committee of the Fourth International",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "SEP",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Deepal Jayasekera",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "SEP",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Borella",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "9 a.m.",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "Saturday, 30 July",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "2:30 p.m.",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "Saturday 30 July",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Borella Cemetery",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "3 p.m.",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "ජනප්‍රිය ට්‍රොට්ස්කිවාදී විජේ ඩයස් දැන් නැත",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "සමාජවාදී සමානතා පක්ෂයේ (සසප) සභාපති විජේ ඩයස් බදාදා වයස අවුරුදු 81 දී දරුණු හෘදයාබාධයකින් මිය ගියේය. ඩයස් මහතා ජාත්‍යන්තර කමිටුවේ ගෝලීය ප්‍රකාශනය වන ලෝක සමාජවාදී වෙබ් අඩවිය වන WSWS.org හි ජාත්‍යන්තර කර්තෘ මණ්ඩලයේ සාමාජිකයෙක් විය.",
        "සසප යනු කම්කරු පන්තියේ හා ජාත්‍යන්තර සමාජවාදී විප්ලවයේ ලෝක පක්ෂය වන හතරවන ජාත්‍යන්තරයේ ජාත්‍යන්තර කමිටුවේ (හජාජාක) ශ්‍රී ලංකා ශාඛාවයි.",
        "සසප, ඩයස් සහ එහි ආරම්භක ප්‍රධාන ලේකම් වූ කීර්ති බාලසූරිය ඇතුලු තරුනයින් කන්ඩායමක් විසින් 1968 දී ආරම්භ කරන ලද විප්ලවවාදී කොමියුනිස්ට් සංගමයේ (විකොස) අනුප්‍රාප්තිකයා වේ. 1987 දෙසැම්බරයේ බාලසූරියගේ අකල් හා ඛේදනීය මරණයෙන් පසු ඩයස් මහතා පක්ෂයේ ප්‍රධාන ලේකම්වරයා ලෙස තේරී පත් විය. ඔහු පසුගිය මැයි මාසයේ පැවති සසප තුන්වන ජාතික සම්මේලනයේ දී අලුතින් පිහිටුවන ලද පක්ෂ සභාපති තනතුරට තේරී පත් විය.",
        "ඩයස් මහතා ගැන සඳහන් කරමින්, ජාත්‍යන්තර කමිටුවේ සභාපති ඩේවිඩ් නෝර්ත් ප්‍රකාශ කළේ, \"විජේගේ ජීවිතය හතරවන ජාත්‍යන්තරයේ ජාත්‍යන්තර කමිටුවේ සමස්ත ඉතිහාසයම පාහේ ආවරණය කරයි\" යනුවෙනි.",
        "නිවේදනයක් නිකුත් කරමින් සසප ප්‍රධාන ලේකම් දීපාල් ජයසේකර කියා සිටියේ, “ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ මෙම පෙර නොවූ විරූ ආර්ථික, දේශපාලන හා සමාජ අර්බුදය මධ්‍යයේ ඔහුගේ පාඩුව විශේෂයෙන් දැනේ. කෙසේ වෙතත්, ඔහුගේ බලගතු දේශපාලන උරුමය සසපයේ කේඩරය සහ මානව වර්ගයා සඳහා සමාජවාදී අනාගතයක් සඳහා ඔහුගේ ජීවිත කාලය පුරාම අරගලය අඛන්ඩව ගෙන යන ජාත්‍යන්තර කමිටුවේ දේශපාලන වැඩ කොටස තුල පවතී.",
        "ඩයස්ගේ දේහය අවසන් ගෞරව දැක්වීම සඳහා බොරැල්ල කනත්ත පාරේ ‘ජයරත්න රෙස්පෙක්ට් හෝම්’ හි පෙරවරු 9 සිට ජූලි 30 සෙනසුරාදා දක්වා තැන්පත් කර ඇත. කෝටේජ් ‘ජයරත්න රෙස්පෙක්ට් හෝම්’ එකෙන් පිටත් වෙන්නේ ප.ව.2.30ට. ජුලි 30 සෙනසුරාදා බොරැල්ල කනත්තට. ‘අවමංගල්‍ය රැස්වීම’ ප.ව. සහ ආදාහනය පස්වරු 5 ට සිදු කිරීමට නියමිතය"
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "සමාජවාදී සමානතා පක්ෂය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "සසප",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "බදාදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "වයස අවුරුදු 81 යි",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඩයස්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ලෝක සමාජවාදී ජාත්‍යන්තර කර්තෘ මණ්ඩලය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "වෙබ් අඩවිය WSWS.org",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "සසප",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලාංකික",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "හතරවන ජාත්‍යන්තරයේ ජාත්‍යන්තර කමිටුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "සසප",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "විප්ලවවාදී කොමියුනිස්ට් සංගමය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "විකොස",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "1968",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඩයස්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "කීර්ති බාලසූරිය",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඩයස්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "පක්ෂය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "දෙසැම්බර් 1987",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "සභාපතිනිය",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "සසප",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "පසුගිය මැයි",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ඩේවිඩ් නෝර්ත්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "හතරවන ජාත්‍යන්තරයේ ජාත්‍යන්තර කමිටුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "සසප",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "දීපාල් ජයසේකර",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "සසප",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "බොරැල්ල",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "9 පෙ.ව.",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජූලි 30 සෙනසුරාදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "2:30 ප.ව.",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජූලි 30 සෙනසුරාදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "බොරැල්ල කනත්ත",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "3 ප.ව.",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "பழம்பெரும் ட்ரொட்ஸ்கிஸ்ட் விஜே டயஸ் இனி இல்லை",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "சோசலிச சமத்துவக் கட்சியின் (சோ.ச.க.) தலைவர் விஜே டயஸ் தனது 81வது வயதில் புதன்கிழமை கடுமையான மாரடைப்பால் காலமானார். நான்காம் அகிலத்தின் அனைத்துலகக் குழுவின் உலகளாவிய வெளியீடான WSWS.org என்ற உலக சோசலிச வலைத் தளத்தின் சர்வதேச ஆசிரியர் குழுவில் திரு. டயஸ் உறுப்பினராக இருந்தார்.",
        "சோசலிச சமத்துவக் கட்சி நான்காம் அகிலத்தின் அனைத்துலகக் குழுவின் (ICFI), தொழிலாள வர்க்கத்தின் மற்றும் சர்வதேச சோசலிசப் புரட்சியின் உலகக் கட்சியாகும்.",
        "1968 இல் டயஸ் மற்றும் அதன் ஸ்தாபக பொதுச் செயலாளராக இருந்த கீர்த்தி பாலசூரியா உள்ளிட்ட இளைஞர்கள் குழுவால் ஸ்தாபிக்கப்பட்ட புரட்சிக் கம்யூனிஸ்ட் கழகத்தின் (RCL) வாரிசு சோசலிச சமத்துவக் கட்சியாகும். 1987 டிசம்பரில் பாலசூரியவின் அகால மரணத்திற்குப் பிறகு, கட்சியின் பொதுச் செயலாளராக திரு டயஸ் தேர்ந்தெடுக்கப்பட்டார். கடந்த மே மாதம் நடைபெற்ற சோசலிச சமத்துவக் கட்சியின் மூன்றாவது தேசிய காங்கிரஸில் புதிதாக உருவாக்கப்பட்ட கட்சித் தலைவர் பதவிக்கு அவர் தேர்ந்தெடுக்கப்பட்டார்.",
        "திரு டயஸைக் குறிப்பிடுகையில், ICFI இன் தலைவர் டேவிட் நோர்த், \"விஜேயின் வாழ்க்கை கிட்டத்தட்ட நான்காம் அகிலத்தின் அனைத்துலகக் குழுவின் முழு வரலாற்றையும் உள்ளடக்கியது\" என்று கூறினார்.",
        "சோசலிச சமத்துவக் கட்சியின் பொதுச் செயலாளர் தீபால் ஜெயசேகர அறிக்கை ஒன்றை வெளியிட்டு, “இலங்கையில் ஏற்பட்டுள்ள இந்த முன்னோடியில்லாத பொருளாதார, அரசியல் மற்றும் சமூக நெருக்கடியின் மத்தியில் அவரது இழப்பு குறிப்பாக உணரப்படுகிறது. எவ்வாறாயினும், அவரது சக்திவாய்ந்த அரசியல் மரபு சோசலிச சமத்துவக் கட்சி மற்றும் நான்காம் அகிலத்தின் அனைத்துலகக் குழுவின் அரசியல் பணிகளில் வாழ்கிறது, இது மனிதகுலத்திற்கான சோசலிச எதிர்காலத்திற்கான அவரது வாழ்நாள் போராட்டத்தைத் தொடர்கிறது.",
        "டயஸின் பூதவுடல் பொரளை கனத்த வீதியில் உள்ள ‘ஜெயரத்ன மரியாதை இல்லத்தில்’ காலை 9 மணி முதல் ஜூலை 30 சனிக்கிழமை வரை இறுதி அஞ்சலிக்காக வைக்கப்பட்டுள்ளது. கோர்டேஜ் மதியம் 2:30 மணிக்கு ‘ஜெயரத்ன ரெஸ்பெக்ட் ஹோமில்’ இருந்து கிளம்புகிறார். பொரளை மயானத்திற்கு ஜூலை 30 சனிக்கிழமை. பிற்பகல் 3 மணிக்கு ‘இறுதிச் சடங்கு’ நடைபெறும். மற்றும் தகனம் மாலை 5 மணிக்கு நடைபெற உள்ளது"
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "சோசலிச சமத்துவக் கட்சி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "சோ.ச.க",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "புதன்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "வயது 81",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "டயஸ்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "உலக சோசலிஸ்ட்டின் சர்வதேச ஆசிரியர் குழு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "தளம் WSWS.org",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "சோ.ச.க",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "நான்காம் அகிலத்தின் அனைத்துலகக் குழு",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "சோ.ச.க",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "புரட்சிகர கம்யூனிஸ்ட் கழகம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "RCL",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "1968",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "டயஸ்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "கீர்த்தி பாலசூரியா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "டயஸ்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "பார்ட்டி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "டிசம்பர் 1987",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "தலைவர்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "சோ.ச.க",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "கடந்த மே",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "டேவிட் நோர்த்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "நான்காம் அகிலத்தின் அனைத்துலகக் குழு",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "சோ.ச.க",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "தீபால் ஜெயசேகர",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சோ.ச.க",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பொரளை",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "காலை 9 மணி",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "சனிக்கிழமை, 30 ஜூலை",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "மதியம் 2:30",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜூலை 30 சனிக்கிழமை",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "பொரளை மயானம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "மதியம் 3 மணி.",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}