{
  "newspaper_id": "virakesari-lk",
  "url": "http://www.virakesari.lk/article/130695",
  "time_ut": 1656860784,
  "original_lang": "ta",
  "original_title": "பிரதமர் ரணில் தலைமையிலான அரசாங்கத்தின் மீது அதிருப்தியில் பொதுஜன பெரமுனவினர் : சாகர காரியவசம்",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Dissatisfied with the government led by Prime Minister Ranil, Budujana Peramuna: Sagara Kariyavasam",
      "author": "Digital Desk 5",
      "body_lines": [
        "Most of the members of the Podujana Peramuna have expressed their dissatisfaction with the government led by Prime Minister Ranil Wickremesinghe. Political instability will exacerbate current crises.",
        "Sagara Kariyawasam, General Secretary of Podujana Peramuna stated that we will urge the President to establish a government led by Sri Lanka Podujana Peramuna.",
        "A meeting between President Gotabaya Rajapaksa and members of Podujana Peramuna will be held at the President's House today.",
        "The ruling party committee meeting between members of the Sri Lanka Podujana Peramuna and President Gotabaya Rajapaksa will be held at the President's House today.",
        "The government has failed to find a solution to the crises that have intensified in the social structure. While Prime Minister Ranil Wickremesinghe has mentioned that there are no alternative plans except to get the cooperation of the International Monetary Fund, it can be observed that the International Monetary Fund has imposed many conditions regarding the cooperation of Sri Lanka.",
        "If the conditions of the International Monetary Fund are implemented, the middle class will suffer more. The main shortcoming is that the parties who highlight only the positive factors of the IMF do not publicize the negative factors.",
        "We supported the government led by United National Party leader Ranil Wickremesinghe to solve the basic problems faced by the people of the country. There is doubt whether the current government - led by the Lanka Podujana Peramuna.",
        "The economy is affected by various factors. The Sri Lanka Podujana Peramuna-led government has a responsibility to protect the mandate given by the people.",
        "We urge the President to establish a Sri Lanka Podujana Peramuna-led government. He said that if the political mistakes are not corrected now, it will affect the future political existence."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Ranil",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "Budujana Peramuna",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "Sagara Kariyavasam",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "the Podujana Peramuna",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sagara Kariyawasam",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Podujana Peramuna",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Podujana Peramuna",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Gotabaya Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Podujana Peramuna",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "House",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Podujana Peramuna",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Gotabaya Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "House",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the International Monetary Fund",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the International Monetary Fund",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the International Monetary Fund",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "IMF",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "United National Party",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Podujana Peramuna",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Podujana Peramuna",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Podujana Peramuna",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "අගමැති රනිල් ප්‍රමුඛ ආණ්ඩුව ගැන සෑහීමකට පත් නොවන බව බුදුජන පෙරමුණ කියයි: සාගර කාරියවසම්",
      "author": "ඩිජිටල් මේසය 5",
      "body_lines": [
        "අග්‍රාමාත්‍ය රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතා ප්‍රමුඛ රජය සම්බන්ධයෙන් පොදුජන පෙරමුණේ බොහෝ මන්ත්‍රීවරුන් සිය අප්‍රසාදය පළ කර තිබේ. දේශපාලන අස්ථාවරත්වය වත්මන් අර්බුද උග්‍ර කරනු ඇත.",
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකා පොදුජන පෙරමුණ ප්‍රමුඛ ආණ්ඩුවක් පිහිටුවන ලෙස අපි ජනාධිපතිවරයාගෙන් ඉල්ලා සිටින බව පොදුජන පෙරමුණේ ප්‍රධාන ලේකම් සාගර කාරියවසම් ප්‍රකාශ කළා.",
        "ජනාධිපති ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ මහතා සහ පොදුජන පෙරමුණේ මන්ත්‍රීවරුන් අතර හමුවක් අද ජනාධිපති මන්දිරයේදී පැවැත්වීමට නියමිතයි.",
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකා පොදුජන පෙරමුණේ මන්ත්‍රීවරුන් සහ ජනාධිපති ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ මහතා අතර ආණ්ඩු පක්ෂ කාරක සභා රැස්වීම අද ජනාධිපති මන්දිරයේදී පැවැත්වීමට නියමිතයි.",
        "සමාජ ව්‍යූහයේ උග්‍ර වී ඇති අර්බුදවලට විසඳුම් සෙවීමට රජය අපොහොසත් වී ඇත.ජාත්‍යන්තර මූල්‍ය අරමුදලේ සහයෝගය ලබා ගැනීම හැර වෙනත් විකල්ප සැලසුම් නොමැති බව අග්‍රාමාත්‍ය රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ සඳහන් කරද්දී ජාත්‍යන්තර ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ සහයෝගිතාව සම්බන්ධයෙන් මුල්‍ය අරමුදල කොන්දේසි රැසක් පනවා ඇත.",
        "ජාත්‍යන්තර මුල්‍ය අරමුදලේ කොන්දේසි ක්‍රියාත්මක කළහොත් තවත් පීඩාවට පත්වන්නේ මධ්‍යම පන්තියයි.ප‍්‍රධානම අඩුව වන්නේ මූල්‍ය අරමුදලේ සාධනීය කරුණු පමණක් ඉස්මතු කරන පාර්ශ්වයන් අයහපත් සාධක ප‍්‍රසිද්ධ නොකිරීමයි.",
        "එක්සත් ජාතික පක්ෂ නායක රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතා ප්‍රමුඛ ආණ්ඩුවට අපි සහයෝගය ලබා දුන්නේ රටේ ජනතාව මුහුණ දෙන මූලික ප්‍රශ්න විසඳීමට. ලංකා පොදුජන පෙරමුණ ප්‍රමුඛ වත්මන් ආණ්ඩුව දැයි සැකයක් පවතී.",
        "ආර්ථිකයට විවිධ සාධක බලපානවා. ජනතාව ලබාදුන් ජනවරම ආරක්ෂා කිරීමේ වගකීම ශ්‍රී ලංකා පොදුජන පෙරමුණ ප්‍රමුඛ රජයට තිබෙනවා.",
        "අපි ජනාධිපතිතුමාගෙන් ඉල්ලා සිටින්නේ ශ්‍රී ලංකා පොදුජන පෙරමුණ ප්‍රමුඛ රජයක් පිහිටුවන ලෙසයි. දේශපාලන වැරදි දැන්වත් නිවැරදි කර නොගතහොත් එය ඉදිරි දේශපාලන පැවැත්මට බලපානු ඇති බවද ඔහු පැවසීය."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "රනිල්",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "බුදුජන පෙරමුණ",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "සාගර කාරියවසම්",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "පොදුජන පෙරමුණ",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "සාගර කාරියවසම්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "පොදුජන පෙරමුණ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "පොදුජන පෙරමුණ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "පොදුජන පෙරමුණ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "නිවස",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "පොදුජන පෙරමුණ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "නිවස",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජාත්‍යන්තර මුල්‍ය අරමුදල",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජාත්‍යන්තර මුල්‍ය අරමුදල",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ජාත්‍යන්තර මුල්‍ය අරමුදල",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "IMF",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "එක්සත් ජාතික පක්ෂය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "පොදුජන පෙරමුණ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "පොදුජන පෙරමුණ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "පොදුජන පෙරමුණ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "பிரதமர் ரணில் தலைமையிலான அரசாங்கத்தின் மீது அதிருப்தியில் பொதுஜன பெரமுனவினர் : சாகர காரியவசம்",
      "author": "Digital Desk 5",
      "body_lines": [
        "பிரதமர் ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க தலைமையிலான அரசாங்கத்தின் மீது பொதுஜன பெரமுனவின் பெரும்பாலான உறுப்பினர்கள் அதிருப்தி தெரிவித்துள்ளார்கள். அரசியல் ஸ்தீரமற்ற தன்மை தற்போதைய நெருக்கடிகளை மேலும் தீவிரப்படுத்தும்.",
        "ஸ்ரீ லங்கா பொதுஜன பெரமுன தலைமையிலான அரசாங்கத்தை ஸ்தாபிக்குமாறு ஜனாதிபதியிடம் வலியுறுத்தவுள்ளோம் என பொதுஜன பெரமுனவின் பொதுச்செயலாளர் சாகர காரியவசம் குறிப்பிட்டார்.",
        "ஜனாதிபதி கோட்டபய ராஜபக்ஷவிற்கும்,பொதுஜன பெரமுனவின் உறுப்பினர்களுக்குமிடையிலான சந்திப்பு இன்று ஜனாதிபதி மாளிகையில் இடம்பெறவுள்ளது.",
        "ஸ்ரீ லங்கா பொதுஜன பெரமுனவின் உறுப்பினர்களுக்கும்,ஜனாதிபதி கோட்டபய ராஜபக்ஷவிற்கும் இடையிலான ஆளும் தரப்பு குழு கூட்டம் இன்று ஜனாதிபதி மாளிகையில் இடம்பெறவுள்ளது.",
        "சமூக கட்டமைப்பில் தீவிரமடைந்துள்ள நெருக்கடிகளுக்கு தீர்வு காண்பதில் அரசாங்கம் தோல்வியடைந்துள்ளது.சர்வதேச நாணய நிதியத்தின் ஒத்துழைப்பை பெற்றுக்கொள்வதை தவிர்து மாற்று திட்டங்கள் ஏதும் கிடையாது என பிரதமர் ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க குறிப்பிட்டுள்ள நிலையில் இலங்கைக்கு ஒத்துழைப்பு வழங்குவது தொடர்பில் சர்வதேச நாணய நிதியம் பல நிபந்தனைகளை விதித்துள்ளதை அவதானிக்க முடிகிறது.",
        "சர்வதேச நாணய நிதியத்தின் நிபந்தனைகளை செயற்படுத்தினால் நடுத்தர மக்கள் மேலும் பாதிக்கப்படுவார்கள்.நாணய நிதியத்தின் சாதக காரணிகளை மாத்திரம் முன்னிலைப்படுத்தும் தரப்பினர் பாதக காரணிகளை பகிரங்கப்படுத்தாமல் இருப்பது பிரதான குறைப்பாடாக காணப்படுகிறது.",
        "நாட்டு மக்கள் எதிர்க்கொண்டுள்ள அடிப்படை பிரச்சினைகளுக்கு தீர்வு காண வேண்டும் என்பதற்காகவே ஐக்கிய தேசிய கட்சி தலைவர் ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க தலைமையிலான அரசாங்கத்திற்கு ஆதரவு வழங்கினோம். தற்போதைய அரசாங்கம் - லங்கா பொதுஜன பெரமுன தலைமையிலானதா என்ற சந்தேகம் காணப்படுகிறது.",
        "பல்வேறு காரணிகளினால் பொருளாதாரம் பாதிக்கப்பட்டுள்ளது. ஸ்ரீ லங்கா பொதுஜன பெரமுன தலைமையிலான  அரசாங்கத்திற்கு நாட்டு மக்கள் வழங்கிய ஆணையை பாதுகாக்க வேண்டிய பொறுபபு காணப்படுகிறது.தவறுகள் இடம்பெற்ற இடத்தில் இருந்து தான் அதற்கு தீர்வு காண வேண்டும்.",
        "ஸ்ரீ லங்கா பொதுஜன பெரமுன தலைமையிலான அரசாங்கத்தை ஸ்தாபிக்க வேண்டும் என்பதை ஜனாதிபதியிடம் வலியுறுத்தவுள்ளோம். அரசியல் ரீதியிலான தவறுகள் தற்போது திருத்திக்கொள்ளாவிடின் அது எதிர்கால அரசியல் இருப்பிற்கு பாதிப்பை ஏற்படுத்தும் என்றார்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ரணில்",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "புதுஜன பெரமுன",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "சாகர காரியவசம்",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "பொதுஜன பெரமுனா",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "சாகர காரியவசம்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "பொதுஜன பெரமுன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "பொதுஜன பெரமுன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "பொதுஜன பெரமுன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "வீடு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பொதுஜன பெரமுன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "வீடு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "சர்வதேச நாணய நிதியம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "சர்வதேச நாணய நிதியம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "சர்வதேச நாணய நிதியம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "IMF",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஐக்கிய தேசிய கட்சி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "பொதுஜன பெரமுன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பொதுஜன பெரமுன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பொதுஜன பெரமுன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}