{
  "newspaper_id": "ada-lk",
  "url": "https://www.ada.lk/breaking_news/ලංකාවේ-අර්බුදය-විසඳන්න-අනෙකුත්-ණය-හිමියන්-සමග-සම්බන්ධීකරණය-කරනවා---ජපානය/11-396723",
  "time_ut": 1661844943,
  "original_lang": "si",
  "original_title": "ලංකාවේ අර්බුදය විසඳන්න අනෙකුත් ණය හිමියන් සමග සම්බන්ධීකරණය කරනවා - ජපානය",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Coordinating with other creditors to resolve Sri Lanka's crisis - Japan",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "TOKYO, Aug 30 (Reuters) - Japan will coordinate with other creditors to resolve Sri Lanka's financial crisis and urge all creditor nations to discuss Sri Lanka's debt from the same table, Japanese Finance Minister Shunichi Suzuki said on Tuesday.",
        "\"We are concerned about the dire socio-economic situation in Sri Lanka,\" Mr Suziki told reporters.",
        "He said that talks with the International Monetary Fund (IMF) should be expedited to implement a debt relief package for Sri Lanka and all bilateral creditors including China and India should meet to discuss the issue.",
        "\"Japan wants to actively cooperate with other lending countries and public organizations.\" He said."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Sri Lanka's",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "Japan",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "TOKYO",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "30",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Reuters",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Japan",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka's",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka's",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Japanese",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Shunichi Suzuki",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Tuesday",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Suziki",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the International Monetary Fund",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "China",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "India",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Japan",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "ලංකාවේ අර්බුදය විසඳන්න අනෙකුත් ණය හිමියන් සමග සම්බන්ධීකරණය කරනවා - ජපානය",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "ටෝකියෝ, අගෝස්තු 30 (රොයිටර්) - ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ මූල්‍ය අර්බුදය විසඳීම සඳහා ජපානය අනෙකුත් ණය හිමියන් සමඟ සම්බන්ධීකරණය කරන බවත් ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ ණය සම්බන්ධයෙන් එකම මේසයක සිට සාකච්ඡා කරන ලෙස සියලුම ණය දෙන ජාතීන්ගෙන් ඉල්ලා සිටින බවත් ජපාන  මුදල් අමාත්‍ය ෂුනිචි සුසුකි මහතා අඟහරුවාදා ප්‍රකාශ කළේය.",
        "\"ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ දරුණු සමාජ-ආර්ථික තත්ත්වය පිළිබඳව අපි කනස්සල්ලට පත්ව සිටිමු,\" සුසිකි මහතා වාර්තාකරුවන්ට පැවසීය.",
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවට ණය සහන පැකේජයක් ක්‍රියාත්මක කිරීමට ජාත්‍යන්තර මූල්‍ය අරමුදල (IMF) සමඟ සාකච්ඡා කඩිනම් කළ යුතු බවත් චීනය සහ ඉන්දියාව ඇතුළු සියලුම ද්විපාර්ශ්වික ණයහිමියන් ගැටලුව සාකච්ඡා කිරීමට රැස්විය යුතු බවත් ඔහු පැවැසීය.",
        "\"ජපානයට අනෙකුත් ණය දෙන රටවල් සහ පොදු සංවිධාන සමඟ ක්‍රියාකාරීව සහයෝගයෙන් කටයුතු කිරීමට අවශ්‍යයි.\" යැයි ඔහු පැවැසීය."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "ජපානය",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ටෝකියෝ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "30",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "රොයිටර්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජපානය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජපන්",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Shunichi Suzuki",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "අඟහරුවාදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "සුසිකි",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ජාත්‍යන්තර මුල්‍ය අරමුදල",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "චීනය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ජපානය",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "இலங்கையின் நெருக்கடியைத் தீர்க்க மற்ற கடன் வழங்குநர்களுடன் ஒருங்கிணைத்தல் - ஜப்பான்",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "டோக்கியோ, ஆகஸ்ட் 30 (ராய்ட்டர்ஸ்) - இலங்கையின் நிதி நெருக்கடியைத் தீர்க்க ஜப்பான் மற்ற கடன் வழங்குநர்களுடன் ஒருங்கிணைந்து, இலங்கையின் கடன் குறித்து ஒரே மேசையில் இருந்து விவாதிக்க அனைத்து கடன் வழங்கும் நாடுகளையும் வலியுறுத்தும் என்று ஜப்பான் நிதி அமைச்சர் ஷுனிச்சி சுசுகி செவ்வாய்க்கிழமை தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "\"இலங்கையின் மோசமான சமூக-பொருளாதார நிலைமை குறித்து நாங்கள் கவலை கொண்டுள்ளோம்\" என்று திரு சுசிகி செய்தியாளர்களிடம் கூறினார்.",
        "இலங்கைக்கான கடன் நிவாரணப் பொதியை அமுல்படுத்த சர்வதேச நாணய நிதியத்துடன் (IMF) பேச்சுவார்த்தைகளை துரிதப்படுத்த வேண்டும் என்றும், சீனா மற்றும் இந்தியா உட்பட அனைத்து இருதரப்பு கடன் வழங்குநர்களும் கூடி இது குறித்து விவாதிக்க வேண்டும் என்றும் அவர் கூறினார்.",
        "\"ஜப்பான் மற்ற கடன் வழங்கும் நாடுகள் மற்றும் பொது அமைப்புகளுடன் தீவிரமாக ஒத்துழைக்க விரும்புகிறது.\" அவன் சொன்னான்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "இலங்கையின்",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "ஜப்பான்",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "டோக்கியோ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "30",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ராய்ட்டர்ஸ்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜப்பான்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கையின்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கையின்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜப்பானியர்",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Shunichi Suzuki",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "செவ்வாய்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சுசிகி",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "சர்வதேச நாணய நிதியம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சீனா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்தியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஜப்பான்",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}