{
  "newspaper_id": "d-b-s-jeyaraj-com",
  "url": "https://dbsjeyaraj.com/dbsj/archives/78879",
  "time_ut": 1659727440,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Sri Lanka Rescinds Permission Given for Chinese Vessel “Yuan Wang 5” to dock at Hambantota for Replenishment: “The Ministry requests that the arrival date of the vessel Yuan Wang 5 in Hambantota be deferred until further consultations are made on this matter,”  says  Lankan  Foreign Ministry note;Chinese Envoy Protests to President Wickremesinghe",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Sri Lanka Rescinds Permission Given for Chinese Vessel “Yuan Wang 5” to dock at Hambantota for Replenishment: “The Ministry requests that the arrival date of the vessel Yuan Wang 5 in Hambantota be deferred until further consultations are made on this matter,”  says  Lankan  Foreign Ministry note;Chinese Envoy Protests to President Wickremesinghe",
      "author": "Administrator",
      "body_lines": [
        "The Government on Thursday (4) decided to rescind the permission granted to the Yuan Wang 5 Chinese research vessel with the relevant official communication to the Chinese Embassy in Colombo being delivered on Friday (5), The Sunday Morning learns.",
        "The Yuan Wang 5’s visit to Sri Lanka that was earlier scheduled for Thursday (11) caused much controversy, with India posting strong concerns and protests over permission being granted for the Chinese vessel to dock in Sri Lanka as the vessel has satellite and missile tracking capabilities.",
        "The Sri Lankan Government made several efforts, including several unofficial discussions being held between the President and the Indian and Chinese envoys in Sri Lanka, to resolve the diplomatic row over the Chinese vessel.",
        "The President has also requested Foreign Minister Ali Sabry to discuss the issue over the Chinese vessel with his Indian and Chinese counterparts on the sidelines of the ASEAN summit in Cambodia. However, despite efforts by the Foreign Minister, the issue was not resolved, with the Chinese leaders not agreeing to consider a change of route for the vessel.",
        "Highly-placed Government sources told The Sunday Morning that during Ali Sabry’s meeting with Chinese Foreign Minister Wang Yi, efforts had been made to explain the crisis faced by the country and the exceptional situation Sri Lanka was in at present and to request the Chinese to help Sri Lanka by changing the Yuan Wang 5’s route to avoid docking in the country at present.",
        "However, the Chinese official had not agreed, saying that permission had been sought from the Sri Lankan Government and that it had been granted for the vessel to dock in Sri Lanka for replenishment.",
        "When Sabry communicated the outcome of the meeting to President Wickremesinghe, it had been decided that the Government had no option but to rescind the permission granted for the Yuan Wang 5 to dock in Hambantota.",
        "“The Ministry requests that the arrival date of the vessel Yuan Wang 5 in Hambantota be deferred until further consultations are made on this matter,” the Foreign Ministry has noted in its note sent to the Chinese Embassy in Colombo last Friday.",
        "“The Ministry of Foreign Affairs of the Democratic Socialist Republic of Sri Lanka avails itself of this opportunity to renew to the Embassy of the People’s Republic of China in Colombo the assurances of its highest consideration,” the note added.",
        "Chinese Ambassador to Colombo Qi Zhenhong requested to meet the President soon after receiving the note on Friday and was granted an appointment last afternoon (6). It is learnt that the Chinese Envoy has expressed China’s concern and displeasure at the Sri Lankan Government’s decision to rescind permission to the Chinese vessel.",
        "It is learnt that the Sri Lankan Government in 2021 and early 2022 had granted permission for several Chinese vessels for replenishment in Sri Lankan ports. Among them are Shi Yan 1 (15 April 2021 to Colombo), Shi Yan 3 (15 May 2021 to Colombo), Hai Ce 3301 (8 December 2021 and 5 January 2022 to Colombo) and Shi Yan 6 (20 April 2022 to Colombo).",
        "All these vessels had sought permission from the Foreign Ministry for docking and replenishments. Another vessel – Xiang Yang Hong 3 – that was due to dock in Colombo on 7 July 2022 for ‘research’ purposes had been cancelled.",
        "It is in this same manner that Yuan Wang 5 had sought permission to dock at the Hambantota Port on 11 August for replenishment."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Sri Lanka",
          "label": "LOC"
        },
        {
          "text": "Chinese",
          "label": "NORP"
        },
        {
          "text": "Yuan Wang",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "Yuan Wang",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "Lankan  Foreign Ministry",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "Wickremesinghe",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Thursday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "4",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Chinese",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Chinese Embassy in Colombo",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Friday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "5",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sunday",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Thursday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "11",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "India",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Chinese",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "The Sri Lankan Government",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Indian",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Chinese",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Chinese",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Ali Sabry",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Chinese",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Indian",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Chinese",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ASEAN",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Cambodia",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Chinese",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "The Sunday Morning",
            "label": "WORK_OF_ART"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ali Sabry",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Chinese",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Wang Yi",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Chinese",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Chinese",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Sri Lankan Government",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sabry",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Hambantota",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Yuan Wang",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Foreign Ministry",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Chinese Embassy in Colombo",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "last Friday",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "The Ministry of Foreign Affairs",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Democratic Socialist Republic of Sri Lanka",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Embassy of the People’s Republic of China",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Colombo",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Chinese",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Colombo Qi Zhenhong",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Friday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "6",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Chinese",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "China",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Sri Lankan Government’s",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Chinese",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the Sri Lankan Government",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "2021",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "early 2022",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Chinese",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lankan",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Shi Yan",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "15 April 2021",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Shi Yan",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "3",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "15 May 2021",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Hai Ce 3301",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "8 December 2021",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "5 January 2022",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Colombo",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Shi Yan",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "20 April 2022",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the Foreign Ministry",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Xiang Yang",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Colombo",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "7 July 2022",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Yuan Wang 5",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Hambantota Port",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "11 August",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "චීන නෞකාවක් වන “යුවාන් වැන්ග් 5” නැවත පිරවීම සඳහා හම්බන්තොට නැංගුරම් ලෑමට ශ්‍රී ලංකාව ලබාදී තිබූ අවසරය ශ්‍රී ලංකාව ඉවත් කරයි: “යුවාන් වැන්ග් 5 යාත්‍රාව හම්බන්තොටට පැමිණීමේ දිනය කල් දමන ලෙස අමාත්‍යාංශය ඉල්ලා සිටියි. විදේශ අමාත්‍යාංශයේ සටහන; චීන නියෝජිත ජනාධිපති වික්‍රමසිංහට විරෝධය පළ කරයි",
      "author": "පරිපාලක",
      "body_lines": [
        "යුවාන් වැන්ග් 5 චීන පර්යේෂණ යාත්‍රාවට ලබාදී තිබූ අවසරය අවලංගු කිරීමට රජය බ්‍රහස්පතින්දා (4) තීරණය කළ අතර අදාළ නිල සන්නිවේදනය කොළඹ චීන තානාපති කාර්යාලය වෙත සිකුරාදා (5) ලබා දීමට නියමිත බව The Sunday Morning වාර්තා කරයි.",
        "මීට පෙර බ්‍රහස්පතින්දා (11) දිනට නියමිතව තිබූ යුවාන් වැන්ග් 5 ශ්‍රී ලංකා සංචාරය බොහෝ ආන්දෝලනයට තුඩු දුන් අතර, යාත්‍රාවට චන්ද්‍රිකා සහ මිසයිල ලුහුබැඳීමේ හැකියාව ඇති බැවින් චීන යාත්‍රාවට ශ්‍රී ලංකාවට පැමිණීමට අවසර දීම සම්බන්ධයෙන් ඉන්දියාව දැඩි කනස්සල්ලක් සහ විරෝධතාවක් පළ කළේය. .",
        "චීන යාත්‍රාව සම්බන්ධයෙන් ඇති වූ රාජ්‍ය තාන්ත්‍රික ගැටුම සමථයකට පත් කිරීම සඳහා ශ්‍රී ලංකා රජය සහ ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ ඉන්දීය සහ චීන තානාපතිවරුන් අතර නිල නොවන සාකච්ඡා කිහිපයක් පැවැත්වීම ඇතුළුව ශ්‍රී ලංකා රජය උත්සාහයන් කිහිපයක්ම ගනු ලැබීය.",
        "කාම්බෝජයේ පැවැත්වෙන ආසියාන් සමුළුවට සමගාමීව චීන යාත්‍රාව සම්බන්ධයෙන් මතුව ඇති ගැටලුව සම්බන්ධයෙන් ඉන්දීය සහ චීන සගයන් සමඟ සාකච්ඡා කරන ලෙස ද ජනාධිපතිවරයා විදේශ අමාත්‍ය අලි සබ්රිගෙන් ඉල්ලීමක් කර තිබෙනවා. කෙසේ වෙතත්, විදේශ අමාත්‍යවරයාගේ උත්සාහය නොතකා, ගැටළුව විසඳී නොතිබූ අතර, යාත්‍රාවේ ගමන් මාර්ගය වෙනස් කිරීම ගැන සලකා බැලීමට චීන නායකයින් එකඟ නොවීය.",
        "Ali Sabry විසින් චීන විදේශ අමාත්‍ය Wang Yi සමඟ පැවති සාකච්ඡාවේදී රට මුහුණ දී ඇති අර්බුදය සහ ශ්‍රී ලංකාව දැනට පවතින සුවිශේෂී තත්ත්වය පැහැදිලි කිරීමටත්, උදව් කරන ලෙස චීනයෙන් ඉල්ලා සිටීමටත් උත්සාහ ගත් බව ඉහළ පෙළේ රජයේ ආරංචි මාර්ග ඉරිදා උදෑසන ප්‍රකාශ කළේය. ශ්‍රී ලංකාව යුවාන් වැන්ග් 5 හි මාර්ගය වෙනස් කරමින් දැනට රට තුළ නැව්ගත වීම වැළැක්වීමට.",
        "කෙසේ වෙතත්, චීන නිලධාරියා එකඟ වී නොමැති අතර, ශ්‍රී ලංකා රජයෙන් අවසර ඉල්ලා ඇති බවත්, යාත්‍රාව නැවත පිරවීම සඳහා ශ්‍රී ලංකාවට නැව්ගත කිරීම සඳහා එය ලබා දී ඇති බවත් පවසමින්.",
        "සබ්රි විසින් රැස්වීමේ ප්‍රතිඵලය ජනාධිපති වික්‍රමසිංහට දැනුම් දුන් විට, යුවාන් වැන්ග් 5 හම්බන්තොට නැව් තටාකාංගනය සඳහා ලබා දී ඇති අවසරය අවලංගු කිරීම හැර රජයට වෙනත් විකල්පයක් නොමැති බව තීරණය කර තිබුණි.",
        "\"යුවාන් වැන්ග් 5 යාත්‍රාව හම්බන්තොටට පැමිණෙන දිනය කල් දමන ලෙස අමාත්‍යාංශය ඉල්ලා සිටිනවා\" යනුවෙන් විදේශ අමාත්‍යාංශය පසුගිය සිකුරාදා කොළඹ චීන තානාපති කාර්යාලය වෙත යවා ඇති සටහනේ සඳහන් කර ඇත.",
        "\"ශ්‍රී ලංකා ප්‍රජාතාන්ත්‍රික සමාජවාදී ජනරජයේ විදේශ කටයුතු අමාත්‍යාංශය කොළඹ පිහිටි මහජන චීන සමූහාණ්ඩුවේ තානාපති කාර්යාලයට එහි ඉහළම සැලකිල්ල පිළිබඳ සහතිකය අලුත් කිරීමේ මෙම අවස්ථාවෙන් ප්‍රයෝජන ගනියි\" යනුවෙන් එම සටහන වැඩිදුරටත් සඳහන් කරයි.",
        "කොළඹ චීන තානාපති Qi Zhenhong සිකුරාදා සටහන ලැබුණු පසු ඉක්මනින්ම ජනාධිපතිවරයා හමුවන ලෙස ඉල්ලා සිටි අතර ඊයේ (6) පස්වරුවේ වේලාවක් ප්‍රදානය කරන ලදී. චීන යාත්‍රාවට අවසර දීම අවලංගු කිරීමට ශ්‍රී ලංකා රජය ගත් තීරණය සම්බන්ධයෙන් චීන නියෝජිතයා චීනයේ කනස්සල්ල සහ අප්‍රසාදය පළ කර ඇති බව දැනගන්නට ඇත.",
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකා රජය 2021 සහ 2022 මුල් භාගයේදී ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ වරායන්හි නැවත පිරවීම සඳහා චීන යාත්‍රා කිහිපයකට අවසර ලබා දී ඇති බව දැනගන්නට ඇත. ඒවා අතර Shi Yan 1 (2021 අප්‍රේල් 15 කොළඹට), Shi Yan 3 (2021 මැයි 15 කොළඹට), Hai Ce 3301 (2021 දෙසැම්බර් 8 සහ 2022 ජනවාරි 5 කොළඹට) සහ Shi Yan 6 (2022 අප්‍රේල් 20 කොළඹට) .",
        "මෙම යාත්‍රා සියල්ල නැව්ගත කිරීම සහ නැවත පිරවීම සඳහා විදේශ අමාත්‍යාංශයෙන් අවසර ඉල්ලා තිබුණි. 2022 ජූලි 7 වැනි දින ‘පර්යේෂණ’ අරමුණු සඳහා කොළඹට නැංගීමට නියමිතව තිබූ තවත් යාත්‍රාවක් - Xiang Yang Hong 3 - අවලංගු කර ඇත.",
        "යුවාන් වැන්ග් 5 නෞකාව නැවත පිරවීම සඳහා අගෝස්තු 11 වැනිදා හම්බන්තොට වරායට නැංගුරම් ලෑමට අවසර ඉල්ලා ඇත්තේද මේ ආකාරයටය."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
          "label": "LOC"
        },
        {
          "text": "චීන",
          "label": "NORP"
        },
        {
          "text": "Yuan Wang",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "Yuan Wang",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "ලංකා විදේශ අමාත්‍යාංශය",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "වික්‍රමසිංහ",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "බ්රහස්පතින්දා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "4",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "චීන",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "කොළඹ චීන තානාපති කාර්යාලය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "සිකුරාදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "5",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉරිදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "බ්රහස්පතින්දා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "11",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "චීන",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකා රජය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දීය",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "චීන",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "චීන",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "අලි සබ්රි",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "චීන",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දීය",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "චීන",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ආසියාන්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "කාම්බෝජය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "චීන",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ඉරිදා උදෑසන",
            "label": "WORK_OF_ART"
          },
          {
            "text": "අලි සබ්රි",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "චීන",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Wang Yi",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "චීන",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "චීන",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකා රජය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "සබ්රි",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "හම්බන්තොට",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Yuan Wang",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "විදේශ අමාත්‍යාංශය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "කොළඹ චීන තානාපති කාර්යාලය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "පසුගිය සිකුරාදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "විදේශ කටයුතු අමාත්‍යාංශය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකා ප්‍රජාතාන්ත්‍රික සමාජවාදී ජනරජය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "මහජන චීන සමූහාණ්ඩුවේ තානාපති කාර්යාලය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "කොළඹ",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "චීන",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Colombo Qi Zhenhong",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "සිකුරාදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "6",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "චීන",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "චීනය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකා රජයේ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "චීන",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකා රජය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "2021",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "2022 මුල",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "චීන",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලාංකික",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Shi Yan",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "2021 අප්‍රේල් 15",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Shi Yan",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "3",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "2021 මැයි 15",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Hai Ce 3301",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "8 දෙසැම්බර් 2021",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "2022 ජනවාරි 5",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "කොළඹ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Shi Yan",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "20 අප්‍රේල් 2022",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "විදේශ අමාත්‍යාංශය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Xiang Yang",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "කොළඹ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "2022 ජූලි 7",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Yuan Wang 5",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "හම්බන්තොට වරාය",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "අගෝස්තු 11",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "“யுவான் வாங் 5” என்ற சீனக் கப்பலுக்கு அம்பாந்தோட்டையில் தரித்து நிற்கும் அனுமதியை இலங்கை ரத்து செய்தது: “யுவான் வாங் 5 கப்பல் ஹம்பாந்தோட்டைக்கு வரும் தேதியை ஒத்திவைக்குமாறு அமைச்சகம் கேட்டுக்கொள்கிறது, இது குறித்து மேலும் ஆலோசனை நடத்தப்படும் வரை,” என்று இலங்கை தெரிவித்துள்ளது. வெளிவிவகார அமைச்சின் குறிப்பு; ஜனாதிபதி விக்கிரமசிங்கவுக்கு சீனத் தூதுவர் எதிர்ப்பு",
      "author": "நிர்வாகி",
      "body_lines": [
        "யுவான் வாங் 5 சீன ஆராய்ச்சிக் கப்பலுக்கு வழங்கப்பட்ட அனுமதியை இரத்து செய்ய அரசாங்கம் வியாழன் (4) தீர்மானித்ததுடன் அது தொடர்பான உத்தியோகபூர்வ தகவல்தொடர்பு கொழும்பில் உள்ள சீனத் தூதரகத்திற்கு வெள்ளிக்கிழமை (5) வழங்கப்படும் என தி சண்டே மார்னிங் அறியுகிறது.",
        "முன்னதாக வியாழக்கிழமை (11) திட்டமிடப்பட்ட யுவான் வாங் 5 இன் இலங்கை விஜயம் பெரும் சர்ச்சையை ஏற்படுத்தியது, இந்த கப்பல் செயற்கைக்கோள் மற்றும் ஏவுகணை கண்காணிப்பு திறன்களைக் கொண்டிருப்பதால் சீனக் கப்பலுக்கு இலங்கையில் தரித்து நிற்க அனுமதி வழங்கப்பட்டதற்கு இந்தியா கடும் கவலைகளையும் எதிர்ப்புகளையும் வெளியிட்டது. .",
        "சீனக் கப்பல் தொடர்பான இராஜதந்திர முரண்பாட்டைத் தீர்ப்பதற்கு ஜனாதிபதிக்கும் இலங்கையில் உள்ள இந்திய மற்றும் சீனத் தூதுவர்களுக்கும் இடையில் நடத்தப்பட்ட பல உத்தியோகபூர்வமற்ற கலந்துரையாடல்கள் உட்பட இலங்கை அரசாங்கம் பல முயற்சிகளை மேற்கொண்டது.",
        "கம்போடியாவில் நடைபெறவுள்ள ஆசியான் மாநாட்டையொட்டி, சீனக் கப்பல் தொடர்பான விவகாரம் குறித்து தனது இந்திய மற்றும் சீன சகாக்களுடன் கலந்துரையாடுமாறும் ஜனாதிபதி, வெளிவிவகார அமைச்சர் அலி சப்ரியிடம் கோரிக்கை விடுத்துள்ளார். எவ்வாறாயினும், வெளியுறவு அமைச்சரின் முயற்சிகள் இருந்தபோதிலும், பிரச்சினை தீர்க்கப்படவில்லை, கப்பலுக்கான பாதையை மாற்றுவது குறித்து பரிசீலிக்க சீன தலைவர்கள் உடன்படவில்லை.",
        "சீன வெளிவிவகார அமைச்சர் வாங் யீ உடனான அலி சப்ரியின் சந்திப்பின் போது, ​​நாடு எதிர்கொண்டுள்ள நெருக்கடி மற்றும் இலங்கையின் தற்போதைய அசாதாரண சூழ்நிலையை விளக்கி, சீனாவின் உதவியைக் கோருவதற்கு முயற்சிகள் மேற்கொள்ளப்பட்டதாக உயர்மட்ட அரசாங்க வட்டாரங்கள் தி சன்டே மோர்னிங் தெரிவித்தன. யுவான் வாங் 5 இன் வழித்தடத்தை மாற்றுவதன் மூலம் இலங்கை தற்போது நாட்டில் கப்பல்துறையை நிறுத்துகிறது.",
        "எவ்வாறாயினும், சீன அதிகாரி ஒப்புக் கொள்ளவில்லை, இலங்கை அரசாங்கத்திடம் அனுமதி கோரப்பட்டுள்ளதாகவும், கப்பல் மீண்டும் நிரப்புவதற்காக இலங்கையில் கப்பல்துறைக்கு அனுப்பப்பட்டது என்றும் கூறினார்.",
        "கூட்டத்தின் முடிவுகளை ஜனாதிபதி விக்கிரமசிங்கவிடம் சப்ரி தெரிவித்தபோது, ​​யுவான் வாங் 5 ஹம்பாந்தோட்டையில் கப்பல் நிறுத்துவதற்கு வழங்கப்பட்ட அனுமதியை இரத்து செய்வதைத் தவிர அரசாங்கத்திற்கு வேறு வழியில்லை என்று தீர்மானிக்கப்பட்டது.",
        "“யுவான் வாங் 5 கப்பல் ஹம்பாந்தோட்டைக்கு வரும் தேதியை ஒத்திவைக்குமாறு அமைச்சகம் கேட்டுக்கொள்கிறது” என்று வெளியுறவு அமைச்சகம் கடந்த வெள்ளிக்கிழமை கொழும்பில் உள்ள சீன தூதரகத்திற்கு அனுப்பிய குறிப்பில் குறிப்பிட்டுள்ளது.",
        "“இலங்கை ஜனநாயக சோசலிச குடியரசின் வெளிவிவகார அமைச்சு, கொழும்பில் உள்ள சீன மக்கள் குடியரசின் தூதரகத்திற்கு அதன் மிக உயர்ந்த பரிசீலனைக்கான உத்தரவாதத்தை புதுப்பிப்பதற்கான இந்த வாய்ப்பைப் பயன்படுத்திக் கொள்கிறது,” என்று குறிப்பில் மேலும் தெரிவிக்கப்பட்டுள்ளது.",
        "கொழும்பில் உள்ள சீனத் தூதுவர் Qi Zhenhong, வெள்ளிக்கிழமை குறித்த குறிப்பு கிடைத்தவுடன் ஜனாதிபதியை விரைவில் சந்திக்குமாறு கோரியதற்கு, நேற்று (6) பிற்பகல் சந்திப்பு வழங்கப்பட்டது. சீனக் கப்பலுக்கான அனுமதியை இரத்துச் செய்யும் இலங்கை அரசாங்கத்தின் தீர்மானம் குறித்து சீனத் தூதுவர் சீனாவின் கவலையையும் அதிருப்தியையும் வெளிப்படுத்தியுள்ளதாக அறியமுடிகிறது.",
        "2021 ஆம் ஆண்டு மற்றும் 2022 ஆம் ஆண்டின் முற்பகுதியில் இலங்கை அரசாங்கம் பல சீனக் கப்பல்களை இலங்கை துறைமுகங்களில் நிரப்புவதற்கு அனுமதி வழங்கியுள்ளதாக அறியமுடிகிறது. அவற்றில் ஷி யான் 1 (15 ஏப்ரல் 2021 முதல் கொழும்பு வரை), ஷி யான் 3 (15 மே 2021 முதல் கொழும்பு வரை), ஹை சி 3301 (8 டிசம்பர் 2021 மற்றும் 5 ஜனவரி 2022 முதல் கொழும்பு வரை) மற்றும் ஷி யான் 6 (20 ஏப்ரல் 2022 முதல் கொழும்பு வரை) .",
        "இந்தக் கப்பல்கள் அனைத்தும், கப்பல்துறை மற்றும் நிரப்பு பணிகளுக்காக வெளியுறவு அமைச்சகத்திடம் அனுமதி பெற்றிருந்தன. ‘ஆராய்ச்சி’ நோக்கங்களுக்காக 7 ஜூலை 2022 அன்று கொழும்பில் நிறுத்தப்படவிருந்த மற்றொரு கப்பல் - Xiang Yang Hong 3 - ரத்து செய்யப்பட்டது.",
        "இதே முறையில்தான் யுவான் வாங் 5 ஆகஸ்ட் 11 ஆம் தேதி அம்பாந்தோட்டை துறைமுகத்தில் நிரப்புவதற்கு அனுமதி கோரியது."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "இலங்கை",
          "label": "LOC"
        },
        {
          "text": "சீன",
          "label": "NORP"
        },
        {
          "text": "Yuan Wang",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "Yuan Wang",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "இலங்கை வெளியுறவு அமைச்சகம்",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "விக்கிரமசிங்க",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "வியாழன்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "4",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "சீன",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "கொழும்பில் உள்ள சீன தூதரகம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "வெள்ளி",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "5",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஞாயிற்றுக்கிழமை",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "வியாழன்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "11",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்தியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சீன",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை அரசு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்தியன்",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "சீன",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சீன",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "அலி சப்ரி",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "சீன",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்தியன்",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "சீன",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆசியான்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "கம்போடியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சீன",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஞாயிறு காலை",
            "label": "WORK_OF_ART"
          },
          {
            "text": "அலி சப்ரி",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "சீன",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Wang Yi",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சீன",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "சீன",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை அரசு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "சப்ரி",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஹம்பாந்தோட்டை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Yuan Wang",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "வெளியுறவு அமைச்சகம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "கொழும்பில் உள்ள சீன தூதரகம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "கடந்த வெள்ளிக்கிழமை",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "வெளியுறவு அமைச்சகம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை ஜனநாயக சோசலிச குடியரசு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "சீன மக்கள் குடியரசின் தூதரகம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "கொழும்பு",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "சீன",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Colombo Qi Zhenhong",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "வெள்ளி",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "6",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "சீன",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "சீனா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை அரசாங்கத்தின்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "சீன",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை அரசு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "2021",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "2022 இன் ஆரம்பத்தில்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சீன",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Shi Yan",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "15 ஏப்ரல் 2021",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Shi Yan",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "3",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "15 மே 2021",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஹை சிஇ 3301",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "8 டிசம்பர் 2021",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "5 ஜனவரி 2022",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "கொழும்பு",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Shi Yan",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "20 ஏப்ரல் 2022",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "வெளியுறவு அமைச்சகம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Xiang Yang",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "கொழும்பு",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "7 ஜூலை 2022",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Yuan Wang 5",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "அம்பாந்தோட்டை துறைமுகம்",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "11 ஆகஸ்ட்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}