{
  "newspaper_id": "news-first-lk",
  "url": "https://www.newsfirst.lk/2022/07/14/mahinda-basil-attygalle-pledge-not-to-leave-country-until-tomorrow-15/",
  "time_ut": 1657796460,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Mahinda, Basil & Attygalle pledge not to leave country until tomorrow (15)",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Mahinda, Basil & Attygalle pledge not to leave country until tomorrow (15)",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); Former Prime Minister Mahinda Rajapaksa, former Minister of Finance Basil Rajapaksa, and former Secretary of the Ministry of Finance S. R. Atygalle have pledged to the Supreme Court today (14), that they will not be traveling overseas until tomorrow (15).",
        "The pledge was made by lawyers representing the above former officials when a petition filed for an investigation against those who are responsible for the current economic crisis was called today.",
        "The Supreme Court also issued an order today preventing former Central Bank Governor W. D. Lakshman from traveling abroad until tomorrow due to the absence of a lawyer representing the former CBSL Governor, who was also named as a respondent in the petition.",
        "This order was made after considering the motion related to this petition before the five-member Supreme Court Justices Jayantha Jayasuriya, Bhuvaneka Aluvihare, Priyantha Jayawardena, Vijith Malalgoda, and L.T.B. Dehideniya.",
        "Chandra Jayaratne, the former president of the Sri Lanka Chamber of Commerce, had filed this petition requesting for an investigation to be ordered against those who are responsible for the current economic crisis.",
        "Mahinda, Basil & Attygalle pledge not to leave country until tomorrow (15)",
        "British MP Calls For International Arrest Warrant Against Gotabaya Rajapaksa"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Basil & Attygalle",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "tomorrow",
          "label": "DATE"
        },
        {
          "text": "15",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "News 1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Mahinda Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Basil Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Ministry of Finance",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "S. R. Atygalle",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Supreme Court",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "14",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "tomorrow",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "15",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "The Supreme Court",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Central Bank",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "W. D. Lakshman",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "tomorrow",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "five",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Supreme Court Justices Jayantha Jayasuriya",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Aluvihare",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Priyantha Jayawardena",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Vijith Malalgoda",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "L.T.B. Dehideniya",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Chandra Jayaratne",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Sri Lanka Chamber of Commerce",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Basil & Attygalle",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "tomorrow",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "15",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "British",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Gotabaya Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "හෙට (15) වනතුරු රට නොයන බවට මහින්ද, බැසිල් සහ ආටිගල පොරොන්දු වෙයි",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); හිටපු අග්‍රාමාත්‍ය මහින්ද රාජපක්ෂ, හිටපු මුදල් අමාත්‍ය බැසිල් රාජපක්ෂ සහ මුදල් අමාත්‍යාංශයේ හිටපු ලේකම් එස්.ආර්.ආටිගල හෙට (15) වනතුරු විදෙස් ගත නොවන බවට ශ්‍රේෂ්ඨාධිකරණයට අද (14) ප්‍රතිඥා දී තිබෙනවා.",
        "වත්මන් ආර්ථික අර්බුදයට වගකිවයුත්තන්ට එරෙහිව පරීක්ෂණයක් පවත්වන ලෙස ඉල්ලා ගොනු කළ පෙත්සමක් අද කැදවූ අවස්ථාවේදී ඉහත හිටපු නිලධාරීන් වෙනුවෙන් පෙනී සිටි නීතිඥවරුන් මෙම ප්‍රතිඥාව ලබාදුන්නා.",
        "මෙම පෙත්සමේ වගඋත්තරකරුවෙකු ලෙස නම් කර ඇති හිටපු මහ බැංකු අධිපතිවරයා වෙනුවෙන් නීතිඥවරයෙකු ඉදිරිපත් නොවීම හේතුවෙන් හිටපු මහ බැංකු අධිපති ඩබ්ලිව් ඩී ලක්ෂ්මන් මහතාට හෙට දිනය දක්වා විදේශ ගතවීම වළක්වාලමින් ශ්‍රේෂ්ඨාධිකරණය අද නියෝගයක් නිකුත් කළා.",
        "මෙම නියෝගය කරනු ලැබුවේ ජයන්ත ජයසූරිය, බුවනෙක අලුවිහාරේ, ප්‍රියන්ත ජයවර්ධන, විජිත් මලල්ගොඩ, සහ එල්.ටී.බී යන පංච පුද්ගල ශ්‍රේෂ්ඨාධිකරණ විනිසුරුවරුන් හමුවේ මෙම පෙත්සමට අදාළ මෝසම සලකා බැලීමෙන් අනතුරුවය. දෙහිදෙණිය.",
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකා වාණිජ මණ්ඩලයේ හිටපු සභාපති චන්ද්‍රා ජයරත්න මෙම පෙත්සම ගොනු කර තිබුණේ වත්මන් ආර්ථික අර්බුදයට වගකිවයුත්තන්ට එරෙහිව පරීක්ෂණයක් පවත්වන ලෙසට ඉල්ලා සිටිමිනි.",
        "හෙට (15) වනතුරු රට නොයන බවට මහින්ද, බැසිල් සහ ආටිගල පොරොන්දු වෙයි",
        "බ්‍රිතාන්‍ය මන්ත්‍රී ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂට එරෙහිව ජාත්‍යන්තර වරෙන්තුවක් ඉල්ලා සිටී"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "බැසිල් සහ ආටිගල",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "හෙට",
          "label": "DATE"
        },
        {
          "text": "15",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "News 1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මහින්ද රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "බැසිල් රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "මුදල් අමාත්යාංශය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "එස්.ආර්.ආටිගල",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රේෂ්ඨාධිකරණය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "14",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "හෙට",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "15",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රේෂ්ඨාධිකරණය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මහ බැංකුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඩබ්ලිව් ඩී ලක්ෂ්මන්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "හෙට",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "පහ",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රේෂ්ඨාධිකරණ විනිසුරුවරුන් වන ජයන්ත ජයසූරිය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "අලුවිහාරේ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ප්‍රියන්ත ජයවර්ධන",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "විජිත් මලල්ගොඩ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "එල්.ටී.බී. දෙහිදෙණිය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "චන්ද්‍රා ජයරත්න",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකා වාණිජ මණ්ඩලය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "බැසිල් සහ ආටිගල",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "හෙට",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "15",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "බ්රිතාන්ය",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "நாளை (15) வரை நாட்டை விட்டு வெளியேற மாட்டோம் என மஹிந்த, பசில், ஆட்டிகல உறுதிமொழி!",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); முன்னாள் பிரதமர் மஹிந்த ராஜபக்ஷ, முன்னாள் நிதியமைச்சர் பசில் ராஜபக்ஷ மற்றும் நிதி அமைச்சின் முன்னாள் செயலாளர் எஸ்.ஆர்.ஆட்டிகல ஆகியோர் நாளை (15) வரை வெளிநாட்டுப் பயணத்தை மேற்கொள்ள மாட்டோம் என உச்ச நீதிமன்றில் இன்று (14) உறுதியளித்துள்ளனர்.",
        "தற்போதைய பொருளாதார நெருக்கடிக்கு காரணமானவர்களுக்கு எதிராக விசாரணை கோரி தாக்கல் செய்யப்பட்ட மனு இன்று விசாரணைக்கு எடுத்துக் கொள்ளப்பட்ட போதே மேற்படி முன்னாள் அதிகாரிகள் சார்பில் ஆஜரான சட்டத்தரணிகள் இந்த உறுதிமொழியை வழங்கினர்.",
        "இந்த மனுவில் பிரதிவாதியாக குறிப்பிடப்பட்டிருந்த மத்திய வங்கியின் முன்னாள் ஆளுநர் டபிள்யூ.டி.லக்ஷ்மன் சார்பில் சட்டத்தரணி ஒருவர் முன்னிலையாகாத காரணத்தினால், அவர் நாளை வரை வெளிநாடு செல்வதைத் தடை செய்து உச்ச நீதிமன்றம் இன்று உத்தரவு பிறப்பித்துள்ளது.",
        "ஜயந்த ஜயசூரிய, புவனேகா அலுவிஹாரே, பிரியந்த ஜயவர்தன, விஜித் மலல்கொட மற்றும் எல்.டி.பி ஆகிய ஐவரடங்கிய மேல் நீதிமன்ற நீதிபதிகள் முன்னிலையில் இந்த மனு தொடர்பான பிரேரணையை பரிசீலித்தபோதே இந்த உத்தரவு பிறப்பிக்கப்பட்டுள்ளது. தெஹிதெனிய.",
        "தற்போதைய பொருளாதார நெருக்கடிக்கு காரணமானவர்களுக்கு எதிராக விசாரணை நடத்த உத்தரவிடுமாறு கோரி இலங்கை வர்த்தக சம்மேளனத்தின் முன்னாள் தலைவர் சந்திரா ஜயரத்ன இந்த மனுவை தாக்கல் செய்திருந்தார்.",
        "நாளை (15) வரை நாட்டை விட்டு வெளியேற மாட்டோம் என மஹிந்த, பசில், ஆட்டிகல உறுதிமொழி!",
        "கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்சவுக்கு எதிராக சர்வதேச கைது வாரண்ட் வழங்குமாறு பிரித்தானிய எம்.பி"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "பசில் & ஆட்டிகல",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "நாளை",
          "label": "DATE"
        },
        {
          "text": "15",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "News 1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "மஹிந்த ராஜபக்ஷ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "பசில் ராஜபக்ச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "நிதி அமைச்சகம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "எஸ்.ஆர்.ஆட்டிகல",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "உச்ச நீதிமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "14",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "நாளை",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "15",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "உச்ச நீதிமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "மத்திய வங்கி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "டபிள்யூ.டி.லக்ஷ்மன்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "நாளை",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஐந்து",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "உச்ச நீதிமன்ற நீதிபதிகள் ஜயந்த ஜயசூரிய",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "அலுவிஹாரே",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "பிரியந்த ஜயவர்தன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "விஜித் மலல்கொட",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "எல்.டி.பி. தெஹிதெனிய",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "சந்திரா ஜயரத்ன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை வர்த்தக சபை",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பசில் & ஆட்டிகல",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "நாளை",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "15",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பிரிட்டிஷ்",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}