{
  "newspaper_id": "lankadeepa-lk",
  "url": "https://www.lankadeepa.lk/news/නැකත්-එපා-ඉල්ලා-අස්වනු/101-616174",
  "time_ut": 1657450437,
  "original_lang": "si",
  "original_title": "නැකත් එපා ඉල්ලා අස්වනු",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Do not resign",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "The Galumuwadora activists say that they will inform the President and the Prime Minister to hand over the letters of resignation immediately without waiting any longer for the resignation.",
        "That the auspiciousness of the people of the country to leave will not apply, and if they try to stay in power for one more day without resigning, they will not be allowed to do so. Mr. Wasantha Mudalige, convener of the Inter-University Student Council, representing the strugglers, said that people's rights will not be abandoned.",
        "He mentioned that after the departure of both President Gotabhaya Rajapaksa and Prime Minister Ranil Wickremesinghe, an all-party government should be formed, but an interim government that could fulfill the economic and political demands of the people with the participation of the activists.",
        "Mr. Mudalige said that if the political parties in the parliament try to build all-party governments, they will not allow it, and said that the people struggled, the youths were shot and died in the oil queues, not to give the all-party eight-bolts a chance to another hornade.",
        "He said this while addressing a press conference held today (10) at the cinema hall in Gota Go village, Galle mouth."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Galumuwadora",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "one more day",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Wasantha Mudalige",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Inter-University Student Council",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Gotabhaya Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Mudalige",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "eight",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "10",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Gota Go village",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "Galle",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "නැකත් එපා ඉල්ලා අස්වනු",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "ඉල්ලා අස්වීම සඳහා තවදුරටත් නැකත් බලමින් නොසිට වහාම ඉල්ලා අස්වීමේ ලියුම් භාරදෙන්නැයි ජනාධිපතිවරයාට සහ අගමැතිවරයාට දැනුම් දෙන බව ගාලුමුවදොර අරගලකරුවෝ පවසති.",
        "රටේ ජනතාව ඉවත්ව යන්නැයි කී පසු නැකත් අදාළ නොවන බවත්, ඉල්ලා අස්වීම නොදී කුමන හෝ ක්‍රමයකින් තව දවසක් හෝ බලයේ සිටීමට ඔවුන් උත්සාහ කරන්නේ නම් එයට ඉඩ නොදෙන බවත්, ඔවුන් ඉල්ලා අස්වන තුරු ජනතාව දැනට අත්පත් කරගෙන සිටින ජනාධිපති මන්දිරය, අගමැති මන්දිරය සහ ජනාධිපති ලේකම්කාර්යාලය යන ගොඩනැගිලි ජනතා අයිතියෙන් ඉවත් නොවනු ඇති බවත්, අරගලකරුවන් නියෝජනය කරමින් අන්තර් විශ්ව විද්‍යාලයීය ශිෂ්‍ය බල මණ්ඩලයේ කැඳවුම්කරු වසන්ත මුදලිගේ මහතා පැවසීය.",
        "ජනාධිපති ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්‍ෂ සහ අග්‍රාමාත්‍ය රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ යන දෙපල ඉවත් වූ පසු ගොඩනැගිය යුත්තේ සර්වපාක්ෂික ආණ්ඩුවක් නොව අරගලකරුවන් ද සම්බන්ධ වූ, ජනතාවගේ ආර්ථික දේශපාලන ඉල්ලීම් ඉටුකරගත හැකි අන්තර්කාලීන පාලනයක් බවත් ඔහු සඳහන් කළේය.",
        "සර්වපාක්ෂික ආණ්ඩු ගොඩනැගීමට පාර්ලිමේන්තුවේ දේශපාලන පක්‍ෂ උත්සාහ කරන්නේ නම් එයට ඉඩනොදෙන බව කී මුදලිගේ මහතා ‘ජනතාව අරගල කළේ, තරුණයන් වෙඩි කෑවේ හා තෙල් පෝලිම්වල මියගියේ සර්වපාක්ෂික අටමගුල් අටවා තවත් හොරනඩයට අවස්ථාව දෙන්නට නොවේ,” යැයි ද කීවේය.",
        "ඔහු මේ බව පැවසුවේ ගාලු මුවදොර ගෝඨා ගෝ ගමේ පිහිටි සිනමා ශාලාවේදී අද (10) පැවති මාධ්‍ය හමුවක් අමතමිනි."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Galumuwadora",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "තව එක දවසක්",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "වසන්ත මුදලිගේ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "අන්තර් විශ්වවිද්‍යාල ශිෂ්‍ය සභාව",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "මුදලිගේ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "අට",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "10",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගෝටා ගෝ ගම",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගාල්ල",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "ராஜினாமா செய்ய வேண்டாம்",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "இராஜினாமாவுக்கு மேலும் காத்திருக்காமல் உடனடியாக ராஜினாமா கடிதங்களை கையளிக்குமாறு ஜனாதிபதி மற்றும் பிரதமருக்கு அறிவிக்கவுள்ளதாக கலுமுவதொர செயற்பாட்டாளர்கள் தெரிவிக்கின்றனர்.",
        "நாட்டு மக்கள் வெளியேறும் சுபம் பொருந்தாது என்றும், பதவி விலகாமல் இன்னும் ஒரு நாள் ஆட்சியில் இருக்க முற்பட்டால் அதற்கு இடமளிக்கப்பட மாட்டாது என்றும் பல்கலைக்கழகங்களுக்கிடையேயான அழைப்பாளர் திரு.வசந்த முதலிகே. போராட்டக்காரர்களை பிரதிநிதித்துவப்படுத்தும் மாணவர் பேரவை, மக்களின் உரிமைகள் கைவிடப்பட மாட்டாது.",
        "ஜனாதிபதி கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ஷ மற்றும் பிரதமர் ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க ஆகிய இருவரும் வெளியேறியதன் பின்னர், சர்வகட்சி அரசாங்கம் அமைக்கப்பட வேண்டும், ஆனால் செயற்பாட்டாளர்களின் பங்களிப்புடன் மக்களின் பொருளாதார மற்றும் அரசியல் கோரிக்கைகளை நிறைவேற்றக்கூடிய இடைக்கால அரசாங்கம் அமைக்கப்பட வேண்டும் என அவர் குறிப்பிட்டுள்ளார்.",
        "பாராளுமன்றத்தில் அரசியல் கட்சிகள் சர்வகட்சி அரசாங்கத்தை உருவாக்க முற்பட்டால் அதற்கு இடமளிக்க மாட்டோம் என தெரிவித்த திரு.முதலிகே, மக்கள் போராடினார்கள், இளைஞர்கள் எண்ணெய் கியூவில் சுட்டுக் கொல்லப்பட்டனர், அனைத்தையும் கொடுப்பதற்காக அல்ல என்றார். கட்சி எட்டு போல்ட் மற்றொரு ஹார்னேட் ஒரு வாய்ப்பு.",
        "காலி முகத்துவாரம் கோட்டா கோ கிராமத்தில் உள்ள திரையரங்கில் இன்று (10) இடம்பெற்ற ஊடகவியலாளர் சந்திப்பில் கலந்து கொண்டு கருத்து தெரிவிக்கும் போதே அவர் மேற்கண்டவாறு தெரிவித்தார்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Galumuwadora",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இன்னும் ஒரு நாள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "வசந்த முதலிகே",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "பல்கலைக்கழகங்களுக்கு இடையிலான மாணவர் பேரவை",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "கோத்தபாய ராஜபக்ச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "முதலிகே",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "எட்டு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "10",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "கோதா கோ கிராமம்",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "காலி",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}