{
  "newspaper_id": "daily-mirror-lk",
  "url": "https://www.dailymirror.lk/breaking_news/No-contribution-was-made-by-govt-for-fmr-prezs-foreign-tours/108-243182",
  "time_ut": 1660670243,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "No contribution was made by govt. for fmr prez’s foreign tours",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "No contribution was made by govt. for fmr prez’s foreign tours",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "Whilst Cabinet Spokesman Bandula Gunawardana admitted that the Sri Lankan government footed the bill to provide former President Gotabaya Rajapaksa to fly to Thailand from Singapore in a chartered flight last week, Information Department said government made no contribution for it.",
        "The Department said that the former president had spent his own private funds on his foreign visits.",
        "Responding to a journalist at yesterday’s post-cabinet news briefing, Minister Gunawardana said the Sri Lanka government paid the bill as it was the responsibility of the government.",
        "“Each and every executive president retired and widows of those passed away enjoy benefits, privileges and special facilities, and they are also paid an allowance under the ‘President Entitlement Act No. 4 of 1986’. Therefore, the government is committed to pay former President Rajapaksa’s bills,” he added.",
        "It was under the provisions of this Act, that former Presidents Maithripala Sirisena, Chandrika Kumaratunga and Mrs. Hema Premadasa are provided with a residence, allowance and other facilities, Minister Gunawardana stressed.",
        "If and when former President Rajapaksa returns home in future, the government must provide him with all facilities and privileges entitled to a retired President from the public purse, he added. (Sandun A. Jayasekera and Chaturanga Samarawickrama)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "fmr prez’s",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Cabinet",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Bandula Gunawardana",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lankan",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Gotabaya Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Thailand",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Singapore",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "last week",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Information Department",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "The Department",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "yesterday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Gunawardana",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Maithripala Sirisena",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Chandrika Kumaratunga",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Hema Premadasa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Gunawardana",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sandun A. Jayasekera",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Chaturanga Samarawickrama",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "රජයෙන් කිසිදු දායකත්වයක් ලබා දී නොමැත. fmr prez ගේ විදේශ සංචාර සඳහා",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "හිටපු ජනාධිපති ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ මහතාට සිංගප්පූරුවේ සිට තායිලන්තයට වරලත් ගුවන් යානයකින් යාමට ලබාදීමේ පනත් කෙටුම්පත ශ්‍රී ලංකා රජය විසින් පසුගිය සතියේ ඉදිරිපත් කළ බව කැබිනට් ප්‍රකාශක බන්දුල ගුණවර්ධන පිළිගත් අතර, ඒ සඳහා රජය කිසිදු දායකත්වයක් ලබා නොදුන් බව ප්‍රවෘත්ති දෙපාර්තමේන්තුව පවසයි.",
        "හිටපු ජනාධිපතිවරයා විදේශ සංචාර සඳහා වියදම් කර ඇත්තේ ඔහුගේ පෞද්ගලික මුදල් බවද එම දෙපාර්තමේන්තුව සඳහන් කළේය.",
        "ඊයේ පැවති කැබිනට් තීරණ දැනුම් දීමේ මාධ්‍ය හමුවේදී මාධ්‍යවේදියෙකුට ප්‍රතිචාර දක්වමින් ගුණවර්ධන අමාත්‍යවරයා කියා සිටියේ ශ්‍රී ලංකා රජය බිල්පත් ගෙවා ඇත්තේ එය රජයේ වගකීමක් බැවින් බවයි.",
        "“සෑම විධායක ජනාධිපතිවරයෙකුම විශ්‍රාම ගිය සහ මියගිය අයගේ වැන්දඹුවන් ප්‍රතිලාභ, වරප්‍රසාද සහ විශේෂ පහසුකම් භුක්ති විඳින අතර, ඔවුන්ට ‘1986 අංක 4 දරන ජනාධිපති හිමිකම් පනත’ යටතේ දීමනාවක් ද ගෙවනු ලැබේ. ඒ නිසා හිටපු ජනාධිපති රාජපක්‍ෂගේ බිල්පත් ගෙවීමට රජය කැපවී සිටිනවා,” ඔහු වැඩිදුරටත් පැවසීය.",
        "හිටපු ජනාධිපතිවරුන් වන මෛත්‍රීපාල සිරිසේන, චන්ද්‍රිකා කුමාරතුංග සහ හේමා ප්‍රේමදාස මහත්මියට නිවසක්, දීමනාවක් ඇතුළු පහසුකම් ලබා දෙන්නේ මෙම පනතේ විධිවිධාන යටතේ බව ද අමාත්‍ය ගුණවර්ධන මහතා අවධාරණය කළේය.",
        "ඉදිරියේදී හිටපු ජනාධිපති රාජපක්ෂ මහතා නිවසට පැමිණියහොත් සහ විශ්‍රාමික ජනාධිපතිවරයෙකුට හිමිවන සියලු පහසුකම් සහ වරප්‍රසාද රජය විසින් ඔහුට ලබාදිය යුතු බවද ඔහු වැඩිදුරටත් පැවසීය. (සඳුන් ඒ ජයසේකර සහ චතුරංග සමරවික්‍රම)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "fmr ජනාධිපතිගේ",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "මණ්ඩල",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "බන්දුල ගුණවර්ධන",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලාංකික",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "තායිලන්තය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "සිංගප්පූරුව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගිය සතිය",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "තොරතුරු දෙපාර්තමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "දෙපාර්තමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ඊයේ",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගුණවර්ධනය",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "මෛත්‍රීපාල සිරිසේන",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "චන්ද්‍රිකා කුමාරතුංග",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "හේමා ප්‍රේමදාස",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගුණවර්ධනය",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "සඳුන් ඒ ජයසේකර",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "චතුරංග සමරවික්‍රම",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "அரசு எந்த பங்களிப்பும் செய்யவில்லை. fmr prez இன் வெளிநாட்டு சுற்றுப்பயணங்களுக்கு",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "முன்னாள் ஜனாதிபதி கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்சவை சிங்கப்பூரில் இருந்து தாய்லாந்துக்கு வாடகை விமானம் மூலம் கடந்த வாரம் செல்வதற்கான சட்டமூலத்தை இலங்கை அரசாங்கம் சமர்ப்பித்ததாக அமைச்சரவைப் பேச்சாளர் பந்துல குணவர்தன ஒப்புக்கொண்ட அதேவேளை, அரசாங்கம் அதற்கு எவ்வித பங்களிப்பும் செய்யவில்லை என தகவல் திணைக்களம் தெரிவித்துள்ளது.",
        "முன்னாள் ஜனாதிபதி தனது வெளிநாட்டு விஜயங்களுக்காக தனது சொந்த நிதியை செலவிட்டுள்ளதாக திணைக்களம் தெரிவித்துள்ளது.",
        "நேற்றைய அமைச்சரவையின் பிந்தைய செய்தியாளர் சந்திப்பில் ஊடகவியலாளர் ஒருவருக்கு பதிலளித்த அமைச்சர் குணவர்தன, சிறிலங்கா அரசாங்கத்தின் பொறுப்பு என்பதாலேயே அதற்கான கட்டணத்தை செலுத்தியதாக தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "\"ஒவ்வொரு நிறைவேற்று ஜனாதிபதியும் ஓய்வு பெற்றவர்களும், இறந்தவர்களின் விதவைகளும் சலுகைகள், சலுகைகள் மற்றும் சிறப்பு வசதிகளை அனுபவிக்கின்றனர், மேலும் அவர்களுக்கு '1986 ஆம் ஆண்டின் ஜனாதிபதி உரிமைச் சட்டம் எண். 4' இன் கீழ் ஒரு கொடுப்பனவும் வழங்கப்படுகிறது. எனவே, முன்னாள் அதிபர் ராஜபக்சேவின் கட்டணத்தை செலுத்த அரசாங்கம் உறுதிபூண்டுள்ளது” என்று அவர் மேலும் கூறினார்.",
        "இந்த சட்டத்தின் விதிகளின் கீழ் தான் முன்னாள் ஜனாதிபதிகளான மைத்திரிபால சிறிசேன, சந்திரிகா குமாரதுங்க மற்றும் திருமதி ஹேமா பிரேமதாச ஆகியோருக்கு குடியிருப்பு, கொடுப்பனவு மற்றும் ஏனைய வசதிகள் வழங்கப்பட்டுள்ளதாக அமைச்சர் குணவர்தன வலியுறுத்தினார்.",
        "எதிர்காலத்தில் முன்னாள் ஜனாதிபதி ராஜபக்ச நாடு திரும்பினால், ஓய்வுபெற்ற ஜனாதிபதிக்கு உரிய அனைத்து வசதிகளையும் சலுகைகளையும் அரசாங்கம் அவருக்கு வழங்க வேண்டும் எனவும் அவர் மேலும் தெரிவித்துள்ளார். (சந்துன் ஏ. ஜயசேகர மற்றும் சதுரங்க சமரவிக்ரம)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "fmr ப்ரெஸ்",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "மந்திரி சபை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "பந்துல குணவர்தன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "தாய்லாந்து",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சிங்கப்பூர்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "கடந்த வாரம்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "தகவல் துறை",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "துறை",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "நேற்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "குணவர்தன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ராஜபக்சே",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "மைத்திரிபால சிறிசேன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "சந்திரிகா குமாரதுங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஹேமா பிரேமதாச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "குணவர்தன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ராஜபக்சே",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "சந்துன் ஏ.ஜெயசேகர",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "சதுரங்க சமரவிக்ரம",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}