{
  "newspaper_id": "tamil-mirror-lk",
  "url": "https://www.tamilmirror.lk/செய்திகள்/நாட்டுக்கு-சேவையாற்ற-எப்போதும்-தயார்/175-300522",
  "time_ut": 1657953218,
  "original_lang": "ta",
  "original_title": "நாட்டுக்கு சேவையாற்ற எப்போதும் தயார்",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Always ready to serve the country",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "Former President Gotabaya Rajapaksa has stated in his resignation letter that he is always ready to continue serving his motherland.",
        "Parliamentary Secretary General Thammika Dasanayake submitted the President's resignation letter in the House today.",
        "He pointed out in the letter that due to the need to periodically shut down the country to protect people from the Corona pandemic in 2020-2021, the economic crisis and foreign exchange shortages that have been escalating over the years have been exacerbated.",
        "In his resignation letter, Kota mentioned that in order to resolve the resulting instability, all efforts were made to form an all-party or national government by inviting all political party leaders representing the Parliament.",
        "He also indicated that he will step down from the post of President from July 14th in accordance with the request of the general public and the leaders of the parliamentary party."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Gotabaya Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "House",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Corona",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "2020-2021",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the years",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Kota",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "July 14th",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "රට වෙනුවෙන් සේවය කිරීමට සැම විටම සූදානම්",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "තම මාතෘ භූමියට තවදුරටත් සේවය කිරීමට තමන් සැමවිටම සූදානම් බව හිටපු ජනාධිපති ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ මහතා සිය ඉල්ලා අස්වීමේ ලිපියෙන් ප්‍රකාශ කර තිබේ.",
        "ජනාධිපතිවරයාගේ ඉල්ලා අස්වීමේ ලිපිය පාර්ලිමේන්තු මහලේකම් තම්මික දසනායක අද සභාවට ඉදිරිපත් කළා.",
        "2020-2021 කාලය තුළ කොරෝනා වසංගතයෙන් ජනතාව ආරක්ෂා කර ගැනීම සඳහා රට වරින් වර වසා දැමීමේ අවශ්‍යතාවය හේතුවෙන් වසර ගණනාවක් තිස්සේ උග්‍ර වෙමින් පවතින ආර්ථික අර්බුදය සහ විදේශ විනිමය හිඟය උග්‍ර වී ඇති බව ඔහු එම ලිපියෙන් පෙන්වා දුන්නේය.",
        "එහි ප්‍රතිඵලයක් ලෙස ඇති වූ අස්ථාවරත්වය විසඳීම සඳහා පාර්ලිමේන්තුව නියෝජනය කරන සියලුම දේශපාලන පක්ෂ නායකයින් කැඳවා සර්ව පාක්ෂික හෝ ජාතික ආණ්ඩුවක් පිහිටුවීමට සියලු උත්සාහයන් ගත් බව කෝටා සිය ඉල්ලා අස්වීමේ ලිපියේ සඳහන් කර ඇත.",
        "මහජනතාවගේ සහ පාර්ලිමේන්තු පක්ෂ නායකයින්ගේ ඉල්ලීම පරිදි ජූලි 14 වැනිදා සිට තමා ජනාධිපති ධුරයෙන් ඉල්ලා අස්වන බවද ඔහු පෙන්වා දුන්නේය."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "නිවස",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "කොරෝනා",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "2020-2021",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "වසර",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "කොටා",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ජූලි 14",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "நாட்டுக்கு சேவையாற்ற எப்போதும் தயார்",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "தனது தாய் நாட்டுக்கு தொடர்ந்தும் சேவையாற்ற எப்போதும் தயாராக இருப்பதாக முன்னாள் ஜனாதிபதி கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ஷ தனது இராஜினாமா கடிதத்தில் குறிப்பிட்டுள்ளார்.",
        "ஜனாதிபதியின் இராஜினாமா கடிதத்தை பாராளுமன்ற செயலாளர் நாயகம் தம்மிக்க தசநாயக்க சபையில் இன்று சமர்ப்பித்தார்.",
        "2020-2021ஆம் ஆண்டுகளில் கொரோனா தொற்றுநோயிலிருந்து மக்களைப் பாதுகாக்க அவ்வப்போது நாட்டை மூட வேண்டியதன் அவசியம் காரணமாக, பல ஆண்டுகளாக அதிகரித்து வந்த பொருளாதார நெருக்கடி மற்றும் அந்நிய செலாவணி பற்றாக்குறை ஆகியவை மேலும் அதிகரித்ததாக கடிதத்தில் சுட்டிக்காட்டியுள்ளார்.",
        "இதனால் ஏற்பட்ட ஸ்திரமின்மைக்கு தீர்வு காணும் வகையில், பாராளுமன்றத்தை பிரதிநிதித்துவப்படுத்தும் அனைத்து அரசியல் கட்சி தலைவர்களை அழைத்து அனைத்து கட்சி அல்லது தேசிய அரசாங்கத்தை அமைக்க அனைத்து முயற்சிகளையும் மேற்கொண்டதாக இராஜினாமா கடிதத்தில் கோட்டா குறிப்பிட்டுள்ளார்.",
        "பொது மக்கள் மற்றும் பாராளுமன்றக் கட்சித் தலைவர்களின் வேண்டுகோளுக்கு இணங்க ஜூலை 14ஆம் திகதி முதல் ஜனாதிபதி பதவியில் இருந்து விலகவுள்ளதாகவும் சுட்டிக்காட்டியுள்ளார்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "வீடு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "கொரோனா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "2020-2021",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆண்டுகள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "கோட்டா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஜூலை 14",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}