{
  "newspaper_id": "daily-mirror-lk",
  "url": "https://www.dailymirror.lk/opinion/In-remembrance-of-Mikhail-Gorbachev/172-244084",
  "time_ut": 1661972929,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "In remembrance of Mikhail Gorbachev",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "In remembrance of Mikhail Gorbachev",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "On the evening of August 30 this year, Mikhail Gorbachev, the first and last President of the Soviet Union passed away. It marked the end of an era and the demise of a man of great integrity.",
        "Gorbachev was said to have been suffering from a long and serious illness. In June, international media reported that he had been admitted to hospital after suffering from a kidney ailment, though the cause of his death has not been announced as yet.",
        "His health had been deteriorating since the beginning of the Covid-19 pandemic and had been in and out of hospital in recent years.",
        "Mikhail Gorbachev, was born in 1931 into a peasant family in southern Russia. In his teens, young Gorbachev operated combine harvesters on collective farms. His political career began during the days where he was student while studying law at the Moscow University. He became the General Secretary of the Central Committee of the Communist Party of the Soviet Union, making him the highest ranking official in the USSR.",
        "A divisive figure in Russia, Gorby, as he was sometimes referred to, aimed at re-energizing the stalled Soviet economy, which was riddled with inefficiency, overblown defence spending and expanding corruption. He called for urgent reorganization and modernization.",
        "He introduced the concept of ‘perestroika’ an attempt to restructure and give more independence to ministries and large state-owned enterprises. He also introduced some concepts of free market-style reforms. In 1988, Gorbachev permitted the establishment of private enterprises in the country. A break from the policies introduced by Vladimir Lenin at time of the Russian revolution.",
        "At the time Gorbachev led the USSR, the world was polarized between country groupings which supported the US and the NATO bloc in the West and the Marxist/Communist bloc led by Russia - the era commonly referred to as the ‘Cold War’ period. The two groupings were completely at logger-heads with each other and proxy wars between the groups were waged in the Asian and African countries. It was a time when these proxy wars were in danger of boiling over into battles of direct confrontation between the two power-blocs. It is to the former Soviet leader’s eternal credit, those differences did not spill over into direct confrontation.",
        "Gorbechev’s foreign policy, marked a period of an improvement of relations between the Soviet Union and Western countries, replacing the era of Cold War hostilities. His re-engagement with the West paved the way for several key disarmament treaties being signed. Moscow and Washington agreed to dismantle their intermediate-range conventional and nuclear missiles. Under Gorbachev, Moscow unilaterally stopped all nuclear tests.Moscow’s relations with the Eastern Bloc countries also underwent a radical change. Whereas formerly Soviet troops ‘ended’ disputes/differences within the USSR countries, Gorbachev’s liberalization included the right of self-determination. Countries were allowed to determine their own internal policies.",
        "The reunification of Germany is also largely credited to Gorbachev who was known for have played a key role in the fall of the ‘Berlin Wall’ which divided Germany into West Germany and East Germany.",
        "In 1986, he announced plans to withdraw the Soviet troops from Afghanistan. The Soviet Union’s armed involvement in Afghanistan cost the Soviet Union at least 15,000 casualties, and filled the country with veterans suffering from combat stress disorders.It was under Gorbachev’s leadership, Moscow unilaterally stopped all nuclear tests which led the way for re-integration with the West and paved the way for several key disarmament treaties which were subsequently signed. It was also during Gorbachev’s term, Moscow and Washington agreed to dismantle their intermediate-range conventional and nuclear missiles.",
        "In 1991, Gorbachev oversaw the dissolution of the Soviet Union. The partial democratization of Soviet society under him led to a number of countries in the former Soviet bloc opting out of the bloc. Gorbachev attempted to draft a new union treaty. However, a group of hardline top officials attempted to stage a coup and to remove him from power to prevent the signing of the new union treaty.",
        "The coup failed, but it prompted Gorbachev to dissolve the Central Committee of the Communist Party of the Soviet Union and to resign as the party’s General Secretary.",
        "By the time Gorbachev stepped down at the end of 1991, the NATO-Soviet frontier was no longer a flashpoint. NATO pulled all, but a few thousand troops back from the eastern flank, and the terrors of the cold war seemed consigned to history books and museums.Mikhail Gorbechev is best remembered for his disarmament initiatives, the unification of Germany, ending the Cold War, as well as for granting Eastern European countries the right to self-determination."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Mikhail Gorbachev",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "the evening",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "this year",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Mikhail Gorbachev",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "first",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Soviet Union",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Gorbachev",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "June",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "recent years",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Mikhail Gorbachev",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "1931",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Russia",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Gorbachev",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the days",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Moscow University",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Central Committee",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Communist Party",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Soviet Union",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "USSR",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Russia",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Gorby",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Soviet",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "1988",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Gorbachev",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Vladimir Lenin",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Russian",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Gorbachev",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "USSR",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "US",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "NATO",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "West",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "Marxist",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Communist",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Russia",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the ‘Cold War’",
            "label": "EVENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "two",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Asian",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "African",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "two",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Soviet",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Gorbechev",
            "label": "PRODUCT"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Soviet Union",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Cold War",
            "label": "EVENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "West",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "Moscow",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Washington",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Gorbachev",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Moscow",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Moscow",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Eastern Bloc",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "Soviet",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "USSR",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Gorbachev",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Germany",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Gorbachev",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the ‘Berlin Wall’",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "Germany",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "West Germany",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "East Germany",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "1986",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Soviet",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Afghanistan",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "The Soviet Union’s",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Afghanistan",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Soviet Union",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "at least 15,000",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Gorbachev",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Moscow",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "West",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "Gorbachev",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Moscow",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Washington",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "1991",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Gorbachev",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Soviet Union",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Soviet",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Soviet",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Gorbachev",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Gorbachev",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Central Committee",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Communist Party",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Soviet Union",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Gorbachev",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the end of 1991",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "NATO",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "NATO",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "a few thousand",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "the cold war",
            "label": "EVENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "Mikhail Gorbechev",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Germany",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Cold War",
            "label": "EVENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "Eastern European",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "මිහායිල් ගොර්බචෙව් සිහිපත් කිරීම සඳහා",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "මේ වසරේ අගෝස්තු 30 වැනිදා සවස සෝවියට් සංගමයේ පළමු සහ අවසාන ජනාධිපතිවරයා වූ මිහායිල් ගොර්බචෙව් අභාවප්‍රාප්ත විය. එය යුගයක අවසානය සනිටුහන් කළ අතර මහා අවංක මිනිසෙකුගේ අභාවය සනිටුහන් කළේය.",
        "ගොර්බචෙව් දිගු හා බරපතල රෝගාබාධයකින් පෙළෙන බව පැවසේ. ඔහුගේ මරණයට හේතුව මෙතෙක් ප්‍රකාශයට පත් කර නොමැති නමුත් වකුගඩු ආබාධයකින් පෙළීමෙන් ඔහු රෝහල් ගත කර ඇති බව ජුනි මාසයේදී ජාත්‍යන්තර මාධ්‍ය වාර්තා කළේය.",
        "Covid-19 වසංගතය ආරම්භයේ සිටම ඔහුගේ සෞඛ්‍ය තත්ත්වය නරක අතට හැරෙමින් තිබූ අතර මෑත වසරවලදී රෝහල තුළ සහ ඉන් පිටත සිට ඇත.",
        "මිහායිල් ගොර්බචෙව් 1931 දී දකුණු රුසියාවේ ගොවි පවුලක උපත ලැබීය. ඔහුගේ නව යොවුන් වියේදී, තරුණ ගොර්බචෙව් සාමූහික ගොවිපලවල ඒකාබද්ධ අස්වනු නෙළන යන්ත්‍ර ක්‍රියාත්මක කළේය. ඔහුගේ දේශපාලන ජීවිතය ආරම්භ වූයේ ඔහු මොස්කව් විශ්ව විද්‍යාලයේ නීති අධ්‍යාපනය හදාරමින් සිටියදී ශිෂ්‍යයෙකු වූ දිනවල ය. ඔහු සෝවියට් සංගමයේ කොමියුනිස්ට් පක්ෂයේ මධ්‍යම කාරක සභාවේ ප්‍රධාන ලේකම් බවට පත් වූ අතර ඔහු සෝවියට් සංගමයේ ඉහළම නිලධාරියා බවට පත්විය.",
        "රුසියාවේ භේදකාරී චරිතයක් වන ගෝර්බි, සමහර විට ඔහුව හැඳින්වූයේ, අකාර්යක්ෂමතාවයෙන්, අධික ලෙස පුපුරවා හරින ලද ආරක්ෂක වියදම් සහ දූෂණය පුළුල් කිරීමෙන් ඇණහිට ඇති සෝවියට් ආර්ථිකය නැවත පණ ගැන්වීමේ අරමුණින් ය. කඩිනම් ප්‍රතිසංවිධානයක් සහ නවීකරණයක් ඉල්ලා සිටියේය.",
        "අමාත්‍යාංශ සහ විශාල රාජ්‍ය ව්‍යවසායන් ප්‍රතිව්‍යුහගත කිරීමට සහ වැඩි ස්වාධීනත්වයක් ලබා දීමට ඔහු 'පෙරෙස්ත්‍රොයිකා' සංකල්පය හඳුන්වා දුන්නේය. ඔහු නිදහස් වෙළඳපල ප්‍රතිසංස්කරණ පිළිබඳ සංකල්ප කිහිපයක් ද හඳුන්වා දුන්නේය. 1988 දී ගොර්බචෙව් රට තුළ පුද්ගලික ව්‍යවසායන් පිහිටුවීමට අවසර දුන්නේය. රුසියානු විප්ලවයේදී ව්ලැඩිමීර් ලෙනින් විසින් හඳුන්වා දුන් ප්‍රතිපත්තිවලින් බිඳීමක්.",
        "ගොර්බචෙව් සෝවියට් සමාජවාදී සමූහාණ්ඩුවට නායකත්වය දුන් අවස්ථාවේදී, ලෝකය එක්සත් ජනපදයට සහ බටහිර නේටෝ කඳවුරට සහ රුසියාවේ නායකත්වයෙන් යුත් මාක්ස්වාදී/කොමියුනිස්ට් කඳවුරට සහය දුන් රට කණ්ඩායම් අතර ධ්‍රැවීකරණය වී ඇත - එම යුගය සාමාන්‍යයෙන් ‘සීතල යුද්ධ’ සමය ලෙස හැඳින්වේ. කණ්ඩායම් දෙක සම්පූර්ණයෙන්ම එකිනෙකා සමඟ ගැටුම් ඇති කර ගත් අතර කණ්ඩායම් අතර ප්‍රොක්සි යුද්ධ ආසියානු සහ අප්‍රිකානු රටවල සිදු විය. මෙම ප්‍රොක්සි යුද්ධ බල-කණ්ඩායම් දෙක අතර සෘජු ගැටුමක සටන් දක්වා උතුරා යාමේ අවදානමකට ලක්ව තිබූ කාලයකි. එය හිටපු සෝවියට් නායකයාගේ සදාකාලික ගෞරවයට ය, එම වෙනස්කම් සෘජු ගැටුමක් දක්වා පැතිර ගියේ නැත.",
        "ගොර්බෙචෙව්ගේ විදේශ ප්‍රතිපත්තිය, සීතල යුද්ධයේ සතුරු යුගය ප්‍රතිස්ථාපනය කරමින් සෝවියට් සංගමය සහ බටහිර රටවල් අතර සබඳතා වැඩිදියුණු කිරීමේ කාල පරිච්ඡේදයක් සලකුණු කළේය. බටහිර සමඟ ඔහුගේ නැවත සම්බන්ධ වීම ප්‍රධාන නිරායුධකරණ ගිවිසුම් කිහිපයකට අත්සන් කිරීමට මග පෑදීය. මොස්කව් සහ වොෂින්ටනය ඔවුන්ගේ අතරමැදි පරාස සාම්ප්‍රදායික සහ න්‍යෂ්ටික මිසයිල විසුරුවා හැරීමට එකඟ විය. ගොර්බචෙව් යටතේ මොස්කව් ඒකපාර්ශ්විකව සියලු න්‍යෂ්ටික අත්හදා බැලීම් නැවැත්වූයේය.ඊස්ටර්න් බ්ලොක් රටවල් සමඟ මොස්කව්හි සබඳතා ද රැඩිකල් වෙනසක් සිදු විය. කලින් සෝවියට් හමුදා සෝවියට් සංගමයේ රටවල් තුළ ආරවුල් / වෙනස්කම් 'අවසන්' කළ අතර, ගොර්බචෙව්ගේ ලිබරල්කරණයට ස්වයං නිර්ණ අයිතිය ඇතුළත් විය. තමන්ගේ අභ්‍යන්තර ප්‍රතිපත්ති තීරණය කිරීමට රටවලට අවසර දෙන ලදී.",
        "ජර්මනිය යලි එක්සත් කිරීම බොහෝ දුරට ගෞරවයට පාත්‍ර වන්නේ ජර්මනිය බටහිර ජර්මනිය සහ නැගෙනහිර ජර්මනිය ලෙස බෙදා වෙන් කළ 'බර්ලින් තාප්පය' බිඳවැටීමේ ප්‍රධාන භූමිකාවක් ඉටු කළ බවට ප්‍රසිද්ධ වූ ගොර්බචෙව්ට ය.",
        "1986 දී ඔහු ඇෆ්ගනිස්ථානයෙන් සෝවියට් හමුදා ඉවත් කර ගැනීමේ සැලසුම් නිවේදනය කළේය. ඇෆ්ගනිස්ථානයේ සෝවියට් සංගමයේ සන්නද්ධ මැදිහත්වීම නිසා සෝවියට් සංගමයට අවම වශයෙන් 15,000 තුවාල සිදු වූ අතර, සටන් ආතති ආබාධවලින් පෙළෙන ප්‍රවීණයන්ගෙන් රට පුරවා ඇත. එය ගොර්බචෙව්ගේ නායකත්වය යටතේ මොස්කව් ඒකපාර්ශ්විකව න්‍යෂ්ටික අත්හදා බැලීම් නවතා දැමුවේ ය. බටහිර සහ පසුව අත්සන් කරන ලද ප්රධාන නිරායුධකරණ ගිවිසුම් කිහිපයකට මග පෑදීය. ගොර්බචෙව්ගේ පාලන සමයේදී මොස්කව් සහ වොෂින්ටනය ඔවුන්ගේ අතරමැදි පරාස සාම්ප්‍රදායික සහ න්‍යෂ්ටික මිසයිල විසුරුවා හැරීමට එකඟ විය.",
        "1991 දී ගොර්බචෙව් සෝවියට් සංගමය විසුරුවා හැරීම අධීක්ෂණය කළේය. ඔහු යටතේ සෝවියට් සමාජය අර්ධ වශයෙන් ප්‍රජාතන්ත්‍රීකරණය කිරීම නිසා පැරනි සෝවියට් සංගමයේ රටවල් ගණනාවක් එම කණ්ඩායමෙන් ඉවත් වීමට හේතු විය. ගොර්බචෙව් නව වෘත්තීය සමිති ගිවිසුමක් කෙටුම්පත් කිරීමට උත්සාහ කළේය. කෙසේ වෙතත්, දැඩි මතධාරී ඉහළ නිලධාරීන් පිරිසක් නව වෘත්තීය සමිති ගිවිසුම අත්සන් කිරීම වැළැක්වීම සඳහා කුමන්ත්‍රණයක් ක්‍රියාත්මක කර ඔහු බලයෙන් පහ කිරීමට උත්සාහ කළහ.",
        "කුමන්ත්‍රණය අසාර්ථක වූ නමුත් එය සෝවියට් සංගමයේ කොමියුනිස්ට් පක්ෂයේ මධ්‍යම කාරක සභාව විසුරුවා හැරීමට සහ පක්ෂයේ ප්‍රධාන ලේකම් ධුරයෙන් ඉල්ලා අස්වීමට ගොර්බචෙව්ව පොළඹවන ලදී.",
        "1991 අවසානයේ ගොර්බචෙව් ඉවත් වන විට, නේටෝ-සෝවියට් දේශසීමා තවදුරටත් ෆ්ලෑෂ් පොයින්ට් නොවීය. නැගෙනහිර දෙසින් නේටෝව හමුදා භටයන් කිහිප දහසක් ආපසු ඇදගෙන ගිය අතර, සීතල යුද්ධයේ භීෂණය ඉතිහාස පොත් සහ කෞතුකාගාරවල තැන්පත් කර ඇති බවක් පෙනෙන්නට තිබුණි. මිහායිල් ගොර්බෙචෙව් ඔහුගේ නිරායුධ කිරීමේ මුලපිරීම්, ජර්මනිය එක්සත් කිරීම, සීතල යුද්ධය අවසන් කිරීම සඳහා වඩාත් හොඳින් සිහිපත් වේ. නැගෙනහිර යුරෝපීය රටවලට ස්වයං නිර්ණ අයිතිය ලබා දීම සඳහා මෙන්ම."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "මිහායිල් ගොර්බචෙව්",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "සවස",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "මේ වසරේ",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මිහායිල් ගොර්බචෙව්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "පළමුවන",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "සෝවියට් සංගමය",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ගොර්බචෙව්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජූනි",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "පසුගිය වසරවල",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "මිහායිල් ගොර්බචෙව්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "1931",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "රුසියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගොර්බචෙව්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "දවස්",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මොස්කව් විශ්ව විද්යාලය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "මධ්යම කාරක සභාව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "කොමියුනිස්ට් පක්ෂය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "සෝවියට් සංගමය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "සෝවියට් සංගමය",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "රුසියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගෝර්බි",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "සෝවියට්",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "1988",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගොර්බචෙව්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ව්ලැඩිමීර් ලෙනින්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "රුසියානු",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ගොර්බචෙව්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "සෝවියට් සංගමය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "එක්සත් ජනපදය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "නේටෝ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "බටහිර",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "මාක්ස්වාදී",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "කොමියුනිස්ට්",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "රුසියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "'සීතල යුද්ධය'",
            "label": "EVENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "දෙක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ආසියානු",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "අප්රිකානු",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "දෙක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "සෝවියට්",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ගොර්බෙචෙව්",
            "label": "PRODUCT"
          },
          {
            "text": "සෝවියට් සංගමය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "සීතල යුද්ධය",
            "label": "EVENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "බටහිර",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "මොස්කව්",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "වොෂින්ටනය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගොර්බචෙව්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "මොස්කව්",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මොස්කව්",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "නැගෙනහිර බ්ලොක්",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "සෝවියට්",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "සෝවියට් සංගමය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගොර්බචෙව්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ජර්මනිය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගොර්බචෙව්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "'බර්ලින් තාප්පය'",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජර්මනිය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "බටහිර ජර්මනිය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "නැගෙනහිර ජර්මනිය",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "1986",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "සෝවියට්",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඇෆ්ගනිස්ථානය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "සෝවියට් සංගමයේ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඇෆ්ගනිස්ථානය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "සෝවියට් සංගමය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "අවම වශයෙන් 15,000",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගොර්බචෙව්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "මොස්කව්",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "බටහිර",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගොර්බචෙව්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "මොස්කව්",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "වොෂින්ටනය",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "1991",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගොර්බචෙව්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "සෝවියට් සංගමය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "සෝවියට්",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "සෝවියට්",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගොර්බචෙව්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ගොර්බචෙව්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "මධ්යම කාරක සභාව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "කොමියුනිස්ට් පක්ෂය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "සෝවියට් සංගමය",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ගොර්බචෙව්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "1991 අවසානයේ",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "නේටෝ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "නේටෝ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "දහස් ගණනක්",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "සීතල යුද්ධය",
            "label": "EVENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "මිහායිල් ගොර්බෙචෙව්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජර්මනිය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "සීතල යුද්ධය",
            "label": "EVENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "නැගෙනහිර යුරෝපීය",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "மிகைல் கோர்பச்சேவ் நினைவாக",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "இந்த ஆண்டு ஆகஸ்ட் 30 அன்று மாலை, சோவியத் ஒன்றியத்தின் முதல் மற்றும் கடைசி ஜனாதிபதியான மிகைல் கோர்பச்சேவ் காலமானார். இது ஒரு சகாப்தத்தின் முடிவையும் ஒரு சிறந்த நேர்மையான மனிதனின் மறைவையும் குறித்தது.",
        "கோர்பச்சேவ் நீண்ட மற்றும் கடுமையான நோயினால் அவதிப்பட்டு வந்ததாக கூறப்படுகிறது. அவரது மரணத்திற்கான காரணம் இதுவரை அறிவிக்கப்படாத போதிலும், சிறுநீரகக் கோளாறினால் அவர் மருத்துவமனையில் அனுமதிக்கப்பட்டுள்ளதாக ஜூன் மாதம் சர்வதேச ஊடகங்கள் செய்தி வெளியிட்டுள்ளன.",
        "கோவிட் -19 தொற்றுநோய் தொடங்கியதில் இருந்து அவரது உடல்நிலை மோசமடைந்து வந்தது மற்றும் சமீபத்திய ஆண்டுகளில் மருத்துவமனையில் மற்றும் வெளியே இருந்தது.",
        "மிகைல் கோர்பச்சேவ், 1931 ஆம் ஆண்டு தெற்கு ரஷ்யாவில் ஒரு விவசாயக் குடும்பத்தில் பிறந்தார். தனது பதின்பருவத்தில், இளம் கோர்பச்சேவ் கூட்டுப் பண்ணைகளில் கூட்டு அறுவடை இயந்திரங்களை இயக்கினார். மாஸ்கோ பல்கலைக்கழகத்தில் சட்டம் பயின்று அவர் மாணவராக இருந்த நாட்களில் அவரது அரசியல் வாழ்க்கை தொடங்கியது. அவர் சோவியத் ஒன்றியத்தின் கம்யூனிஸ்ட் கட்சியின் மத்தியக் குழுவின் பொதுச் செயலாளராக ஆனார், அவரை சோவியத் ஒன்றியத்தின் மிக உயர்ந்த பதவியில் ஆக்கினார்.",
        "ரஷ்யாவில் ஒரு பிளவுபடுத்தும் நபர், கோர்பி, சில சமயங்களில் அவர் குறிப்பிடப்படுவது போல், திறமையின்மை, மிகைப்படுத்தப்பட்ட பாதுகாப்பு செலவுகள் மற்றும் ஊழலை விரிவுபடுத்துதல் ஆகியவற்றால் சிக்கியிருந்த சோவியத் பொருளாதாரத்தை மீண்டும் உற்சாகப்படுத்துவதை நோக்கமாகக் கொண்டிருந்தார். அவசர மறுசீரமைப்பு மற்றும் நவீனமயமாக்கலுக்கு அவர் அழைப்பு விடுத்தார்.",
        "அவர் 'பெரெஸ்ட்ரோயிகா' என்ற கருத்தை அறிமுகப்படுத்தினார், இது அமைச்சகங்கள் மற்றும் பெரிய அரசுக்கு சொந்தமான நிறுவனங்களுக்கு மறுசீரமைப்பு மற்றும் அதிக சுதந்திரத்தை வழங்கும் முயற்சியாகும். அவர் தடையற்ற சந்தை-பாணி சீர்திருத்தங்கள் பற்றிய சில கருத்துக்களையும் அறிமுகப்படுத்தினார். 1988 இல், கோர்பச்சேவ் நாட்டில் தனியார் நிறுவனங்களை நிறுவ அனுமதித்தார். ரஷ்ய புரட்சியின் போது விளாடிமிர் லெனின் அறிமுகப்படுத்திய கொள்கைகளில் இருந்து முறிவு.",
        "கோர்பச்சேவ் சோவியத் ஒன்றியத்திற்கு தலைமை தாங்கிய நேரத்தில், அமெரிக்கா மற்றும் மேற்கு நாடுகளில் உள்ள நேட்டோ முகாம் மற்றும் ரஷ்யா தலைமையிலான மார்க்சிஸ்ட்/கம்யூனிஸ்ட் கூட்டணிக்கு ஆதரவளித்த நாடு குழுக்களுக்கு இடையே உலகம் துருவப்படுத்தப்பட்டது - இது பொதுவாக 'பனிப்போர்' காலம் என்று குறிப்பிடப்படுகிறது. இரண்டு குழுக்களும் ஒருவருக்கொருவர் முற்றிலும் முரண்பட்டன மற்றும் குழுக்களுக்கு இடையேயான பினாமி போர்கள் ஆசிய மற்றும் ஆப்பிரிக்க நாடுகளில் நடத்தப்பட்டன. இந்த ப்ராக்ஸி போர்கள் இரண்டு அதிகார-கூட்டங்களுக்கு இடையிலான நேரடி மோதலின் போர்களாக கொதிக்கும் அபாயத்தில் இருந்த காலம் அது. இது முன்னாள் சோவியத் தலைவரின் நித்திய வரவு, அந்த வேறுபாடுகள் நேரடி மோதலாக பரவவில்லை.",
        "கோர்பெச்சேவின் வெளியுறவுக் கொள்கை, சோவியத் யூனியனுக்கும் மேற்கத்திய நாடுகளுக்கும் இடையிலான உறவுகளை மேம்படுத்துவதற்கான காலகட்டத்தைக் குறித்தது, இது பனிப்போர் விரோதங்களின் சகாப்தத்தை மாற்றியது. மேற்கத்திய நாடுகளுடனான அவரது மறு-நிச்சயதார்த்தம் பல முக்கிய ஆயுதக் குறைப்பு ஒப்பந்தங்கள் கையெழுத்திட வழி வகுத்தது. மாஸ்கோவும் வாஷிங்டனும் தங்களுடைய இடைநிலை தூர மரபுவழி மற்றும் அணுசக்தி ஏவுகணைகளை அகற்ற ஒப்புக்கொண்டன. கோர்பச்சேவின் கீழ், மாஸ்கோ ஒருதலைப்பட்சமாக அனைத்து அணுசக்தி சோதனைகளையும் நிறுத்தியது. கிழக்கு பிளாக் நாடுகளுடனான மாஸ்கோவின் உறவுகளும் தீவிரமான மாற்றத்திற்கு உட்பட்டன. முன்னர் சோவியத் துருப்புக்கள் சோவியத் ஒன்றிய நாடுகளுக்குள் இருந்த சச்சரவுகள்/வேறுபாடுகளை முடிவுக்குக் கொண்டு வந்த நிலையில், கோர்பச்சேவின் தாராளமயமாக்கல் சுயநிர்ணய உரிமையை உள்ளடக்கியது. நாடுகள் தங்கள் உள் கொள்கைகளைத் தீர்மானிக்க அனுமதிக்கப்பட்டன.",
        "ஜெர்மனியை மேற்கு ஜெர்மனி மற்றும் கிழக்கு ஜெர்மனி எனப் பிரித்த ‘பெர்லின் சுவரின்’ வீழ்ச்சியில் முக்கியப் பங்காற்றியதாக அறியப்பட்ட கோர்பச்சேவுக்கு ஜெர்மனியின் மறு ஒருங்கிணைப்பு பெருமளவில் உள்ளது.",
        "1986 இல், ஆப்கானிஸ்தானில் இருந்து சோவியத் துருப்புக்களை திரும்பப் பெறும் திட்டத்தை அறிவித்தார். ஆப்கானிஸ்தானில் சோவியத் யூனியனின் ஆயுதமேந்திய ஈடுபாட்டால் சோவியத் யூனியனுக்கு குறைந்தது 15,000 பேர் பலியாகினர், மேலும் போர் மன அழுத்தக் கோளாறுகளால் பாதிக்கப்பட்ட படைவீரர்களால் நாட்டை நிரப்பினர். கோர்பச்சேவ் தலைமையில் மாஸ்கோ ஒருதலைப்பட்சமாக அனைத்து அணுசக்தி சோதனைகளையும் நிறுத்தியது. மேற்கு மற்றும் பல முக்கிய ஆயுதக் குறைப்பு ஒப்பந்தங்களுக்கு வழி வகுத்தது, அவை பின்னர் கையெழுத்திடப்பட்டன. கோர்பச்சேவ் ஆட்சியின் போது, ​​மாஸ்கோவும் வாஷிங்டனும் தங்கள் இடைநிலை-தூர மரபுவழி மற்றும் அணுசக்தி ஏவுகணைகளை அகற்ற ஒப்புக்கொண்டன.",
        "1991 இல், சோவியத் ஒன்றியத்தின் கலைப்பை கோர்பச்சேவ் மேற்பார்வையிட்டார். அவரது கீழ் சோவியத் சமுதாயத்தின் பகுதி ஜனநாயகமயமாக்கல் முன்னாள் சோவியத் முகாமில் உள்ள பல நாடுகள் முகாமில் இருந்து விலக வழிவகுத்தது. கோர்பச்சேவ் ஒரு புதிய தொழிற்சங்க ஒப்பந்தத்தை உருவாக்க முயன்றார். எவ்வாறாயினும், புதிய தொழிற்சங்க உடன்படிக்கையில் கையொப்பமிடுவதைத் தடுக்க கடுமையான உயர் அதிகாரிகள் குழு ஆட்சிக் கவிழ்ப்பு மற்றும் அவரை அதிகாரத்திலிருந்து அகற்ற முயற்சித்தது.",
        "ஆட்சிக்கவிழ்ப்பு தோல்வியடைந்தது, ஆனால் சோவியத் ஒன்றியத்தின் கம்யூனிஸ்ட் கட்சியின் மத்தியக் குழுவை கலைத்து, கட்சியின் பொதுச் செயலாளர் பதவியை ராஜினாமா செய்ய கோர்பச்சேவைத் தூண்டியது.",
        "1991 ஆம் ஆண்டின் இறுதியில் கோர்பச்சேவ் பதவி விலகும் நேரத்தில், நேட்டோ-சோவியத் எல்லையானது இனி ஒரு ஃப்ளாஷ் பாயிண்ட் ஆக இருக்கவில்லை. நேட்டோ அனைவரையும் இழுத்தது, ஆனால் சில ஆயிரம் துருப்புக்கள் கிழக்குப் பக்கத்திலிருந்து பின்வாங்கியது, மற்றும் பனிப்போரின் பயங்கரங்கள் வரலாற்று புத்தகங்கள் மற்றும் அருங்காட்சியகங்களுக்கு அனுப்பப்பட்டது அத்துடன் கிழக்கு ஐரோப்பிய நாடுகளுக்கு சுயநிர்ணய உரிமையை வழங்குவதற்காகவும்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "மிகைல் கோர்பச்சேவ்",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "மாலை",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்த வருடம்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "மிகைல் கோர்பச்சேவ்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "முதலில்",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "சோவியத் ஒன்றியம்",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "கோர்பச்சேவ்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜூன்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "சமீபத்திய ஆண்டுகளில்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "மிகைல் கோர்பச்சேவ்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "1931",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரஷ்யா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "கோர்பச்சேவ்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "நாட்கள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "மாஸ்கோ பல்கலைக்கழகம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "மத்திய குழு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "கம்யூனிஸ்ட் கட்சி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "சோவியத் ஒன்றியம்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சோவியத் ஒன்றியம்",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ரஷ்யா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "கோர்பி",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சோவியத்",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "1988",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "கோர்பச்சேவ்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "விளாடிமிர் லெனின்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரஷ்யன்",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "கோர்பச்சேவ்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "சோவியத் ஒன்றியம்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "எங்களுக்கு",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "நேட்டோ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "மேற்கு",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "மார்க்சிஸ்ட்",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "கம்யூனிஸ்ட்",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரஷ்யா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "'பனிப்போர்'",
            "label": "EVENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "இரண்டு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆசிய",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆப்பிரிக்க",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "இரண்டு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "சோவியத்",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "கோர்பெச்சேவ்",
            "label": "PRODUCT"
          },
          {
            "text": "சோவியத் ஒன்றியம்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "பனிப்போர்",
            "label": "EVENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "மேற்கு",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "மாஸ்கோ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "வாஷிங்டன்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "கோர்பச்சேவ்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "மாஸ்கோ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "மாஸ்கோ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "கிழக்கு தொகுதி",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "சோவியத்",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "சோவியத் ஒன்றியம்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "கோர்பச்சேவ்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஜெர்மனி",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "கோர்பச்சேவ்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "'பெர்லின் சுவர்'",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜெர்மனி",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "மேற்கு ஜெர்மனி",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "கிழக்கு ஜெர்மனி",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "1986",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சோவியத்",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆப்கானிஸ்தான்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சோவியத் ஒன்றியத்தின்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆப்கானிஸ்தான்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சோவியத் ஒன்றியம்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "குறைந்தது 15,000",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "கோர்பச்சேவ்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "மாஸ்கோ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "மேற்கு",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "கோர்பச்சேவ்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "மாஸ்கோ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "வாஷிங்டன்",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "1991",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "கோர்பச்சேவ்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "சோவியத் ஒன்றியம்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சோவியத்",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "சோவியத்",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "கோர்பச்சேவ்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "கோர்பச்சேவ்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "மத்திய குழு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "கம்யூனிஸ்ட் கட்சி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "சோவியத் ஒன்றியம்",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "கோர்பச்சேவ்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "1991 இன் இறுதியில்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "நேட்டோ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "நேட்டோ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "சில ஆயிரம்",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "பனிப்போர்",
            "label": "EVENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "மிகைல் கோர்பெச்சேவ்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜெர்மனி",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "பனிப்போர்",
            "label": "EVENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "கிழக்கு ஐரோப்பிய",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}