{
  "newspaper_id": "lankadeepa-lk",
  "url": "https://www.lankadeepa.lk/news/විමල්ගේ-නායකත්වයෙන්-නව-සන්ධානය-පිහිටුවීම-හතර/101-618374",
  "time_ut": 1660874874,
  "original_lang": "si",
  "original_title": "විමල්ගේ නායකත්වයෙන් නව සන්ධානය පිහිටුවීම හතර",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "The formation of the new alliance under the leadership of Vimal",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "The Independent Party Union says that a new political alliance led by Mr. Wimal Weerawansa will be formed on the 4th of next month.",
        "Mr. Vasudeva Nanayakkara, the leader of the Democratic Left Front, said that the name of the new political alliance will also be announced on that day.",
        "Several rounds of discussions regarding the new alliance to be unveiled at the National Youth Service Council premises were held in recent days with the participation of representatives of the Independent Party Union."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Vimal",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "The Independent Party Union",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Wimal Weerawansa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the 4th of next month",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Vasudeva Nanayakkara",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Democratic Left Front",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "that day",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the National Youth Service Council",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "recent days",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Independent Party Union",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "විමල්ගේ නායකත්වයෙන් නව සන්ධානය පිහිටුවීම හතර",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "විමල් වීරවංශ මහතාගේ නායකත්වයෙන් යුතු නව දේශපාලන සන්ධානයක් ලබන මස 4 වෙනිදා පිහිටුවන බව ස්වාධීන පක්ෂ එකමුතුව පවසයි.",
        "නව දේශපාලන සන්ධානයේ නමද එදින ප්‍රකාශයට පත්කරන බව ප්‍රජාතන්ත්‍රවාදී වාමාංශික පෙරමුණේ නායක පාර්ලිමේන්තු මන්ත්‍රී වාසුදේව නානායක්කාර මහතා පැවසීය.",
        "ජාතික තරුණ සේවා සභා පරිශ්‍රයේදී එළිදැක්වීමට නියමිත නව සන්ධානය සම්බන්ධයෙන්වූ සාකච්ඡා වට කිහිපයක් ස්වාධීන පක්ෂ එකමුතුවේ නියෝජිතයන්ගේ සහභාගීත්වයෙන් පසුගිය දිනවල පැවැත්විණ."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "විමල්",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "නිදහස් පක්ෂ සංගමය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "විමල් වීරවංශ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ලබන මස 4 වැනිදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "වාසුදේව නානායක්කාර",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ප්‍රජාතන්ත්‍රවාදී වාම පෙරමුණ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "එදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ජාතික තරුණ සේවා සභාව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "මෑත දින",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "නිදහස් පක්ෂ සංගමය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "விமல் தலைமையில் புதிய கூட்டணி உருவானது",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "திரு.விமல் வீரவன்ச தலைமையில் புதிய அரசியல் கூட்டணி அடுத்த மாதம் 4ஆம் திகதி உருவாக்கப்படும் என சுதந்திரக் கட்சி ஒன்றியம் தெரிவித்துள்ளது.",
        "புதிய அரசியல் கூட்டணியின் பெயரும் அன்றைய தினம் அறிவிக்கப்படும் என ஜனநாயக இடதுசாரி முன்னணியின் தலைவர் திரு.வாசுதேவ நாணயக்கார தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "தேசிய இளைஞர் சேவை மன்ற வளாகத்தில் வெளியிடப்படவுள்ள புதிய கூட்டணி தொடர்பான பல சுற்றுக் கலந்துரையாடல்கள் கடந்த சில நாட்களாக சுதந்திரக் கட்சி ஒன்றியப் பிரதிநிதிகளின் பங்குபற்றலுடன் இடம்பெற்றன."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "விமல்",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "சுதந்திரக் கட்சி ஒன்றியம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "விமல் வீரவன்ச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "அடுத்த மாதம் 4ம் தேதி",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "வாசுதேவ நாணயக்கார",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜனநாயக இடது முன்னணி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "அந்த நாள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "தேசிய இளைஞர் சேவை கவுன்சில்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "சமீபத்திய நாட்கள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சுதந்திரக் கட்சி ஒன்றியம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}