{
  "newspaper_id": "virakesari-lk",
  "url": "http://www.virakesari.lk/article/132496",
  "time_ut": 1659091665,
  "original_lang": "ta",
  "original_title": "இலங்கையின் பொருளாதார நெருக்கடி தொடர்பில் அரச தலைவர்களுடன் பிலிப்பைன்ஸில் கலந்துரையாடவுள்ளார் மைத்திரி",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Maithiri will discuss Sri Lanka's economic crisis with the heads of state in the Philippines",
      "author": "Vishnu",
      "body_lines": [
        "Former President Maithripala Sirisena has gone to the Philippines to attend the 'International Leadership Conference - 2022', where he will discuss Sri Lanka's economic crisis during a meeting with the heads of state of other countries.",
        "Former President Maithripala Sirisena is in the Philippines to attend the 'International Leadership Conference 2022' in Manila, Philippines.",
        "He left the country early on the 29th of Friday through a Singapore Airlines flight.",
        "The 'International Leadership Conference 2022' will be held on 30th and 31st. About 28 countries will be represented in this conference, including heads of state and members of parliament.",
        "It is considered a rare opportunity for Sri Lanka that Sri Lanka's sixth Executive President Maithripala Sirisena has been given the opportunity to deliver the opening speech at this conference in which many major countries are participating.",
        "Former President Maithripala Sirisena has said that he is looking forward to meeting many foreign leaders at this international conference in which important world leaders will participate.",
        "Former President Maithripala Sirisena has mentioned that he will focus on the support available from abroad for the current economic crisis in Sri Lanka."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Sri Lanka's",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "Philippines",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Maithripala Sirisena",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Philippines",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the 'International Leadership Conference - 2022'",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka's",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Maithripala Sirisena",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Philippines",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the 'International Leadership Conference 2022'",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "Manila",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Philippines",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the 29th of Friday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Singapore Airlines",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "The 'International Leadership Conference 2022'",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "30th and 31st",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "About 28",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka's",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "sixth",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Maithripala Sirisena",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Maithripala Sirisena",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Maithripala Sirisena",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "මෛත්‍රී ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ ආර්ථික අර්බුදය පිලිපීනයේ රාජ්‍ය නායකයන් සමඟ සාකච්ඡා කරනු ඇත",
      "author": "විෂ්ණු",
      "body_lines": [
        "හිටපු ජනාධිපති මෛත්‍රීපාල සිරිසේන මහතා පිලිපීනයට ගොස් ඇත්තේ 'ජාත්‍යන්තර නායකත්ව සමුළුව - 2022' සඳහා සහභාගී වීම සඳහා වන අතර එහිදී ඔහු අනෙකුත් රටවල රාජ්‍ය නායකයින් සමඟ පැවැත්වෙන සාකච්ඡාවකදී ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ ආර්ථික අර්බුදය පිළිබඳව සාකච්ඡා කරනු ඇත.",
        "පිලිපීනයේ මැනිලා නුවර පැවැත්වෙන 2022 ජාත්‍යන්තර නායකත්ව සමුළුවට සහභාගී වීම සඳහා හිටපු ජනාධිපති මෛත්‍රීපාල සිරිසේන මහතා පිලිපීනයට පැමිණ සිටියි.",
        "ඔහු සිංගප්පූරු ගුවන් සේවයට අයත් ගුවන් යානයකින් 29 සිකුරාදා අලුයම රටින් පිටත් විය.",
        "‘ජාත්‍යන්තර නායකත්ව සමුළුව 2022’ ලබන 30 සහ 31 යන දෙදින තුළ පැවැත්වේ. මෙම සමුළුව සඳහා රාජ්‍ය නායකයින් සහ පාර්ලිමේන්තු මන්ත්‍රීවරුන් ඇතුළු රටවල් 28ක් පමණ නියෝජනය වේ.",
        "ප්‍රධාන රටවල් රැසක් සහභාගී වන මෙම සමුළුවේ සමාරම්භක දේශනය පැවැත්වීමට ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ හයවන විධායක ජනාධිපති මෛත්‍රීපාල සිරිසේන මහතාට අවස්ථාව හිමිවීම ශ්‍රී ලංකාවට ලැබුණු දුර්ලභ අවස්ථාවක් ලෙස සැලකේ.",
        "ලෝකයේ වැදගත් රාජ්‍ය නායකයින් සහභාගී වන මෙම ජාත්‍යන්තර සමුළුවේදී විදෙස් නායකයින් රැසක් හමුවීමට අපේක්ෂාවෙන් පසුවන බව හිටපු ජනාධිපති මෛත්‍රීපාල සිරිසේන මහතා පැවසීය.",
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ වත්මන් ආර්ථික අර්බුදය සඳහා විදේශයන්ගෙන් ලැබෙන සහයෝගය පිළිබඳව අවධානය යොමු කරන බව හිටපු ජනාධිපති මෛත්‍රීපාල සිරිසේන මහතා සඳහන් කරයි."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "පිලිපීනය",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "මෛත්‍රීපාල සිරිසේන",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "පිලිපීනය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "'ජාත්‍යන්තර නායකත්ව සමුළුව - 2022'",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "මෛත්‍රීපාල සිරිසේන",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "පිලිපීනය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "'ජාත්‍යන්තර නායකත්ව සමුළුව 2022'",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "මැනිලා",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "පිලිපීනය",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "29 සිකුරාදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "සිංගප්පූරු ගුවන් සේවය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "'ජාත්‍යන්තර නායකත්ව සමුළුව 2022'",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "30 සහ 31",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "28 ක් පමණ",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "හය වන",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "මෛත්‍රීපාල සිරිසේන",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "මෛත්‍රීපාල සිරිසේන",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "මෛත්‍රීපාල සිරිසේන",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "இலங்கையின் பொருளாதார நெருக்கடி தொடர்பில் அரச தலைவர்களுடன் பிலிப்பைன்ஸில் கலந்துரையாடவுள்ளார் மைத்திரி",
      "author": "Vishnu",
      "body_lines": [
        "'சர்வதேச தலைமைத்துவ மாநாடு - 2022' இல் கலந்து கொள்வதற்காக பிலிப்பைன்ஸ் சென்றுள்ள முன்னாள் ஜனாதிபதி மைத்திரிபால சிறிசேன , அங்கு ஏனைய நாடுகளின் அரச தலைவர்களுடனான சந்திப்பின் போது இலங்கையின் பொருளாதார நெருக்கடிகள் தொடர்பில் கலந்துரையாடவுள்ளார்.",
        "பிலிப்பைன்ஸின் மனிலா நகரில் இடம்பெறும் 'சர்வதேச தலைமைத்துவ மாநாடு 2022' இல் கலந்து கொள்வதற்காக முன்னாள் ஜனாதிபதி மைத்திரிபால சிறிசேன பிலிப்பைன்ஸ் சென்றுள்ளார்.",
        "சிங்கப்பூர் விமான சேவையொன்றின் ஊடாக அவர் 29 ஆம் திகதி வெள்ளிக்கிழமை அதிகாலை நாட்டிலிருந்து புறப்பட்டுச் சென்றார்.",
        "30, 31 ஆம் திகதிகளில் 'சர்வதேச தலைமைத்துவ மாநாடு 2022' இடம்பெறவுள்ளது. இம்மாநாட்டில் சுமார் 28 நாடுகளை பிரதிநிதித்துவப்படுத்தி அரச தலைவர்கள் , பாராளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர்கள் உள்ளிட்ட முக்கியஸ்தர்கள் கலந்து கொள்ளவுள்ளனர்.",
        "பல முக்கிய நாடுகள் பங்கேற்கும் இந்த மாநாட்டில் ஆரம்ப உரையை ஆற்றுவதற்கு இலங்கையின் ஆறாவது நிறைவேற்று ஜனாதிபதி மைத்திரிபால சிறிசேனவிற்கு வாய்ப்பளிக்கப்பட்டுள்ளமை இலங்கைக்கு கிடைத்த அரிய வாய்ப்பாக கருதப்படுகிறது.",
        "உலக நாடுகளின் முக்கிய தலைவர்கள் பங்கேற்கும் இந்த சர்வதேச மாநாட்டில் பல வெளிநாட்டு தலைவர்களை சந்திக்க எதிர்பார்த்துள்ளதாக முன்னாள் ஜனாதிபதி மைத்திரிபால சிறிசேன தெரிவித்துள்ளார்.",
        "இலங்கையில் தற்போது நிலவும் பொருளாதார நெருக்கடிக்கு வெளிநாடுகளில் இருந்து கிடைக்கக்கூடிய ஆதரவு குறித்து இதன் போது கவனம் செலுத்தவுள்ளதாக முன்னாள் ஜனாதிபதி மைத்திரிபால சிறிசேன குறிப்பிட்டுள்ளார்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "இலங்கையின்",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "பிலிப்பைன்ஸ்",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "மைத்திரிபால சிறிசேன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "பிலிப்பைன்ஸ்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "'சர்வதேச தலைமைத்துவ மாநாடு - 2022'",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கையின்",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "மைத்திரிபால சிறிசேன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "பிலிப்பைன்ஸ்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "'சர்வதேச தலைமைத்துவ மாநாடு 2022'",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "மணிலா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "பிலிப்பைன்ஸ்",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "29 வெள்ளிக்கிழமை",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சிங்கப்பூர் ஏர்லைன்ஸ்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "'சர்வதேச தலைமைத்துவ மாநாடு 2022'",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "30 மற்றும் 31",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சுமார் 28",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கையின்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆறாவது",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "மைத்திரிபால சிறிசேன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "மைத்திரிபால சிறிசேன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "மைத்திரிபால சிறிசேன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}