{
  "newspaper_id": "lankadeepa-lk",
  "url": "https://www.lankadeepa.lk/news/බ්‍රිතාන්‍ය-අගමැති-ජොන්සන්-ඉල්ලා-අස්වෙයි/101-615999",
  "time_ut": 1657185160,
  "original_lang": "si",
  "original_title": "බ්‍රිතාන්‍ය අගමැති ජොන්සන් ඉල්ලා අස්වෙයි",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "British Prime Minister Johnson resigns",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "British Prime Minister Boris Johnson, who continued to say that he would not be influenced by anyone, resigned from the leadership of the Conservative Party and the position of Prime Minister.",
        "The Prime Minister was under pressure from his cabinet members as well as the Attorney General to resign.",
        "Johnson has been accused of violating health laws during the lockdown and giving a top government post to party member Chris Pincher, who was accused of sexually harassing women. That is why he was pressured to resign."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "British",
          "label": "NORP"
        },
        {
          "text": "Johnson",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "British",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Boris Johnson",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Conservative Party",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "Johnson",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Chris Pincher",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "බ්‍රිතාන්‍ය අගමැති ජොන්සන් ඉල්ලා අස්වෙයි",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "කිසිවෙකුගේ බලපෑමට ඉල්ලා අසනොවන බව දිගින් දිගටම පැවසූ බ්‍රිතාන්‍ය අග්‍රාමාත්‍ය බොරිස් ජොන්සන්, කොන්සර්වටිව් පක්ෂ නායකත්වයෙන් සහ අග්‍රාමාත්‍ය ධුරයෙන්ද ඉල්ලා අස්විය.",
        "අග්‍රාමාත්‍යවරයාට ධුරයෙන් ඉවත් වන්නැයි ඔහුගේ කැබිනට් මණ්ඩල සාමාජිකයන්ගෙන් මෙන්ම නීතිපති වරයාගෙන්ද බලපෑම් එල්ල වී තිබුණි.",
        "ලොක් ඩවුන් සමයේ සෞඛ්‍ය නීති උල්ලංඝනය කිරීම සහ කාන්තාවන්ට ලිංගික හිරිහැර කළේ යැයි චෝදනා එල්ල වූ පක්ෂ සාමාජික ක්‍රිස් පින්චර්ට රජයේ ඉහළ තනතුරක් දීම ජොන්සන්ට එල්ල වී ඇති චෝදනාය.ඔහුට ධුරයෙන් ඉවත් වන්නැයි බලපෑම් එල්ල වූයේ ඒ නිසාය."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "බ්රිතාන්ය",
          "label": "NORP"
        },
        {
          "text": "ජොන්සන්",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "බ්රිතාන්ය",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "බොරිස් ජොන්සන්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "කොන්සර්වේටිව් පක්ෂය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "ජොන්සන්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ක්රිස් පින්චර්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "பிரிட்டிஷ் பிரதமர் ஜான்சன் ராஜினாமா செய்தார்",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "எவராலும் தமக்கு செல்வாக்கு இல்லை என தொடர்ந்து தெரிவித்த பிரித்தானிய பிரதமர் போரிஸ் ஜோன்சன், கன்சர்வேட்டிவ் கட்சியின் தலைமைப் பதவியிலிருந்தும், பிரதமர் பதவியிலிருந்தும் விலகினார்.",
        "பிரதமருக்கு அவரது அமைச்சரவை உறுப்பினர்கள் மற்றும் சட்டமா அதிபர் பதவி விலகுமாறு அழுத்தம் கொடுக்கப்பட்டது.",
        "பூட்டுதலின் போது சுகாதாரச் சட்டங்களை மீறியதாக ஜான்சன் மீது குற்றம் சாட்டப்பட்டுள்ளது, மேலும் பெண்களை பாலியல் ரீதியாக துன்புறுத்தியதாக குற்றம் சாட்டப்பட்ட கட்சி உறுப்பினர் கிறிஸ் பிஞ்சருக்கு உயர் அரசாங்க பதவியை வழங்கியதாக குற்றம் சாட்டப்பட்டது."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "பிரிட்டிஷ்",
          "label": "NORP"
        },
        {
          "text": "ஜான்சன்",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "பிரிட்டிஷ்",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "போரிஸ் ஜான்சன்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "கன்சர்வேடிவ் கட்சி",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஜான்சன்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "கிறிஸ் பின்சர்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}