{
  "newspaper_id": "economy-next-com",
  "url": "https://economynext.com/crisis-hit-sri-lanka-lifts-ban-on-qatar-charity-as-it-tries-to-secure-fuel-supply-from-doha-96705/",
  "time_ut": 1656585360,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Crisis-hit Sri Lanka lifts ban on Qatar Charity as it tries to secure fuel supply from Doha",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Crisis-hit Sri Lanka lifts ban on Qatar Charity as it tries to secure fuel supply from Doha",
      "author": "Shihar Aneez",
      "body_lines": [
        "ECONOMYNEXT – Sri Lanka has lifted a ban on Qatar Charity, a top minister said, months after the government froze the charity’s accounts accusing it of funding Islamic terrorism together with a prominent lawyer",
        "A former police minister and a close ally of President Gotabaya Rajapaksa Sarath Weerasekara told parliament on January 07 2021 that the ringleader of the Easter Sunday suicide bombers Zaharan Hashim had conducted lectures in an organisation maintained by Sri Lankan lawyer Hejaz Hisbullah. The organisation, named ‘Pearl of Unity’, and its local branc was funded by Qatar Charity which Weerasekara claimed was banned by the United Nations.",
        "The Criminal Investigation Department (CID) subsequently froze the accounts of Qatar Charity in Sri Lanka.",
        "The move, along with President Rajapaksa’s flat refusal to honour Qatar’s request through the Organisation of Islamic Countries (OIC) to stop cremating Sri Lanka’s minority Muslims who died of COVID-19, soured the Middle Eastern nation’s relations with Sri Lanka.",
        "Power and Energy Minister Kanchana Wijesekera who led a delegation to discuss possibilities of securing a fuel credit line to Sri Lanka said he met Qatar Charity officials in Doha on June 29.",
        "“Met the Officials of the Qatar Charity yesterday. Conveyed the message that the Defense Ministry has informed the Attorney General its decision to lift the ban on the fund which was imposed in 2019,” Wijesekera tweeted.",
        "He also discussed the Charity’s work in Sri Lanka and globally.",
        "Wijesekera’s statement on lifting the ban comes at a time Sri Lanka is gradually coming to a standstill as it does not have any fuel imports until mid next month. Wijesekera on Sunday June 26 before leaving to Qatar told reporters that he was exploring possibilities of importing fuel from the oil-rich country.",
        "During his visit, Wijesekera met Saad Sherida Al-Kaabi, the Qatar Minister of State for Energy Affairs and the President and CEO of Qatar Energy, and discussed the supply of petroleum products, liquid petroleum (LP) gas and liquefied natural gas (LNG) to Sri Lanka to overcome the energy crisis with the assistance of Qatar Energy and the Qatar Development Fund.",
        "The minister also met Deputy Director General of the Qatar Fund for Development and said that he “discussed a possible credit line facility for petroleum and gas supply” and was “informed that funds has been allocated for medical supplies and will consider the request for a credit facility [and] support the IMF program”.",
        "Despite many leaders of the ruling Sri Lanka Podujana Peremuna (SLPP) approaching Middle Eastern countries for fuel, President Rajapaksa administration has hardly got a positive response, government officials told EconomyNext.",
        "The legal case involved with Qatar Charity saw the arrest of Hejaz Hisbullah Hisbullah by the CID on April 14, 2020, who was placed under a detention order by President Rajapaksa, under the Prevention of Terrorism Act (PTA) for allegedly “aiding and abetting” the Easter Sunday bombers and for engaging in activities deemed “detrimental to religious harmony among communities.”",
        "He was detained for a long time without being charged. However, amid mounting international pressure, the government charged him before a court released him on bail early this year.",
        "Qatar is one of the top foreign employment providers for Sri Lanka along with the United Arab Emirates.",
        "Sri Lankan diplomats in the Middle East have told EconomyNext that the governments there do not give as much priority to Sri Lankan issues as they did before the island nation’s political leaders’ action soured diplomatic relations. (Colombo/Jun30/2022)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Sri Lanka",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "Qatar Charity",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "Doha",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Qatar Charity",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "months",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Islamic",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Gotabaya Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Weerasekara",
            "label": "PRODUCT"
          },
          {
            "text": "January 07 2021",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Easter",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sunday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Zaharan Hashim",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lankan",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Hejaz Hisbullah",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Qatar",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Weerasekara",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the United Nations",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "The Criminal Investigation Department",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "CID",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Qatar Charity",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Qatar",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Organisation of Islamic Countries",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "OIC",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka’s",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Muslims",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "COVID-19",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Middle Eastern",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Kanchana Wijesekera",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Qatar Charity",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Doha",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "June 29",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "yesterday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Defense Ministry",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "2019",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Charity",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Wijesekera",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "mid next month",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sunday June 26",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Qatar",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Wijesekera",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Saad Sherida Al-Kaabi",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Qatar",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "State for Energy Affairs",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Qatar Energy",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "LNG",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Qatar Energy",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Qatar Development Fund",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the Qatar Fund for Development",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "IMF",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka Podujana Peremuna",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Middle Eastern",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "EconomyNext",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Qatar",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Hejaz Hisbullah Hisbullah",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "CID",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "April 14, 2020",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Prevention of Terrorism Act",
            "label": "LAW"
          },
          {
            "text": "Easter",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sunday",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "early this year",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Qatar",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the United Arab Emirates",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lankan",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Middle East",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lankan",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Colombo/Jun30/2022",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "අර්බුදකාරී ශ්‍රී ලංකාව කටාර් පුණ්‍යායතනයේ තහනම ඉවත් කරයි, එය දෝහා වෙතින් ඉන්ධන සැපයීම සුරක්ෂිත කිරීමට උත්සාහ කරයි",
      "author": "ශිහාර් අනීස්",
      "body_lines": [
        "ECONOMYNEXT - ශ්‍රී ලංකාව කටාර් පුණ්‍යායතනය සඳහා පනවා තිබූ තහනම ඉවත් කර ඇති බව ප්‍රමුඛ අමාත්‍යවරයෙක් ප්‍රකාශ කළේ, ප්‍රමුඛ නීතිඥයෙකු සමඟ එක්ව ඉස්ලාමීය ත්‍රස්තවාදයට අරමුදල් සපයන බවට චෝදනා කරමින් රජය පුණ්‍යායතනයේ ගිණුම් අත්හිටුවා මාස කිහිපයකට පසුවය.",
        "පාස්කු ඉරිදා මරාගෙන මැරෙන බෝම්බකරුවන්ගේ ප්‍රධානියා සහරාන් හෂීම් දේශන පවත්වා ඇත්තේ ශ්‍රී ලංකා නීතීඥ හෙජාස් හිස්බුල්ලා විසින් පවත්වාගෙන යනු ලබන සංවිධානයක බව හිටපු පොලිස් ඇමතිවරයෙකු සහ ජනාධිපති ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂගේ සමීපතම සගයෙකු වන සරත් වීරසේකර 2021 ජනවාරි 07 දින පාර්ලිමේන්තුවට පැවසීය. ‘පර්ල් ඔෆ් යුනිටි’ නම් වූ සංවිධානය සහ එහි දේශීය ශාඛාව සඳහා අරමුදල් සපයන ලද්දේ කටාර් පුණ්‍යායතනය විසිනි, එය එක්සත් ජාතීන්ගේ සංවිධානය විසින් තහනම් කරන ලද බව වීරසේකර ප්‍රකාශ කළේය.",
        "අපරාධ පරීක්ෂණ දෙපාර්තමේන්තුව (CID) පසුව කටාර් පුණ්‍යායතනයේ ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ ගිණුම් අත්හිටුවන ලදී.",
        "COVID-19 හේතුවෙන් මියගිය ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ සුළුතර මුස්ලිම්වරුන් ආදාහනය කිරීම නතර කරන ලෙස ඉස්ලාමීය රටවල සංවිධානය (OIC) හරහා කටාර් රාජ්‍යයේ ඉල්ලීමට ගරු කිරීම ජනාධිපති රාජපක්ෂගේ පැතලි ප්‍රතික්ෂේප කිරීමත් සමඟ මැදපෙරදිග ජාතියේ ශ්‍රී ලංකාව සමඟ සබඳතා පළුදු විය.",
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවට ඉන්ධන ණය මාර්ගයක් ලබා ගැනීමේ හැකියාව පිළිබඳව සාකච්ඡා කිරීමට නියෝජිත පිරිසකට නායකත්වය දුන් විදුලිබල හා බලශක්ති අමාත්‍ය කංචන විජේසේකර ජුනි 29 වැනිදා දෝහාහිදී කටාර් පුණ්‍යායතන නිලධාරීන් හමුවූ බව පැවසීය.",
        "“ඊයේ කටාර් පුණ්‍යායතනයේ නිලධාරීන් හමුවුණා. 2019 වසරේ පනවා තිබූ අරමුදලට පනවා තිබූ තහනම ඉවත් කිරීමට ගත් තීරණය ආරක්ෂක අමාත්‍යාංශය විසින් නීතිපතිවරයාට දන්වා ඇති බවට පණිවිඩයක් ලබා දුන්නා,” විජේසේකර ට්විටර් පණිවුඩයක් නිකුත් කරමින් කියා සිටියේය.",
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ සහ ගෝලීය වශයෙන් පුණ්‍යායතනයේ කටයුතු පිළිබඳව ද ඔහු සාකච්ඡා කළේය.",
        "තහනම ඉවත් කිරීම පිළිබඳ විජේසේකරගේ ප්‍රකාශය පැමිණෙන්නේ ලබන මස මැද වන තෙක් ශ්‍රී ලංකාව කිසිදු ඉන්ධන ආනයනයක් නොමැති බැවින් ක්‍රමයෙන් ඇණහිට ඇති අවස්ථාවක ය. විජේසේකර ජූනි 26 ඉරිදා කටාරයට යාමට පෙර වාර්තාකරුවන්ට පැවසුවේ තෙල්වලින් පොහොසත් රටෙන් ඉන්ධන ආනයනය කිරීමේ හැකියාව සොයා බලන බවයි.",
        "විජේසේකර සිය සංචාරයේදී කටාර් බලශක්ති කටයුතු පිළිබඳ රාජ්‍ය අමාත්‍ය Saad Sherida Al-Kaabi හමුවී කටාර් බලශක්තියේ සභාපති සහ ප්‍රධාන විධායක නිලධාරිනිය හමුවී ඛනිජ තෙල් නිෂ්පාදන, ද්‍රව පෙට්‍රෝලියම් (LP) ගෑස් සහ ද්‍රව ස්වභාවික වායු (LNG) සැපයීම පිළිබඳව සාකච්ඡා කළේය. කටාර් බලශක්ති සහ කටාර් සංවර්ධන අරමුදලේ සහාය ඇතිව බලශක්ති අර්බුදයෙන් මිදීමට ශ්‍රී ලංකාවට.",
        "අමාත්‍යවරයා සංවර්ධනය සඳහා කටාර් අරමුදලේ නියෝජ්‍ය අධ්‍යක්ෂ ජනරාල්වරයා ද හමුවී “ඛනිජ තෙල් සහ ගෑස් සැපයීම සඳහා හැකි ණය පහසුකම් පිළිබඳව සාකච්ඡා කළ” බවත්, “වෛද්‍ය සැපයුම් සඳහා මුදල් වෙන් කර ඇති බවත්, ණයක් සඳහා වන ඉල්ලීම සලකා බලන බවත් දන්වා ඇති බවත්” පැවසීය. පහසුකම [සහ] IMF වැඩසටහනට සහාය වන්න”.",
        "පාලක ශ්‍රී ලංකා පොදුජන පෙරමුණේ (SLPP) බොහෝ නායකයින් ඉන්ධන සඳහා මැදපෙරදිග රටවල් වෙත යොමු වුවද, ජනාධිපති රාජපක්ෂ පාලනයට යහපත් ප්‍රතිචාරයක් ලැබී නොමැති බව රජයේ නිලධාරීන් EconomyNext වෙත පැවසීය.",
        "කටාර් පුණ්‍යායතනයට සම්බන්ධ නීතිමය නඩුවේදී 2020 අප්‍රේල් 14 වන දින CID විසින් හෙජාස් හිස්බුල්ලා හිස්බුල්ලා අත්අඩංගුවට ගනු ලැබූ අතර, ඔහු \"උදව් සහ අනුබල දීම\" යන චෝදනාව යටතේ ත්‍රස්තවාදය වැළැක්වීමේ පනත (PTA) යටතේ ජනාධිපති රාජපක්ෂ විසින් රැඳවුම් නියෝග යටතේ තබා ඇත. පාස්කු ඉරිදා බෝම්බ ප්‍රහාර එල්ල කිරීම සහ \"ප්‍රජාවන් අතර ආගමික සහජීවනයට හානිදායක\" ලෙස සැලකෙන ක්‍රියාකාරකම්වල නිරත වීම හේතුවෙන්.",
        "ඔහුට චෝදනා එල්ල නොවී දීර්ඝ කාලයක් රඳවා තබාගෙන සිටියේය. කෙසේ වෙතත්, වැඩෙන ජාත්‍යන්තර බලපෑම් මධ්‍යයේ, උසාවියකින් ඔහු මේ වසර මුලදී ඇප මත මුදා හැරීමට පෙර රජය ඔහුට චෝදනා කළේය.",
        "කටාර් යනු එක්සත් අරාබි එමීර් රාජ්‍යය සමඟින් ශ්‍රී ලංකාව සඳහා ප්‍රමුඛතම විදේශ රැකියා සපයන්නන්ගෙන් එකකි.",
        "මැදපෙරදිග සිටින ශ්‍රී ලංකා රාජ්‍ය තාන්ත්‍රිකයින් EconomyNext වෙත පවසා ඇත්තේ දිවයිනේ දේශපාලන නායකයින්ගේ ක්‍රියාව රාජ්‍ය තාන්ත්‍රික සබඳතා පළුදු වීමට පෙර එහි රජයන් ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ ප්‍රශ්නවලට තරම් ප්‍රමුඛතාවයක් ලබා නොදෙන බවයි. (කොළඹ/ජුනි30/2022)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "කටාර් පුණ්‍යායතනය",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "දෝහා",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "කටාර් පුණ්‍යායතනය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "මාස",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉස්ලාමීය",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "වීරසේකර",
            "label": "PRODUCT"
          },
          {
            "text": "2021 ජනවාරි 07",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාස්කු",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉරිදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "සහරාන් හෂීම්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලාංකික",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "හෙජාස් හිස්බුල්ලා",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "කටාර්",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "වීරසේකර",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "එක්සත් ජාතීන්ගේ",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "අපරාධ පරීක්ෂණ දෙපාර්තමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "CID",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "කටාර් පුණ්‍යායතනය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "කටාර්",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉස්ලාමීය රටවල සංවිධානය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ස්ථානාධිපති",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මුස්ලිම්",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "COVID-19",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "මැද පෙරදිග",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "කාංචන විජේසේකර",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "කටාර් පුණ්‍යායතනය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "දෝහා",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජූනි 29",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ඊයේ",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ආරක්ෂක අමාත්යාංශය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "2019",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "පුණ්යායතනය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "විජේසේකර",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ලබන මාසයේ මැද",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජුනි 26 ඉරිදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "කටාර්",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "විජේසේකර",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Saad Sherida Al-Kaabi",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "කටාර්",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "බලශක්ති කටයුතු සඳහා රාජ්ය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "කටාර් බලශක්ති",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "එල්එන්ජී",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "කටාර් බලශක්ති",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "කටාර් සංවර්ධන අරමුදල",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "සංවර්ධනය සඳහා කටාර් අරමුදල",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "IMF",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකා පොදුජන පෙරමුණ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "මැද පෙරදිග",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "EconomyNext",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "කටාර්",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "හිජාස් හිස්බුල්ලා හිස්බුල්ලා",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "CID",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "2020 අප්‍රේල් 14",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ත්‍රස්තවාදය වැළැක්වීමේ පනත",
            "label": "LAW"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාස්කු",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉරිදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "මේ වසරේ මුල",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "කටාර්",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "එක්සත් අරාබි එමීර් රාජ්‍යය",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලාංකික",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "මැද පෙරදිග",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලාංකික",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "කොළඹ/ජුනි30/2022",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "நெருக்கடியால் பாதிக்கப்பட்டுள்ள இலங்கை, தோஹாவில் இருந்து எரிபொருள் விநியோகத்தை பாதுகாக்க முயற்சிக்கும் கத்தார் அறக்கட்டளை மீதான தடையை நீக்கியது",
      "author": "ஷிஹார் அனீஸ்",
      "body_lines": [
        "பொருளாதாரம் - கத்தார் அறக்கட்டளை மீதான தடையை இலங்கை நீக்கியுள்ளது, ஒரு முக்கிய சட்டத்தரணியுடன் சேர்ந்து இஸ்லாமிய பயங்கரவாதத்திற்கு நிதியுதவி செய்ததாக குற்றம் சாட்டி அறக்கட்டளையின் கணக்குகளை அரசாங்கம் முடக்கிய சில மாதங்களுக்குப் பிறகு, உயர்மட்ட அமைச்சர் ஒருவர் கூறினார்.",
        "முன்னாள் பொலிஸ் அமைச்சரும் ஜனாதிபதி கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்சவின் நெருங்கிய கூட்டாளியுமான சரத் வீரசேகர ஜனவரி 07 2021 அன்று பாராளுமன்றத்தில் ஈஸ்டர் ஞாயிறு தற்கொலை குண்டுதாரிகளின் தலைவன் சஹாரான் ஹாசிம் இலங்கை சட்டத்தரணி ஹெஜாஸ் ஹிஸ்புல்லாவால் பராமரிக்கப்படும் அமைப்பில் விரிவுரைகளை நடத்தியதாக தெரிவித்தார். ‘பேர்ல் ஆஃப் யூனிட்டி’ என்று பெயரிடப்பட்ட இந்த அமைப்பு மற்றும் அதன் உள்ளூர் கிளை கத்தார் தொண்டு நிறுவனத்தால் நிதியளிக்கப்பட்டது, இது ஐக்கிய நாடுகள் சபையால் தடைசெய்யப்பட்டதாக வீரசேகர கூறியது.",
        "இதையடுத்து இலங்கையில் உள்ள கத்தார் தொண்டு நிறுவனத்தின் கணக்குகளை குற்றப் புலனாய்வுத் துறை (சிஐடி) முடக்கியது.",
        "COVID-19 நோயால் இறந்த இலங்கையின் சிறுபான்மை முஸ்லிம்களை தகனம் செய்வதை நிறுத்துமாறு இஸ்லாமிய நாடுகளின் அமைப்பு (OIC) மூலம் கத்தாரின் கோரிக்கையை நிறைவேற்ற ஜனாதிபதி ராஜபக்ஷ மறுத்த இந்த நடவடிக்கை, இலங்கையுடனான மத்திய கிழக்கு தேசத்தின் உறவுகளை மோசமாக்கியது.",
        "இலங்கைக்கான எரிபொருள் கடனைப் பெறுவதற்கான சாத்தியக்கூறுகள் குறித்து கலந்துரையாடுவதற்காக ஒரு தூதுக்குழுவை வழிநடத்திய மின்சக்தி மற்றும் எரிசக்தி அமைச்சர் காஞ்சன விஜேசேகர, ஜூன் 29 அன்று தோஹாவில் கட்டார் தொண்டு நிறுவன அதிகாரிகளை சந்தித்ததாக தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "“கத்தார் தொண்டு நிறுவன அதிகாரிகளை நேற்று சந்தித்தேன். 2019 ஆம் ஆண்டு விதிக்கப்பட்ட நிதியின் மீதான தடையை நீக்குவதற்கான தனது முடிவை பாதுகாப்பு அமைச்சு சட்டமா அதிபருக்கு அறிவித்துள்ளதாக செய்தி வெளியிட்டுள்ளது,” என விஜேசேகர ட்வீட் செய்துள்ளார்.",
        "இலங்கையிலும் உலகளாவிய ரீதியிலும் தொண்டு நிறுவனத்தின் பணிகள் குறித்தும் கலந்துரையாடினார்.",
        "அடுத்த மாத நடுப்பகுதி வரை இலங்கையில் எரிபொருள் இறக்குமதி இல்லை என்பதால், இலங்கை படிப்படியாக ஸ்தம்பித்து வரும் வேளையில், தடையை நீக்குவது குறித்து விஜேசேகரவின் அறிக்கை வந்துள்ளது. விஜேசேகர, ஜூன் 26 ஞாயிற்றுக்கிழமை கட்டாருக்குச் செல்வதற்கு முன் செய்தியாளர்களிடம், எண்ணெய் வளம் மிக்க நாட்டிலிருந்து எரிபொருளை இறக்குமதி செய்வதற்கான சாத்தியக்கூறுகளை ஆராய்ந்து வருவதாகக் கூறினார்.",
        "விஜேசேகர தனது விஜயத்தின் போது, ​​கத்தார் எரிசக்தி விவகாரங்களுக்கான இராஜாங்க அமைச்சரும், கத்தார் எரிசக்தியின் ஜனாதிபதியும் தலைமை நிர்வாக அதிகாரியுமான Saad Sherida Al-Kaabi ஐச் சந்தித்து, பெட்ரோலிய பொருட்கள், திரவ பெட்ரோலியம் (LP) எரிவாயு மற்றும் திரவமாக்கப்பட்ட இயற்கை எரிவாயு (LNG) விநியோகம் குறித்து விவாதித்தார். கட்டார் எரிசக்தி மற்றும் கட்டார் அபிவிருத்தி நிதியத்தின் உதவியுடன் எரிசக்தி நெருக்கடியை சமாளிக்க இலங்கைக்கு.",
        "கத்தார் வளர்ச்சிக்கான நிதியத்தின் துணை இயக்குநர் ஜெனரலையும் சந்தித்த அமைச்சர், பெட்ரோலியம் மற்றும் எரிவாயு விநியோகத்திற்கான சாத்தியமான கடன் இணைப்பு வசதி பற்றி விவாதித்ததாகவும், \"மருத்துவப் பொருட்களுக்கு நிதி ஒதுக்கீடு செய்யப்பட்டுள்ளதாகவும், கடனுக்கான கோரிக்கையை பரிசீலிப்பதாகவும் தெரிவித்தார். வசதி [மற்றும்] IMF திட்டத்தை ஆதரிக்கவும்”.",
        "ஆளும் ஸ்ரீலங்கா பொதுஜன பெரமுனவின் (SLPP) பல தலைவர்கள் எரிபொருளுக்காக மத்திய கிழக்கு நாடுகளை அணுகிய போதிலும், ஜனாதிபதி ராஜபக்ஷ நிர்வாகத்திற்கு சாதகமான பதில் கிடைக்கவில்லை என்று அரசாங்க அதிகாரிகள் EconomyNext க்கு தெரிவித்தனர்.",
        "கத்தார் தொண்டு நிறுவனத்துடன் தொடர்புடைய சட்ட வழக்கு, ஏப்ரல் 14, 2020 அன்று சிஐடியால் கைது செய்யப்பட்ட ஹெஜாஸ் ஹிஸ்புல்லாஹ் ஹிஸ்புல்லாவைக் கண்டது, அவர் \"உதவி செய்ததற்காக\" பயங்கரவாதத் தடுப்புச் சட்டத்தின் (PTA) கீழ் ஜனாதிபதி ராஜபக்ஷவால் தடுப்புக் காவலில் வைக்கப்பட்டார். ஈஸ்டர் ஞாயிறு குண்டுத்தாக்குதல்கள் மற்றும் \"சமூகங்களுக்கிடையில் மத நல்லிணக்கத்திற்கு தீங்கு விளைவிக்கும்\" செயல்களில் ஈடுபட்டதற்காக.",
        "அவர் மீது வழக்குப் பதிவு செய்யாமல் நீண்ட நேரம் காவலில் வைக்கப்பட்டார். எவ்வாறாயினும், அதிகரித்து வரும் சர்வதேச அழுத்தங்களுக்கு மத்தியில், நீதிமன்றம் அவரை இந்த ஆண்டு தொடக்கத்தில் பிணையில் விடுவிப்பதற்கு முன்பு அரசாங்கம் அவர் மீது குற்றம் சாட்டியது.",
        "ஐக்கிய அரபு எமிரேட்ஸுடன் இணைந்து இலங்கைக்கான சிறந்த வெளிநாட்டு வேலைவாய்ப்பை வழங்கும் நாடுகளில் கத்தார் ஒன்றாகும்.",
        "தீவு தேசத்தின் அரசியல் தலைவர்களின் நடவடிக்கை இராஜதந்திர உறவுகளை சீர்குலைப்பதற்கு முன்னர் இலங்கை பிரச்சினைகளுக்கு வழங்கிய முன்னுரிமையை அங்குள்ள அரசாங்கங்கள் வழங்குவதில்லை என மத்திய கிழக்கிலுள்ள இலங்கை இராஜதந்திரிகள் EconomyNext இடம் தெரிவித்துள்ளனர். (கொழும்பு/ஜூன்30/2022)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "இலங்கை",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "கத்தார் தொண்டு நிறுவனம்",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "தோஹா",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "கத்தார் தொண்டு நிறுவனம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "மாதங்கள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இஸ்லாமிய",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "வீரசேகர",
            "label": "PRODUCT"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜனவரி 07 2021",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஈஸ்டர்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஞாயிற்றுக்கிழமை",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜஹாரான் ஹாஷிம்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஹெஜாஸ் ஹிஸ்புல்லா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "கத்தார்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "வீரசேகர",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஐக்கிய நாடுகள்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "குற்றப் புலனாய்வுத் துறை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "சி.ஐ.டி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "கத்தார் தொண்டு நிறுவனம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ராஜபக்சே",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "கத்தார்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இஸ்லாமிய நாடுகளின் அமைப்பு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "OIC",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கையின்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "முஸ்லிம்கள்",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "COVID-19",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "மத்திய கிழக்கு",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "காஞ்சனா விஜேசேகர",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "கத்தார் தொண்டு நிறுவனம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "தோஹா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜூன் 29",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "நேற்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாதுகாப்பு அமைச்சகம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "2019",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "தொண்டு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "விஜேசேகர",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "அடுத்த மாதத்தின் மத்தியில்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜூன் 26 ஞாயிறு",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "கத்தார்",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "விஜேசேகர",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "சாத் ஷெரிடா அல்-காபி",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "கத்தார்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "எரிசக்தி விவகாரங்களுக்கான மாநிலம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "கத்தார் ஆற்றல்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "எல்என்ஜி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "கத்தார் ஆற்றல்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "கத்தார் மேம்பாட்டு நிதி",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "வளர்ச்சிக்கான கத்தார் நிதி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "IMF",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஸ்ரீலங்கா பொதுஜன பெரமுன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "மத்திய கிழக்கு",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ராஜபக்சே",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "EconomyNext",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "கத்தார்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஹிஜாஸ் ஹிஸ்புல்லாஹ் ஹிஸ்புல்லாஹ்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "சி.ஐ.டி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஏப்ரல் 14, 2020",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ராஜபக்சே",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "பயங்கரவாதத் தடைச் சட்டம்",
            "label": "LAW"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஈஸ்டர்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஞாயிற்றுக்கிழமை",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இந்த ஆண்டின் தொடக்கத்தில்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "கத்தார்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஐக்கிய அரபு எமிரேட்ஸ்",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "மத்திய கிழக்கு",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "கொழும்பு/ஜூன்30/2022",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}