{
  "newspaper_id": "ada-derana-lk",
  "url": "http://www.adaderana.lk/news/84683/sri-lankas-2023-budget-should-be-consistent-with-imf-program-breuer",
  "time_ut": 1662019980,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Sri Lanka’s 2023 budget should be consistent with IMF program: Breuer",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Sri Lanka’s 2023 budget should be consistent with IMF program: Breuer",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "Sri Lanka’s 2023 Budget needs to be consistent with the economic reforms program and macroeconomic framework under the International Monetary Fund (IMF) program, says Peter Breuer, Chief of the Debt Capital Markets Division, Monetary and Capital Market Department.",
        "IMF staff and the Sri Lankan authorities announced this morning that they have reached a staff-level agreement to support the island nation’s economic policies with a 48-month arrangement under the Extended Fund Facility (EFF) of about USD 2.9 billion."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Sri Lanka’s",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "2023",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka’s",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "2023",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "the International Monetary Fund",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Peter Breuer",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Debt Capital Markets Division",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Capital Market Department",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lankan",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "this morning",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "48-month",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Extended Fund Facility",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "EFF",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "about USD 2.9 billion",
            "label": "MONEY"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ 2023 අයවැය ජාත්‍යන්තර මූල්‍ය අරමුදලේ වැඩසටහනට අනුකූල විය යුතුය: Breuer",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ 2023 අයවැය ආර්ථික ප්‍රතිසංස්කරණ වැඩසටහනට සහ ජාත්‍යන්තර මූල්‍ය අරමුදලේ (IMF) වැඩසටහන යටතේ ඇති සාර්ව ආර්ථික රාමුවට අනුකූල විය යුතු බව මුදල් හා ප්‍රාග්ධන වෙළෙඳපොළ දෙපාර්තමේන්තුවේ ණය ප්‍රාග්ධන වෙළෙඳපොළ අංශයේ ප්‍රධානී Peter Breuer පවසයි.",
        "IMF කාර්ය මණ්ඩලය සහ ශ්‍රී ලංකා බලධාරීන් අද උදෑසන නිවේදනය කළේ ඇමරිකානු ඩොලර් බිලියන 2.9 ක පමණ විස්තීරණ අරමුදල් පහසුකම (EFF) යටතේ මාස 48 ක වැඩපිළිවෙලක් සමඟ දිවයිනේ ආර්ථික ප්‍රතිපත්තිවලට සහාය වීම සඳහා කාර්ය මණ්ඩල මට්ටමේ එකඟතාවයකට පැමිණ ඇති බවයි."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "2023",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "2023",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජාත්‍යන්තර මුල්‍ය අරමුදල",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "පීටර් බෲවර්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ණය ප්‍රාග්ධන වෙළෙඳපොළ අංශය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ප්රාග්ධන වෙළෙඳපොළ දෙපාර්තමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලාංකික",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "මේ උදෑසන",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "48-මාස",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "විස්තීරණ අරමුදල් පහසුකම",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "EFF",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඩොලර් බිලියන 2.9 ක් පමණ වේ",
            "label": "MONEY"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "இலங்கையின் 2023 வரவு செலவுத் திட்டம் சர்வதேச நாணய நிதியத்தின் திட்டத்துடன் இணக்கமாக இருக்க வேண்டும்: ப்ரூயர்",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "இலங்கையின் 2023 வரவுசெலவுத் திட்டம் பொருளாதார சீர்திருத்தத் திட்டம் மற்றும் சர்வதேச நாணய நிதியத்தின் (IMF) திட்டத்தின் கீழ் உள்ள பெரிய பொருளாதார கட்டமைப்பிற்கு இசைவாக இருக்க வேண்டும் என்று நாணய மற்றும் மூலதன சந்தைத் திணைக்களத்தின் கடன் மூலதன சந்தைப் பிரிவின் தலைவர் பீட்டர் ப்ரூயர் கூறுகிறார்.",
        "IMF ஊழியர்களும் இலங்கை அதிகாரிகளும் இன்று காலை 2.9 பில்லியன் அமெரிக்க டாலர்களின் விரிவாக்கப்பட்ட நிதி வசதியின் (EFF) கீழ் 48 மாத ஏற்பாட்டுடன் தீவு நாட்டின் பொருளாதாரக் கொள்கைகளை ஆதரிப்பதற்கான ஊழியர்கள் அளவிலான உடன்பாட்டை எட்டியுள்ளதாக அறிவித்தனர்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "இலங்கையின்",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "2023",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கையின்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "2023",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "சர்வதேச நாணய நிதியம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "பீட்டர் ப்ரூயர்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "கடன் மூலதன சந்தை பிரிவு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "மூலதன சந்தை துறை",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று காலை",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "48-மாதம்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "விரிவாக்கப்பட்ட நிதி வசதி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "EFF",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "சுமார் 2.9 பில்லியன் அமெரிக்க டாலர்கள்",
            "label": "MONEY"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}