{
  "newspaper_id": "economy-next-com",
  "url": "https://economynext.com/sri-lanka-govt-schools-to-start-from-july-25-97834/",
  "time_ut": 1658570340,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Sri Lanka govt schools to start from July 25",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Sri Lanka govt schools to start from July 25",
      "author": "",
      "body_lines": [
        "ECONOMYNEXT – Sri Lanka’s government schools, which were closed due to fuel shortage, will be reopened with physical classrooms from Monday, July 25, the Education Ministry said.",
        "Physical classrooms will be held only on Monday, Tuesday, and Friday until further notice while the schools are expected to continue with online education on both Tuesday and Thursday of each week, the ministry said.",
        "Schools were closed towards the latter part of June due to fuel shortage.",
        "The government decision to reopen schools come as the country’s fuel stocks have improved while President Ranil Wickremesinghe has instructed state-run Sri Lanka Transport Board depots to supply fuel for vans and buses engaged with school services. (Colombo/July 23/2022)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Sri Lanka",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "from July 25",
          "label": "DATE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka’s",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Monday, July 25",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Education Ministry",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Monday, Tuesday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Friday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Tuesday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Thursday of each week",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "June",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka Transport Board",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Colombo",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "ශ්‍රී ලංකා රජයේ පාසල් ජූලි 25 සිට ආරම්භ වේ",
      "author": "",
      "body_lines": [
        "ECONOMYNEXT - ඉන්ධන හිඟය හේතුවෙන් වසා දැමුණු ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ රජයේ පාසල් ජුලි 25 සඳුදා සිට භෞතික පන්ති කාමර සමඟ නැවත විවෘත කරන බව අධ්‍යාපන අමාත්‍යාංශය පවසයි.",
        "නැවත දැනුම් දෙන තුරු භෞතික පන්ති කාමර සඳුදා, අඟහරුවාදා සහ සිකුරාදා දින පමණක් පැවැත්වෙන අතර සෑම සතියකම අඟහරුවාදා සහ බ්‍රහස්පතින්දා යන දින දෙකෙහිම පාසල් මාර්ගගත අධ්‍යාපනය දිගටම කරගෙන යාමට අපේක්ෂා කරන බව අමාත්‍යාංශය පවසයි.",
        "ඉන්ධන හිඟය හේතුවෙන් ජුනි මස අග භාගයේදී පාසල් වසා දැමුණි.",
        "පාසල් විවෘත කිරීමට රජය තීරණය කර ඇත්තේ රටේ ඉන්ධන තොග ඉහළ ගොස් ඇති අතර, පාසල් සේවාවල යෙදෙන වෑන් රථ සහ බස් රථ සඳහා ඉන්ධන සැපයීමට ජනාධිපති රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතා ශ්‍රී ලංකා ගමනාගමන මණ්ඩලයේ රජයේ ඩිපෝවලට උපදෙස් දී ඇති බැවිනි. (කොළඹ/ජූලි 23/2022)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "ජූලි 25 සිට",
          "label": "DATE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජූලි 25 සඳුදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "අධ්යාපන අමාත්යාංශය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "සඳුදා අඟහරුවාදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "සිකුරාදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "අඟහරුවාදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "සෑම සතියකම බ්‍රහස්පතින්දා",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ජූනි",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකා ගමනාගමන මණ්ඩලය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "කොළඹ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "இலங்கை அரசுப் பள்ளிகள் ஜூலை 25 முதல் தொடங்கும்",
      "author": "",
      "body_lines": [
        "ECONOMYNEXT – எரிபொருள் தட்டுப்பாடு காரணமாக மூடப்பட்டிருந்த இலங்கையின் அரச பாடசாலைகள், ஜூலை 25 திங்கட்கிழமை முதல் பௌதீக வகுப்பறைகளுடன் மீண்டும் திறக்கப்படும் என கல்வி அமைச்சு தெரிவித்துள்ளது.",
        "ஒவ்வொரு வாரமும் செவ்வாய் மற்றும் வியாழன் ஆகிய இரு தினங்களிலும் பள்ளிகள் ஆன்லைன் கல்வியைத் தொடரும் என எதிர்பார்க்கப்படும் அதே வேளையில், உடல் வகுப்பறைகள் மறு அறிவிப்பு வரும் வரை திங்கள், செவ்வாய் மற்றும் வெள்ளிக்கிழமைகளில் மட்டுமே நடைபெறும் என்று அமைச்சகம் தெரிவித்துள்ளது.",
        "எரிபொருள் தட்டுப்பாடு காரணமாக ஜூன் மாத இறுதியில் பள்ளிகள் மூடப்பட்டன.",
        "பாடசாலை சேவையில் ஈடுபடும் வேன்கள் மற்றும் பஸ்களுக்கு எரிபொருளை விநியோகிக்குமாறு ஜனாதிபதி ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க அரச போக்குவரத்துச் சபை டிப்போக்களுக்கு பணிப்புரை விடுத்துள்ள நிலையில், நாட்டின் எரிபொருள் கையிருப்பில் முன்னேற்றம் ஏற்பட்டுள்ள நிலையில் பாடசாலைகளை மீள திறக்க அரசாங்கம் தீர்மானித்துள்ளது. (கொழும்பு/ஜூலை 23/2022)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "இலங்கை",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "ஜூலை 25 முதல்",
          "label": "DATE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கையின்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "திங்கட்கிழமை, ஜூலை 25",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "கல்வி அமைச்சு",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "திங்கள், செவ்வாய்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "வெள்ளி",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "செவ்வாய்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஒவ்வொரு வாரமும் வியாழன்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஜூன்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை போக்குவரத்து சபை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "கொழும்பு",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}