{
  "newspaper_id": "daily-mirror-lk",
  "url": "https://www.dailymirror.lk/latest_news/20-25-member-Cabinet-to-be-appointed/342-241479",
  "time_ut": 1658365692,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "20-25 member Cabinet to be appointed",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "20-25 member Cabinet to be appointed",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "A Cabinet of 20-25 members will be appointed within the next few days to serve under President Ranil Wickremesinghe who will be sworn in tomorrow, Daily Mirror learns.",
        "The new government tries to make it as representative as possible. The new President also articulated it in his speech to Parliament upon announcement of his victory at the secret ballot yesterday.",
        "Daily Mirror learns that a lot of young MPs will be given responsibilities in the government. The president is expected to appoint someone acceptable to all the parties as the prime minister. Unless any leader from the opposition is willing to accept premiership, it will be offered to MP Dinesh Gunawardane who nominated Mr.Wickremesinghe to the presidency in the secret ballot.",
        "According to the Constitution, the size of the Cabinet cannot exceed 30. The new government is planning to normalize fuel and cooking gas supplies and delivery of fertilizer for farmers for cultivation in the upcoming season. Also, the government is expected to resume talks with the International Monetary Fund (IMF) to secure financial assistance to get over the current economic crisis. (Kelum Bandara)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "20-25",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "Cabinet",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Cabinet",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "20-25",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "the next few days",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "tomorrow",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Daily Mirror",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "yesterday",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Daily Mirror",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Dinesh Gunawardane",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Constitution",
            "label": "LAW"
          },
          {
            "text": "Cabinet",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "30",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the upcoming season",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the International Monetary Fund",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kelum Bandara",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "20-25 ක කැබිනට් මණ්ඩලයක් පත් කෙරේ",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "හෙට දිවුරුම් දෙන ජනාධිපති රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ යටතේ ක්‍රියා කිරීම සඳහා සාමාජිකයින් 20-25 කින් යුත් කැබිනට් මණ්ඩලයක් ඉදිරි දින කිහිපය තුළ පත් කිරීමට නියමිත බව ඩේලි මිරර් වෙත වාර්තා වේ.",
        "නව රජය උත්සාහ කරන්නේ එය හැකිතාක් නියෝජනය කිරීමටයි. ඊයේ පැවති රහස් ඡන්දයෙන් ජයග්‍රහණය ප්‍රකාශ කිරීමත් සමඟ නව ජනාධිපතිවරයා පාර්ලිමේන්තුව අමතමින් කළ කතාවේදීද එය ප්‍රකාශ කළේය.",
        "තරුණ මන්ත්‍රීවරුන් රැසකට ආණ්ඩුවේ වගකීම් හිමිවන බව ඩේලි මිරර් වෙත වාර්තා වේ. ජනාධිපතිවරයා සියලු පක්ෂවලට පිළිගත හැකි අයෙක් අගමැති ලෙස පත් කිරීමට බලාපොරොත්තු වේ. විපක්‍ෂයේ කිසිදු නායකයකු අගමැතිකම භාර ගැනීමට කැමැත්තක්‌ නොදක්‌වන්නේ නම් එය රහස්‌ ඡන්දයෙන් වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතා ජනාධිපති ධුරයට පත් කළ දිනේෂ් ගුණවර්ධන මන්ත්‍රීවරයාට පිරිනැමීමට නියමිතය.",
        "ආණ්‌ඩුක්‍රම ව්‍යවස්‌ථාවට අනුව කැබිනට්‌ මණ්‌ඩල ප්‍රමාණය 30 ඉක්මවිය නොහැක. ඉදිරි කන්නයේ දී ගොවීන්ට වගා කිරීම සඳහා ඉන්ධන සහ ඉවුම් පිහුම් ගෑස්‌ සැපයීම සහ පොහොර ලබාදීම සාමාන්‍යකරණය කිරීමට නව රජය සැලසුම් කරයි. එසේම වත්මන් ආර්ථික අර්බුදයෙන් ගොඩ ඒම සඳහා මූල්‍ය ආධාර ලබා ගැනීම සඳහා රජය ජාත්‍යන්තර මූල්‍ය අරමුදල (IMF) සමඟ නැවත සාකච්ඡා ආරම්භ කිරීමට බලාපොරොත්තු වේ. (කැළුම් බණ්ඩාර)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "20-25",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "මණ්ඩල",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "මණ්ඩල",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "20-25",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉදිරි දින කිහිපය",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "හෙට",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඩේලි මිරර්",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඊයේ",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ඩේලි මිරර්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "දිනේෂ් ගුණවර්ධන",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ආණ්ඩුක්රම ව්යවස්ථාව",
            "label": "LAW"
          },
          {
            "text": "මණ්ඩල",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "30",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉදිරි සමය",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජාත්‍යන්තර මුල්‍ය අරමුදල",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "කැළුම් බණ්ඩාර",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "20-25 பேர் கொண்ட அமைச்சரவை நியமிக்கப்படும்",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "நாளை பதவியேற்கவுள்ள ஜனாதிபதி ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்கவின் கீழ் பணியாற்றுவதற்கு 20-25 பேர் கொண்ட அமைச்சரவை அடுத்த சில நாட்களுக்குள் நியமிக்கப்படும் என டெய்லி மிரர் செய்தி வெளியிட்டுள்ளது.",
        "புதிய அரசாங்கம் அதை முடிந்தவரை பிரதிநிதித்துவப்படுத்த முயற்சிக்கிறது. நேற்றைய இரகசிய வாக்கெடுப்பில் வெற்றி பெற்றதாக அறிவிக்கப்பட்டவுடன் புதிய ஜனாதிபதி பாராளுமன்றத்தில் ஆற்றிய உரையிலும் இதனை வெளிப்படுத்தினார்.",
        "நிறைய இளம் பாராளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர்களுக்கு அரசாங்கத்தில் பொறுப்புகள் வழங்கப்படவுள்ளதாக டெய்லி மிரர் அறிகிறது. அனைத்து கட்சிகளும் ஏற்றுக்கொள்ளக்கூடிய ஒருவரை ஜனாதிபதி பிரதமராக நியமிப்பார் என எதிர்பார்க்கப்படுகிறது. எதிர்க்கட்சியில் இருந்து எந்தத் தலைவரும் பிரதமர் பதவியை ஏற்கத் தயாராக இல்லை என்றால், இரகசிய வாக்கெடுப்பில் திரு.விக்கிரமசிங்கவை ஜனாதிபதியாகப் பரிந்துரைத்த பாராளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர் தினேஷ் குணவர்தனவுக்கு அது வழங்கப்படும்.",
        "அரசியலமைப்பின் படி, அமைச்சரவையின் அளவு 30 ஐ தாண்டக்கூடாது. புதிய அரசாங்கம் எரிபொருள் மற்றும் சமையல் எரிவாயு விநியோகம் மற்றும் விவசாயிகளுக்கு பயிர்ச்செய்கைக்கான உரங்களை எதிர்வரும் பருவத்தில் வழங்குவதை சீராக்க திட்டமிட்டுள்ளது. மேலும், தற்போதைய பொருளாதார நெருக்கடியிலிருந்து விடுபட நிதி உதவியைப் பெறுவதற்காக சர்வதேச நாணய நிதியத்துடன் (IMF) அரசாங்கம் மீண்டும் பேச்சுவார்த்தைகளை ஆரம்பிக்கும் என்று எதிர்பார்க்கப்படுகிறது. (கெலும் பண்டார)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "20-25",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "மந்திரி சபை",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "மந்திரி சபை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "20-25",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "அடுத்த சில நாட்கள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "நாளை",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "டெய்லி மிரர்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "நேற்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "டெய்லி மிரர்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "தினேஷ் குணவர்தன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "அரசியலமைப்பு",
            "label": "LAW"
          },
          {
            "text": "மந்திரி சபை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "30",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "வரவிருக்கும் பருவம்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சர்வதேச நாணய நிதியம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "கெலும் பண்டார",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}