{
  "newspaper_id": "ada-lk",
  "url": "https://www.ada.lk/breaking_news/ජාතික-සභාව-ගැන-කෙටුම්පත-පක්ෂ-නායකයන්ට-ඉදිරිපත්-කරයි/11-396715",
  "time_ut": 1661832885,
  "original_lang": "si",
  "original_title": "ජාතික සභාව ගැන කෙටුම්පත පක්ෂ නායකයන්ට ඉදිරිපත් කරයි",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "The draft about the National Assembly is presented to the party leaders",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "Prime Minister Dinesh Gunawardena presented a preliminary draft to the party leaders yesterday (29th) for the establishment of a National Assembly consisting of the parties representing the Parliament. It was during the party leaders' meeting held at the Parliament complex.",
        "The government's proposal regarding the establishment of sectoral supervision committees in the Parliament was also discussed.",
        "Here, the party leaders expressed different opinions, and the party leaders stated that the purpose of this should be to guide the political decisions of the parties in the Parliament by common agreement.",
        "It was also decided to get the views of the respective parties in writing regarding the proposal drafted by the government on the National Assembly and Sectoral Monitoring Committees. It was also decided to prepare a new and improved draft with those ideas and present it to the party leaders' meeting which will be reconvened on Friday (2022.09.02) under the chairmanship of Prime Minister Dinesh Gunawardena.",
        "The government's proposal regarding the addition of 17 sectoral monitoring committees and 3 more to the existing 12 standing committees was also presented to the party leaders.",
        "Leaders of parties and groups representing the Sri Lanka Podujana Peramuna, Samagi Jana Balawegaya, Sri Lanka Freedom Party, independent parties, Ceylon Labor Congress, United National Party, EPDP, National Congress etc. attended this meeting.",
        "In this regard, on 12.08.2022, a meeting of party leaders was held at the Parliament complex under the chairmanship of the Prime Minister and all the party leaders representing the Parliament participated in it."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "the National Assembly",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Dinesh Gunawardena",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "yesterday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "29th",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "National Assembly",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the National Assembly",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sectoral Monitoring Committees",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Friday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "2022.09.02",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Dinesh Gunawardena",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "17",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "3",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "12",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "Podujana Peramuna",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Samagi",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Jana Balawegaya",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka Freedom Party",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ceylon Labor Congress",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "United National Party",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "EPDP",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "National Congress",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "12.08.2022",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "ජාතික සභාව ගැන කෙටුම්පත පක්ෂ නායකයන්ට ඉදිරිපත් කරයි",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව නියෝජනය කරන පක්ෂවලින් සමන්විත ජාතික සභාවක් පිහිටුවීම සඳහා, මූලික කෙටුම්පතක් අග්‍රාමාත්‍ය දිනේෂ් ගුණවර්ධන මහතා විසින් පක්ෂ නායකයන් වෙත ඊයේ (29දා) දින ඉදිරිපත් කරනු ලැබීය.  ඒ, පාර්ලිමේන්තු සංකීර්ණයේදී පැවති පක්ෂ නායක රැස්වීමේදීය.",
        "මෙහිදී පාර්ලිමේන්තුවේ ආංශික අධීක්ෂණය කාරක සභා ස්ථාපිත කිරීම සම්බන්ධයෙන්ද රජයේ යෝජනාව සාකච්ඡාවට ලක් විය.",
        "මෙහිදි පක්ෂ නායකයන් විවිධ අදහස් දැක්වූ අතර, පාර්ලිමේන්තුවේ පක්ෂවල පොදු එකඟතාවයකින් ප්‍රතිපත්තිමය තීරණ ගැනීමට මග පෙන්වීම මෙහි අරමුණ විය යුතු බව පක්ෂ නායකයෝ ප්‍රකාශ කළහ.",
        "ජාතික සභාව සහ ආංශික අධීක්ෂණ කාරක සභා පිළිබඳ රජය කෙටුම්පත් කළ යෝජනාව සම්බන්ධයෙන් ඒ ඒ පක්ෂවල අදහස් කඩිනමින් ලිඛිතව ලබාගැනීමටද මෙහිදී තීරණය විය. එම අදහස් සමග වැඩි දියුණු කළ නව කෙටුම්පතක් සකසා, එය අග්‍රාමාත්‍ය දිනේෂ් ගුණවර්ධන මහතාගේ ප්‍රධානත්වයෙන් සිකුරාදා (2022.09.02) යළි රැස්වන පක්ෂ නායක රැස්වීමට ඉදිරිපත් කිරීමටද තීරණය කෙරිණි.",
        "ආංශික අධීක්ෂණ කාරක සභා 17 ක් සහ දැනට ඇති ස්ථාවර කාරක සභා 12 ට තවත් 3ක් එකතු කිරීම සම්බන්ධයෙන් රජයේ යෝජනාවද මෙහිදී පක්ෂ නායකයන් වෙත ඉදිරිපත් කෙරිණි.",
        "මෙම රැස්වීමට ශ්‍රී ලංකා පොදුජන පෙරමුණ, සමගි ජන බලවේගය,  ශ්‍රි ලංකා නිදහස් පක්ෂය, ස්වාධීන වූ පක්ෂ, ලංකා කම්කරු කොංග්‍රසය, එක්සත් ජාතික පක්ෂය, ඊපීඩීපී, ජාතික කොංග්‍රසය ආදී පාර්ලිමේන්තුවේ නියෝජනය කරන පක්ෂ, කණ්ඩායම් නායකයෝ  එක්ව සිටියහ.",
        "මේ සම්බන්ධයෙන් 2022.08.12 දිනද අග්‍රාමාත්‍යවරයාගේ ප්‍රධානත්වයෙන් පාර්ලිමේන්තු සංකීර්ණයේදී පක්ෂ නායක රැස්වීමක් පැවති අතර ඊටද පාර්ලිමේන්තුව නියෝජනය කරන සියලු පක්ෂ නායකයෝ සහභාගි වූහ."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ජාතික සභාව",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "දිනේෂ් ගුණවර්ධන",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඊයේ",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "29 වැනි",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජාතික රැස්වීම",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ජාතික සභාව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ආංශික අධීක්ෂණ කමිටු",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "සිකුරාදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "2022.09.02",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "දිනේෂ් ගුණවර්ධන",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "17",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "3",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "12",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "පොදුජන පෙරමුණ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "සමගි",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජන බලවේගය",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකා නිදහස් පක්ෂය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ලංකා කම්කරු කොංග්‍රසය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "එක්සත් ජාතික පක්ෂය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඊ.පී.ඩී.පී",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජාතික කොංග්රසය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "2022.08.12",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "தேசிய சட்டமன்றம் பற்றிய வரைவு கட்சித் தலைவர்களுக்கு வழங்கப்படுகிறது",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "பாராளுமன்றத்தை பிரதிநிதித்துவப்படுத்தும் கட்சிகளை உள்ளடக்கிய தேசிய பேரவையை ஸ்தாபிப்பதற்கான பூர்வாங்க வரைவை பிரதமர் தினேஷ் குணவர்தன நேற்று (29) கட்சித் தலைவர்களிடம் கையளித்தார். பாராளுமன்ற கட்டிடத் தொகுதியில் நடைபெற்ற கட்சித் தலைவர்கள் கூட்டத்தின் போதே அவர் இவ்வாறு தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "பாராளுமன்றத்தில் துறைசார் கண்காணிப்புக் குழுக்களை அமைப்பது தொடர்பான அரசாங்கத்தின் முன்மொழிவு குறித்தும் கலந்துரையாடப்பட்டது.",
        "இங்கு கட்சித் தலைவர்கள் பல்வேறு கருத்துக்களை வெளியிட்டதுடன், பொது உடன்படிக்கையின் மூலம் பாராளுமன்றத்தில் கட்சிகளின் அரசியல் தீர்மானங்களை வழிநடத்துவதே இதன் நோக்கமாக இருக்க வேண்டும் என கட்சித் தலைவர்கள் தெரிவித்தனர்.",
        "தேசிய சபை மற்றும் துறைசார் கண்காணிப்புக் குழுக்கள் தொடர்பில் அரசாங்கத்தினால் முன்வைக்கப்பட்ட பிரேரணை தொடர்பில் எழுத்து மூலம் அந்தந்த கட்சிகளின் கருத்துக்களைப் பெறவும் தீர்மானிக்கப்பட்டது. அந்த யோசனைகளை உள்ளடக்கிய புதிய மற்றும் மேம்படுத்தப்பட்ட வரைபு ஒன்றை தயாரித்து அதனை பிரதமர் தினேஷ் குணவர்தன தலைமையில் எதிர்வரும் வெள்ளிக்கிழமை (2022.09.02) மீண்டும் கூடவுள்ள கட்சித் தலைவர்கள் கூட்டத்தில் சமர்ப்பிப்பதற்கும் தீர்மானிக்கப்பட்டது.",
        "தற்போதுள்ள 12 நிலைக்குழுக்களுடன் 17 துறைசார் கண்காணிப்புக் குழுக்களையும் மேலும் 3 குழுக்களையும் சேர்ப்பது தொடர்பான அரசாங்கத்தின் யோசனையும் கட்சித் தலைவர்களிடம் முன்வைக்கப்பட்டது.",
        "ஸ்ரீலங்கா பொதுஜன பெரமுன, சமகி ஜன பலவேகய, ஸ்ரீலங்கா சுதந்திரக் கட்சி, சுயேச்சைக் கட்சிகள், இலங்கை தொழிலாளர் காங்கிரஸ், ஐக்கிய தேசியக் கட்சி, ஈபிடிபி, தேசிய காங்கிரஸ் போன்ற கட்சிகளின் தலைவர்கள் இந்தக் கூட்டத்தில் கலந்துகொண்டனர்.",
        "இதனடிப்படையில் 12.08.2022 அன்று பிரதமர் தலைமையில் பாராளுமன்ற கட்டடத் தொகுதியில் கட்சித் தலைவர்கள் கூட்டம் இடம்பெற்றதுடன் அதில் பாராளுமன்றத்தைப் பிரதிநிதித்துவப்படுத்தும் அனைத்துக் கட்சித் தலைவர்களும் கலந்துகொண்டனர்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "தேசிய சட்டமன்றம்",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "தினேஷ் குணவர்தன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "நேற்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "29 ஆம் தேதி",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "தேசிய சட்டமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "தேசிய சட்டமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "துறைசார் கண்காணிப்புக் குழுக்கள்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "வெள்ளி",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "2022.09.02",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "தினேஷ் குணவர்தன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "17",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "3",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "12",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "பொதுஜன பெரமுன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "சமகி",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜன பலவேகயா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஸ்ரீலங்கா சுதந்திரக் கட்சி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை தொழிலாளர் காங்கிரஸ்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஐக்கிய தேசிய கட்சி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஈ.பி.டி.பி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "தேசிய காங்கிரஸ்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "12.08.2022",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}