{
  "newspaper_id": "ada-lk",
  "url": "https://www.ada.lk/breaking_news/හිරුණිකාගේ-ඉල්ලීම/11-395197",
  "time_ut": 1657187836,
  "original_lang": "si",
  "original_title": "හිරුණිකාගේ ඉල්ලීම",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Hirunika's request",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "Former Member of Parliament Mrs. Hirunika Premachandra said that the last day of the struggle to free the country from the Rajapaksas should be on the 9th, and for that all parties should unite.",
        "While attending a press conference held at the office of the opposition leader in Colombo today (07), she stated that the ousting of President Gotabhaya Rajapaksa cannot be done by individual parties.",
        "\"This fight is the last fight, as I always say. It will be the last day to rid the country of the Rajapaksas. On that day, everyone should take to the streets regardless of party color. My personal opinion is that in order to protect the common people of the country, Sajaba, JVP, T All the NA and vanguards should join hands and stand together in front of the people as a great human wall, then the politicians in front will be the first to eat tear gas and water attacks.",
        "This is not something that a single party can do alone. Sahaba cannot oust the president alone. The JVP alone cannot oust the President. The defenders cannot do it alone. University student unions cannot do it alone. It can be done if all these people join together. So if the 9th is the last day, you have to prepare this week. Yesterday we went to the President's house. Today I think the monks came down. Tomorrow I think the university youths will be out. So the last day of all this is that he will go home on the 9th.",
        "No one needs to join here or become a leader of the struggle. Credit for this struggle should not go to anyone. People should take the credit for the struggle. Party politics are irrelevant at this time. Find out who our common enemy is. From the man who can to the man who can't, he roams the streets.\""
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Hirunika Premachandra",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the last day",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Rajapaksas",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "07",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Gotabhaya Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Rajapaksas",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "that day",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sajaba",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "JVP",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "NA",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "first",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sahaba",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "9th",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "the last day",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "this week",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Yesterday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Today",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Tomorrow",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the last day",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        []
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "හිරුණිකාගේ ඉල්ලීම",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "රට රාජපක්ෂවරුන්ගෙන් මුදවා ගැනීම සඳහා සිදු කරන අරගලයන්ගේ අවසන් දිනය එළැඹෙන 09 වැනිදා විය යුතු බවත්, ඒ සඳහා සියලු පක්ෂ එකට එක්විය යුතු බවත් හිටපු පාර්ලිමේන්තු මන්ත්‍රී හිරුණිකා ප්‍රේමචන්ද්‍ර මහත්මිය පැවසුවාය.",
        "ජනාධිපති ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ මහතා පළවා හැරීම තනි තනි පක්ෂ ලෙස සිදු කළ නොහැකි බව අද (07දා) කොළඹ විපක්ෂනායක කාර්යාලයේ පැවති මාධ්‍ය හමුවකට එක්වෙමින් ඇය සඳහන් කළාය.",
        "\"මේ කරන සටන මම හැමදාම කියනවා වගේ සිදු කරන අවසන් සටන. රට රාජපක්ෂවරුන්ගෙන් මුදවා ගැනීමේ අවසන් දිනය ලෙස එය සනිටුහන් වෙයි. එදාට පක්ෂ පාට භේදයකින් තොරව සියලු දෙනා පාරට බහින්න ඔ්නී. මගේ පෞද්ගලික මතය නම් රටේ සාමාන්‍ය ජනතාව ආරක්ෂා කිරීම සඳහා සජබ, ජේවීපී, ටී.එන්.ඒ, පෙරටුගාමී යන සියලුදෙනාම මහා මිනිස් පවුරක් ලෙස ජනතාව ඉදිරියෙන් අත්වැල් බැඳගෙන එකට හිට ගන්න ඔ්නී. එතකොට කඳුලු ගෑස්, ජල ප්‍රහාර මුලින්ම කන්නේ ඉදිරියේ ඉන්න දේශපාලඥයෝ.",
        "මේක තනි පක්ෂයකට තනියෙන් කරන්න පුලුවන් දෙයක් නෙවෙයි. සජබයට තනියෙන් ජනාධිපතිව පළවා හරින්න බෑ. ජේ.වී.පී එකට තනියෙන් ජනාධිපතිව පළවා හරින්න බෑ. ‌ෙපරටුගාමී අයට තනියෙන් කරන්න බෑ. විශ්ව විද්‍යාල ශිෂ්‍ය සංලම් වලට තනියෙන් කරන්න බෑ. මේ සියලු දෙනා එකතුවුනොත් කරන්න පුලුවන්. ඉතින් 09 වැනිදා නම් අවසන් දවස වෙන්න ඔ්නී මේ සතියම සූදානම් වීම කරන්න ඔ්නී. ඊයේ අපි ජනාධිපතිවරයාගේ ගේ ඉදිරියට ගියා. අද මම හිතන්නේ භික්ෂූන් වහන්සේලා බහිවා. හෙට මම හිතන්නේ විශ්ව විද්‍යාල තරුණ තරුණියන් එළියට බහිනවා. ඉතින් මේ සියල්ලේ අවසන් දිනය වෙන්න ඔ්නී 09 වැනිදා මෙයා ගෙදර යන එක.",
        "කවුරුත් මෙතන එක දාගන්නවත්, අරගලයේ නායකයෙක් වෙන්නවත් අවශ්‍ය නෑ. කාටවත් මේ අරගලයේ ක්‍රෙඩිට් එක යා යුතු නෑ. අරගලයේ ක්‍රෙඩිට් එක මිනිස්සු තමයි ගන්න ඔ්නී. මේ වෙලාවේ පක්ෂ දේශපාලනය වැඩක් නෑ. අපේ පොදු හතුරා කවුද කියලා හඳුනා ගන්න ඔ්නී. ඇති හැකි මිනිහාගේ ඉදන් නැති බැරි මිනිහා දක්වා පාරේ රස්තියාදු වෙනවා.\""
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "හිරුණිකා ප්‍රේමචන්ද්‍ර",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "අවසාන දිනය",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "රාජපක්ෂලා",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "07",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "රාජපක්ෂලා",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "එදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "සජාබා",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජ.වි.පෙ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "NA",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "පළමුවන",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "සහබා",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "9 වැනි",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "අවසාන දිනය",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මෙම සතිය",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඊයේ",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "හෙට",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "අවසාන දිනය",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        []
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "ஹிருணிகா வேண்டுகோள்",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "ராஜபக்ஷக்களிடம் இருந்து நாட்டை விடுவிக்கும் போராட்டத்தின் இறுதி நாள் எதிர்வரும் 9ஆம் திகதி இருக்க வேண்டும் எனவும், அதற்காக அனைத்து தரப்பினரும் ஒன்றிணைய வேண்டும் எனவும் முன்னாள் பாராளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர் திருமதி ஹிருணிகா பிரேமச்சந்திர தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "கொழும்பில் உள்ள எதிர்க்கட்சித் தலைவர் அலுவலகத்தில் இன்று (07) நடைபெற்ற ஊடகவியலாளர் சந்திப்பில் கலந்துகொண்டு கருத்துத் தெரிவிக்கையில், ஜனாதிபதி கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ஷவை பதவியில் இருந்து நீக்குவதை தனிப்பட்ட கட்சிகளால் செய்ய முடியாது.",
        "“இந்தப் போராட்டம் நான் எப்பொழுதும் கூறுவது போல் கடைசிப் போராட்டம். ராஜபக்சக்களிடம் இருந்து நாட்டை விடுவிப்பதற்கான கடைசி நாளாக இது அமையும். அன்றைய தினம் கட்சி பேதமின்றி அனைவரும் வீதியில் இறங்க வேண்டும் என்பது எனது தனிப்பட்ட கருத்து. நாட்டின் சாமானிய மக்களை காக்க, சஜபா, ஜேவிபி, டி அனைத்து NA மற்றும் முன்னணி வீரர்கள் கைகோர்த்து மாபெரும் மனித சுவராக மக்கள் முன் நிற்க வேண்டும், அப்போது முன்னால் அரசியல்வாதிகள் கண்ணீர் புகை மற்றும் தண்ணீரை முதலில் சாப்பிடுவார்கள் தாக்குதல்கள்.",
        "இது தனி ஒரு கட்சியால் மட்டும் செய்யக்கூடிய காரியம் அல்ல. சஹாபாக்களால் ஜனாதிபதியை மட்டும் பதவியில் இருந்து அகற்ற முடியாது. ஜே.வி.பி.யால் மாத்திரம் ஜனாதிபதியை வெளியேற்ற முடியாது. பாதுகாவலர்களால் தனியாக செய்ய முடியாது. பல்கலைகழக மாணவர் சங்கங்களால் தனியாக செய்ய முடியாது. இவர்கள் அனைவரும் ஒன்று சேர்ந்தால் முடியும். எனவே 9ம் தேதி கடைசி நாள் என்றால் இந்த வாரமே தயாராக வேண்டும். நேற்று ஜனாதிபதி மாளிகைக்கு சென்றிருந்தோம். இன்று துறவிகள் இறங்கி வந்தார்கள் என்று நினைக்கிறேன். நாளை பல்கலைக்கழக இளைஞர்கள் வெளியேறுவார்கள் என்று நினைக்கிறேன். அதனால் இதற்கெல்லாம் கடைசி நாளான அவர் வரும் 9ம் தேதி வீட்டுக்கு செல்வார்.",
        "இங்கு யாரும் சேரவோ, போராட்டத் தலைவர் ஆகவோ தேவையில்லை. இந்தப் போராட்டத்தின் பெருமை யாருக்கும் போய்விடக் கூடாது. போராட்டத்தின் பெருமையை மக்கள் ஏற்க வேண்டும். இந்த நேரத்தில் கட்சி அரசியல் தேவையற்றது. நமது பொது எதிரி யார் என்று தெரிந்து கொள்ளுங்கள். முடியும் மனிதன் முதல் முடியாதவன் வரை தெருக்களில் அலைகிறான்.\""
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஹிருணிகா பிரேமச்சந்திர",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "கடைசி நாள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ராஜபக்சேக்கள்",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "07",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "கோத்தபாய ராஜபக்ச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ராஜபக்சேக்கள்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "அந்த நாள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சஜபா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜே.வி.பி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "என்.ஏ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "முதலில்",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "சஹாபா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "9வது",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "கடைசி நாள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்த வாரம்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "நேற்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "நாளை",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "கடைசி நாள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        []
      ]
    }
  }
}