{
  "newspaper_id": "ada-derana-lk",
  "url": "http://www.adaderana.lk/news/84013/litro-to-reduce-domestic-lp-gas-prices-from-aug-05",
  "time_ut": 1659335280,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Litro to reduce domestic LP gas prices from Aug. 05",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Litro to reduce domestic LP gas prices from Aug. 05",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "The prices of Litro domestic LP gas cylinders will be reduced from 05 August 2022, says Litro chairman Muditha Pieris.",
        "He says that they will lower the price of gas in the future by a greater amount than the recent increase in prices.",
        "Speaking to the media, the Litro chairman also said that according to the gas price in the global market, the gas price is expected to be reduced by August 5.",
        "“I don’t want to say the exact price in rupees now. But I will give you a hint. We will reduce the price by more than the last increase. We increased it by around Rs. 50. But we will definitely reduce it by a lot more,” he said."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Aug. 05",
          "label": "DATE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Litro",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "05 August 2022",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Litro",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Muditha Pieris",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "Litro",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "August 5",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        []
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "Litro ගෘහස්ථ LP ගෑස් මිල අගෝස්තු 05 සිට අඩු කරයි",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "ලිට්‍රෝ ගෘහස්ථ LP ගෑස් සිලින්ඩරවල මිල 2022 අගෝස්තු 05 වැනිදා සිට අඩු කරන බව ලිට්‍රෝ සභාපති මුදිත පීරිස් මහතා පවසයි.",
        "පසුගියදා ගෑස් මිල වැඩි කළ ප්‍රමාණයට වඩා විශාල ප්‍රමාණයකින් ඉදිරියේදී ගෑස් මිල අඩු කරන බව ඔහු පවසයි.",
        "මාධ්‍ය වෙත අදහස් දක්වමින් ලිට්‍රෝ සභාපතිවරයා ද කියා සිටියේ ගෝලීය වෙළඳපොලේ ගෑස් මිලට අනුව අගෝස්තු 5 වනදා වන විට ගෑස් මිල අඩු කිරීමට අපේක්ෂා කරන බවයි.",
        "“මට දැන් නියම මිල රුපියල් වලින් කියන්න අවශ්‍ය නැහැ. නමුත් මම ඔබට ඉඟියක් දෙන්නම්. අපි පසුගිය වැඩි කිරීමට වඩා වැඩි මිල අඩු කරන්නෙමු. අපි ඒක රුපියලකින් විතර වැඩි කළා. 50. නමුත් අපි අනිවාර්යයෙන්ම එය තවත් විශාල ප්‍රමාණයකින් අඩු කරන්නෙමු,” ඔහු පැවසීය."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "අගෝස්තු 05",
          "label": "DATE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ලිට්රෝ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "2022 අගෝස්තු 05",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ලිට්රෝ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "මුදිත පීරිස්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "ලිට්රෝ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "අගෝස්තු 5",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        []
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "ஆகஸ்ட் 05 முதல் உள்நாட்டு எல்பி எரிவாயு விலையை லிட்ரோ குறைக்க உள்ளது",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "Litro உள்நாட்டு LP எரிவாயு சிலிண்டர்களின் விலைகள் 05 ஆகஸ்ட் 2022 முதல் குறைக்கப்படும் என Litro தலைவர் முடித பீரிஸ் தெரிவித்துள்ளார்.",
        "எதிர்காலத்தில் எரிவாயுவின் விலையை அண்மைய விலையேற்றத்தை விட அதிக அளவில் குறைக்கவுள்ளதாக அவர் கூறுகிறார்.",
        "ஊடகங்களுக்கு கருத்து தெரிவித்த Litro தலைவர் மேலும், உலக சந்தையில் எரிவாயு விலைக்கு ஏற்ப, ஆகஸ்ட் 5ம் தேதிக்குள் எரிவாயு விலை குறைக்கப்படும் என எதிர்பார்க்கப்படுகிறது.",
        "“இப்போது சரியான விலையை ரூபாயில் சொல்ல விரும்பவில்லை. ஆனால் நான் உங்களுக்கு ஒரு குறிப்பு தருகிறேன். கடந்த விலையை விட கூடுதலாக விலையை குறைப்போம். நாங்கள் அதை சுமார் ரூ. 50. ஆனால் கண்டிப்பாக இன்னும் நிறைய குறைப்போம்,” என்றார்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ஆகஸ்ட் 05",
          "label": "DATE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "லிட்ரோ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "05 ஆகஸ்ட் 2022",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "லிட்ரோ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "முதிதா பீரிஸ்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "லிட்ரோ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆகஸ்ட் 5",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        []
      ]
    }
  }
}