{
  "newspaper_id": "news-first-lk",
  "url": "https://www.newsfirst.lk/2022/09/03/indian-hc-meets-president-to-handover-statue-and-discuss-ties/",
  "time_ut": 1662185580,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Indian HC meets President to handover statue, and discuss ties",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Indian HC meets President to handover statue, and discuss ties",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); The Indian High Commissioner handed over a statue of Maitri Buddha brought from India to President Ranil Wickremesinghe.",
        "It added that during the discussions they reviewed all-around bilateral cooperation and agreed to further strengthen close India – Sri Lanka ties in all spheres.",
        "Indian HC meets President to handover statue, and discuss ties"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Indian",
          "label": "NORP"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "News 1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Indian",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Maitri Buddha",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "India",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "India",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Indian",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "ප්‍රතිමාව භාරදීමට සහ සබඳතා පිළිබඳව සාකච්ඡා කිරීමට ඉන්දීය මහාධිකරණය ජනපති හමුවෙයි",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); ඉන්දියාවේ සිට රැගෙන ආ මෛත්‍රී බුද්ධ ප්‍රතිමාවක් ඉන්දීය මහ කොමසාරිස්වරයා විසින් ජනාධිපති රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතා වෙත පිළිගැන්වීය.",
        "එම සාකච්ඡාවලදී ඔවුන් ද්විපාර්ශ්වික සහයෝගීතාව සමාලෝචනය කළ අතර සෑම ක්ෂේත්‍රයකම සමීප ඉන්දීය - ශ්‍රී ලංකා සබඳතා තවදුරටත් ශක්තිමත් කිරීමට එකඟ වූ බව එහි වැඩිදුරටත් සඳහන් වේ.",
        "ප්‍රතිමාව භාරදීමට සහ සබඳතා පිළිබඳව සාකච්ඡා කිරීමට ඉන්දීය මහාධිකරණය ජනපති හමුවෙයි"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ඉන්දීය",
          "label": "NORP"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "News 1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දීය",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "මෛත්‍රී බුදුන්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දීය",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "சிலையை ஒப்படைக்க குடியரசுத் தலைவரைச் சந்தித்து, உறவுகள் குறித்து விவாதிக்க இந்திய உயர்நீதிமன்றம்",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); இந்தியாவில் இருந்து கொண்டுவரப்பட்ட மைத்திரி புத்தரின் சிலையை இந்திய உயர்ஸ்தானிகர் ஜனாதிபதி ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்கவிடம் கையளித்தார்.",
        "கலந்துரையாடலின் போது அவர்கள் இருதரப்பு ஒத்துழைப்பை மறுபரிசீலனை செய்ததோடு, அனைத்து துறைகளிலும் நெருக்கமான இந்தியா - இலங்கை உறவுகளை மேலும் வலுப்படுத்த ஒப்புக்கொண்டனர்.",
        "சிலையை ஒப்படைக்க குடியரசுத் தலைவரைச் சந்தித்து, உறவுகள் குறித்து விவாதிக்க இந்திய உயர்நீதிமன்றம்"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "இந்தியன்",
          "label": "NORP"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "News 1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்தியன்",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "மைத்ரி புத்தர்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்தியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இந்தியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இந்தியன்",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}