{
  "newspaper_id": "lankadeepa-lk",
  "url": "https://www.lankadeepa.lk/news/අයි-එම්-එෆ්-සහතිකයක්-ඉල්ලයි/101-618440",
  "time_ut": 1660962732,
  "original_lang": "si",
  "original_title": "අයි.එම්.එෆ් සහතිකයක් ඉල්ලයි",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Requests an IMF certificate",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "In order to obtain approval from the Executive Board of the International Monetary Fund to extend an extended funding facility to Sri Lanka as Sri Lanka's debt has been determined to be unsustainable, the International Monetary Fund said in a statement that it needs sufficient assurances from creditors that Sri Lanka will restore debt sustainability.",
        "It is stated in the announcement that officials of the International Monetary Fund will visit Sri Lanka from the 24th to the 31st to discuss economic and financial reforms and policies with the Sri Lankan authorities.",
        "The IMF stated that the purpose of the visit was to make progress towards reaching a staff-level agreement to provide credit to Sri Lanka soon.",
        "The International Monetary Fund said that Masahiro Nozaki and Peter Brewer will lead the team of IMF officials visiting Sri Lanka."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "the Executive Board",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the International Monetary Fund",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka's",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the International Monetary Fund",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the International Monetary Fund",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the 24th to the 31st",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lankan",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "IMF",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "The International Monetary Fund",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Masahiro Nozaki",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Peter Brewer",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "අයි.එම්.එෆ් සහතිකයක් ඉල්ලයි",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ ණය තිරසර නොවන බව තීරණය කර ඇති නිසා ශ්‍රී ලංකාවට විස්තීරණ අරමුදල් පහසුකමක් ලබා දීමට ජාත්‍යන්තර මූල්‍ය අරමුදලේ විධායක මණ්ඩලයෙන් අනුමැතිය ලබා ගැනීම සඳහා ශ්‍රී ලංකාව ණය තිරසරභාවය නැවත ස්ථාපනය කරන බවට ප්‍රමාණවත් සහතිකයක් ණය හිමියන්ගෙන් අවශ්‍ය බව ජාත්‍යන්තර මූල්‍ය අරමුදල නිවේදනයක් නිකුත් කරමින් ප්‍රකාශ කළේය.",
        "ආර්ථික සහ මූල්‍ය ප්‍රතිසංස්කරණ,ප්‍රතිපත්ති පිළිබඳව ශ්‍රී ලංකා බලධාරීන් සමඟ සාකච්ඡා කිරීමට එළඹෙන 24 වෙනිදා සිට 31 වෙනිදා දක්වා ජාත්‍යන්තර මූල්‍ය අරමුදලේ නිලධාරීන් ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ සංචාරයක නිරත වන බව එම නිවේදනයේ සඳහන් වේ.",
        "නුදුරේදීම ශ්‍රී ලංකාවට ණය මුදලක් ලබා දීම සඳහා කාර්ය මණ්ඩල මට්ටමේ ගිවිසුමකට එළඹීම සඳහා ප්‍රගතියක් ලබා ගැනීම සංචාරයේ අරමුණ බව ජාත්‍යන්තර මූල්‍ය අරමුදල ප්‍රකාශ කළේය.",
        "මසහිරෝ නොසාකි සහ පීටර් බෲවර් මහත්වරුන් ශ්‍රී ලංකාවට පැමිණෙන ජාත්‍යන්තර මූල්‍ය අරමුදලේ නිලධාරීන් කණ්ඩායමට නායකත්වය දෙනු ඇතැයි ජාත්‍යන්තර මූල්‍ය අරමුදල පැවසුවේය."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "විධායක මණ්ඩලය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජාත්‍යන්තර මුල්‍ය අරමුදල",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජාත්‍යන්තර මුල්‍ය අරමුදල",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ජාත්‍යන්තර මුල්‍ය අරමුදල",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "24 සිට 31 දක්වා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලාංකික",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "IMF",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ජාත්‍යන්තර මුල්‍ය අරමුදල",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Masahiro Nozaki",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "පීටර් බෲවර්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "IMF சான்றிதழைக் கோருகிறது",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "இலங்கையின் கடன் தாங்க முடியாதது என தீர்மானிக்கப்பட்டுள்ள நிலையில், இலங்கைக்கு நீட்டிக்கப்பட்ட நிதி வசதியை வழங்குவதற்கு சர்வதேச நாணய நிதியத்தின் நிறைவேற்று சபையின் அனுமதியைப் பெறுவதற்கு, கடனளிப்பவர்களிடமிருந்து போதுமான உத்தரவாதம் தேவை என்று சர்வதேச நாணய நிதியம் அறிக்கையொன்றில் தெரிவித்துள்ளது. கடன் நிலைத்தன்மையை இலங்கை மீட்டெடுக்கும்.",
        "சர்வதேச நாணய நிதியத்தின் அதிகாரிகள் எதிர்வரும் 24 ஆம் திகதி முதல் 31 ஆம் திகதி வரை இலங்கைக்கு விஜயம் செய்து பொருளாதார மற்றும் நிதி சீர்திருத்தங்கள் மற்றும் கொள்கைகள் தொடர்பில் இலங்கை அதிகாரிகளுடன் கலந்துரையாடவுள்ளதாக அந்த அறிவிப்பில் குறிப்பிடப்பட்டுள்ளது.",
        "இலங்கைக்கு விரைவில் கடனுதவி வழங்குவதற்கான பணியாளர் மட்ட உடன்படிக்கையை எட்டுவதற்கு முன்னேற்றம் காண்பதே இந்த விஜயத்தின் நோக்கமாகும் என சர்வதேச நாணய நிதியம் தெரிவித்துள்ளது.",
        "இலங்கைக்கு விஜயம் செய்யும் சர்வதேச நாணய நிதியத்தின் அதிகாரிகள் குழுவிற்கு மசாஹிரோ நோஸாகி மற்றும் பீட்டர் ப்ரூவர் ஆகியோர் தலைமை தாங்கவுள்ளதாக சர்வதேச நாணய நிதியம் தெரிவித்துள்ளது."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "நிர்வாக குழு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "சர்வதேச நாணய நிதியம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கையின்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சர்வதேச நாணய நிதியம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "சர்வதேச நாணய நிதியம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "24 முதல் 31 வரை",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "IMF",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "சர்வதேச நாணய நிதியம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Masahiro Nozaki",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "பீட்டர் ப்ரூவர்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}