{
  "newspaper_id": "news-first-lk",
  "url": "https://www.newsfirst.lk/2022/08/15/s-p-pushes-sri-lankan-bonds-deeper-into-junk-territory-with-default-rating/",
  "time_ut": 1660572420,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "S&P pushes Sri Lankan bonds deeper into junk territory with ‘default’ rating",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "S&P pushes Sri Lankan bonds deeper into junk territory with ‘default’ rating",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "(Reuters) – Global ratings agency S&P Global on Monday slashed its rating on Sri Lankan bonds to 'D', representing default, following missed interest and principal payments.",
        "The South Asian nation, which had defaulted on a bond payment earlier this year and has $12 billion in overseas debt with private creditors, has been battling the worst financial crisis in its independent history.",
        "Sri Lanka's external public debt freeze prevents payment of interest and principal obligations due on the government's international sovereign bonds.",
        "S&P said it did not expect the Sri Lankan government, which remains in default on some foreign currency obligations, to make the bond payments within 30 calendar days after their due dates.",
        "The ratings agency affirmed its 'SD' long-term and 'SD' short-term foreign currency sovereign ratings on Sri Lanka, as well as reiterated the outlook for the island nation at 'negative'.",
        "The country is considering a restructuring of local and foreign debt. It is due to restart bailout talks with the International Monetary Fund (IMF) in August in the hope of securing $3 billion in funding.",
        "S&P pushes Sri Lankan bonds deeper into junk territory with ‘default’ rating",
        "India and Sri Lanka two sides of the same coin, must forge ahead together –President",
        "Chinese Research/Survey vessel Yuan Wang 5 enters the Sea of Sri Lanka",
        "Sri Lanka Navy Marines complete RIMPAC 2022 hosted by the US Pacific Fleet"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "S&P",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "Sri Lankan",
          "label": "NORP"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Reuters",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "S&P Global",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Monday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lankan",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "South Asian",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "earlier this year",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "$12 billion",
            "label": "MONEY"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka's",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "S&P",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lankan",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "30 calendar days",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the International Monetary Fund",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "August",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "$3 billion",
            "label": "MONEY"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "S&P",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lankan",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "India",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "two",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Chinese Research/Survey",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Yuan Wang",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Sea of Sri Lanka",
            "label": "LOC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the US Pacific Fleet",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "S&P ශ්‍රී ලංකා බැඳුම්කර 'පෙරනිමි' ශ්‍රේණිගත කිරීම සමඟ කුණු ප්‍රදේශයට ගැඹුරට තල්ලු කරයි",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "(රොයිටර්) - Global ratings agency S&P Global විසින් සඳුදා ශ්‍රී ලංකා බැඳුම්කරවල ශ්‍රේණිගත කිරීම 'D' දක්වා අඩු කරන ලද අතර එය පැහැර හැරීම් නියෝජනය කරමින්, මග හැරුණු පොලී සහ මූලික ගෙවීම් හේතුවෙන්.",
        "මෙම වසර මුලදී බැඳුම්කර ගෙවීම පැහැර හරින ලද සහ පුද්ගලික ණය හිමියන් සමඟ ඩොලර් බිලියන 12 ක විදේශ ණය ඇති දකුණු ආසියානු ජාතිය, එහි ස්වාධීන ඉතිහාසයේ නරකම මූල්‍ය අර්බුදය සමඟ පොරබදමින් සිටී.",
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ බාහිර රාජ්‍ය ණය කැටි කිරීම රජයේ ජාත්‍යන්තර ස්වෛරීත්ව බැඳුම්කර සඳහා ගෙවිය යුතු පොලී සහ මූලික වගකීම් ගෙවීම වළක්වයි.",
        "S&P පැවසුවේ, සමහර විදේශ මුදල් බැඳීම් පැහැර හරිමින් සිටින ශ්‍රී ලංකා රජය ඔවුන්ගේ නියමිත දිනට පසුව දින දර්ශන දින 30ක් ඇතුළත බැඳුම්කර ගෙවීම් සිදු කරනු ඇතැයි අපේක්ෂා නොකරන බවයි.",
        "ශ්‍රේණිගත කිරීමේ නියෝජිතායතනය ශ්‍රී ලංකාව පිළිබඳ එහි 'SD' දිගුකාලීන සහ 'SD' කෙටි කාලීන විදේශ මුදල් ස්වෛරී ශ්‍රේණිගත කිරීම් තහවුරු කළ අතර, දිවයිනේ ජාතිය සඳහා 'ඍණාත්මක' ඉදිරි දැක්ම නැවත අවධාරණය කළේය.",
        "දේශීය හා විදේශීය ණය ප්‍රතිව්‍යුහගත කිරීමක් ගැන රට සලකා බලයි. එය ඩොලර් බිලියන 3 ක අරමුදල් ලබා ගැනීමේ බලාපොරොත්තුවෙන් අගෝස්තු මාසයේදී ජාත්‍යන්තර මූල්‍ය අරමුදල (IMF) සමඟ ඇපදීමේ සාකච්ඡා නැවත ආරම්භ කිරීමට නියමිතය.",
        "S&P ශ්‍රී ලංකා බැඳුම්කර 'පෙරනිමි' ශ්‍රේණිගත කිරීම සමඟ කුණු ප්‍රදේශයට ගැඹුරට තල්ලු කරයි",
        "ඉන්දියාව සහ ශ්‍රී ලංකාව එකම කාසියක දෙපැත්තක්, එකට ඉදිරියට යා යුතුයි -ජනාධිපති",
        "චීන පර්යේෂණ/සමීක්ෂණ යාත්‍රාව යුවාන් වැන්ග් 5 ශ්‍රී ලංකා මුහුදට ඇතුළු වෙයි",
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකා නාවික හමුදා මැරීන් භටයින් එක්සත් ජනපද පැසිෆික් බලඇණිය විසින් සත්කාරකත්වය සපයන ලද RIMPAC 2022 සම්පූර්ණ කරයි"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "S&P",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "ශ්‍රී ලාංකික",
          "label": "NORP"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "රොයිටර්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "S&P Global",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "සඳුදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලාංකික",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "දකුණු ආසියානු",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "මීට පෙර මෙම වසරේ",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඩොලර් බිලියන 12 කි",
            "label": "MONEY"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "S&P",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලාංකික",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "දින දර්ශන දින 30",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ජාත්‍යන්තර මුල්‍ය අරමුදල",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "අගෝස්තු",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඩොලර් බිලියන 3 යි",
            "label": "MONEY"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "S&P",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලාංකික",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "දෙක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "චීන පර්යේෂණ/සමීක්ෂණය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Yuan Wang",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකා මුහුද",
            "label": "LOC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "එක්සත් ජනපද පැසිෆික් බලඇණිය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "S&P இலங்கைப் பத்திரங்களை 'இயல்புநிலை' மதிப்பீட்டில் குப்பைப் பகுதிக்குள் ஆழமாகத் தள்ளுகிறது",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "(ராய்ட்டர்ஸ்) – Global ratings agency S&P Global திங்களன்று இலங்கைப் பத்திரங்கள் மீதான மதிப்பீட்டை 'D' ஆகக் குறைத்துள்ளது, இது தவறிய வட்டி மற்றும் அசல் கொடுப்பனவுகளைத் தொடர்ந்து இயல்புநிலையைக் குறிக்கிறது.",
        "தெற்காசிய நாடு, இந்த ஆண்டின் தொடக்கத்தில் கடன் பத்திரத்தை செலுத்தத் தவறி, தனியார் கடனாளிகளிடம் $12 பில்லியன் வெளிநாட்டுக் கடனைக் கொண்டுள்ளது, அதன் சுதந்திர வரலாற்றில் மிக மோசமான நிதி நெருக்கடியுடன் போராடி வருகிறது.",
        "இலங்கையின் வெளிநாட்டு பொதுக் கடன் முடக்கம் அரசாங்கத்தின் சர்வதேச இறையாண்மைப் பத்திரங்கள் மீதான வட்டி மற்றும் முதன்மைக் கடப்பாடுகளை செலுத்துவதைத் தடுக்கிறது.",
        "சில வெளிநாட்டு நாணயக் கடமைகளில் தவறியிருக்கும் இலங்கை அரசாங்கம், பத்திரப்பதிவுகளை 30 நாட்காட்டி நாட்களுக்குள் செலுத்தும் என்று எதிர்பார்க்கவில்லை என்று S&P கூறியது.",
        "மதிப்பீட்டு நிறுவனம் இலங்கை மீதான அதன் 'SD' நீண்ட கால மற்றும் 'SD' குறுகிய கால வெளிநாட்டு நாணய இறையாண்மை மதிப்பீடுகளை உறுதிப்படுத்தியது, அத்துடன் தீவின் தேசத்திற்கான கண்ணோட்டத்தை 'எதிர்மறை' என மீண்டும் வலியுறுத்தியது.",
        "உள்நாட்டு மற்றும் வெளிநாட்டு கடனை மறுசீரமைக்க நாடு பரிசீலித்து வருகிறது. 3 பில்லியன் டாலர் நிதியைப் பெறும் நம்பிக்கையில் ஆகஸ்ட் மாதம் சர்வதேச நாணய நிதியத்துடன் (IMF) பிணை எடுப்புப் பேச்சுக்களை மீண்டும் தொடங்க உள்ளது.",
        "S&P இலங்கைப் பத்திரங்களை 'இயல்புநிலை' மதிப்பீட்டில் குப்பைப் பகுதிக்குள் ஆழமாகத் தள்ளுகிறது",
        "இந்தியாவும் இலங்கையும் ஒரே நாணயத்தின் இரு பக்கங்கள், ஒன்றாக முன்னேற வேண்டும் - ஜனாதிபதி",
        "சீன ஆராய்ச்சி/ஆய்வுக் கப்பல் யுவான் வாங் 5 இலங்கைக் கடலுக்குள் நுழைந்தது",
        "இலங்கை கடற்படை கடற்படையினர் அமெரிக்க பசிபிக் கடற்படையால் நடத்தப்பட்ட RIMPAC 2022 ஐ நிறைவு செய்தனர்"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "எஸ்&பி",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "இலங்கை",
          "label": "NORP"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ராய்ட்டர்ஸ்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "எஸ்&பி குளோபல்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "திங்கட்கிழமை",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "தெற்காசிய",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்த ஆண்டின் தொடக்கத்தில்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "$12 பில்லியன்",
            "label": "MONEY"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கையின்",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "எஸ்&பி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "30 காலண்டர் நாட்கள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "சர்வதேச நாணய நிதியம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆகஸ்ட்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "$3 பில்லியன்",
            "label": "MONEY"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "எஸ்&பி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இந்தியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இரண்டு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "சீன ஆராய்ச்சி/கணக்கெடுப்பு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Yuan Wang",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை கடல்",
            "label": "LOC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "அமெரிக்க பசிபிக் கடற்படை",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}