{
  "newspaper_id": "news-first-lk",
  "url": "https://www.newsfirst.lk/2022/07/06/sri-lanka-seeks-credit-assistance-from-russia-to-import-fuel/",
  "time_ut": 1657104000,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Sri Lanka seeks Credit Assistance from Russia to import fuel",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Sri Lanka seeks Credit Assistance from Russia to import fuel",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); Sri Lankan President Gotabaya Rajapaksa said he had a very productive telephone conversation with Russia President Vladimir Putin.",
        "“While thanking him for all the support extended by his government to overcome the challenges of the past, I requested an offer of credit support to import fuel to Sri Lanka in defeating the current economic challenges,” said the President on Twitter.",
        "President Rajapaksa has also requested to restart Aeroflot operations in Sri Lanka.",
        "“We unanimously agreed that strengthening bilateral relations in sectors such as tourism, trade & culture was paramount in reinforcing the friendship our two nations share,” tweeted the President.",
        "Sri Lanka seeks Credit Assistance from Russia to import fuel"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Sri Lanka",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "Russia",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lankan",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Gotabaya Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Russia",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Vladimir Putin",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Twitter",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Aeroflot",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "two",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Russia",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "ඉන්ධන ආනයනය කිරීම සඳහා ශ්‍රී ලංකාව රුසියාවෙන් ණය ආධාර අපේක්ෂා කරයි",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); තමන් රුසියානු ජනාධිපති ව්ලැඩිමීර් පුටින් සමඟ ඉතා ඵලදායී දුරකථන සංවාදයක නිරත වූ බව ශ්‍රී ලංකා ජනාධිපති ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ මහතා පැවසීය.",
        "\"පසුගිය අභියෝග ජය ගැනීම සඳහා තම රජය ලබාදුන් සියලු සහයෝගයට ස්තූතිය පුද කරන අතරම වත්මන් ආර්ථික අභියෝග පරාජය කිරීම සඳහා ශ්‍රී ලංකාවට ඉන්ධන ආනයනය කිරීමට ණය ආධාරයක් ලබාදෙන ලෙස මා ඉල්ලා සිටියා\" යනුවෙන් ජනාධිපතිවරයා ට්විටර් පණිවුඩයක් නිකුත් කරමින් කියා සිටියේය.",
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ Aeroflot මෙහෙයුම් නැවත ආරම්භ කරන ලෙස ද ජනාධිපතිතුමා ඉල්ලීමක් කර ඇත.",
        "“අපගේ ජාතීන් දෙක බෙදාහදා ගන්නා මිත්‍රත්වය ශක්තිමත් කිරීමේදී සංචාරක ව්‍යාපාරය, වෙළඳ සහ සංස්කෘතිය වැනි අංශවල ද්විපාර්ශ්වික සබඳතා ශක්තිමත් කිරීම ප්‍රමුඛ වන බවට අපි ඒකමතිකව එකඟ වෙමු,” ජනාධිපතිවරයා ට්වීට් කළේය.",
        "ඉන්ධන ආනයනය කිරීම සඳහා ශ්‍රී ලංකාව රුසියාවෙන් ණය ආධාර අපේක්ෂා කරයි"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "රුසියාව",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලාංකික",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "රුසියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ව්ලැඩිමීර් පුටින්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ට්විටර්",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Aeroflot",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "දෙක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "රුසියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "எரிபொருளை இறக்குமதி செய்வதற்கு ரஷ்யாவிடம் இருந்து இலங்கை கடன் உதவியை நாடுகிறது",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); ரஷ்ய ஜனாதிபதி விளாடிமிர் புட்டினுடன் தாம் மிகவும் பயனுள்ள தொலைபேசி உரையாடலை நடத்தியதாக இலங்கை ஜனாதிபதி கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ச தெரிவித்துள்ளார்.",
        "\"கடந்த கால சவால்களை வெற்றிகொள்வதற்கு அவரது அரசாங்கம் வழங்கிய அனைத்து ஆதரவிற்கும் நன்றி தெரிவிக்கும் அதே வேளையில், தற்போதைய பொருளாதார சவால்களை தோற்கடிப்பதற்காக இலங்கைக்கு எரிபொருளை இறக்குமதி செய்வதற்கு கடன் உதவியை வழங்குமாறு கோரியுள்ளேன்\" என ஜனாதிபதி டுவிட்டரில் தெரிவித்துள்ளார்.",
        "இலங்கையில் ஏரோஃப்ளோட் நடவடிக்கைகளை மீண்டும் தொடங்குமாறு ஜனாதிபதி ராஜபக்ஷவும் கோரிக்கை விடுத்துள்ளார்.",
        "\"சுற்றுலா, வர்த்தகம் மற்றும் கலாச்சாரம் போன்ற துறைகளில் இருதரப்பு உறவுகளை வலுப்படுத்துவது நமது இரு நாடுகளும் பகிர்ந்து கொள்ளும் நட்பை வலுப்படுத்துவதில் மிக முக்கியமானது என்பதை நாங்கள் ஒருமனதாக ஒப்புக்கொண்டோம்\" என்று ஜனாதிபதி ட்வீட் செய்தார்.",
        "எரிபொருளை இறக்குமதி செய்வதற்கு ரஷ்யாவிடம் இருந்து இலங்கை கடன் உதவியை நாடுகிறது"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "இலங்கை",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "ரஷ்யா",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரஷ்யா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "விளாடிமிர் புடின்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ட்விட்டர்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ராஜபக்சே",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஏரோஃப்ளோட்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இரண்டு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரஷ்யா",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}