{
  "newspaper_id": "ada-derana-lk",
  "url": "http://www.adaderana.lk/news/83442/lp-gas-shipment-further-delayed",
  "time_ut": 1657012200,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "LP Gas shipment further delayed",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "LP Gas shipment further delayed",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "Litro Gas company states that the ship carrying 3,724 metric tonnes of liquified petroleum (LP) gas which was expected to reach the country between the 6th and 8th of this month would be further delayed.",
        "It has been informed that the ship would be delayed further due to changes in the weather conditions.",
        "Accordingly, the ship is expected to reach the island on 9th of July.",
        "The LP gas shipment is scheduled to arrive the island in accordance with the agreement signed between the World Bank and the Litro Gas company for the import of 100,000 metric tonnes of LP gas.",
        "Another ship carrying LP gas is expected to arrive the country between 11th and 12th of July, said Litro chairman Muditha Peris."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Litro Gas company",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "3,724 metric tonnes",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "6th",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "9th of July",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the World Bank",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Litro Gas company",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "100,000 metric tonnes",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "between 11th and 12th of July",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Litro",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Muditha Peris",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "LP ගෑස් ප්‍රවාහනය තවදුරටත් ප්‍රමාදයි",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "ලිට්‍රෝ ගෑස් සමාගම පවසන්නේ මේ මස 6 වැනිදා සිට 8 වැනිදා දක්වා දිවයිනට පැමිණීමට නියමිතව තිබූ ද්‍රව පෙට්‍රෝලියම් ගෑස් මෙට්‍රික් ටොන් 3724ක් රැගත් නෞකාව තවදුරටත් ප්‍රමාද වන බවයි.",
        "කාලගුණික විපර්යාස හේතුවෙන් නෞකාව තවදුරටත් ප්‍රමාද වනු ඇති බවටයි දන්වා ඇත්තේ.",
        "ඒ අනුව එම නෞකාව ජුලි මස 9 වනදා දිවයිනට ළඟා වීමට නියමිතයි.",
        "LP ගෑස් මෙට්‍රික් ටොන් ලක්ෂයක් ආනයනය කිරීම සඳහා ලෝක බැංකුව සහ ලිට්‍රෝ ගෑස් සමාගම අතර අත්සන් කර ඇති ගිවිසුමට අනුව මෙම LP ගෑස් තොගය දිවයිනට පැමිණීමට නියමිතයි.",
        "එල්පී ගෑස් රැගත් තවත් නෞකාවක් ජූලි 11 සහ 12 අතර දිවයිනට පැමිණීමට අපේක්ෂා කරන බව ලිට්‍රෝ සභාපති මුදිත පීරිස් මහතා පවසයි."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ලිට්‍රෝ ගෑස් සමාගම",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "මෙට්‍රික් ටොන් 3,724 කි",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "6 වැනි",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "ජූලි 9 වෙනිදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ලෝක බැංකුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ලිට්රෝ ගෑස් සමාගම",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "මෙට්‍රික් ටොන් 100,000 කි",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ජූලි 11 සහ 12 අතර",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ලිට්රෝ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "මුදිත පීරිස්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "எல்பி எரிவாயு ஏற்றுமதி மேலும் தாமதமானது",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "இம்மாதம் 6ஆம் திகதி முதல் 8ஆம் திகதி வரை நாட்டை வந்தடையும் என எதிர்பார்க்கப்பட்ட 3,724 மெற்றிக் தொன் திரவ வாயுவை ஏற்றிச் செல்லும் கப்பல் மேலும் தாமதமாகும் என லிட்ரோ கேஸ் நிறுவனம் தெரிவித்துள்ளது.",
        "காலநிலையில் ஏற்பட்டுள்ள மாற்றங்கள் காரணமாக கப்பல் மேலும் தாமதமாகும் என தெரிவிக்கப்பட்டுள்ளது.",
        "அதன்படி, கப்பல் ஜூலை 9ஆம் தேதி தீவை வந்தடையும் என்று எதிர்பார்க்கப்படுகிறது.",
        "100,000 மெட்ரிக் டன் எல்பி எரிவாயு இறக்குமதிக்காக உலக வங்கிக்கும் லிட்ரோ கேஸ் நிறுவனத்துக்கும் இடையில் கைச்சாத்திடப்பட்ட உடன்படிக்கையின் பிரகாரம் எல்பி எரிவாயு ஏற்றுமதி தீவை வந்தடையத் திட்டமிடப்பட்டுள்ளது.",
        "எல்.பி எரிவாயுவை ஏற்றிச் செல்லும் மற்றுமொரு கப்பல் ஜூலை 11ஆம் திகதிக்கும் 12ஆம் திகதிக்கும் இடையில் நாட்டை வந்தடையும் என எதிர்பார்க்கப்படுவதாக லிட்ரோ நிறுவனத்தின் தலைவர் முதித பெரிஸ் தெரிவித்துள்ளார்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "லிட்ரோ எரிவாயு நிறுவனம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "3,724 மெட்ரிக் டன்",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "6வது",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஜூலை 9 ஆம் தேதி",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "உலக வங்கி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "லிட்ரோ எரிவாயு நிறுவனம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "100,000 மெட்ரிக் டன்",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஜூலை 11 மற்றும் 12 க்கு இடையில்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "லிட்ரோ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "முதிதா பெரிஸ்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}