{
  "newspaper_id": "daily-ft-lk",
  "url": "https://www.ft.lk/business/Provisional-approval-for-two-Adani-Group-wind-power-projects-worth-500-m/34-738774",
  "time_ut": 1660688200,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Provisional approval for two Adani Group wind power projects worth $ 500 m",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Provisional approval for two Adani Group wind power projects worth $ 500 m",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "Minister Wijesekera assures all held up or delayed sustainable power projects and agreements will be expedited",
        "21 of 46 projects that were delayed due to Sri Lanka Electricity Act amendments will enter into power purchase agreements next week",
        "Power and Energy Minister Kanchana Wijesekera yesterday confirmed that provisional approvals were issued for two Adani Group wind projects worth $ 500 million.",
        "These include a 286MW wind power project in Mannar and a 234MW wind power project in Pooneryn.",
        "Minister Wijesekera made the disclosure during a meeting with officials of the Ceylon Electricity Board (CEB) and Sri Lanka Sustainable Energy Authority (SLEA) yesterday to discuss the progress of renewable energy projects. He also said that 21 of 46 projects that were delayed due to Sri Lanka Electricity Act amendments will enter into power purchase agreements next week.",
        "In addition, he said 26 renewable proposals from EOIs that were given provisional approvals will be expedited with grid clearance and transmission plans, whilst other proposals are to be evaluated within the next 30-days."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "two",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "Adani Group",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "500",
          "label": "MONEY"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Wijesekera",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "21",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "46",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "next week",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Energy",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kanchana Wijesekera",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "yesterday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "two",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Adani Group",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "$ 500 million",
            "label": "MONEY"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "286MW",
            "label": "PRODUCT"
          },
          {
            "text": "Mannar",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "234MW",
            "label": "PRODUCT"
          },
          {
            "text": "Pooneryn",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Wijesekera",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Ceylon Electricity Board",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka Sustainable Energy Authority",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "yesterday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "21",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "46",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "next week",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "26",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "the next 30-days",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "ඩොලර් මිලියන 500ක් වටිනා Adani සමූහ ව්‍යාපෘති දෙකක් සඳහා තාවකාලික අනුමැතිය",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "අත්හිටුවා ඇති හෝ ප්‍රමාද වී ඇති සියලුම තිරසාර විදුලි ව්‍යාපෘති සහ ගිවිසුම් කඩිනම් කරන බවට අමාත්‍ය විජේසේකර සහතික වෙයි",
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකා විදුලිබල පනත් සංශෝධන හේතුවෙන් ප්‍රමාද වූ ව්‍යාපෘති 46න් 21ක් ලබන සතියේ විදුලිය මිලදී ගැනීමේ ගිවිසුම්වලට එළැඹේ.",
        "ඩොලර් මිලියන 500ක අදානි සමූහ ව්‍යාපෘති දෙකක් සඳහා තාවකාලික අනුමැතිය ලබාදුන් බව විදුලිබල හා බලශක්ති අමාත්‍ය කංචන විජේසේකර මහතා ඊයේ තහවුරු කළේය.",
        "මන්නාරමේ මෙගාවොට් 286ක සුළං බල ව්‍යාපෘතියක් සහ පුනරීන් ප්‍රදේශයේ මෙගාවොට් 234ක සුළං බල ව්‍යාපෘතියක් ඊට ඇතුළත්.",
        "පුනර්ජනනීය බලශක්ති ව්‍යාපෘතිවල ප්‍රගතිය පිළිබඳව සාකච්ඡා කිරීම සඳහා ලංකා විදුලිබල මණ්ඩලයේ (CEB) සහ ශ්‍රී ලංකා සුනිත්‍ය බලශක්ති අධිකාරියේ (SLEA) නිලධාරීන් සමඟ ඊයේ පැවති සාකච්ඡාවකදී අමාත්‍ය විජේසේකර මහතා මේ බව අනාවරණය කළේය. ශ්‍රී ලංකා විදුලිබල පනත් සංශෝධන හේතුවෙන් ප්‍රමාද වූ ව්‍යාපෘති 46 න් 21 ක් ලබන සතියේ විදුලිය මිලදී ගැනීමේ ගිවිසුම්වලට එළඹෙන බව ද ඔහු පැවසීය.",
        "ඊට අමතරව, තාවකාලික අනුමැතිය ලබා දී ඇති EOIs වෙතින් පුනර්ජනනීය යෝජනා 26 ක් ජාල නිෂ්කාශනය සහ සම්ප්‍රේෂණ සැලසුම් සමඟ කඩිනම් කරන අතර අනෙකුත් යෝජනා ඉදිරි දින 30 තුළ ඇගයීමට ලක් කිරීමට නියමිත බව ඔහු පැවසීය."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "දෙක",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "Adani Group",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "500",
          "label": "MONEY"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "විජේසේකර",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "21",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "46",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඊළඟ සතිය",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශක්තිය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "කාංචන විජේසේකර",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඊයේ",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "දෙක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Adani Group",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඩොලර් මිලියන 500 කි",
            "label": "MONEY"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "286MW",
            "label": "PRODUCT"
          },
          {
            "text": "මන්නාරම",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "234MW",
            "label": "PRODUCT"
          },
          {
            "text": "පුනරීන්",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "විජේසේකර",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ලංකා විදුලිබල මණ්ඩලය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකා සුනිත්‍ය බලශක්ති අධිකාරිය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඊයේ",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "21",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "46",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඊළඟ සතිය",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "26",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉදිරි දින 30",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "$500 மில்லியன் மதிப்பிலான இரண்டு அதானி குழும காற்றாலை மின் திட்டங்களுக்கு தற்காலிக ஒப்புதல்",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "நிலுவையில் உள்ள அல்லது தாமதமான அனைத்து நிலையான மின் திட்டங்கள் மற்றும் ஒப்பந்தங்கள் விரைவுபடுத்தப்படும் என அமைச்சர் விஜேசேகர உறுதியளித்துள்ளார்.",
        "இலங்கை மின்சார சட்டத் திருத்தங்கள் காரணமாக தாமதமான 46 திட்டங்களில் 21 திட்டங்களுக்கு அடுத்த வாரம் மின்சாரம் கொள்வனவு ஒப்பந்தங்கள் மேற்கொள்ளப்படவுள்ளன.",
        "500 மில்லியன் டொலர் பெறுமதியான இரண்டு அதானி குழும காற்றாலை திட்டங்களுக்கு தற்காலிக அனுமதி வழங்கப்பட்டுள்ளதாக மின்சக்தி மற்றும் எரிசக்தி அமைச்சர் காஞ்சன விஜேசேகர நேற்று உறுதிப்படுத்தினார்.",
        "மன்னாரில் 286 மெகாவாட் காற்றாலை மின் திட்டமும் பூனேரியில் 234 மெகாவாட் காற்றாலை மின் திட்டமும் இதில் அடங்கும்.",
        "புதுப்பிக்கத்தக்க எரிசக்தி திட்டங்களின் முன்னேற்றம் குறித்து ஆலோசிப்பதற்காக இலங்கை மின்சார சபை மற்றும் இலங்கை நிலையான எரிசக்தி அதிகார சபையின் (SLEA) அதிகாரிகளுடன் நேற்று இடம்பெற்ற சந்திப்பின் போது அமைச்சர் விஜேசேகர இந்த தகவலை வெளியிட்டார். இலங்கை மின்சார சட்டத் திருத்தங்கள் காரணமாக தாமதமான 46 திட்டங்களில் 21 திட்டங்களுக்கு அடுத்த வாரம் மின்சாரம் கொள்வனவு ஒப்பந்தங்கள் மேற்கொள்ளப்படும் என்றும் அவர் கூறினார்.",
        "கூடுதலாக, தற்காலிக ஒப்புதல்கள் வழங்கப்பட்ட EOI களின் 26 புதுப்பிக்கத்தக்க திட்டங்கள் கிரிட் கிளியரன்ஸ் மற்றும் டிரான்ஸ்மிஷன் திட்டங்களுடன் விரைவுபடுத்தப்படும், மற்ற திட்டங்கள் அடுத்த 30 நாட்களுக்குள் மதிப்பீடு செய்யப்படும் என்றார்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "இரண்டு",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "அதானி குழுமம்",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "500",
          "label": "MONEY"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "விஜேசேகர",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "21",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "46",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "அடுத்த வாரம்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஆற்றல்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "காஞ்சனா விஜேசேகர",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "நேற்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இரண்டு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "அதானி குழுமம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "$ 500 மில்லியன்",
            "label": "MONEY"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "286மெகாவாட்",
            "label": "PRODUCT"
          },
          {
            "text": "மன்னார்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "234மெகாவாட்",
            "label": "PRODUCT"
          },
          {
            "text": "பூனேரின்",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "விஜேசேகர",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை மின்சார சபை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை நிலையான எரிசக்தி அதிகாரசபை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "நேற்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "21",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "46",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "அடுத்த வாரம்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "26",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "அடுத்த 30 நாட்கள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}