{
  "newspaper_id": "island-lk",
  "url": "http://island.lk/hnb-joins-slt-mobitel-in-enhancing-e-commerce-capabilities-for-smes-with-cochchi-lk/",
  "time_ut": 1661453640,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "HNB joins SLT-MOBITEL in enhancing e-commerce capabilities for SMEs with Cochchi.lk",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "HNB joins SLT-MOBITEL in enhancing e-commerce capabilities for SMEs with Cochchi.lk",
      "author": "Thilina Walpola",
      "body_lines": [
        "Connecting local SMEs to new e-commerce markets and buyers, Sri Lanka’s most digitally innovative bank, HNB PLC, partnered with SLT-MOBITEL to offer SMEs free access to the new online trading platform Cochchi.lk.",
        "The partnership between the two industry giants will provide HNB SMEs additional benefits when onboarding to the new e-commerce platform. HNB Deputy general Manager- Retail & SME Banking, Sanjay Wijemanne, HNB Assistant General Manager- SME, Kailaivasan Indravasan, HNB Head of SME Products & Partnerships, Niluka Amarasinghe, and SLT Chief Information and Digital Officer, Tilak Gamlath, SLT General Manager- Digital Transformation Projects, Ishari Siriwardane, SLT Deputy General Manager Digital Projects, Dinesh Perera and SLT Senior Manager (Marketing)-SME Product Development, Lalwin De Zoysa were present at a special ceremony held to commemorate the partnership.",
        "Hemas partners with Clean Ocean Force to safeguard Negombo’s threatened ecosystems",
        "Leave a Reply Cancel replyYour email address will not be published. Required fields are marked *Comment Name *",
        "Save my name, email, and website in this browser for the next time I comment."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "HNB",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "SLT-MOBITEL",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "Cochchi.lk",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka’s",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "HNB PLC",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "SLT-MOBITEL",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Cochchi.lk",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "two",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "HNB",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "HNB",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Manager- Retail & SME Banking",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sanjay Wijemanne",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "HNB",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Manager- SME",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kailaivasan Indravasan",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "HNB Head",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "SME Products & Partnerships",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Niluka Amarasinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "SLT",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Digital Officer",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Tilak Gamlath",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Digital Transformation Projects",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ishari Siriwardane",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "SLT",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Digital Projects",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Perera",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "SLT",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Lalwin De Zoysa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Clean Ocean Force",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Negombo",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [],
        []
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "Cochchi.lk සමඟින් කුඩා හා මධ්‍ය පරිමාණ ව්‍යවසායකයින් සඳහා ඊ-වාණිජ්‍ය හැකියාවන් වැඩිදියුණු කිරීමට HNB SLT-MOBITEL සමඟ එක්වෙයි",
      "author": "තිළිණ වල්පොල",
      "body_lines": [
        "දේශීය කුඩා හා මධ්‍ය පරිමාණ ව්‍යවසායකයින් නව ඊ-වාණිජ්‍ය වෙලඳපොලවල් සහ ගැනුම්කරුවන් වෙත සම්බන්ධ කරමින්, ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ වඩාත්ම ඩිජිටල් නවෝත්පාදන බැංකුව වන HNB PLC, නව මාර්ගගත වෙළඳ වේදිකාවක් වන Cochchi.lk වෙත SMEs වෙත නොමිලේ ප්‍රවේශය ලබා දීම සඳහා SLT-MOBITEL සමඟ හවුල් විය.",
        "කර්මාන්තයේ දැවැන්තයින් දෙදෙනා අතර හවුල්කාරිත්වය HNB SMEs නව ඊ-වාණිජ්‍ය වේදිකාවට ඇතුළු වන විට අමතර ප්‍රතිලාභ ලබා දෙනු ඇත. HNB නියෝජ්‍ය සාමාන්‍යාධිකාරී- සිල්ලර හා කුඩා හා මධ්‍ය පරිමාණ බැංකුකරණය, සංජය විජේමාන්න, HNB සහකාර සාමාන්‍යාධිකාරී- SME, Kailaivasan Indravasan, HNB SME නිෂ්පාදන සහ හවුල්කාරිත්වයේ ප්‍රධානී නිලූකා අමරසිංහ, සහ SLT ප්‍රධාන තොරතුරු සහ ඩිජිටල් නිලධාරී තිලක් ගම්ලත්, ශ්‍රී ලංකා ටෙලිකොම් ඩිජිටල් සාමාන්‍යාධිකාරී පරිවර්තන ව්‍යාපෘති, ඉෂාරි සිරිවර්ධන, ශ්‍රී ලංකා ටෙලිකොම් නියෝජ්‍ය සාමාන්‍යාධිකාරී ඩිජිටල් ව්‍යාපෘති, දිනේෂ් පෙරේරා සහ ශ්‍රී ලංකා ටෙලිකොම් ජ්‍යෙෂ්ඨ කළමනාකාර (අලෙවිකරණය) - කුඩා හා මධ්‍ය පරිමාණ ව්‍යවසායක නිෂ්පාදන සංවර්ධන, ලාල්වින් ද සොයිසා යන මහත්ම මහත්මීහු මෙම හවුල්කාරිත්වය අනුස්මරණය කිරීම සඳහා පැවැති විශේෂ උත්සවයකට සහභාගි වූහ.",
        "මීගමුවේ තර්ජනයට ලක්ව ඇති පරිසර පද්ධති ආරක්ෂා කිරීමට හේමාස් Clean Ocean Force සමඟ හවුල් වෙයි",
        "පිළිතුරක් දෙන්න පිළිතුර අවලංගු කරන්න ඔබගේ විද්‍යුත් තැපැල් ලිපිනය ප්‍රකාශයට පත් නොකෙරේ. අවශ්‍ය ක්ෂේත්‍ර සලකුණු කර ඇත *අදහස් නම *",
        "මම ඊළඟ වතාවේ අදහස් දැක්වීම සඳහා මගේ නම, විද්‍යුත් තැපෑල සහ වෙබ් අඩවිය මෙම බ්‍රවුසරයේ සුරකින්න."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "එච්.එන්.බී",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "SLT-MOBITEL",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "Cochchi.lk",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "HNB PLC",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "SLT-MOBITEL",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Cochchi.lk",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "දෙක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "එච්.එන්.බී",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "එච්.එන්.බී",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "කළමනාකරු- සිල්ලර හා කුඩා හා මධ්‍ය පරිමාණ බැංකුකරණය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "සංජය විජේමාන්න",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "එච්.එන්.බී",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "කළමනාකරු - SME",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "කෛලයිවාසන් ඉන්ද්‍රවාසන්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "HNB ප්‍රධානියා",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "SME නිෂ්පාදන සහ හවුල්කාරිත්වයන්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "නිලූකා අමරසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකා ටෙලිකොම්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඩිජිටල් නිලධාරියා",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "තිලක් ගම්ලත්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඩිජිටල් පරිවර්තන ව්යාපෘති",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉෂාරි සිරිවර්ධන",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකා ටෙලිකොම්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඩිජිටල් ව්යාපෘති",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "පෙරේරා",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකා ටෙලිකොම්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ලාල්වින් ද සොයිසා",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "පිරිසිදු සාගර බලකාය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "මීගමුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [],
        []
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "Cochchi.lk உடன் SME களுக்கான e-commerce திறன்களை மேம்படுத்துவதில் SLT-MOBITEL உடன் HNB இணைந்துள்ளது.",
      "author": "திலின வல்பொல",
      "body_lines": [
        "புதிய இ-காமர்ஸ் சந்தைகள் மற்றும் வாங்குபவர்களுடன் உள்ளூர் SMEகளை இணைக்கும், இலங்கையின் மிகவும் டிஜிட்டல் புதுமையான வங்கியான HNB PLC, SME களுக்கு புதிய ஆன்லைன் வர்த்தக தளமான Cochchi.lk க்கு இலவச அணுகலை வழங்க SLT-MOBITEL உடன் கைகோர்த்துள்ளது.",
        "புதிய இ-காமர்ஸ் தளத்தில் நுழையும் போது, ​​இரண்டு தொழில் நிறுவனங்களின் கூட்டாண்மை HNB SMEகளுக்கு கூடுதல் பலன்களை வழங்கும். HNB பிரதிப் பொது முகாமையாளர்- சில்லறை மற்றும் SME வங்கியியல், சஞ்சய் விஜேமன்னே, HNB உதவிப் பொது முகாமையாளர்- SME, கைலைவாசன் இந்திரவாசன், SME தயாரிப்புகள் மற்றும் கூட்டாண்மைகளின் HNB தலைவர், நிலுகா அமரசிங்க, மற்றும் SLT தலைமை தகவல் மற்றும் டிஜிட்டல் அதிகாரி, திலக் கம்லத், SLT டிஜிட்டல் பொது முகாமையாளர். மாற்றம் திட்டங்கள், இஷாரி சிறிவர்தன, SLT பிரதிப் பொது முகாமையாளர் டிஜிட்டல் திட்டங்கள், தினேஷ் பெரேரா மற்றும் SLT சிரேஷ்ட முகாமையாளர் (சந்தைப்படுத்தல்)-SME தயாரிப்பு அபிவிருத்தி, லால்வின் டி சொய்சா ஆகியோர் இந்த கூட்டாண்மையை நினைவுகூரும் வகையில் நடைபெற்ற விசேட விழாவில் கலந்துகொண்டனர்.",
        "நீர்கொழும்போவின் அச்சுறுத்தலுக்கு உள்ளான சுற்றுச்சூழல் அமைப்புகளைப் பாதுகாப்பதற்காக ஹேமாஸ் கிளீன் ஓஷன் ஃபோர்ஸுடன் கைகோர்க்கிறது",
        "ஒரு பதிலை விடுங்கள் பதிலை ரத்துசெய் உங்கள் மின்னஞ்சல் முகவரி வெளியிடப்படாது. தேவையான புலங்கள் குறிக்கப்பட்டுள்ளன *கருத்து பெயர் *",
        "அடுத்த முறை நான் கருத்து தெரிவிக்க, எனது பெயர், மின்னஞ்சல் மற்றும் இணையதளத்தை இந்த உலாவியில் சேமிக்கவும்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "HNB",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "SLT-MOBITEL",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "கொச்சி.எல்கே",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கையின்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "HNB PLC",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "SLT-MOBITEL",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "கொச்சி.எல்கே",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இரண்டு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "HNB",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "HNB",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "மேலாளர்- சில்லறை & SME வங்கி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "சஞ்சய் விஜேமான்னே",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "HNB",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "மேலாளர் - SME",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "கைலைவாசன் இந்திரவாசன்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "HNB தலைவர்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "SME தயாரிப்புகள் & கூட்டாண்மைகள்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "நிலுகா அமரசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "எஸ்.எல்.டி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "டிஜிட்டல் அதிகாரி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "திலக் கம்லத்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "டிஜிட்டல் மாற்றம் திட்டங்கள்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இஷாரி சிறிவர்தன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "எஸ்.எல்.டி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "டிஜிட்டல் திட்டங்கள்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "பெரேரா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "எஸ்.எல்.டி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "லால்வின் டி சொய்சா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "சுத்தமான கடல் படை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "நீர்கொழும்பு",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [],
        []
      ]
    }
  }
}