{
  "newspaper_id": "ada-lk",
  "url": "https://www.ada.lk/breaking_news/යාපනය---කිලිනොච්චි-අතර-නව--කාර්යාල-ප්‍රවාහන-දුම්රිය-සේවාවක්/11-395105",
  "time_ut": 1656994590,
  "original_lang": "si",
  "original_title": "යාපනය - කිලිනොච්චි අතර නව  කාර්යාල ප්‍රවාහන දුම්රිය සේවාවක්",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "A new office transport train service between Jaffna and Kilinochchi",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "In view of the fuel crisis in the country, steps will be taken to start the new train service between Kilinochchi and Jaffna from the coming week to prevent the inconvenience caused by the lack of buses for the transportation of office workers, says Mr. Douglas Devananda.",
        "Every day, thousands of public and private sector employees come to Kilinochchi from Jaffna and according to the request made by the Minister from the Ministry of Transport to start this train service for their convenience, a group of officials from the Ministry of Transport came to Kilinochchi and after investigating the matter, the Ministry of Transport decided to start the train transport from the coming week. The officials informed Fisheries Minister Douglas Devananda that Minister Bandula Gunawardena had given instructions.",
        "Officials of the Ministry of Transport and General Manager of Railways A.D.P. Mr. Seneviratne, Jaffna Station Master Pradeepan, Kilinochchi District Station Master Shri Mohan, Fisheries Minister's Additional Coordinating Secretary Kotiswaran Rushankan have discussed the matters required to start the new train service.",
        "Afterwards, a special discussion was held with the Northern Province Railway Service Director Visumidara and Kilinochchi Station Master Sigamani, District Secretary Mrs. Rupavathi Ketheeswaram and the team and discussed at length the issues related to starting the train service. Speaking in this discussion, the Deputy General Manager of Railways said that according to the request of the Minister of Fisheries Douglas Devananda, steps will be taken to start this train service within the coming week and the start date will be announced soon."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Jaffna",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "Kilinochchi",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Kilinochchi",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Jaffna",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the coming week",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Douglas Devananda",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "thousands",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kilinochchi",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Jaffna",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Ministry of Transport",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Ministry of Transport",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kilinochchi",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Ministry of Transport",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the coming week",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Fisheries",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Douglas Devananda",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Bandula Gunawardena",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the Ministry of Transport",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Seneviratne",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Jaffna Station",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Pradeepan",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kilinochchi District Station",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "Shri Mohan",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Additional Coordinating",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kotiswaran Rushankan",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the Northern Province Railway Service",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Visumidara",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kilinochchi Station",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sigamani",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "District",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Rupavathi Ketheeswaram",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Douglas Devananda",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the coming week",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "යාපනය - කිලිනොච්චි අතර නව  කාර්යාල ප්‍රවාහන දුම්රිය සේවාවක්",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "රට තුල පවතින ඉන්ධන අර්බුධය හමුවේ කාර්යාල සේවකයන්ගේ ප්‍රවාහන පහස්කම් සදහා ප්‍රමාණවත් බස් ධාවනය නොවීම නිසා සිදුවන අපහසුතා වලක්වාලමින් කිලිනොච්චි හා යාපනය අතර නව දුම්රිය ගම්න් වාර එළැඹෙන සතියේ සිට ආරම්භ කිරීමට පියවර ගන්නා බව ධීවර අමාත්‍ය ඩග්ලස් දේවානන්දා මහතා පවසයි.",
        "දිනකට දහස් ගණන් රාජ්‍ය හා පෞද්ගලික අංශයේ සේවකයන් යාපනයේ සිට කිලිනොච්චියට පැමිණෙන අතර ඔවුන්ගේ ගමන් පහසුව සදහා මෙම දුම්රිය සේවාව ආරම්භ කිරීම පිළිබද අමාත්‍යවරයා ප්‍රවාහන අමාත්‍යාංශයෙන් කරන ලද ඉල්ලීමකට අනුව එහි නිලධාරීන් පිරිසක් කිලිනොච්චියට පැමිණ මේ පිළිබද කරුණු සොයා බැලීමෙන් අනතුරුව එළැඹෙන සතියේ සිට දුම්රිය ප්‍රවාහන කටයුතු ආරම්භ කිරීමට ප්‍රවාහන අමාත්‍ය බන්දුල ගුණවර්ධන මහතා උපදෙස් දී ඇති බව නිළධාරීන් ධීවර අමාත්‍ය ඩග්ලස් දේවානන්දා මහතාට දන්වන ලදි.",
        "ප්‍රවාහන අමාත්‍යාංශයේ නිළධාරීන් හා දුම්රිය සාමාන්‍යාධිකාරි ඒ.ඩී.පී. සෙනෙවිරත්න මහතා යාපනයේ දුම්රිය ස්ථානාධිපති ප්‍රදීපන්, කිලිනොච්චි දිස්ත්‍රික්කයේ දුම්රිය ස්ථානාධිපති ශ්‍රී මෝහන් ධීවර අමාත්‍යවරයාගේ අතිරේක සම්බන්ධීකරණ ලේකම් කොටිස්වරන් රුෂාන්කන් යන අය නව දුම්රිය සේවාව ආරම්භ කිරීමට අවශ්‍ය කරුණු පිළිබද සාකච්ඡා කර තිබේ.",
        "පසුව උතුරු පළාතේ දුම්රිය සේවා අධ්‍යක්ෂ විසුමිදර හා කිලිනොච්චි දුම්රිය ස්ථානාධිපති සිගාමනි, දිස්ත්‍රික් ලේකම් රූපවතී කේතීස්වරම් මහත්මිය ඇතුළු කණ්ඩායම සමග විශේෂ සාකච්ඡාවක් කොට දුම්රිය සේවාව ආරම්භ කිරීමට අදාල කරුණු කෙරෙහි දීර්ඝ ලෙස සාකච්ඡා කරන ලදි. මෙම සාකච්ඡාවේදී අදහස් දැක්වු දුම්රිය නියෝජ්‍ය සාමාන්‍යාධිකාරීවරයා කියා සිටියේ ධීවර අමාත්‍ය ඩග්ලස් දේවානන්දා මහතාගේ ඉල්ලීමට අනුව එළැඹෙන සතිය තුල මෙම දුම්රිය සේවාව ආරම්භ කිරීමට පියවර ගන්නා බවත් ආරම්භ කරන දිනය නුදුරේදීම ප්‍රකාශයට පත් කරන බවත්ය."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "යාපනය",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "කිලිනොච්චි",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "කිලිනොච්චි",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "යාපනය",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉදිරි සතිය",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඩග්ලස් දේවානන්ද",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "දහස්",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "කිලිනොච්චි",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "යාපනය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ප්රවාහන අමාත්යාංශය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ප්රවාහන අමාත්යාංශය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "කිලිනොච්චි",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ප්රවාහන අමාත්යාංශය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉදිරි සතිය",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ධීවර",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඩග්ලස් දේවානන්ද",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "බන්දුල ගුණවර්ධන",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ප්රවාහන අමාත්යාංශය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "සෙනෙවිරත්න",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "යාපනය දුම්රිය ස්ථානය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ප්‍රදීපන්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "කිලිනොච්චි දිස්ත්‍රික් ස්ථානය",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී මෝහන්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "අතිරේක සම්බන්ධීකරණය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "කෝටීස්වරන් රුෂන්කන්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "උතුරු පළාත් දුම්රිය සේවය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "විසුමිදර",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "කිලිනොච්චිය දුම්රිය ස්ථානය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "සිගාමනී",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "දිසා",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "රූපවතී කේතීස්වරම්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඩග්ලස් දේවානන්ද",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉදිරි සතිය",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "யாழ்ப்பாணத்திற்கும் கிளிநொச்சிக்கும் இடையில் புதிய அலுவலக போக்குவரத்து ரயில் சேவை",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "நாட்டில் நிலவும் எரிபொருள் நெருக்கடியை கருத்தில் கொண்டு அலுவலக ஊழியர்களின் போக்குவரத்துக்கு பஸ்கள் இன்மையால் ஏற்படும் அசௌகரியங்களை தடுக்கும் வகையில் கிளிநொச்சிக்கும் யாழ்ப்பாணத்திற்கும் இடையிலான புதிய புகையிரத சேவையை எதிர்வரும் வாரத்தில் ஆரம்பிக்க நடவடிக்கை எடுக்கப்படும் என டக்ளஸ் தேவானந்தா தெரிவித்துள்ளார். .",
        "யாழ்ப்பாணத்தில் இருந்து தினமும் ஆயிரக்கணக்கான அரச மற்றும் தனியார் துறை ஊழியர்கள் கிளிநொச்சிக்கு வந்து செல்வதுடன் அவர்களின் வசதிக்காக இந்த புகையிரத சேவையை ஆரம்பிக்குமாறு போக்குவரத்து அமைச்சிலிருந்து அமைச்சர் விடுத்த வேண்டுகோளுக்கு அமைய போக்குவரத்து அமைச்சின் அதிகாரிகள் குழுவொன்று கிளிநொச்சிக்கு வருகை தந்தது. மற்றும் இது தொடர்பில் ஆராய்ந்த பின்னர் எதிர்வரும் வாரத்தில் இருந்து புகையிரத போக்குவரத்தை ஆரம்பிக்க போக்குவரத்து அமைச்சு தீர்மானித்துள்ளது.அமைச்சர் பந்துல குணவர்தன பணிப்புரை வழங்கியதாக கடற்றொழில் அமைச்சர் டக்ளஸ் தேவானந்தாவிற்கு அதிகாரிகள் தெரிவித்தனர்.",
        "போக்குவரத்து அமைச்சக அதிகாரிகள் மற்றும் ரயில்வே பொது மேலாளர் ஏ.டி.பி. செனவிரத்ன, யாழ் நிலைய அதிபர் பிரதீபன், கிளிநொச்சி மாவட்ட நிலைய அதிபர் ஸ்ரீ மோகன், கடற்றொழில் அமைச்சரின் மேலதிக ஒருங்கிணைப்புச் செயலாளர் கோடீஸ்வரன் ருஷாங்கன் ஆகியோர் புதிய புகையிரத சேவையை ஆரம்பிப்பதற்கு தேவையான விடயங்கள் தொடர்பில் கலந்துரையாடியுள்ளனர்.",
        "அதன் பின்னர் வடமாகாண புகையிரத சேவை பணிப்பாளர் விசுமிதாரா மற்றும் கிளிநொச்சி நிலைய அதிபர் சிகாமணி, மாவட்ட செயலாளர் திருமதி ரூபாவதி கேதீஸ்வரம் மற்றும் குழுவினருடன் விசேட கலந்துரையாடல் இடம்பெற்றதுடன் புகையிரத சேவையை ஆரம்பிப்பது தொடர்பிலான விடயங்கள் தொடர்பில் விரிவாக கலந்துரையாடப்பட்டது. இக்கலந்துரையாடலில் பேசிய புகையிரத பிரதி பொது முகாமையாளர், கடற்றொழில் அமைச்சர் டக்ளஸ் தேவானந்தாவின் வேண்டுகோளுக்கு இணங்க எதிர்வரும் வாரத்திற்குள் இந்த புகையிரத சேவையை ஆரம்பிக்க நடவடிக்கை எடுக்கப்படும் எனவும், ஆரம்பமாகும் திகதி விரைவில் அறிவிக்கப்படும் எனவும் தெரிவித்தார்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "யாழ்",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "கிளிநொச்சி",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "கிளிநொச்சி",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "யாழ்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "வரும் வாரம்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "டக்ளஸ் தேவானந்தா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஆயிரக்கணக்கான",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "கிளிநொச்சி",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "யாழ்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "போக்குவரத்து அமைச்சகம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "போக்குவரத்து அமைச்சகம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "கிளிநொச்சி",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "போக்குவரத்து அமைச்சகம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "வரும் வாரம்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "மீன்வளம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "டக்ளஸ் தேவானந்தா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "பந்துல குணவர்தன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "போக்குவரத்து அமைச்சகம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "செனவிரத்ன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "யாழ்ப்பாணம் நிலையம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "பிரதீபன்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "கிளிநொச்சி மாவட்ட நிலையம்",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஸ்ரீ மோகன்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "கூடுதல் ஒருங்கிணைப்பு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "கோடீஸ்வரன் ருஷாங்கன்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "வடக்கு மாகாண ரயில்வே சேவை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "விசுமிதாரா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "கிளிநொச்சி நிலையம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "சிகாமணி",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "மாவட்டம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரூபாவதி கேதீஸ்வரம்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "டக்ளஸ் தேவானந்தா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "வரும் வாரம்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}