{
  "newspaper_id": "daily-ft-lk",
  "url": "https://www.ft.lk/news/Wajira-Abeywardena-sworn-in-as-Member-of-Parliament/56-737999",
  "time_ut": 1658951606,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Wajira Abeywardena sworn in as Member of Parliament",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Wajira Abeywardena sworn in as Member of Parliament",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "Wajira Abeywardana was sworn in as a National List Member of the United National Party (UNP) yesterday before the Speaker of Parliament Mahinda Yapa Abeywardana.",
        "Following taking the oath before the Speaker, he signed the Member Roll kept before the Secretary General of Parliament Dhammika Dasanayake.",
        "Abeywardana was appointed as the National List member of the United National Party, given the vacancy created due to the swearing in of Ranil Wickremesinghe as the President.",
        "He has been elected to the Parliament of Sri Lanka for the first time from Galle district representing the United National Party at the 1994 election. Thereon, until the year 2010, Abeywardana has been elected to Parliament at every election from Galle district representing the United National Party. In 2015 Parliamentary elections he was elected to the Parliament of Sri Lanka representing the Galle district.",
        "He has worked in the capacity of the Minister of State Administration, Home Affairs, Provincial Councils and Local Government and as the Minister of State Administration, Management and Reform Projects. He is currently the chairman of the United National Party.",
        "Abeywardana was born on 2 September 1961 and is an alumnus of Mahinda Vidyalaya, Galle. He also holds an engineering degree from the University of Moratuwa."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Wajira Abeywardena",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "Parliament",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Wajira Abeywardana",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "National List",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the United National Party",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "UNP",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "yesterday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Mahinda Yapa Abeywardana",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "Abeywardana",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "National List",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the United National Party",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the Parliament of Sri Lanka",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "first",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Galle",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the United National Party",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "1994",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Thereon",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the year 2010",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Abeywardana",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Galle",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the United National Party",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "2015",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Parliament of Sri Lanka",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Galle",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "State Administration",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Home Affairs",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Provincial Councils and Local Government",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "State Administration",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Management and Reform Projects",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the United National Party",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Abeywardana",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "2 September 1961",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Mahinda Vidyalaya",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Galle",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the University of Moratuwa",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "වජිර අබේවර්ධන මන්ත්‍රීවරයා ලෙස දිවුරුම් දෙයි",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "වජිර අබේවර්ධන මහතා එක්සත් ජාතික පක්ෂයේ (එජාප) ජාතික ලැයිස්තු මන්ත්‍රීවරයෙකු ලෙස කථානායක මහින්ද යාපා අබේවර්ධන මහතා ඉදිරියේ ඊයේ දිවුරුම් දුන්නේය.",
        "කථානායකවරයා ඉදිරියේ දිවුරුම් දීමෙන් අනතුරුව ඔහු පාර්ලිමේන්තු මහලේකම් ධම්මික දසනායක මහතා ඉදිරියේ තබා ඇති මන්ත්‍රී නාමලේඛනයට අත්සන් කළේය.",
        "අබේවර්ධන මහතා එක්සත් ජාතික පක්ෂයේ ජාතික ලැයිස්තු මන්ත්‍රීවරයා ලෙස පත් කරනු ලැබුවේ රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතා ජනාධිපතිවරයා ලෙස දිවුරුම් දීමත් සමඟ ඇති වූ පුරප්පාඩුව හමුවේයි.",
        "ඔහු 1994 මැතිවරණයේදී එක්සත් ජාතික පක්ෂය නියෝජනය කරමින් ගාල්ල දිස්ත්‍රික්කයෙන් ප්‍රථම වරට ශ්‍රී ලංකා පාර්ලිමේන්තුවට තේරී පත්වී ඇත. එතැන් සිට 2010 වසර දක්වා සෑම මැතිවරණයකදීම එක්සත් ජාතික පක්ෂය නියෝජනය කරමින් ගාල්ල දිස්ත්‍රික්කයෙන් අබේවර්ධන මහතා පාර්ලිමේන්තුවට තේරී පත් විය. 2015 පාර්ලිමේන්තු මැතිවරණයේදී ඔහු ගාල්ල දිස්ත්‍රික්කය නියෝජනය කරමින් ශ්‍රී ලංකා පාර්ලිමේන්තුවට තේරී පත් විය.",
        "ඔහු රාජ්‍ය පරිපාලන, ස්වදේශ කටයුතු, පළාත් සභා සහ පළාත් පාලන අමාත්‍යවරයා ලෙසත් රාජ්‍ය පරිපාලන, කළමනාකරණ සහ ප්‍රතිසංස්කරණ ව්‍යාපෘති අමාත්‍යවරයා ලෙසත් කටයුතු කර ඇත. ඔහු දැනට එක්සත් ජාතික පක්ෂයේ සභාපතිවරයාය.",
        "අබේවර්ධන 1961 සැප්තැම්බර් 2 වන දින උපත ලැබූ අතර ඔහු ගාල්ල මහින්ද විද්‍යාලයේ ආදි සිසුවෙකි. ඔහු මොරටුව විශ්වවිද්‍යාලයේ ඉංජිනේරු උපාධියක්ද ලබා ඇත."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "වජිර අබේවර්ධන",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "වජිර අබේවර්ධන",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජාතික ලැයිස්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "එක්සත් ජාතික පක්ෂය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "එජාප",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඊයේ",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මහින්ද යාපා අබේවර්ධන",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "අබේවර්ධන ය",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජාතික ලැයිස්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "එක්සත් ජාතික පක්ෂය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකා පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "පළමුවන",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගාල්ල",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "එක්සත් ජාතික පක්ෂය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "1994",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "එහිදී",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "2010 වර්ෂය",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "අබේවර්ධන ය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගාල්ල",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "එක්සත් ජාතික පක්ෂය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "2015",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකා පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගාල්ල",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "රාජ්ය පරිපාලනය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ස්වදේශ කටයුතු",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "පළාත් සභා සහ පළාත් පාලන",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "රාජ්ය පරිපාලනය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "කළමනාකරණ සහ ප්රතිසංස්කරණ ව්යාපෘති",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "එක්සත් ජාතික පක්ෂය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "අබේවර්ධන ය",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "2 සැප්තැම්බර් 1961",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මහින්ද විද්‍යාලය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගාල්ල",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මොරටුව විශ්වවිද්‍යාලය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "பாராளுமன்ற உறுப்பினராக வஜிர அபேவர்தன சத்தியப்பிரமாணம் செய்துகொண்டார்",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "ஐக்கிய தேசியக் கட்சியின் தேசியப் பட்டியல் உறுப்பினராக வஜிர அபேவர்தன நேற்று பாராளுமன்ற சபாநாயகர் மஹிந்த யாப்பா அபேவர்தன முன்னிலையில் பதவிப்பிரமாணம் செய்துகொண்டார்.",
        "சபாநாயகர் முன்னிலையில் சத்தியப்பிரமாணம் செய்து கொண்டதன் பின்னர், பாராளுமன்ற செயலாளர் நாயகம் தம்மிக்க தசநாயக்க முன்னிலையில் வைக்கப்பட்டிருந்த உறுப்பினர் பட்டியலில் அவர் கையொப்பமிட்டார்.",
        "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க ஜனாதிபதியாக பதவிப் பிரமாணம் செய்து கொண்டதன் காரணமாக ஏற்பட்ட வெற்றிடத்துக்கு ஐக்கிய தேசியக் கட்சியின் தேசியப் பட்டியல் உறுப்பினராக அபேவர்தன நியமிக்கப்பட்டுள்ளார்.",
        "1994 தேர்தலில் ஐக்கிய தேசியக் கட்சியை பிரதிநிதித்துவப்படுத்தி காலி மாவட்டத்தில் இருந்து முதல் தடவையாக இலங்கை பாராளுமன்றத்திற்கு தெரிவு செய்யப்பட்டுள்ளார். அதன் பின்னர், 2010 ஆம் ஆண்டு வரை, ஐக்கிய தேசியக் கட்சியை பிரதிநிதித்துவப்படுத்தி காலி மாவட்டத்தில் இருந்து ஒவ்வொரு தேர்தலிலும் அபேவர்தன பாராளுமன்றத்திற்கு தெரிவு செய்யப்பட்டார். 2015 நாடாளுமன்றத் தேர்தலில் காலி மாவட்டத்தைப் பிரதிநிதித்துவப்படுத்தி இலங்கை நாடாளுமன்றத்துக்குத் தேர்ந்தெடுக்கப்பட்டார்.",
        "அவர் மாநில நிர்வாகம், உள்நாட்டலுவல்கள், மாகாண சபைகள் மற்றும் உள்ளூராட்சி அமைச்சராகவும், மாநில நிர்வாகம், மேலாண்மை மற்றும் சீர்திருத்தத் திட்டங்கள் அமைச்சராகவும் பணியாற்றியுள்ளார். தற்போது ஐக்கிய தேசியக் கட்சியின் தலைவராக உள்ளார்.",
        "அபேவர்தன 2 செப்டம்பர் 1961 இல் பிறந்தார் மற்றும் காலி மஹிந்த வித்தியாலயத்தின் பழைய மாணவர் ஆவார். மொரட்டுவ பல்கலைக்கழகத்தில் பொறியியல் பட்டமும் பெற்றுள்ளார்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "வஜிர அபேவர்தன",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "வஜிர அபேவர்தன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "தேசிய பட்டியல்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஐக்கிய தேசிய கட்சி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஐ.தே.க",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "நேற்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "மஹிந்த யாப்பா அபேவர்தன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "அபேவர்தன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "தேசிய பட்டியல்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஐக்கிய தேசிய கட்சி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "முதலில்",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "காலி",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஐக்கிய தேசிய கட்சி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "1994",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "அதன் மீது",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "2010 ஆம் ஆண்டு",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "அபேவர்தன",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "காலி",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஐக்கிய தேசிய கட்சி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "2015",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "காலி",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "மாநில நிர்வாகம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "உள்நாட்டு விவகாரங்கள்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "மாகாண சபைகள் மற்றும் உள்ளூராட்சி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "மாநில நிர்வாகம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "மேலாண்மை மற்றும் சீர்திருத்த திட்டங்கள்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஐக்கிய தேசிய கட்சி",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "அபேவர்தன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "2 செப்டம்பர் 1961",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "மஹிந்த வித்தியாலயம்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "காலி",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "மொரட்டுவ பல்கலைக்கழகம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}