{
  "newspaper_id": "d-b-s-jeyaraj-com",
  "url": "https://dbsjeyaraj.com/dbsj/archives/78868",
  "time_ut": 1659553560,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Sri Lankan  President Ranil Wickremesinghe  affirms nation’s commitment to the ‘One China Policy’ and asks  countries to “refrain from provocations”, in a message apparently directed to the United States",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Sri Lankan  President Ranil Wickremesinghe  affirms nation’s commitment to the ‘One China Policy’ and asks  countries to “refrain from provocations”, in a message apparently directed to the United States",
      "author": "Administrator",
      "body_lines": [
        "Sri Lanka’s President Ranil Wickremesinghe on Thursday affirmed the island nation’s commitment to the ‘One China Policy’ and asked countries to “refrain from provocations”, in a message apparently directed to the United States, days after U.S. House Speaker Nancy Pelosi’s controversial visit to Taiwan.",
        "In a series of tweets, Mr. Wickremesinghe said: “During a meeting with H.E. Qi Zhenghong, Ambassador of China, I reiterated Sri Lanka’s firm commitment to the one-China policy, as well as to the UN Charter principles of sovereignty and territorial integrity of nations. Countries must refrain from provocations which further escalate the current global tensions. Mutual respect and non-interference in the internal affairs of countries are important foundations for peaceful cooperation and non-confrontation.” The Chinese Ambassador “discussed the manner in which the bilateral relations could be further strengthened,” the President’s office later said in a statement, of their meeting held Wednesday afternoon, hours after Mr. Wickremesinghe delivered his inaugural address following his election as President.",
        "On July 20, a majority of lawmakers backed the six-time Prime Minister and senior politician for Presidency after the top office fell vacant after mass citizens’ protests ousted former President Gotabaya Rajapaksa in the wake of a severe economic downturn. Ambassador Qi met Mr. Wickremesinghe on July 22 to convey a congratulatory message from Chinese President Xi Jinping, among the first world leaders to reach out to Mr. Wickremesinghe. “I attach great importance to the development of China-Sri Lanka relations and am willing to provide support and assistance within our capacity to President Wickremesinghe and the Sri Lankan people in their efforts,” President Xi had said in his message.",
        "Mr. Wickremesinghe, in his maiden speech as President on Wednesday, highlighted Indian assistance during Sri Lanka’s economic crisis, thanked Prime Minister Narendra Modi, and regretted that traditional Sri Lanka-Japan ties had been adversely affected by the [Rajapaksa] government’s opposition to Japanese projects. Notably, China found no mention in the address. He quoted a visiting Tibetan monk who had said the crisis could be solved only through unity.",
        "The developments come even as Sri Lanka braves a deepening economic crisis and awaits International Monetary Fund (IMF) assistance for relief. The IMF has assured Sri Lanka of support, based on its success in restructuring its foreign debt with its creditors, including sovereign bond holders — to whom Colombo owes nearly half of its external loans — multilateral agencies, and key bilateral lenders such as China, Japan, and India. The government has also sought bridge financing assistance from India and China to tide over the next few months, but neither partner has responded positively yet.",
        "Meanwhile, Colombo appears to be walking a tight rope as the competing geostrategic interests of India and China come to the fore again. Earlier this week, New Delhi raised concern with President Wickremesinghe over the scheduled arrival of Yuan Wang 5 — a Chinese vessel involved in space and satellite tracking — at the southern Hambantota Port on August 11. India’s apprehensions “were discussed” at this week’s Cabinet meeting, a government spokesman said. An official at the Ministry of Defence on Thursday said “there is no change yet” on the scheduled arrival of the vessel."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Sri Lankan",
          "label": "NORP"
        },
        {
          "text": "Ranil Wickremesinghe",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "the ‘One China Policy’",
          "label": "EVENT"
        },
        {
          "text": "the United States",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka’s",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Thursday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the ‘One China Policy’",
            "label": "EVENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "the United States",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "days",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "U.S. House",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Nancy Pelosi’s",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Taiwan",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "H.E. Qi Zhenghong",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "China",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "one",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "China",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "UN",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Chinese",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Wednesday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "afternoon",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "hours",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "July 20",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "six",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Gotabaya Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Qi",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "July 22",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Chinese",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Xi Jinping",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "first",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "China",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Xi",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Wednesday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Indian",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka’s",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Narendra Modi",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka-Japan",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Rajapaksa",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Japanese",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "China",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Tibetan",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "International Monetary Fund",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "IMF",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Colombo",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "nearly half",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "China",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Japan",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "India",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "India",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "China",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the next few months",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Colombo",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "India",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "China",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Earlier this week",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "New Delhi",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Yuan Wang",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Chinese",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Hambantota Port",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "August 11",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "India",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "week",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Cabinet",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Ministry of Defence",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Thursday",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "ශ්‍රී ලංකා ජනාධිපති රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ 'එක් චීනයක්' ප්‍රතිපත්තියට ජාතියේ කැපවීම තහවුරු කරන අතර, පෙනෙන විදිහට එක්සත් ජනපදය වෙත යොමු කරන ලද පණිවිඩයක් මගින් \"ප්‍රකෝප කිරීම්වලින් වළකින ලෙස\" රටවල්වලින් ඉල්ලා සිටී.",
      "author": "පරිපාලක",
      "body_lines": [
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ ජනාධිපති රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ බ්‍රහස්පතින්දා 'එක් චීනයක්' ප්‍රතිපත්තියට දිවයිනේ ජාතියේ කැපවීම තහවුරු කළ අතර \"ප්‍රකෝප කිරීම්වලින් වළකින ලෙස\" රටවල්වලින් ඉල්ලා සිටියේ, එක්සත් ජනපද සභා කථානායක නැන්සි පෙලෝසිගේ මතභේදාත්මක තායිවාන සංචාරයෙන් දින කිහිපයකට පසුව, පෙනෙන විදිහට එක්සත් ජනපදයට යවන ලද පණිවිඩයක ය. .",
        "ට්විටර් පණිවුඩ මාලාවක වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතා මෙසේ පැවසීය: “එච්.ඊ. චීනයේ තානාපති Qi Zhenghong මහතා, එක් චීනයක් ප්‍රතිපත්තියට මෙන්ම ජාතීන්ගේ ස්වෛරීභාවය සහ භෞමික අඛණ්ඩතාව පිළිබඳ එක්සත් ජාතීන්ගේ ප්‍රඥප්ති මූලධර්මවලට ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ දැඩි කැපවීම මම නැවත අවධාරණය කළෙමි. වත්මන් ගෝලීය ආතතීන් තව දුරටත් උත්සන්න කරන ප්‍රකෝප කිරීම් වලින් රටවල් වැළකිය යුතුය. අන්‍යෝන්‍ය ගරුත්වය සහ රටවල අභ්‍යන්තර කටයුතුවලට මැදිහත් නොවීම සාමකාමී සහයෝගීතාවයට සහ ගැටුම් ඇති නොවීමට වැදගත් පදනම් වේ. චීන තානාපතිවරයා “ද්විපාර්ශ්වික සබඳතා තවදුරටත් ශක්තිමත් කර ගත හැකි ආකාරය පිළිබඳව සාකච්ඡා කළ බව” ජනාධිපති කාර්යාලය පසුව නිවේදනයක් නිකුත් කරමින් කියා සිටියේ, වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතා ජනාධිපති ලෙස තේරී පත්වීමෙන් පසු සිය මංගල දේශනය පවත්වා පැය කිහිපයකට පසුව, බදාදා පස්වරුවේ පැවති ඔවුන්ගේ රැස්වීමේ දී ය.",
        "ජුලි 20 වෙනිදා, දැඩි ආර්ථික පසුබෑමකින් පසු හිටපු ජනාධිපති ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ නෙරපා හරින ලද මහජන විරෝධතාවලින් පසු ඉහළ නිලය පුරප්පාඩු වීමෙන් පසු හය වතාවක් අගමැති සහ ජ්‍යෙෂ්ඨ දේශපාලනඥයාට ජනාධිපති ධුරය සඳහා නීති සම්පාදකයින් බහුතරයක් සහාය දුන්හ. වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතා වෙත ළඟා වූ ප්‍රථම ලෝක නායකයන් අතර චීන ජනාධිපති ෂී ජින්පින්ගේ සුබපැතුම් පණිවිඩයක් යැවීමට තානාපති Qi වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතා හමුවූයේ ජූලි 22 වැනිදාය. \"චීන-ශ්‍රී ලංකා සබඳතා වර්ධනයට මම විශාල වැදගත්කමක් ලබා දෙන අතර ජනාධිපති වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතාට සහ ශ්‍රී ලාංකීය ජනතාවට ඔවුන්ගේ ප්‍රයත්නයන් සඳහා අපගේ හැකියාව තුළ සහයෝගය සහ සහාය ලබා දීමට කැමැත්තෙමි,\" ජනාධිපති ෂී සිය පණිවිඩයේ සඳහන් කර ඇත.",
        "වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතා, බදාදා ජනාධිපති ලෙස සිය මංගල කතාවේදී, ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ ආර්ථික අර්බුදයේදී ඉන්දීය ආධාර උද්දීපනය කළ අතර, අගමැති නරේන්ද්‍ර මෝදිට ස්තුතිය පුද කළ අතර, [රාජපක්ෂ] ආන්ඩුව ජපානයට විරුද්ධ වීම නිසා සම්ප්‍රදායික ශ්‍රී ලංකා-ජපාන සබඳතාවලට අහිතකර ලෙස බලපා තිබීම ගැන කනගාටු විය. ව්යාපෘති. චීනය ලිපිනයේ කිසිදු සඳහනක් සොයා නොගැනීම විශේෂත්වයකි. අර්බුදය විසඳිය හැක්කේ සමගියෙන් පමණක් බව පැවසූ ටිබෙට් භික්ෂුවක් උපුටා දක්වමින් ඔහු පැවසීය.",
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකාව ගැඹුරු වන ආර්ථික අර්බුදයකට මුහුණ දෙමින් සහ සහන සඳහා ජාත්‍යන්තර මූල්‍ය අරමුදලේ (IMF) සහාය බලාපොරොත්තුවෙන් සිටින අවස්ථාවක දී මෙම වර්ධනයන් පැමිණේ. බහුපාර්ශ්වික නියෝජිතායතන සහ චීනය, ජපානය වැනි ප්‍රධාන ද්විපාර්ශ්වික ණය දෙන්නන් - ස්වෛරී බැඳුම්කර හිමියන්ට - කොළඹ බාහිර ණය වලින් අඩකට ආසන්න ප්‍රමාණයක් ගෙවිය යුතු - එහි ණයහිමියන් සමඟ එහි විදේශ නය ප්‍රතිව්‍යුහගත කිරීමේ සාර්ථකත්වය මත පදනම්ව, IMF ශ්‍රී ලංකාවට සහාය සහතික කර ඇත. , සහ ඉන්දියාව. ඉදිරි මාස කිහිපය තුළ වඩදිය බාදිය සඳහා රජය ඉන්දියාවෙන් සහ චීනයෙන් පාලම් මූල්‍ය ආධාර ඉල්ලා ඇත, නමුත් කිසිදු හවුල්කරුවෙකු තවමත් ධනාත්මක ප්‍රතිචාරයක් දක්වා නොමැත.",
        "මේ අතර, ඉන්දියාවේ සහ චීනයේ තරඟකාරී භූ මූලෝපායික අවශ්‍යතා යලිත් කරළියට එද්දී කොළඹ තද ලණුවක ගමන් කරන බව පෙනේ. මෙම සතිය මුලදී, නව දිල්ලිය අගෝස්තු 11 වන දින දකුණු හම්බන්තොට වරායට අභ්‍යවකාශ හා චන්ද්‍රිකා ලුහුබැඳීමේ යෙදී සිටින චීන යාත්‍රාවක් වන යුවාන් වැන්ග් 5 පැමිණීමට නියමිතව තිබීම ගැන ජනාධිපති වික්‍රමසිංහ වෙත කනස්සල්ල පළ කළේය. මේ සතියේ කැබිනට් රැස්වීමේදී ඉන්දියාවේ භීතිකාවන් \"සාකච්ඡා කරන ලදී\" , රජයේ ප්‍රකාශකයෙක් පැවසීය. ආරක්ෂක අමාත්‍යාංශයේ නිලධාරියෙක් බ්‍රහස්පතින්දා පැවසුවේ යාත්‍රාව පැමිණීමට නියමිතව ඇති “තාම වෙනසක් නැත” යනුවෙනි."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ශ්‍රී ලාංකික",
          "label": "NORP"
        },
        {
          "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "'එක් චීනයේ ප්‍රතිපත්තිය'",
          "label": "EVENT"
        },
        {
          "text": "එක්සත් ජනපදය",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "බ්රහස්පතින්දා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "'එක් චීනයේ ප්‍රතිපත්තිය'",
            "label": "EVENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "එක්සත් ජනපදය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "දින",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "එක්සත් ජනපද මන්දිරය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "නැන්සි පෙලෝසිගේ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "තායිවානය",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "H.E. Qi Zhenghong",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "චීනය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "එක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "චීනය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "එ.ජා",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "චීන",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "බදාදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "දහවල්",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "පැය",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ජූලි 20",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "හය",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Qi",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජූලි 22",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "චීන",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Xi Jinping",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "පළමුවන",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "චීනය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Xi",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "බදාදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දීය",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "නරේන්ද්‍ර මෝදි",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකාව-ජපානය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජපන්",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "චීනය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ටිබෙට්",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජාත්යන්තර මූල්ය අරමුදල",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "IMF",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "කොළඹ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ආසන්න වශයෙන් භාගයක්",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "චීනය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජපානය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "චීනය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉදිරි මාස කිහිපය",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "කොළඹ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "චීනය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මේ සතිය මුල",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "නව දිල්ලි",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Yuan Wang",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "චීන",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "හම්බන්තොට වරාය",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "අගෝස්තු 11",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "සතිය",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මණ්ඩල",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ආරක්ෂක අමාත්යාංශය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "බ්රහස්පතින්දා",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "இலங்கை ஜனாதிபதி ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க, ‘ஒரே சீனா கொள்கை’க்கான தேசத்தின் உறுதிப்பாட்டை உறுதிப்படுத்தியதுடன், “ஆத்திரமூட்டல்களில் இருந்து விலகி இருங்கள்” என்று அமெரிக்காவிற்கு அனுப்பிய செய்தியில், நாடுகளை கேட்டுக்கொண்டுள்ளார்.",
      "author": "நிர்வாகி",
      "body_lines": [
        "சிறிலங்காவின் ஜனாதிபதி ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க வியாழன் அன்று 'ஒரு சீனக் கொள்கை'க்கான தீவு தேசத்தின் உறுதிப்பாட்டை உறுதிப்படுத்தினார் மற்றும் \"ஆத்திரமூட்டல்களில் இருந்து விலகி இருங்கள்\" என்று அமெரிக்காவிற்கு அனுப்பிய ஒரு செய்தியில், அமெரிக்க நாடாளுமன்ற சபாநாயகர் நான்சி பெலோசியின் சர்ச்சைக்குரிய தைவான் பயணத்திற்கு சில நாட்களுக்குப் பிறகு. .",
        "தொடர்ச்சியான ட்வீட்களில், திரு. விக்கிரமசிங்க கூறினார்: “H.E. உடனான சந்திப்பின் போது. சீனாவின் தூதுவர் Qi Zhenghong, ஒரே சீனா கொள்கை மற்றும் நாடுகளின் இறையாண்மை மற்றும் பிராந்திய ஒருமைப்பாடு பற்றிய ஐ.நா சாசனக் கோட்பாடுகளுக்கு இலங்கையின் உறுதியான உறுதிப்பாட்டை நான் மீண்டும் வலியுறுத்தினேன். தற்போதைய உலகளாவிய பதட்டங்களை மேலும் அதிகரிக்கும் ஆத்திரமூட்டல்களை நாடுகள் தவிர்க்க வேண்டும். பரஸ்பர மரியாதை மற்றும் நாடுகளின் உள் விவகாரங்களில் தலையிடாதது அமைதியான ஒத்துழைப்பு மற்றும் மோதலின்மைக்கு முக்கியமான அடித்தளமாகும். சீனத் தூதுவர் “இருதரப்பு உறவுகளை மேலும் வலுப்படுத்துவது குறித்து விவாதித்தார்,” என்று ஜனாதிபதி அலுவலகம் பின்னர் ஒரு அறிக்கையில் தெரிவித்தது, ஜனாதிபதியாகத் தேர்ந்தெடுக்கப்பட்டதைத் தொடர்ந்து திரு. விக்கிரமசிங்க தனது பதவியேற்பு உரையை நிகழ்த்திய சில மணிநேரங்களுக்குப் பிறகு, புதன்கிழமை பிற்பகல் நடைபெற்ற அவர்களின் சந்திப்பில்.",
        "ஜூலை 20 அன்று, கடுமையான பொருளாதார வீழ்ச்சியை அடுத்து, முன்னாள் ஜனாதிபதி கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ஷவை வெகுஜன மக்கள் எதிர்ப்புக்களால் வெளியேற்றியதை அடுத்து, உயர்மட்ட பதவி காலியானதைத் தொடர்ந்து, ஆறு முறை பிரதமராகவும், மூத்த அரசியல்வாதியாகவும் இருந்தவருக்கு ஆதரவளித்தார். சீன ஜனாதிபதி ஷி ஜின்பிங்கின் வாழ்த்துச் செய்தியைத் தெரிவிக்க, தூதுவர் குய் ஜூலை 22 அன்று திரு விக்கிரமசிங்கவைச் சந்தித்தார், திரு விக்கிரமசிங்கவை அணுகிய முதல் உலகத் தலைவர்களில் ஒருவர். \"சீனா-இலங்கை உறவுகளின் வளர்ச்சிக்கு நான் அதிக முக்கியத்துவம் கொடுப்பதோடு, ஜனாதிபதி விக்கிரமசிங்க மற்றும் இலங்கை மக்களுக்கும் அவர்களின் முயற்சிகளுக்கு எங்கள் திறனுக்குள் ஆதரவையும் உதவியையும் வழங்க தயாராக உள்ளேன்\" என்று ஜனாதிபதி ஜி தனது செய்தியில் தெரிவித்துள்ளார்.",
        "திரு. விக்கிரமசிங்க, புதனன்று ஜனாதிபதியாக தனது முதல் உரையில், இலங்கையின் பொருளாதார நெருக்கடியின் போது இந்திய உதவியை எடுத்துரைத்தார், பிரதமர் நரேந்திர மோடிக்கு நன்றி தெரிவித்தார், மேலும் [ராஜபக்ஷ] ஜப்பானிய அரசாங்கத்தின் எதிர்ப்பால் பாரம்பரிய இலங்கை-ஜப்பான் உறவுகள் மோசமாக பாதிக்கப்பட்டதற்கு வருத்தம் தெரிவித்தார். திட்டங்கள். இந்த முகவரியில் சீனா குறிப்பிடவில்லை என்பது குறிப்பிடத்தக்கது. அவர் வருகை தந்திருந்த திபெத்திய துறவி ஒருவரை மேற்கோள் காட்டினார், அவர் ஒற்றுமை மூலம் மட்டுமே நெருக்கடியை தீர்க்க முடியும் என்று கூறினார்.",
        "ஆழமடைந்து வரும் பொருளாதார நெருக்கடியை இலங்கை துணிச்சலுடன் எதிர்கொண்டு, சர்வதேச நாணய நிதியத்தின் (IMF) நிவாரணத்திற்காக காத்திருக்கும் நிலையிலும் இந்த அபிவிருத்திகள் வந்துள்ளன. சர்வதேச நாணய நிதியம் இலங்கையின் வெளிநாட்டுக் கடனை மறுசீரமைப்பதில் அதன் வெற்றியின் அடிப்படையில், அதன் கடனாளிகள், இறையாண்மை பத்திர வைத்திருப்பவர்கள் உட்பட - கொழும்பு அதன் வெளிப்புறக் கடன்களில் கிட்டத்தட்ட பாதிக்கு கடன்பட்டுள்ளது - பலதரப்பு முகவர் நிறுவனங்கள் மற்றும் சீனா, ஜப்பான் போன்ற முக்கிய இருதரப்பு கடன் வழங்குநர்கள். , மற்றும் இந்தியா. அரசாங்கம் அடுத்த சில மாதங்களில் இந்தியா மற்றும் சீனாவிடமிருந்து பிரிட்ஜ் நிதி உதவியை நாடியுள்ளது, ஆனால் இரு பங்குதாரரும் இதுவரை சாதகமாக பதிலளிக்கவில்லை.",
        "இதற்கிடையில், இந்தியா மற்றும் சீனாவின் போட்டியிடும் புவிசார் மூலோபாய நலன்கள் மீண்டும் முன்னுக்கு வருவதால் கொழும்பு இறுக்கமான கயிற்றில் நடப்பது போல் தோன்றுகிறது. இந்த வார தொடக்கத்தில், ஆகஸ்ட் 11 ஆம் தேதி தெற்கு ஹம்பாந்தோட்டை துறைமுகத்தில் யுவான் வாங் 5 - சீனக் கப்பலான யுவான் வாங் 5-ன் வருகை குறித்து புது டெல்லி ஜனாதிபதி விக்கிரமசிங்கவிடம் கவலை தெரிவித்தது. , அரசாங்க செய்தி தொடர்பாளர் கூறினார். வியாழக்கிழமை பாதுகாப்பு அமைச்சகத்தின் அதிகாரி ஒருவர், கப்பலின் திட்டமிடப்பட்ட வருகையில் \"இன்னும் எந்த மாற்றமும் இல்லை\" என்றார்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "இலங்கை",
          "label": "NORP"
        },
        {
          "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "‘ஒரு சீனா கொள்கை’",
          "label": "EVENT"
        },
        {
          "text": "ஐக்கிய நாடுகள்",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கையின்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "வியாழன்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "‘ஒரு சீனா கொள்கை’",
            "label": "EVENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஐக்கிய நாடுகள்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "நாட்களில்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "அமெரிக்க மாளிகை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "நான்சி பெலோசியின்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "தைவான்",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "H.E. Qi Zhenghong",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "சீனா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஒன்று",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "சீனா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஐ.நா",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "சீன",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "புதன்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "பிற்பகல்",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "மணி",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஜூலை 20",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆறு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "குய்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜூலை 22",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சீன",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Xi Jinping",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "முதலில்",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "சீனா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Xi",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "புதன்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்தியன்",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கையின்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "நரேந்திர மோடி",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை-ஜப்பான்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ராஜபக்சே",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜப்பானியர்",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "சீனா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "திபெத்தியன்",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சர்வதேச நாணய நிதியம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "IMF",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "கொழும்பு",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "கிட்டத்தட்ட பாதி",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "சீனா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜப்பான்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்தியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்தியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சீனா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "அடுத்த சில மாதங்கள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "கொழும்பு",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்தியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சீனா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்த வார தொடக்கத்தில்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "புது தில்லி",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Yuan Wang",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "சீன",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஹம்பாந்தோட்டை துறைமுகம்",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆகஸ்ட் 11",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்தியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "வாரம்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "மந்திரி சபை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாதுகாப்பு அமைச்சகம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "வியாழன்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}