{
  "newspaper_id": "ada-lk",
  "url": "https://www.ada.lk/breaking_news/ගෑස්-පෝලිමේ-මරණයක්/11-395353",
  "time_ut": 1657621993,
  "original_lang": "si",
  "original_title": "ගෑස් පෝලිමේ මරණයක්",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "A death in the gas line",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "Kottawa police said that a person who was waiting in a gas queue at the Kottawa bus station died today (12th) after being admitted to the Homagama base hospital for treatment due to a sudden medical condition.",
        "The police say that Jayatissa Perera (63), a resident of 1015 Liyanagoda Road, Kottawa, is an electrical engineer.",
        "This person is said to have gone with his son to a Litro gas distribution point which was organized at the main bus stand in Kottawa city center this morning.",
        "For that, a large number of people had come and waited in the queue and the deceased person also came to the place in a car and waited there expecting to buy a gas cylinder.",
        "The police said that this person, who fell ill along with the people staying there, was taken to the Homagama Base Hospital for treatment and later died while receiving treatment there.",
        "The post-mortem examination of the body of the deceased person is to be conducted by the Homagama Coroner Justice of the Peace Mr. Chinthaka Udayakumara at the Homagama Basic Hospital's Accident Investigation Court."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Kottawa police",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kottawa",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Jayatissa Perera",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "63",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "1015",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kottawa",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Litro",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kottawa city",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "this morning",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "the Homagama Base Hospital",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the Homagama Coroner Justice",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Chinthaka Udayakumara",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Homagama Basic Hospital's",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Accident Investigation Court",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "ගෑස් පෝලිමේ මරණයක්",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "කොට්ටාව බස් නැවතුම්පළ භූමියේ ගෑස් පෝලිමක රැඳී සිටි පුද්ගලයෙකු හදිසියේ ඇති වූ රෝගී තත්ත්වයක් හේතුවෙන් ප්‍රතිකාර සදහා හෝමාගම මූලික රෝහලට ඇතුළත් කිරීමෙන් පසුව අද (12දා) ජීවිතක්ෂයට පත්ව ඇතැයි කොට්ටාව පොලිසිය පවසයි .",
        "මෙසේ මියගොස් ඇත්තේ කොට්ටාව , ලියනගොඩ පාර අංක 1015 හි පදිංචි ජයතිස්ස පෙරේරා නමැති (63) හැවිරිදි  විදුලි ඉංජිනේරුවරයෙකු බව පොලීසිය කියයි .",
        "මෙම පුද්ගලයා අද උදෑසන කොට්ටාව නගර මධ්‍යයේ පිහිටි ප්‍රධාන බස් නැවතුම්පල භූමියේ සංවිධානය කර තිබූ ලිට්රෝ ගෑස් බෙදාදීමේ ස්ථානයකට තම පුතු සමග ගොස් ඇතැයි පැවසේ .",
        "ඒ සදහා විශාල පිරිසක් පැමිණ පෝලිමේ රැඳී සිට ඇති  අතර මියගිය පුද්ගලයා ද  මෝටර් රථයකින් එම ස්ථානයට පැමිණ ගෑස් සිලින්ඩරයක් මිළදී ගැනීමේ අපේක්ෂාවෙන් එහි රැඳී සිට ඇති අතර එම අවස්ථාවේදී උදෑසන නවයට පමණ මෙම පුද්ගලයා කිසියම් රෝගී තත්ත්වයකට පත්ව ඇතැයි පැවසේ .",
        "එහිදී රැදී සිටි පිරිස් හා එක්ව අසනීප තත්ත්වයෙන් පසු වූ  මෙම පුද්ගලයා  ප්‍රතිකාර සඳහා හෝමාගම මූලික රෝහලට ඇතුළත් කිරීමට පියවරගෙන ඇති  බවත් පසුව  එහි ප්‍රතිකාර ලබමින් සිටියදී මෙසේ මියගොස් ඇති බවත් පොලිසිය පවසයි .",
        "මිය ගිය පුද්ගලයාගේ මෘත දේහය පිළිබඳ පශ්චාත් මරණ පරීක්ෂණය හෝමාගම හදිසි මරණ පරීක්ෂක සාමවිනිසුරු චින්තක උදයකුමාර මහතා විසින් හෝමාගම මූලික රෝහලේ හදිසි මරණ පරීක්ෂණ අධිකරණයේ දී  සිදුකිරීමට නියමිතය ."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "කොට්ටාව පොලිසිය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kottawa",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ජයතිස්ස පෙරේරා",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "63",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "1015",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kottawa",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ලිට්රෝ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "කොට්ටාව නගරය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මේ උදෑසන",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "හෝමාගම මූලික රෝහල",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "හෝමාගම හදිසි මරණ පරීක්ෂක",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "චින්තක උදයකුමාර",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "හෝමාගම මූලික රෝහලේ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "හදිසි අනතුරු විමර්ශන අධිකරණය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "எரிவாயு கம்பியில் ஒரு மரணம்",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "கொட்டாவ பேருந்து நிலையத்தில் எரிவாயு வரிசையில் காத்திருந்த ஒருவர் திடீர் சுகயீனம் காரணமாக ஹோமாகம ஆதார வைத்தியசாலையில் சிகிச்சைக்காக அனுமதிக்கப்பட்ட பின்னர் இன்று (12) உயிரிழந்துள்ளதாக கொட்டாவ பொலிஸார் தெரிவித்தனர்.",
        "1015 லியனகொட வீதி, கொட்டாவ பகுதியைச் சேர்ந்த ஜயதிஸ்ஸ பெரேரா (வயது 63) என்பவர் மின்சார பொறியியலாளர் என பொலிஸார் தெரிவிக்கின்றனர்.",
        "இந்த நபர் இன்று காலை கொட்டாவ நகர மையத்தில் உள்ள பிரதான பஸ் நிலையத்தில் ஏற்பாடு செய்யப்பட்டிருந்த லிட்ரோ எரிவாயு விநியோக நிலையத்திற்கு தனது மகனுடன் சென்றதாக கூறப்படுகிறது.",
        "அதற்காக ஏராளமானோர் வந்து வரிசையில் காத்திருந்தனர், இறந்த நபரும் காரில் அந்த இடத்திற்கு வந்து காஸ் சிலிண்டர் வாங்கும் எண்ணத்தில் காத்திருந்தார்.",
        "அங்கு தங்கியிருந்தவர்களுடன் சேர்ந்து சுகயீனமடைந்த இந்த நபர் சிகிச்சைக்காக ஹோமாகம ஆதார வைத்தியசாலைக்கு கொண்டு செல்லப்பட்டு சிகிச்சை பலனின்றி உயிரிழந்துள்ளதாக பொலிஸார் தெரிவித்தனர்.",
        "உயிரிழந்த நபரின் சடலத்தின் பிரேத பரிசோதனை ஹோமாகம அடிப்படை வைத்தியசாலையின் விபத்து விசாரணை நீதிமன்றில் ஹோமாகம மரண விசாரணை அதிகாரி சமாதான நீதவான் திரு.சிந்தக உதயகுமாரவினால் நடத்தப்படவுள்ளது."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "கொட்டாவ பொலிஸ்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kottawa",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஜயதிஸ்ஸ பெரேரா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "63",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "1015",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kottawa",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "லிட்ரோ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "கொட்டாவ நகரம்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று காலை",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஹோமாகம ஆதார வைத்தியசாலை",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஹோமாகம மரண விசாரணை நீதிபதி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "சிந்தக உதயகுமார",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஹோமாகம அடிப்படை வைத்தியசாலை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "விபத்து விசாரணை நீதிமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}