{
  "newspaper_id": "virakesari-lk",
  "url": "http://www.virakesari.lk/article/130790",
  "time_ut": 1656946858,
  "original_lang": "ta",
  "original_title": "சஜித் தலைமையில் முக்கிய கட்சி தலைவர்களுடன் விசேட கூட்டம் - மைத்திரி, விக்கி உள்ளிட்டோர் பங்கேற்பு",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Special meeting with major party leaders led by Sajith - Maithiri, Vicky etc. participated",
      "author": "T Yuwaraj",
      "body_lines": [
        "Maithripala Sirisena, former president and leader of the Sri Lanka Freedom Party, was present at a special discussion held at the opposition leader's office in Colombo under the leadership of opposition leader Sajith Premadasa.",
        "Organized by United People's Shakti Member of Parliament Budhika Patirana, the discussion was themed 'Meeting on National Policies and Future Action'.",
        "When asked the Deputy President of the Tamil Progressive Alliance Velusathi Radhakrishnan about the issue that was brought to attention during this,",
        "The theme of the discussion was 'Meeting on National Policies and Future Actions' and detailed attention was paid to the reforms to be carried out in the 22nd Constitutional Amendment. It was attended by all parties interested in the National Seer Amendments.",
        "During this, there was a wide consultation on the ideas presented by the Leader of the Opposition Sajith Premadasa and the civil organizations.",
        "Each party who participated in the discussion on national reforms shared their views and ideas.",
        "He said that attention was paid to the principles to be included in the 22nd constitutional amendment to eliminate corruption and fraud.",
        "Civil activists including Vigden Ivar, Gamini Viyangoda, KW Janaranjana, Tamil Progressive Alliance President Mano Ganesan, Vice Presidents V. Iradhakrishnan, Palani Digambaram, Sri Lanka Muslim Congress President Raup Hakeem, Tamil People's National Alliance President CV Wickineswaran and many others. It is noteworthy that the Mukistas participated in this discussion."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Sajith - Maithiri",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "Vicky",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Maithripala Sirisena",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Sri Lanka Freedom Party",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sajith Premadasa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "United People's",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Budhika Patirana",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the Tamil Progressive Alliance Velusathi Radhakrishnan",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "22nd",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Constitutional Amendment",
            "label": "LAW"
          },
          {
            "text": "the National Seer Amendments",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "22nd",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Vigden Ivar",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Gamini Viyangoda",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Janaranjana",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Tamil Progressive Alliance",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Mano Ganesan",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Presidents V. Iradhakrishnan",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Palani Digambaram",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka Muslim Congress",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Raup Hakeem",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Tamil People's",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "National Alliance",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "CV Wickineswaran",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Mukistas",
            "label": "LOC"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "සජිත් - මෛත්‍රී, විකී ඇතුළු ප්‍රධාන පක්ෂ නායකයන් සමඟ විශේෂ හමුවකට සහභාගි විය",
      "author": "ටී යුවරාජ්",
      "body_lines": [
        "විපක්ෂ නායක සජිත් ප්‍රේමදාස මහතාගේ ප්‍රධානත්වයෙන් කොළඹ විපක්ෂ නායක කාර්යාලයේ පැවති විශේෂ සාකච්ඡාවකට හිටපු ජනාධිපති සහ ශ්‍රී ලංකා නිදහස් පක්ෂයේ නායක මෛත්‍රීපාල සිරිසේන මහතා සහභාගී විය.",
        "එක්සත් ජනතා ශක්ති පාර්ලිමේන්තු මන්ත්‍රී බුද්ධික පතිරණ විසින් සංවිධානය කරන ලද මෙම සාකච්ඡාව ‘ජාතික ප්‍රතිපත්ති සහ ඉදිරි ක්‍රියාමාර්ග පිළිබඳ රැස්වීම’ යන තේමාවෙන් පැවැත්විණි.",
        "මෙහිදී අවධානයට ලක්වූ ගැටලුව පිළිබඳව දෙමළ ප්‍රගතිශීලී සන්ධානයේ නියෝජ්‍ය සභාපති වේලුසති රාධක්‍රිෂ්ණන්ගෙන් විමසූ විට,",
        "‘ජාතික ප්‍රතිපත්ති සහ ඉදිරි ක්‍රියාමාර්ග පිළිබඳ රැස්වීම’ යන තේමාව යටතේ පැවති මෙම සාකච්ඡාවේ දී 22 වැනි ආණ්ඩුක්‍රම ව්‍යවස්ථා සංශෝධනයෙන් සිදු කිරීමට නියමිත ප්‍රතිසංස්කරණ පිළිබඳව සවිස්තර අවධානය යොමු කෙරිණි. ජාතික දැක්ම සංශෝධන සඳහා උනන්දුවක් දක්වන සියලුම පාර්ශ්වයන් එයට සහභාගී විය.",
        "මේ අතර විපක්ෂ නායක සජිත් ප්‍රේමදාස මහතා ඇතුළු සිවිල් සංවිධාන ඉදිරිපත් කළ අදහස් සම්බන්ධයෙන් පුළුල් සාකච්ඡාවක් ද සිදු විය.",
        "ජාතික ප්‍රතිසංස්කරණ පිළිබඳ සාකච්ඡාවට සහභාගි වූ සෑම පාර්ශ්වයක්ම තම අදහස් හා අදහස් හුවමාරු කර ගත්හ.",
        "දූෂණය සහ වංචාව පිටුදැකීම සඳහා 22 වැනි ආණ්ඩුක්‍රම ව්‍යවස්ථා සංශෝධනයට ඇතුළත් කළ යුතු ප්‍රතිපත්ති පිළිබඳව මෙහිදී අවධානය යොමු වූ බව ඔහු සඳහන් කළේය.",
        "විග්ඩන් අයිවර්, කාමිණී වියන්ගොඩ, කේ.ඩබ්ලිව්.ජනරංජන, දෙමළ ප්‍රගතිශීලි සන්ධානයේ සභාපති මනෝ ගනේෂන්, උප සභාපතිවරුන් වන වී.ඉරාධක්‍රිෂ්ණන්, පලනි දිගම්බරම්, ශ්‍රී ලංකා මුස්ලිම් කොංග්‍රසයේ සභාපති රවුප් හකීම්, දෙමළ ජනතා ජාතික සන්ධානයේ සභාපති සී.වී.විකිනේශ්වරන් ඇතුළු සිවිල් ක්‍රියාකාරීන් රැසක් ද එක්ව සිටීම විශේෂත්වයකි. මුකිස්තාලා මේ සාකච්ඡාවට සහභාගි වුණා කියලා."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "සජිත් - මෛත්‍රී",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "විකී",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "මෛත්‍රීපාල සිරිසේන",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකා නිදහස් පක්ෂය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "සජිත් ප්‍රේමදාස",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "එක්සත් ජනතා",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "බුද්ධික පතිරණ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "දෙමළ ප්‍රගතිශීලී සන්ධානය වේලුසති රාධක්‍රිෂ්ණන්",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "22 වැනි",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ව්යවස්ථා සංශෝධනය",
            "label": "LAW"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජාතික දැක්ම සංශෝධන",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "22 වැනි",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "විග්ඩන් අයිවර්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගාමිණී වියන්ගොඩ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජනරංජන",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "දෙමළ ප්‍රගතිශීලී සන්ධානය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Mano Ganesan",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "සභාපතිවරුන් වී.ඉරාධක්‍රිෂ්ණන්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "පලනි දිගම්බරම්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකා මුස්ලිම් කොංග්‍රසය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "රවුප් හකීම්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "දෙමළ ජනතාවගේ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජාතික සන්ධානය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "සී.වී.විකිනේශ්වරන්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "මුකිස්ටාස්",
            "label": "LOC"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "சஜித் தலைமையில் முக்கிய கட்சி தலைவர்களுடன் விசேட கூட்டம் - மைத்திரி, விக்கி உள்ளிட்டோர் பங்கேற்பு",
      "author": "T Yuwaraj",
      "body_lines": [
        "எதிர்க்கட்சி தலைவர் சஜித் பிரேமதாச தலைமையில் கொழும்பிலுள்ள எதிர்க்கட்சி தலைவர் அலுவலகத்தில் இன்று திங்கட்கிழமை இடம்பெற்ற விசேட கலந்துரையாடலொன்றில் முன்னாள் ஜனாதிபதியும் ஸ்ரீலங்கா சுதந்திர கட்சியின் தலைவருமான மைத்திரிபால சிறிசேனவும் கலந்து கொண்டிருந்தார்.",
        "ஐக்கிய மக்கள் சக்தியின் பாராளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர் புத்திக பத்திரணவினால் ஏற்பாடு செய்யப்பட்டிருந்த இந்த கலந்துரையாடல் , 'தேசிய கொள்கைகள் மற்றும் எதிர்கால நடவடிக்கை தொடர்பான கூட்டம்' என்ற தொனிப்பொருளில் இடம்பெற்றது.",
        "இதன் போது அவதானம் செலுத்தப்பட்ட விடயம் தொடர்பில் தமிழ் முற்போக்கு கூட்டணியின் பிரதி தலைவர் வேலுசாதி இராதாகிருஷ்ணனிடம் வினவிய போது ,",
        "'தேசிய கொள்கைகள் மற்றும் எதிர்கால நடவடிக்கை தொடர்பான கூட்டம்' என்ற தொனிப்பொருளில் இடம்பெற்ற இந்த கலந்துரையாடலில் 22 ஆவது அரசியலமைப்பு திருத்தத்தில் மேற்கொள்ளப்பட வேண்டிய சீர்திருத்தங்கள் தொடர்பில் விரிவாக அவதானம் செலுத்தப்பட்டது. தேசிய சீர் திருத்தங்களில் ஆர்வமுள்ள அனைத்து தரப்பினரும் இதில் கலந்து கொண்டனர்.",
        "இதன் போது எதிர்க்கட்சி தலைவர் சஜித் பிரேமதாச மற்றும் சிவில் அமைப்புக்களால் முன்வைக்கப்பட்ட கருத்துக்கள் தொடர்பில் பரந்தளவில் கலந்தாலோசிக்கப்பட்டது.",
        "தேசிய மறுசீரமைப்புக்கள் தொடர்பில் கலந்துரையாடலில் கலந்து கொண்ட ஒவ்வொரு தரப்பினரும் தமது நிலைப்பாடுகளையும் , யோசனைகளையும் பகிர்ந்து கொண்டனர்.",
        "ஊழல் , மோசடிகளை முற்றாக இல்லாதொழிப்பதற்கு 22 ஆவது அரசியலமைப்பு திருத்தத்தில் உள்ளடக்கப்பட வேண்டிய கொள்கைகள் தொடர்பில் இதன் போது அவதானம் செலுத்தப்பட்டது என்றார்.",
        "விக்டன் ஐவர், காமினி வியங்கொட, கே.டபிள்யு.ஜனரஞ்சன உள்ளிட்ட சிவில் செயற்பாட்டாளர்களும் , தமிழ் முற்போக்கு கூட்டணியின் தலைவர் மனோ கணேஷன், பிரதி தலைவர்களான வீ.இராதாகிருஷ்ணன், பழனி திகாம்பரம், ஸ்ரீலங்கா முஸ்லிம் காங்ரஸ் தலைவர் ரவுப் ஹக்கீம், தமிழ் மக்கள் தேசிய கூட்டணியின் தலைவர் சி.வி.விக்கினேஸ்வரன் உள்ளிட்ட பல முக்கிஸ்தர்கள் இந்த கலந்துரையாடலில் கலந்து கொண்டமை குறிப்பிடத்தக்கது."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "சஜித் - மைத்திரி",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "விக்கி",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "மைத்திரிபால சிறிசேன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஸ்ரீலங்கா சுதந்திரக் கட்சி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "சஜித் பிரேமதாச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஐக்கிய மக்கள்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "புத்திக பதிரண",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "தமிழ் முற்போக்கு கூட்டணி வேலுசதி ராதாகிருஷ்ணன்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "22வது",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "அரசியலமைப்பு திருத்தம்",
            "label": "LAW"
          },
          {
            "text": "தேசிய சீர் திருத்தங்கள்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "22வது",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "விக்டன் ஐவர்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "காமினி வியங்கொட",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜனரஞ்சனா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "தமிழ் முற்போக்கு கூட்டணி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Mano Ganesan",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "தலைவர்கள் வி.இராதாகிருஷ்ணன்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "பழனி திகாம்பரம்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஸ்ரீலங்கா முஸ்லிம் காங்கிரஸ்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரவூப் ஹக்கீம்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "தமிழ் மக்கள்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "தேசியக் கூட்டணி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "சி.வி.விக்கினேஸ்வரன்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "முகிஸ்தாஸ்",
            "label": "LOC"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}