{
  "newspaper_id": "economy-next-com",
  "url": "https://economynext.com/capital-alliance-ct-clsa-win-top-sri-lankas-cfa-capital-market-awards-96689/",
  "time_ut": 1656568620,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Capital Alliance, CT CLSA win top Sri Lanka’s CFA capital market awards",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Capital Alliance, CT CLSA win top Sri Lanka’s CFA capital market awards",
      "author": "",
      "body_lines": [
        "ECONOMYNEXT  – Sri Lanka’s Capital Alliance and CTCLSA Securities have carried away top capital market awards given by the Chartered Financial Analysts’ chapter in the island, the organization said.",
        "Capital Alliance Securities Private Ltd was awarded Gold for the Best Stockbroking Research Team, CFA said. Asia Securities Private Ltd was awarded the Silver, while CT CLSA Securities Private Ltd received the Bronze award",
        "Capital Alliance and also got the award for the Best Sector Report.  Asia Securities Private Ltd and Capital Alliance Securities Private Ltd share the Bronze award. The Silver award was not presented.",
        "CT CLSA Securities got the Gold award for the Best Equity Research Report. Capital Alliance Securities Private Ltd won both the Silver and the Bronze awards.",
        "Sunshine Holdings PLC got the Gold for Best Investor Relations. The Silver was won by National Development Bank PLC. Dialog Axiata PLC and John Keells Holdings PLC share the Bronze.",
        "Expolanka Holdings PLC under was commended for improved investor relations practices over the past year.",
        "Senfin Money Market Fund was named the the Best Unit Trust Fund. JB Vantage Short-Term Gilt Fund won the Silver. The Bronze award was not presented."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Capital Alliance",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "CT CLSA",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "Sri Lanka’s",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Capital Alliance",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "CTCLSA Securities",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Chartered Financial Analysts",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Capital Alliance Securities Private Ltd",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Gold for the Best Stockbroking Research Team",
            "label": "WORK_OF_ART"
          },
          {
            "text": "CFA",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Asia Securities Private Ltd",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "CT CLSA Securities Private Ltd",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Bronze",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Capital Alliance",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Capital Alliance Securities Private Ltd",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Bronze",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "CT CLSA Securities",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Capital Alliance Securities Private Ltd",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Bronze",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sunshine Holdings PLC",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Gold for Best Investor Relations",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "National Development Bank PLC",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Dialog Axiata PLC",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "John Keells Holdings PLC",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Bronze",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Expolanka Holdings PLC",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the past year",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Bronze",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "Capital Alliance, CT CLSA ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ ඉහළම CFA ප්‍රාග්ධන වෙළෙඳපොළ සම්මාන දිනා ගනී",
      "author": "",
      "body_lines": [
        "ECONOMYNEXT - ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ ප්‍රාග්ධන සන්ධානය සහ CTCLSA සුරැකුම්පත් විසින් දිවයිනේ වරලත් මූල්‍ය විශ්ලේෂකයින්ගේ පරිච්ෙඡ්දය විසින් පිරිනමනු ලබන ඉහළම ප්‍රාග්ධන වෙළෙඳපොළ සම්මාන ලබාගෙන ඇති බව එම සංවිධානය පවසයි.",
        "Capital Alliance Securities Private Ltd හොඳම කොටස් තැරැව්කාර පර්යේෂණ කණ්ඩායම සඳහා රන් සම්මානයෙන් පිදුම් ලැබූ බව CFA පවසයි. Asia Securities Private Ltd රිදී සම්මානයෙන් පිදුම් ලැබූ අතර CT CLSA Securities Private Ltd ලෝකඩ සම්මානයෙන් පිදුම් ලැබීය.",
        "Capital Alliance සහ හොඳම අංශයේ වාර්තාවට හිමි සම්මානය ද හිමි විය. Asia Securities Private Ltd සහ Capital Alliance Securities Private Ltd යන සමාගම් ලෝකඩ සම්මානය බෙදා ගනී. රිදී සම්මානය පිරිනැමුණේ නැහැ.",
        "CT CLSA Securities හොඳම කොටස් පර්යේෂණ වාර්තාව සඳහා රන් සම්මානය ලබා ගත්තේය. සීමාසහිත Capital Alliance Securities Private සමාගම රිදී සහ ලෝකඩ සම්මාන දෙකම දිනා ගත්තේය.",
        "සන්ෂයින් හෝල්ඩිංග්ස් පීඑල්සී හොඳම ආයෝජක සබඳතා සඳහා රන් සම්මානය ලබා ගත්තේය. රිදී පදක්කම ජාතික සංවර්ධන බැංකුව පීඑල්සී විසින් දිනා ගන්නා ලදී. ඩයලොග් ආසියාටා පීඑල්සී සහ ජෝන් කීල්ස් හෝල්ඩිංග්ස් පීඑල්සී ලෝකඩ පදක්කම බෙදා ගනී.",
        "එක්ස්පෝලංකා හෝල්ඩිංග්ස් පීඑල්සී යටතේ පසුගිය වසර තුළ වැඩිදියුණු කළ ආයෝජක සබඳතා භාවිතයන් ඇගයීමට ලක් විය.",
        "සෙන්ෆින් මුදල් වෙළෙඳපොළ අරමුදල හොඳම ඒකක භාර අරමුදල ලෙස නම් කරන ලදී. JB Vantage කෙටි කාලීන ගිල්ට් අරමුදල රිදී පදක්කම දිනා ගත්තේය. ලෝකඩ සම්මානය පිරිනැමුවේ නැත."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ප්රාග්ධන සන්ධානය",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "CT CLSA",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ප්රාග්ධන සන්ධානය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "CTCLSA සුරැකුම්පත්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "වරලත් මුල්‍ය විශ්ලේෂකයින්",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Capital Alliance Securities Private Ltd",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "හොඳම කොටස් තැරැව්කාර පර්යේෂණ කණ්ඩායම සඳහා රන්",
            "label": "WORK_OF_ART"
          },
          {
            "text": "සටන් විරාම ගිවිසුම",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Asia Securities Private Ltd",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "CT CLSA Securities Private Ltd",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ලෝකඩ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ප්රාග්ධන සන්ධානය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Capital Alliance Securities Private Ltd",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ලෝකඩ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "CT CLSA සුරැකුම්පත්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Capital Alliance Securities Private Ltd",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ලෝකඩ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "සන්ෂයින් හෝල්ඩිංග්ස් පීඑල්සී",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "හොඳම ආයෝජක සබඳතා සඳහා රන්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජාතික සංවර්ධන බැංකුව පීඑල්සී",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Dialog Axiata PLC",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජෝන් කීල්ස් හෝල්ඩිංග්ස් පීඑල්සී",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ලෝකඩ",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "එක්ස්පෝලංකා හෝල්ඩිංග්ස් පීඑල්සී",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "පසුගිය වසරේ",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ලෝකඩ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "Capital Alliance, CT CLSA இலங்கையின் CFA மூலதன சந்தை விருதுகளை வென்றது",
      "author": "",
      "body_lines": [
        "ECONOMYNEXT - இலங்கையின் கேபிட்டல் அலையன்ஸ் மற்றும் CTCLSA செக்யூரிட்டீஸ் ஆகியவை தீவில் உள்ள பட்டய நிதி ஆய்வாளர்கள் அத்தியாயத்தால் வழங்கப்பட்ட உயர்மட்ட மூலதன சந்தை விருதுகளை எடுத்துச் சென்றுள்ளதாக அந்த அமைப்பு தெரிவித்துள்ளது.",
        "கேபிடல் அலையன்ஸ் செக்யூரிட்டீஸ் பிரைவேட் லிமிடெட் சிறந்த பங்குத் தரகு ஆராய்ச்சிக் குழுவிற்கான தங்கம் வழங்கப்பட்டது, CFA தெரிவித்துள்ளது. ஆசியா செக்யூரிட்டீஸ் பிரைவேட் லிமிடெட் வெள்ளியும், சிடி சிஎல்எஸ்ஏ செக்யூரிட்டீஸ் பிரைவேட் லிமிடெட் வெண்கல விருதையும் பெற்றன.",
        "கேபிட்டல் அலையன்ஸ் மற்றும் சிறந்த துறை அறிக்கைக்கான விருதையும் பெற்றது. ஆசியா செக்யூரிட்டீஸ் பிரைவேட் லிமிடெட் மற்றும் கேபிடல் அலையன்ஸ் செக்யூரிட்டீஸ் பிரைவேட் லிமிடெட் ஆகியவை வெண்கல விருதைப் பகிர்ந்து கொள்கின்றன. வெள்ளி விருது வழங்கப்படவில்லை.",
        "CT CLSA செக்யூரிட்டீஸ் சிறந்த ஈக்விட்டி ஆராய்ச்சி அறிக்கைக்கான தங்க விருதைப் பெற்றது. கேபிடல் அலையன்ஸ் செக்யூரிட்டீஸ் பிரைவேட் லிமிடெட் வெள்ளி மற்றும் வெண்கல விருதுகளை வென்றது.",
        "சிறந்த முதலீட்டாளர் உறவுகளுக்கான தங்கத்தை Sunshine Holdings PLC பெற்றது. வெள்ளியை தேசிய வளர்ச்சி வங்கி பிஎல்சி வென்றது. Dialog Axiata PLC மற்றும் John Keells Holdings PLC ஆகியவை வெண்கலத்தை பகிர்ந்து கொள்கின்றன.",
        "எக்ஸ்போலங்கா ஹோல்டிங்ஸ் பிஎல்சி கடந்த வருடத்தில் மேம்படுத்தப்பட்ட முதலீட்டாளர் உறவுமுறைகளுக்காகப் பாராட்டப்பட்டது.",
        "சென்ஃபின் மனி மார்க்கெட் ஃபண்ட் சிறந்த யூனிட் டிரஸ்ட் ஃபண்ட் என்று பெயரிடப்பட்டது. ஜேபி வான்டேஜ் குறுகிய கால கில்ட் ஃபண்ட் வெள்ளி வென்றது. வெண்கல விருது வழங்கப்படவில்லை."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "மூலதனக் கூட்டணி",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "CT CLSA",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "இலங்கையின்",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "மூலதனக் கூட்டணி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "CTCLSA பத்திரங்கள்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "பட்டய நிதி ஆய்வாளர்கள்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "கேபிடல் அலையன்ஸ் செக்யூரிட்டீஸ் பிரைவேட் லிமிடெட்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "சிறந்த பங்குத் தரகு ஆராய்ச்சிக் குழுவிற்கான தங்கம்",
            "label": "WORK_OF_ART"
          },
          {
            "text": "CFA",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆசியா செக்யூரிட்டீஸ் பிரைவேட் லிமிடெட்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "CT CLSA Securities Private Ltd",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "வெண்கலம்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "மூலதனக் கூட்டணி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "கேபிடல் அலையன்ஸ் செக்யூரிட்டீஸ் பிரைவேட் லிமிடெட்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "வெண்கலம்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "CT CLSA பத்திரங்கள்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "கேபிடல் அலையன்ஸ் செக்யூரிட்டீஸ் பிரைவேட் லிமிடெட்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "வெண்கலம்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "சன்ஷைன் ஹோல்டிங்ஸ் பிஎல்சி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "சிறந்த முதலீட்டாளர் உறவுகளுக்கான தங்கம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "தேசிய வளர்ச்சி வங்கி பிஎல்சி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Dialog Axiata PLC",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜான் கீல்ஸ் ஹோல்டிங்ஸ் பிஎல்சி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "வெண்கலம்",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "எக்ஸ்போலங்கா ஹோல்டிங்ஸ் பிஎல்சி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "கடந்த ஆண்டு",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "வெண்கலம்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}