{
  "newspaper_id": "daily-mirror-lk",
  "url": "https://www.dailymirror.lk/latest_news/Children-infected-with-Dengue-COVID-19-on-the-rise-at-LRH-Paediatrician/342-242871",
  "time_ut": 1660219802,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Children infected with Dengue, COVID-19 on the rise at LRH: Paediatrician",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Children infected with Dengue, COVID-19 on the rise at LRH: Paediatrician",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "The number of children who are currently receiving treatment for dengue virus and also for COVID-19 at the Lady Ridgeway Hospital (LRH) in Colombo is increasing, LRH Consultant Paediatrician Dr. Deepal Perera said.",
        "He told the Daily Mirror that they found 25 dengue-positive cases - 18 with normal dengue fever, and another eight with dengue haemorrhagic fever (DHF) are being treated at the hospital.",
        "Meanwhile, he stated that nine normal COVID-19-positive children are being treated at the COVID wards, and another two patients are at the hospital's intensive care unit (ICU).",
        "The number of dengue and COVID-positive cases were found after random checking on the patients. If we have checked all the patients, the number would have been more, Dr. Perera said.",
        "Therefore, the doctor advised the people to clean their environment, including their homes and school premises.",
        "He also advised to follow basic health guidelines again to prevent children getting infected with COVID-19 virus. (Chaturanga Samarawickrama)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Dengue",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "the Lady Ridgeway Hospital",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "Colombo",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "LRH",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Deepal Perera",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the Daily Mirror",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "25",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "DHF",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "nine",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "two",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ICU",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Perera",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "Chaturanga Samarawickrama",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "LRH හි වැඩිවෙමින් පවතින ඩෙංගු, COVID-19 ආසාදිත දරුවන්: ළමා රෝග විශේෂඥ වෛද්‍ය",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "කොළඹ රිජ්වේ ආර්යා රෝහලේ (LRH) දැනට ඩෙංගු වයිරසයට සහ COVID-19 සඳහා ප්‍රතිකාර ලබන දරුවන්ගේ සංඛ්‍යාව ඉහළ යමින් පවතින බව LRH ළමා රෝග පිළිබඳ විශේෂඥ වෛද්‍ය දීපාල් පෙරේරා මහතා පැවසීය.",
        "ඔහු ඩේලි මිරර් වෙත පැවසුවේ ඩෙංගු-ධනාත්මක රෝගීන් 25 ක් - සාමාන්‍ය ඩෙංගු උණ 18 ක් සහ ඩෙංගු රක්තපාත උණ (ඩීඑච්එෆ්) ඇති තවත් අට දෙනෙකු රෝහලේ ප්‍රතිකාර ලබන බවයි.",
        "මේ අතර, ඔහු ප්‍රකාශ කළේ සාමාන්‍ය COVID-19-ධනාත්මක ළමුන් නව දෙනෙකු COVID වාට්ටු වල ප්‍රතිකාර ලබන අතර තවත් රෝගීන් දෙදෙනෙකු රෝහලේ දැඩි සත්කාර ඒකකයේ (ICU) සිටින බවයි.",
        "ඩෙංගු සහ කොවිඩ් ආසාදිතයින් සංඛ්‍යාව සොයාගනු ලැබුවේ අහඹු ලෙස රෝගීන් පරීක්ෂා කිරීමෙන් අනතුරුවයි. අපි සියලුම රෝගීන් පරීක්‍ෂා කළා නම් එම සංඛ්‍යාව මීට වඩා වැඩි වෙන්න තිබුණා යැයි වෛද්‍ය පෙරේරා මහතා පැවසීය.",
        "එබැවින් තම නිවෙස් පාසල් පරිශ්‍ර ඇතුළු පරිසරය පිරිසිදු කරන ලෙස වෛද්‍යවරයා ජනතාවට උපදෙස් දුන්නේය.",
        "දරුවන් COVID-19 වෛරසය ආසාදනය වීම වැළැක්වීම සඳහා මූලික සෞඛ්‍ය මාර්ගෝපදේශ අනුගමනය කරන ලෙස ද ඔහු උපදෙස් දුන්නේය. (චතුරංග සමරවික්‍රම)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ඩෙංගු",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "රිජ්වේ ආර්යා රෝහල",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "කොළඹ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "LRH",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "දීපාල් පෙරේරා",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ඩේලි මිරර්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "25",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "DHF",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "නවය",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "දෙක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "දැඩි සත්කාර ඒකකය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "පෙරේරා",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "චතුරංග සමරවික්‍රම",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "டெங்கு, கோவிட்-19 நோயால் பாதிக்கப்பட்ட குழந்தைகள் LRH இல் அதிகரித்து வருகின்றனர்: குழந்தை நல மருத்துவர்",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "கொழும்பில் உள்ள லேடி ரிட்ஜ்வே மருத்துவமனையில் (LRH) டெங்கு வைரஸ் மற்றும் COVID-19 க்கு தற்போது சிகிச்சை பெற்று வரும் குழந்தைகளின் எண்ணிக்கை அதிகரித்து வருவதாக LRH குழந்தை நல மருத்துவர் டாக்டர் தீபால் பெரேரா தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "டெங்கு நோயால் பாதிக்கப்பட்ட 25 பேர் - 18 பேர் சாதாரண டெங்கு காய்ச்சலுடனும், மேலும் 8 பேர் டெங்கு ரத்தக்கசிவு காய்ச்சலுடனும் (DHF) மருத்துவமனையில் சிகிச்சை பெற்று வருவதாக டெய்லி மிரருக்கு அவர் தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "இதற்கிடையில், ஒன்பது சாதாரண COVID-19-பாசிட்டிவ் குழந்தைகள் கோவிட் வார்டுகளில் சிகிச்சை பெற்று வருவதாகவும், மேலும் இரண்டு நோயாளிகள் மருத்துவமனையின் தீவிர சிகிச்சை பிரிவில் (ICU) இருப்பதாகவும் அவர் கூறினார்.",
        "டெங்கு மற்றும் கோவிட்-பாசிட்டிவ் வழக்குகளின் எண்ணிக்கை நோயாளிகளை சீரற்ற சோதனைக்குப் பிறகு கண்டறியப்பட்டது. அனைத்து நோயாளிகளையும் நாங்கள் பரிசோதித்திருந்தால், எண்ணிக்கை அதிகமாக இருந்திருக்கும், டாக்டர் பெரேரா கூறினார்.",
        "எனவே, வீடு, பள்ளி வளாகம் உள்ளிட்ட சுற்றுப்புறங்களைச் சுத்தம் செய்யுமாறு மருத்துவர் அறிவுறுத்தினார்.",
        "குழந்தைகள் COVID-19 வைரஸால் பாதிக்கப்படுவதைத் தடுக்க அடிப்படை சுகாதார வழிகாட்டுதல்களைப் பின்பற்றவும் அவர் அறிவுறுத்தினார். (சதுரங்க சமரவிக்ரம)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "டெங்கு",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "லேடி ரிட்ஜ்வே மருத்துவமனை",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "கொழும்பு",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "LRH",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "தீபால் பெரேரா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "டெய்லி மிரர்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "25",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "DHF",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஒன்பது",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "இரண்டு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஐ.சி.யு",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பெரேரா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "சதுரங்க சமரவிக்ரம",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}