{
  "newspaper_id": "lankadeepa-lk",
  "url": "https://www.lankadeepa.lk/news/ජනපති-මැදුරේ-ආරක්ෂාවට-පියවර-ගනී/101-616319",
  "time_ut": 1657640341,
  "original_lang": "si",
  "original_title": "ජනපති මැදුරේ ආරක්ෂාවට පියවර ගනී",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Measures are being taken to protect the presidential palace",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "The Director General of Archaeology, Professor Anura Manatunga has issued a statement saying that due to the events of the last 9th, archaeological monuments including the President's House in Colombo have been damaged and legal action will have to be taken in accordance with the Antiquities Ordinance Act.",
        "He has mentioned that in order to prevent further damage to the old monuments located in those places and to protect valuable ancient and cultural properties, appropriate actions were taken with the security officials and the parties leading the struggle, and the officials of the department will continue to regularly inspect those places.",
        "As the Director General of Archaeology, it has come to my special attention as the Director General of Archeology that due to the events that took place on the 9th and the subsequent circumstances, the archaeological monuments including the President's House in Colombo have been damaged and the ancient and cultural objects in those places should be prevented from being further destroyed or misplaced. referred to",
        "Thus, at the first possible opportunity, our officials have taken maximum measures to protect the valuable objects in those places. Today (July 12), I personally inspected the damaged places of the President's House, the President's Secretariat and the Araliyagaha Mandir along with the Additional Secretary (Heritage Division) of the Ministry of Religious and Cultural Affairs of the Buddha Sasana (Heritage Division) and the relevant officials of the Archeology Department.",
        "Appropriate measures were taken with the security personnel and parties leading the struggle to prevent further damage to the ancient monuments located in those places and to protect the valuable ancient and cultural properties. The officers of our department will continue to check those places regularly.",
        "I hereby emphasize that to avoid damaging or stealing monuments and antiquities which are public property and the nation's heritage, legal action will have to be taken in accordance with the Antiquities Ordinance. Furthermore, I remind you that protecting national heritage is the responsibility and duty of the general public."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Anura Manatunga",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the last 9th",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "House",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Antiquities Ordinance Act",
            "label": "LAW"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "Archaeology",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "9th",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "House",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "first",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Today",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "July 12",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "House",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Secretariat",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Araliyagaha Mandir",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "Heritage Division",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Ministry of Religious and Cultural Affairs of the Buddha Sasana",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Heritage Division",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Archeology Department",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [],
        []
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "ජනපති මැදුරේ ආරක්ෂාවට පියවර ගනී",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "ඉකුත් 9 වැනි දින වූ සිදුවීම්වලින් ඇති වූ තත්වයන් නිසා කොළඹ ජනාධිපති මන්දිරය ඇතුළු පුරාවිද්‍යා ස්මාරකවලට හානි සිදු වී ඇති බවත් එසේ හානි සිදුකළහොත් පුරාවිද්‍යා ආඥා පනත ප්‍රකාරව නීතිමය ක්‍රියාමාර්ග ගැනීමට සිදුවන බවත් පුරාවිද්‍යා අධ්‍යක්ෂ ජනරාල්, මහාචාර්ය අනුර මනතුංග මහතා නිවේදනයක් නිකුත් කරමින් කියා සිටී.",
        "එම ස්ථානවල පිහිටි පැරණි ස්මාරකවලට තව දුරටත් හානිවීම වලක්වා ගැනීම සදහාත්, වටිනා පෞරාණික හා සංස්කෘතික දේපළ ආරක්ෂා කර ගැනීම සදහාත් ආරක්ෂක නිලධාරීන් සහ අරගලයට නායකත්වය දෙන පාර්ශව සමග සුදුසු ක්‍රියා මාර්ග ගත් බවත්, දෙපාර්තමේන්තුවේ නිලධාරීන් ඉදිරියටත් එම ස්ථාන නිරන්තර පරීක්ෂාවට ලක් කරන බවත් ඔහු සඳහන් කර ඇත.",
        "ඉකුත් 9 වන දින සිදු වූ සිදුවීම් සහ ඉන්පසුව ඇති වූ තත්වයන් නිසා කොළඹ ජනාධිපති මන්දිරය ඇතුළු පුරාවිද්‍යා ස්මාරකවලට හානි සිදු වී ඇති බවත් එම ස්ථානවල තිබුණු පෞරාණික හා සංස්කෘතික වස්තූන්ට තවදුරටත් විනාශවීම සිදු වීම හෝ අස්ථාන ගත වීම වලක්වා ගත යුතු බවත් පුරාවිද්‍යා අධ්‍යක්ෂ ජනරාල්වරයා වශයෙන් මාගේ විශේෂ අවධානයට යොමු වීය.",
        "මේ අනුව හැකි පළමු අවස්ථාවේදී ම අපගේ නිලධාරීන් එම ස්ථානයන් හී ඇති වටිනා වස්තූන් ආරක්ෂා කර ගැනීමට උපරිම පියවර ගෙන ඇත. අද දින (ජුලී 12) බුද්ධ ශාසන ආගමික හා සංස්කෘතික කටයුතු අමාත්‍යාංශයේ අතිරේක ලේකම්තුමිය( උරුම අංශය) සහ පුරාවිද්‍යා දෙපාර්තමේන්තුවේ අදාළ නිලධාරීන් සමග හානි සිදු වූ බව කියන ජනාධිපති මන්දිරය,ජනාධිපති ලේකම් කාර්යාලය සහ අරලියගහ මන්දිරය යන ස්ථාන මා විසින් පෞද්ගලිකවම පරීක්ෂා කරනු ලැබීය.",
        "එම ස්ථානවල පිහිටි පැරණි ස්මාරකවලට තව දුරටත් හානි සිදුවීම වලක්වා ගැනීම සදහාත්,වටිනා පෞරාණික හා සංස්කෘතික දේපළ ආරක්ෂා කර ගැනීම සදහාත් ආරක්ෂක නිලධාරීන් සහ අරගලයට නායකත්වය දෙන පාර්ශව සමග සුදුසු ක්‍රියා මාර් ග ගනු ලැබීය. අප දෙපාර්තමේන්තුවේ නිලධාරීන් ඉදිරියටත් එම ස්ථාන නිරන්තර පරීක්ෂාවට ලක් කරනු ඇත.",
        "මහජන දේපළ සහ ජාතියේ උරුමය වන ස්මාරක සහ පුරාවස්තූන්ට හානි කිරීම හෝ සොරකම් කිරීමෙන් වලකින ලෙසත් එසේ කළ හොත් ඒ සදහා පුරාවිද්‍යා ආඥා පනත ප්‍රකාරව නීතිමය ක්‍රියාමාර්ග ගැනීමට සිදුවන බවත් මෙයින් අවධාරණය කරමි. තවද, ජාතික උරුමයන් ආරක්ෂා කරගැනීම පොදු මහ ජනතාවගේ ද වගකීම සහ යුතුකම බවද සිහිපත් කරමි."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "අනුර මනතුංග",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "පසුගිය 9 වෙනිදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "නිවස",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "පුරාවස්තු ආඥා පනත",
            "label": "LAW"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "පුරාවිද්යාව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "9 වැනි",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "නිවස",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "පළමුවන",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජූලි 12",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "නිවස",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ලේකම් කාර්යාලය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "අරලියගහ මන්දිරය",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "උරුම අංශය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "බුද්ධ ශාසනයේ ආගමික හා සංස්කෘතික කටයුතු අමාත්‍යාංශය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "උරුම අංශය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "පුරාවිද්‍යා දෙපාර්තමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [],
        []
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "ஜனாதிபதி மாளிகையை பாதுகாக்க நடவடிக்கை எடுக்கப்பட்டு வருகிறது",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "கடந்த 9ஆம் திகதி இடம்பெற்ற சம்பவங்களினால் கொழும்பில் உள்ள ஜனாதிபதி மாளிகை உள்ளிட்ட தொல்பொருள் நினைவுச் சின்னங்கள் சேதமடைந்துள்ளதாக தொல்பொருள் திணைக்களத்தின் பணிப்பாளர் நாயகம் பேராசிரியர் அனுர மானதுங்க அறிக்கையொன்றை வெளியிட்டுள்ளார். .",
        "அந்த இடங்களில் அமைந்துள்ள பழைய நினைவுச் சின்னங்களுக்கு மேலும் சேதம் ஏற்படாமல் தடுக்கவும், பெறுமதிமிக்க புராதன, கலாசாரச் சொத்துக்களைப் பாதுகாக்கவும் பாதுகாப்பு அதிகாரிகள் மற்றும் போராட்டத்தை முன்னெடுத்துச் செல்லும் தரப்பினருடன் உரிய நடவடிக்கை எடுக்கப்பட்டதுடன், திணைக்கள அதிகாரிகள் தொடர்ந்தும் நடவடிக்கை எடுப்பதாக அவர் குறிப்பிட்டுள்ளார். அந்த இடங்களை தொடர்ந்து ஆய்வு செய்ய வேண்டும்.",
        "இரட்டைக் குடியுரிமை பெற்றிருந்த ஜனாதிபதி கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ஷ, 2019ஆம் ஆண்டு ஜனாதிபதித் தேர்தலில் போட்டியிடுவதற்காக தனது அமெரிக்கக் குடியுரிமையைத் துறந்ததாக 'தி இந்து' நாளிதழ் குறிப்பிட்டுள்ளது.",
        "எனவே, சாத்தியமான முதல் சந்தர்ப்பத்தில், எங்கள் அதிகாரிகள் அந்த இடங்களில் உள்ள மதிப்புமிக்க பொருட்களைப் பாதுகாக்க அதிகபட்ச நடவடிக்கைகளை எடுத்துள்ளனர். இன்று (ஜூலை 12) நான் புத்தசாசன மத கலாசார அலுவல்கள் அமைச்சின் (பாரம்பரியப் பிரிவு) மேலதிகச் செயலாளருடன் (பாரம்பரியப் பிரிவு) ஜனாதிபதி மாளிகை, ஜனாதிபதி செயலகம் மற்றும் கோயில் இல்லம் ஆகியவற்றின் சேதமடைந்த இடங்களை நேரில் பார்வையிட்டேன். தொல்லியல் துறை சம்பந்தப்பட்ட அதிகாரிகள்.",
        "அந்த இடங்களில் அமைந்துள்ள புராதன நினைவுச் சின்னங்களுக்கு மேலும் சேதம் ஏற்படாமல் தடுக்கவும், பெறுமதிமிக்க புராதன, கலாசாரச் சொத்துக்களைப் பாதுகாக்கவும் பாதுகாப்புப் பணியாளர்கள் மற்றும் தரப்பினர் போராட்டத்தை முன்னெடுத்துச் சென்று உரிய நடவடிக்கை எடுக்கப்பட்டது. அந்த இடங்களை எங்கள் துறை அதிகாரிகள் தொடர்ந்து சோதனை செய்வார்கள்.",
        "பொதுச் சொத்துக்கள் மற்றும் தேசத்தின் பாரம்பரியச் சின்னங்களான நினைவுச் சின்னங்கள் மற்றும் பழங்காலப் பொருட்களை சேதப்படுத்துவதையோ அல்லது திருடுவதையோ தவிர்க்க, தொல்பொருட்கள் கட்டளைச் சட்டத்தின்படி சட்ட நடவடிக்கை எடுக்கப்பட வேண்டும் என்பதை இதன் மூலம் வலியுறுத்துகிறேன். மேலும், தேசிய பாரம்பரியத்தைப் பாதுகாப்பது பொதுமக்களின் பொறுப்பும் கடமையும் என்பதை நான் உங்களுக்கு நினைவூட்டுகிறேன்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "அனுர மனதுங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "கடந்த 9ம் தேதி",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "வீடு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "தொல்பொருட்கள் கட்டளைச் சட்டம்",
            "label": "LAW"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "தொல்லியல்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "9வது",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "வீடு",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "முதலில்",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜூலை 12",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "வீடு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "செயலகம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "அரலியகஹா மந்திர்",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாரம்பரிய பிரிவு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "புத்த சாசனத்தின் மத மற்றும் கலாச்சார அலுவல்கள் அமைச்சு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாரம்பரிய பிரிவு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "தொல்லியல் துறை",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [],
        []
      ]
    }
  }
}