{
  "newspaper_id": "lankadeepa-lk",
  "url": "https://www.lankadeepa.lk/world_news/ඇමෙරිකා-ජනපතිට-කොරෝනා/14-616835",
  "time_ut": 1658419480,
  "original_lang": "si",
  "original_title": "ඇමෙරිකා ජනපතිට කොරෝනා",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Corona for the US President",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "It is seen in an announcement issued by the White House that United States President Joe Biden has been infected with the Covid-19 virus.",
        "The announcement issued by the White House further states that although 79-year-old Biden is infected with the Covid-19 virus, he is not showing severe symptoms.",
        "The White House has further said that President Biden has received the two doses of the main anti-Covid vaccine and the booster vaccine doses.",
        "White House spokeswoman Karin Jean-Pierre has explained that the President is in quarantine at the White House and his duties are being carried out as usual.",
        "It has been further stated in the announcement issued by the White House that President Joe Biden is taking Paxlovide, an antiviral drug for Covid disease."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Corona",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "US",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "the White House",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "United States",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Joe Biden",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the White House",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "79-year-old",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Biden",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "The White House",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Biden",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "two",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "White House",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Karin Jean-Pierre",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the White House",
            "label": "FAC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the White House",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Joe Biden",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Paxlovide",
            "label": "PRODUCT"
          },
          {
            "text": "Covid",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "ඇමෙරිකා ජනපතිට කොරෝනා",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "ඇමෙරිකා එක්සත් ජනාධිපති ජෝ බයිඩන් ට කොවිඩ්-19 වයිරසය අසාදනය වී ඇතැයි ධවල මන්දිරය නිකුත් කළ නිවේදනයක දැක්වෙයි.",
        "79 හැවිරිදි බයිඩන් ට කොවිඩ් වයිරසය ආසාදනය වුවත්, දරුණු රෝග ලක්ෂණ පෙන්නුම් නොකරන බව ධවල මන්දිරය නිකුත් කළ නිවේදනයේ වැඩි දුරටත් සදහන් වෙයි.",
        "ජනාධිපති බයිඩන් ප්‍රධාන කොවිඩ් මර්දන එන්නත් මාත්‍රා දෙක සහ බූස්ටර් එන්නත් මාත්‍රා දෙකම ලබා ගෙන ඇති බව ද ධවල මන්දිරය වැඩි දුරටත් පවසා තිබේ.",
        "ජනාධිපතිවරයා ධවල මන්දිරයේ නිරෝධායනය වන අතර රාජකාරි කටයුතු සාමාන්‍ය පරිදි සිදුකරන බව ධවල මන්දිර ප්‍රකාශිකා කැරින් ජීන් පියෙර් පැහැදිලි කර තිබේ.",
        "ජනාධිපති ජෝ බයිඩන් කොවිඩ් රෝගය සඳහා  ප්‍රතිවෛරස් ඖෂධයක් වන පැක්ස්ලොවිඩ් ලබා ගන්නා බව ධවල මන්දිරය නිකුත් කළ නිවේදනයේ වැඩි දුරටත් සදහන් වී ඇත."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "කොරෝනා",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "එක්සත් ජනපදය",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ධවල මන්දිරය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "එක්සත් ජනපදය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Joe Biden",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ධවල මන්දිරය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "79 හැවිරිදිය",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "බයිඩෙන්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ධවල මන්දිරය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "බයිඩෙන්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "දෙක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ධවල මන්දිරය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Karin Jean-Pierre",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ධවල මන්දිරය",
            "label": "FAC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ධවල මන්දිරය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Joe Biden",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "පැක්ස්ලොවයිඩ්",
            "label": "PRODUCT"
          },
          {
            "text": "කොවිඩ්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "அமெரிக்க அதிபருக்கு கொரோனா",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "அமெரிக்க ஜனாதிபதி ஜோ பிடனுக்கு கோவிட்-19 வைரஸ் தொற்று ஏற்பட்டுள்ளதாக வெள்ளை மாளிகை வெளியிட்டுள்ள அறிவிப்பில் தெரிவிக்கப்பட்டுள்ளது.",
        "79 வயதான பிடென் கோவிட் -19 வைரஸால் பாதிக்கப்பட்டிருந்தாலும், அவர் கடுமையான அறிகுறிகளைக் காட்டவில்லை என்று வெள்ளை மாளிகை வெளியிட்டுள்ள அறிவிப்பில் மேலும் கூறப்பட்டுள்ளது.",
        "ஜனாதிபதி பிடன் முக்கிய கோவிட் எதிர்ப்பு தடுப்பூசி மற்றும் பூஸ்டர் தடுப்பூசி அளவுகளின் இரண்டு டோஸ்களைப் பெற்றுள்ளார் என்று வெள்ளை மாளிகை மேலும் கூறியுள்ளது.",
        "ஜனாதிபதி வெள்ளை மாளிகையில் தனிமைப்படுத்தப்பட்டுள்ளதாகவும், அவரது கடமைகள் வழமை போன்று முன்னெடுக்கப்படுவதாகவும் வெள்ளை மாளிகையின் பேச்சாளர் கரின் ஜீன் பியர் விளக்கமளித்துள்ளார்.",
        "ஜனாதிபதி ஜோ பிடன், கோவிட் நோய்க்கான வைரஸ் தடுப்பு மருந்தான பாக்ஸ்லோவைடை உட்கொள்வதாக வெள்ளை மாளிகை வெளியிட்டுள்ள அறிவிப்பில் மேலும் தெரிவிக்கப்பட்டுள்ளது."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "கொரோனா",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "எங்களுக்கு",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "வெள்ளை மாளிகை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "அமெரிக்கா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Joe Biden",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "வெள்ளை மாளிகை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "79 வயதானவர்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "பிடன்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "வெள்ளை மாளிகை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "பிடன்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இரண்டு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "வெள்ளை மாளிகை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "கரின் ஜீன்-பியர்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "வெள்ளை மாளிகை",
            "label": "FAC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "வெள்ளை மாளிகை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Joe Biden",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாக்ஸ்லோவைடு",
            "label": "PRODUCT"
          },
          {
            "text": "கோவிட்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}