{
  "newspaper_id": "economy-next-com",
  "url": "https://economynext.com/sri-lankas-presidential-vote-alahapperuma-comes-from-far-behind-after-premadasas-withdrawal-97699/",
  "time_ut": 1658292600,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Sri Lanka’s presidential vote – Alahapperuma comes from far behind after Premadasa’s withdrawal",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Sri Lanka’s presidential vote – Alahapperuma comes from far behind after Premadasa’s withdrawal",
      "author": "",
      "body_lines": [
        "ECONOMYNEXT – Sri Lanka’s former Media Minister Dullas Alahapperuma’s chances to win the presidential vote have increased after Opposition Leader Sajith Premadasa withdrew from the presidential race to support his rival, but the outcome will be decided by individual secret votes.",
        "Since Premadasa’s withdrawal, many independent and minority political parties have pledged support to Alahapperuma, but he is not favoured by the majority of the former ruling Sri Lanka Podujana Peramuna (SLPP) lawmakers, a block vote which will be the deciding factor on Wednesday’s vote.",
        "Analysts have come up with their own predictions which show both Alahepperuma and Acting President Ranil Wickremesinghe having equal chances to become the eighth executive president of Sri Lanka.",
        "“We are confident Dullas-Sajith team will make it through this morning and begin the process to end the Sri Lanka crisis,” Premadasa’s close ally and lawmaker Harsha de Silva tweeted Wednesday (20) morning.",
        "Wickremesinghe’s camp has not commented on their strength, but it believes lawmakers who are attacked and affected by the protesters will not vote for their own SLPP colleague Alahepperuma because Premadasa is now seen close to protesters. (Colombo/Jul20/2022)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Sri Lanka",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "Premadasa",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka’s",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Media",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Dullas Alahapperuma",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sajith Premadasa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Premadasa",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "Podujana Peramuna",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Wednesday",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "eighth",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Dullas-Sajith",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "this morning",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Premadasa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Wednesday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "20) morning",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Wickremesinghe’s",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Premadasa",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Colombo/Jul20/2022",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ ජනාධිපති ඡන්දය - ප්‍රේමදාසගේ ඉවත්වීමෙන් පසු අලහප්පෙරුම එන්නේ බොහෝ පසුපසිනි",
      "author": "",
      "body_lines": [
        "ECONOMYNEXT - විපක්ෂ නායක සජිත් ප්‍රේමදාස සිය ප්‍රතිවාදියාට සහය දැක්වීම සඳහා ජනාධිපතිවරණ තරඟයෙන් ඉවත්වීමෙන් පසු ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ හිටපු ජනමාධ්‍ය අමාත්‍ය ඩලස් අලහප්පෙරුම මහතාට ජනාධිපතිවරණ ජයග්‍රහණය කිරීමේ අවස්ථාව වැඩි වී ඇත, නමුත් ප්‍රතිඵලය තනි තනි රහස් ඡන්දයෙන් තීරණය වේ.",
        "ප්‍රේමදාස ඉවත්වීමෙන් පසු, බොහෝ ස්වාධීන සහ සුළුතර දේශපාලන පක්ෂ අලහප්පෙරුමට සහාය පළ කර ඇතත්, හිටපු පාලක ශ්‍රී ලංකා පොදුජන පෙරමුණේ (SLPP) මන්ත්‍රීවරුන්ගෙන් බහුතරය ඔහුට කැමති නැත, එය බදාදා ඡන්දයේ තීරණාත්මක සාධකය වනු ඇත.",
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ අටවැනි විධායක ජනාධිපතිවරයා වීමට අලහප්පෙරුම සහ වැඩබලන ජනාධිපති රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ යන දෙදෙනාටම සමාන අවස්ථා තිබෙන බව විශ්ලේෂකයෝ තමන්ගේම අනාවැකි ඉදිරිපත් කර තිබේ.",
        "“ඩලස්-සජිත් කණ්ඩායම අද උදෑසන එය ජයගෙන ශ්‍රී ලංකා අර්බුදය අවසන් කිරීමේ ක්‍රියාවලිය ආරම්භ කරනු ඇතැයි අපට විශ්වාසයි,” ප්‍රේමදාසගේ සමීප සගයකු සහ නීති සම්පාදක හර්ෂ ද සිල්වා බදාදා (20) උදෑසන ට්විටර් පණිවුඩයක් නිකුත් කළේය.",
        "වික්‍රමසිංහගේ කඳවුර ඔවුන්ගේ ශක්තිය ගැන අදහස් දක්වා නැත, නමුත් ප්‍රේමදාස දැන් විරෝධතාකරුවන්ට සමීපව සිටින බැවින් විරෝධතාකරුවන්ගෙන් පහර කෑමට සහ පීඩාවට පත් වූ මන්ත්‍රීවරුන් තමන්ගේම ශ්‍රී ලංකා පොදුජන පෙරමුණේ සගයකු වන අලහප්පෙරුම මහතාට ඡන්දය නොදෙනු ඇතැයි එය විශ්වාස කරයි. (කොළඹ/ජූලි20/2022)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "ප්‍රේමදාස ය",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මාධ්ය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඩලස් අලහප්පෙරුම",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "සජිත් ප්‍රේමදාස",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ප්‍රේමදාස ය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "පොදුජන පෙරමුණ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "බදාදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "අටවැනි",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ඩලස් - සජිත්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "මේ උදෑසන",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ප්‍රේමදාස ය",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "බදාදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "20) උදෑසන",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "වික්‍රමසිංහගේ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ප්‍රේමදාස ය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "කොළඹ/ජූලි20/2022",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "இலங்கையின் ஜனாதிபதி வாக்கெடுப்பு - பிரேமதாசவின் விலகலுக்குப் பிறகு அழகப்பெரும மிகவும் பின்தங்கிய நிலையில் இருந்து வருகிறார்",
      "author": "",
      "body_lines": [
        "ECONOMYNEXT - இலங்கையின் முன்னாள் ஊடகத்துறை அமைச்சர் டலஸ் அழகப்பெருமவின் ஜனாதிபதி வாக்கெடுப்பில் வெற்றிபெறும் வாய்ப்பு எதிர்க்கட்சித் தலைவர் சஜித் பிரேமதாச தனது போட்டியாளரை ஆதரிப்பதற்காக ஜனாதிபதிப் போட்டியில் இருந்து விலகியதை அடுத்து, தனிப்பட்ட இரகசிய வாக்குகளால் தீர்மானிக்கப்படும்.",
        "பிரேமதாச வெளியேறியதில் இருந்து, பல சுயேச்சை மற்றும் சிறுபான்மை அரசியல் கட்சிகள் அழகப்பெருமவுக்கு ஆதரவளிப்பதாக உறுதியளித்துள்ளன, ஆனால், புதன் கிழமை வாக்கெடுப்பில் தீர்மானிக்கும் காரணியாக இருக்கும் தொகுதி வாக்கெடுப்பு, முன்னாள் ஆளும் ஸ்ரீலங்கா பொதுஜன பெரமுன (SLPP) நாடாளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர்களில் பெரும்பான்மையினரால் அவருக்கு ஆதரவாக இல்லை.",
        "இலங்கையின் எட்டாவது நிறைவேற்று அதிகாரம் கொண்ட ஜனாதிபதியாக வருவதற்கு அலஹெப்பெரும மற்றும் பதில் ஜனாதிபதி ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க ஆகிய இருவருக்குமே சம வாய்ப்புகள் இருப்பதாக ஆய்வாளர்கள் தங்கள் சொந்த கணிப்புகளை முன்வைத்துள்ளனர்.",
        "பிரேமதாசவின் நெருங்கிய கூட்டாளியும் பாராளுமன்ற உறுப்பினருமான ஹர்ஷ டி சில்வா புதன்கிழமை (20) காலை ட்வீட் செய்துள்ளார், “டலஸ்-சஜித் அணி இன்று காலை வெற்றியடைந்து இலங்கை நெருக்கடியை முடிவுக்கு கொண்டுவரும் செயல்முறையைத் தொடங்கும் என்று நாங்கள் நம்புகிறோம்.",
        "விக்கிரமசிங்கவின் முகாம் அவர்களின் பலம் குறித்து கருத்து தெரிவிக்கவில்லை, ஆனால் எதிர்ப்பாளர்களால் தாக்கப்பட்ட மற்றும் பாதிக்கப்பட்ட சட்டமியற்றுபவர்கள் தங்கள் சொந்த SLPP சகாவான அழஹெப்பெருமவுக்கு வாக்களிக்க மாட்டார்கள் என்று அது நம்புகிறது, ஏனெனில் பிரேமதாச இப்போது எதிர்ப்பாளர்களுடன் நெருக்கமாக இருக்கிறார். (கொழும்பு/ஜூலை20/2022)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "இலங்கை",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "பிரேமதாச",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கையின்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஊடகம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "டலஸ் அழகப்பெரும",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "சஜித் பிரேமதாச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பிரேமதாச",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "பொதுஜன பெரமுன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "புதன்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "எட்டாவது",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "டலஸ்-சஜித்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று காலை",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "பிரேமதாச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "புதன்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "20) காலை",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "விக்கிரமசிங்கவின்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "பிரேமதாச",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "கொழும்பு/ஜூலை20/2022",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}