{
  "newspaper_id": "news-first-lk",
  "url": "https://www.newsfirst.lk/2022/07/15/slpp-to-support-ranil-for-president/",
  "time_ut": 1657883280,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "SLPP to support Ranil for President",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "SLPP to support Ranil for President",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); The General Secretary of the Sri Lanka Podujana Peramuna, Attorney-At-Law Sagara Kariyawasam states that the SLPP will support Acting President Ranil Wickremesinghe at the upcoming election for President.",
        "The election for President will take place on the 20th of July in Parliament..",
        "Earlier, Parliamentarian Dullas Alahapperuma expressed his intentions to contest for the vacant post of President of Sri Lanka, after the resignation of former President Gotabaya Rajapaksa was confirmed today (15).",
        "New President : MPs now represent entire electorate of Sri Lanka, says BASL"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Ranil",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "News 1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "Podujana Peramuna",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the 20th of July",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Parliamentarian Dullas Alahapperuma",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Gotabaya Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "15",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "SLPP සහය රනිල්ට",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); ඉදිරි ජනාධිපතිවරණයේදී ශ්‍රී ලංකා පොදුජන පෙරමුණ වැඩබලන ජනාධිපති රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතාට සහය පළ කරන බව ශ්‍රී ලංකා පොදුජන පෙරමුණේ ප්‍රධාන ලේකම් නීතීඥ සාගර කාරියවසම් මහතා පවසයි.",
        "ජනපතිවරණය ජූලි 20 වැනිදා පාර්ලිමේන්තුවේදී පැවැත්වේ.",
        "හිටපු ජනාධිපති ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ මහතාගේ ඉල්ලා අස්වීම අද (15) තහවුරු වීමත් සමඟ පුරප්පාඩු වූ ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ ජනාධිපති ධූරය සඳහා තරඟ කිරීමට පාර්ලිමේන්තු මන්ත්‍රී ඩලස් අලහප්පෙරුම මහතා මීට පෙර අදහස් පළ කළේය.",
        "නව ජනාධිපති : පාර්ලිමේන්තු මන්ත්‍රීවරුන් දැන් ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ සමස්ත මැතිවරණ කොට්ඨාසයම නියෝජනය කරන බව BASL පවසයි"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "රනිල්",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "News 1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "පොදුජන පෙරමුණ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ජූලි 20 වැනිදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තු මන්ත්‍රී ඩලස් අලහප්පෙරුම",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "15",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "ஜனாதிபதி தேர்தலில் ரணிலுக்கு SLPP ஆதரவு",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); எதிர்வரும் ஜனாதிபதித் தேர்தலில் ஶ்ரீலங்கா பொதுஜன பெரமுன பதில் ஜனாதிபதி ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்கவுக்கு ஆதரவளிக்கும் என ஸ்ரீலங்கா பொதுஜன பெரமுனவின் பொதுச் செயலாளர் சட்டத்தரணி சாகர காரியவசம் தெரிவித்துள்ளார்.",
        "குடியரசுத் தலைவர் பதவிக்கான தேர்தல் ஜூலை 20ஆம் தேதி நாடாளுமன்றத்தில் நடைபெறுகிறது.",
        "இலங்கையின் முன்னாள் ஜனாதிபதி கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்சவின் இராஜினாமா இன்று (15) உறுதி செய்யப்பட்டதையடுத்து வெற்றிடமாகவுள்ள ஜனாதிபதி பதவிக்கு போட்டியிடவுள்ளதாக நாடாளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர் டலஸ் அழகப்பெரும முன்னதாக தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "புதிய ஜனாதிபதி: பாராளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர்கள் இப்போது இலங்கையின் முழு வாக்காளர்களையும் பிரதிநிதித்துவப்படுத்துகின்றனர் என்று BASL தெரிவித்துள்ளது"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ரணில்",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "News 1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "பொதுஜன பெரமுன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஜூலை 20 ஆம் தேதி",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர் டலஸ் அழகப்பெரும",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "15",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}