{
  "newspaper_id": "lankadeepa-lk",
  "url": "https://www.lankadeepa.lk/latest_news/වජිර-තව-අනාවැකියක්-කියයි/1-616610",
  "time_ut": 1658128594,
  "original_lang": "si",
  "original_title": "වජිර තව අනාවැකියක් කියයි",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Vajira makes another prophecy",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "United National Party Chairman Mr. Vajira Abeywardena says that Ranil Wickremesinghe will get 140 votes or more in the parliamentary election to select the President.",
        "Mr. Abeywardena, who said that none of his previous predictions were wrong, also said that \"Ranil\" is 1000 percent \"sure\" that he will be the president.",
        "Mr. Abeywardena said that as the chairman of the United National Party, he has discussed the matters necessary to free the country from anarchy with Pohottuwa and other members of the party.",
        "The UNP chairman also said that if all 225 members of the parliament work together, the country can be freed from anarchy. Mr. Vajira Abeywardena said that the democratic struggle, which was also approved by the United National Party, had gone to a point where the flames would ignite and if the process of burning down the houses of the people's representatives and destroying the state property continued, the country would be completely destroyed.",
        "Acting President Ranil Wickramasinghe is the only leader who has clearly presented a program at a time of crisis when no one has clearly presented a series of policies that will take the country forward, said Mr. Vajira Abiveardhana."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Vajira",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "United National Party",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Vajira Abeywardena",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "140",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Abeywardena",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "1000 percent",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Abeywardena",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the United National Party",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Pohottuwa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "UNP",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "225",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Vajira Abeywardena",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the United National Party",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickramasinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Vajira Abiveardhana",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "වජිර තව අනාවැකියක් කියයි",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "ජනාධිපතිවරයා තෝරන පාර්ලිමේන්තු ඡන්දයේ දී රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ ඡන්ද 140ක් හෝ ඊට වැඩියෙන් ගන්නා බව එක්සත් ජාතික පක්ෂ සභාපති වජිර අබේවර්ධන මහතා පවසයි.",
        "තමා මීට පෙර පැවසූ අනාවැකි එකක්වත් වැරදී නැති බව කී අබේවර්ධන මහතා \"රනිල්\" ජනපති වීම සියයට දහසක් \"ෂුවර්\" බව ද කීය.",
        "එක්සත් ජාතික පක්ෂයේ සභාපතිවරයා වශයෙන් තමා පොහොට්ටුව ඇතුළු සෙසු පක්ෂවල මන්ත්‍රීවරුන් සමග රට අරාජිකත්වයෙන් මුදා ගැනීම සඳහා අවශ්‍ය කරුණු සාකච්ඡා කර තිබෙන බව කී අබෙිවර්ධන මහතා ජනාධිපතිවරයා තෝරන්නේ රහස් ඡන්දයකින් හෙයින් ඉක්මනින්ම ශ්‍රී ලංකාවට යහපතක් කාලයක් උදාවනු ඇතැයි විශ්වාසය තබා ගත හැකි බවද සඳහන් කළේය.",
        "පාර්ලිමේන්තුවේ 225 ම එකමුතුව කටයුතු කළොත් රට අරාජිකත්වයෙන් මුදා ගත හැකි බව ද එජාප සභාපතිවරයා කීය. එක්සත් ජාතික පක්ෂ විසින් ද අනුමත කළ ප්‍රජතාන්ත්‍රවාදී අරගලය ගිනි දැල් පත්තු වෙන තැනකට ගමන් කළ බවද රටේ මහජන නියෝජිතයන්ගේ නිවාස ගිනි බත් කරන, රාජ්‍ය දේපොළ විනාශ කරන ක්‍රියාදාමය ඉදිරියට ගමන් කළහොත් රට සම්පූර්ණයෙන්ම විනාශයට යන බවද වජිර අබේවර්ධන මහතා කීය.",
        "කිසිවෙක් රට ඉදිරියට ගෙනයන ප්‍රතිපත්ති මාලාවක් පැහැදිලිව ජාතියට ඉදිරිපත් නොකළ අර්බුදකාරී මොහොතක වැඩපිළිවෙලක් පැහැදිලිව ඉදිරිපත් කළ එකම නායකයා වැඩ බලන ජනාධිපති රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ බවද වජිර අබෙිවර්ධන මහතා පැවසීය ."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "වජිර",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "එක්සත් ජාතික පක්ෂය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "වජිර අබේවර්ධන",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "140",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "අබේවර්ධන ය",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "සියයට 1000ක්",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "අබේවර්ධන ය",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "එක්සත් ජාතික පක්ෂය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "පොහොට්ටුව",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "එජාප",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "225",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "වජිර අබේවර්ධන",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "එක්සත් ජාතික පක්ෂය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "වජිර අභිවර්ධන",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "வஜிரா மற்றொரு தீர்க்கதரிசனம் கூறுகிறார்",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "ஜனாதிபதியை தெரிவு செய்வதற்கான பாராளுமன்றத் தேர்தலில் ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க 140 அல்லது அதற்கு மேற்பட்ட வாக்குகளைப் பெறுவார் என ஐக்கிய தேசியக் கட்சியின் தலைவர் திரு வஜிர அபேவர்தன தெரிவித்துள்ளார்.",
        "தனது முன்னைய கணிப்புகள் எதுவும் தவறில்லை என தெரிவித்த திரு.அபேவர்தன, தான் ஜனாதிபதியாவார் என்பதில் \"ரணில்\" 1000 வீதம் \"நிச்சயம்\" எனவும் தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "ஐக்கிய தேசியக் கட்சியின் தலைவர் என்ற வகையில் பொஹொட்டுவ மற்றும் கட்சியின் ஏனைய உறுப்பினர்களுடன் நாட்டை அராஜகத்திலிருந்து விடுவிப்பதற்கு தேவையான விடயங்கள் தொடர்பில் கலந்துரையாடியுள்ளதாக திரு.அபேவர்தன தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "நாடாளுமன்றத்தில் உள்ள 225 உறுப்பினர்களும் ஒன்றிணைந்து செயற்பட்டால் நாட்டை அராஜகத்திலிருந்து விடுவிக்க முடியும் எனவும் ஐக்கிய தேசியக் கட்சியின் தலைவர் தெரிவித்துள்ளார். ஐக்கிய தேசியக் கட்சியும் அங்கீகரித்த ஜனநாயகப் போராட்டம் தீப்பற்றி எரியும் நிலைக்குச் சென்றுள்ளதாகவும், மக்கள் பிரதிநிதிகளின் வீடுகளை எரித்து அரச சொத்துக்களை அழிக்கும் நடவடிக்கை தொடர்ந்தால், வஜிர அபேவர்தன, நாடு முற்றிலுமாக அழிக்கப்படும்.",
        "நாட்டை முன்னோக்கி கொண்டு செல்லும் கொள்கைகளை எவரும் தெளிவாக முன்வைக்காத நெருக்கடியான நேரத்தில் ஒரு வேலைத்திட்டத்தை தெளிவாக முன்வைத்த ஒரே தலைவர் பதில் ஜனாதிபதி ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க மட்டுமே என வஜிர அபிவர்தன தெரிவித்தார்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "வஜிரா",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ஐக்கிய தேசிய கட்சி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "வஜிர அபேவர்தன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "140",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "அபேவர்தன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "1000 சதவீதம்",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "அபேவர்தன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஐக்கிய தேசிய கட்சி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "பொஹொட்டுவ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஐ.தே.க",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "225",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "வஜிர அபேவர்தன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஐக்கிய தேசிய கட்சி",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "வஜிர அபிவர்தன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}