{
  "newspaper_id": "ada-derana-lk",
  "url": "http://www.adaderana.lk/news/83501/petrol-diesel-can-be-sold-for-around-rs-250-pucsl-chairman-tells-cope",
  "time_ut": 1657257300,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Petrol, diesel can be sold for around Rs. 250, PUCSL chairman tells COPE",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Petrol, diesel can be sold for around Rs. 250, PUCSL chairman tells COPE",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "Petrol and diesel can be sold at a price of approximately Rs. 250 in Sri Lanka, said the chairman of the Public Utilities Commission of Sri Lanka (PUCSL) Janaka Ratnayake said in a personal statement made to the Committee on Public Enterprises (COPE).",
        "He stated this when COPE members in Parliament on July 06, under the chairmanship of MP Prof. Charita Herath to examine the Auditor General’s report for the years 2018 and 2019 and current performance of the Public Utilities Commission of Sri Lanka.",
        "Explaining this further, PUCSL chairman mentioned that this was revealed in the statistics on the import prices of petroleum and the taxes levied by the government. He pointed out that petrol and diesel can be provided in Sri Lanka at Rs. 200 less than the current price. According to this, petrol and diesel can be sold at a price of approximately Rs. 250. He also said the government has collected a tax of Rs. 280 for one litre of diesel imported on July 01.",
        "The PUCSL chairman noted that this is his personal statement and he would make the statement after consulting the data. Accordingly, the members present asked about the awareness of the officials of the commission and the officials of the board of directors said that they are not aware of it. It was also mentioned here that the Ministry of Finance has not formally informed about this.",
        "COPE members inquired Ratnayake about his qualifications for becoming the chairman of this commission. He pointed out that he has obtained a special degree in Public Administration from the University of Sri Jayewardenepura and a postgraduate degree in Business Administration (MBA) from the University of Colombo. He also mentioned that he has also studied at Harvard University. As for his political qualifications, he stated that since 2005, the Rajapaksas have been greatly supported in forming governments.",
        "COPE chairman mentioned that the statement made by PUCSL chief regarding the fuel price is more serious and the attention of the country would be drawn to the matter. Therefore, officials from the Ministry of Power & Energy and the PUCSL Chairman are expected to be summoned before the COPE to inspect the matter in the future, Prof. Herath said further.",
        "Further, the purchase by the commission of a “Benz” car manufactured in the year 2005 without fuel or driver from a company called General Business (Pvt) Ltd without entering into any agreement for a period of one year from December 07, 2021 was also discussed at length at the COPE meeting. It was revealed that the annual rent for this vehicle was Rs. 4,500,000 and that Rs. 2,187,500 was paid on May 31 this year to the aforesaid company.",
        "However, the COPE inquired as to why the files regarding the hiring of this vehicle were not submitted for audit, recommendations were given to hire a 15-year-old vehicle, as well as the irregularities in calling for bids for the hiring of this vehicle, and the issues of transparency in the payment of rent for this vehicle. In particular, the committee instructed the officer who signed the approval to provide money for this institution to act responsibly.",
        "Accordingly, Prof. Herath recommended that an investigation be conducted and a full report be submitted to the COPE.",
        "Further, although it was informed that the organization structure and salary structure of the PUCSL should be developed under the recommendation of the National Salary and Cadre Commission and the approval of the Department of Management Services and that the Finance Minister should submit an amendment to the Cabinet and approve it, the committee discussed spending on certain functions without doing it by the end of 2021.",
        "In particular, the COPE paid attention to the fact that Rs. 45,873,483 was paid to the staff of the institution under 11 types of allowances. In addition, the committee paid more attention to the fact that Rs. 86,808,538 of the total operating cost, (49% of the total amount) was spent on public awareness programs.",
        "In particular, attention was paid to the approved electricity generation plan for the years 2018-2037. The officials present mentioned that data on another new generation plan was submitted in the year 2021 and was not approved as the appropriate requirements were not met. Here, the Committee mentioned that when the political authorities change, problems arise due to the change of these plans, so all parties should pay more attention to this.",
        "Furthermore, under the Electricity (Distribution) Performance Standards Orders mentioned in a special gazette notice issued in 2016, the commission was assigned the responsibility of preparing and implementing the performance rules. Thus, the work that should be implemented within 36 months after the decree came into effect, although almost 4 years have passed, the committee drew attention to the fact that even the adaptation phase, which was planned to be completed in 2018, has not yet been completed. The officials who were present mentioned that this was planned to be done in 3 phases in 3 years and that it has not happened yet due to the need to change the system and the problems in the relationship between the parties involved."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "250",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "PUCSL",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "COPE",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "250",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Public Utilities Commission",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Janaka Ratnayake",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Committee on Public Enterprises",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "COPE",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "COPE",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "July 06",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "MP",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Charita Herath",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Auditor General’s",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the years 2018 and",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "2019",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Public Utilities Commission",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "PUCSL",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "200",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "250",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "280",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "one",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "July 01",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "PUCSL",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Ministry of Finance",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "COPE",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Public Administration",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the University of Sri Jayewardenepura",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Business Administration",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the University of Colombo",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Harvard University",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "2005",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Rajapaksas",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "COPE",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "PUCSL",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Ministry of Power & Energy",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "PUCSL",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "COPE",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Herath",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the year 2005",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "General Business (Pvt) Ltd",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "a period of",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "one year",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "December 07, 2021",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "COPE",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "4,500,000",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "2,187,500",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "May 31 this year",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the COPE inquired",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "15-year-old",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Herath",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "COPE",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "PUCSL",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Cadre Commission",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Department of Management Services",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Finance",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Cabinet",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the end of 2021",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "COPE",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "45,873,483",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "86,808,538",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "49%",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the years 2018-2037",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the year 2021",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Committee",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "2016",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "36 months",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "almost 4 years",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "2018",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "3",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "3 years",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "පෙට්‍රල්, ඩීසල් රුපියල් 100කට විතර විකුණන්න පුළුවන්. 250, PUCSL සභාපති කෝප් කමිටුවට කියයි",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "පෙට්‍රල් සහ ඩීසල් දළ වශයෙන් රු. ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ 250 ක් බව ශ්‍රී ලංකා මහජන උපයෝගිතා කොමිෂන් සභාවේ (PUCSL) සභාපති ජනක රත්නායක මහතා පොදු ව්‍යාපාර පිළිබඳ කාරක සභාවට (COPE) පෞද්ගලික ප්‍රකාශයක් කරමින් පැවසීය.",
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකා මහජන උපයෝගිතා කොමිෂන් සභාවේ 2018 සහ 2019 වසර සඳහා වන විගණකාධිපති වාර්තාව සහ වත්මන් ක්‍රියාකාරීත්වය විමර්ශනය කිරීම සඳහා පාර්ලිමේන්තු මන්ත්‍රී මහාචාර්ය චරිතා හේරත් මහතාගේ ප්‍රධානත්වයෙන් ජුලි 06 වැනිදා කෝප් සාමාජිකයන් පාර්ලිමේන්තුවේදී මේ බව ප්‍රකාශ කළේය.",
        "මේ පිළිබඳව තවදුරටත් පැහැදිලි කළ මහජන උපයෝගිතා කොමිසමේ සභාපතිවරයා සඳහන් කළේ ඛනිජ තෙල් ආනයනික මිල ගණන් සහ රජය අය කරන බදු පිළිබඳ සංඛ්‍යාලේඛනවලින් මේ බව හෙළි වූ බවයි. ඔහු පෙන්වා දුන්නේ පෙට්‍රල් සහ ඩීසල් ශ්‍රී ලංකාව තුළ රු. දැනට පවතින මිලට වඩා 200ක් අඩුයි. මේ අනුව පෙට්‍රල් සහ ඩීසල් දළ වශයෙන් රු. 250. රජය රුපියල් 250 ක බද්දක් අයකරගෙන ඇතැයි ද ඔහු පැවසීය. ජූලි 01 වැනිදා ආනයනය කළ ඩීසල් ලීටරයක් ​​රුපියල් 280කි.",
        "මෙය තමාගේ පෞද්ගලික ප්‍රකාශයක් බවත් දත්ත විමසා බැලීමෙන් අනතුරුව ප්‍රකාශය කරන බවත් මහජන උපයෝගිතා කොමිසමේ සභාපතිවරයා සඳහන් කළේය. ඒ අනුව කොමිසමේ නිලධාරීන් දැනුවත් කිරීම සම්බන්ධයෙන් පැමිණ සිටි සාමාජිකයින් විමසූ අතර අධ්‍යක්ෂ මණ්ඩල නිලධාරීන් පැවසුවේ තමන් ඒ පිළිබඳව නොදන්නා බවයි. මේ පිළිබඳව මුදල් අමාත්‍යාංශය නිල වශයෙන් දැනුම් දී නොමැති බවද මෙහිදී සඳහන් කෙරුණා.",
        "මෙම කොමිසමේ සභාපතිවරයා වීමට රත්නායක මහතාගේ සුදුසුකම් පිළිබඳව කෝප් කමිටු සාමාජිකයින් විමසා සිටියා. තමා ශ්‍රී ජයවර්ධනපුර විශ්වවිද්‍යාලයෙන් රාජ්‍ය පරිපාලනය පිළිබඳ විශේෂ උපාධියක්ද, කොළඹ විශ්වවිද්‍යාලයෙන් ව්‍යාපාර පරිපාලනය පිළිබඳ පශ්චාත් උපාධියක්ද (MBA) ලබාගෙන ඇති බවද ඔහු පෙන්වා දුන්නේය. ඔහු හාවඩ් විශ්වවිද්‍යාලයේද අධ්‍යාපනය ලබා ඇති බවද සඳහන් කළේය. ඔහුගේ දේශපාලන සුදුසුකම් සම්බන්ධයෙන් ඔහු ප්‍රකාශ කළේ 2005 වසරේ සිට ආණ්ඩු පිහිටුවීමේදී රාජපක්ෂවරුන්ට විශාල සහයෝගයක් ලැබුණු බවයි.",
        "ඉන්ධන මිල සම්බන්ධයෙන් මහජන උපයෝගිතා කොමිසමේ ප්‍රධානියා කළ ප්‍රකාශය වඩාත් බරපතළ බවත් ඒ පිළිබඳව රටේ අවධානය යොමු කරන බවත් කෝප් කමිටු සභාපතිවරයා සඳහන් කළේය. එම නිසා ඉදිරියේදී මේ පිළිබඳව සොයා බැලීම සඳහා විදුලිබල හා බලශක්ති අමාත්‍යාංශයේ නිලධාරීන් සහ මහජන උපයෝගිතා කොමිසමේ සභාපතිවරයා කෝප් කමිටුව හමුවට කැඳවීමට බලාපොරොත්තු වන බවද මහාචාර්ය හේරත් මහතා වැඩිදුරටත් පැවසීය.",
        "තවද, 2021 දෙසැම්බර් 07 වැනි දින සිට වසරක කාලයක් සඳහා කිසිදු ගිවිසුමකට එළැඹීමකින් තොරව 2005 වර්ෂයේ දී ඉන්ධන හෝ රියැදුරු නොමැතිව නිෂ්පාදනය කරන ලද “Benz” මෝටර් රථයක් General Business (Pvt) Ltd නම් සමාගමෙන් කොමිස් මුදලින් මිලදී ගැනීමද කෝප් කමිටු රැස්වීමේදී දීර්ඝ ලෙස සාකච්ඡා කළා. මෙම වාහනයේ වාර්ෂික කුලිය රු. 4,500,000 ක් වන අතර එම රු. 2,187,500 මෙම වසරේ මැයි 31 දින ඉහත සඳහන් සමාගමට ගෙවා ඇත.",
        "කෙසේ වෙතත් මෙම වාහනය කුලියට ගැනීම සම්බන්ධ ලිපිගොනු විගණනයට ඉදිරිපත් නොකළේ මන්දැයි කෝප් කමිටුව විමසා සිටියේ වසර 15ක් පැරණි වාහනයක් කුලියට ගැනීමට නිර්දේශ ලබා දීම මෙන්ම මෙම වාහනය කුලියට ගැනීම සඳහා ලංසු කැඳවීමේ අක්‍රමිකතා පිළිබඳවය. , සහ මෙම වාහනය සඳහා කුලී ගෙවීමේ විනිවිදභාවය පිළිබඳ ගැටළු. විශේෂයෙන්ම මෙම ආයතනයට මුදල් ලබා දෙන ලෙස අනුමැතියට අත්සන් කළ නිලධාරියාට වගකීමෙන් කටයුතු කරන ලෙස කමිටුව උපදෙස් දුන්නේය.",
        "ඒ අනුව පරීක්ෂණයක් පවත්වා සම්පූර්ණ වාර්තාවක් කෝප් කමිටුවට ඉදිරිපත් කරන ලෙස මහාචාර්ය හේරත් නිර්දේශ කළේය.",
        "තවද, ජාතික වැටුප් හා සේවක සංඛ්‍යා කොමිෂන් සභාවේ නිර්දේශය සහ කළමනාකරණ සේවා දෙපාර්තමේන්තුවේ අනුමැතිය යටතේ PUCSL හි සංවිධාන ව්‍යුහය සහ වැටුප් ව්‍යුහය සංවර්ධනය කළ යුතු බවත් මුදල් අමාත්‍යවරයා විසින් කැබිනට් මණ්ඩලයට සංශෝධනයක් ඉදිරිපත් කළ යුතු බවත් දන්වා සිටියද. සහ එය අනුමත කරන අතර, 2021 අවසානය වන විට එය සිදු නොකර ඇතැම් කාර්යයන් සඳහා වියදම් කිරීම පිළිබඳව කමිටුව සාකච්ඡා කළේය.",
        "විශේෂයෙන්ම කෝප් කමිටුවේ අවධානය යොමු වූයේ රු. 45,873,483 දීමනා වර්ග 11ක් යටතේ ආයතනයේ කාර්ය මණ්ඩලය වෙත ගෙවා ඇත. ඊට අමතරව කමිටුව වැඩි අවධානයක් යොමු කළේ රු. සමස්ත මෙහෙයුම් පිරිවැයෙන් 86,808,538, (මුළු මුදලින් 49%) මහජනතාව දැනුවත් කිරීමේ වැඩසටහන් සඳහා වියදම් කරන ලදී.",
        "විශේෂයෙන්ම 2018-2037 වසර සඳහා අනුමත විදුලි ජනන සැලැස්ම කෙරෙහි අවධානය යොමු විය. 2021 වසරේ තවත් නව ජනන සැලැස්මක් පිළිබඳ දත්ත ඉදිරිපත් කර ඇති අතර සුදුසු අවශ්‍යතා සපුරා නොමැති බැවින් එය අනුමත නොකළ බව පැමිණ සිටි නිලධාරීන් සඳහන් කළේය. මෙහිදී කාරක සභාව සඳහන් කළේ දේශපාලන අධිකාරිය වෙනස් වන විට මෙම සැලසුම් වෙනස් කිරීම හේතුවෙන් ගැටලු මතුවන බැවින් ඒ පිළිබඳව සියලු පාර්ශ්ව වැඩි අවධානයක් යොමු කළ යුතු බවයි.",
        "තවද, 2016 වසරේ නිකුත් කරන ලද විශේෂ ගැසට් නිවේදනයක සඳහන් විදුලි (බෙදාහැරීමේ) කාර්ය සාධන ප්‍රමිති නියෝග යටතේ, කාර්ය සාධන නීති සකස් කිරීමේ සහ ක්‍රියාත්මක කිරීමේ වගකීම කොමිෂන් සභාවට පවරා ඇත. මේ අනුව, නියෝගය ක්‍රියාත්මක වී මාස 36ක් ඇතුළත ක්‍රියාත්මක කළ යුතු වැඩකටයුතු වසර 4කට ආසන්න කාලයක් ගතවී ඇතත්, 2018 වසරේ නිම කිරීමට සැලසුම් කර තිබූ අනුවර්තන අදියර පවා මෙතෙක් සිදුවී නොමැති බව කමිටුවේ අවධානය යොමු විය. සම්පූර්ණ කර ඇත. මෙය වසර 3ක් තුළ අදියර 3ක් යටතේ සිදුකිරීමට සැලසුම් කර තිබූ බවත්, ක්‍රමය වෙනස් කිරීමේ අවශ්‍යතාවය සහ ඊට සම්බන්ධ පාර්ශ්ව අතර පවතින සබඳතාවයේ පවතින ගැටලු හේතුවෙන් එය මෙතෙක් සිදු නොවූ බවත් පැමිණ සිටි නිලධාරීන් සඳහන් කළා."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "250",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "PUCSL",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "කෝප්",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "250",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මහජන උපයෝගිතා කොමිෂන් සභාව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජානක රත්නායක",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "පොදු ව්‍යාපාර පිළිබඳ කාරක සභාව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "කෝප්",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "කෝප්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජූලි 06",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "පා.ම",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "චරිත හේරත්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "විගණකාධිපතිගේ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "වසර 2018 සහ",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "2019",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මහජන උපයෝගිතා කොමිෂන් සභාව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "PUCSL",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "200",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "250",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "280",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "එක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජූලි 01",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "PUCSL",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "මුදල් අමාත්යාංශය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "කෝප්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "රාජ්ය පරිපාලනය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ජයවර්ධනපුර විශ්වවිද්‍යාලය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ව්යාපාර පරිපාලනය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "කොළඹ විශ්වවිද්‍යාලය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "හාවඩ් විශ්ව විද්‍යාලය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "2005",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "රාජපක්ෂලා",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "කෝප්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "PUCSL",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "විදුලිබල හා බලශක්ති අමාත්යාංශය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "PUCSL",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "කෝප්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "හේරත්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "2005 වර්ෂය",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "General Business (Pvt) Ltd",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "කාල සීමාවක්",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "වසරක්",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "2021 දෙසැම්බර් 07",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "කෝප්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "4,500,000",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "2,187,500 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "මේ වසරේ මැයි 31",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "කෝප් කමිටුව විමසා සිටියේය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "අවුරුදු 15 යි",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "හේරත්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "කෝප්",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "PUCSL",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "සේවක සංඛ්‍යා කොමිසම",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "කළමනාකරණ සේවා දෙපාර්තමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "මූල්ය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "මණ්ඩල",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "2021 අවසානයේ",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "කෝප්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "45,873,483 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "86,808,538 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "49%",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "2018-2037 වසර",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "වසර 2021",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "කමිටුවක්",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "2016",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මාස 36 යි",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "වසර 4 කට ආසන්න කාලයක්",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "2018",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "3",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "අවුරුදු 3 යි",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "பெட்ரோல், டீசல் விலை சுமார் ரூ. 250, PUCSL தலைவர் COPE க்கு கூறுகிறார்",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "பெட்ரோல் மற்றும் டீசல் விலை சுமார் ரூ. இலங்கையில் 250 என்று இலங்கை பொதுப் பயன்பாடுகள் ஆணைக்குழுவின் (PUCSL) தலைவர் ஜனக ரத்நாயக்க, பொது நிறுவனங்கள் தொடர்பான குழுவிற்கு (COPE) தனிப்பட்ட முறையில் அளித்த அறிக்கையில் தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "2018 மற்றும் 2019 ஆம் ஆண்டுகளுக்கான கணக்காய்வாளர் நாயகத்தின் அறிக்கை மற்றும் இலங்கை பொதுப் பயன்பாடுகள் ஆணைக்குழுவின் தற்போதைய செயற்பாடுகளை ஆராய்வதற்காக பாராளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர் பேராசிரியர் சரித ஹேரத் தலைமையில் கோப் உறுப்பினர்கள் ஜூலை 06 ஆம் திகதி பாராளுமன்றத்தில் உரையாற்றிய போதே அவர் இவ்வாறு தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "இது தொடர்பில் மேலும் விளக்கமளித்த PUCSL தலைவர், பெட்ரோலியத்தின் இறக்குமதி விலைகள் மற்றும் அரசாங்கம் விதிக்கும் வரிகள் குறித்த புள்ளிவிபரங்களில் இது தெரியவந்துள்ளதாக குறிப்பிட்டார். இலங்கையில் பெற்றோல் மற்றும் டீசலை ரூபாவிற்கு வழங்க முடியும் என அவர் சுட்டிக்காட்டியுள்ளார். தற்போதைய விலையை விட 200 குறைவு. இதன்படி பெட்ரோல், டீசல் விலை தோராயமாக ரூ. 250. அரசு ரூ. வரி வசூலித்துள்ளதாகவும் அவர் கூறினார். ஜூலை 01 அன்று இறக்குமதி செய்யப்பட்ட ஒரு லிட்டர் டீசல் 280 ரூபாய்.",
        "PUCSL தலைவர், இது அவரது தனிப்பட்ட அறிக்கை என்றும், தரவுகளை கலந்தாலோசித்த பிறகு தான் அறிக்கை வெளியிடுவேன் என்றும் குறிப்பிட்டார். இதன்படி, அங்கிருந்த உறுப்பினர்கள் ஆணைக்குழுவின் அதிகாரிகளிடம் இதுபற்றிய விழிப்புணர்வு குறித்து கேட்டதற்கு, அது குறித்து தங்களுக்கு தெரியவில்லை என நிர்வாக குழு அதிகாரிகள் தெரிவித்தனர். இது தொடர்பில் நிதியமைச்சு முறைப்படி தெரிவிக்கவில்லை எனவும் இங்கு குறிப்பிடப்பட்டுள்ளது.",
        "இந்த ஆணைக்குழுவின் தலைவராக இருப்பதற்கான தகுதிகள் குறித்து கோப் உறுப்பினர்கள் ரத்நாயக்கவிடம் கேட்டறிந்தனர். தாம் ஸ்ரீ ஜயவர்தனபுர பல்கலைக்கழகத்தில் பொது நிர்வாக சிறப்புப் பட்டத்தையும், கொழும்பு பல்கலைக்கழகத்தில் வணிக நிர்வாகத்தில் (MBA) முதுகலைப் பட்டத்தையும் பெற்றுள்ளதாக அவர் சுட்டிக்காட்டினார். ஹார்வர்ட் பல்கலைகழகத்திலும் படித்துள்ளதாகவும் அவர் குறிப்பிட்டுள்ளார். தனது அரசியல் தகுதியைப் பொறுத்தவரை, 2005 ஆம் ஆண்டிலிருந்து, அரசாங்கங்களை அமைப்பதில் ராஜபக்சக்கள் பெரிதும் ஆதரிக்கப்பட்டதாக அவர் குறிப்பிட்டார்.",
        "எரிபொருள் விலை தொடர்பில் PUCSL தலைவர் விடுத்துள்ள கருத்து மிகவும் பாரதூரமானது எனவும், இவ்விடயம் தொடர்பில் நாட்டின் கவனத்தை ஈர்க்கவுள்ளதாகவும் கோப் தலைவர் குறிப்பிட்டுள்ளார். எனவே, மின்சக்தி மற்றும் எரிசக்தி அமைச்சின் அதிகாரிகள் மற்றும் PUCSL தலைவர் ஆகியோர் எதிர்காலத்தில் இந்த விடயத்தை ஆய்வு செய்வதற்காக கோப் முன் அழைக்கப்படுவார்கள் என எதிர்பார்க்கப்படுவதாக பேராசிரியர் ஹேரத் மேலும் தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "மேலும், டிசம்பர் 07, 2021 முதல் ஒரு வருட காலத்திற்கு எந்தவித ஒப்பந்தமும் செய்து கொள்ளாமல் ஜெனரல் பிசினஸ் (பிரைவேட்) லிமிடெட் என்ற நிறுவனத்திடம் இருந்து 2005 ஆம் ஆண்டு எரிபொருள் அல்லது ஓட்டுனர் இல்லாமல் தயாரிக்கப்பட்ட “பென்ஸ்” காரை கமிஷன் மூலம் வாங்கியது. கோப் கூட்டத்தில் நீண்ட நேரம் விவாதிக்கப்பட்டது. இந்த வாகனத்திற்கு ஆண்டு வாடகை ரூ.100 என்பது தெரியவந்தது. 4,500,000 மற்றும் அந்த ரூ. மேற்கூறிய நிறுவனத்திற்கு இந்த ஆண்டு மே 31 அன்று 2,187,500 செலுத்தப்பட்டது.",
        "எவ்வாறாயினும், இந்த வாகனத்தை வாடகைக்கு எடுப்பது தொடர்பான கோப்புகள் ஏன் தணிக்கைக்கு சமர்ப்பிக்கப்படவில்லை, 15 வருடங்கள் பழமையான வாகனத்தை வாடகைக்கு எடுப்பதற்கான பரிந்துரைகள் வழங்கப்பட்டன, அத்துடன் இந்த வாகனத்தை வாடகைக்கு எடுப்பதற்கு ஏலம் கோருவதில் உள்ள குளறுபடிகள் குறித்தும் கோப் குழு வினவியது. , மற்றும் இந்த வாகனத்திற்கான வாடகையை செலுத்துவதில் வெளிப்படைத்தன்மையின் சிக்கல்கள். குறிப்பாக, இந்த நிறுவனத்திற்கு பணத்தை வழங்குமாறு ஒப்புதலில் கையெழுத்திட்ட அதிகாரியை பொறுப்புடன் செயல்படுமாறு குழு அறிவுறுத்தியது.",
        "இதன்படி, விசாரணை நடத்தி முழுமையான அறிக்கையை கோப் குழுவிடம் சமர்ப்பிக்குமாறு பேராசிரியர் ஹேரத் பரிந்துரைத்தார்.",
        "மேலும், தேசிய சம்பள மற்றும் பணியாளர்கள் ஆணைக்குழுவின் பரிந்துரை மற்றும் முகாமைத்துவ சேவைகள் திணைக்களத்தின் அங்கீகாரத்தின் கீழ் PUCSL இன் நிறுவன கட்டமைப்பு மற்றும் சம்பள அமைப்பு உருவாக்கப்பட வேண்டும் என்றும் நிதியமைச்சர் அமைச்சரவையில் ஒரு திருத்தத்தை சமர்ப்பிக்க வேண்டும் என்றும் தெரிவிக்கப்பட்டது. 2021 ஆம் ஆண்டின் இறுதிக்குள் அதைச் செய்யாமல் சில செயல்பாடுகளுக்குச் செலவு செய்வது குறித்து குழு விவாதித்தது.",
        "குறிப்பாக கோப் குழு கவனம் செலுத்தியது. 45,873,483 நிறுவன ஊழியர்களுக்கு 11 வகையான கொடுப்பனவுகளின் கீழ் வழங்கப்பட்டது. மேலும், இந்த குழு அதிக கவனம் செலுத்தி ரூ. மொத்த இயக்கச் செலவில் 86,808,538, (மொத்தத் தொகையில் 49%) பொது விழிப்புணர்வு நிகழ்ச்சிகளுக்காக செலவிடப்பட்டது.",
        "குறிப்பாக, 2018-2037 ஆம் ஆண்டுக்கான அங்கீகரிக்கப்பட்ட மின் உற்பத்தித் திட்டம் குறித்து கவனம் செலுத்தப்பட்டது. மற்றொரு புதிய தலைமுறை திட்டத்தின் தரவு 2021 ஆம் ஆண்டில் சமர்ப்பிக்கப்பட்டதாகவும், அதற்கான தேவைகள் பூர்த்தி செய்யப்படாததால் அங்கீகரிக்கப்படவில்லை என்றும் அங்கிருந்த அதிகாரிகள் குறிப்பிட்டுள்ளனர். இங்கு அரசியல் அதிகாரங்கள் மாறும்போது இத்திட்டங்கள் மாற்றப்படுவதால் பிரச்சனைகள் ஏற்படுவதால் அனைத்து தரப்பினரும் இதில் அதிக கவனம் செலுத்த வேண்டும் என குழு குறிப்பிட்டுள்ளது.",
        "மேலும், 2016 ஆம் ஆண்டு வெளியிடப்பட்ட விசேட வர்த்தமானி அறிவிப்பில் குறிப்பிடப்பட்டுள்ள மின்சாரம் (விநியோகம்) செயல்திறன் தர நிர்ணய ஆணைகளின் கீழ், செயல்திறன் விதிகளை தயாரித்து நடைமுறைப்படுத்துவதற்கான பொறுப்பு ஆணைக்குழுவிற்கு வழங்கப்பட்டது. இதனால், அரசாணை அமலுக்கு வந்து 36 மாதங்களுக்குள் செயல்படுத்த வேண்டிய பணிகள், கிட்டத்தட்ட 4 ஆண்டுகள் கடந்தும், 2018ல் முடிக்க திட்டமிடப்பட்ட தழுவல் கட்டம் கூட இன்னும் நடக்கவில்லை என, குழு கவனத்தை ஈர்த்தது. முடிக்கப்பட்டது. இதனை 3 வருடங்களில் 3 கட்டங்களாக மேற்கொள்ள திட்டமிடப்பட்டிருந்ததாகவும், முறைமை மாற்றப்பட வேண்டியதன் காரணமாகவும், சம்பந்தப்பட்ட தரப்பினரிடையே ஏற்பட்டுள்ள உறவில் ஏற்பட்டுள்ள பிரச்சினைகளாலும் இதுவரை அது நடைபெறவில்லை எனவும் அங்கிருந்த அதிகாரிகள் குறிப்பிட்டுள்ளனர்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "250",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "PUCSL",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "கோப்",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "250",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "பொது பயன்பாட்டு ஆணையம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜனக ரத்நாயக்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "பொது நிறுவனங்களுக்கான குழு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "கோப்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "கோப்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜூலை 06",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "எம்.பி",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "சரிதா ஹேரத்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆடிட்டர் ஜெனரல்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆண்டுகள் 2018 மற்றும்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "2019",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "பொது பயன்பாட்டு ஆணையம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "PUCSL",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "200",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "250",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "280",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஒன்று",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜூலை 01",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "PUCSL",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "நிதி அமைச்சகம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "கோப்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "பொது நிர்வாகம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஸ்ரீ ஜயவர்தனபுர பல்கலைக்கழகம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "வியாபார நிர்வாகம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "கொழும்பு பல்கலைக்கழகம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஹார்வர்ட் பல்கலைக்கழகம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "2005",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ராஜபக்சேக்கள்",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "கோப்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "PUCSL",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "மின்சாரம் மற்றும் எரிசக்தி அமைச்சகம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "PUCSL",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "கோப்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஹேரத்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "2005 ஆம் ஆண்டு",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜெனரல் பிசினஸ் (பிரைவேட்) லிமிடெட்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஒரு காலம்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஒரு வருடம்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "டிசம்பர் 07, 2021",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "கோப்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "4,500,000",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "2,187,500",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்த ஆண்டு மே 31",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "கோப் விசாரித்தது",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "15 வயது",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஹேரத்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "கோப்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "PUCSL",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "கேடர் கமிஷன்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "மேலாண்மை சேவைகள் துறை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "நிதி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "மந்திரி சபை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "2021 இறுதியில்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "கோப்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "45,873,483",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "86,808,538",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "49%",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "2018-2037 ஆண்டுகள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "2021 ஆம் ஆண்டு",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "குழு",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "2016",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "36 மாதங்கள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "கிட்டத்தட்ட 4 ஆண்டுகள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "2018",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "3",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "3 ஆண்டுகள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}