{
  "newspaper_id": "lankadeepa-lk",
  "url": "https://www.lankadeepa.lk/news/ලංකාපුර-පරිපාලන-නිලධාරිනිය-ඝාතනයට-සැමියා-අත්අඩංගුවට/101-615911",
  "time_ut": 1657019399,
  "original_lang": "si",
  "original_title": "ලංකාපුර පරිපාලන නිලධාරිනිය ඝාතනයට සැමියා අත්අඩංගුවට",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Husband arrested for murdering Lankapura administrative officer",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "The Lankapura police say that her husband was arrested on suspicion of murdering the chief administrative officers of the Lankapura Divisional Secretariat along with the ax allegedly used in the killing on the evening of (5).",
        "On the 4th at around 2:30 in the morning, Ms. Yamuna Padmini, an administrative officer, was killed while she was residing at her house in Talpotha Lankapura. Herat Mudiansela's husband, Kapila Senarath Bandara (41), the father of two children, was arrested on suspicion of this. .P. K. Mr. Pathirana said.",
        "According to the investigating police, the suspect confessed to the police that his wife scolded him not to come home after drinking alcohol, and to pay the debt due, and as a result of an argument between the two, he attacked him with an axe.",
        "Statements of another suspect related to this murder will be obtained and further investigation of the incident will be conducted by Polonnaruwa Senior Superintendent of Police Mr. Oshan Hewawitharana. P. K. A team of police officers including Mr. Pathirana."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Lankapura",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the evening",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "5",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "4th",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "2:30 in the morning",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "Yamuna Padmini",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Talpotha Lankapura",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Herat Mudiansela's",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kapila Senarath Bandara",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "41",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "two",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "K.",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Pathirana",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "two",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Polonnaruwa Senior Superintendent of Police",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Oshan Hewawitharana",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "P. K. A",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Pathirana",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "ලංකාපුර පරිපාලන නිලධාරිනිය ඝාතනයට සැමියා අත්අඩංගුවට",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "ලංකාපුර ප්‍රාදේශීය ලේකම් කාර්යාලයේ ප්‍රධාන පරිපාලන නිලධාරීන්ගේ ඝාතනයට සැකපිට ඇයගේ ස්වාමියා, ඝාතනයට යොදාගත් බව කියන පොරවද සමඟ (5) වෙනිදා සවස  අත්අඩංගුවට ගත් බව ලංකාපුර පොලිසිය කියයි.",
        "ඉකුත් 4 වනදා අලුයම දෙකයි තිහට පමණ තල්පොත ලංකාපුර නිවසේ පදිංචිව සිටියදී පරිපාලන නිලධාරිනිය වූ යමූනා පද්මිණී මහත්මිය ඝාතනයට ලක්වූ අතර අැයෙග් සැමියා වන හේරත් මුදියන්සේලාගේ කපිල සෙනරත් බණ්ඩාර (41) දෙදරු පියා මෙලෙස සැකපිට අත්අඩංගුවට ගත් බව ලංකාපුර පොලිස් ස්ථානාධිපති පොලිස් පරීක්ෂක පී. .පී. කේ. පතිරණ මහතා පැවැසීය.",
        "තම බිරිඳ තමාට මත්පැන් බී නිවසට නොපැමිණෙන ලෙසත්, ගෙවීමට ඇති ණය මුදල් ගෙවන ලෙසට බැණ වැදුණු බවත්, ඒ අනුව දෙදෙනා අතර බහින් බස් වීමක් දුරදිගයාම හේතුවෙන් තමා පොරවෙන් පහර දුන් බවට සැකකරු පොලිසියට පාපොච්චාරණය කර  බවද පරීක්ෂණ සිදුකරන පොලිසිය සඳහන් කරයි.",
        "මෙම ඝාතනය සම්බන්ධ තවදුරටත් සැකකරුවෙක් ප්‍රකාශ ලබා ගන්නා අතර සිද්ධිය පිළිබඳ වැඩිදුර විමර්ශන කටයුතු පොලොන්නරුව ජේ්‍යෂ්ඨ පොලිස් අධිකාරි ඕශාන් හේවාවිතාරණ මහතාගේ උපදෙස් පරිදි  ලංකාපුර පොලිස් ස්ථානාධිපති පොලිස් පරීක්ෂක පී. පී. කේ. පතිරණ මහතා ඇතුළු පොලිස් නිලධාරීහු කණ්ඩායමක් සිදුකරති."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ලංකාපුර",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "සවස",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "5",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "4 වැනි",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාන්දර 2:30 ට",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "යමුනා පද්මිණී",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "තල්පොත ලංකාපුර",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "හේරත් මුදියන්සේලාගේ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "කපිල සෙනරත් බණ්ඩාර",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "41",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "දෙක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "කේ.",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "පතිරණ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "දෙක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "පොළොන්නරුව ජ්‍යෙෂ්ඨ පොලිස් අධිකාරි",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඔෂාන් හේවාවිතාරණ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "පී.කේ.ඒ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "පතිරණ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "லங்காபுர நிர்வாக அதிகாரியை கொலை செய்த கணவர் கைது",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "லங்காபுர பிரதேச செயலகத்தின் பிரதான நிர்வாக அதிகாரிகளை கொலைக்கு பயன்படுத்தியதாக கூறப்படும் கோடரியுடன் (5) மாலை சந்தேகத்தின் பேரில் அவரது கணவர் கைது செய்யப்பட்டதாக லங்காபுர பொலிஸார் தெரிவிக்கின்றனர்.",
        "கடந்த 4ஆம் திகதி அதிகாலை 2:30 மணியளவில் தல்பொத லங்காபுரவில் உள்ள தனது வீட்டில் வசித்து வந்த நிர்வாக உத்தியோகத்தர் திருமதி யமுனா பத்மினி படுகொலை செய்யப்பட்டார்.ஹேரத் முடியன்செலவின் கணவர் கபில செனரத் பண்டார (41) இரண்டு பிள்ளைகளின் தந்தையாவார். , இது தொடர்பாக சந்தேகத்தின் பேரில் கைது செய்யப்பட்டார். .பி. கே. பத்திரன தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "விசாரணை நடத்திய பொலிசார் கூறுகையில், மது அருந்திவிட்டு வீட்டுக்கு வரக்கூடாது என்றும், கடனை கட்டுமாறும் மனைவி திட்டியதாகவும், இருவருக்கும் இடையே ஏற்பட்ட வாக்குவாதம் காரணமாக கோடரியால் தாக்கியதாகவும் சந்தேக நபர் பொலிஸாரிடம் வாக்குமூலம் அளித்துள்ளார்.",
        "இந்த கொலையுடன் தொடர்புடைய மற்றுமொரு சந்தேகநபரின் வாக்குமூலங்கள் பெறப்படுவதுடன், சம்பவம் தொடர்பான மேலதிக விசாரணைகளை பொலன்னறுவை சிரேஷ்ட பொலிஸ் அத்தியட்சகர் திரு.ஓஷான் ஹேவாவிதாரண நடத்துவார். பி. கே. பத்திரன உள்ளிட்ட பொலிஸ் அதிகாரிகள் குழு."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "லங்காபுர",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "மாலை",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "5",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "4வது",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "அதிகாலை 2:30 மணி",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "யமுனா பத்மினி",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "தல்பொத லங்காபுர",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஹெராத் முடிசெலாவின்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "கபில செனரத் பண்டார",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "41",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "இரண்டு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "கே.",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "பத்திரனா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இரண்டு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பொலன்னறுவை சிரேஷ்ட பொலிஸ் அத்தியட்சகர்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஒஷான் ஹேவாவிதாரண",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "பி.கே. ஏ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "பத்திரனா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}