{
  "newspaper_id": "daily-mirror-lk",
  "url": "https://www.dailymirror.lk/breaking_news/Another-round-of-talks-between-President-IMF/108-243793",
  "time_ut": 1661519014,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Another round of talks between President, IMF",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Another round of talks between President, IMF",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "Another round of discussions with the International Monetary Fund, with the aim of finding solutions to the financial crisis facing Sri Lanka, was held this afternoon (24) at the President's Office under the patronage of President Ranil Wickremesinghe.",
        "Presidential Media Division said that President Wickremesinghe joined the meeting via zoom technology and both parties exchanged ideas in a positive manner.",
        "The IMF had made a request for additional information pertaining to electricity tariff revisions, Excise Act etc and it was decided at this meeting to provide the requested  information by next Monday.",
        "Financial and legal advisors of the IMF joined today’s meeting and another round of discussions has been scheduled for next Wednesday (31).",
        "Peter Breuer, Head of the International Monetary Fund's Negotiation Panel, Deputy Head Masahiro Nozaki, Tubagus Feridhanusetyawan, Permanent Representative of the International Monetary Fund in Sri Lanka, and Chief of Staff to the President and Senior Advisor to the President on National Security Sagala Ratnayake, President's Secretary Saman Ekanayake, Central Bank Governor Dr. Nandalal Weerasinghe and several other Central Bank senior officers were present on this occasion, it added."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "the International Monetary Fund",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "this afternoon",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "24",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Presidential Media Division",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "next Monday",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "IMF",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "next Wednesday",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Peter Breuer",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the International Monetary Fund's Negotiation Panel",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Head Masahiro Nozaki",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Feridhanusetyawan",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the International Monetary Fund",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "National Security Sagala Ratnayake",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Saman Ekanayake",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Central Bank",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Nandalal Weerasinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Central Bank",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "ජනපති, IMF අතර තවත් සාකච්ඡා වටයක්",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකාව මුහුණ දී සිටින මූල්‍ය අර්බුදයට විසඳුම් සෙවීමේ අරමුණින් ජාත්‍යන්තර මූල්‍ය අරමුදල සමඟ තවත් සාකච්ඡා වටයක් ජනාධිපති රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතාගේ ප්‍රධානත්වයෙන් අද (24) පස්වරුවේ ජනාධිපති කාර්යාලයේදී පැවැත්විණි.",
        "ජනාධිපති මාධ්‍ය අංශය පැවසුවේ, සූම් තාක්ෂණය ඔස්සේ ජනාධිපති වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතා හමුවට එක් වූ අතර දෙපාර්ශවය ධනාත්මකව අදහස් හුවමාරු කරගත් බවයි.",
        "විදුලි ගාස්තු සංශෝධන, සුරාබදු පනත ආදියට අදාළ අමතර තොරතුරු සඳහා IMF ඉල්ලීමක් කර තිබූ අතර ලබන සඳුදා වන විට ඉල්ලා සිටින තොරතුරු ලබා දීමට මෙම රැස්වීමේදී තීරණය විය.",
        "IMF හි මූල්‍ය සහ නීති උපදේශකයින් අද රැස්වීමට එක් වූ අතර තවත් සාකච්ඡා වටයක් ලබන බදාදා (31) පැවැත්වීමට නියමිතය.",
        "ජාත්‍යන්තර මූල්‍ය අරමුදලේ සාකච්ඡා මණ්ඩලයේ ප්‍රධානී පීටර් බෲවර්, නියෝජ්‍ය ප්‍රධානී මසාහිරෝ නොසාකි, ජාත්‍යන්තර මූල්‍ය අරමුදලේ ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ නිත්‍ය නියෝජිත Tubagus Feridhanusetyawan, ජනාධිපති කාර්ය මණ්ඩල ප්‍රධානී සහ ජාතික ආරක්ෂාව පිළිබඳ ජනාධිපති ජ්‍යෙෂ්ඨ උපදේශක සාගල රත්නායක, මෙම අවස්ථාවට ජනාධිපති ලේකම් සමන් ඒකනායක, මහ බැංකු අධිපති ආචාර්ය නන්දලාල් වීරසිංහ යන මහත්වරුන් ඇතුළු මහ බැංකුවේ ජ්‍යෙෂ්ඨ නිලධාරීන් රැසක් එක්ව සිටි බව එහි වැඩිදුරටත් සඳහන්."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ජාත්‍යන්තර මුල්‍ය අරමුදල",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "අද පස්වරුවේ",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "24",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ජනාධිපති මාධ්‍ය අංශය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ලබන සඳුදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "IMF",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ලබන බදාදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "පීටර් බෲවර්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජාත්‍යන්තර මූල්‍ය අරමුදලේ සාකච්ඡා මණ්ඩලය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Head Masahiro Nozaki",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ෆෙරිධනුසෙට්යාවන්",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජාත්‍යන්තර මුල්‍ය අරමුදල",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජාතික ආරක්ෂාව සාගල රත්නායක",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "සමන් ඒකනායක",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "මහ බැංකුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "නන්දලාල් වීරසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "මහ බැංකුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "ஜனாதிபதி, IMF இடையே மற்றொரு சுற்று பேச்சுவார்த்தை",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "இலங்கை எதிர்நோக்கும் நிதி நெருக்கடிக்கு தீர்வு காணும் நோக்கில் சர்வதேச நாணய நிதியத்துடனான மற்றுமொரு சுற்று கலந்துரையாடல் இன்று (24) பிற்பகல் ஜனாதிபதி அலுவலகத்தில் ஜனாதிபதி ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க தலைமையில் இடம்பெற்றது.",
        "ஜூம் தொழில்நுட்பத்தின் ஊடாக ஜனாதிபதி விக்கிரமசிங்க சந்திப்பில் இணைந்ததாகவும், இரு தரப்பினரும் சாதகமான முறையில் கருத்துக்களைப் பரிமாறிக் கொண்டதாகவும் ஜனாதிபதி ஊடகப் பிரிவு தெரிவித்துள்ளது.",
        "மின் கட்டண திருத்தங்கள், கலால் சட்டம் போன்றவை தொடர்பான கூடுதல் தகவல்களுக்கு IMF கோரிக்கை விடுத்துள்ளது, மேலும் கோரப்பட்ட தகவல்களை வரும் திங்கட்கிழமைக்குள் வழங்க இந்த கூட்டத்தில் முடிவு செய்யப்பட்டது.",
        "சர்வதேச நாணய நிதியத்தின் நிதி மற்றும் சட்ட ஆலோசகர்கள் இன்றைய கூட்டத்தில் இணைந்ததுடன், அடுத்த புதன்கிழமை (31) மற்றுமொரு சுற்று கலந்துரையாடலுக்கு திட்டமிடப்பட்டுள்ளது.",
        "சர்வதேச நாணய நிதியத்தின் பேச்சுவார்த்தைக் குழுவின் தலைவர் பீட்டர் ப்ரூயர், பிரதித் தலைவர் மசாஹிரோ நோசாகி, டுபாகஸ் பெரிதானுசெட்யவான், சர்வதேச நாணய நிதியத்தின் இலங்கைக்கான நிரந்தரப் பிரதிநிதி மற்றும் ஜனாதிபதியின் தலைமை அதிகாரியும், தேசிய பாதுகாப்பு தொடர்பான ஜனாதிபதியின் சிரேஷ்ட ஆலோசகருமான சாகல ரத்நாயக்க, ஜனாதிபதியின் செயலாளர் சமன் ஏக்கநாயக்க, மத்திய வங்கியின் ஆளுநர் கலாநிதி நந்தலால் வீரசிங்க மற்றும் மத்திய வங்கியின் சிரேஷ்ட அதிகாரிகள் பலரும் இந்நிகழ்வில் கலந்துகொண்டனர்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "சர்வதேச நாணய நிதியம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று மதியம்",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "24",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஜனாதிபதி ஊடகப் பிரிவு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "அடுத்த திங்கள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "IMF",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "அடுத்த புதன்கிழமை",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பீட்டர் ப்ரூயர்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "சர்வதேச நாணய நிதியத்தின் பேச்சுவார்த்தை குழு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Head Masahiro Nozaki",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "பெரிதானுசேத்யவான்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சர்வதேச நாணய நிதியம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "தேசிய பாதுகாப்பு சாகல ரத்நாயக்க",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "சமன் ஏகநாயக்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "மத்திய வங்கி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "நந்தலால் வீரசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "மத்திய வங்கி",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}