{
  "newspaper_id": "lankadeepa-lk",
  "url": "https://www.lankadeepa.lk/news/එජාප-සංවත්සර-උත්සව-සංවිධානය-රුවන්ගේ-නායකත්වයෙන්/101-618956",
  "time_ut": 1661770243,
  "original_lang": "si",
  "original_title": "එජාප සංවත්සර උත්සව සංවිධානය රුවන්ගේ නායකත්වයෙන්",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "The organization of UNP anniversary celebrations is under the leadership of Ruwan",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "It has been decided to organize the work of the UNP's 76th anniversary celebration by a committee headed by Mr. Ruwan Wijayawardena, UNP Deputy Leader and Presidential Advisor.",
        "The United National Party 76th anniversary is scheduled to be held at the Sugathadasa Stadium in Colombo on September 6 under the theme \"Ekwemu\".",
        "On the occasion of the party's anniversary, all religious ceremonies are also scheduled to be held on September 4 in all the constituencies across the island."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "UNP",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "Ruwan",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "UNP",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "76th",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ruwan Wijayawardena",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "UNP",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Presidential Advisor",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "The United National Party",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "76th",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Sugathadasa Stadium in Colombo",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "September 6",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "September 4",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "එජාප සංවත්සර උත්සව සංවිධානය රුවන්ගේ නායකත්වයෙන්",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "එක්සත් ජාතික පක්ෂයේ 76 වන සංවත්සර උත්සවයේ වැඩ කටයුතු එජාප නියෝජ්‍ය නායක ජනාධිපති උපදේශක රුවන් විජයවර්ධන මහතාගේ  නායකත්වයෙන් යුතු කමිටුවක් මගින් සංවිධානය කිරීමට තීරණය කර තිබෙි.",
        "එක්සත් ජාතික පක්ෂ 76 වන සංවත්සරය  “එක්වෙමු“ යන තේමාව යටතේ ලබන සැප්තැම්බර් 06 ද කොළඹ සුගතදාස ක්‍රිඩාංගනයේදි පැවැත්වීමට නියමිතය.",
        "පක්ෂ සංවත්සරය නිමිත්තෙන් සැප්තැම්බර් 04 දා දිවයින පුරා සෑම මැතිවරණ කොට්ඨාශයකම සර්ව ආගමික වතාවත් පැවැත්වීමට ද නියමිතය."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "එජාප",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "රුවන්",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "එජාප",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "76 වැනි",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "රුවන් විජයවර්ධන",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "එජාප",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජනාධිපති උපදේශක",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "එක්සත් ජාතික පක්ෂයයි",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "76 වැනි",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඒ කොළඹ සුගතදාස ක්‍රීඩාංගණයේදීයි",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "සැප්තැම්බර් 6",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "සැප්තැම්බර් 4",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "ருவான் தலைமையில் ஐக்கிய தேசியக் கட்சியின் வருடாந்த விழா ஏற்பாடுகள் இடம்பெற்றுள்ளன",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "ஐக்கிய தேசியக் கட்சியின் 76ஆவது ஆண்டு நிறைவு விழாவின் பணிகளை ஐக்கிய தேசியக் கட்சியின் பிரதித் தலைவரும் ஜனாதிபதியின் ஆலோசகருமான திரு.ருவான் விஜயவர்தன தலைமையிலான குழுவினால் ஏற்பாடு செய்ய தீர்மானிக்கப்பட்டுள்ளது.",
        "ஐக்கிய தேசியக் கட்சியின் 76ஆவது ஆண்டு நிறைவு விழா எதிர்வரும் செப்டெம்பர் 6ஆம் திகதி கொழும்பு சுகததாச விளையாட்டரங்கில் “எக்வேமு” எனும் தொனிப்பொருளில் நடைபெறவுள்ளது.",
        "கட்சியின் ஆண்டு நிறைவை முன்னிட்டு, நாடு முழுவதும் உள்ள அனைத்து தொகுதிகளிலும் செப்டம்பர் 4 ஆம் தேதி அனைத்து மத வழிபாடுகளும் நடைபெற உள்ளன."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ஐ.தே.க",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "ருவான்",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ஐ.தே.க",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "76வது",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ருவான் விஜயவர்தன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஐ.தே.க",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜனாதிபதி ஆலோசகர்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஐக்கிய தேசியக் கட்சி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "76வது",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "கொழும்பு சுகததாச மைதானம்",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "செப்டம்பர் 6",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "செப்டம்பர் 4",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}