{
  "newspaper_id": "ada-lk",
  "url": "https://www.ada.lk/uncategorized/සජිත්---මෛත්‍රී-තීරණාත්මක-හමුවක/1-395096",
  "time_ut": 1656932515,
  "original_lang": "si",
  "original_title": "සජිත් - මෛත්‍රී තීරණාත්මක හමුවක",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Sajith - Maithri in a crucial meeting",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "A special meeting chaired by former President Maithripala Sirisena and Leader of the Opposition Sajith Premadasa was held today (04th) at the office of the Leader of the Opposition in Colombo.",
        "Arrangements were made for this discussion to be held as a crucial meeting of the 'National Reforms and Progress' program to rebuild the country, which has seriously collapsed.",
        "The discussion was attended by CV Wigneswaran, P. Digambaram, Samagi Jana Balavega General Secretary Ranjith Maddumabandara, Samagi Jana Balavega MP Rajitha Senaratne were present.",
        "In addition, a group of civil activists including Victor Ivan, Janaranjana, Gamini Viangoda were also present."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Sajith - Maithri",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Maithripala Sirisena",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "04th",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the 'National Reforms and Progress'",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "CV Wigneswaran",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "P. Digambaram",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Samagi Jana Balavega",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ranjith Maddumabandara",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Samagi Jana",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Rajitha Senaratne",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Victor Ivan",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Janaranjana",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Gamini Viangoda",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "සජිත් - මෛත්‍රී තීරණාත්මක හමුවක",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "හිටපු ජනාධිපති මෛත්‍රීපාල සිරිසේන සහ විපක්ෂනායක සජිත් ප්‍රේමදාස මහත්වරුන්ගේ ප්‍රධානත්වයෙන් විශේෂ හමුවක් අද (04දා) කොළඹ විපක්ෂනායක කාර්යාලයේදී පැවැත්විණි.",
        "බරපතල ලෙස කඩා වැටී තිබෙන දේශය ගොඩ නැගීම උදෙසා වූ ‘ජාතික ප්‍රතිසංස්කරණ හා ඉදිරි ගමන’ වැඩසටහනේ තීරණාත්මක හමුවක් ලෙස මෙම සාකච්ඡාව පැවැතිවීමට කටයුතු යොදා තිබුණේය.",
        "මෙම සාකච්ඡාවට සී.වී විග්නේෂ්වරන්, පී. දිගම්බරම්, සමගි ජන බලවේගයේ මහලේකම් රංජිත් මද්දුමබණ්ඩාර, සමගි ජන බලවේගයේ පාර්ලිමේන්තු මන්ත්‍රී රාජිත සේනාරත්න යන මහත්වරුන් එක්ව සිටියහ.",
        "මීට අමතරව වික්ටර් අයිවන්, ජනරංජන, ගාමිණි වියන්ගොඩ ඇතුලු සිවිල් ක්‍රියාකාරීන් පිරිසක්ද එක්ව සිටියහ."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "සජිත් - මෛත්‍රී",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "මෛත්‍රීපාල සිරිසේන",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "04 වැනි",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "'ජාතික ප්‍රතිසංස්කරණ සහ ප්‍රගතිය'",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "සී.වී.විග්නේෂ්වරන්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "පී.දිගම්බරම්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "සමගි ජන බලවේගය",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "රංජිත් මද්දුමබණ්ඩාර",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "සමගි ජන",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "රාජිත සේනාරත්න",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "වික්ටර් අයිවන්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජනරංජන",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගාමිණී වියන්ගොඩ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "சஜித் - மைத்திரி முக்கிய சந்திப்பில்",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "முன்னாள் ஜனாதிபதி மைத்திரிபால சிறிசேன மற்றும் எதிர்க்கட்சித் தலைவர் சஜித் பிரேமதாச தலைமையில் விசேட சந்திப்பு ஒன்று இன்று (04) கொழும்பில் உள்ள எதிர்க்கட்சித் தலைவர் அலுவலகத்தில் இடம்பெற்றது.",
        "கடுமையாக வீழ்ச்சியடைந்துள்ள நாட்டை மீளக் கட்டியெழுப்புவதற்கான 'தேசிய சீர்திருத்தங்கள் மற்றும் முன்னேற்றம்' திட்டத்தின் முக்கியமான கூட்டமாக இந்த கலந்துரையாடல் நடைபெறுவதற்கு ஏற்பாடுகள் செய்யப்பட்டிருந்தன.",
        "இந்தக் கலந்துரையாடலில் சி.வி.விக்னேஸ்வரன், பி. திகாம்பரம், சமகி ஜன பலவேக பொதுச் செயலாளர் ரஞ்சித் மத்துமபண்டார, சமகி ஜன பலவேக பாராளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர் ராஜித சேனாரத்ன ஆகியோர் கலந்துகொண்டனர்.",
        "மேலும், விக்டர் ஐவன், ஜனரஞ்சன, காமினி வியாங்கொட உள்ளிட்ட சிவில் செயற்பாட்டாளர்கள் குழுவும் கலந்துகொண்டனர்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "சஜித் - மைத்திரி",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "மைத்திரிபால சிறிசேன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "04வது",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "'தேசிய சீர்திருத்தங்கள் மற்றும் முன்னேற்றம்'",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "சி.வி.விக்னேஸ்வரன்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "பி.திகாம்பரம்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "சமகி ஜன பலவேகா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரஞ்சித் மத்துமபண்டார",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "சமகி ஜன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ராஜித சேனாரத்ன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "விக்டர் இவான்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜனரஞ்சனா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "காமினி வியாங்கொட",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}