{
  "newspaper_id": "ada-lk",
  "url": "https://www.ada.lk/breaking_news/නොමිළේ-දෙන-යුරියා-මෙට්‍රික්-ටොන්-1000ක්-ඉදිරි-දෙසතිය-තුළ-මෙරටට/11-396624",
  "time_ut": 1661497870,
  "original_lang": "si",
  "original_title": "නොමිළේ දෙන යුරියා මෙට්‍රික් ටොන් 1000ක් ඉදිරි දෙසතිය තුළ මෙරටට",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "1000 metric tons of free urea to this country in the next fortnight",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "The World Food and Agriculture Organization has agreed to provide 375,000 50 kg bags of urea fertilizer to low-income farming families in Sri Lanka for rice cultivation.",
        "This stock of urea fertilizer is to be given free of charge to 375,000 farmers who have less than an acre of paddy at the rate of 50 kg per farmer.",
        "Agriculture Minister Mahinda Amaraweera agreed to provide urea fertilizer for the high season as per a discussion held with officials of the World Food and Agriculture Organization.",
        "The Minister of Agriculture said that our country will receive 1000 metric tons as its first stock in the next two weeks.",
        "Yesterday (25) the Minister held a discussion with small, medium and large scale mill owners regarding the purchase of paddy in the spring season and cultivation activities in the high season. He also discussed about providing urea fertilizer for the high season.",
        "Rice mill owners said that the farmers say that the urea fertilizer provided by the government in the yala season is 100 percent of high quality. Therefore, they said, the paddy yield in the yala season will exceed the expected level. It was planned to cultivate about 275,000 hectares of paddy this year, but with the government's decision to provide urea fertilizer, the amount of paddy cultivated has now increased to 512,000 hectares.",
        "Meanwhile, the World Food and Agriculture Organization has also decided to provide a subsidy of 18,000 rupees per family to 14 lakh families to grow mung beans with the aim of increasing the nutrition of women-led low-income families.",
        "Thus, in order to popularize mung bean cultivation in Anuradhapura, Polonnaruwa, Monaragala, Ampara and Hambantota districts, the women of those districts have decided to give the money subsidy to the basic farming families.",
        "The Secretary of the Ministry Mr. Rohana Pushpakumara and many small, medium and large scale paddy mill owners participated in this discussion."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "The World Food and Agriculture Organization",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "375,000 50 kg",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "375,000",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "50 kg",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Mahinda Amaraweera",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the high season",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the World Food and Agriculture Organization",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "1000 metric tons",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "first",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "the next two weeks",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Yesterday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "25",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "the spring season",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the high season",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the high season",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Rice",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the yala season",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "100 percent",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "the yala season",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "this year",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "512,000",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the World Food and Agriculture Organization",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "18,000",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "14",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Anuradhapura",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Polonnaruwa",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Monaragala",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ampara",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Hambantota",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Rohana Pushpakumara",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "නොමිළේ දෙන යුරියා මෙට්‍රික් ටොන් 1000ක් ඉදිරි දෙසතිය තුළ මෙරටට",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ අඩු ආදායම්ලාභී ගොවි පවුල්වලට වී වගාව සඳහා කිලෝග්‍රෑම් 50ක බරින් යුත් යුරියා පොහොර මලු 375,000ක් ලබා දීමට ලෝක ආහාර හා කෘෂිකර්ම සංවිධානය විසින් එකඟතාවය පළ කර තිබේ.",
        "මෙම යුරියා පොහොර තොගය අක්කරයකට වඩා අඩු කුඹුරු ප්‍රමාණයක් තිබෙන ගොවීන් 375,000කට එක් ගොවියෙකුට කිලෝග්‍රෑම් 50ක් බැගින්  නොමිලයේ ලබා දීමට නියමිතය.",
        "කෘෂිකර්ම අමාත්‍ය මහින්ද අමරවීර මහතා ලෝක ආහාර හා කෘෂිකර්ම සංවිධානයේ නිලධාරින් සමග සිදු කරන ලද සාකච්ඡාවක් පරිදි මහ කන්නය සඳහා යුරියා පොහොර ලබා දීමට එකඟතාවය පළ කරනු ලැබීය.",
        "එහි පළමු තොගය වශයෙන් මෙට්‍රික් 1000ක් ඉදිරි සති දෙක තුළ අප රටට ලැබීමට නියමිත බව කෘෂිකර්ම අමාත්‍යවරයා පැවසීය.",
        "ඊයේ (25) කුඩා , මධ්‍යම හා මහා මහා පරිමාණ මෝල් හිමිකරුවන් සමග ඇමැතිවරයා යල කන්නයේ වී මිල දී ගැනීම හා මහ කන්නයේ වගා කටයුතු  සම්බන්ධව සාකච්ඡාවක් පවත්වනු ලැබීය.එහි දී මහ කන්නය සඳහා යුරියා පොහොර ලබා දීම සම්බන්ධව ද  සාකච්ඡා කළේය.",
        "රජය විසින් යල කන්නයේ ලබා දෙන ලද යුරියා පොහොර සියයට සියයක්ම ගුණාත්මකභාවයෙන් ඉහළ මට්ටමක පවතින ගොවි ජනතාව පවසන බව සහල් මෝල් හිමියෝ  පැවසූහ. මේනිසා යල කන්නයේ වී අස්වැන්න අපේක්ෂිත මට්ටම ඉක්මවා යනු ඇතැයි ඔවුහු සඳහන් කළහ. මෙවර යල කන්නයේ හෙක්ටෙයාර් 275,000ක් පමණ වී වගා කිරීමට සැළසුම් කර තිබුනත් රජය විසින්  යුරියා පොහොර ලබා දීමට ගත් තීරණයත් සමග වී වගා කළ කුඹුරු ප්‍රමාණය මේ වනවිට හෙක්ටෙයාර් 512,000 දක්වා ඉහළ ගොස් තිබේ.",
        "මේ අතර ලෝක ආහාර හා කෘෂිකර්ම  සංවිධානය විසින් කාන්තාවන් මූලික  අඩු ආදායම්ලාභී පවුල්වල පෝෂණය ඉහළ නැංවීමේ අරමුණින්  මුං ඇට වගා කිරීමට එක් පවුලකට රුපියල් 18,000ක් බැගින්  පවුල් ලක්ෂ 14කට සහනාධාර මුදලක් ලබා දීමට ද තීරණය කර ඇති බව ද  පැවසීය.",
        "මේ අනුව අනුරාධපුර, පොලොන්නරුව, , මොනරාගල , අම්පාර හා හම්බන්තොට දිස්ත්‍රික්කවල මුං ඇට වගාව ප්‍රචලිත කිරීම සඳහා එම දිස්ත්‍රික්කවල කාන්තාවන් මූළික ගොවිපවුල්වලට එම මුදල් සහනාධාරය ලබා දීමට තීරණය කර තිබේ.",
        "මෙම සාකච්ඡාවට අමාත්‍යාංශයේ ලේකම් රෝහණ පුෂ්පකුමාර මහතා සහ කුඩා, මධ්‍යම හා මහා පරිමාණ වී මෝල් අයිතිකරුවන් රැසක් සහභාගි වූහ."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ලෝක ආහාර හා කෘෂිකර්ම සංවිධානය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "375,000 කි 50 කි",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "375,000 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "කිලෝ ග්රෑම් 50 කි",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "මහින්ද අමරවීර",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉහළ සමය",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ලෝක ආහාර හා කෘෂිකර්ම සංවිධානය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "මෙට්‍රික් ටොන් 1000 කි",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "පළමුවන",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉදිරි සති දෙක",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ඊයේ",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "25",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "වසන්ත සමය",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉහළ සමය",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉහළ සමය",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "සහල්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "යල කන්නය",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "සියයට සියයක්",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "යල කන්නය",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මේ වසරේ",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "512,000 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ලෝක ආහාර හා කෘෂිකර්ම සංවිධානය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "18,000 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "14",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "අනුරාධපුර",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "පොළොන්නරුව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මොනරාගල",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "අම්පාර",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "හම්බන්තොට",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "රෝහණ පුෂ්පකුමාර",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "அடுத்த பதினைந்து நாட்களில் இந்த நாட்டுக்கு 1000 மெட்ரிக் டன் யூரியா இலவசம்",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "இலங்கையில் உள்ள குறைந்த வருமானம் பெறும் விவசாயக் குடும்பங்களுக்கு நெற்செய்கைக்காக 375,000 50 கிலோ யூரியா உர மூட்டைகளை வழங்க உலக உணவு மற்றும் விவசாய அமைப்பு இணங்கியுள்ளது.",
        "ஒரு ஏக்கருக்கும் குறைவான நெல் பயிரிட்டுள்ள 375,000 விவசாயிகளுக்கு ஒரு விவசாயிக்கு 50 கிலோ வீதம் இந்த யூரியா உரம் இலவசமாக வழங்கப்பட உள்ளது.",
        "உலக உணவு மற்றும் விவசாய அமைப்பின் அதிகாரிகளுடன் இடம்பெற்ற கலந்துரையாடலின் பிரகாரம் விவசாய அமைச்சர் மஹிந்த அமரவீர உயர் பருவத்திற்கான யூரியா உரத்தை வழங்குவதற்கு இணக்கம் தெரிவித்துள்ளார்.",
        "அடுத்த இரண்டு வாரங்களில் 1000 மெட்ரிக் தொன்களை முதல் கையிருப்பாக நமது நாடு பெற்றுக்கொள்ளும் என விவசாய அமைச்சர் தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "நேற்றைய தினம் (25) சிறு, குறு, நடுத்தர மற்றும் பாரிய ஆலை உரிமையாளர்களுடன் இளவேனிற் பருவ நெல் கொள்வனவு மற்றும் அதிக பருவத்தில் பயிர்ச் செய்கை நடவடிக்கைகள் தொடர்பில் கலந்துரையாடிய அமைச்சர், உயர் பருவத்திற்கான யூரியா உரம் வழங்குவது தொடர்பிலும் கலந்துரையாடினார்.",
        "அரிசி ஆலை உரிமையாளர்கள் கூறுகையில், 'யாழ் பருவத்தில் அரசு வழங்கும் யூரியா உரம் 100 சதவீதம் உயர் தரம் வாய்ந்தது என விவசாயிகள் கூறுகின்றனர். எனவே, ஏல பருவத்தில் நெல் விளைச்சல் எதிர்பார்த்த அளவை விட அதிகமாக இருக்கும் என்றனர். இவ்வருடம் சுமார் 275,000 ஹெக்டேர் நெல் பயிரிட திட்டமிடப்பட்டிருந்தது, ஆனால் அரசாங்கம் யூரியா உரம் வழங்க தீர்மானித்ததன் மூலம் தற்போது 512,000 ஹெக்டேர்களாக பயிரிடப்பட்ட நெற்பயிர்களின் அளவு அதிகரித்துள்ளது.",
        "இதற்கிடையில், பெண்கள் தலைமையிலான குறைந்த வருமானம் பெறும் குடும்பங்களின் ஊட்டச்சத்தை அதிகரிக்கும் நோக்கில், வெண்டைக்காய் பயிரிட, 14 லட்சம் குடும்பங்களுக்கு, ஒரு குடும்பத்துக்கு, 18,000 ரூபாய் மானியம் வழங்க, உலக உணவு மற்றும் வேளாண்மை அமைப்பும் முடிவு செய்துள்ளது.",
        "இதனால் அநுராதபுரம், பொலன்னறுவை, மொனராகலை, அம்பாறை மற்றும் ஹம்பாந்தோட்டை மாவட்டங்களில் வெண்டைக்காய் செய்கையை பிரபலப்படுத்தும் நோக்கில், அந்த மாவட்டங்களை சேர்ந்த பெண்கள் அடிப்படை விவசாய குடும்பங்களுக்கு பண மானியத்தை வழங்க தீர்மானித்துள்ளனர்.",
        "இக்கலந்துரையாடலில் அமைச்சின் செயலாளர் திரு.ரோஹன புஷ்பகுமார மற்றும் சிறு, நடுத்தர மற்றும் பாரிய நெல் ஆலை உரிமையாளர்கள் பலரும் கலந்துகொண்டனர்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "உலக உணவு மற்றும் வேளாண்மை அமைப்பு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "375,000 50 கிலோ",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "375,000",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "50 கிலோ",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "மஹிந்த அமரவீர",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "உயர் பருவம்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "உலக உணவு மற்றும் விவசாய அமைப்பு",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "1000 மெட்ரிக் டன்",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "முதலில்",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "அடுத்த இரண்டு வாரங்கள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "நேற்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "25",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "வசந்த காலம்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "உயர் பருவம்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "உயர் பருவம்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "அரிசி",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "யலா பருவம்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "100 சதவீதம்",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "யலா பருவம்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்த வருடம்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "512,000",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "உலக உணவு மற்றும் விவசாய அமைப்பு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "18,000",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "14",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "அனுராதபுரம்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "பொலன்னறுவை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "மொனராகலை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "அம்பாறை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஹம்பாந்தோட்டை",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ரோஹன புஷ்பகுமார",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}