{
  "newspaper_id": "tamil-mirror-lk",
  "url": "https://www.tamilmirror.lk/செய்திகள்/ஓமான்-தூதுவருடன்-ஜனாதிபதி-சந்திப்பு/175-299577",
  "time_ut": 1656705291,
  "original_lang": "ta",
  "original_title": "ஓமான் தூதுவருடன் ஜனாதிபதி சந்திப்பு",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "President meeting with Ambassador of Oman",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "Ambassador of Oman to Sri Lanka Ahmed Ali Saeed Al Rasheed has assured President Gotabaya Rajapaksa of support to strengthen bilateral relations between Sri Lanka and Oman in the areas of fuel, gas, energy, employment and investment promotion.",
        "He said this yesterday (01) when he met the President at the Presidential Palace in Fort Colombo before leaving the country after finishing his service as Ambassador to Sri Lanka.",
        "Meanwhile, President Gotabaya Rajapaksa requested the Omani Ambassador to cooperate in increasing job opportunities for Sri Lankan students in Oman.",
        "The President's Media Unit has mentioned that the focus has also been on expanding trade and investment opportunities in the country. (a)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Oman",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Oman",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ahmed Ali Saeed Al Rasheed",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Gotabaya Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Oman",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "this yesterday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "01",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Presidential Palace",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Gotabaya Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Omani",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lankan",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Oman",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Media Unit",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "ජනපති ඕමාන් තානාපති හමුවෙයි",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "ඉන්ධන, ගෑස්, බලශක්තිය, රැකියා සහ ආයෝජන ප්‍රවර්ධනය යන ක්ෂේත්‍රවල ශ්‍රී ලංකාව සහ ඕමානය අතර ද්විපාර්ශ්වික සබඳතා ශක්තිමත් කිරීමට සහාය දෙන බව ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ ඕමාන් තානාපති අහමඩ් අලි සයීඩ් අල් රෂීඩ් මහතා ජනාධිපති ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ මහතාට සහතික විය.",
        "ඔහු මේ බව පැවසුවේ ඊයේ (01) ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ තානාපතිවරයා ලෙස සිය සේවය නිමවා දිවයිනෙන් පිටත්ව යාමට පෙර කොළඹ කොටුව ජනාධිපති මන්දිරයේදී ජනාධිපතිවරයා හමුවූ අවස්ථාවේදීය.",
        "මේ අතර, ශ්‍රී ලාංකික සිසුන්ට ඕමානයේ රැකියා අවස්ථා ඉහළ නැංවීමට සහයෝගය ලබා දෙන ලෙස ජනාධිපති ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ මහතා ඕමාන තානාපතිවරයාගෙන් ඉල්ලීමක් කළේය.",
        "රට තුළ වෙළෙඳ සහ ආයෝජන අවස්ථා පුළුල් කිරීම කෙරෙහි ද අවධානය යොමු වී ඇති බව ජනාධිපති මාධ්‍ය අංශය සඳහන් කර ඇත. (ඒ)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ඕමානය",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ඕමානය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "අහමඩ් අලි සයීඩ් අල් රෂීඩ්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඕමානය",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "මේ ඊයේ",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "01",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජනාධිපති මන්දිරය",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඕමාන්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලාංකික",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඕමානය",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "මාධ්‍ය ඒකකය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "ஓமான் தூதுவருடன் ஜனாதிபதி சந்திப்பு",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "எரிபொருள், எரிவாயு, எரிசக்தி, வேலைவாய்ப்பு மற்றும் முதலீட்டு ஊக்குவிப்பு போன்றவற்றில் இலங்கைக்கும் ஓமானுக்கும் இடையிலான இருதரப்பு உறவுகளை வலுப்படுத்துவதற்கு ஆதரவளிப்பதாக இலங்கைக்கான ஓமான் தூதுவர் அஹமட் அலி சயீட் அல் ரஷீட் ஜனாதிபதி கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ஷவிடம் உறுதியளித்துள்ளார்.",
        "இலங்கைக்கான தூதுவராக தனது சேவைக்காலத்தை முடித்துக் கொண்டு நாட்டை விட்டு வெளியேறுவதற்கு முன்னர் நேற்று  (01) கொழும்பு - கோட்டையில் உள்ள ஜனாதிபதி மாளிகையில் ஜனாதிபதியை சந்தித்த போதே அவர் இதனைத் தெரிவித்துள்ளார்.",
        "இதன்போது, ஓமானில் இலங்கையிலுள்ள பயிலுநர்களுக்கான வேலை வாய்ப்புக்களை அதிகரிப்பதற்கு ஒத்துழைக்குமாறு ஜனாதிபதி கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ஷ ஓமானிய தூதுவரிடம் கோரிக்கை விடுத்தார்.",
        "இக்கலந்துரையாடலில் நாட்டில் வர்த்தக மற்றும் முதலீட்டு வாய்ப்புக்களை விரிவுபடுத்துவது குறித்தும் கவனம் செலுத்தப்பட்டுள்ளதாக ஜனாதிபதி ஊடக பிரிவு குறிப்பிட்டுள்ளது. (a)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ஓமன்",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ஓமன்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "அகமது அலி சயீத் அல் ரஷீத்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஓமன்",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இது நேற்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "01",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜனாதிபதி மாளிகை",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஓமானி",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஓமன்",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஊடகப் பிரிவு",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}