{
  "newspaper_id": "news-first-lk",
  "url": "https://www.newsfirst.lk/2022/08/16/gotabaya-entitled-to-public-funds-bandula/",
  "time_ut": 1660632060,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Gotabaya entitled to Public Funds – Bandula",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Gotabaya entitled to Public Funds – Bandula",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); Cabinet Spokesperson Minister Bandula Gunawardena told reporters on Tuesday (16) that Former President Gotabaya Rajapaksa is entitled to use public funds.",
        "At the weekly Cabinet Media Briefing, journalists questioned who is funding the Former President's overseas travel.",
        "Cabinet Spokesperson Minister Bandula Gunawardena said that any Former President and sitting President are entitled to perks and privileges as per the Presidential Elections Act of Sri Lanka.",
        "The former Sri Lankan president Gotabaya Rajapaksa, who fled overseas to escape protests against his government, arrived in Thailand last week on a flight from Singapore, where he had been staying since mid-July."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Gotabaya",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "News 1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Bandula Gunawardena",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Tuesday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "16",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Gotabaya Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "weekly",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Cabinet Media Briefing",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Bandula Gunawardena",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Presidential Elections Act of Sri Lanka",
            "label": "LAW"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lankan",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Gotabaya Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Thailand",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "last week",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Singapore",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "mid-July",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "ගෝඨාභයට මහජන මුදල් හිමියි - බන්දුල",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); හිටපු ජනාධිපති ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ මහතාට මහජන මුදල් පරිහරණය කිරීමට අයිතියක් ඇති බව කැබිනට් ප්‍රකාශක අමාත්‍ය බන්දුල ගුණවර්ධන අඟහරුවාදා (16) මාධ්‍යවේදීන් හමුවේ ප්‍රකාශ කළේය.",
        "සතිපතා පැවැත්වෙන කැබිනට් මාධ්‍ය හමුවේදී මාධ්‍යවේදීන් ප්‍රශ්න කළේ හිටපු ජනාධිපතිවරයාගේ විදෙස් ගමන් සඳහා මුදල් සපයන්නේ කවුරුන්ද යන්නයි.",
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ ජනාධිපතිවරණ පනතට අනුව ඕනෑම හිටපු ජනාධිපතිවරයෙකුට සහ බලයේ සිටින ජනාධිපතිවරයෙකුට වරප්‍රසාද සහ වරප්‍රසාද හිමිවන බව කැබිනට් ප්‍රකාශක අමාත්‍ය බන්දුල ගුණවර්ධන මහතා පැවසීය.",
        "තම රජයට එරෙහි විරෝධතාවලින් බේරීම සඳහා විදේශගත වූ ශ්‍රී ලංකා හිටපු ජනාධිපති ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ පසුගිය සතියේ තායිලන්තයට පැමිණියේ සිංගප්පූරුවේ සිට ගුවන් යානයකින් වන අතර එහිදී ඔහු ජූලි මැද සිට නැවතී සිටියේය."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ගෝඨාභය",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "News 1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "බන්දුල ගුණවර්ධන",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "අඟහරුවාදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "16",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "සතිපතා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "කැබිනට් මාධ්‍ය සාකච්ඡාව",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "බන්දුල ගුණවර්ධන",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ ජනාධිපති මැතිවරණ පනත",
            "label": "LAW"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලාංකික",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "තායිලන්තය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගිය සතිය",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "සිංගප්පූරුව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජූලි මැද",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "கோட்டாபயவுக்கு பொது நிதிகள் – பந்துல",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); முன்னாள் ஜனாதிபதி கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ஷ பொது நிதியைப் பயன்படுத்துவதற்கு உரிமையுள்ளவர் என அமைச்சரவைப் பேச்சாளர் அமைச்சர் பந்துல குணவர்தன செவ்வாய்க்கிழமை (16) செய்தியாளர்களிடம் தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "வாராந்த அமைச்சரவை ஊடகவியலாளர் சந்திப்பில், முன்னாள் ஜனாதிபதியின் வெளிநாட்டுப் பயணங்களுக்கு நிதியளிப்பது யார் என ஊடகவியலாளர்கள் கேள்வி எழுப்பினர்.",
        "இலங்கையின் ஜனாதிபதி தேர்தல் சட்டத்தின் பிரகாரம் சலுகைகள் மற்றும் சலுகைகளுக்கு முன்னாள் ஜனாதிபதி மற்றும் பதவியில் இருக்கும் எந்தவொரு ஜனாதிபதிக்கும் உரிமை உண்டு என அமைச்சரவைப் பேச்சாளர் அமைச்சர் பந்துல குணவர்தன தெரிவித்துள்ளார்.",
        "தனது அரசாங்கத்திற்கு எதிரான போராட்டங்களில் இருந்து தப்பிக்க வெளிநாடுகளுக்கு தப்பிச் சென்ற இலங்கையின் முன்னாள் ஜனாதிபதி கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ச, ஜூலை நடுப்பகுதியில் இருந்து தங்கியிருந்த சிங்கப்பூரில் இருந்து விமானம் மூலம் கடந்த வாரம் தாய்லாந்து வந்தடைந்தார்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "கோட்டாபய",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "News 1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "பந்துல குணவர்தன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "செவ்வாய்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "16",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "வாரந்தோறும்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "அமைச்சரவை ஊடகவியலாளர் சந்திப்பு",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பந்துல குணவர்தன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை ஜனாதிபதி தேர்தல் சட்டம்",
            "label": "LAW"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "தாய்லாந்து",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "கடந்த வாரம்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சிங்கப்பூர்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜூலை நடுப்பகுதி",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}