{
  "newspaper_id": "daily-ft-lk",
  "url": "https://www.ft.lk/news/Tamils-will-only-invest-in-SL-if-Govt-provides-political-solution-Mavai/56-738818",
  "time_ut": 1660779334,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Tamils will only invest in SL if Govt. provides political solution: Mavai",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Tamils will only invest in SL if Govt. provides political solution: Mavai",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "Asks Govt. to give political solution to gain confidence of diaspora",
        "Illankai Tamil Arasu Kachchi (ITAK) Leader Mavai Senathirajah said Tamils will only invest in Sri Lanka with",
        "confidence if the Government of President Ranil Wickremesinghe is able to provide an acceptable political solution to the ethic problem relating to the country’s Tamil people.",
        "Commenting on the Government’s decision to delist six organisations and 361 persons of concern from its terror list, Senathirajah said while it is commendable that the ban has been lifted, it can be assured it has done so in a bid to attract investments and financial assistance to the now ailing country.",
        "It can be assumed that the Government removed the ban on diaspora organisations with a view to getting investments and financial assistance to Sri Lanka. “The Government should also provide a proper response to the major issues of the country such as the ethnic problem and the political solution for the Tamil people. Only then will the Government get the help it expects from the diaspora Tamils,” he said.",
        "Meanwhile, Tamil National People’s Front General Secretary Selvarajah Kajendren has urged the Tamil diaspora to refrain from contributing to Sri Lankan financially until a solution is provided to Tamil through a federal system of Government. Kajendren said the Government is now attempting to attract those of the diaspora because it is facing a severe financial crisis.",
        "“Ranil Wickremesinghe’s Government’s aim is to recover from the economic crisis and avoid the international pressures at the upcoming UNHRC sessions,” he said. He requested members of the Tamil diaspora abroad to not fall trap to the Sri Lankan Government."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "Illankai Tamil Arasu Kachchi",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "six",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "361",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Senathirajah",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Tamil",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Tamil National People’s Front",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Selvarajah Kajendren",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Tamil",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lankan",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "Tamil",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kajendren",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickremesinghe’s",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Tamil",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Sri Lankan Government",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "දෙමළ ජනතාව ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ ආයෝජනය කරන්නේ රජයක් නම් පමණයි. දේශපාලන විසඳුමක් සපයයි: මාවෙයි",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "රජයෙන් අසයි. ඩයස්පෝරාවේ විශ්වාසය දිනාගන්න දේශපාලන විසඳුමක් දෙන්න කියලා",
        "ඉලංකෙයි තමිල් අරසු කච්චි (ITAK) නායක මාවෙයි සේනාධිරාජා පැවසුවේ දෙමළ ජනතාව ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ ආයෝජනය කරන්නේ පමණක් බවයි.",
        "රටේ දෙමළ ජනතාවට අදාළ ආචාර ධර්ම ගැටලුවට පිළිගත හැකි දේශපාලන විසඳුමක් ලබාදීමට ජනාධිපති රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතාගේ රජයට හැකි නම් විශ්වාසය.",
        "සංවිධානය හයක් සහ අදාළ පුද්ගලයන් 361ක් තම ත්‍රස්ත ලැයිස්තුවෙන් ඉවත් කිරීමට රජය ගත් තීරණය පිළිබඳව අදහස් දක්වමින් සේනාධිරාජා කියා සිටියේ තහනම ඉවත් කිරීම ප්‍රශංසනීය වන අතර, ආයෝජන සහ මූල්‍ය ආධාර ආකර්ෂණය කර ගැනීමේ උත්සාහයක් ලෙස එය සිදු කර ඇති බවට සහතික විය හැකි බවයි. දැන් රෝගී රට.",
        "රජය ඩයස්පෝරා සංවිධාන තහනම ඉවත් කළේ ශ්‍රී ලංකාවට ආයෝජන සහ මූල්‍ය ආධාර ලබා ගැනීමේ අරමුණින් යැයි උපකල්පනය කළ හැකිය. “ජනවාර්ගික ගැටලුව, දෙමළ ජනතාවට දේශපාලන විසඳුම වැනි රටේ ප්‍රධාන ප්‍රශ්නවලටත් රජය නිසි ප්‍රතිචාරයක් ලබාදිය යුතුයි. ඩයස්පෝරා දෙමළ ජනතාවගෙන් රජය බලාපොරොත්තු වන සහය ලැබෙන්නේ එවිටයි,” ඔහු පැවසීය.",
        "මේ අතර දෙමළ ජාතික ජනතා පෙරමුණේ ප්‍රධාන ලේකම් සෙල්වරාජා කජේන්ද්‍රන් දෙමළ ඩයස්පෝරාවෙන් ඉල්ලා සිටින්නේ ෆෙඩරල් ආණ්ඩු ක්‍රමයක් හරහා දෙමළ භාෂාවට විසඳුමක් ලබා දෙන තුරු ශ්‍රී ලංකාවට මුල්‍ය දායකත්වය ලබා දීමෙන් වළකින ලෙසයි. රජය දැඩි මූල්‍ය අර්බුදයකට මුහුණ දී සිටින බැවින් ඩයස්පෝරාවේ අය ආකර්ෂණය කර ගැනීමට රජය දැන් උත්සාහ කරමින් සිටින බව කජේන්ද්‍රන් පැවසීය.",
        "“රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතාගේ රජයේ අරමුණ ආර්ථික අර්බුදයෙන් ගොඩ ඒම සහ එළැඹෙන එක්සත් ජාතීන්ගේ මානව හිමිකම් කවුන්සිල සැසිවාරයේදී ජාත්‍යන්තර බලපෑම් වළක්වා ගැනීමයි,” ඔහු පැවසීය. ශ්‍රී ලංකා රජයට හසු නොවන ලෙස විදේශගත දෙමළ ඩයස්පෝරාවේ සාමාජිකයන්ගෙන් ඔහු ඉල්ලා සිටියේය."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "ඉලංකෙයි තමිල් අරසු කච්චි",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "හය",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "361",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "සේනාධිරාජා",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "දෙමළ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "දෙමළ ජාතික ජනතා පෙරමුණ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "සෙල්වරාජා කජේන්ද්‍රන්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "දෙමළ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලාංකික",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "දෙමළ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "කජේන්ද්‍රන්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහගේ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "දෙමළ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකා රජය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "அரசால் மட்டுமே தமிழர்கள் இலங்கையில் முதலீடு செய்வார்கள். அரசியல் தீர்வை வழங்குகிறது: மாவை",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "அரசிடம் கேட்கிறது. புலம்பெயர் மக்களின் நம்பிக்கையைப் பெறுவதற்கு அரசியல் தீர்வை வழங்க வேண்டும்",
        "இலங்கையில் மட்டுமே தமிழர்கள் முதலீடு செய்வார்கள் என இலங்கைத் தமிழ் அரசுக் கட்சித் தலைவர் மாவை சேனாதிராஜா தெரிவித்துள்ளார்.",
        "நாட்டின் தமிழ் மக்கள் தொடர்பான நெறிமுறைப் பிரச்சினைக்கு ஏற்றுக்கொள்ளக்கூடிய அரசியல் தீர்வை ஜனாதிபதி ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்கவின் அரசாங்கத்தால் வழங்க முடிந்தால் நம்பிக்கை.",
        "ஆறு அமைப்புக்கள் மற்றும் கவலைக்குரிய 361 நபர்களை பயங்கரவாதப் பட்டியலில் இருந்து நீக்குவதற்கான அரசாங்கத்தின் முடிவு குறித்து கருத்துத் தெரிவித்த சேனாதிராஜா, தடை நீக்கப்பட்டிருப்பது பாராட்டத்தக்கது என்றாலும், முதலீடுகளையும் நிதியுதவிகளையும் ஈர்க்கும் முயற்சியில் அவ்வாறு செய்திருப்பதை உறுதிப்படுத்த முடியும். இப்போது நோய்வாய்ப்பட்ட நாடு.",
        "புலம்பெயர் அமைப்புக்கள் மீதான தடையை அரசாங்கம் நீக்கியது இலங்கைக்கு முதலீடுகள் மற்றும் நிதி உதவிகளை பெறும் நோக்கிலேயே என்று கருதலாம். இனப்பிரச்சினை, தமிழ் மக்களுக்கான அரசியல் தீர்வு போன்ற நாட்டின் பிரதான பிரச்சினைகளுக்கும் அரசாங்கம் உரிய பதிலை வழங்க வேண்டும். அப்போதுதான் புலம்பெயர் தமிழர்களிடம் அரசாங்கம் எதிர்பார்க்கும் உதவிகள் கிடைக்கும்” என்றார்.",
        "இதேவேளை, தமிழ் தேசிய மக்கள் முன்னணியின் பொதுச் செயலாளர் செல்வராஜா கஜேந்திரன், சமஷ்டி ஆட்சி முறை மூலம் தமிழுக்கு தீர்வு கிடைக்கும் வரை இலங்கைக்கு நிதி உதவி செய்வதைத் தவிர்க்குமாறு புலம்பெயர் தமிழர்களை வலியுறுத்தியுள்ளார். அரசாங்கம் கடுமையான நிதி நெருக்கடியை எதிர்கொள்வதால், புலம்பெயர்ந்த மக்களைக் கவரும் முயற்சியில் தற்போது ஈடுபட்டுள்ளதாக கஜேந்திரன் தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "“பொருளாதார நெருக்கடியில் இருந்து மீண்டு வரவிருக்கும் UNHRC அமர்வுகளில் சர்வதேச அழுத்தங்களைத் தவிர்ப்பதே ரணில் விக்ரமசிங்கவின் அரசாங்கத்தின் நோக்கமாகும்,” என்று அவர் கூறினார். இலங்கை அரசாங்கத்தின் வலையில் சிக்க வேண்டாம் என வெளிநாடுகளில் வாழும் தமிழ் புலம்பெயர் தமிழர்களை அவர் கேட்டுக்கொண்டுள்ளார்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை தமிழ் அரசு கச்சி",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஆறு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "361",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "சேனாதிராஜா",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "தமிழ்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "தமிழ் தேசிய மக்கள் முன்னணி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "செல்வராஜா கஜேந்திரன்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "தமிழ்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "தமிழ்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "கஜேந்திரன்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்கவின்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "தமிழ்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை அரசு",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}