{
  "newspaper_id": "ada-lk",
  "url": "https://www.ada.lk/breaking_news/ජනපති-ජයග්‍රහණය-හැටන්--එ-ජා-ප-පාක්ෂිකයන්-සමරති/11-395594",
  "time_ut": 1658312698,
  "original_lang": "si",
  "original_title": "ජනපති ජයග්‍රහණය හැටන්  එ.ජා.ප පාක්ෂිකයන් සමරති",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "UNP party members celebrate the President's victory",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "As the 8th Executive President of the Democratic People's Government of Sri Lanka, Mr. Ranil Wickramasinghe was elected today (20th) in the secret ballot held in the Parliament, a group of United National Party members in Hatton town expressed their happiness by lighting firecrackers.",
        "Our camera captured how the United National Party members gathered near the clock tower in the center of Hatton and expressed their happiness by lighting firecrackers.",
        "The United National Party members who spoke to the media said that the current President Ranil Wickramasinghe is the only leader who can rebuild the motherland that has fallen economically.",
        "The United National Party said that all the MPs representing the Parliament should support the current President Ranil Wickramasinghe to abandon political opinions and rebuild the country economically."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "UNP",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "8th",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Democratic People's Government of Sri Lanka",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickramasinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "20th",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "United National Party",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Hatton",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the United National Party",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Hatton",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "The United National Party",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickramasinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "The United National Party",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickramasinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "ජනපති ජයග්‍රහණය හැටන්  එ.ජා.ප පාක්ෂිකයන් සමරති",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "ශ්‍රි ලංකා ප්‍රජාතන්ත්‍රවාදි ජන රජයේ 8 වන විධායක ජනාධිපතිවරයා වශයෙන් රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතා අද  (20දා)  පාර්ලිමේන්තුවේ පැවති රහස් ජන්දයෙන් තේරි පත්විමේ නිසා  හැටන් නගරයේ එක්සත් ජාතික පාක්ෂිකයන් පිරිසක් රතිඤ්ඤා දල්වමින් සතුට  පල කලහ.",
        "හැටන් නගර මධ්‍යයේ ඔරලෝසු කණුව අසලට එක් වු එක්සත් ජාතික පාක්ෂිකයන් රතිඤ්ඤා දල්වමින් සිය සතුට පල කල අයුරු අප කැමරාවේ සටහන් විය.",
        "මෙහිදි මාධ්‍යට අදහස් දැක් වු එක්සත් ජාතික පාක්ෂිකයන් කියා සිටියේ ආර්ථික වශයෙන් වැටි ඇති මව්බිම යලි ගොඩ ගැනිමට හැකි එකම නායකයා වත්මන් ජනාධිපති රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතා බවයි.",
        "දේශපාලන මතයන් අතහැර මෙරට ආර්ථික වශයෙන් ගොඩගැනිමට වත්මන් ජනාධිපති රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතාට පාර්ලිමේන්තුව නියෝජනය කරන සියළුම මන්ත්‍රිවරන් සහයෝගය ලබාදිය යුතු බවයි එක්සත් ජාතික පාක්ෂිකයන් කියා සිටියේ."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "එජාප",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "8 වැනි",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකා ප්‍රජාතන්ත්‍රවාදී ජනතා රජය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "20 වැනි",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "එක්සත් ජාතික පක්ෂය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "හැටන්",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "එක්සත් ජාතික පක්ෂය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "හැටන්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "එක්සත් ජාතික පක්ෂයයි",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "එක්සත් ජාතික පක්ෂයයි",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "ஜனாதிபதியின் வெற்றியை ஐக்கிய தேசியக் கட்சி உறுப்பினர்கள் கொண்டாடுகின்றனர்",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "இலங்கை ஜனநாயக மக்கள் அரசாங்கத்தின் 8ஆவது நிறைவேற்றுத் தலைவராக திரு.ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க இன்று (20) பாராளுமன்றத்தில் நடைபெற்ற இரகசிய வாக்கெடுப்பில் தெரிவு செய்யப்பட்டதையடுத்து, ஹட்டன் நகரில் ஐக்கிய தேசியக் கட்சி உறுப்பினர்கள் பட்டாசு கொளுத்தி மகிழ்ச்சியை வெளிப்படுத்தினர்.",
        "ஹட்டன் நகரின் மையப்பகுதியில் அமைந்துள்ள மணிக்கூட்டு கோபுரத்திற்கு அருகில் ஐக்கிய தேசியக் கட்சியினர் ஒன்று கூடி பட்டாசு கொளுத்தி மகிழ்ச்சியை வெளிப்படுத்திய விதம் எமது கமெராவில் பதிவாகியுள்ளது.",
        "பொருளாதார ரீதியில் வீழ்ச்சியடைந்துள்ள தாய்நாட்டை மீளக் கட்டியெழுப்பக்கூடிய ஒரே தலைவர் தற்போதைய ஜனாதிபதி ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்கவினால் மட்டுமே என ஊடகங்களுக்கு கருத்து தெரிவித்த ஐக்கிய தேசிய கட்சி உறுப்பினர்கள் தெரிவித்துள்ளனர்.",
        "அரசியல் கருத்துக்களை கைவிட்டு நாட்டை பொருளாதார ரீதியாக கட்டியெழுப்ப தற்போதைய ஜனாதிபதி ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்கவிற்கு பாராளுமன்றத்தை பிரதிநிதித்துவப்படுத்தும் அனைத்து பாராளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர்களும் ஆதரவளிக்க வேண்டுமென ஐக்கிய தேசிய கட்சி தெரிவித்துள்ளது."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ஐ.தே.க",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "8வது",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை ஜனநாயக மக்கள் அரசாங்கம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "20வது",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஐக்கிய தேசிய கட்சி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஹட்டன்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஐக்கிய தேசிய கட்சி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஹட்டன்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஐக்கிய தேசியக் கட்சி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஐக்கிய தேசியக் கட்சி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}