{
  "newspaper_id": "daily-mirror-lk",
  "url": "https://www.dailymirror.lk/breaking_news/204-Lankan-flights-stopped-for-refuelling-at-Thiruvananthapuram-airport/108-243429",
  "time_ut": 1661003573,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "204 Lankan flights stopped for refuelling at Thiruvananthapuram airport",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "204 Lankan flights stopped for refuelling at Thiruvananthapuram airport",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "Four more international flights from Sri Lanka had a stopover at Thiruvananthapuram airport for refuelling on Friday. Of them, three flights, operated by SriLankan Airlines, then proceeded to Melbourne, Sydney and Paris, while the fourth, an AirArabia flight, left for Sharjah.",
        "Since May 27, 204 flights from the crisis-hit island nation have made technical landing at Thiruvananthapuram airport owing to the scarcity of fuel back home. Most of the arriving flights are the ones operated by SriLankan Airlines, the official flag carrier of the neighbouring country. The stopovers have helped Thiruvananthapuram airport earn around `1.5 crore in landing fees alone. This excludes refuelling revenue, the new Indian Express reported.",
        "Of the 204 flights that stopped at Thiruvananthapuram, 130 were SriLankan Airlines aircraft bound to destinations including Melbourne, Sydney, Paris and Frankfurt, 11 were Flydubai flights to Dubai, 45 were Air Arabia flights bound for Sharjah, nine Oman Air flights bound for Muscat, seven Gulf Air flights bound for Bahrain and one flight each of Emirates and Fits Voyage.",
        "Sources said the airport is considering this as an opportunity to facilitate and help the struggling island nation. Recently, flights from Colombo started using Kochi airport for technical landings and refuelling too."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "204",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "Lankan",
          "label": "NORP"
        },
        {
          "text": "Thiruvananthapuram",
          "label": "FAC"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Four",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Thiruvananthapuram",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "Friday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "three",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "SriLankan Airlines",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Melbourne",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sydney",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Paris",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "fourth",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "AirArabia",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "May 27",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "204",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Thiruvananthapuram",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "SriLankan Airlines",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Thiruvananthapuram",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "1.5",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Indian Express",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "204",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Thiruvananthapuram",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "130",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "SriLankan Airlines",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Melbourne",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sydney",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Paris",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Frankfurt",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "11",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Flydubai",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Dubai",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "45",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Air Arabia",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "nine",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Oman Air",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Muscat",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "seven",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Gulf Air",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Bahrain",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "one",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Emirates",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Colombo",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kochi",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "තිරුවානන්තපුරම් ගුවන් තොටුපළේ ඉන්ධන පිරවීම සඳහා ලංකා ගුවන් ගමන් 204ක් නතර කර ඇත",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "සිකුරාදා ඉන්ධන පිරවීම සඳහා ශ්‍රී ලංකාවෙන් තවත් ජාත්‍යන්තර ගුවන් ගමන් හතරක් තිරුවානන්තපුරම් ගුවන් තොටුපළේ නතර කර තිබුණි. ඉන්, ශ්‍රී ලංකන් ගුවන් සේවය විසින් මෙහෙයවනු ලබන ගුවන් ගමන් තුනක්, පසුව මෙල්බර්න්, සිඩ්නි සහ පැරිස් වෙත ගමන් ගත් අතර, සිව්වැන්න වූ AirArabia ගුවන් යානය සාජා බලා පිටත් විය.",
        "මැයි 27 වනදා සිට අර්බුදකාරී දූපත් රාජ්‍යයේ සිට ගුවන් ගමන් 204 ක් තිරුවානන්තපුරම් ගුවන් තොටුපළට ආපසු ගෙදර එන ඉන්ධන හිඟය හේතුවෙන් තාක්ෂණික ගොඩබෑම සිදු කර ඇත. පැමිණෙන බොහෝ ගුවන් ගමන් අසල්වැසි රටේ නිල ධජ වාහකය වන ශ්‍රී ලංකන් ගුවන් සමාගම විසින් මෙහෙයවනු ලැබේ. මෙම නැවතුම් ස්ථාන තිරුවානන්තපුරම් ගුවන් තොටුපළට ගොඩබෑමේ ගාස්තුවෙන් පමණක් රුපියල් කෝටි 1.5ක් පමණ උපයා ගැනීමට උපකාරී වී ඇත. මෙය ඉන්ධන පිරවීමේ ආදායම බැහැර කරන බව New Indian Express වාර්තා කරයි.",
        "තිරුවානන්තපුරම් හි නතර වූ ගුවන් ගමන් 204 න් 130 ක් මෙල්බර්න්, සිඩ්නි, පැරිස් සහ ෆ්‍රැන්ක්ෆර්ට් ඇතුළු ගමනාන්ත වෙත යන ශ්‍රී ලංකන් ගුවන් යානා වන අතර, 11 ක් ෆ්ලයිඩුබායි ගුවන් යානා ඩුබායි වෙත, 45 එයාර් ඇරබියා ගුවන් යානා සාජා වෙත, ඕමාන් එයාර් ගුවන් යානා 9 ක් මස්කට් බලා පිටත් විය. ගල්ෆ් එයාර් ගුවන් යානා හතක් බහරේනය බලා පිටත්ව ගිය අතර එමිරේට්ස් සහ ෆිට්ස් වොයේජ් යන එක් ගුවන් යානය බැගින්.",
        "අරගල කරන දූපත් ජාතියට පහසුකම් සැලසීමට සහ උපකාර කිරීමට මෙය අවස්ථාවක් ලෙස ගුවන් තොටුපළ සලකන බව ආරංචි මාර්ග පවසයි. මෑතකදී, කොළඹ සිට පැමිණෙන ගුවන් ගමන් තාක්ෂණික ගොඩබෑම සහ ඉන්ධන පිරවීම සඳහා ද කොචි ගුවන් තොටුපළ භාවිතා කිරීමට පටන් ගත්තේය."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "204",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "ලාංකික",
          "label": "NORP"
        },
        {
          "text": "තිරුවානන්තපුරම්",
          "label": "FAC"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "හතර",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "තිරුවානන්තපුරම්",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "සිකුරාදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "තුන්",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකන් ගුවන් සේවය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "මෙල්බර්න්",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "සිඩ්නි",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "පැරිස්",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "හතරවන",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "AirArabia",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "මැයි 27",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "204",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "තිරුවානන්තපුරම්",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකන් ගුවන් සේවය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "තිරුවානන්තපුරම්",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "1.5",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දියන් එක්ස්ප්‍රස්",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "204",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "තිරුවානන්තපුරම්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "130",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකන් ගුවන් සේවය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "මෙල්බර්න්",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "සිඩ්නි",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "පැරිස්",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ෆ්රෑන්ක්ෆර්ට්",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "11",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ෆ්ලයිඩුබායි",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඩුබායි",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "45",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "එයාර් අරාබිය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "නවය",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඕමාන් එයාර්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "මස්කට්",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "හත",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගල්ෆ් ගුවන්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "බහරේනය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "එක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "එමිරේට්ස්",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "කොළඹ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "කොචි",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "திருவனந்தபுரம் விமான நிலையத்தில் 204 இலங்கை விமானங்கள் எரிபொருள் நிரப்புவதற்காக நிறுத்தப்பட்டன",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "இலங்கையில் இருந்து மேலும் நான்கு சர்வதேச விமானங்கள் வெள்ளிக்கிழமை எரிபொருள் நிரப்புவதற்காக திருவனந்தபுரம் விமான நிலையத்தில் நிறுத்தப்பட்டன. அவற்றில், ஸ்ரீலங்கன் ஏர்லைன்ஸால் இயக்கப்படும் மூன்று விமானங்கள், பின்னர் மெல்போர்ன், சிட்னி மற்றும் பாரிஸுக்குச் சென்றன, நான்காவது, ஏர் அரேபியா விமானம் ஷார்ஜாவிற்குப் புறப்பட்டது.",
        "மே 27 முதல், நெருக்கடியால் பாதிக்கப்பட்ட தீவு நாட்டிலிருந்து 204 விமானங்கள் திருவனந்தபுரம் விமான நிலையத்தில் நாட்டிற்கு எரிபொருள் தட்டுப்பாடு காரணமாக தொழில்நுட்ப தரையிறக்கம் செய்யப்பட்டன. வரும் விமானங்களில் பெரும்பாலானவை அண்டை நாட்டின் உத்தியோகபூர்வ கொடி கேரியர் நிறுவனமான ஸ்ரீலங்கன் ஏர்லைன்ஸால் இயக்கப்படுகின்றன. இந்த நிறுத்தங்கள் திருவனந்தபுரம் விமான நிலையத்திற்கு தரையிறங்கும் கட்டணமாக மட்டும் சுமார் 1.5 கோடி ரூபாய் ஈட்ட உதவியது. இது எரிபொருள் நிரப்பும் வருவாயை விலக்குகிறது என்று புதிய இந்தியன் எக்ஸ்பிரஸ் தெரிவித்துள்ளது.",
        "திருவனந்தபுரத்தில் நிறுத்தப்பட்ட 204 விமானங்களில், 130 மெல்போர்ன், சிட்னி, பாரிஸ் மற்றும் பிராங்பேர்ட் உள்ளிட்ட இடங்களுக்குச் செல்லும் ஸ்ரீலங்கன் ஏர்லைன்ஸ் விமானங்கள், 11 ஃப்ளைடுபாய் விமானங்கள் துபாய், 45 ஏர் அரேபியா விமானங்கள் ஷார்ஜா, 9 ஓமன் ஏர் விமானங்கள் மஸ்கட் செல்லும். ஏழு கல்ஃப் ஏர் விமானங்கள் பஹ்ரைனுக்கும், தலா ஒரு விமானம் எமிரேட்ஸ் மற்றும் ஃபிட்ஸ் வோயேஜ்.",
        "போராடும் தீவு தேசத்தை எளிதாக்குவதற்கும் உதவுவதற்கும் இது ஒரு வாய்ப்பாக விமான நிலையம் கருதுகிறது என்று வட்டாரங்கள் தெரிவித்தன. சமீபத்தில், கொழும்பில் இருந்து வரும் விமானங்கள் தொழில்நுட்ப தரையிறக்கத்திற்கும் எரிபொருள் நிரப்புவதற்கும் கொச்சி விமான நிலையத்தைப் பயன்படுத்தத் தொடங்கியது."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "204",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "இலங்கை",
          "label": "NORP"
        },
        {
          "text": "திருவனந்தபுரம்",
          "label": "FAC"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "நான்கு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "திருவனந்தபுரம்",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "வெள்ளி",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "மூன்று",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஸ்ரீலங்கன் ஏர்லைன்ஸ்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "மெல்போர்ன்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சிட்னி",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாரிஸ்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "நான்காவது",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஏர் அரேபியா",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "மே 27",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "204",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "திருவனந்தபுரம்",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஸ்ரீலங்கன் ஏர்லைன்ஸ்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "திருவனந்தபுரம்",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "1.5",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்தியன் எக்ஸ்பிரஸ்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "204",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "திருவனந்தபுரம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "130",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஸ்ரீலங்கன் ஏர்லைன்ஸ்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "மெல்போர்ன்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சிட்னி",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாரிஸ்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "பிராங்பேர்ட்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "11",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஃப்ளைடுபாய்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "துபாய்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "45",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஏர் அரேபியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஒன்பது",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஓமன் ஏர்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "மஸ்கட்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஏழு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "வளைகுடா ஏர்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "பஹ்ரைன்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஒன்று",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "எமிரேட்ஸ்",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "கொழும்பு",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "கொச்சி",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}