{
  "newspaper_id": "news-first-lk",
  "url": "https://www.newsfirst.lk/2022/06/24/19-year-old-dies-in-accident-near-filling-station/",
  "time_ut": 1656054060,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "19-year-old dies in accident near filling station",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "19-year-old dies in accident near filling station",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); A youth who was waiting in line near the Pandulagama filling station in Anuradhapura died in a road accident this morning.",
        "Police stated that the youth died on the spot after he collided with a lorry transporting heavy equipment.",
        "The deceased was identified as a 19-year-old resident of Thambuththegama.",
        "Police said that the victim was waiting in line for fuel on the left-side of the Anuradhapura – Puttlam Road.",
        "5-year no-pay leave for Public Sector to work in Private Sector?",
        "Another group of 35 people detained for illegal migration attempt to Australia"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "19-year-old",
          "label": "DATE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Pandulagama",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Anuradhapura",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "this morning",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "19-year-old",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Thambuththegama",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "5-year",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Private Sector",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "35",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Australia",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "ඉන්ධන පිරවුම්හල අසල සිදුවූ රිය අනතුරකින් 19 හැවිරිදි තරුණයෙක් මියයයි",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); අනුරාධපුර, පණ්ඩුලගම ඉන්ධන පිරවුම්හල අසල පෝලිමේ රැදී සිටි තරුණයෙකු අද උදෑසන සිදුවූ රිය අනතුරකින් ජීවිතක්ෂයට පත්වුණා.",
        "බර උපකරණ ප්‍රවාහනය කරමින් තිබූ ලොරි රථයක ගැටීමෙන් තරුණයා එම ස්ථානයේදීම මියගොස් ඇති බවයි පොලිසිය සඳහන් කළේ.",
        "මියගොස් ඇත්තේ තඹුත්තේගම ප්‍රදේශයේ පදිංචි 19 හැවිරිදි තරුණයෙකි.",
        "මියගිය පුද්ගලයා අනුරාධපුර - පුත්තලම මාර්ගයේ වම් පසින් ඉන්ධන ලබා ගැනීමට පෝලිමේ සිට ඇති බවයි පොලිසිය පැවසුවේ.",
        "පෞද්ගලික අංශයේ වැඩ කිරීමට රාජ්‍ය අංශයට වසර 5ක වැටුප් රහිත නිවාඩු ද?",
        "නීතිවිරෝධී ලෙස ඕස්ට්‍රේලියාවට සංක්‍රමණය වීමට උත්සාහ කළ තවත් 35 දෙනෙකුගෙන් යුත් කණ්ඩායමක් අත්අඩංගුවට ගෙන තිබේ"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "19 හැවිරිදිය",
          "label": "DATE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "පණ්ඩුලගම",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "අනුරාධපුර",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මේ උදෑසන",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "19 හැවිරිදිය",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "තඹුත්තේගම",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "අවුරුදු 5ක්",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "පෞද්ගලික අංශයේ",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "35",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඕස්ට්රේලියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "எரிபொருள் நிரப்பு நிலையம் அருகே நடந்த விபத்தில் 19 வயது இளைஞர் உயிரிழந்தார்",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); அனுராதபுரம் பந்துலகம எரிபொருள் நிரப்பு நிலையத்திற்கு அருகில் வரிசையில் காத்திருந்த இளைஞர் ஒருவர் இன்று காலை இடம்பெற்ற வாகன விபத்தில் உயிரிழந்துள்ளார்.",
        "கனரக உபகரணங்களை ஏற்றிச் சென்ற லொறியுடன் மோதியதில் குறித்த இளைஞர் சம்பவ இடத்திலேயே உயிரிழந்துள்ளதாக பொலிஸார் தெரிவித்தனர்.",
        "உயிரிழந்தவர் தம்புத்தேகம பகுதியைச் சேர்ந்த 19 வயதுடையவர் என அடையாளம் காணப்பட்டுள்ளார்.",
        "பாதிக்கப்பட்டவர் அனுராதபுரம் - புத்தளம் வீதியின் இடதுபுறத்தில் எரிபொருளுக்காக வரிசையில் காத்திருந்ததாக பொலிஸார் தெரிவித்தனர்.",
        "தனியார் துறையில் பணிபுரிய பொதுத்துறைக்கு 5 ஆண்டு ஊதியம் இல்லாத விடுப்பு?",
        "அவுஸ்திரேலியாவிற்கு சட்டவிரோதமாக குடியேற முயற்சித்த 35 பேர் கொண்ட மற்றொரு குழு கைது செய்யப்பட்டுள்ளனர்"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "19 வயது",
          "label": "DATE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "பந்துலகம",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "அனுராதபுரம்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று காலை",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "19 வயது",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "தம்புத்தேகம",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "5-ஆண்டு",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "தனியார் துறை",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "35",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆஸ்திரேலியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  },
  "title": "19-year-old dies in accident near filling station",
  "body_lines": [
    "COLOMBO (News 1st); A youth who was waiting in line near the Pandulagama filling station in Anuradhapura died in a road accident this morning.",
    "Police stated that the youth died on the spot after he collided with a lorry transporting heavy equipment.",
    "The deceased was identified as a 19-year-old resident of Thambuththegama.",
    "Police said that the victim was waiting in line for fuel on the left-side of the Anuradhapura – Puttlam Road.",
    "5-year no-pay leave for Public Sector to work in Private Sector?",
    "Another group of 35 people detained for illegal migration attempt to Australia"
  ],
  "translate": {
    "en": {
      "title": "19-year-old dies in accident near filling station",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); A youth who was waiting in line near the Pandulagama filling station in Anuradhapura died in a road accident this morning.",
        "Police stated that the youth died on the spot after he collided with a lorry transporting heavy equipment.",
        "The deceased was identified as a 19-year-old resident of Thambuththegama.",
        "Police said that the victim was waiting in line for fuel on the left-side of the Anuradhapura – Puttlam Road.",
        "5-year no-pay leave for Public Sector to work in Private Sector?",
        "Another group of 35 people detained for illegal migration attempt to Australia"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "19-year-old",
          "label": "DATE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Pandulagama",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Anuradhapura",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "this morning",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "19-year-old",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Thambuththegama",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "5-year",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Private Sector",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "35",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Australia",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "ඉන්ධන පිරවුම්හල අසල සිදුවූ රිය අනතුරකින් 19 හැවිරිදි තරුණයෙක් මියයයි",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); අනුරාධපුර, පණ්ඩුලගම ඉන්ධන පිරවුම්හල අසල පෝලිමේ රැදී සිටි තරුණයෙකු අද උදෑසන සිදුවූ රිය අනතුරකින් ජීවිතක්ෂයට පත්වුණා.",
        "බර උපකරණ ප්‍රවාහනය කරමින් තිබූ ලොරි රථයක ගැටීමෙන් තරුණයා එම ස්ථානයේදීම මියගොස් ඇති බවයි පොලිසිය සඳහන් කළේ.",
        "මියගොස් ඇත්තේ තඹුත්තේගම ප්‍රදේශයේ පදිංචි 19 හැවිරිදි තරුණයෙකි.",
        "මියගිය පුද්ගලයා අනුරාධපුර - පුත්තලම මාර්ගයේ වම් පසින් ඉන්ධන ලබා ගැනීමට පෝලිමේ සිට ඇති බවයි පොලිසිය පැවසුවේ.",
        "පෞද්ගලික අංශයේ වැඩ කිරීමට රාජ්‍ය අංශයට වසර 5ක වැටුප් රහිත නිවාඩු ද?",
        "නීතිවිරෝධී ලෙස ඕස්ට්‍රේලියාවට සංක්‍රමණය වීමට උත්සාහ කළ තවත් 35 දෙනෙකුගෙන් යුත් කණ්ඩායමක් අත්අඩංගුවට ගෙන තිබේ"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "19 හැවිරිදිය",
          "label": "DATE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "පණ්ඩුලගම",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "අනුරාධපුර",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මේ උදෑසන",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "19 හැවිරිදිය",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "තඹුත්තේගම",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "අවුරුදු 5ක්",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "පෞද්ගලික අංශයේ",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "35",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඕස්ට්රේලියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "எரிபொருள் நிரப்பு நிலையம் அருகே நடந்த விபத்தில் 19 வயது இளைஞர் உயிரிழந்தார்",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); அனுராதபுரம் பந்துலகம எரிபொருள் நிரப்பு நிலையத்திற்கு அருகில் வரிசையில் காத்திருந்த இளைஞர் ஒருவர் இன்று காலை இடம்பெற்ற வாகன விபத்தில் உயிரிழந்துள்ளார்.",
        "கனரக உபகரணங்களை ஏற்றிச் சென்ற லொறியுடன் மோதியதில் குறித்த இளைஞர் சம்பவ இடத்திலேயே உயிரிழந்துள்ளதாக பொலிஸார் தெரிவித்தனர்.",
        "உயிரிழந்தவர் தம்புத்தேகம பகுதியைச் சேர்ந்த 19 வயதுடையவர் என அடையாளம் காணப்பட்டுள்ளார்.",
        "பாதிக்கப்பட்டவர் அனுராதபுரம் - புத்தளம் வீதியின் இடதுபுறத்தில் எரிபொருளுக்காக வரிசையில் காத்திருந்ததாக பொலிஸார் தெரிவித்தனர்.",
        "தனியார் துறையில் பணிபுரிய பொதுத்துறைக்கு 5 ஆண்டு ஊதியம் இல்லாத விடுப்பு?",
        "அவுஸ்திரேலியாவிற்கு சட்டவிரோதமாக குடியேற முயற்சித்த 35 பேர் கொண்ட மற்றொரு குழு கைது செய்யப்பட்டுள்ளனர்"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "19 வயது",
          "label": "DATE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "பந்துலகம",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "அனுராதபுரம்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று காலை",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "19 வயது",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "தம்புத்தேகம",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "5-ஆண்டு",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "தனியார் துறை",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "35",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆஸ்திரேலியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}