{
  "newspaper_id": "virakesari-lk",
  "url": "http://www.virakesari.lk/article/130316",
  "time_ut": 1656399129,
  "original_lang": "ta",
  "original_title": "ஆசிரியைகளின் இடமாற்றத்துக்கு இடைக்காலத் தடை - கல்முனை மேல் நீதிமன்றம் அதிரடி",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Interim injunction against transfer of teachers - Kalmunai High Court Action",
      "author": "Digital Desk 5",
      "body_lines": [
        "The Kalmunai High Court has issued an interim injunction against the transfer of 07 teachers on duty in the Kalmunai Education Zone by the Eastern Provincial Ministry of Education to other zones.",
        "The Writ of Certiorari under the provisions of Article 154 P (4) (b) of the Constitution was summoned in the presence of Kalmunai High Court Judge Hon. Troxy last (24).",
        "In this case, the Provincial Director of Education of the Eastern Provincial Department of Education, Mrs. Nakuleswari Pillainayakam, Additional Provincial Director of Education J. Arulanantham and the Secretary to the Ministry of Education, Eastern Province were named as defendants.",
        "After hearing the arguments of the petitioners, the Hon'ble High Court Judge directed that the case be re-called on Monday (27).",
        "When the petition was called for support again on Monday (27), the lawyers appearing on behalf of the petitioners submitted lengthy submissions that it was unreasonable and lawful to grant the petitioners an unauthorized transfer under Section 185 of the Establishment Procedure Code of the Eastern Provincial Public Service.",
        "Satisfied with the submissions, the High Court Judge issued an interim injunction restraining the transfer of the petitioners and directed them to send notice to the respondents appearing before the Hon'ble House (01).",
        "Attorney MM on behalf of the petitioners in the case. Senior lawyer Arif Samsuddin, lawyer Khalid Muhaimin and lawyer Mubarak Assam appeared on Nur Jahan's instructions."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "The Kalmunai High Court",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "07",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Eastern Provincial Ministry of Education",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Article 154 P",
            "label": "LAW"
          },
          {
            "text": "4",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Constitution",
            "label": "LAW"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kalmunai High Court",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Hon",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Troxy",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "24",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Provincial",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Eastern Provincial Department of Education",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Nakuleswari Pillainayakam",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "J. Arulanantham",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Ministry of Education",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Eastern Province",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Hon'ble High Court",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Monday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "27",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Monday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "27",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Section 185 of the Establishment Procedure Code of the Eastern Provincial Public Service",
            "label": "LAW"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the Hon'ble House",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "01",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "MM",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Arif Samsuddin",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Khalid Muhaimin",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Mubarak Assam",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Nur Jahan's",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "ගුරු මාරුවීම්වලට එරෙහිව අතුරු තහනම් නියෝගයක් - කල්මුණේ මහාධිකරණයෙන්",
      "author": "ඩිජිටල් මේසය 5",
      "body_lines": [
        "නැගෙනහිර පළාත් අධ්‍යාපන අමාත්‍යාංශය මගින් කල්මුණේ අධ්‍යාපන කලාපයේ සේවයේ නියුතු ගුරුවරුන් 07 දෙනෙකු වෙනත් කලාපවලට ස්ථාන මාරු කිරීමට එරෙහිව කල්මුණේ මහාධිකරණය විසින් අතුරු තහනම් නියෝගයක් නිකුත් කර තිබේ.",
        "ආණ්ඩුක්‍රම ව්‍යවස්ථාවේ 154 පි (4) (ආ) වගන්තියේ විධිවිධාන යටතේ සර්ටියෝරාරිගේ ආඥාව කල්මුණේ මහාධිකරණ විනිසුරු ගරු ට්‍රොක්සි මහතා ඉදිරියේ පසුගිය (24) කැඳවන ලදී.",
        "මෙම නඩුවේදී නැගෙනහිර පළාත් අධ්‍යාපන දෙපාර්තමේන්තුවේ පළාත් අධ්‍යාපන අධ්‍යක්ෂ මහත්මිය. නකුලේශ්වරී පිල්ලෙයිනායගම්, අතිරේක පළාත් අධ්‍යාපන අධ්‍යක්ෂ ජේ. අරුලානන්දම් සහ නැගෙනහිර පළාත් අධ්‍යාපන අමාත්‍යාංශයේ ලේකම් විත්තිකරුවන් ලෙස නම් කර තිබුණි.",
        "පෙත්සම්කාර පාර්ශ්වයේ කරුණු දැක්වීම්වලට සවන් දුන් ගරු මහාධිකරණ විනිසුරුවරයා නඩුව ලබන සඳුදා (27) යළි කැඳවන ලෙසට නියෝග කළේය.",
        "මෙම පෙත්සම සඳුදා (27) යළි කැඳවූ අවස්ථාවේදී පෙත්සම්කරුවන් වෙනුවෙන් පෙනී සිටි නීතීඥවරුන් දීර්ඝ ලෙස දීර්ඝ ලෙස කරුණු දක්වමින් කියා සිටියේ නැගෙනහිර පළාත් ආයතන විධිවිධාන සංග්‍රහයේ 185 වගන්තිය යටතේ පෙත්සම්කරුවන්ට අනවසර ස්ථාන මාරුවක් ලබාදීම අසාධාරණ සහ නීත්‍යානුකූල බවයි. පොදු සේවා.",
        "ඉදිරිපත් වූ කරුණු පිළිබඳව සෑහීමකට පත් වූ මහාධිකරණ විනිසුරුවරයා පෙත්සම්කරුවන්ට ස්ථාන මාරුවීම් ලබා දීම වළක්වමින් අතුරු තහනම් නියෝගයක් නිකුත් කළ අතර ගරු සභාව (01) හමුවේ පෙනී සිටින වගඋත්තරකරුවන්ට නොතීසි යවන ලෙසට නියෝග කළේය.",
        "මෙම නඩුවේ පෙත්සම්කරුවන් වෙනුවෙන් නීතිඥ එම්.එම්. නූර් ජහාන්ගේ උපදෙස් මත ජ්‍යෙෂ්ඨ නීතිඥ අරිෆ් සම්සුදීන්, නීතිඥ කලීඩ් මුහයිමින් සහ නීතිඥ මුබාරක් අසාම් පෙනී සිටියහ."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "කල්මුණේ මහාධිකරණය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "07",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "නැගෙනහිර පළාත් අධ්‍යාපන අමාත්‍යාංශය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "154 පි",
            "label": "LAW"
          },
          {
            "text": "4",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ආණ්ඩුක්රම ව්යවස්ථාව",
            "label": "LAW"
          },
          {
            "text": "කල්මුණේ මහාධිකරණය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගරු",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ට්රොක්සි",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "24",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "පළාත්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "නැගෙනහිර පළාත් අධ්‍යාපන දෙපාර්තමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "නකුලේශ්වරී පිල්ලෙනායකම්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජේ.අරුලානන්දම්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "අධ්යාපන අමාත්යාංශය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "නැගෙනහිර පළාත",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ගරු මහාධිකරණය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "සඳුදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "27",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "සඳුදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "27",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "නැගෙනහිර පළාත් රාජ්‍ය සේවයේ ආයතන පරිපාටි සංග්‍රහයේ 185 වගන්තිය",
            "label": "LAW"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ගරු සභාව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "01",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "එම්.එම්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "අරිෆ් සම්සුදීන්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "කාලිඩ් මුහයිමින්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "මුබාරක් අසාම්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "නූර් ජහාන්ගේ",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "ஆசிரியைகளின் இடமாற்றத்துக்கு இடைக்காலத் தடை - கல்முனை மேல் நீதிமன்றம் அதிரடி",
      "author": "Digital Desk 5",
      "body_lines": [
        "கிழக்கு மாகாண கல்வி அமைச்சினால் கல்முனை கல்வி வலையத்தில் கடமை புரியும் 07 ஆசிரியைகளுக்கு வேறு வலையங்களுக்கு வழங்கப்பட்ட இடமாற்றத்துக்கு கல்முனை மேல் நீதிமன்றம் இடைக்காலத் தடை உத்தரவு பிறப்பித்துள்ளது.",
        "அரசியல் அமைப்பின் உறுப்புரை 154 P (4) (b) யின் ஏற்பாடுகளின் கீழ் மேற்கொள்ளப்பட்ட உறுதிகேள் எழுத்தாணை மனு (Writ of Certiorari) கல்முனை மேல் நீதிமன்ற நீதிபதி கெளரவ ட்றொக்சி முன்னிலையில் கடந்த (24) திகதி ஆதரிப்பதற்காக அழைக்கப்பட்டது.",
        "குறித்த வழக்கில் கிழக்கு மாகாண கல்வித் திணைக்களத்தின் மாகாணக் கல்விப் பணிப்பாளர் திருமதி. நகுலேஸ்வரி பிள்ளைநாயகம், மேலதிக மாகாணக் கல்விப்  பணிப்பாளர் ஜெ.அருளானந்தம் மற்றும் கிழக்கு மாகாணக் கல்வி அமைச்சின் செயலாளர் ஆகியோர் பிரதிவாதிகளாக பெயரிடப்பட்டிருந்தனர்.",
        "மனுதாரர்கள் தரப்பு வாதங்களைக் கேட்டறிந்த கெளரவ மேல்நீதிமன்ற நீதிபதி குறித்த வழக்கை மீண்டும் (27) திங்கட்கிழமை அழைக்குமாறு உத்தரவிட்டார்.",
        "குறித்த எழுத்தானை மனு மீண்டும் நேற்று (27) திங்கட்கிழமை ஆதரிப்பதற்காக அழைக்கப்பட்டபோது மனுதாரர்கள் சார்பாக தோன்றிய சட்டத்தரணிகள் கிழக்கு மாகாண அரச சேவைக்கான தாபன நடைமுறை ஒழுங்கு விதிக்கோவையின் பிரிவு 185 யின் கீழ் அங்கீகரிக்கப்படாத ஒரு இடமாற்றத்தை மனுதாரர்களுக்கு வழங்கியமை நியாயமற்றதும் சட்டமுறணானதுமாகும் என நீண்ட சமர்ப்பணங்களை முன்வைத்தனர்.",
        "குறித்த சமர்ப்பணங்களில் மீது திருப்தியுற்ற மேல் நீதிமன்ற நீதிபதி மனுதார்களுக்கு வழங்கப்பட்டுள்ள இடமாற்றத்துக்கு இடைக்கால தடை உத்தரவைப் பிறப்பித்துள்ளதோடு எதிர்வரும் (01) கெளரவ மன்றில் தோன்ற பிரதிவாதிகளுக்கு அறிவித்தல் அனுப்புமாறு கட்டளை ஆக்கியுள்ளார்.",
        "குறித்த வழக்கில் மனுதாரர்கள் சார்பில் சட்டத்தரணி எம்.எம். நூர்ஜஹானின் அறிவுறுத்தலில் சிரேஷ்ட சட்டத்தரணி ஆரிப் சம்சுதீன், சட்டத்தரணி காலித் முஹைமீன் மற்றும் சட்டத்தரணி முபாறக் அஸ்ஸம் ஆகியோர் தோன்றி இருந்தனர்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "கல்முனை மேல் நீதிமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "07",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "கிழக்கு மாகாண கல்வி அமைச்சு",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "கட்டுரை 154 பி",
            "label": "LAW"
          },
          {
            "text": "4",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "அரசியலமைப்பு",
            "label": "LAW"
          },
          {
            "text": "கல்முனை மேல் நீதிமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "கௌரவ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ட்ராக்ஸி",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "24",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "மாகாணம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "கிழக்கு மாகாண கல்வி திணைக்களம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "நகுலேஸ்வரி பிள்ளைநாயகம்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜெ.அருளானந்தம்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "கல்வி அமைச்சு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "கிழக்கு மாகாணம்",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "மாண்புமிகு உயர்நீதிமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "திங்கட்கிழமை",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "27",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "திங்கட்கிழமை",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "27",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "கிழக்கு மாகாண பொதுச் சேவையின் ஸ்தாபன நடைமுறைச் சட்டத்தின் பிரிவு 185",
            "label": "LAW"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "மாண்புமிகு இல்லம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "01",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "எம்.எம்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆரிப் சம்சுதீன்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "காலித் முஹைமின்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "முபாரக் அசாம்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "நூர் ஜஹானின்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}