{
  "newspaper_id": "news-first-lk",
  "url": "https://www.newsfirst.lk/2022/09/03/a-loaf-of-bread-is-now-rs-300/",
  "time_ut": 1662175800,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "A loaf of bread is now Rs. 300/-",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "A loaf of bread is now Rs. 300/-",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); The Lanka Bakery Owners' Association says that the price of a loaf of bread will be sold at Rs.300/-.",
        "The Chairman of the Lanka Bekary Owners' Association N.K Jayawardena said that such steps had to be taken due to the rapid increase in  Wheat flour prices.",
        "He further said he has instructed all bakery owners across the country about the price revision.",
        "Additionally, he says Wheat Flour is priced at over Rs. 20,000 in the wholesale market.",
        "Jayawardena further pointed out that more than 2,000 bakeries across the country have closed down amidst the shortage of Wheat Flour."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "News 1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "The Lanka Bakery Owners' Association",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the Lanka Bekary Owners' Association",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "Wheat Flour",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "20,000",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "more than 2,000",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Wheat Flour",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "පාන් ගෙඩියක් දැන් රු. 300/-",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); පාන් ගෙඩියක මිල රුපියල් 300/-කට අලෙවි කරන බව ලංකා බේකරි හිමියන්ගේ සංගමය පවසයි.",
        "ලංකා බේකරි හිමියන්ගේ සංගමයේ සභාපති එන්.කේ ජයවර්ධන මහතා පැවසුවේ තිරිඟු පිටි මිල සීඝ්‍රයෙන් ඉහළ යාම හේතුවෙන් මෙවැනි පියවර ගැනීමට සිදුව ඇති බවයි.",
        "මිල සංශෝධනය සම්බන්ධයෙන් දිවයින පුරා සිටින සියලුම බේකරි හිමියන්ට උපදෙස් ලබාදී ඇති බව ඔහු වැඩිදුරටත් පැවසීය.",
        "මීට අමතරව තිරිඟු පිටි මිල රු. තොග වෙළඳපොලේ 20,000 කි.",
        "තිරිඟු පිටි හිඟය මධ්‍යයේ රට පුරා පිහිටි බේකරි 2000කට අධික ප්‍රමාණයක් වසා දමා ඇති බවද ජයවර්ධන මහතා වැඩිදුරටත් පෙන්වා දුන්නේය."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "News 1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ලංකා බේකරි හිමියන්ගේ සංගමය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ලංකා බෙකරි හිමියන්ගේ සංගමය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "තිරිඟු පිටි",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "20,000 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "2,000 කට වඩා වැඩිය",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "තිරිඟු පිටි",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "ஒரு ரொட்டி இப்போது ரூ. 300/-",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); ரொட்டி ஒன்றின் விலை ரூபா 300/-க்கு விற்பனை செய்யப்படவுள்ளதாக லங்கா பேக்கரி உரிமையாளர்கள் சங்கம் தெரிவித்துள்ளது.",
        "கோதுமை மாவின் விலை வேகமாக அதிகரித்து வருவதால் இவ்வாறான நடவடிக்கைகளை மேற்கொள்ள வேண்டியுள்ளதாக லங்கா பெக்கரி உரிமையாளர்கள் சங்கத்தின் தலைவர் என்.கே ஜயவர்தன தெரிவித்துள்ளார்.",
        "நாடு முழுவதும் உள்ள அனைத்து பேக்கரி உரிமையாளர்களுக்கும் விலை திருத்தம் குறித்து அறிவுறுத்தியுள்ளதாக அவர் மேலும் தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "மேலும், கோதுமை மாவின் விலை ரூ. ரூ. மொத்த சந்தையில் 20,000.",
        "கோதுமை மாவின் தட்டுப்பாட்டிற்கு மத்தியில் நாடு முழுவதும் 2000க்கும் மேற்பட்ட பேக்கரிகள் மூடப்பட்டுள்ளதாக ஜயவர்தன மேலும் சுட்டிக்காட்டினார்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "News 1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "லங்கா பேக்கரி உரிமையாளர்கள் சங்கம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "லங்கா பெக்காரி உரிமையாளர்கள் சங்கம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "கோதுமை மாவு",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "20,000",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "2,000க்கு மேல்",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "கோதுமை மாவு",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}