{
  "newspaper_id": "daily-mirror-lk",
  "url": "https://www.dailymirror.lk/business-news/SL-to-welcome-more-Swiss-travellers-this-winter-with-travel-advisory-easing/273-243753",
  "time_ut": 1661465776,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "​SL to welcome more Swiss travellers this winter with travel advisory easing",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "​SL to welcome more Swiss travellers this winter with travel advisory easing",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "The government of Switzerland announced this week the relaxation of the travel advice to Sri Lanka, a move that could help the island nation welcome more visitors from that country for the upcoming winter season.​​",
        "The previous warning against visiting the island nation has been eased for Swiss travellers with the improvement in the ground situation witnessed in recent weeks.",
        "Mid-July the government of Switzerland advised its citizens to avoid all unnecessary trips to Sri Lanka, other than air transit via Bandaranaike International Airport. The decision came as state of emergency was imposed at the time.",
        "With tensions in the country easing, Switzerland has followed the direction of other tourism source markets, such a​​s France, giving the green light to enter the destination.",
        "The move was welcomed by the Sri Lanka Association of Inbound Tour Operators (SLAITO) and One Industry One Voice.",
        "In a joint statement released to the media, the associations said the easing of the travel advisory will help Swiss tour operators to promote Sri Lanka once again.",
        "“Switzerland is an important market for us, especially for the winter season and the relaxation is timely,” the associations said.",
        "Sri Lanka received no tourists from Switzerland for the month of August so far. However, during the first few months of the year, when tourism was picking up momentum before the economic and political crisis in the country spiraled out of control, interest from that market in destination Sri Lanka was improving.",
        "For the 1 January to 23 August period, a total of 9,546 tourists from Switzerland visited Sri Lanka, provisional data from the Sri Lanka Tourism Development Authority (SLTDA) showed."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Swiss",
          "label": "NORP"
        },
        {
          "text": "this winter",
          "label": "DATE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Switzerland",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "this week",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "winter",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Swiss",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "recent weeks",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Mid-July",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Switzerland",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Bandaranaike International Airport",
            "label": "FAC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Switzerland",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "a​​s France",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the Sri Lanka Association of Inbound Tour Operators",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "SLAITO",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "One",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Swiss",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Switzerland",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the winter season",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Switzerland",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the month of August",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the first few months of the year",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the 1 January to 23 August",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "9,546",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Switzerland",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Sri Lanka Tourism Development Authority",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "සංචාරක උපදේශන ලිහිල් කිරීම සමඟ මෙම ශීත ඍතුවේ දී තවත් ස්විට්සර්ලන්ත සංචාරකයින් පිළිගැනීමට SL",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "ස්විට්සර්ලන්ත රජය මේ සතියේ ශ්‍රී ලංකාවට සංචාරක උපදෙස් ලිහිල් කරන බව නිවේදනය කළේය, එය ඉදිරි ශීත ඍතුව සඳහා එම රටෙන් තවත් අමුත්තන් පිළිගැනීමට දිවයිනට උපකාර කළ හැකි පියවරකි.",
        "මෑත සතිවල දක්නට ලැබුණු භූගත තත්ත්වය වැඩිදියුණු වීමත් සමඟ ස්විට්සර්ලන්ත සංචාරකයින් සඳහා දිවයිනට පැමිණීමට එරෙහිව පෙර අනතුරු ඇඟවීම ලිහිල් කර ඇත.",
        "බණ්ඩාරනායක ජාත්‍යන්තර ගුවන් තොටුපළ හරහා ගුවන් ගමනාගමනය හැර ශ්‍රී ලංකාවට අනවශ්‍ය සියලු සංචාරවලින් වළකින ලෙස ස්විට්සර්ලන්ත රජය ජූලි මැද භාගයේදී සිය පුරවැසියන්ට උපදෙස් දුන්නේය. එම අවස්ථාවේදී හදිසි නීතිය පනවා තිබූ බැවින් මෙම තීරණය ගෙන ඇත.",
        "රටේ ආතතීන් ලිහිල් වීමත් සමඟ, ස්විට්සර්ලන්තය ගමනාන්තයට ඇතුළු වීමට හරිත එළියක් ලබා දෙමින් ප්‍රංශය වැනි අනෙකුත් සංචාරක ප්‍රභවයන්ගේ දිශාව අනුගමනය කර ඇත.",
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකා අභ්‍යන්තර සංචාරක ක්‍රියාකරුවන්ගේ සංගමය (SLAITO) සහ One Industry One Voice විසින් මෙම පියවර පිළිගනු ලැබීය.",
        "මාධ්‍ය වෙත නිකුත් කරන ලද ඒකාබද්ධ ප්‍රකාශයක සංගම් පවසන්නේ සංචාරක උපදේශනය ලිහිල් කිරීම ස්විස් සංචාරක ක්‍රියාකරුවන්ට නැවත වරක් ශ්‍රී ලංකාව ප්‍රවර්ධනය කිරීමට උපකාරී වනු ඇති බවයි.",
        "\"ස්විට්සර්ලන්තය අපට වැදගත් වෙළඳපොලක් වන අතර, විශේෂයෙන්ම ශීත ඍතුව සඳහා සහ විවේකය කාලෝචිත වේ,\" සංගම් පැවසීය.",
        "අගෝස්තු මාසය සඳහා මෙතෙක් ශ්‍රී ලංකාවට ස්විට්සර්ලන්තයෙන් සංචාරකයින් ලැබී නොමැත. කෙසේ වෙතත්, වසරේ මුල් මාස කිහිපය තුළ, රටේ ආර්ථික හා දේශපාලන අර්බුදය පාලනයෙන් මිදීමට පෙර සංචාරක ව්‍යාපාරය වේගවත් වූ විට, ගමනාන්තය වන ශ්‍රී ලංකාව කෙරෙහි එම වෙළඳපොළේ උනන්දුව වැඩි දියුණු වෙමින් පැවතුනි.",
        "ජනවාරි 1 සිට අගෝස්තු 23 දක්වා කාලය තුළ ස්විට්සර්ලන්තයේ සිට සංචාරකයින් 9,546 ක් ශ්‍රී ලංකාවට පැමිණ ඇති බව ශ්‍රී ලංකා සංචාරක සංවර්ධන අධිකාරියේ (SLTDA) තාවකාලික දත්ත පෙන්වා දෙයි."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ස්විස්",
          "label": "NORP"
        },
        {
          "text": "මෙම ශීත",
          "label": "DATE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ස්විට්සර්ලන්තය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මෙම සතිය",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශීත ඍතුව",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ස්විස්",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "මෑත සති",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ජූලි මැද",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ස්විට්සර්ලන්තය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "බණ්ඩාරනායක ජාත්‍යන්තර ගුවන්තොටුපළ",
            "label": "FAC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ස්විට්සර්ලන්තය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "a ප්රංශය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකා අභ්‍යන්තර සංචාරක ක්‍රියාකරුවන්ගේ සංගමය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "SLAITO",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "එක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ස්විස්",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ස්විට්සර්ලන්තය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශීත සමය",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ස්විට්සර්ලන්තය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "අගෝස්තු මාසය",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "වසරේ මුල් මාස කිහිපය",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ජනවාරි 1 සිට අගෝස්තු 23 දක්වා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "9,546 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ස්විට්සර්ලන්තය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකා සංචාරක සංවර්ධන අධිකාරිය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "இந்த குளிர்காலத்தில் அதிகமான சுவிஸ் பயணிகளை பயண ஆலோசனை தளர்த்தியுடன் வரவேற்க SL",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "சுவிட்சர்லாந்து அரசாங்கம் இந்த வாரம் இலங்கைக்கான பயண ஆலோசனையை தளர்த்துவதாக அறிவித்தது, இது வரவிருக்கும் குளிர்காலத்தில் அந்த நாட்டிலிருந்து அதிகமான பார்வையாளர்களை வரவேற்க தீவு நாட்டிற்கு உதவும்.",
        "கடந்த வாரங்களில் நிலத்தடி நிலைமையில் ஏற்பட்ட முன்னேற்றத்துடன், தீவு நாட்டிற்குச் செல்வதற்கு எதிரான முந்தைய எச்சரிக்கை சுவிஸ் பயணிகளுக்கு தளர்த்தப்பட்டுள்ளது.",
        "ஜூலை நடுப்பகுதியில் சுவிட்சர்லாந்து அரசாங்கம் பண்டாரநாயக்க சர்வதேச விமான நிலையத்தின் ஊடாக விமானப் போக்குவரத்தைத் தவிர இலங்கைக்கான அனைத்து தேவையற்ற பயணங்களையும் தவிர்க்குமாறு தனது குடிமக்களுக்கு அறிவுறுத்தியது. அப்போது அவசர நிலை அமல்படுத்தப்பட்டதால் இந்த முடிவு எடுக்கப்பட்டது.",
        "நாட்டில் பதட்டங்கள் தணிந்த நிலையில், சுவிட்சர்லாந்து மற்ற சுற்றுலா மூல சந்தைகளான பிரான்ஸ் போன்றவற்றின் திசையை பின்பற்றி, இலக்குக்குள் நுழைய பச்சை விளக்கு கொடுத்தது.",
        "இந்நடவடிக்கையை இலங்கை உள்வரும் சுற்றுலா செயற்பாட்டாளர்களின் சங்கம் (SLAITO) மற்றும் ஒரு கைத்தொழில் ஒரு குரல் வரவேற்றன.",
        "ஊடகங்களுக்கு வெளியிடப்பட்ட கூட்டறிக்கையில், பயண ஆலோசனையை தளர்த்துவது சுவிஸ் சுற்றுலா நடத்துபவர்களுக்கு மீண்டும் இலங்கையை மேம்படுத்த உதவும் என்று சங்கங்கள் தெரிவித்தன.",
        "\"சுவிட்சர்லாந்து எங்களுக்கு ஒரு முக்கியமான சந்தையாகும், குறிப்பாக குளிர்காலம் மற்றும் ஓய்வெடுப்பது சரியான நேரத்தில்\" என்று சங்கங்கள் தெரிவித்தன.",
        "ஆகஸ்ட் மாதத்திற்கு இதுவரை சுவிட்சர்லாந்தில் இருந்து இலங்கைக்கு சுற்றுலாப் பயணிகள் வரவில்லை. எவ்வாறாயினும், ஆண்டின் முதல் சில மாதங்களில், நாட்டின் பொருளாதார மற்றும் அரசியல் நெருக்கடி கட்டுப்பாட்டை மீறுவதற்கு முன்னர், சுற்றுலா வேகத்தை உயர்த்தியபோது, ​​அந்த சந்தையின் இலக்கு இலங்கையில் முன்னேற்றம் கண்டது.",
        "ஜனவரி 1 முதல் ஆகஸ்ட் 23 வரையான காலப்பகுதியில், சுவிட்சர்லாந்தில் இருந்து மொத்தம் 9,546 சுற்றுலாப் பயணிகள் இலங்கைக்கு வருகை தந்துள்ளதாக இலங்கை சுற்றுலா அபிவிருத்தி அதிகார சபையின் (SLTDA) தற்காலிகத் தகவல்கள் தெரிவிக்கின்றன."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "சுவிஸ்",
          "label": "NORP"
        },
        {
          "text": "இந்த குளிர்காலத்தில்",
          "label": "DATE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "சுவிட்சர்லாந்து",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்த வாரம்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "குளிர்காலம்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "சுவிஸ்",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "சமீபத்திய வாரங்கள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஜூலை நடுப்பகுதி",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சுவிட்சர்லாந்து",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "பண்டாரநாயக்க சர்வதேச விமான நிலையம்",
            "label": "FAC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "சுவிட்சர்லாந்து",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஒரு பிரான்ஸ்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "உள்வரும் சுற்றுலா நடத்துபவர்களின் இலங்கை சங்கம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "SLAITO",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஒன்று",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "சுவிஸ்",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "சுவிட்சர்லாந்து",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "குளிர்காலம்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சுவிட்சர்லாந்து",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆகஸ்ட் மாதம்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆண்டின் முதல் சில மாதங்கள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஜனவரி 1 முதல் ஆகஸ்ட் 23 வரை",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "9,546",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "சுவிட்சர்லாந்து",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை சுற்றுலா அபிவிருத்தி அதிகாரசபை",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}