{
  "newspaper_id": "lankadeepa-lk",
  "url": "https://www.lankadeepa.lk/news/’’රටේ-පාලනය-බාරගන්න-සූදානම්’’/101-616245",
  "time_ut": 1657533550,
  "original_lang": "si",
  "original_title": "’’රටේ පාලනය බාරගන්න සූදානම්’’",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "\"Ready to take control of the country\"",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "Janatha Vimukthi Peramuna leader and Member of Parliament Mr. Anura Kumara Dissanayake said today that he is ready to take over if the government of the country is handed over at this time.",
        "Anura Kumara Mahata also mentioned that 'we are people who are ready to accept the responsibility and do not leave anything out of fear.'",
        "But since there are only three representatives in the parliament, if the bills of the president and the prime minister are there in the parliament, there is a chance for someone else to become the president and prime minister.",
        "Mr. Dissanayake also said that since a contradiction has been created between the will of the people and the parliament, a parliament that reflects the will of the people should be established."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Janatha Vimukthi Peramuna",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Anura Kumara Dissanayake",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Anura Kumara Mahata",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "only three",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Dissanayake",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "’’රටේ පාලනය බාරගන්න සූදානම්’’",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "මේ අවස්ථාවේ රටේ පාලනය භාරදුන්නොත් භාරගැනීමට සූදානම් බව ජනතා විමුක්ති පෙරමුණේ නායක, පාර්ලිමේන්තු මන්ත්‍රී අනුර කුමාර දිසානායක මහතා අද පැවසීය.",
        "‘අපි කිසිවක් බියගුළුකමින් දාල යන්නේ නැති වගකීම භාරගන්න සූදානම් මිනිස්සු.’ යැයි ද අනුර කුමාර මහාතා සඳහන් කළේය.",
        "නමුත් පාර්ලිමේන්තුවේ තම නියෝජිතයන් තිදෙනෙකු පමණක් බැවින් ජනාධිපතිවරයාගේ හා අගමැතිවරයාගේ පනත් පාර්ලිමේන්තුවේ තිබෙනවා නම් ඕනෙ වෙලාවක වෙන කෙනෙකුට නැටවිය හැකි ජනාධිපතිවරයකු, අගමැතිවරයකු බවට පත්වීමේ ඉඩක් තිබෙන බව කී ජවිපෙ නායකයා එසේ වුවත් ඒ තුළ පවා තමන්ට උවමනා කණ්ඩායමක් පත්කරගන්න දෙනවා නම් ඊට සූදානම් බව කීවේය.",
        "දැන් ජනතාවගේ කැමැත්තත් පාර්ලිමේන්තුවත් අතර පරස්පරයක් නිර්මාණය වී ඇති බැවින් ජනතා කැමැත්ත පිළිඹිබු වන පාර්ලිමේන්තුවක් ඇතිකර ගත යුතු බව දිසානායක මහතා එතෙක් නිශ්චිත කාලරාමුවක් සඳහා ජනතා විමුක්ති පෙරමුණ වෙත පැවරෙන වගකීම් භාරගන්නට සූදානම් බව ද කීවේය."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ජනතා විමුක්ති පෙරමුණ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "අනුර කුමාර දිසානායක",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "අනුර කුමාර මහත්තයා",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "තුනක් පමණි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "දිසානායක",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "\"நாட்டைக் கட்டுப்படுத்தத் தயார்\"",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "இந்த நேரத்தில் நாட்டின் அரசாங்கத்தை ஒப்படைத்தால் பொறுப்பேற்கத் தயார் என மக்கள் விடுதலை முன்னணியின் தலைவரும் நாடாளுமன்ற உறுப்பினருமான திரு அனுரகுமார திஸாநாயக்க இன்று தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "அநுரகுமார மஹத மேலும், 'நாங்கள் பொறுப்பை ஏற்கத் தயாராக உள்ளவர்கள், பயந்து எதையும் விட்டுச் செல்லாதவர்கள்' என்றும் குறிப்பிட்டார்.",
        "ஆனால், நாடாளுமன்றத்தில் மூன்று பிரதிநிதிகள் மட்டுமே இருப்பதால், ஜனாதிபதி மற்றும் பிரதமரின் மசோதாக்கள் நாடாளுமன்றத்தில் இருந்தால், வேறு யாராவது ஜனாதிபதி மற்றும் பிரதமராக வர வாய்ப்பு உள்ளது.",
        "மக்களின் விருப்பத்திற்கும் பாராளுமன்றத்திற்கும் இடையில் முரண்பாடு உருவாக்கப்பட்டுள்ளதால், மக்களின் விருப்பத்தை பிரதிபலிக்கும் பாராளுமன்றம் உருவாக்கப்பட வேண்டுமெனவும் திரு.திஸாநாயக்க தெரிவித்தார்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ஜனதா விமுக்தி பெரமுனா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "அனுரகுமார திஸாநாயக்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "அனுர குமார மஹத",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "மூன்று மட்டுமே",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "திசாநாயக்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}