{
  "newspaper_id": "economy-next-com",
  "url": "https://economynext.com/sri-lanka-petrol-price-hiked-to-rs470-a-litre-diesel-rs460-96454/",
  "time_ut": 1656207360,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Sri Lanka petrol price hiked to Rs470 a litre, diesel Rs460",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Sri Lanka petrol price hiked to Rs470 a litre, diesel Rs460",
      "author": "",
      "body_lines": [
        "ECONOMYNEXT – Sri Lanka has raised the petrol price to 470 rupees a litre by 50 rupees and auto diesel to 460 rupees a litre by 60 rupees an energy ministry official said as the country reels from fuel shortages amid money printing.",
        "Prices at both state-run Ceylon Petroleum Corporation and Lanka IOC has been raised by the same proportion.",
        "Petrol Octane 95 was raised by 100 rupees to 550 rupees a litre.",
        "Sri Lanka’s rupee has collapsed from 200 to 360 to the US dollar in the wake of a botched float with forced dollar sales to the central bank (surrender requirement) and forex shortages are persisting with continued money printing.",
        "Sri Lanka is now under severe fuel shortages with the country unable to find dollars to pay large import bills amid the liquidity injections. (Colombo/June26/2022)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Sri Lanka",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "470",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "50",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "460",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "60",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Ceylon Petroleum Corporation",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Petrol Octane",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "95",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "100",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "550",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka’s",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "200 to 360",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "US",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ පෙට්‍රල් ලීටරයක මිල රුපියල් 470 දක්වාත්, ඩීසල් රුපියල් 460 දක්වාත් ඉහළ නැංවීය",
      "author": "",
      "body_lines": [
        "ආර්ථිකය - මුදල් මුද්‍රණය මධ්‍යයේ රට ඉන්ධන හිඟයෙන් පෙළෙද්දී ශ්‍රී ලංකාව පෙට්‍රල් ලීටරයක මිල රුපියල් 470 දක්වා රුපියල් 50කින් සහ ඔටෝ ඩීසල් ලීටරයක් ​​රුපියල් 460 දක්වා රුපියල් 60කින් ඉහළ දමා ඇති බව බලශක්ති අමාත්‍යාංශයේ නිලධාරියෙක් පැවසීය.",
        "රජය විසින් පවත්වාගෙන යනු ලබන ලංකා ඛනිජ තෙල් නීතිගත සංස්ථාවේ සහ ලංකා IOC යන සමාගම් දෙකෙහිම මිල ගණන් එකම අනුපාතයකින් ඉහළ දමා ඇත.",
        "පෙට්‍රල් ඔක්ටේන් 95 ලීටරයක් ​​රුපියල් 550 දක්වා රුපියල් 100කින් ඉහළ දමා ඇත.",
        "මහ බැංකුවට බලහත්කාරයෙන් ඩොලර් විකිණීම (අවසන් කිරීමේ අවශ්‍යතාවය) සහ විදේශ විනිමය හිඟය අඛණ්ඩව මුදල් මුද්‍රණය කිරීමත් සමඟ අඛණ්ඩව පැවතීම හේතුවෙන් ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ රුපියල එක්සත් ජනපද ඩොලරයට 200 සිට 360 දක්වා පහත වැටී ඇත.",
        "ද්‍රවශීලතා එන්නත් මධ්‍යයේ විශාල ආනයන බිල්පත් ගෙවීමට ඩොලර් සොයා ගැනීමට නොහැකි වීමත් සමඟ ශ්‍රී ලංකාව දැන් දැඩි ඉන්ධන හිඟයකට මුහුණ දී සිටී. (කොළඹ/ජුනි26/2022)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "470",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "50",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "460",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "60",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ලංකා ඛනිජ තෙල් නීතිගත සංස්ථාව",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "පෙට්‍රල් ඔක්ටේන්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "95",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "100",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "550",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "200 සිට 360 දක්වා",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "එක්සත් ජනපදය",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "இலங்கையில் பெட்ரோல் விலை லிட்டருக்கு 470 ரூபாயாகவும், டீசல் விலை 460 ரூபாயாகவும் அதிகரித்துள்ளது",
      "author": "",
      "body_lines": [
        "பொருளாதாரம் - இலங்கையில் பெட்ரோல் விலை லிட்டருக்கு 470 ரூபாயாக 50 ரூபாவாலும், ஆட்டோ டீசல் 460 ரூபாயாக 60 ரூபாவாலும் உயர்த்தப்பட்டுள்ளதாக எரிசக்தி அமைச்சின் அதிகாரி ஒருவர் தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "அரச நிறுவனமான இலங்கை பெற்றோலியக் கூட்டுத்தாபனம் மற்றும் லங்கா ஐஓசி ஆகிய இரண்டின் விலைகளும் ஒரே விகிதத்தில் உயர்த்தப்பட்டுள்ளன.",
        "பெற்றோல் ஒக்டேன் 95 ஒரு லீற்றர் 100 ரூபாவால் 550 ரூபாவாக அதிகரிக்கப்பட்டுள்ளது.",
        "இலங்கையின் ரூபாயின் மதிப்பு அமெரிக்க டொலருக்கு 200 இலிருந்து 360 ஆக வீழ்ச்சியடைந்துள்ளது, மத்திய வங்கிக்கு (சரணடைதல் தேவை) மற்றும் அந்நிய செலாவணி தட்டுப்பாடு தொடர்ந்து பணம் அச்சடிப்பதன் மூலம் தொடர்ந்து வீழ்ச்சியடைந்துள்ளது.",
        "இலங்கை இப்போது கடுமையான எரிபொருள் பற்றாக்குறைக்கு உள்ளாகியுள்ளது, பணப்புழக்க ஊசிகளுக்கு மத்தியில் பெரிய இறக்குமதி கட்டணங்களைச் செலுத்துவதற்கு டாலர்களைக் கண்டுபிடிக்க முடியவில்லை. (கொழும்பு/ஜூன்26/2022)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "இலங்கை",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "470",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "50",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "460",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "60",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை பெற்றோலியக் கூட்டுத்தாபனம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பெட்ரோல் ஆக்டேன்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "95",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "100",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "550",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கையின்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "200 முதல் 360 வரை",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "எங்களுக்கு",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}