{
  "newspaper_id": "ada-lk",
  "url": "https://www.ada.lk/breaking_news/මන්නාරම-ධීවර-වාඩියකට-ගිනි-තැබීමෙන්-කෝටියක-පාඩුවක්/11-396382",
  "time_ut": 1660731508,
  "original_lang": "si",
  "original_title": "මන්නාරම ධීවර වාඩියකට ගිනි තැබීමෙන් කෝටියක පාඩුවක්",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "A loss of one crore due to the burning of a fishing village in Mannar",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "According to the Pesalai Police, the fishermen have suffered a loss of nearly one crore rupees due to a group of people setting fire to a fishing village in the Pesalai area of ​​Mannar last night (16th).",
        "Fishermen say that a group of people who suddenly came to the fishing lodge in Pesalai set it on fire and ran away.",
        "Also, 500 kilos of prawns, 800 kilos of prawns, over 100 kilos of fish and many nets caught by the fishermen have been completely destroyed by the fire.",
        "Before setting fire to the fishermen's wadis, there was a conflict between two groups of fishermen in the Pesalai area and it is also reported that the fishermen's wadis have been set on fire while a complaint is being investigated by the Pesalai Police.",
        "After the related fire, the affected fishermen have also submitted a complaint to the Mannar Senior Superintendent of Police and the Pesalai Police and the Mannar Police have started a comprehensive investigation to find the persons involved in the fire."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "one",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "Mannar",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "the Pesalai Police",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "nearly one",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Pesalai",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "last night",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "16th",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Pesalai",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "500",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "800",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "between two",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Pesalai",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Pesalai Police",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the Pesalai Police",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Mannar Police",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "මන්නාරම ධීවර වාඩියකට ගිනි තැබීමෙන් කෝටියක පාඩුවක්",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "මන්නාරම පේසාලෙයි ප්‍රදේශයේ පිහිටි ධීවර වාඩියකට ඊයේ (16දා) රාත්‍රියේ කිසියම් පිරිසක් විසින් ගිනිතබා පලායම හේතුවෙන් රුපියල් කෝටියකට ආසන්න අලාභයක් විඳීමට අදාල ධීවරයින්ට සිදුව ඇතැයි පේසාලෙයි පොලීසිය පවසයි.",
        "පේසාලෙයි ප්‍රදේශයේ පිහිටි අදාල ධීවර වාඩියට හදීසියේම පැමිණි නාදුනන පිරිසක ගිනිතබා පලා ගොස් ඇති අතර එම ගින්නෙන් ධීවර වාඩි 03 ක් සහ අලුත්ම බෝට්ටු එන්ජින් 03 ක් සම්පූරණයෙන්ම ගිනිගෙන විනාශ වී ඇති බවට ධීවරයින් පවසති.",
        "එමෙන්ම ධීවරයින් විසින් අල්ලන ලද කකුලුවන් කිලෝ 500 ක් , ඉස්සන් කිලෝ 800 ක් , මාලු කිලෝ 100 කට අධික, දැල් ආම්පන්න රැසක්ද ගින්නෙන් සම්පූරණයෙන්ම විනාශ වී ඇත.",
        "ධීවර වාඩිවලට ගිනිගැනීමට පෙරදී පේසාලෙයි ප්‍රදේශයේම ධීවරයින් දෙපිරිසක් අතර ගැටුමක් ඇති වී අදාල ගැටුම පිළිබඳව පේසාලෙයි පොලීසියේද පැමිණිල්ලක් විභාග වෙමින් පවතින අතරවාරයේදී මෙලෙස ධීවර වාඩිවලට ගිනිතබා ඇති බවටද වාර්ථා වෙයි.",
        "අදාල ගිනිතැබීමෙන් පසුව පීඩාවට පත් වූ ධීවරයින් විසින් මන්නාරම ජ්‍යේෂ්ඨ පොලිස් අධිකාරි කාර්යාලයටද පැමිණිල්ලක් ඉදිරිපත් කොට ඇති අතර ගිනිතැබූ පුද්ගලයින් සොයා මේ වන විට පේසාලෙයි පොලීසිය සහ මන්නාරම් පොලීසිය විසින් පුලුල් පරික්ෂණයක් අරඹා ඇත."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "එක",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "මන්නාරම",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "පේසාලේ පොලිසිය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ආසන්න වශයෙන් එකක්",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "පේසාලෙයි",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "අවසන් රාත්රිය",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "16 වැනි",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "පේසාලෙයි",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "500",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "800",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "දෙකක් අතර",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "පේසාලෙයි",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "පේසාලේ පොලිසිය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "පේසාලේ පොලිසිය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "මන්නාරම පොලිසිය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "மன்னாரில் மீனவ கிராமம் எரிந்ததால் ஒரு கோடி நஷ்டம்",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "மன்னார், பேசாலை பகுதியில் உள்ள மீனவ கிராமமொன்றுக்கு நேற்றிரவு (16) இரவு சிலர் தீ வைத்ததால் மீனவர்களுக்கு கிட்டத்தட்ட ஒரு கோடி ரூபா நஷ்டம் ஏற்பட்டுள்ளதாக பேசாலை பொலிஸார் தெரிவித்தனர்.",
        "பேசாலையில் உள்ள மீன்பிடி விடுதிக்கு திடீரென வந்த சிலர் தீ வைத்துவிட்டு ஓடியதாக மீனவர்கள் தெரிவிக்கின்றனர்.",
        "மேலும் மீனவர்களால் பிடிக்கப்பட்ட 500 கிலோ இறால், 800 கிலோ இறால், 100 கிலோவுக்கும் அதிகமான மீன்கள் மற்றும் பல வலைகள் முற்றாக எரிந்து நாசமாகியுள்ளன.",
        "மீனவர்களின் வாடிகளுக்கு தீ வைப்பதற்கு முன்னர் பேசாலை பிரதேசத்தில் மீனவர்கள் இரு குழுக்களுக்கிடையில் மோதல் ஏற்பட்டுள்ளதுடன் இது தொடர்பில் பேசாலை பொலிஸார் விசாரணைகளை மேற்கொண்டு வரும் நிலையில் மீனவர்களின் வாடிகள் தீ வைத்து எரிக்கப்பட்டுள்ளதாகவும் தெரிவிக்கப்படுகின்றது.",
        "இது தொடர்பான தீ விபத்தின் பின்னர் பாதிக்கப்பட்ட மீனவர்கள் மன்னார் சிரேஷ்ட பொலிஸ் அத்தியட்சகரிடம் முறைப்பாடு செய்ததோடு பேசாலை பொலிஸாருக்கும் மன்னார் பொலிஸார் தீவிபத்தில் ஈடுபட்டவர்களைக் கண்டறிய விரிவான விசாரணைகளை ஆரம்பித்துள்ளனர்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ஒன்று",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "மன்னார்",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "பேசாலை பொலிஸ்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "கிட்டத்தட்ட ஒன்று",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "பேசாலை",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "நேற்று இரவு",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "16வது",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பேசாலை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "500",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "800",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இரண்டு இடையே",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "பேசாலை",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "பேசாலை பொலிஸ்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பேசாலை பொலிஸ்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "மன்னார் காவல்துறை",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}