{
  "newspaper_id": "economy-next-com",
  "url": "https://economynext.com/crisis-hit-sri-lanka-to-supply-fertilizer-at-25-pct-cost-amid-looming-food-shortage-96956/",
  "time_ut": 1657016820,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Crisis-hit Sri Lanka to supply fertilizer at 25-pct cost amid looming food shortage",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Crisis-hit Sri Lanka to supply fertilizer at 25-pct cost amid looming food shortage",
      "author": "Neshella Perera",
      "body_lines": [
        "ECONOMYNEXT – Sri Lanka will supply fertilizer at 10,000 rupees per 50 kg bag for paddy cultivation, 25 percent of the original cost of 40,000 rupees as the crisis hit nation is trying to boost its rice production amid a looming food shortage after an ill-sighter fertilizer policy.",
        "Sri Lanka’s rice production has dropped sharply since President Gotabaya Rajapaksa banned chemical fertilizers in April last year. Agriculture Minister Mahinda Amaraweera said the rice production has fallen up to 40 percent in the last ‘Maha’ cultivation season ended in February this year.",
        "“Paddy farmers will be given fertilizer for 10,000 rupees and in the global market is selling it for 40,000 rupees,” Amaraweera, also a co-cabinet spokesman told a weekly cabinet media briefing on Tuesday (05).",
        "He also said corn cultivators and other crop producers will be also receiving the fertilizer at the same price in the future.",
        "Before the ban, the government had been providing a 50 kg fertilizer bag at 350 rupees. However, increased global prices and nearly 80% depreciation in the rupee currency against the US dollar have increased the import price of fertilizer.",
        "The lack of fertilizer application has forced the government to import rice from India and Myanmar. The shortage and looming food crisis have increased the prices to more than doubled. Rice is the staple food in the island nation.",
        "Rajapaksa stubbornly maintained the fertilizer ban policy despite many protests by farmers. He was forced to cancel the policy after the production of rice and vegetables started to fall in November. However, the government could not supply the required fertilizer to farmers due to dollar shortage.",
        "Sri Lanka brought an organic fertilizer shipment from China, however it was not approved Sri Lankan authorities because the supply did not meet the required standards.",
        "Later, the government imported nitrogen fertilizer from India, but farmers rejected it because of bad odour.",
        "Amaraweera said Sri Lanka will receive a shipment of 40,000 MT of chemical fertilizer on July 9, from Oman under the Indian Credit Line, this will be distributed to farmers. Another 25,000 MT is expected to be reach the country in the near future.",
        "The fertilizer will be used in the next Maha cultivation season starting in November this year, Amaraweera said adding that Sri Lanka will reach self-sufficiency and will no longer have to import rice.",
        "“We want the next Maha season to be successful and for all this to be carried out we have taken the relevant measures,” the Agriculture Minister said.",
        "He also said the paddy has been cultivated in 475,000 hectare land across the country in the on going Yala cultivation season, much higher than the expected 275,000 hectare. (Colombo/July 05/2022)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Sri Lanka",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "25",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "10,000",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "50 kg",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "25 percent",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "40,000",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka’s",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Gotabaya Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "April last year",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Mahinda Amaraweera",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "up to 40 percent",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "February this year",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "10,000",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "40,000",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Amaraweera",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "weekly",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Tuesday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "05",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "50 kg",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "350",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "nearly 80%",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "US",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "India",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Myanmar",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Rice",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "November",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "China",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lankan",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "India",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Amaraweera",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "40,000",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "MT",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "July 9",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Oman",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Indian Credit Line",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "25,000",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "MT",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "November this year",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Amaraweera",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Agriculture",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "475,000",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "275,000",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "අර්බුදකාරී ශ්‍රී ලංකාව ආහාර හිඟය මධ්‍යයේ සියයට 25 ක මිලකට පොහොර සැපයීමට",
      "author": "නෙෂෙල්ලා පෙරේරා",
      "body_lines": [
        "ආර්ථිකය - ශ්‍රී ලංකාව වී වගාව සඳහා කිලෝග්‍රෑම් 50 බෑගයකට රුපියල් 10,000 බැගින් පොහොර සපයනු ඇත, අර්බුදයට ගොදුරු වූ ජාතියේ මුල් පිරිවැය රුපියල් 40,000 න් සියයට 25 ක්, නොපෙනෙන පොහොරකින් පසු ඇති වන ආහාර හිඟයක් මධ්‍යයේ සහල් නිෂ්පාදනය ඉහළ නැංවීමට උත්සාහ කරයි. ප්රතිපත්ති.",
        "ජනාධිපති ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ මහතා පසුගිය වසරේ අප්‍රේල් මාසයේදී රසායනික පොහොර තහනම් කිරීමෙන් පසු ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ සහල් නිෂ්පාදනය තියුනු ලෙස පහත වැටී ඇත. කෘෂිකර්ම අමාත්‍ය මහින්ද අමරවීර මහතා පැවසුවේ, මේ වසරේ පෙබරවාරි මාසයේ අවසන් වූ පසුගිය ‘මහ’ වගා කන්නයේ සහල් නිෂ්පාදනය සියයට 40 දක්වා පහත වැටී ඇති බවයි.",
        "වී ගොවීන්ට රුපියල් 10,000ට පොහොර ලබා දෙන බවත්, ගෝලීය වෙළෙඳපොළේ එය රුපියල් 40,000කට අලෙවි කරන බවත් සම කැබිනට් ප්‍රකාශකයෙකු වන අමරවීර අඟහරුවාදා (05) සතිපතා පැවැත්වෙන කැබිනට් මාධ්‍ය හමුවේදී පැවසීය.",
        "ඉදිරියේදී බඩඉරිඟු වගාකරුවන්ට සහ අනෙකුත් බෝග නිෂ්පාදකයින්ට ද එම මිලටම පොහොර ලැබෙනු ඇති බව ද ඔහු පැවසීය.",
        "තහනමට පෙර රජය විසින් කිලෝග්‍රෑම් 50 පොහොර මිටියක් රුපියල් 350 කට ලබා දී ඇත. කෙසේ වෙතත්, ගෝලීය මිල ඉහළ යාම සහ එක්සත් ජනපද ඩොලරයට සාපේක්ෂව රුපියලේ මුදල 80% කට ආසන්න අවප්‍රමාණය වීම හේතුවෙන් පොහොර ආනයනික මිල ඉහළ ගොස් තිබේ.",
        "පොහොර යෙදීම ප්‍රමාණවත් නොවීම හේතුවෙන් ඉන්දියාවෙන් සහ මියන්මාරයෙන් සහල් ආනයනය කිරීමට රජයට සිදුව තිබේ. හිඟය සහ ආහාර අර්බුදය හේතුවෙන් මිල දෙගුණයකටත් වඩා වැඩි වී තිබේ. දිවයිනේ ප්‍රධාන ආහාරය බත් ය.",
        "ගොවීන්ගේ බොහෝ විරෝධතා නොතකා රාජපක්ෂ මුරණ්ඩු ලෙස පොහොර තහනම් ප්‍රතිපත්තිය පවත්වාගෙන ගියේය. නොවැම්බර් මාසයේදී සහල් සහ එළවළු නිෂ්පාදනය පහත වැටීමට පටන් ගැනීමෙන් පසුව ඔහුට එම ප්‍රතිපත්තිය අවලංගු කිරීමට සිදුවිය. නමුත් ඩොලර් හිඟය නිසා ගොවීන්ට අවශ්‍ය පොහොර ලබාදීමට රජයට නොහැකි වුණා.",
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකාව චීනයෙන් කාබනික පොහොර තොගයක් ගෙන ආ නමුත් සැපයුම නියමිත ප්‍රමිතීන්ට අනුකූල නොවීම නිසා ශ්‍රී ලංකා බලධාරීන් එය අනුමත නොකළේය.",
        "පසුව රජය විසින් ඉන්දියාවෙන් නයිට්‍රජන් පොහොර ආනයනය කළ නමුත් දුර්ගන්ධය නිසා ගොවීන් එය ප්‍රතික්ෂේප කළේය.",
        "ඉන්දීය ණය රේඛාව යටතේ ඕමානයෙන් ජුලි 9 වැනිදා ශ්‍රී ලංකාවට රසායනික පොහොර මෙට්‍රික් ටොන් 40,000ක නැව්ගත කිරීමක් ලැබෙනු ඇති බවත්, මෙය ගොවීන් වෙත බෙදා හරින බවත් අමරවීර පැවසීය. නුදුරු අනාගතයේදී තවත් මෙට්‍රික් ටොන් 25,000ක් මෙරටට පැමිණීමට අපේක්ෂා කෙරේ.",
        "මේ වසරේ නොවැම්බරයේදී ආරම්භ වන මීළඟ මහ වගා කන්නයේ දී මෙම පොහොර භාවිත කරන බවත්, ශ්‍රී ලංකාව ස්වයංපෝෂිත වන බවත් තවදුරටත් සහල් ආනයනය කිරීමට සිදු නොවන බවත් අමරවීර මහතා පැවසීය.",
        "ඉදිරි මහ කන්නය සාර්ථක කර ගැනීමට අවශ්‍ය බවත් මේ සියල්ල සිදු කිරීමට අපි අදාළ ක්‍රියාමාර්ග ගෙන ඇති බවත් කෘෂිකර්ම අමාත්‍යවරයා පැවසීය.",
        "ඉදිරි යල වගා කන්නයේ දී රට පුරා හෙක්ටයාර් 475,000 ක වී වගා කර ඇති බවත් එය අපේක්ෂිත හෙක්ටයාර 275,000 ට වඩා බෙහෙවින් වැඩි බවත් ඔහු පැවසීය. (කොළඹ/ජූලි 05/2022)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "25",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "10,000 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "කිලෝ ග්රෑම් 50 කි",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "සියයට 25 කි",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "40,000 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "පසුගිය වසරේ අප්රේල්",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මහින්ද අමරවීර",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "සියයට 40 දක්වා",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "මේ වසරේ පෙබරවාරි",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "10,000 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "40,000 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "අමරවීර",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "සතිපතා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "අඟහරුවාදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "05",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "කිලෝ ග්රෑම් 50 කි",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "350",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ආසන්න වශයෙන් 80%",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "එක්සත් ජනපදය",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මියන්මාරය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "සහල්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "නොවැම්බර්",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "චීනය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලාංකික",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "අමරවීර",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "40,000 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "එම්.ටී",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජූලි 9",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඕමානය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දියානු ණය රේඛාව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "25,000 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "එම්.ටී",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "මේ වසරේ නොවැම්බර්",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "අමරවීර",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "කෘෂිකර්ම",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "475,000 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "275,000 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "நெருக்கடியில் சிக்கித் தவிக்கும் இலங்கை உணவுப் பற்றாக்குறைக்கு மத்தியில் 25 சதவீத விலையில் உரத்தை வழங்க உள்ளது",
      "author": "நெஷெல்லா பெரேரா",
      "body_lines": [
        "பொருளாதாரம் - நெல் சாகுபடிக்கு 50 கிலோ மூட்டை ஒன்றுக்கு 10,000 ரூபாய் என்ற விலையில் இலங்கை உரத்தை வழங்கும், நெருக்கடியால் பாதிக்கப்பட்ட தேசம் தனது அரிசி உற்பத்தியை அதிகரிக்க முயற்சித்து வரும் நிலையில், அதன் அசல் செலவான 40,000 ரூபாயில் 25 சதவீதம், மோசமான உரத்தின் பின்னர், உணவுப் பற்றாக்குறையை அதிகரித்து வருகிறது. கொள்கை.",
        "ஜனாதிபதி கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ச கடந்த ஆண்டு ஏப்ரல் மாதம் இரசாயன உரங்களுக்கு தடை விதித்ததன் பின்னர் இலங்கையின் அரிசி உற்பத்தி வெகுவாகக் குறைந்துள்ளது. இந்த வருடம் பெப்ரவரி மாதம் முடிவடைந்த கடந்த ‘மஹா’ பயிர்ச்செய்கைப் பருவத்தில் அரிசி உற்பத்தி 40 வீதமாக வீழ்ச்சியடைந்துள்ளதாக விவசாய அமைச்சர் மஹிந்த அமரவீர தெரிவித்துள்ளார்.",
        "“நெல் விவசாயிகளுக்கு 10,000 ரூபாய்க்கு உரம் வழங்கப்படும், உலக சந்தையில் 40,000 ரூபாய்க்கு விற்கப்படுகிறது” என அமைச்சரவை இணைப் பேச்சாளரான அமரவீர செவ்வாய்க்கிழமை (05) வாராந்த அமைச்சரவை ஊடகவியலாளர் சந்திப்பில் தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "சோளம் பயிரிடுபவர்கள் மற்றும் பிற பயிர் உற்பத்தியாளர்களும் எதிர்காலத்தில் அதே விலையில் உரங்களைப் பெறுவார்கள் என்றும் அவர் கூறினார்.",
        "தடைக்கு முன்னர் அரசாங்கம் 50 கிலோ உரமூட்டை 350 ரூபாவிற்கு வழங்கி வந்தது. எவ்வாறாயினும், உலகளாவிய விலை அதிகரிப்பு மற்றும் அமெரிக்க டொலருக்கு நிகரான ரூபாயின் பெறுமதி கிட்டத்தட்ட 80% வீழ்ச்சியினால் உரத்தின் இறக்குமதி விலை அதிகரித்துள்ளது.",
        "உர பயன்பாடு இல்லாததால், இந்தியா மற்றும் மியான்மரில் இருந்து அரிசியை இறக்குமதி செய்ய வேண்டிய கட்டாயம் அரசுக்கு ஏற்பட்டுள்ளது. தட்டுப்பாடு மற்றும் உணவு நெருக்கடியால் விலை இருமடங்காக அதிகரித்துள்ளது. தீவு நாட்டில் அரிசி பிரதான உணவாகும்.",
        "விவசாயிகளின் பல எதிர்ப்புகளையும் மீறி உரத்தடை கொள்கையை ராஜபக்சே பிடிவாதமாக கடைப்பிடித்தார். நவம்பரில் அரிசி மற்றும் காய்கறிகளின் உற்பத்தி வீழ்ச்சியடையத் தொடங்கியதை அடுத்து அவர் பாலிசியை ரத்து செய்ய வேண்டிய கட்டாயம் ஏற்பட்டது. ஆனால், டாலர் தட்டுப்பாடு காரணமாக விவசாயிகளுக்கு தேவையான உரத்தை அரசால் வழங்க முடியவில்லை.",
        "இலங்கை சீனாவில் இருந்து ஒரு கரிம உரக் கப்பலைக் கொண்டு வந்தது, இருப்பினும் வழங்கல் தேவையான தரத்தை பூர்த்தி செய்யாததால் இலங்கை அதிகாரிகளால் அங்கீகரிக்கப்படவில்லை.",
        "பின்னர், அரசாங்கம் இந்தியாவில் இருந்து நைட்ரஜன் உரத்தை இறக்குமதி செய்தது, ஆனால் துர்நாற்றம் காரணமாக விவசாயிகள் அதை நிராகரித்தனர்.",
        "இந்திய கடன் வரியின் கீழ் ஓமானில் இருந்து ஜூலை 9 ஆம் தேதி இலங்கைக்கு 40,000 மெட்ரிக் டன் இரசாயன உரம் ஏற்றுமதி செய்யப்படும் என்றும், இது விவசாயிகளுக்கு விநியோகிக்கப்படும் என்றும் அமரவீர கூறினார். மேலும் 25,000 மெட்ரிக் டன் எதிர்காலத்தில் நாட்டை வந்தடையும் என்று எதிர்பார்க்கப்படுகிறது.",
        "இந்த ஆண்டு நவம்பர் மாதம் முதல் அடுத்த மகா பயிர்ச்செய்கை பருவத்தில் இந்த உரம் பயன்படுத்தப்படும் என்றும், இலங்கை தன்னிறைவு அடையும் என்றும், இனி அரிசியை இறக்குமதி செய்ய வேண்டியதில்லை என்றும் அமரவீர கூறினார்.",
        "“அடுத்த மகா பருவம் வெற்றியடைய வேண்டும் என்று நாங்கள் விரும்புகிறோம், இவை அனைத்தும் நிறைவேற்றப்படுவதற்கு நாங்கள் உரிய நடவடிக்கைகளை எடுத்துள்ளோம்,” என்று விவசாய அமைச்சர் கூறினார்.",
        "தற்போது நடந்து வரும் யாலா பயிர்ச்செய்கை பருவத்தில் நாடு முழுவதும் 475,000 ஹெக்டேர் நிலத்தில் நெல் பயிரிடப்பட்டுள்ளது, இது எதிர்பார்த்த 275,000 ஹெக்டேரை விட அதிகமாகும். (கொழும்பு/ஜூலை 05/2022)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "இலங்கை",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "25",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "10,000",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "50 கிலோ",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "25 சதவீதம்",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "40,000",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கையின்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "கடந்த ஆண்டு ஏப்ரல்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "மஹிந்த அமரவீர",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "40 சதவீதம் வரை",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்த ஆண்டு பிப்ரவரி",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "10,000",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "40,000",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "அமரவீர",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "வாரந்தோறும்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "செவ்வாய்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "05",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "50 கிலோ",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "350",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "கிட்டத்தட்ட 80%",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "எங்களுக்கு",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இந்தியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "மியான்மர்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "அரிசி",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ராஜபக்சே",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "நவம்பர்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சீனா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இந்தியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "அமரவீர",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "40,000",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "எம்டி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜூலை 9",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஓமன்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்திய கடன் வரி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "25,000",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "எம்டி",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இந்த ஆண்டு நவம்பர்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "அமரவீர",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "வேளாண்மை",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "475,000",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "275,000",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}