{
  "newspaper_id": "d-b-s-jeyaraj-com",
  "url": "https://dbsjeyaraj.com/dbsj/archives/78978",
  "time_ut": 1660330620,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Sri Lanka  Grants Permission for  Chinese space and satellite tracking vessel “Yuan Wang 5” to dock  on August 16 at  Hambantota port subject to conditions that the visiting Chinese vessel’s Automatic Identification System (AIS) must  be kept switched on within the EEZ of Sri Lanka and that no scientific research be conducted in Sri Lankan waters.",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Sri Lanka  Grants Permission for  Chinese space and satellite tracking vessel “Yuan Wang 5” to dock  on August 16 at  Hambantota port subject to conditions that the visiting Chinese vessel’s Automatic Identification System (AIS) must  be kept switched on within the EEZ of Sri Lanka and that no scientific research be conducted in Sri Lankan waters.",
      "author": "Administrator",
      "body_lines": [
        "Sri Lanka on Saturday cleared the arrival of Chinese space and satellite tracking vessel Yuan Wang 5 on August 16 at the southern Hambantota port, a day after New Delhi reiterated its security concerns over the vessel’s visit earlier scheduled on August 11.",
        "Even as Colombo was put on a delicate diplomatic spot, dealing with two of its close partners with competing geostrategic interests in the island, Sri Lanka’s fresh approval, announced by its Ministry of Foreign Affairs in a statement, effectively points to a five-day postponement of the arrival of the Chinese ship, and a week’s stop as was earlier planned.",
        "The Ministry said it held “extensive consultations” at a high level through diplomatic channels with “all parties” concerned, with a view to resolving the matter in a spirit of “friendship, mutual trust and constructive dialogue, taking into account the interests of all parties concerned”. While it said the developments were “in light of certain concerns raised with the Ministry”, it stopped short of naming India in its statement. “Having considered all material in place, on 13 August 2022 the clearance to the Embassy of the People’s Republic of China was conveyed for the deferred arrival of the vessel from 16-22 August 2022,” the Ministry said, confirming the development, and the duration of the vessel to be berthed at the southern Hambantota Port.",
        "Further, the Ministry stated that when it had cleared the scheduled visit earlier in July, it was based on the Defence Ministry’s conditions that the visiting Chinese vessel’s Automatic Identification System (AIS) be kept switched on within the EEZ of Sri Lanka and that no scientific research be conducted in Sri Lankan waters.",
        "The development comes after New Delhi raised the matter with President Ranil Wickremesinghe, and made public remarks twice at the Ministry of External Affairs’s weekly briefing on July 28, and more recently, on Friday. India “carefully monitors any development having a bearing on its security and economic interests”, MEA spokesperson Arindam Bagchi earlier said, and on Friday “rejected insinuations” that Sri Lanka was “pressured”. New Delhi’s remarks came days after China asked India to “not disturb normal exchanges” between Sri Lanka and China, and termed India’s security concerns over the vessel visit “senseless”.",
        "Meanwhile, the Indian Air force has gifted a Dornier 228 Maritime Patrol Aircraft to the Sri Lankan Air Force (SLAF), and another aircraft is to be donated within two years, SLAF has said. The aircraft is expected to be handed over in a formal ceremony on August 15, in the presence of Mr. Wickremesinghe. The gesture, according to the SLAF, was in response to a request made by the Sri Lankan government to India in 2018 for two Dornier reconnaissance aircrafts to enhance the island’s maritime surveillance capabilities.",
        "In March this year, Sri Lanka’s Defence Ministry announced signing of two maritime pacts with India, through which Sri Lanka was to receive a Floating Dock Facility and a Dornier reconnaissance aircraft at no cost. The agreements “will not result in hindrance or threat to the national security of Sri Lanka,” the Defence Ministry then said, amid criticism from the political opposition over the apparent secrecy of the agreements, signed without any official announcement."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Sri Lanka",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "Chinese",
          "label": "NORP"
        },
        {
          "text": "Yuan Wang",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "August 16",
          "label": "DATE"
        },
        {
          "text": "Hambantota",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "Chinese",
          "label": "NORP"
        },
        {
          "text": "Automatic Identification System",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "AIS",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "Sri Lanka",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "Sri Lankan",
          "label": "LOC"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Saturday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Chinese",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Yuan Wang",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "August 16",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Hambantota",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "a day",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "New Delhi",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "August 11",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Colombo",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "two",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka’s",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ministry of Foreign Affairs",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "five-day",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Chinese",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "week",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "The Ministry",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "India",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "13 August 2022",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the People’s Republic of China",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "16-22",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "August 2022",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Hambantota Port",
            "label": "FAC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "earlier in July",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Defence Ministry’s",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Chinese",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Automatic Identification System",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "AIS",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lankan",
            "label": "LOC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "New Delhi",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Ministry of External Affairs’s",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "weekly",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "July 28",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Friday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "India",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Arindam Bagchi",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Friday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "New Delhi’s",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "China",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "India",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "China",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "India",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the Indian Air",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Sri Lankan Air Force",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "two years",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "SLAF",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "August 15",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "SLAF",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lankan",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "India",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "2018",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "two",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "March this year",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka’s",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Defence Ministry",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "two",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "India",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "a Floating Dock Facility and a Dornier",
            "label": "WORK_OF_ART"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Defence Ministry",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "චීන අභ්‍යවකාශ සහ චන්ද්‍රිකා ලුහුබැඳීමේ යාත්‍රාවක් වන “යුවාන් වැන්ග් 5” අගෝස්තු 16 වැනිදා හම්බන්තොට වරායේ නැව්ගත කිරීමට ශ්‍රී ලංකාව අවසර දෙයි ශ්‍රී ලංකා මුහුදේ කිසිදු විද්‍යාත්මක පර්යේෂණයක් සිදු නොකළ යුතු බව.",
      "author": "පරිපාලක",
      "body_lines": [
        "චීනයේ අභ්‍යවකාශ සහ චන්ද්‍රිකා ලුහුබැඳීමේ යාත්‍රාව වන යුවාන් වැන්ග් 5 අගෝස්තු 16 වන දින දකුණු හම්බන්තොට වරායට පැමිණීම ශ්‍රී ලංකාව සෙනසුරාදා නිෂ්කාශනය කරන ලදී, අගෝස්තු 11 දිනට නියමිත යාත්‍රාවේ සංචාරය පිළිබඳව නවදිල්ලිය සිය ආරක්ෂක ගැටළු නැවත අවධාරණය කිරීමෙන් දිනකට පසුවය.",
        "දිවයිනේ තරඟකාරී භූ මූලෝපායික අවශ්‍යතා සමඟ එහි සමීප හවුල්කරුවන් දෙදෙනෙකු සමඟ කටයුතු කරමින් කොළඹ සියුම් රාජ්‍ය තාන්ත්‍රික ස්ථානයකට පත් කර තිබියදීත්, විදේශ කටයුතු අමාත්‍යාංශය නිවේදනයක් නිකුත් කරමින් ප්‍රකාශයට පත් කරන ලද ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ නැවුම් අනුමැතිය, දින පහක කල් දැමීමක් ඵලදායී ලෙස පෙන්වා දෙයි. චීන නෞකාව පැමිණීම සහ කලින් සැලසුම් කළ පරිදි සතියක නැවතුම.",
        "“සියලු දෙනාගේම අවශ්‍යතා සැලකිල්ලට ගනිමින් මිත්‍රත්වය, අන්‍යෝන්‍ය විශ්වාසය සහ නිර්මාණාත්මක සංවාදයේ ආත්මයෙන් ප්‍රශ්නය විසඳීමේ අදහසින්, අදාළ “සියලු පාර්ශවයන්” සමඟ රාජ්‍ය තාන්ත්‍රික මාර්ග හරහා ඉහළ මට්ටමින් “පුළුල් උපදේශන” පැවැත්වූ බව අමාත්‍යාංශය පවසයි. අදාළ පාර්ශවයන්.\" මෙම වර්ධනයන් “අමාත්‍යාංශය සමඟ මතු කරන ලද යම් යම් උත්සුකයන් මත” බව එය පැවසුවද, එය සිය ප්‍රකාශයේ ඉන්දියාව නම් කිරීම නතර කළේය. \"සියලු කරුණු සලකා බලා, 2022 අගෝස්තු 13 වන දින, 2022 අගෝස්තු 16-22 දින දක්වා කල් දැමූ යාත්‍රාව පැමිණීම සඳහා චීන මහජන සමූහාණ්ඩුවේ තානාපති කාර්යාලයට නිෂ්කාශනය දන්වා ඇත,\" අමාත්‍යාංශය සංවර්ධනය තහවුරු කරමින් පැවසීය. දකුණු හම්බන්තොට වරායේ නැංගුරම් ලෑමට නියමිත යාත්‍රාවේ කාලසීමාව.",
        "තවද, එම අමාත්‍යාංශය ප්‍රකාශ කළේ ජුලි මස මුලදී නියමිත සංචාරය නිෂ්කාශනය කළ විට, සංචාරය කරන චීන යාත්‍රාවේ ස්වයංක්‍රීය හඳුනාගැනීමේ පද්ධතිය (AIS) ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ EEZ තුළ ක්‍රියාත්මක කළ යුතු බවට ආරක්ෂක අමාත්‍යාංශයේ කොන්දේසි මත පදනම් වූ බවත් කිසිදු විද්‍යාත්මක නොවන බවත්ය. ශ්‍රී ලංකා මුහුදේ පර්යේෂණ සිදු කළ යුතුයි.",
        "නවදිල්ලිය විසින් මෙම කාරණය ජනාධිපති රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ වෙත ඉදිරිපත් කිරීමෙන් පසුව, ජූලි 28 වැනි දින විදේශ කටයුතු අමාත්‍යාංශයේ සතිපතා සාකච්ඡාවේදී සහ වඩාත් මෑතකදී සිකුරාදා ප්‍රසිද්ධියේ ප්‍රකාශ කිරීම දෙවරක් සිදු කිරීමෙන් පසුව මෙම වර්ධනය සිදු විය. ඉන්දියාව “සිය ආරක්‍ෂාව සහ ආර්ථික අවශ්‍යතා කෙරෙහි බලපාන ඕනෑම වර්ධනයක් ප්‍රවේශමෙන් නිරීක්‍ෂණය කරයි”, MEA ප්‍රකාශක Arindam Bagchi මීට පෙර ප්‍රකාශ කළ අතර සිකුරාදා ශ්‍රී ලංකාව “පීඩනයට” ලක්ව ඇති බවට “ඉංග්‍රීසියෙන්” ප්‍රතික්ෂේප කළේය. ශ්‍රී ලංකාව සහ චීනය අතර “සාමාන්‍ය හුවමාරුවලට බාධා නොකරන ලෙස” චීනය ඉන්දියාවෙන් ඉල්ලා දින කිහිපයකට පසුව නව දිල්ලියේ ප්‍රකාශය සිදු වූ අතර, යාත්‍රා සංචාරය සම්බන්ධයෙන් ඉන්දියාවේ ආරක්ෂක උත්සුකයන් “අඥාන” ලෙස හැඳින්වීය.",
        "මේ අතර ඉන්දීය ගුවන් හමුදාව විසින් ඩෝනියර් 228 සමුද්‍රීය මුර සංචාර ගුවන් යානයක් ශ්‍රී ලංකා ගුවන් හමුදාවට (ශ්‍රී ලංකා ගුවන් හමුදාවට) තිළිණ කර ඇති අතර තවත් ගුවන් යානයක් වසර දෙකක් ඇතුළත පරිත්‍යාග කිරීමට නියමිත බව ගුවන් හමුදාව පවසයි. වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතා ඉදිරියේ අගෝස්තු 15 වැනිදා විධිමත් උත්සවයකින් යානය භාරදීමට නියමිතය. ශ්‍රී ලංකා ගුවන් හමුදාවට අනුව, මෙම අභිනය, දිවයිනේ සමුද්‍ර නිරීක්ෂණ හැකියාවන් වැඩි දියුණු කිරීම සඳහා ඩෝනියර් ඔත්තු බැලීමේ ගුවන් යානා දෙකක් සඳහා ශ්‍රී ලංකා රජය 2018 දී ඉන්දියාවට කරන ලද ඉල්ලීමකට ප්‍රතිචාර දක්වයි.",
        "මෙම වසරේ මාර්තු මාසයේදී, ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ ආරක්ෂක අමාත්‍යාංශය ඉන්දියාව සමඟ සමුද්‍ර ගිවිසුම් දෙකක් අත්සන් කරන බව නිවේදනය කළ අතර, ඒ හරහා ශ්‍රී ලංකාවට පාවෙන තටාක පහසුකමක් සහ ඩෝනියර් ඔත්තු බැලීමේ ගුවන් යානයක් කිසිදු වියදමකින් තොරව ලැබෙනු ඇත. ගිවිසුම් \"ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ ජාතික ආරක්ෂාවට බාධාවක් හෝ තර්ජනයක් ඇති නොකරනු ඇත\" යනුවෙන් ආරක්ෂක අමාත්‍යාංශය පසුව ප්‍රකාශ කළේ, කිසිදු නිල ප්‍රකාශයකින් තොරව අත්සන් කරන ලද ගිවිසුම්වල රහස්‍යභාවය පිළිබඳ දේශපාලන විපක්ෂයේ විවේචන මධ්‍යයේ ය."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "චීන",
          "label": "NORP"
        },
        {
          "text": "Yuan Wang",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "අගෝස්තු 16",
          "label": "DATE"
        },
        {
          "text": "හම්බන්තොට",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "චීන",
          "label": "NORP"
        },
        {
          "text": "ස්වයංක්‍රීය හඳුනාගැනීමේ පද්ධතිය",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "AIS",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "ශ්‍රී ලාංකික",
          "label": "LOC"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "සෙනසුරාදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "චීන",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Yuan Wang",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "අගෝස්තු 16",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "හම්බන්තොට",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "දවසක්",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "නව දිල්ලි",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "අගෝස්තු 11",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "කොළඹ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "දෙක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "විදේශ කටයුතු අමාත්යංශය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "දින පහක්",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "චීන",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "සතිය",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "අමාත්යාංශය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "2022 අගෝස්තු 13",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මහජන චීන සමූහාණ්ඩුව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "16-22",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "2022 අගෝස්තු",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "හම්බන්තොට වරාය",
            "label": "FAC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "කලින් ජූලි මාසයේදී",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ආරක්ෂක අමාත්‍යාංශයේ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "චීන",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ස්වයංක්‍රීය හඳුනාගැනීමේ පද්ධතිය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "AIS",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලාංකික",
            "label": "LOC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "නව දිල්ලි",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "විදේශ කටයුතු අමාත්‍යාංශයේ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "සතිපතා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජූලි 28",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "සිකුරාදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Arindam Bagchi",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "සිකුරාදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "නවදිල්ලියේ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "චීනය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "චීනය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දියානු ගුවන්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකා ගුවන් හමුදාව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "අවුරුදු දෙකක්",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගුවන් හමුදා",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "අගෝස්තු 15",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගුවන් හමුදා",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලාංකික",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "2018",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "දෙක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "මේ වසරේ මාර්තු",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ආරක්ෂක අමාත්යාංශය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "දෙක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාවෙන තටාක පහසුකම සහ ඩෝනියර්",
            "label": "WORK_OF_ART"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ආරක්ෂක අමාත්යාංශය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "சீன விண்வெளி மற்றும் செயற்கைக்கோள் கண்காணிப்பு கப்பலான “யுவான் வாங் 5” ஆகஸ்ட் 16 ஆம் தேதி அம்பாந்தோட்டை துறைமுகத்தில் நிறுத்துவதற்கு இலங்கை அனுமதி வழங்கியுள்ளது. இலங்கைக் கடற்பரப்பில் அறிவியல் ஆய்வுகள் நடத்தப்படக்கூடாது.",
      "author": "நிர்வாகி",
      "body_lines": [
        "ஆகஸ்ட் 11 ஆம் தேதி முன்னதாக திட்டமிடப்பட்ட கப்பலின் வருகை குறித்து புது தில்லி தனது பாதுகாப்புக் கவலைகளை மீண்டும் வலியுறுத்திய ஒரு நாளுக்குப் பிறகு, ஆகஸ்ட் 16 அன்று தெற்கு ஹம்பாந்தோட்டை துறைமுகத்தில் சீன விண்வெளி மற்றும் செயற்கைக்கோள் கண்காணிப்பு கப்பலான யுவான் வாங் 5 வருகையை இலங்கை சனிக்கிழமை அனுமதித்தது.",
        "தீவில் போட்டியிடும் புவி மூலோபாய நலன்களுடன் அதன் நெருங்கிய பங்காளிகள் இருவருடன் கொழும்பை ஒரு நுட்பமான இராஜதந்திர இடத்தில் வைத்து, இலங்கையின் புதிய ஒப்புதல், அதன் வெளிவிவகார அமைச்சினால் அறிவிக்கப்பட்டது, ஐந்து நாட்களுக்கு ஒத்திவைக்கப்படுவதை திறம்பட சுட்டிக்காட்டுகிறது. சீனக் கப்பலின் வருகை, மற்றும் முன்பு திட்டமிட்டபடி ஒரு வாரம் நிறுத்தம்.",
        "“நட்பு, பரஸ்பர நம்பிக்கை மற்றும் ஆக்கபூர்வமான உரையாடல், அனைவரின் நலன்களையும் கருத்தில் கொண்டு, இந்த விவகாரத்தை தீர்க்கும் நோக்கில், சம்பந்தப்பட்ட “அனைத்து தரப்பினருடனும்” இராஜதந்திர வழிகள் மூலம் உயர் மட்டத்தில் “விரிவான ஆலோசனைகளை” நடத்தியதாக அமைச்சகம் கூறியது. சம்பந்தப்பட்ட கட்சிகள்.\" \"அமைச்சகத்துடன் எழுப்பப்பட்ட சில கவலைகளின் வெளிச்சத்தில்\" முன்னேற்றங்கள் என்று அது கூறியிருந்தாலும், அது தனது அறிக்கையில் இந்தியாவின் பெயரைக் குறிப்பிடுவதை நிறுத்தியது. \"அனைத்து பொருட்களையும் கருத்தில் கொண்டு, ஆகஸ்ட் 13, 2022 அன்று, சீன மக்கள் குடியரசின் தூதரகத்திற்கு 16-22 ஆகஸ்ட் 2022 வரை கப்பல் தாமதமாக வருவதற்கு அனுமதி வழங்கப்பட்டது,\" என்று அமைச்சகம் கூறியது, வளர்ச்சியை உறுதிப்படுத்தியது, மற்றும் தெற்கு ஹம்பாந்தோட்டை துறைமுகத்தில் நிறுத்தப்படும் கப்பலின் காலம்.",
        "மேலும், ஜூலையில் திட்டமிடப்பட்ட பயணத்தை அனுமதித்தபோது, ​​பாதுகாப்பு அமைச்சின் நிபந்தனைகளின் அடிப்படையில், வருகை தரும் சீனக் கப்பலின் தானியங்கி அடையாள அமைப்பு (AIS) இலங்கையின் EEZ க்குள் சுவிட்ச் ஆன் செய்யப்பட்டிருக்க வேண்டும் என்றும் அது அறிவியல் பூர்வமாக இல்லை என்றும் அமைச்சகம் கூறியது. இலங்கை கடற்பரப்பில் ஆய்வு நடத்தப்பட வேண்டும்.",
        "புதுடெல்லி ஜனாதிபதி ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்கவிடம் இந்த விடயத்தை எழுப்பிய பின்னர், வெளிவிவகார அமைச்சின் வாராந்திர மாநாட்டில் ஜூலை 28 மற்றும் சமீபத்தில் வெள்ளிக்கிழமை இரண்டு முறை பகிரங்கக் கருத்துக்களை வெளியிட்ட பின்னர் இந்த வளர்ச்சி ஏற்பட்டுள்ளது. இந்தியா \"தனது பாதுகாப்பு மற்றும் பொருளாதார நலன்களில் தாக்கத்தை ஏற்படுத்தும் எந்தவொரு வளர்ச்சியையும் கவனமாகக் கண்காணிக்கிறது\" என்று MEA செய்தித் தொடர்பாளர் அரிந்தம் பாக்சி முன்பு கூறியதுடன், வெள்ளிக்கிழமை இலங்கை \"அழுத்தத்திற்கு உள்ளானது\" என்று \"நிராகரித்தது\". இலங்கைக்கும் சீனாவிற்கும் இடையிலான \"சாதாரண பரிமாற்றங்களைத் தொந்தரவு செய்ய வேண்டாம்\" என்று சீனா இந்தியாவைக் கேட்டுக்கொண்ட சில நாட்களுக்குப் பிறகு புதுடெல்லியின் கருத்துக்கள் வந்தன, மேலும் கப்பல் வருகை குறித்த இந்தியாவின் பாதுகாப்பு கவலைகள் \"புத்தியற்றது\" என்று கூறியது.",
        "இதற்கிடையில், இந்திய விமானப்படை இலங்கை விமானப்படைக்கு (SLAF) டோர்னியர் 228 கடல்சார் ரோந்து விமானத்தை பரிசாக வழங்கியுள்ளது, மேலும் இரண்டு ஆண்டுகளுக்குள் மற்றொரு விமானம் நன்கொடையாக வழங்கப்படும் என்று விமானப்படை தெரிவித்துள்ளது. விக்கிரமசிங்க முன்னிலையில் ஆகஸ்ட் 15 ஆம் தேதி முறையான விழாவில் விமானம் ஒப்படைக்கப்படும் என்று எதிர்பார்க்கப்படுகிறது. 2018 ஆம் ஆண்டு இலங்கை அரசாங்கம் இரண்டு டோர்னியர் உளவு விமானங்கள் தீவின் கடல்சார் கண்காணிப்பு திறன்களை மேம்படுத்துவதற்காக இந்தியாவிடம் விடுத்த கோரிக்கைக்கு பதிலளிக்கும் வகையில் இந்த சைகை, SLAF தெரிவித்துள்ளது.",
        "இந்த ஆண்டு மார்ச் மாதம், இலங்கையின் பாதுகாப்பு அமைச்சகம் இந்தியாவுடன் இரண்டு கடல்சார் ஒப்பந்தங்களில் கையெழுத்திடுவதாக அறிவித்தது, இதன் மூலம் இலங்கைக்கு மிதக்கும் கப்பல் வசதி மற்றும் டோர்னியர் உளவு விமானம் செலவில்லாமல் கிடைக்கும். இந்த ஒப்பந்தங்கள் \"இலங்கையின் தேசிய பாதுகாப்பிற்கு இடையூறாகவோ அல்லது அச்சுறுத்தலையோ ஏற்படுத்தாது\" என்று பாதுகாப்பு அமைச்சு பின்னர் கூறியது, இந்த ஒப்பந்தங்களின் வெளிப்படையான இரகசியத்தன்மை குறித்த அரசியல் எதிர்ப்பின் விமர்சனங்களுக்கு மத்தியில், எந்த உத்தியோகபூர்வ அறிவிப்பும் இன்றி கையொப்பமிடப்பட்டது."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "இலங்கை",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "சீன",
          "label": "NORP"
        },
        {
          "text": "Yuan Wang",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "ஆகஸ்ட் 16",
          "label": "DATE"
        },
        {
          "text": "ஹம்பாந்தோட்டை",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "சீன",
          "label": "NORP"
        },
        {
          "text": "தானியங்கி அடையாள அமைப்பு",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "AIS",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "இலங்கை",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "இலங்கை",
          "label": "LOC"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சனிக்கிழமை",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சீன",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Yuan Wang",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆகஸ்ட் 16",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஹம்பாந்தோட்டை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஒரு நாள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "புது தில்லி",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆகஸ்ட் 11",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "கொழும்பு",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இரண்டு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கையின்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "வெளிநாட்டு அலுவல்கள் அமைச்சு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஐந்து நாள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சீன",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "வாரம்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "அமைச்சகம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்தியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "13 ஆகஸ்ட் 2022",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சீன மக்கள் குடியரசு",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "16-22",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆகஸ்ட் 2022",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "அம்பாந்தோட்டை துறைமுகம்",
            "label": "FAC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "முன்னதாக ஜூலை மாதம்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாதுகாப்பு அமைச்சகத்தின்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "சீன",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "தானியங்கி அடையாள அமைப்பு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "AIS",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "LOC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "புது தில்லி",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "வெளியுறவு அமைச்சகத்தின்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "வாரந்தோறும்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜூலை 28",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "வெள்ளி",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்தியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "அரிந்தம் பாக்சி",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "வெள்ளி",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "புது டெல்லியின்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சீனா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்தியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சீனா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்தியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இந்திய விமானம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை விமானப்படை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இரண்டு ஆண்டுகளுக்கு",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "விமானப்படை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆகஸ்ட் 15",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "விமானப்படை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்தியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "2018",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இரண்டு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இந்த ஆண்டு மார்ச்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கையின்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாதுகாப்பு அமைச்சகம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இரண்டு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்தியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஒரு மிதக்கும் கப்பல்துறை வசதி மற்றும் ஒரு டோர்னியர்",
            "label": "WORK_OF_ART"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாதுகாப்பு அமைச்சகம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}