{
  "newspaper_id": "lankadeepa-lk",
  "url": "https://www.lankadeepa.lk/latest_news/පළාත්-හතරකට-තද-වැසි/1-618894",
  "time_ut": 1661740577,
  "original_lang": "si",
  "original_title": "පළාත් හතරකට තද වැසි",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Heavy rains in four provinces",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "According to the Department of Meteorology, Uva, East, North and North Central provinces will experience rain or thunder in the evening in the coming days.",
        "A spokesperson of the department said that favorable atmospheric conditions are being created for rains in those provinces.",
        "The spokesman mentioned that there will be several periods of rain in the Western, Sabaragamuwa and North-Western provinces, Kandy, Nuwara Eliya, Galle and Matara districts today (29) and in the rest of the island there will be scattered showers or thunderstorms in the evening or at night.",
        "He also said that some places in Uva, Eastern, North Central and Northern provinces will experience heavy rains of more than 75 mm.",
        "The Department of Meteorology advises people to take action to avoid accidents as lightning accidents and temporary strong winds are also possible along with thunderstorms."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "four",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "the Department of Meteorology",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Uva",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "East",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "North Central",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "the coming days",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sabaragamuwa",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "North-Western",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kandy, Nuwara Eliya",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Galle",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Matara",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "29",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "night",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Uva",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Eastern",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "North Central",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "more than 75",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "The Department of Meteorology",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "පළාත් හතරකට තද වැසි",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "ඌව, නැගෙනහිර, උතුරු සහ උතුරු මැද පළාත්වලට ඉදිරි දිනවලදී සවස් කාලයේ වැසි හෝ ගිගුරුම් සහිත වැනි ඇතිවන බව කාලගුණ විද්‍යා දෙපාර්තමේන්තුව පවසයි.",
        "එම පළාත්වලට වැසි ඇතිවීමට හිතකර වායුගෝලීය තත්වයක් නිර්මාණය වෙමින් පවතින බව එම දෙපාර්තමේන්තුවේ ප්‍රකාශකයෙක් පැවසීය.",
        "බස්නාහිර, සබරගමුව සහ වයඹ පළාත්වලත්, මහනුවර, නුවරඑළිය, ගාල්ල සහ මාතර දිස්ත්‍රික්කවලත් අද (29) දිනයේත් වැසි වාර කිහිපයක් ඇතිවන අතර දිවයිනේ සෙසු ප්‍රදේශවල සවස් කාලයේදී හෝ රාත්‍රී කාලයේදී තැනින් තැන වැසි හෝ ගිගුරුම් සහිත වැසි ඇතිවන බව එම ප්‍රකාශකයා සඳහන් කළේය.",
        "ඌව, නැගෙනහිර, උතුරු මැද හා උතුරු පළාත්වල ඇතැම් ස්ථානවලට මිලිමීටර 75ට වැඩි තරමක තද වැසි ඇතිවන බව ද ඔහු කීවේය.",
        "ගිගුරුම් සහිත වැසි සමඟ අකුණු අනතුරු සහ තාවකාලික තද සුළං ද ඇතිවිය හැකි බැවින් අනතුරු වළක්වාගැනීමට ක්‍රියා කරන්නැයි කාලගුණ විද්‍යා දෙපාර්තමේන්තුව ජනතාවට දැනුම්දීමක් කරයි."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "හතර",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "කාලගුණ විද්‍යා දෙපාර්තමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඌව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "නැගෙනහිර",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "උතුරු මැද",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉදිරි දින",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "සබරගමුව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "වයඹ",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "මහනුවර, නුවරඑළිය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගාල්ල",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මාතර",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "29",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "රෑ",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ඌව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "නැගෙනහිර",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "උතුරු මැද",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "75 ට වැඩි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "කාලගුණ විද්‍යා දෙපාර්තමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "நான்கு மாவட்டங்களில் கனமழை",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "எதிர்வரும் நாட்களில் ஊவா, கிழக்கு, வடக்கு மற்றும் வடமத்திய மாகாணங்களில் மாலை வேளையில் மழை அல்லது இடியுடன் கூடிய மழை பெய்யும் என வளிமண்டலவியல் திணைக்களம் தெரிவித்துள்ளது.",
        "அந்த மாகாணங்களில் மழை பெய்வதற்கான சாதகமான வளிமண்டல சூழல் உருவாகி வருவதாக திணைக்களத்தின் பேச்சாளர் ஒருவர் தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "இன்று (29) மேல், சப்ரகமுவ மற்றும் வடமேல் மாகாணங்களிலும், கண்டி, நுவரெலியா, காலி மற்றும் மாத்தறை மாவட்டங்களிலும் பல தடவைகள் மழை பெய்யும் எனவும், நாட்டின் ஏனைய பகுதிகளில் பரவலாக மழை அல்லது இடியுடன் கூடிய மழை பெய்யும் எனவும் பேச்சாளர் குறிப்பிட்டுள்ளார். மாலை அல்லது இரவில்.",
        "ஊவா, கிழக்கு, வடமத்திய மற்றும் வடமாகாணங்களில் சில இடங்களில் 75 மில்லிமீற்றருக்கும் அதிகமான பலத்த மழை பெய்யக்கூடும் என்றும் அவர் கூறினார்.",
        "இடியுடன் கூடிய மழையுடன் கூடிய மின்னல் விபத்துக்கள் மற்றும் தற்காலிக பலத்த காற்றும் வீசக்கூடும் என்பதால், விபத்துக்களை தவிர்ப்பதற்கு நடவடிக்கை எடுக்குமாறு வளிமண்டலவியல் திணைக்களம் மக்களுக்கு அறிவுறுத்தியுள்ளது."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "நான்கு",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "வளிமண்டலவியல் திணைக்களம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஊவா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "கிழக்கு",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "வட மத்திய",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "வரும் நாட்கள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "சப்ரகமுவ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "வடமேற்கு",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "கண்டி, நுவரெலியா",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "காலி",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "மாத்தறை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "29",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "இரவு",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஊவா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "கிழக்கு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "வட மத்திய",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "75 க்கு மேல்",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "வளிமண்டலவியல் திணைக்களம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}