{
  "newspaper_id": "news-first-lk",
  "url": "https://www.newsfirst.lk/2022/08/26/sjb-wants-full-presidential-pardon-for-ranjan-ramanayake-with-political-rights/",
  "time_ut": 1661513220,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "SJB wants full Presidential Pardon for Ranjan Ramanayake with Political Rights",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "SJB wants full Presidential Pardon for Ranjan Ramanayake with Political Rights",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st);  Opposition Leader Sajith Premadasa said that the SJB will call for the President to grant a full pardon to Ranjan Ramanayake, who was released from prison on Friday (26).",
        "Sajith Premadasa said that the 'Conditional Presidential Pardon' given to Ranjan Ramanayake is one under Article 34 (1) (b).*",
        "He said if Ramanayake was granted a pardon under Article 34 (2) of the Constitution, the latter would be given back his democratic rights.",
        "The Opposition Leader said the President and the Government must Grant a Full Presidential Pardon to Ranjan Ramanayake that will include his civic and political rights.",
        "\"This pardon does not include political rights,\" said the Opposition Leader.",
        "The Opposition Leader stressed that Ranjan Ramanayake will be appointed to the next available spot in the National List of the Samagi Jana Balavegaya, as for that process to commence Ranjan Ramanayake must be given a Full Presidential Pardon.",
        "“I’d love to speak like I used to, but I cannot,” – Ranjan talks to the press after released from prison",
        "SJB wants full Presidential Pardon for Ranjan Ramanayake with Political Rights"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "SJB",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "Presidential Pardon for Ranjan Ramanayake",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "News 1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sajith Premadasa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "SJB",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ranjan Ramanayake",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Friday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "26",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the 'Conditional Presidential Pardon'",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ranjan Ramanayake",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Article 34",
            "label": "LAW"
          },
          {
            "text": "1",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Ramanayake",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Article 34",
            "label": "LAW"
          },
          {
            "text": "2",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Constitution",
            "label": "LAW"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Ranjan Ramanayake",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "Ranjan Ramanayake",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the National List of the Samagi",
            "label": "EVENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "Jana Balavegaya",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ranjan Ramanayake",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "a Full Presidential Pardon",
            "label": "WORK_OF_ART"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Ranjan",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "SJB",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Presidential Pardon for Ranjan Ramanayake",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "SJB දේශපාලන අයිතිවාසිකම් ඇති රන්ජන් රාමනායකට පූර්ණ ජනාධිපති සමාව අවශ්‍යයි",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); සිකුරාදා (26) බන්ධනාගාරයෙන් නිදහස් වූ රන්ජන් රාමනායකට පූර්ණ සමාව ලබා දෙන ලෙස SJB ජනාධිපතිවරයාගෙන් ඉල්ලා සිටින බව විපක්ෂ නායක සජිත් ප්‍රේමදාස මහතා පැවසීය.",
        "සජිත් ප්‍රේමදාස කියා සිටියේ රන්ජන් රාමනායකට ලබා දී ඇති 'කොන්දේසි සහිත ජනාධිපති සමාව' 34 (1) (ආ)* යටතේ එකක් බවයි.",
        "ආණ්ඩුක්‍රම ව්‍යවස්ථාවේ 34 (2) වගන්තිය යටතේ රාමනායක මහතාට සමාවක් ලබා දෙන්නේ නම්, රාමනායක මහතාට ඔහුගේ ප්‍රජාතන්ත්‍රවාදී අයිතිවාසිකම් නැවත ලබා දෙන බව ඔහු පැවසීය.",
        "රන්ජන් රාමනායක මහතාගේ ප්‍රජා සහ දේශපාලන අයිතිවාසිකම් ඇතුළත් පූර්ණ ජනාධිපති සමාවක් ජනාධිපතිවරයා සහ රජය විසින් ඔහුට ලබාදිය යුතු බව විපක්ෂ නායකවරයා පැවසීය.",
        "“මෙම සමාවට දේශපාලන අයිතිවාසිකම් ඇතුළත් නොවේ,” විපක්ෂ නායකවරයා පැවසීය.",
        "සමගි ජන බලවේගයේ ජාතික ලැයිස්තුවේ මීළඟ ස්ථානයට රන්ජන් රාමනායක පත් කරන බවත් එම ක්‍රියාවලිය ආරම්භ කිරීමට නම් රන්ජන් රාමනායකට පූර්ණ ජනාධිපති සමාවක් දිය යුතු බවත් විපක්ෂ නායකවරයා අවධාරණය කළේය.",
        "\"මම ඉස්සර වගේ කතා කරන්න කැමතියි, නමුත් මට බැහැ\" - රංජන් බන්ධනාගාරයෙන් නිදහස් වූ පසු මාධ්‍ය වෙත කතා කරයි",
        "SJB දේශපාලන අයිතිවාසිකම් ඇති රන්ජන් රාමනායකට පූර්ණ ජනාධිපති සමාව අවශ්‍යයි"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "එස්.ජේ.බී",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "රන්ජන් රාමනායකට ජනාධිපති සමාව",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "News 1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "සජිත් ප්‍රේමදාස",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "එස්.ජේ.බී",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "රන්ජන් රාමනායක",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "සිකුරාදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "26",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "'කොන්දේසි සහිත ජනාධිපති සමාව'",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "රන්ජන් රාමනායක",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "34 වැනි වගන්තිය",
            "label": "LAW"
          },
          {
            "text": "1",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "රාමනායක",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "34 වැනි වගන්තිය",
            "label": "LAW"
          },
          {
            "text": "2",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ආණ්ඩුක්රම ව්යවස්ථාව",
            "label": "LAW"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "රන්ජන් රාමනායක",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "රන්ජන් රාමනායක",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "සමගි ජාතික ලැයිස්තුව",
            "label": "EVENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජන බලවේගය",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "රන්ජන් රාමනායක",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "පූර්ණ ජනාධිපති සමාවක්",
            "label": "WORK_OF_ART"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "රන්ජන්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "එස්.ජේ.බී",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "රන්ජන් රාමනායකට ජනාධිපති සමාව",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "அரசியல் உரிமைகளுடன் கூடிய ரஞ்சன் ராமநாயக்கவிற்கு ஜனாதிபதியின் முழுமையான மன்னிப்பை SJB விரும்புகிறது",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); வெள்ளிக்கிழமை (26) சிறையிலிருந்து விடுவிக்கப்பட்ட ரஞ்சன் ராமநாயக்கவுக்கு பூரண மன்னிப்பு வழங்குமாறு ஜனாதிபதியிடம் SJB கோரிக்கை விடுக்கவுள்ளதாக எதிர்க்கட்சித் தலைவர் சஜித் பிரேமதாச தெரிவித்துள்ளார்.",
        "ரஞ்சன் ராமநாயக்கவுக்கு வழங்கப்பட்டுள்ள நிபந்தனைகளுடன் கூடிய ஜனாதிபதி மன்னிப்பு 34 (1) (ஆ) பிரிவின் கீழ் ஒன்று என சஜித் பிரேமதாச தெரிவித்துள்ளார்.",
        "அரசியலமைப்பின் 34 (2) பிரிவின் கீழ் ராமநாயக்கவுக்கு மன்னிப்பு வழங்கப்பட்டால், அவர் தனது ஜனநாயக உரிமைகளை திரும்பப் பெறுவார் என்று அவர் கூறினார்.",
        "ரஞ்சன் ராமநாயக்கவின் குடியுரிமை மற்றும் அரசியல் உரிமைகளை உள்ளடக்கிய முழுமையான ஜனாதிபதி மன்னிப்பை ஜனாதிபதியும் அரசாங்கமும் வழங்க வேண்டும் என எதிர்க்கட்சித் தலைவர் தெரிவித்துள்ளார்.",
        "\"இந்த மன்னிப்பில் அரசியல் உரிமைகள் இல்லை\" என்று எதிர்க்கட்சித் தலைவர் கூறினார்.",
        "சமகி ஜன பலவேகயவின் தேசியப் பட்டியலில் அடுத்த இடத்தில் ரஞ்சன் ராமநாயக்க நியமிக்கப்படுவார் என்றும், அந்தச் செயற்பாடுகளை ஆரம்பிப்பதற்கு ரஞ்சன் ராமநாயக்கவுக்கு பூரண ஜனாதிபதி மன்னிப்பு வழங்கப்பட வேண்டும் என்றும் எதிர்க்கட்சித் தலைவர் வலியுறுத்தினார்.",
        "\"நான் முன்பு போல் பேச விரும்புகிறேன், ஆனால் என்னால் முடியாது,\" - சிறையில் இருந்து வெளிவந்த பிறகு ரஞ்சன் செய்தியாளர்களிடம் பேசுகிறார்",
        "அரசியல் உரிமைகளுடன் கூடிய ரஞ்சன் ராமநாயக்கவிற்கு ஜனாதிபதியின் முழுமையான மன்னிப்பை SJB விரும்புகிறது"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "எஸ்.ஜே.பி",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "ரஞ்சன் ராமநாயக்கவுக்கு ஜனாதிபதி மன்னிப்பு",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "News 1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சஜித் பிரேமதாச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "எஸ்.ஜே.பி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரஞ்சன் ராமநாயக்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "வெள்ளி",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "26",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "'நிபந்தனை ஜனாதிபதி மன்னிப்பு'",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரஞ்சன் ராமநாயக்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "கட்டுரை 34",
            "label": "LAW"
          },
          {
            "text": "1",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ராமநாயக்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "கட்டுரை 34",
            "label": "LAW"
          },
          {
            "text": "2",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "அரசியலமைப்பு",
            "label": "LAW"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ரஞ்சன் ராமநாயக்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "ரஞ்சன் ராமநாயக்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "சமகி தேசிய பட்டியல்",
            "label": "EVENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜன பலவேகயா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரஞ்சன் ராமநாயக்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "முழு ஜனாதிபதி மன்னிப்பு",
            "label": "WORK_OF_ART"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ரஞ்சன்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "எஸ்.ஜே.பி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரஞ்சன் ராமநாயக்கவுக்கு ஜனாதிபதி மன்னிப்பு",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}