{
  "newspaper_id": "daily-mirror-lk",
  "url": "https://www.dailymirror.lk/breaking_news/India-to-support-early-solution-in-SL-through-democratic-means-Indian-HC/108-241166",
  "time_ut": 1657891624,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "India to support early solution in SL through democratic means: Indian HC",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "India to support early solution in SL through democratic means: Indian HC",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "India will continue to stand with the people of Sri Lanka as they seek to realize their aspirations for prosperity and progress through democratic means and values as well as established institutions and a constitutional framework, Indian High Commission in Sri Lanka said.",
        "Spokesperson of Ministry of External Affairs, Government of India at a media briefing yesterday said that India looked forward to an early solution of the situation related to the government and its leadership in Sri Lanka through democratic means and values, established institutions and constitutional framework.",
        "The Spokesperson added that India will support the people of Sri Lanka in all possible ways in their endeavor to find a way forward.",
        "A statement issued by the High Commission said the commitment India have demonstrated in helping the Sri Lankan people, to address the challenges arising out of the current situation in Sri Lanka underlines India’s ‘Neighbourhood First’ policy as well as the SAGAR - Security and Growth for All in the Region – vision.",
        "\"Moving forward, India’s support and solidarity with the people of Sri Lanka will continue,” it added.",
        "The Spokesperson noted India responded with urgency to assist the people of Sri Lanka in overcoming their economic hardships and emphasized that India expeditiously finalized and delivered assistance as well as support worth about US$ 3.8 billion in 2022.",
        "\"Such assistance has been in the form of currency swaps, deferment of repayment of Sri Lanka's liabilities to the Reserve Bank of India under the Asian Clearing Union mechanism, credit assistance of more than US$ 1.5 billion for fuel, food, medicines, fertilizers, and other essential commodities.India also categorically denied having any role in facilitating the departure or travel of former President Gotabaya Rajapaksa from Sri Lanka,the statement added."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "India",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "Indian",
          "label": "NORP"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "India",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Indian High Commission",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Spokesperson of Ministry of External Affairs",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "India",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "yesterday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "India",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Spokesperson",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "India",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the High Commission",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "India",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lankan",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "India",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "SAGAR - Security",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "India",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Spokesperson",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "India",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "India",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "about US$ 3.8 billion",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "2022",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka's",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Reserve Bank of India",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Asian Clearing Union",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "more than US$ 1.5 billion",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "India",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Gotabaya Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "ප්‍රජාතන්ත්‍රවාදී ක්‍රම හරහා ශ්‍රී ලංකාව තුළ ඉක්මන් විසඳුමකට ඉන්දියාව සහාය වනු ඇත: ඉන්දීය එච්.සී",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "ප්‍රජාතන්ත්‍රවාදී මාධ්‍යයන් සහ සාරධර්ම මෙන්ම ස්ථාපිත ආයතන සහ ව්‍යවස්ථාමය රාමුවක් තුළින් සෞභාග්‍යය සහ ප්‍රගතිය සඳහා වූ ඔවුන්ගේ අභිලාෂයන් සාක්ෂාත් කර ගැනීමට උත්සාහ කරන ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ ජනතාව සමඟ ඉන්දියාව දිගටම පෙනී සිටින බව ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ ඉන්දීය මහ කොමසාරිස් කාර්යාලය පවසයි.",
        "ඉන්දීය රජයේ විදේශ කටයුතු අමාත්‍යාංශයේ ප්‍රකාශක ඊයේ පැවති මාධ්‍ය හමුවකදී කියා සිටියේ ප්‍රජාතන්ත්‍රවාදී මාධ්‍යයන් සහ සාරධර්ම, ස්ථාපිත ආයතන සහ ව්‍යවස්ථාමය රාමුව හරහා ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ රජය සහ එහි නායකත්වය සම්බන්ධ තත්ත්වයට ඉක්මන් විසඳුමක් ලබා ගැනීමට ඉන්දියාව අපේක්ෂා කරන බවයි.",
        "ඉදිරි මාවතක් සෙවීමේ ප්‍රයත්නයට ඉන්දියාව හැකි සෑම ආකාරයකින්ම ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ ජනතාවට සහාය දෙන බව ප්‍රකාශකයා පැවසීය.",
        "මහ කොමසාරිස් කාර්යාලය නිකුත් කළ නිවේදනයක දැක්වෙන්නේ, ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ වත්මන් තත්ත්වය හේතුවෙන් පැන නගින අභියෝගවලට මුහුණ දීම සඳහා ශ්‍රී ලාංකීය ජනතාවට උපකාර කිරීම සඳහා ඉන්දියාව පෙන්නුම් කර ඇති කැපවීම ඉන්දියාවේ 'අසල්වැසි ප්‍රථම' ප්‍රතිපත්තිය මෙන්ම සාගර් - ආරක්ෂාව සහ වර්ධනය සඳහා වන ප්‍රතිපත්තියත් ය. කලාපයේ සියල්ල - දැක්ම.",
        "\"ඉදිරියට යන විට, ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ ජනතාව සමඟ ඉන්දියාවේ සහයෝගය සහ සහයෝගීතාවය දිගටම පවතිනු ඇත,\" එය වැඩිදුරටත් පැවසීය.",
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ ජනතාවගේ ආර්ථික දුෂ්කරතා මඟහරවා ගැනීම සඳහා ඉන්දියාව හදිසි ප්‍රතිචාරයක් දැක්වූ බව සඳහන් කළ ප්‍රකාශකයා, ඉන්දියාව 2022 දී ඇමරිකානු ඩොලර් බිලියන 3.8 ක් පමණ වටිනා ආධාර මෙන්ම ආධාර ද කඩිනමින් අවසන් කර ලබා දුන් බව අවධාරණය කළේය.",
        "“එවැනි ආධාර මුදල් හුවමාරු කිරීම, ආසියානු නිෂ්කාශන සංගමයේ යාන්ත්‍රණය යටතේ ඉන්දියානු සංචිත බැංකුව වෙත ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ බැරකම් ආපසු ගෙවීම කල් දැමීම, ඉන්ධන, ආහාර, ඖෂධ, පොහොර සඳහා ඇමරිකානු ඩොලර් බිලියන 1.5 කට වැඩි ණය ආධාර, සහ අනෙකුත් අත්‍යාවශ්‍ය භාණ්ඩ. හිටපු ජනාධිපති ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ මහතාට ශ්‍රී ලංකාවෙන් පිටත්ව යාමට හෝ ගමන් කිරීමට පහසුකම් සැලසීමේ කිසිදු කාර්යභාරයක් ඉන්දියාව විසින් තරයේ ප්‍රතික්ෂේප කරන බව එම නිවේදනයේ වැඩිදුරටත් සඳහන් වේ."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ඉන්දියාව",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "ඉන්දීය",
          "label": "NORP"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දීය මහ කොමසාරිස්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "විදේශ කටයුතු අමාත්‍යාංශයේ ප්‍රකාශක",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඊයේ",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ප්‍රකාශක",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "මහ කොමසාරිස්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලාංකික",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "සාගර් - ආරක්ෂාව",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ප්‍රකාශක",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඇමරිකානු ඩොලර් බිලියන 3.8 ක් පමණ වේ",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "2022",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දියානු සංචිත බැංකුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ආසියානු නිෂ්කාශන සංගමය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඇමරිකානු ඩොලර් බිලියන 1.5 කට වඩා",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "ஜனநாயக வழிமுறைகள் மூலம் இலங்கையில் விரைவான தீர்வை இந்தியா ஆதரிக்கும்: இந்திய உயர் நீதிமன்றம்",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "ஜனநாயக வழிமுறைகள் மற்றும் விழுமியங்கள் மற்றும் நிறுவப்பட்ட நிறுவனங்கள் மற்றும் அரசியலமைப்பு கட்டமைப்பின் மூலம் செழிப்பு மற்றும் முன்னேற்றத்திற்கான அவர்களின் அபிலாஷைகளை நனவாக்க முயலும் இலங்கை மக்களுடன் இந்தியா தொடர்ந்து நிற்கும் என்று இலங்கைக்கான இந்திய உயர்ஸ்தானிகராலயம் தெரிவித்துள்ளது.",
        "இந்திய அரசாங்கத்தின் வெளிவிவகார அமைச்சின் செய்தித் தொடர்பாளர் நேற்று நடைபெற்ற ஊடகவியலாளர் சந்திப்பில், ஜனநாயக வழிமுறைகள் மற்றும் விழுமியங்கள், ஸ்தாபிக்கப்பட்ட நிறுவனங்கள் மற்றும் அரசியலமைப்பு கட்டமைப்பின் மூலம் இலங்கையில் அரசாங்கம் மற்றும் அதன் தலைமை தொடர்பான நிலைமைக்கு விரைவில் தீர்வு காண இந்தியா எதிர்பார்த்துள்ளதாகத் தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "இலங்கை மக்களுக்கு முன்னோக்கிச் செல்லும் வழியைக் கண்டறியும் முயற்சிக்கு இந்தியா அனைத்து வழிகளிலும் ஆதரவளிக்கும் என்று பேச்சாளர் மேலும் கூறினார்.",
        "உயர் ஸ்தானிகராலயம் வெளியிட்டுள்ள அறிக்கையில், இலங்கையின் தற்போதைய சூழ்நிலையில் எழும் சவால்களை எதிர்கொள்ள, இலங்கை மக்களுக்கு உதவுவதில் இந்தியா வெளிப்படுத்திய அர்ப்பணிப்பு, இந்தியாவின் 'அண்டை நாடுகளுக்கு முதலில்' கொள்கை மற்றும் SAGAR - பாதுகாப்பு மற்றும் வளர்ச்சியை அடிக்கோடிட்டுக் காட்டுகிறது. பிராந்தியத்தில் உள்ள அனைத்தும் - பார்வை.",
        "\"முன்னோக்கிச் செல்லும்போது, ​​இலங்கை மக்களுடன் இந்தியாவின் ஆதரவும் ஒற்றுமையும் தொடரும்\" என்று அது மேலும் கூறியது.",
        "இலங்கை மக்களின் பொருளாதார நெருக்கடிகளை சமாளிப்பதற்கு இந்தியா அவசரமாகப் பதிலளித்ததுடன், 2022 ஆம் ஆண்டில் சுமார் 3.8 பில்லியன் அமெரிக்க டொலர் பெறுமதியான உதவிகளையும், உதவிகளையும் இந்தியா விரைவாக இறுதி செய்து வழங்கியதாகவும் செய்தித் தொடர்பாளர் குறிப்பிட்டார்.",
        "\"அத்தகைய உதவிகள் நாணய பரிமாற்றங்கள், ஆசிய கிளியர் யூனியன் பொறிமுறையின் கீழ் இந்திய ரிசர்வ் வங்கிக்கு இலங்கையின் கடன்களை திருப்பிச் செலுத்துவதை ஒத்திவைத்தல், எரிபொருள், உணவு, மருந்துகள், உரங்கள், 1.5 பில்லியன் அமெரிக்க டாலர்களுக்கு மேல் கடன் உதவி, மற்றும் பிற அத்தியாவசியப் பொருட்கள். முன்னாள் ஜனாதிபதி கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ஷ இலங்கையில் இருந்து வெளியேறுவதற்கு அல்லது பயணத்தை எளிதாக்குவதில் எந்தப் பங்கும் இல்லை என்று இந்தியாவும் திட்டவட்டமாக மறுத்துள்ளது."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "இந்தியா",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "இந்தியன்",
          "label": "NORP"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "இந்தியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்திய உயர் ஸ்தானிகராலயம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "வெளியுறவு அமைச்சகத்தின் செய்தி தொடர்பாளர்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்தியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "நேற்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்தியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "செய்தி தொடர்பாளர்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்தியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "உயர் ஆணையம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்தியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்தியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சாகர் - பாதுகாப்பு",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இந்தியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "செய்தி தொடர்பாளர்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்தியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்தியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சுமார் 3.8 பில்லியன் அமெரிக்க டாலர்கள்",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "2022",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கையின்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்திய ரிசர்வ் வங்கி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆசிய கிளியரிங் யூனியன்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "1.5 பில்லியன் அமெரிக்க டாலர்களுக்கு மேல்",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்தியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}