{
  "newspaper_id": "daily-mirror-lk",
  "url": "https://www.dailymirror.lk/latest_news/Prices-of-bakery-products-could-be-lowered-drastically-if-govt-intervenes-Bakery-owners-Assn/342-242993",
  "time_ut": 1660450072,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Prices of bakery products  could be lowered drastically, if govt. intervenes: Bakery owners Assn",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Prices of bakery products  could be lowered drastically, if govt. intervenes: Bakery owners Assn",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "If the government intervenes to control and reduce the prices of flour, eggs and margarine, the price of a loaf of bread and a bun could be brought down by Rs. 50 and Rs.25, the All Ceylon Bakery Owner's Association (ACBOA) said.",
        "Association's head N.K. Jayawardane told the Daily Mirror that they have come to a situation where they are unable to continue with their profession.",
        "\"Price of an egg is sold now at Rs.65. \"Price if a bag of flour is going up steadily almost every day. The market price of margarine is definitely beyond our reach,\" he said.",
        "The price of an egg in South India is Rs. 18. If the government can import and sell them at the cost of Rs. 30, we can reduce the prices of bread and bun, Jayawardene said.",
        "Mafia dominates the egg industry; they even threatened us not to import eggs from India, he said. \"No control in the price of wheat flour in the market. The dealers and agencies increase the prices as they wish and do so indiscriminately, saying there is a scarcity of wheat flour in the market,\" he said.",
        "Therefore, the government should step in and take necessary but stern action to reduce the prices of bakery ingredients, he added. (Chaturanga Samarawickrama)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Bakery",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Rs",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "50",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Association (",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ACBOA",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Association",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "N.K. Jayawardane",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Daily Mirror",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Rs.65",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "almost every day",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "South India",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "18",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Mafia",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "India",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Chaturanga Samarawickrama",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "රජය කටයුතු කළහොත් බේකරි නිෂ්පාදනවල මිල විශාල ලෙස පහත දැමිය හැකිය. මැදිහත් වේ: බේකරි හිමියන් සහකාර",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "රජය මැදිහත් වී පිටි, බිත්තර, මාගරින් මිල පාලනය කර අඩු කළහොත් පාන් ගෙඩියක සහ බනිස් ගෙඩියක මිල රු. 50ක් සහ රුපියල් 25ක් වන බව සමස්ත ලංකා බේකරි හිමියන්ගේ සංගමය (ACBOA) පැවසීය.",
        "සංගමයේ ප්‍රධානී එන්.කේ. ජයවර්ධන ඩේලි මිරර් වෙත කියා සිටියේ තම වෘත්තිය කරගෙන යාමට නොහැකි තත්ත්වයකට ඔවුන් පැමිණ ඇති බවයි.",
        "\"දැන් බිත්තරයක මිල රුපියල් 65 ට අලෙවි වෙනවා. \"හැමදාම වගේ පිටි බෑගයක් ක්‍රමයෙන් ඉහළ යනවා නම් මිල. මාගරින් වෙළඳපල මිල නියත වශයෙන්ම අපට ළඟාවිය නොහැකි තරම්ය,\" ඔහු පැවසීය.",
        "දකුණු ඉන්දියාවේ බිත්තරයක මිල රු. 18. රජයට ඒවා ආනයනය කර විකිණීමට හැකි නම් රු. 30, අපට පාන් සහ බනිස් මිල අඩු කළ හැකිය, ජයවර්ධන පැවසීය.",
        "බිත්තර කර්මාන්තයේ මාෆියාව ආධිපත්‍යය දරයි; ඉන්දියාවෙන් බිත්තර ආනයනය නොකරන ලෙස පවා ඔවුන් අපට තර්ජනය කළ බව ඔහු පැවසීය. \"වෙළෙඳපොළේ තිරිඟු පිටි මිල පාලනයක් නැහැ. වෙළෙඳ පොළේ තිරිඟු පිටි හිඟයක් පවතින බව පවසමින් අලෙවි නියෝජිතයන් සහ නියෝජිත ආයතන තමන්ට අවශ්‍ය පරිදි මිල වැඩි කර අසීමිත ලෙස කරනවා,\" ඔහු පැවසීය.",
        "එබැවින් රජය මැදිහත් වී බේකරි අමුද්‍රව්‍ය මිල අඩු කිරීමට අවශ්‍ය නමුත් දැඩි ක්‍රියාමාර්ග ගත යුතු බව ඔහු වැඩිදුරටත් පැවසීය. (චතුරංග සමරවික්‍රම)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "බේකරිය",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "රුපියල්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "50",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "සංගමය (",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ACBOA",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "සංගමය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "එන්.කේ. ජයවර්ධන ය",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඩේලි මිරර්",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "රුපියල් 65යි",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "සෑම දිනකම පාහේ",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "දකුණු ඉන්දියාව",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "18",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "මාෆියාව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "චතුරංග සමරවික්‍රම",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "அரசு வந்தால் பேக்கரி பொருட்களின் விலை பெருமளவு குறைக்கப்படும். தலையிடுகிறது: பேக்கரி உரிமையாளர்கள் Assn",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "அரசாங்கம் தலையிட்டு மாவு, முட்டை மற்றும் நல்லெண்ணெய் ஆகியவற்றின் விலைகளைக் கட்டுப்படுத்தி குறைத்தால், ஒரு ரொட்டி மற்றும் ஒரு ரொட்டியின் விலையை ரூ. 50 மற்றும் ரூ.25 என அகில இலங்கை பேக்கரி உரிமையாளர் சங்கம் (ACBOA) தெரிவித்துள்ளது.",
        "சங்கத்தின் தலைவர் என்.கே. அவர்கள் தமது தொழிலை தொடர முடியாத நிலைமைக்கு வந்துள்ளதாக ஜெயவர்தன டெய்லி மிரருக்கு தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "\"இப்போது ஒரு முட்டையின் விலை ரூ.65க்கு விற்கப்படுகிறது. \"ஒரு மூட்டை மாவின் விலை கிட்டத்தட்ட ஒவ்வொரு நாளும் சீராக ஏறிக்கொண்டிருக்கிறது. வெண்ணெயின் சந்தை விலை நிச்சயமாக எங்களால் எட்ட முடியாததாக இருக்கும்,\" என்று அவர் கூறினார்.",
        "தென்னிந்தியாவில் முட்டை ஒன்றின் விலை ரூ. 18. அரசாங்கம் அவற்றை இறக்குமதி செய்து விற்க முடிந்தால் ரூ. 30, நாங்கள் ரொட்டி மற்றும் ரொட்டியின் விலைகளை குறைக்க முடியும், ஜெயவர்த்தன கூறினார்.",
        "முட்டை தொழிலில் மாஃபியா ஆதிக்கம் செலுத்துகிறது; இந்தியாவில் இருந்து முட்டைகளை இறக்குமதி செய்யக் கூடாது என்று மிரட்டினர், என்றார். \"சந்தையில் கோதுமை மாவின் விலையில் கட்டுப்பாடு இல்லை. சந்தையில் கோதுமை மாவுக்கு தட்டுப்பாடு இருப்பதாகக் கூறி டீலர்கள் மற்றும் ஏஜென்சிகள் தங்கள் விருப்பப்படி விலையை உயர்த்துகிறார்கள்,\" என்று அவர் கூறினார்.",
        "எனவே, பேக்கரி பொருட்களின் விலையை குறைக்க அரசு நடவடிக்கை எடுத்து தேவையான ஆனால் கடுமையான நடவடிக்கை எடுக்க வேண்டும் என்று அவர் மேலும் கூறினார். (சதுரங்க சமரவிக்ரம)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "பேக்கரி",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ரூ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "50",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "சங்கம் (",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஏசிபிஓஏ",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "சங்கம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "என்.கே. ஜெயவர்த்தனே",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "டெய்லி மிரர்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ரூ.65",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "கிட்டத்தட்ட ஒவ்வொரு நாளும்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "தென் இந்தியா",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "18",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "மாஃபியா",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்தியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "சதுரங்க சமரவிக்ரம",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}