{
  "newspaper_id": "lankadeepa-lk",
  "url": "https://www.lankadeepa.lk/latest_news/ජලයට-කොටුවූ-තරුණයෝ-දෙකක්-බේරා-ගැනෙති/1-615860",
  "time_ut": 1656939298,
  "original_lang": "si",
  "original_title": "ජලයට කොටුවූ තරුණයෝ දෙකක් බේරා ගැනෙති",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Two youths trapped in the water are rescued",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "A police lifeguard team has gone there and rescued two youths who were trapped in a wasteland in the Haragama area of ​​Victoria Reservoir by opening several sluice gates due to the rise in the water level of Polgolla Reservoir due to the torrential rain that hit the Kandy area for the past few days.",
        "The sluice gates of the Polgolla reservoir were opened and at around 03.00 in the evening, the two young men were trapped in the middle of the respective island.",
        "In this regard, after being informed by the Talatuoya Police, under the guidance of Chief Inspector Yapa, Station Commander of the Kandy Division Police Lifeguard Unit attached to Dalada Maligawa Police, female Police Sergeant 1721 Jayanthi, Police Sergeant 61265 Mangala, Police Constable Hathai 73092 Premalal, and Suvechcha Lifeguard Officer Krinsnarathne went there within minutes. After a 45-hour operation, they were safely brought to land using ropes.",
        "A resident of Gurudeniya area and two residents of Nuwara Eliya area were rescued."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Two",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Haragama",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "Reservoir",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Polgolla Reservoir",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kandy",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the past few days",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Polgolla",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "around 03.00",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "two",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the Talatuoya Police",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Yapa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Kandy Division Police Lifeguard Unit",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Dalada Maligawa Police",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "1721 Jayanthi",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Mangala, Police",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Constable Hathai",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Premalal",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Suvechcha Lifeguard",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Officer Krinsnarathne",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "minutes",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "45-hour",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Gurudeniya",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "two",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Nuwara Eliya",
            "label": "LOC"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "ජලයට කොටුවූ තරුණයෝ දෙකක් බේරා ගැනෙති",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "මහනුවර ප්‍රදේශයට ඉකුත් දින කීපය ඇදහැලුණු ධාරානිපාත වර්ෂාව හේතුවෙන් පොල්ගොල්ල ජලාශයේ ජල මට්ටම ඉහළ යාම නිසා වාන් දොරටු කිහිපයක් විවෘත කිරීමෙන් වික්ටෝරියා ජලාශයේ හාරගම ප්‍රදේශයේ  මුඩුබිමක කොටුවී සිටි තරුණයන් දෙදෙනකු  පොලිස් ජිවිතාරක්ෂක කණ්ඩායමක් එහි ගොස් ඔවුන් බේරා ගෙන තිබේ.",
        "පොල්ගොල්ල ජලාශයේ වාන් දොරටු විවෘත කර ඇති අතර සවස 03.00ට පමණ එම තරුණයන් දෙදෙනා අදාල දූපත මැද කොටු වී තිබේ .",
        "ඒ සම්බන්ධයෙන් තලාතුඔය පොලිසිය විසින් දැනුම් දීමෙන් අනතුරුව දළදා මාළිගාව පොලීසියට අනුයුක්ත මහනුවර කොට්ඨාස පොලිස් ජීවිතාරක්ෂක ඒකකයේ ස්ථානාධිපති ප්‍රධාන පොලිස් පරීක්ෂක යාපා මහතාගේ මෙහෙයවීමෙන් කාන්තා පොලිස් සැරයන් 1721 ජයන්ති , පොලිස් සැරයන් 61265 මංගල , පොලිස් කොස්තාපල් හතයි 73092 ප්‍රේමලාල් , සුවෙච්චා ජීවිතාරක්ෂක නිලධාරී ක්‍රිංශ්නරත්න යන නිලධාරීන් එහි ගොස් විනාඩි 45ක මෙහෙයුමකින් පසු කඹ යොදා ගනිමින් ඔවුන් නිරුපද්‍රිතව ගොඩබිමට ගෙනැවිත් තිබේ .",
        "එසේ බේරාගෙන ඇත්තේ  ගුරුදෙනිය ප්‍රදේශයේ පදිංචිකරුවෙකු සහ  නුවරඑළිය ප්‍රදේශයේ පදිංචිකරුවන් දෛදෙනෙකි."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "දෙක",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "හාරගම",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජලාශය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "පොල්ගොල්ල ජලාශය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "මහනුවර",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "පසුගිය දින කිහිපය",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "පොල්ගොල්ල",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "03.00 පමණ",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "දෙක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the Talatuoya Police",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "යාපා",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "මහනුවර කොට්ඨාශ පොලිස් ජීවිතාරක්ෂක ඒකකය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "දළදා මාලිගාව පොලිසිය",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "1721 ජයන්ති",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "මංගල, පොලිසිය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "කොස්තාපල් හතායි",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ප්‍රේමලාල්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "සුවෙච්ච ජීවිතාරක්ෂක",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ක්‍රිංස්නාරත්න නිලධාරී",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "මිනිත්තු",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "45-පැය",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ගුරුදෙණිය",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "දෙක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "නුවරඑළිය",
            "label": "LOC"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "தண்ணீரில் சிக்கிய இரு இளைஞர்கள் மீட்கப்பட்டனர்",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "கண்டி பிரதேசத்தில் பெய்து வரும் அடை மழை காரணமாக பொல்கொல்ல நீர்த்தேக்கத்தின் நீர் மட்டம் உயர்வடைந்ததையடுத்து விக்டோரியா நீர்த்தேக்கத்தின் ஹரகம பிரதேசத்தில் உள்ள பாழ் நிலத்தில் சிக்கியிருந்த இரு இளைஞர்களை பொலிஸ் உயிர்காப்பு குழுவினர் அங்கு சென்று பல வான்கதவுகளை திறந்து மீட்டுள்ளனர். கடந்த சில நாட்களாக.",
        "பொல்கொல்ல நீர்த்தேக்கத்தின் வான்கதவுகள் திறக்கப்பட்டு மாலை 03.00 மணியளவில் குறித்த இரு இளைஞர்களும் அந்தந்த தீவின் நடுப்பகுதியில் சிக்கியுள்ளனர்.",
        "இது தொடர்பில் தலத்துஓயா பொலிஸாருக்கு அறிவிக்கப்பட்டதையடுத்து, தலதா மாளிகை பொலிஸ் பிரிவுக்குட்பட்ட கண்டி பிரதேச பொலிஸ் உயிர்காப்பு பிரிவின் நிலைய கட்டளைத்தளபதி பிரதம பரிசோதகர் யாப்பாவின் வழிகாட்டலின் கீழ், பெண் பொலிஸ் சார்ஜன்ட் 1721 ஜெயந்தி, பொலிஸ் சார்ஜன்ட் 61265 மங்கள, பொலிஸ் கான்ஸ்டபிள் ஹத்தாய் 73092. பிரேமலால், மற்றும் சுவேச்ச உயிர்காப்பு அதிகாரி கிருஷ்ணரத்ன ஆகியோர் சில நிமிடங்களில் அங்கு சென்றனர்.45 மணி நேர அறுவை சிகிச்சைக்கு பின், கயிறுகள் மூலம் அவர்கள் பாதுகாப்பாக தரையிறக்கப்பட்டனர்.",
        "குருதெனிய பிரதேசத்தை சேர்ந்த ஒருவரும் நுவரெலியா பிரதேசத்தை சேர்ந்த இருவருமே இவ்வாறு மீட்கப்பட்டுள்ளனர்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "இரண்டு",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ஹரகம",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "நீர்த்தேக்கம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "பொல்கொல்ல நீர்த்தேக்கம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "கண்டி",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "கடந்த சில நாட்களாக",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "போல்கொல்லா",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "சுமார் 03.00",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "இரண்டு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the Talatuoya Police",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "யாப்பா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "கண்டி பிரிவு பொலிஸ் உயிர்காப்பு பிரிவு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "தலதா மாளிகை பொலிஸ்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "1721 ஜெயந்தி",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "மங்களா, போலீஸ்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "கான்ஸ்டபிள் ஹத்தாய்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "பிரேமலால்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "சுவேச்ச உயிர்காப்பாளர்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "அதிகாரி கிருஷ்ணரத்ன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "நிமிடங்கள்",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "45-மணிநேரம்",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "குருதெனிய",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இரண்டு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "நுவரெலியா",
            "label": "LOC"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}