{
  "newspaper_id": "news-first-lk",
  "url": "https://www.newsfirst.lk/2022/08/18/10-people-arrested-on-illegal-migration-attempt/",
  "time_ut": 1660796400,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "10 people arrested on illegal migration attempt",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "10 people arrested on illegal migration attempt",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); Sri Lanka Navy apprehended 10 individuals, suspected to be on an illegal migration attempt to a foreign country via sea, during a special operation conducted on seas off Kurusapadu, Talaimannar on the night of 16th August 2022.",
        "Sri Lanka Navy has been conducting regular operations and patrols covering the sea and coastal areas around the island to suppress illegal migration and other forms of illegal activities.",
        "In a similar operation, the Inshore Patrol Craft P 175 of SLNS Buwaneka in the North Central Naval Command intercepted a suspicious dinghy in the sea area of Kurusapadu on the night of 16th August.",
        "Upon investigation, the Navy apprehended 10 individuals who were suspected to be on an illegal migration attempt to a foreign country via sea.",
        "Among the apprehended individuals were; 04 males including 02 boat operators and 02 females who are over 18 years of age and 04 other individuals below 18 years of age.",
        "The Navy also held the dinghy used for this illegal sea voyage.",
        "The suspects were identified as residents of Pesalai, Urumalai, Kilinochchi, and Kantale, and they were handed over to the Talaimannar Police for onward legal action.",
        "As it is observed that human smugglers organize this nature of rackets using unsafe methods to make fast money, the Navy urges the public to refrain from risking their lives by engaging in perilous sea voyages and being victims before the law."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "10",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "News 1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka Navy",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "10",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kurusapadu",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Talaimannar",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the night of 16th August 2022",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka Navy",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the Inshore Patrol Craft",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "175",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "the North Central Naval Command",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kurusapadu",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the night of 16th August",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Navy",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "10",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "04",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "02",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "18 years of age",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "04",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "18 years of age",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Navy",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Pesalai",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Urumalai",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kilinochchi",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kantale",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Talaimannar Police",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Navy",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "නීතිවිරෝධී ලෙස සංක්‍රමණය වීමට උත්සාහ කළ පුද්ගලයින් 10 දෙනෙකු අත්අඩංගුවට",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); ශ්‍රී ලංකා නාවික හමුදාව විසින් 2022 අගෝස්තු මස 16 වන දින රාත්‍රියේ තලෙයිමන්නාරම, කුරුසපාඩු මුහුදු ප්‍රදේශයේ සිදුකළ විශේෂ මෙහෙයුමකදී මුහුදු මාර්ගයෙන් විදේශයකට සංක්‍රමණය වීමට උත්සාහ කළ බවට සැක කෙරෙන පුද්ගලයින් 10 දෙනෙකු අත්අඩංගුවට ගන්නා ලදී.",
        "නීතිවිරෝධී සංක්‍රමණ සහ අනෙකුත් නීති විරෝධී ක්‍රියාකාරකම් මැඩපැවැත්වීම සඳහා ශ්‍රී ලංකා නාවික හමුදාව දිවයින වටා මුහුදු සහ වෙරළබඩ ප්‍රදේශ ආවරණය වන පරිදි නිරන්තර මෙහෙයුම් සහ මුර සංචාර පවත්වයි.",
        "මෙවැනිම මෙහෙයුමකදී උතුරු මැද නාවික විධානයට අයත් ශ්‍රී ලංකා නාවික නෞකා බුවනෙක නෞකාවේ P 175 දරණ වෙරළ මුර යාත්‍රාව විසින් කුරුසපාඩු මුහුදු ප්‍රදේශයේදී සැකකටයුතු ඩිංගි යාත්‍රාවක් අගෝස්‌තු 16 වැනිදා රාත්‍රියේ අත්අඩංගුවට ගන්නා ලදී.",
        "ඒ අනුව සිදුකළ විමර්ශනයකදී නීතිවිරෝධී ලෙස මුහුදු මාර්ගයෙන් විදේශ රටකට සංක්‍රමණය වීමට උත්සාහ කළ බවට සැක කෙරෙන පුද්ගලයින් 10 දෙනෙකු නාවික හමුදාව විසින් අත්අඩංගුවට ගෙන ඇත.",
        "අත්අඩංගුවට ගත් පුද්ගලයින් අතර; බෝට්ටු ක්‍රියාකරුවන් 02 ක් සහ වයස අවුරුදු 18 ට වැඩි කාන්තාවන් 02 ක් සහ වයස අවුරුදු 18 ට අඩු තවත් පුද්ගලයින් 04 ක් ඇතුළුව පිරිමි 04 ක්.",
        "මෙම නීතිවිරෝධී මුහුදු ගමන සඳහා යොදාගත් ඩිංගි යාත්‍රාව ද නාවික හමුදාව සතුව තිබී ඇත.",
        "සැකකරුවන් පේසාලේ, ඌරුමලෙයි, කිලිනොච්චිය සහ කන්තලේ ප්‍රදේශවල පදිංචිකරුවන් බවට හඳුනාගෙන ඇති අතර, ඔවුන් ඉදිරි නීතිමය කටයුතු සඳහා තලෙයිමන්නාරම පොලිසිය වෙත භාර දීමට කටයුතු කෙරිණි.",
        "මිනිස් ජාවාරම්කරුවන් අනාරක්ෂිත ක්‍රම භාවිත කරමින් වේගයෙන් මුදල් ඉපයීම සඳහා මෙවැනි ජාවාරම් සංවිධානය කරන බව නිරීක්ෂණය වන බැවින් අනතුරුදායක මුහුදු ගමන්වල නිරත වෙමින් නීතිය ඉදිරියේ ගොදුරු බවට පත්වීමෙන් ජීවිත අවදානමට ලක්වීමෙන් වළකින ලෙස නාවික හමුදාව මහජනතාවගෙන් ඉල්ලා සිටී."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "10",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "News 1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකා නාවික හමුදාව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "10",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "කුරුසපාඩු",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "තලෙයිමන්නාරම",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "2022 අගෝස්තු 16 වෙනිදා රාත්‍රිය",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකා නාවික හමුදාව",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "වෙරළ මුර යාත්‍රාව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "175",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "උතුරු මැද නාවික විධානය",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "කුරුසපාඩු",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "අගෝස්තු 16 රෑ",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "නාවික",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "10",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "04",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "02",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "වයස අවුරුදු 18 යි",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "04",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "වයස අවුරුදු 18 යි",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "නාවික",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "පේසාලෙයි",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඌරුමලෙයි",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "කිලිනොච්චි",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "කන්තලේ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "තලෙයිමන්නාරම පොලිසිය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "නාවික",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "சட்டவிரோதமாக குடியேற முயன்ற 10 பேர் கைது செய்யப்பட்டுள்ளனர்",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); இலங்கை கடற்படையினர் 2022 ஆகஸ்ட் 16 ஆம் திகதி இரவு தலைமன்னார் குருசபாடு கடற்பரப்பில் மேற்கொண்ட விசேட நடவடிக்கையின் போது கடல் வழியாக வெளிநாட்டுக்கு சட்டவிரோதமாக குடியேற முயற்சித்ததாக சந்தேகிக்கப்படும் 10 நபர்கள் கைது செய்யப்பட்டனர்.",
        "இலங்கை கடற்படை சட்டவிரோத குடியேற்றம் மற்றும் பிற சட்டவிரோத நடவடிக்கைகளை ஒடுக்குவதற்காக தீவைச் சுற்றியுள்ள கடல் மற்றும் கரையோரப் பகுதிகளை உள்ளடக்கிய வழக்கமான நடவடிக்கைகள் மற்றும் ரோந்துப் பணிகளை மேற்கொண்டு வருகிறது.",
        "இதேபோன்ற நடவடிக்கையில், வட மத்திய கடற்படை கட்டளையில் உள்ள SLNS புவனேகாவின் Inshore Patrol Craft P 175 ஆகஸ்ட் 16 அன்று இரவு குருசபாடு கடற்பகுதியில் சந்தேகத்திற்கிடமான டிங்கி படகு ஒன்றை இடைமறித்தது.",
        "விசாரணையில், கடல் வழியாக வெளிநாடுகளுக்கு சட்டவிரோதமாக குடியேற முயன்றதாக சந்தேகிக்கப்படும் 10 நபர்களை கடற்படையினர் கைது செய்தனர்.",
        "கைது செய்யப்பட்டவர்களில்; 02 படகு நடத்துநர்கள் மற்றும் 02 பெண்கள் உட்பட 04 ஆண்கள் 18 வயதுக்கு மேற்பட்டவர்கள் மற்றும் 04 பேர் 18 வயதுக்குட்பட்டவர்கள்.",
        "இந்த சட்டவிரோத கடல் பயணத்திற்கு பயன்படுத்தப்பட்ட டிங்கி படகுகளையும் கடற்படையினர் வைத்திருந்தனர்.",
        "சந்தேகநபர்கள் பேசாலை, உருமலை, கிளிநொச்சி மற்றும் கந்தளாய் ஆகிய பகுதிகளைச் சேர்ந்தவர்கள் என அடையாளம் காணப்பட்டு, அவர்கள் தலைமன்னார் பொலிஸாரிடம் மேலதிக சட்ட நடவடிக்கைகளுக்காக ஒப்படைக்கப்பட்டனர்.",
        "மனித கடத்தல்காரர்கள் பாதுகாப்பற்ற முறைகளை பயன்படுத்தி வேகமாக பணம் சம்பாதிப்பதற்காக இவ்வாறான மோசடிகளை ஏற்பாடு செய்வதை அவதானிக்கின்ற நிலையில், அபாயகரமான கடல் பயணங்களில் ஈடுபட்டு சட்டத்தின் முன் பலியாவதன் மூலம் உயிரை பணயம் வைப்பதை தவிர்க்குமாறு கடற்படை பொதுமக்களை கேட்டுக்கொண்டுள்ளது."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "10",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "News 1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை கடற்படை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "10",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "குருசபாடு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "தலைமன்னார்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆகஸ்ட் 16, 2022 இரவு",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை கடற்படை",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "கடலோர ரோந்து கைவினை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "175",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "வட மத்திய கடற்படை கட்டளை",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "குருசபாடு",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆகஸ்ட் 16 இரவு",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "கடற்படை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "10",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "04",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "02",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "18 வயது",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "04",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "18 வயது",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "கடற்படை",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பேசாலை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "உருமலை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "கிளிநொச்சி",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "கந்தளே",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "தலைமன்னார் காவல்துறை",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "கடற்படை",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}