{
  "newspaper_id": "daily-mirror-lk",
  "url": "https://www.dailymirror.lk/breaking_news/Protesters-brutally-assault-soldiers-steal-two-T-56-weapons-along-with-ammunition-Army/108-241078",
  "time_ut": 1657782927,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Protesters brutally assault soldiers, steal two T-56 weapons along with ammunition: Army",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Protesters brutally assault soldiers, steal two T-56 weapons along with ammunition: Army",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "The Sri Lanka Army said today that protesters had brutally assaulted two soldiers last night during the protests near Parliament and took two automatic T-56 assault rifles from their possession along with ammunition.",
        "Army Spokesman Brigadier Nilantha Premaratna said two army soldiers were brutally assaulted and their weapons and ammunition were stolen by protesters who behaved violently in and around the Parliament roundabout.",
        "He urged the public to be vigilant as violence can be spread using these stolen weapons.",
        "Meanwhile, the spokesman said at least 16 soldiers have been injured during the clash with protesters yesterday and are receiving treatment at the Army Hospital. (DSB)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Army",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "The Sri Lanka Army",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "two",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "last night",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "two",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "T-56",
            "label": "PRODUCT"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Army",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Nilantha Premaratna",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "two",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "at least 16",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "yesterday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Army Hospital",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "DSB",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "විරෝධතාකරුවන් සොල්දාදුවන්ට අමානුෂික ලෙස පහර දී පතොරම් සමඟ ටී 56 අවි දෙකක් සොරකම් කරයි: හමුදාව",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "ඊයේ රාත්‍රියේ පාර්ලිමේන්තුව ආසන්නයේ පැවති විරෝධතා අතරතුර විරෝධතාකරුවන් හමුදා සෙබළුන් දෙදෙනෙකුට අමානුෂික ලෙස පහර දී ඔවුන් සතුව තිබී ස්වයංක්‍රීය ටී 56 ගිනි අවි දෙකක් පතොරම් සමඟ රැගෙන ගිය බව ශ්‍රී ලංකා යුද හමුදාව අද ප්‍රකාශ කළා.",
        "පාර්ලිමේන්තු වටරවුමේ සහ ඒ අවට ප්‍රචණ්ඩකාරී ලෙස හැසිරුණු විරෝධතාකරුවන් විසින් හමුදා සෙබළුන් දෙදෙනෙකුට අමානුෂික ලෙස පහර දී ඔවුන්ගේ ආයුධ සහ පතොරම් සොරකම් කර ඇති බව යුද හමුදා මාධ්‍ය ප්‍රකාශක බ්‍රිගේඩියර් නිලන්ත ප්‍රේමරත්න මහතා පැවසීය.",
        "මෙම සොරකම් කරන ලද අවි භාවිත කරමින් ප්‍රචණ්ඩත්වය පැතිර යා හැකි බැවින් විමසිලිමත් වන ලෙස ඔහු ජනතාවගෙන් ඉල්ලා සිටියේය.",
        "මේ අතර, විරෝධතාකරුවන් සමඟ ඊයේ ඇති වූ ගැටුමේදී අවම වශයෙන් සෙබළුන් 16 දෙනෙකු තුවාල ලබා යුද හමුදා රෝහලේ ප්‍රතිකාර ලබන බව එම ප්‍රකාශකයා පැවසීය. (DSB)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "හමුදා",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකා යුද හමුදාව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "දෙක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "අවසන් රාත්රිය",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "දෙක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ටී-56",
            "label": "PRODUCT"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "හමුදා",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "නිලන්ත ප්‍රේමරත්න",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "දෙක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "අවම වශයෙන් 16",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඊයේ",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "හමුදා රෝහල",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඩී.එස්.බී",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "ஆர்ப்பாட்டக்காரர்கள் இராணுவத்தினரை கொடூரமாக தாக்கி இரண்டு T-56 ஆயுதங்களுடன் வெடிமருந்துகளையும் திருடியுள்ளனர்: இராணுவம்",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "நேற்றிரவு பாராளுமன்றத்திற்கு அருகாமையில் இடம்பெற்ற ஆர்ப்பாட்டத்தின் போது ஆர்ப்பாட்டக்காரர்கள் இரு இராணுவத்தினரை கொடூரமான முறையில் தாக்கியதாகவும், அவர்களிடம் இருந்து இரண்டு தானியங்கி T-56 ரக துப்பாக்கிகளையும் வெடிமருந்துகளுடன் எடுத்துச் சென்றதாகவும் சிறிலங்கா இராணுவம் இன்று தெரிவித்துள்ளது.",
        "பாராளுமன்ற சுற்றுவட்டத்திலும் அதனைச் சுற்றியும் வன்முறையில் ஈடுபட்ட ஆர்ப்பாட்டக்காரர்களால் இரண்டு இராணுவ வீரர்கள் கொடூரமான முறையில் தாக்கப்பட்டு அவர்களது ஆயுதங்கள் மற்றும் வெடிபொருட்கள் திருடப்பட்டதாக இராணுவப் பேச்சாளர் பிரிகேடியர் நிலந்த பிரேமரத்ன தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "இந்த திருடப்பட்ட ஆயுதங்களைப் பயன்படுத்தி வன்முறைகள் பரவக்கூடும் என்பதால், பொதுமக்கள் விழிப்புடன் இருக்குமாறு அவர் கேட்டுக் கொண்டார்.",
        "இதேவேளை, நேற்று ஆர்ப்பாட்டக்காரர்களுடனான மோதலில் குறைந்தது 16 இராணுவத்தினர் காயமடைந்து இராணுவ மருத்துவமனையில் சிகிச்சை பெற்று வருவதாக பேச்சாளர் தெரிவித்தார். (டி.எஸ்.பி.)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "இராணுவம்",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை இராணுவம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இரண்டு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "நேற்று இரவு",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இரண்டு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "டி-56",
            "label": "PRODUCT"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இராணுவம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "நிலந்த பிரேமரத்ன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இரண்டு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "குறைந்தது 16",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "நேற்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இராணுவ மருத்துவமனை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "டி.எஸ்.பி",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}