{
  "newspaper_id": "daily-mirror-lk",
  "url": "https://www.dailymirror.lk/latest_news/Progress-on-second-booster-dose-rollout-not-satisfactory-Dr-Ginige/342-243651",
  "time_ut": 1661342874,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Progress on second booster dose rollout not satisfactory: Dr. Ginige",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Progress on second booster dose rollout not satisfactory: Dr. Ginige",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "Claiming that Sri Lanka is yet to be out of the woods with the looming Covid-19 threat, Epidemiology Unit Director Dr. Samitha Ginige said today the progress of obtaining the fourth dose or the second booster dose of the Covid vaccine was not at all satisfactory.",
        "He told a news conference at the Health Promotion Bureau that only nearly 150,000 people had obtained the second booster dose by now.",
        "Dr. Ginige said the fourth dose or the second booster dose of the Covid vaccine was recommended for high risk groups such as people over 60-years of age and people with chronic diseases.",
        "“We recommend that the second booster dose should be obtained three months after obtaining the first booster dose. However, the progress of obtaining the second booster dose is not at all satisfactory.”",
        "He said that there were sufficient stocks of Covid vaccines right now as all the required vaccines for people over 20 had been procured and that only around 5,000 people turn up daily to obtain the vaccine by now.",
        "Dr. Ginige said there was an increase in the number of Covid patients during the last few weeks and that the number of deaths were also increasing in line with the increase of the number of cases.",
        "He said it was vital for people to obtain the booster dose and adapt to health practices to prevent the disease being spread among the community. (Ajith Siriwardana)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "second",
          "label": "ORDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "Ginige",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Epidemiology Unit",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Samitha Ginige",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "fourth",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "second",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Covid",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the Health Promotion Bureau",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "only nearly 150,000",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "second",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Ginige",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "fourth",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "second",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Covid",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "60-years",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "second",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "three months",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "first",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "second",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "only around 5,000",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Ginige",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the last few weeks",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Ajith Siriwardana",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "දෙවන බූස්ටර මාත්‍රාව නිකුත් කිරීමේ ප්‍රගතිය සෑහීමකට පත් නොවේ: වෛද්‍ය ගිනිගේ",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකාව තවමත් කොවිඩ් 19 තර්ජනයෙන් මිදී නොමැති බව පවසමින් වසංගත රෝග විද්‍යා අංශයේ අධ්‍යක්ෂ වෛද්‍ය සමිත ගිනිගේ අද පැවසුවේ කොවිඩ් එන්නතෙහි සිව්වන මාත්‍රාව හෝ දෙවන බූස්ටර මාත්‍රාව ලබා ගැනීමේ ප්‍රගතිය කිසිසේත්ම සතුටුදායක නොවන බවයි. .",
        "සෞඛ්‍ය ප්‍රවර්ධන කාර්යාංශයේ පැවති ප්‍රවෘත්ති සාකච්ඡාවකදී ඔහු කියා සිටියේ මේ වන විට දෙවන බූස්ටර මාත්‍රාව ලබාගෙන ඇත්තේ 150,000 කට ආසන්න පිරිසක් පමණක් බවයි.",
        "වයස අවුරුදු 60 ට වැඩි පුද්ගලයින් සහ නිදන්ගත රෝග ඇති පුද්ගලයින් වැනි අධි අවදානම් කණ්ඩායම් සඳහා කොවිඩ් එන්නතෙහි සිව්වන මාත්‍රාව හෝ දෙවන බූස්ටර මාත්‍රාව නිර්දේශ කරන බව වෛද්‍ය ගිනිගේ පැවසීය.",
        "“පළමු බූස්ටර මාත්‍රාව ලබා ගැනීමෙන් මාස තුනකට පසු දෙවන බූස්ටර මාත්‍රාව ලබා ගත යුතු බව අපි නිර්දේශ කරමු. කෙසේ වෙතත්, දෙවන බූස්ටර මාත්‍රාව ලබා ගැනීමේ ප්‍රගතිය කිසිසේත් සතුටුදායක නැත.",
        "වයස අවුරුදු 20ට වැඩි පුද්ගලයින් සඳහා අවශ්‍ය සියලුම එන්නත් ලබාගෙන ඇති බැවින් මේ වන විට ප්‍රමාණවත් කොවිඩ් එන්නත් තොග ඇති බවත් මේ වන විට එන්නත ලබා ගැනීම සඳහා දිනකට පැමිණෙන්නේ 5000ක පමණ පිරිසක් බවත් ඔහු පැවසීය.",
        "පසුගිය සති කිහිපය තුළ කොවිඩ් රෝගීන්ගේ වැඩිවීමක් දක්නට ලැබුණු බවත්, රෝගීන් සංඛ්‍යාව වැඩිවීමට සමගාමීව මරණ සංඛ්‍යාව ද ඉහළ යමින් පවතින බවත් වෛද්‍ය ගිනිගේ මහතා පැවසීය.",
        "රෝගය ප්‍රජාව අතර පැතිරීම වැළැක්වීම සඳහා බූස්ටර මාත්‍රාව ලබා ගැනීම සහ සෞඛ්‍ය පුරුදුවලට අනුගත වීම අත්‍යවශ්‍ය බව ඔහු පැවසීය. (අජිත් සිරිවර්ධන)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "දෙවැනි",
          "label": "ORDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "Ginige",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "වසංගත රෝග ඒකකය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "සමිත ගිනිගේ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "හතරවන",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "දෙවැනි",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "කොවිඩ්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "සෞඛ්‍ය ප්‍රවර්ධන කාර්යාංශය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "150,000කට ආසන්නයි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "දෙවැනි",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Ginige",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "හතරවන",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "දෙවැනි",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "කොවිඩ්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "අවුරුදු 60 ක්",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "දෙවැනි",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "මාස තුනක්",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "පළමුවන",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "දෙවැනි",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "5,000 ක් පමණ පමණි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Ginige",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "පසුගිය සති කිහිපය",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "අජිත් සිරිවර්ධන",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "இரண்டாவது பூஸ்டர் டோஸ் வெளியீட்டின் முன்னேற்றம் திருப்திகரமாக இல்லை: டாக்டர் கினிகே",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "கோவிட்-19 அச்சுறுத்தலில் இருந்து இலங்கை இன்னும் வெளிவரவில்லை என்று கூறிய தொற்றுநோயியல் பிரிவு பணிப்பாளர் டாக்டர் சமிதா கினிகே, கோவிட் தடுப்பூசியின் நான்காவது டோஸ் அல்லது இரண்டாவது பூஸ்டர் டோஸைப் பெறுவதற்கான முன்னேற்றம் திருப்திகரமாக இல்லை என்று கூறினார். .",
        "சுகாதார மேம்பாட்டு பணியகத்தில் நடைபெற்ற செய்தி மாநாட்டில் அவர் கூறுகையில், தற்போது 150,000 பேர் மட்டுமே இரண்டாவது பூஸ்டர் டோஸை பெற்றுள்ளனர்.",
        "கொவிட் தடுப்பூசியின் நான்காவது டோஸ் அல்லது இரண்டாவது பூஸ்டர் டோஸ் 60 வயதுக்கு மேற்பட்டவர்கள் மற்றும் நாட்பட்ட நோய்கள் உள்ளவர்கள் போன்ற அதிக ஆபத்துள்ள குழுக்களுக்கு பரிந்துரைக்கப்படுவதாக டாக்டர் கினிகே கூறினார்.",
        "\"முதல் பூஸ்டர் டோஸைப் பெற்ற மூன்று மாதங்களுக்குப் பிறகு இரண்டாவது பூஸ்டர் டோஸ் எடுக்கப்பட வேண்டும் என்று நாங்கள் பரிந்துரைக்கிறோம். இருப்பினும், இரண்டாவது பூஸ்டர் டோஸைப் பெறுவதற்கான முன்னேற்றம் திருப்திகரமாக இல்லை.",
        "20 வயதுக்கு மேற்பட்டவர்களுக்கு தேவையான அனைத்து தடுப்பூசிகளும் வாங்கப்பட்டுவிட்டதால், தற்போது போதுமான அளவு கோவிட் தடுப்பூசிகள் கையிருப்பில் இருப்பதாகவும், தற்போது தினமும் சுமார் 5,000 பேர் மட்டுமே தடுப்பூசியைப் பெற வருவதாகவும் அவர் கூறினார்.",
        "கடந்த சில வாரங்களாக கொவிட் நோயாளர்களின் எண்ணிக்கையில் அதிகரிப்பு ஏற்பட்டுள்ளதாகவும், நோய்த்தொற்றுகளின் எண்ணிக்கை அதிகரிப்பதற்கு ஏற்ப இறப்பு எண்ணிக்கையும் அதிகரித்து வருவதாகவும் டாக்டர் கினிகே தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "சமூகத்தினரிடையே பரவும் நோயைத் தடுக்க, பூஸ்டர் டோஸைப் பெறுவதும், சுகாதார நடைமுறைகளை மக்கள் ஏற்றுக்கொள்வதும் இன்றியமையாதது என்றார். (அஜித் சிறிவர்தன)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "இரண்டாவது",
          "label": "ORDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "Ginige",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "தொற்றுநோயியல் பிரிவு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "சமிதா கினிகே",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "நான்காவது",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "இரண்டாவது",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "கோவிட்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "சுகாதார மேம்பாட்டு பணியகம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "கிட்டத்தட்ட 150,000 மட்டுமே",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "இரண்டாவது",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Ginige",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "நான்காவது",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "இரண்டாவது",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "கோவிட்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "60 ஆண்டுகள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இரண்டாவது",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "மூன்று மாதங்கள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "முதலில்",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "இரண்டாவது",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "சுமார் 5,000 மட்டுமே",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Ginige",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "கடந்த சில வாரங்களாக",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "அஜித் சிறிவர்தன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}