{
  "newspaper_id": "news-first-lk",
  "url": "https://www.newsfirst.lk/2022/07/24/two-arrested-with-heroin-worth-rs-16mn/",
  "time_ut": 1658645580,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Two arrested with heroin worth Rs. 16Mn",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Two arrested with heroin worth Rs. 16Mn",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); Mount Lavinia Police arrested two suspects in possession of heroin worth over Rs. 16 million in Aththidiya.",
        "The two suspects, identified as 35 and 37 year old residents of Aththidiya, were arrested by the Mount Lavinia Police Crimes Investigations Division during a raid.",
        "The Police managed to seize 855g of heroin worth over Rs. 16 million, an electronic scale and a sum of Rs. 41,000 suspected to have been earned via the sale of heroin.",
        "One of the suspects were identified as a Dehiwala Mount Lavinia Municipal Council worker, while it was revealed that the illegal business was being conducted in association with an inmate at the Boossa prison and another suspect residing overseas."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Two",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "16Mn",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "News 1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Mount Lavinia Police",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "two",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "16 million",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Aththidiya",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "two",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "35 and 37 year old",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Aththidiya",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Mount Lavinia Police Crimes Investigations Division",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "855",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "16 million",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "41,000",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "One",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Dehiwala Mount Lavinia Municipal Council",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Boossa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "රුපියල් කෝටි 100ක හෙරොයින් සමඟ දෙදෙනෙක් අත්අඩංගුවට මිලියන 16",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); රුපියල් කෝටියකට අධික වටිනාකමකින් යුත් හෙරොයින් ළඟ තබාගෙන සිටි සැකකරුවන් දෙදෙනෙකු ගල්කිස්ස පොලිසිය විසින් අත්අඩංගුවට ගෙන තිබේ. අත්තිඩියේ මිලියන 16යි.",
        "අත්තිඩිය ප්‍රදේශයේ පදිංචි 35 සහ 37 හැවිරිදි සැකකරුවන් දෙදෙනා ගල්කිස්ස පොලිසියේ අපරාධ විමර්ශන කොට්ඨාශය විසින් සිදුකළ වැටලීමකදී අත්අඩංගුවට ගෙන ඇත.",
        "රුපියල් කෝටියකට අධික වටිනාකමකින් යුත් හෙරොයින් ග්‍රෑම් 855ක් අත්අඩංගුවට ගැනීමට පොලිසිය සමත් විය. මිලියන 16ක්, ඉලෙක්ට්‍රොනික තරාදියක් සහ රු. 41,000ක් හෙරොයින් අලෙවියෙන් උපයා ගත් බවට සැක කෙරේ.",
        "එක් සැකකරුවෙකු දෙහිවල ගල්කිස්ස මහ නගර සභාවේ සේවකයෙකු බවට හඳුනාගෙන ඇති අතර, බූස්ස බන්ධනාගාරයේ රැඳවියෙකු සහ විදේශගතව සිටින තවත් සැකකරුවෙකු සමඟ එක්ව මෙම නීතිවිරෝධී ව්‍යාපාරය පවත්වාගෙන යන බවට අනාවරණ වී තිබෙනවා."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "දෙක",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "මිලියන 16",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "News 1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගල්කිස්ස පොලිසිය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "දෙක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "මිලියන 16 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "අත්තිඩිය",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "දෙක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "වයස අවුරුදු 35 සහ 37 යි",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "අත්තිඩිය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගල්කිස්ස පොලිසියේ අපරාධ විමර්ශන කොට්ඨාශය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "855",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "මිලියන 16 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "41,000 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "එක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "දෙහිවල ගල්කිස්ස මහ නගර සභාව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "බූස්ස",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "ரூபாய் மதிப்புள்ள ஹெரோயினுடன் இருவர் கைது. 16 மில்லியன்",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); ஒரு இலட்சம் ரூபாவுக்கும் அதிகமான பெறுமதியான ஹெரோயின் போதைப்பொருளுடன் இரு சந்தேக நபர்களை கல்கிசை பொலிஸார் கைது செய்துள்ளனர். அத்திடியவில் 16 மில்லியன்.",
        "கல்கிசை பொலிஸ் குற்றப் புலனாய்வுப் பிரிவினரால் மேற்கொள்ளப்பட்ட சுற்றிவளைப்பின் போது அத்திடிய பிரதேசத்தைச் சேர்ந்த 35 மற்றும் 37 வயதுடைய சந்தேக நபர்கள் இருவரும் கைது செய்யப்பட்டுள்ளனர்.",
        "இதன்போது 855 கிராம் ஹெராயின் போதைப் பொருளை பொலிஸார் கைப்பற்றியுள்ளனர். 16 மில்லியன், மின்னணு அளவுகோல் மற்றும் ரூ. 41,000 ஹெரோயின் விற்பனை மூலம் சம்பாதித்ததாக சந்தேகிக்கப்படுகிறது.",
        "சந்தேகநபர்களில் ஒருவர் தெஹிவளை கல்கிசை மாநகர சபை ஊழியர் என அடையாளம் காணப்பட்ட நிலையில், பூஸ்ஸ சிறைச்சாலையில் உள்ள கைதி ஒருவருக்கும் வெளிநாட்டில் வசிக்கும் மற்றுமொரு சந்தேகநபர் ஒருவருக்கும் இணைந்து இந்த சட்டவிரோத வியாபாரம் நடத்தப்பட்டமை தெரியவந்துள்ளது."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "இரண்டு",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "16 மில்லியன்",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "News 1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "கல்கிசை பொலிஸ்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இரண்டு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "16 மில்லியன்",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "அத்திடியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இரண்டு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "35 மற்றும் 37 வயது",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "அத்திடியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "கல்கிசை பொலிஸ் குற்றப் புலனாய்வுப் பிரிவு",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "855",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "16 மில்லியன்",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "41,000",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஒன்று",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "தெஹிவளை கல்கிசை மாநகர சபை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "பூஸ்ஸா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}