{
  "newspaper_id": "lankadeepa-lk",
  "url": "https://www.lankadeepa.lk/news/ලංකාපුර-ප්‍රා-ලේ-කාර්යාලයේ-ප්‍රධාන-පරිපාලන-නිලධාරිනිය-ඝාතනය-කරයි/101-615808",
  "time_ut": 1656904606,
  "original_lang": "si",
  "original_title": "ලංකාපුර ප්‍රා.ලේ කාර්යාලයේ ප්‍රධාන පරිපාලන නිලධාරිනිය ඝාතනය කරයි",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "The chief administrative officer of the Lankapura district office is killed",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "Lankapura Police say that the chief administrative officer of the Polonnaruwa Lankapura Divisional Secretariat was hacked to death with sharp weapons at her home at around 2.30 this morning.",
        "According to the investigating police, the person who has been murdered is ML Yamuna Patmini, a 42-year-old mother of two who resided at Talpotha Polonnaru address.",
        "Police say that the regional secretary's husband and two children were present when she was killed.",
        "The Lankapura police say that they have started preliminary investigations to find out who might have killed her and for what reason.",
        "Further investigations related to the incident are being carried out by a team of special police officers as per the instructions of Polonnaruwa Senior Superintendent of Police Mr. Oshan Hewawitharana."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Lankapura",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "the Polonnaruwa Lankapura",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ML Yamuna Patmini",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "42-year-old",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "two",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Talpotha Polonnaru",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "two",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Lankapura",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Polonnaruwa Senior Superintendent of Police",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Oshan Hewawitharana",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "ලංකාපුර ප්‍රා.ලේ කාර්යාලයේ ප්‍රධාන පරිපාලන නිලධාරිනිය ඝාතනය කරයි",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "පොලොන්නරුව ලංකාපුර ප්‍රාදේශීය ලේකම් කාර්යාලයේ ප්‍රධාන පරිපාලන නිලධාරිනිය අද අලුයම 2.30 ට පමණ ඇයගේ නිවසේදී තියුණු ආයුධවලින් කපා කොටා ඝාතනය කර ඇති බව ලංකාපුර පොලිසිය කියයි.",
        "මෙලෙස ඝාතනයට ලක්ව ඇත්තේ, තල්පොත පොළොන්නරු ලිපිනයේ පදිංචිව සිටි 42 හැවිරිදි දෙදරු මවක වන එම්.එල් යමුනා පත්මිණි යන අය බව පරීක්ෂණ සිදුකරන පොලිසිය කියයි.",
        "ඝාතනයට ලක් වෙද්දී ප්‍රදේශීය ලේකම්වරියගේ ස්වාමියා සහ දරුවන් දෙදෙනාද සිට ඇති බව පොලිසිය සඳහන් කරයි.",
        "ඇය කවුරුන් විසින් ඝාතනය කරන්නට ඇත්ද, කුමන හේතුවක් මත ඝාතනය කළාද යන්න, මූලික පරීක්ෂණ කටයුතු ආරම්භ කර ඇති බව ලංකාපුර පොලිසිය කියයි.",
        "සිද්ධිය සම්බන්ධ වැඩිදුර පරීක්ෂණ කටයුතු පොලොන්නරුව ජ්‍යෙෂ්ඨ පොලිස් අධිකාරී ඕශාන් හේවාවිතාරණ මහතාගේ උපදෙස් පරිදි විශේෂ පොලිස් නිලධාරීන් කණ්ඩායමක් විසින් සිදුකරයි."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ලංකාපුරය",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "පොලොන්නරුව ලංකාපුරය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "එම් එල් යමුනා පත්මිණී",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "42 හැවිරිදිය",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "දෙක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "තල්පොත පොළොන්නරු",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "දෙක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ලංකාපුරය",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "පොළොන්නරුව ජ්‍යෙෂ්ඨ පොලිස් අධිකාරි",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඔෂාන් හේවාවිතාරණ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "லங்காபுர மாவட்ட அலுவலகத்தின் தலைமை நிர்வாக அதிகாரி கொல்லப்பட்டார்",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "பொலன்னறுவை லங்காபுர பிரதேச செயலகத்தின் பிரதான நிர்வாக அதிகாரி இன்று அதிகாலை 2.30 மணியளவில் அவரது வீட்டில் கூரிய ஆயுதங்களால் வெட்டி படுகொலை செய்யப்பட்டதாக லங்காபுர பொலிஸார் தெரிவிக்கின்றனர்.",
        "தல்பொத பொலன்னறு முகவரியில் வசிக்கும் எம்.எல்.யமுனா பத்மினி என்ற 42 வயதுடைய இரண்டு பிள்ளைகளின் தாயாரே இவ்வாறு கொலைசெய்யப்பட்டுள்ளதாக விசாரணைகளை பொலிஸார் மேற்கொண்டுள்ளனர்.",
        "பிரதேச செயலாளரின் கணவரும் இரண்டு பிள்ளைகளும் கொல்லப்பட்ட போது அங்கு இருந்ததாக பொலிஸார் தெரிவிக்கின்றனர்.",
        "அவளை யார் கொலை செய்திருக்கலாம், என்ன காரணம் என்று கண்டறிய முதற்கட்ட விசாரணைகளை ஆரம்பித்துள்ளதாக லங்காபுர பொலிஸார் தெரிவிக்கின்றனர்.",
        "சம்பவம் தொடர்பான மேலதிக விசாரணைகளை பொலன்னறுவை சிரேஷ்ட பொலிஸ் அத்தியட்சகர் திரு.ஓஷான் ஹேவாவிதாரணவின் பணிப்புரைக்கமைய விசேட பொலிஸ் அதிகாரிகள் குழுவினால் மேற்கொள்ளப்பட்டு வருகின்றது."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "லங்காபுர",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "பொலன்னறுவை லங்காபுர",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "எம்.எல்.யமுனா பத்மினி",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "42 வயது",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இரண்டு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "தல்பொத பொலன்னாறு",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இரண்டு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "லங்காபுர",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பொலன்னறுவை சிரேஷ்ட பொலிஸ் அத்தியட்சகர்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஒஷான் ஹேவாவிதாரண",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}