{
  "newspaper_id": "lankadeepa-lk",
  "url": "https://www.lankadeepa.lk/news/මෝටර්-රථ-දෙපාර්තමේන්තුවේ-ප්‍රධානියෙක්-ටෙන්ඩර්-මගඩියක/101-615734",
  "time_ut": 1656739651,
  "original_lang": "si",
  "original_title": "මෝටර් රථ දෙපාර්තමේන්තුවේ ප්‍රධානියෙක් ටෙන්ඩර් මගඩියක",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "A head of the motor department is in a tender trap",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "It is reported that a senior official of the Motor Transport Department's Driving License Printing Division has obtained a contract to supply 200 computers by submitting fake business certificates.",
        "Sources state that this information was revealed during an investigation based on a complaint received by the Motor Transport Department's Head Office Audit Division and that the accused officer also holds a high position in the Sri Lanka Army.",
        "It is reported that the relevant senior military officer has submitted a registered company in the name of his wife and obtained the tender for importing computers and one computer has been supplied at a price of over two lakh rupees.",
        "It is reported from the Department of Motor Transport that during the audit, the computers were imported through an unregistered company at a higher price.",
        "The Sri Lanka Army provided the driver's license printing due to complaints of corruption and irregularities in the printing of the driver's license done through the Werahera office, and even so, it is alleged that there are still more irregularities in the printing of the driver's license."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "the motor department",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "the Motor Transport Department's Driving License Printing Division",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "200",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the Motor Transport Department's",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Head Office Audit Division",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Sri Lanka Army",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "one",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the Department of Motor Transport",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "The Sri Lanka Army",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Werahera",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "මෝටර් රථ දෙපාර්තමේන්තුවේ ප්‍රධානියෙක් ටෙන්ඩර් මගඩියක",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "මෝටර් රථ ප්‍රවාහන දෙපාර්තමේන්තුවේ රියදුරු බලපත් මුද්‍රණ අංශයේ උසස් නිලධාරියෙක් ව්‍යාජ ව්‍යාපාර සහතික ඉදිරිපත් කර පරිගණක 200 ක් සැපයීමේ කොන්ත්‍රාතත්ුවක් ලබාගෙන ඇතැයි වාර්තා වේ.",
        "මෝටර් රථ ප්‍රවාහන දෙපාර්තමේන්තු ප්‍රධාන කාර්යාල විගණන අංශය ලැබුණු පැමිණිල්ලකට අනුව කළ පරීක්‍ෂණයකදී මෙම තොරතුරු අනාවරණය වී ඇති බවත් චෝදනාව එල්ල වී ඇති නිලධාරියා ශ්‍රී ලංකා යුද හමුදාවේ ද උසස් තනතුරක් දරන්නෙකු බවත් ආරංචිමාර්ග සඳහන් කරයි.",
        "අදාල උසස් හමුදා නිලධාරියා සිය බිරිදගේ නමින් ලියාපදිංචි සමාගමක් ඉදිරිපත් කර පරිගණක ගෙන්වීමේ ටෙන්ඩරය ලබාගෙන ඇති බවත් එක් පරිගණකයක් රුපියල් ලක්ෂ දෙකකට අධික මිලකට සපයා ඇති බවත් වාර්තා වේ.",
        "මෙම පරිගණක සැයීමේදී පරිගණක වැඩි මිලක් ඉදිරිපත් කර ලියාපදිංචි නොමැති සමාගමක් හරහා ගෙන්වා ඇතැයි විගණන පරීක්‍ෂණයේදී හෙළිවී ඇතැයි මෝටර් රථ ප්‍රවාහන දෙපාර්තමේන්තුවෙන් වාර්තා වේ.",
        "වේරහැර කාර්යාලය හරහා සිදුකරන රියදුරු බලපත් මුද්‍රණයේදී දූෂණ සහ අක්‍රමිකතා සිදුවන බවට ලැබුණු පැමිණිලි හේතුවෙන් රියදුරු බලපත් මුද්‍රණය ශ්‍රී ලංකා යුද හමුදාව ලබාදුන් අතර එසේ වුවද රියදුරු බලපත් මුද්‍රණයේදී තව දුරටත් අක්‍රමිකතා සිදුවන බවට චෝදනා එල්ල වේ."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "මෝටර් රථ දෙපාර්තමේන්තුව",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "මෝටර් රථ ප්‍රවාහන දෙපාර්තමේන්තුවේ රියදුරු බලපත්‍ර මුද්‍රණ අංශය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "200",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "මෝටර් රථ ප්රවාහන දෙපාර්තමේන්තුවේ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ප්‍රධාන කාර්යාලයේ විගණන අංශය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකා යුද හමුදාව",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "එක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "මෝටර් රථ ප්රවාහන දෙපාර්තමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකා යුද හමුදාව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "වේරහැර",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "மோட்டார் துறை தலைவர் ஒருவர் டெண்டர் பொறியில் சிக்கியுள்ளார்",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "மோட்டார் போக்குவரத்து திணைக்களத்தின் சாரதி அனுமதிப்பத்திரம் அச்சடிக்கும் பிரிவின் உயர் அதிகாரி ஒருவர் போலியான வர்த்தக சான்றிதழ்களை சமர்ப்பித்து 200 கணினிகளை வழங்குவதற்கான ஒப்பந்தத்தை பெற்றுள்ளதாக தெரிவிக்கப்படுகிறது.",
        "மோட்டார் போக்குவரத்து திணைக்களத்தின் தலைமை அலுவலக கணக்காய்வு பிரிவிற்கு கிடைத்த முறைப்பாட்டின் அடிப்படையில் மேற்கொள்ளப்பட்ட விசாரணையின் போதே இந்த தகவல் தெரியவந்துள்ளதாகவும், குற்றம் சுமத்தப்பட்ட அதிகாரி இலங்கை இராணுவத்தில் உயர் பதவியையும் வகிக்கின்றார் எனவும் தகவல்கள் தெரிவிக்கின்றன.",
        "குறித்த சிரேஷ்ட இராணுவ அதிகாரி தனது மனைவியின் பெயரில் பதிவு செய்யப்பட்ட நிறுவனமொன்றை சமர்ப்பித்து கணனிகளை இறக்குமதி செய்வதற்கான டெண்டரைப் பெற்று இரண்டு இலட்சம் ரூபாவிற்கும் அதிகமான விலையில் கணனி ஒன்று வழங்கப்பட்டுள்ளதாக தெரிவிக்கப்படுகின்றது.",
        "தணிக்கையின் போது அதிக விலைக்கு பதிவு செய்யப்படாத நிறுவனம் ஒன்றின் ஊடாக குறித்த கணனிகள் இறக்குமதி செய்யப்பட்டுள்ளதாக மோட்டார் போக்குவரத்து திணைக்களம் தெரிவித்துள்ளது.",
        "வேரஹெர அலுவலகத்தினூடாக மேற்கொள்ளப்பட்ட சாரதி அனுமதிப்பத்திரம் அச்சிடுவதில் ஊழல் மற்றும் முறைகேடுகள் இடம்பெற்றதாக எழுந்த முறைப்பாடுகள் காரணமாகவே இலங்கை இராணுவம் சாரதி அனுமதிப்பத்திரத்தை அச்சிடுவதற்கு வழங்கியது."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "மோட்டார் துறை",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "மோட்டார் போக்குவரத்து துறையின் ஓட்டுநர் உரிமம் அச்சிடும் பிரிவு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "200",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "மோட்டார் போக்குவரத்து துறையின்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "தலைமை அலுவலக தணிக்கை பிரிவு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை இராணுவம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஒன்று",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "மோட்டார் போக்குவரத்து துறை",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை இராணுவம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "வெரஹெரா",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}