{
  "newspaper_id": "daily-mirror-lk",
  "url": "https://www.dailymirror.lk/breaking_news/Main-framework-of-restructuring-CEB-to-be-presented-to-Cabinet/108-244269",
  "time_ut": 1662277457,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Main framework of restructuring CEB to be presented to Cabinet",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Main framework of restructuring CEB to be presented to Cabinet",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "The main framework of restructuring the Ceylon Electricity Board (CEB) will be presented to the cabinet of ministers by the end of this month, Power and Energy Minister Kanchana Wijesekera said.",
        "Earlier, the minister said a committee has been appointed to restructure the CEB.",
        "The minister said today that he had discussed proposals of the CEB reforms committee this morning.",
        "The committee has met with development agencies, sector experts, stakeholders and will meet political parties and Public Utilities Commission of Sri Lanka (PUCSL) next week, Minister Wijesekera said.(DSB)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "CEB",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "Cabinet",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "the Ceylon Electricity Board",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the end of this month",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kanchana Wijesekera",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "CEB",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "CEB",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "this morning",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Public Utilities Commission of Sri Lanka",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "PUCSL",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "next week",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Wijesekera",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "ලංවිම ප්‍රතිව්‍යුහගත කිරීමේ ප්‍රධාන රාමුව කැබිනට් මණ්ඩලයට ඉදිරිපත් කිරීමට නියමිතය",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "ලංකා විදුලිබල මණ්ඩලය ප්‍රතිව්‍යුහගත කිරීමේ ප්‍රධාන රාමුව මේ මස අගදී අමාත්‍ය මණ්ඩලයට ඉදිරිපත් කරන බව විදුලිබල හා බලශක්ති අමාත්‍ය කංචන විජේසේකර මහතා පවසයි.",
        "මීට පෙර අමාත්‍යවරයා කියා සිටියේ විදුලිබල මණ්ඩලය ප්‍රතිව්‍යුහගත කිරීම සඳහා කමිටුවක් පත් කර ඇති බවයි.",
        "අමාත්‍යවරයා කියා සිටියේ අද පෙරවරුවේ ලංවිම ප්‍රතිසංස්කරණ කමිටුවේ යෝජනා සම්බන්ධයෙන් සාකච්ඡා කළ බවයි.",
        "මෙම කමිටුව සංවර්ධන ආයතන, අංශ විශේෂඥයින්, පාර්ශවකරුවන් හමුවී ඇති අතර ඉදිරි සතියේ දේශපාලන පක්ෂ සහ ශ්‍රී ලංකා මහජන උපයෝගිතා කොමිෂන් සභාව (PUCSL) හමුවීමට නියමිත බව අමාත්‍ය විජේසේකර මහතා පැවසීය.(DSB)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ලංවිම",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "මණ්ඩල",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ලංකා විදුලිබල මණ්ඩලය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "මේ මාසයේ අවසානය",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "කාංචන විජේසේකර",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ලංවිම",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ලංවිම",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මේ උදෑසන",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකා මහජන උපයෝගිතා කොමිෂන් සභාව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "PUCSL",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඊළඟ සතිය",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "විජේසේකර",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "CEBயை மறுசீரமைப்பதற்கான பிரதான கட்டமைப்பு அமைச்சரவைக்கு வழங்கப்படவுள்ளது",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "இலங்கை மின்சார சபையை மறுசீரமைப்பதற்கான பிரதான கட்டமைப்பு இம்மாத இறுதிக்குள் அமைச்சரவைக்கு சமர்ப்பிக்கப்படும் என மின்வலு மற்றும் எரிசக்தி அமைச்சர் காஞ்சன விஜேசேகர தெரிவித்துள்ளார்.",
        "முன்னதாக, இலங்கை மின்சார சபையை மறுசீரமைக்க குழுவொன்று நியமிக்கப்பட்டுள்ளதாக அமைச்சர் தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "மின்சார சபையின் சீர்திருத்தக் குழுவின் முன்மொழிவுகள் குறித்து இன்று காலை கலந்துரையாடியதாக அமைச்சர் இன்று தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "இந்தக் குழு, அபிவிருத்தி முகவர், துறை நிபுணர்கள், பங்குதாரர்களை சந்தித்து அடுத்த வாரம் அரசியல் கட்சிகள் மற்றும் இலங்கை பொதுப் பயன்பாடுகள் ஆணைக்குழுவை (PUCSL) சந்திக்கும் என அமைச்சர் விஜேசேகர தெரிவித்தார்.(DSB)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "CEB",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "மந்திரி சபை",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை மின்சார சபை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்த மாத இறுதியில்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "காஞ்சனா விஜேசேகர",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "CEB",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "CEB",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று காலை",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை பொது பயன்பாட்டு ஆணைக்குழு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "PUCSL",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "அடுத்த வாரம்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "விஜேசேகர",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}