{
  "newspaper_id": "daily-mirror-lk",
  "url": "https://www.dailymirror.lk/business-news/Litro-gas-denies-statements-regarding-salary-scale/273-240212",
  "time_ut": 1656707660,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Litro gas denies statements regarding salary scale",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Litro gas denies statements regarding salary scale",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "Says baseless allegations have been made with intention of causing a negative impact on goodwill of company",
        "Points out less than 2% of annual turnover spent on salaries",
        "Asserts company severely impacted by rising global LPG prices, foreign currency fluctuations and not increasing prices of LPG in SL",
        "Stresses company is built on a model of efficiency and professionalism",
        "Litro Gas Lanka, Sri Lanka’s national LPG provider, yesterday denied the statements making rounds on social media, regarding its salary structure.",
        "In a statement to the media, it said the company spends less than 2 percent of its annual turnover on salaries for its less than 200-member staff.  “Our team includes experts and professionals with global and local experience in their chosen field of expertise and are not paid state-backed pensions or other tax-free incentives or facilities available for government employees,” said Litro Gas Lanka Chairman and CEO Muditha Peiris.",
        "He elaborated that many on the Litro Gas Lanka team have continued their career from Lanka Gas Co and Royal Shell Gas and have been serving for well over 20 years. The Litro Gas Lanka employees have always taken pride in their core values of delivering performance as a sustainable and tightly knit team, stressed Peiris.",
        "He added that while the salary structure of Litro Gas Lanka is governed by Companies Act of 2007 No 07 and regulated to be on par with other state-owned enterprises (SOEs), it is in no way as per the incorrect and false information shared on social media.",
        "He stressed the baseless allegations have been made with the intention of causing a negative impact on the goodwill generated by the company in the minds of the consumers.",
        "“The company vehemently denies the allegations and reiterates that such deliberate acts of sabotage are aimed at causing great harm and damage to the good name and reputation Litro Gas Lanka has cultivated over the years as the country’s leading LPG provider,” said Peiris.",
        "He pointed out that the company has been severely impacted by the rising global LPG prices, foreign currency fluctuations and not increasing the prices of LPG in Sri Lanka in keeping with the changing international rates of LPG.",
        "The once robust entity that consistently performed as a leading SOE with growth potential, has been incurring losses recently, having passed on the cost benefit to the consumers for a considerable period of time, pointed out Peiris.",
        "The statement highlighted that as a fully-owned subsidiary of Sri Lanka Insurance Corporation, Litro Gas Lanka has been a major contributor towards the Treasury coffers since inception. The company is built on a model of efficiency and professionalism and has inculcated in its staff ethics of efficiency, effectiveness and being result oriented, the factors that have played a major role in its success."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "less than 2%",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "annual",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "LPG",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "SL",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "Litro Gas Lanka",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka’s",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "LPG",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "yesterday",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "less than 2 percent",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "annual",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "less than",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "200",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Litro Gas Lanka",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Muditha Peiris",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the Litro Gas Lanka",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Lanka Gas Co",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "well over 20 years",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "The Litro Gas Lanka",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Peiris",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Litro Gas Lanka",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "Litro Gas Lanka",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the years",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Peiris",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "LPG",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "LPG",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Peiris",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka Insurance Corporation",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Litro Gas Lanka",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Treasury",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "වැටුප් පරිමාණය සම්බන්ධ ප්‍රකාශ ලිට්‍රෝ ගෑස් ප්‍රතික්ෂේප කරයි",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "සමාගමේ හොඳ හිතට අහිතකර බලපෑමක් ඇති කිරීමේ අරමුණින් පදනම් විරහිත චෝදනා එල්ල කර ඇති බව පවසයි",
        "වැටුප් සඳහා වැය වන වාර්ෂික පිරිවැටුමෙන් 2%කට වඩා අඩු ප්‍රමාණයක් පෙන්වා දෙයි",
        "ගෝලීය LPG මිල ඉහළ යාම, විදේශ මුදල් උච්චාවචනයන් සහ ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ LPG මිල වැඩි නොකිරීම හේතුවෙන් Asserts සමාගමට දැඩි බලපෑමක් එල්ල වී ඇත.",
        "ආතති සමාගම ගොඩනඟා ඇත්තේ කාර්යක්ෂමතාව සහ වෘත්තීයභාවය පිළිබඳ ආකෘතියක් මත ය",
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ ජාතික LPG සපයන්නා වන ලිට්‍රෝ ගෑස් ලංකා, ඊයේ සිය වැටුප් ව්‍යුහය සම්බන්ධයෙන් සමාජ මාධ්‍ය ඔස්සේ කෙරෙන ප්‍රකාශ ප්‍රතික්ෂේප කළේය.",
        "මාධ්‍ය වෙත ප්‍රකාශයක් කරමින්, සමාගම සිය වාර්ෂික පිරිවැටුමෙන් සියයට 2 කටත් අඩු ප්‍රමාණයක් සාමාජිකයින් 200 කට අඩු කාර්ය මණ්ඩලය සඳහා වැටුප් සඳහා වැය කරන බව පැවසීය. ලිට්‍රෝ ගෑස් ලංකා සමාගමේ සභාපති සහ ප්‍රධාන විධායක නිලධාරී මුදිත පීරිස් මහතා පැවසුවේ, “අපගේ කණ්ඩායමට ඔවුන් තෝරාගත් විශේෂඥ ක්ෂේත්‍රයේ ගෝලීය සහ දේශීය අත්දැකීම් ඇති විශේෂඥයින් සහ වෘත්තිකයන් ඇතුළත් වන අතර රාජ්‍ය අනුග්‍රහය සහිත විශ්‍රාම වැටුප් හෝ වෙනත් බදු රහිත දිරිගැන්වීම් හෝ රාජ්‍ය සේවකයින් සඳහා ලබා ගත හැකි පහසුකම් නොමැත.",
        "Litro Gas Lanka කණ්ඩායමේ බොහෝ දෙනෙක් Lanka Gas Co සහ Royal Shell Gas වෙතින් තම වෘත්තීය ජීවිතය කරගෙන ගොස් වසර 20කට වැඩි කාලයක් සේවය කරන බව ඔහු විස්තර කළේය. ලිට්‍රෝ ගෑස් ලංකා සේවකයින් සෑම විටම තිරසාර හා දැඩි ලෙස බැඳී ඇති කණ්ඩායමක් ලෙස කාර්ය සාධනය ලබා දීමේ ඔවුන්ගේ මූලික වටිනාකම් ගැන ආඩම්බර වන බව පීරිස් අවධාරණය කළේය.",
        "ලිට්‍රෝ ගෑස් ලංකා හි වැටුප් ව්‍යුහය 2007 අංක 07 දරන සමාගම් පනත මගින් පාලනය වන අතර අනෙකුත් රාජ්‍ය ව්‍යවසායන් (SOEs) සමඟ සමපාත වන ලෙස නියාමනය කර ඇතත්, එය කිසිඳු ආකාරයකින් බෙදා නොගත් වැරදි සහ අසත්‍ය තොරතුරු අනුව නොවන බව ඔහු පැවසීය. සමාජ මාධ්ය.",
        "පදනම් විරහිත චෝදනා එල්ල කර ඇත්තේ සමාගම පාරිභෝගිකයන් තුළ ඇති කර තිබෙන හොඳ හිතට අහිතකර බලපෑමක් ඇති කිරීමේ අරමුණින් බව ඔහු අවධාරණය කළේය.",
        "\"සමාගම එම චෝදනා තරයේ ප්‍රතික්ෂේප කරන අතර, මෙවැනි හිතාමතා කඩාකප්පල්කාරී ක්‍රියාවන් සිදු කරන්නේ රටේ ප්‍රමුඛ පෙළේ LPG සැපයුම්කරු ලෙස ලිට්‍රෝ ගෑස් ලංකා සමාගම වසර ගණනාවක් තිස්සේ වගා කර ඇති හොඳ නමට සහ කීර්ති නාමයට විශාල හානියක් හා හානියක් සිදුකිරීමේ අරමුණින් බව යලි අවධාරණය කරයි,\" පීරිස් පැවසීය.",
        "ගෝලීය වශයෙන් ඉහළ යන LPG මිල ගණන්, විදේශ මුදල් උච්චාවචනයන් සහ වෙනස් වන ජාත්‍යන්තර LPG මිලට අනුව ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ LPG මිල ඉහළ නොදැමීම නිසා සමාගමට දැඩි බලපෑමක් එල්ල වී ඇති බව ඔහු පෙන්වා දුන්නේය.",
        "වර්ධන විභවයක් සහිත ප්‍රමුඛ පෙළේ SOE ලෙස අඛණ්ඩව ක්‍රියා කළ ශක්තිමත් ආයතනයක්, සැලකිය යුතු කාලයක් පාරිභෝගිකයන් වෙත පිරිවැය ප්‍රතිලාභය ලබා දෙමින් මෑතක සිට පාඩු ලබමින් සිටින බව පීරිස් පෙන්වා දුන්නේය.",
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකා රක්‍ෂණ සංස්ථාවේ පූර්ණ අනුබද්ධිත ආයතනයක් ලෙස ලිට්‍රෝ ගෑස් ලංකා සමාගම ආරම්භයේ සිටම භාණ්ඩාගාර භාණ්‌ඩාගාර සඳහා ප්‍රධාන දායකත්වයක්‌ ලබාදී ඇති බව එම ප්‍රකාශයේ සඳහන් වේ. සමාගම කාර්යක්‍ෂමතාව සහ වෘත්තීයභාවය පිළිබඳ ආකෘතියක් මත ගොඩනගා ඇති අතර එහි සාර්ථකත්වය සඳහා ප්‍රධාන කාර්යභාරයක් ඉටු කර ඇති සාධක වන කාර්යක්‍ෂමතාව, ඵලදායිතාව සහ ප්‍රතිඵල නැඹුරු වීම යන මාණ්ඩලික ආචාර ධර්මවලට ඇතුළත් කර ඇත."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "2% ට වඩා අඩු",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "වාර්ෂික",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "එල්.පී.ජී",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "එස්.එල්",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "ලිට්‍රෝ ගෑස් ලංකා",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "එල්.පී.ජී",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඊයේ",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "සියයට 2 ට වඩා අඩුය",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "වාර්ෂික",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "අඩු",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "200",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ලිට්‍රෝ ගෑස් ලංකා",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "මුදිත පීරිස්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ලිට්‍රෝ ගෑස් ලංකා",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ලංකා ගෑස් සමාගම",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "හොඳින් අවුරුදු 20 කට වැඩි",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ලිට්‍රෝ ගෑස් ලංකා",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "පීරිස්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ලිට්‍රෝ ගෑස් ලංකා",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "ලිට්‍රෝ ගෑස් ලංකා",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "වසර",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "පීරිස්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "එල්.පී.ජී",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "එල්.පී.ජී",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "පීරිස්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකා රක්ෂණ සංස්ථාව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ලිට්‍රෝ ගෑස් ලංකා",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "භාණ්ඩාගාර",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "சம்பள அளவு தொடர்பான அறிக்கைகளை Litro gas மறுத்துள்ளது",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "நிறுவனத்தின் நல்லெண்ணத்தில் எதிர்மறையான தாக்கத்தை ஏற்படுத்தும் நோக்கத்துடன் ஆதாரமற்ற குற்றச்சாட்டுகள் கூறப்பட்டுள்ளன",
        "சம்பளத்திற்காக செலவழிக்கப்பட்ட வருடாந்திர விற்றுமுதலில் 2% க்கும் குறைவானதை சுட்டிக்காட்டுகிறது",
        "அதிகரித்துவரும் உலகளாவிய LPG விலைகள், வெளிநாட்டு நாணய ஏற்ற இறக்கங்கள் மற்றும் இலங்கையில் LPG விலைகளை அதிகரிக்காததன் காரணமாக அஸர்ட்ஸ் நிறுவனம் கடுமையாக பாதிக்கப்பட்டுள்ளது.",
        "ஸ்ட்ரெஸ் நிறுவனம் செயல்திறன் மற்றும் தொழில்முறையின் மாதிரியில் கட்டமைக்கப்பட்டுள்ளது",
        "இலங்கையின் தேசிய LPG வழங்குநரான Litro Gas Lanka, தனது சம்பள அமைப்பு தொடர்பில் சமூக ஊடகங்களில் பரப்பப்படும் அறிக்கைகளை நேற்று மறுத்துள்ளது.",
        "ஊடகங்களுக்கு ஒரு அறிக்கையில், நிறுவனம் அதன் 200-க்கும் குறைவான ஊழியர்களுக்கான சம்பளத்திற்காக அதன் வருடாந்திர வருவாயில் 2 சதவீதத்திற்கும் குறைவாகவே செலவிடுகிறது. \"எங்கள் குழுவில் அவர்கள் தேர்ந்தெடுத்த நிபுணத்துவத் துறையில் உலகளாவிய மற்றும் உள்ளூர் அனுபவமுள்ள நிபுணர்கள் மற்றும் தொழில் வல்லுநர்கள் உள்ளனர், மேலும் அரச ஆதரவுடன் கூடிய ஓய்வூதியம் அல்லது அரசாங்க ஊழியர்களுக்கு வரியில்லா சலுகைகள் அல்லது வசதிகள் வழங்கப்படவில்லை\" என்று Litro Gas Lanka தலைவரும் பிரதம நிறைவேற்று அதிகாரியுமான முதித பீரிஸ் தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "லிட்ரோ கேஸ் லங்கா அணியில் உள்ள பலர் லங்கா கேஸ் கோ மற்றும் ரோயல் ஷெல் கேஸ் ஆகியவற்றில் இருந்து தங்கள் வாழ்க்கையைத் தொடர்ந்து 20 ஆண்டுகளுக்கும் மேலாக சேவையாற்றி வருவதாக அவர் விரிவாகக் கூறினார். லிட்ரோ கேஸ் லங்கா ஊழியர்கள் நிலையான மற்றும் இறுக்கமான குழுவாக செயல்திறனை வழங்குவதற்கான அவர்களின் முக்கிய மதிப்புகளில் எப்போதும் பெருமை கொள்கிறார்கள், பீரிஸ் வலியுறுத்தினார்.",
        "Litro Gas Lanka இன் சம்பளக் கட்டமைப்பானது 2007 ஆம் ஆண்டின் 07 ஆம் இலக்க நிறுவனங்களின் சட்டத்தினால் நிர்வகிக்கப்பட்டு, ஏனைய அரச நிறுவனங்களுக்கு (SOEs) இணையாக இருக்குமாறு ஒழுங்குபடுத்தப்பட்டாலும், அது எந்த வகையிலும் தவறான மற்றும் தவறான தகவல்களால் பகிரப்படவில்லை என்றும் அவர் கூறினார். சமூக ஊடகம்.",
        "நுகர்வோர் மனதில் நிறுவனம் ஏற்படுத்திய நல்லெண்ணத்தில் எதிர்மறையான தாக்கத்தை ஏற்படுத்தும் நோக்கில் ஆதாரமற்ற குற்றச்சாட்டுகள் முன்வைக்கப்பட்டுள்ளதாக அவர் வலியுறுத்தினார்.",
        "\"கம்பெனியானது குற்றச்சாட்டுகளை கடுமையாக மறுப்பதுடன், நாட்டின் முன்னணி LPG வழங்குனராக லிட்ரோ கேஸ் லங்கா பல ஆண்டுகளாக வளர்த்து வரும் நற்பெயருக்கும் நற்பெயருக்கும் பெரும் தீங்கு மற்றும் சேதத்தை ஏற்படுத்தும் நோக்கில் இத்தகைய வேண்டுமென்றே நாசவேலை செய்யும் செயல்கள் என்று மீண்டும் வலியுறுத்துகிறது\" என்று பீரிஸ் கூறினார்.",
        "அதிகரித்துவரும் உலகளாவிய LPG விலைகள், வெளிநாட்டு நாணயங்களின் ஏற்ற இறக்கங்கள் மற்றும் மாறிவரும் சர்வதேச LPG விலைகளுக்கு ஏற்ப இலங்கையில் LPG விலைகளை அதிகரிக்காததனால் நிறுவனம் கடுமையாகப் பாதிக்கப்பட்டுள்ளதாக அவர் சுட்டிக்காட்டினார்.",
        "ஒரு காலத்தில் வலுவான SOE ஆக வளர்ச்சித் திறனைக் கொண்ட முன்னணி நிறுவனமாகத் தொடர்ந்து செயல்பட்டது, சமீபகாலமாக நஷ்டத்தைச் சந்தித்து வருகிறது, கணிசமான காலத்திற்கு செலவுப் பலனை நுகர்வோருக்கு வழங்கியது, பீரிஸ் சுட்டிக்காட்டினார்.",
        "இலங்கை காப்புறுதிக் கூட்டுத்தாபனத்தின் முழுமையான துணை நிறுவனமாக, லிட்ரோ கேஸ் லங்கா ஆரம்பம் முதல் திறைசேரி கருவூலத்திற்கு பெரும் பங்களிப்பை வழங்கி வருவதாக அந்த அறிக்கையில் சுட்டிக்காட்டப்பட்டுள்ளது. நிறுவனம் செயல்திறன் மற்றும் நிபுணத்துவத்தின் மாதிரியில் கட்டமைக்கப்பட்டுள்ளது மற்றும் அதன் வெற்றியில் முக்கிய பங்கு வகித்த காரணிகளான செயல்திறன், செயல்திறன் மற்றும் முடிவு சார்ந்த நெறிமுறைகளில் அதன் பணியாளர் நெறிமுறைகளை புகுத்தியுள்ளது."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "2% க்கும் குறைவாக",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆண்டு",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "எல்.பி.ஜி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "எஸ்.எல்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "லிட்ரோ கேஸ் லங்கா",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கையின்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "எல்.பி.ஜி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "நேற்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "2 சதவீதத்திற்கும் குறைவாக",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆண்டு",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "விட குறைவாக",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "200",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "லிட்ரோ கேஸ் லங்கா",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "முதித பீரிஸ்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "லிட்ரோ கேஸ் லங்கா",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "லங்கா கேஸ் கோ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "20 ஆண்டுகளுக்கு மேல்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "லிட்ரோ கேஸ் லங்கா",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "பீரிஸ்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "லிட்ரோ கேஸ் லங்கா",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "லிட்ரோ கேஸ் லங்கா",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆண்டுகள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "பீரிஸ்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "எல்.பி.ஜி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "எல்.பி.ஜி",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பீரிஸ்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை காப்புறுதி கூட்டுத்தாபனம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "லிட்ரோ கேஸ் லங்கா",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "கருவூலம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}