{
  "newspaper_id": "news-first-lk",
  "url": "https://www.newsfirst.lk/2022/07/09/slpp-reforms-group-want-president-to-resign/",
  "time_ut": 1657358520,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "SLPP reforms group want President to resign",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "SLPP reforms group want President to resign",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); The reforms group of the Sri Lanka Podujana Peramuna has called on President Gotabaya Rajapaksa to resign immediately, given the present situation in the country.",
        "The statement further says that they believe that an all-party government should be formed with the participation of all the members of parliament who agree within a certain time frame under a suitable prime minister.",
        "Sri Lanka: Navy ships with unidentified persons left Colombo Port"
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "the Sri Lanka Podujana Peramuna",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "Gotabaya Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Navy",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Colombo Port",
            "label": "PRODUCT"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "ශ්‍රී ලංකා පොදුජන පෙරමුණේ ප්‍රතිසංස්කරණ කණ්ඩායමට ජනාධිපතිවරයා ඉල්ලා අස්විය යුතුයි",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); රටේ පවතින තත්ත්වය හමුවේ වහාම ඉල්ලා අස්වන ලෙස ශ්‍රී ලංකා පොදුජන පෙරමුණේ ප්‍රතිසංස්කරණ කණ්ඩායම ජනාධිපති ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ මහතාගෙන් ඉල්ලා සිටියි.",
        "සුදුසු අගමැතිවරයෙකු යටතේ නියමිත කාල සීමාවක් තුළ එකඟ වන සියලුම මන්ත්‍රීවරුන්ගේ සහභාගීත්වයෙන් සර්ව පාක්ෂික ආණ්ඩුවක් පිහිටුවිය යුතු බවට ඔවුන් විශ්වාස කරන බවද එම නිවේදනයේ වැඩිදුරටත් සඳහන් වේ.",
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකාව: නාඳුනන පුද්ගලයින් සමඟ නාවික හමුදාවේ නෞකා කොළඹ වරායෙන් පිටත් විය"
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකා පොදුජන පෙරමුණ",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "නාවික",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "කොළඹ වරාය",
            "label": "PRODUCT"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "SLPP சீர்திருத்தக் குழு ஜனாதிபதி பதவி விலக வேண்டும்",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); நாட்டின் தற்போதைய நிலைமையை கருத்தில் கொண்டு ஜனாதிபதி கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ஷவை உடனடியாக பதவி விலகுமாறு ஸ்ரீலங்கா பொதுஜன பெரமுனவின் சீர்திருத்தக் குழு கோரிக்கை விடுத்துள்ளது.",
        "பொருத்தமான பிரதமரின் கீழ் குறிப்பிட்ட காலத்திற்குள் உடன்படும் அனைத்து நாடாளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர்களின் பங்களிப்புடன் சர்வகட்சி அரசாங்கம் அமைக்கப்பட வேண்டும் என அவர்கள் நம்புவதாக அந்த அறிக்கையில் மேலும் தெரிவிக்கப்பட்டுள்ளது.",
        "இலங்கை: கொழும்பு துறைமுகத்தில் இருந்து அடையாளம் தெரியாத நபர்களுடன் கடற்படை கப்பல்கள் புறப்பட்டன"
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ஸ்ரீலங்கா பொதுஜன பெரமுனா",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "கடற்படை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "கொழும்பு துறைமுகம்",
            "label": "PRODUCT"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}