{
  "newspaper_id": "tamil-mirror-lk",
  "url": "https://www.tamilmirror.lk/செய்திகள்/ஜனாதிபதியுடன்-ஐ-எம்-எப்-பேச்சுவார்த்தை/175-303052",
  "time_ut": 1661542161,
  "original_lang": "ta",
  "original_title": "ஜனாதிபதியுடன் ஐ.எம்.எப். பேச்சுவார்த்தை",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "IMF with President negotiation",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "Another round of talks between President Ranil Wickremesinghe and representatives of the International Monetary Fund was held yesterday (26) afternoon to find a solution to the current financial crisis in the country.",
        "In this meeting held at the President's Office, President Ranil Wickremesinghe joined the discussion through Zoom technology and positive views were exchanged on both sides.",
        "In today's discussion regarding the Treasury including Electricity Tariff Amendment and Liquor Act, it was agreed to provide the information by next Monday in compliance with the request made by the representatives of the International Monetary Fund to provide the necessary additional information.",
        "International Monetary Fund financial advisers, legal advisers attended yesterday's talks and it was decided to hold the next round of talks next Wednesday (31).",
        "Peter Breuer, Chairman of the International Monetary Fund's Consultative Council, Vice-Chairman Osiro Kosaigo, IMF Permanent Representative to Sri Lanka Tobagans, Chief of Staff to the President and Senior Adviser to the President on National Security Sagala Ratnayake, Secretary to the President Saman Ekanayake, Central Bank Governor Kalanidhi Nandalal Weerasinghe, Senior officials of the Central Bank, including the Treasury Secretary, participated in the discussion. (a)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the International Monetary Fund",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "yesterday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "26) afternoon",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Zoom",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Treasury",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Electricity Tariff Amendment",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Liquor Act",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "next Monday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the International Monetary Fund",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "International Monetary Fund",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "yesterday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "next Wednesday",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Peter Breuer",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the International Monetary Fund's",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Consultative Council",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Osiro Kosaigo",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "IMF Permanent Representative",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Tobagans",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "National Security Sagala Ratnayake",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Saman Ekanayake",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Central Bank",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Nandalal Weerasinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Central Bank",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Treasury",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "ජනාධිපති සමග IMF සාකච්ඡා",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "රටේ පවතින වත්මන් මූල්‍ය අර්බුදයට විසඳුම් සෙවීම සඳහා ජනාධිපති රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතා සහ ජාත්‍යන්තර මුල්‍ය අරමුදලේ නියෝජිතයින් අතර තවත් සාකච්ඡා වටයක් ඊයේ (26) පස්වරුවේ පැවැත්විණි.",
        "ජනාධිපති කාර්යාලයේ පැවති මෙම හමුවේදී සූම් තාක්ෂණය ඔස්සේ ජනාධිපති රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතා සාකච්ඡාවට එක් වූ අතර එහිදී දෙපාර්ශවයේම ධනාත්මක අදහස් හුවමාරු විය.",
        "විදුලි ගාස්තු සංශෝධන සහ මත්පැන් පනත ඇතුළු භාණ්ඩාගාරය සම්බන්ධයෙන් අද පැවති සාකච්ඡාවේදී ජාත්‍යන්තර මූල්‍ය අරමුදලේ නියෝජිතයින් විසින් අවශ්‍ය අමතර තොරතුරු ලබාදෙන ලෙස කළ ඉල්ලීමට අනුව ලබන සඳුදා වන විට එම තොරතුරු ලබාදීමට එකඟතාව පළ විය.",
        "ඊයේ පැවති සාකච්ඡා සඳහා ජාත්‍යන්තර මුල්‍ය අරමුදලේ මූල්‍ය උපදේශකයින්, නීති උපදේශකයින් සහභාගී වූ අතර මීළඟ සාකච්ඡා වටය ලබන බදාදා (31) පැවැත්වීමට තීරණය කර ඇත.",
        "ජාත්‍යන්තර මුල්‍ය අරමුදලේ උපදේශක කමිටුවේ සභාපති පීටර් බෲවර්, උපසභාපති ඔසිරෝ කොසායිගෝ, ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ ජාත්‍යන්තර මූල්‍ය අරමුදලේ නිත්‍ය නියෝජිත ටොබගන්ස්, ජනාධිපති කාර්ය මණ්ඩල ප්‍රධානී සහ ජාතික ආරක්ෂාව පිළිබඳ ජනාධිපති ජ්‍යෙෂ්ඨ උපදේශක සාගල රත්නායක, ජනාධිපති ලේකම් සමන් ඒකනායක , මහ බැංකු අධිපති කලනිති නන්දලාල් වීරසිංහ, භාණ්ඩාගාර ලේකම් ඇතුළු මහ බැංකුවේ ජ්‍යෙෂ්ඨ නිලධාරීන් මෙම සාකච්ඡාවට සහභාගි වූහ. (ඒ)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජාත්‍යන්තර මුල්‍ය අරමුදල",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඊයේ",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "26) සවස",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "විශාලනය කරන්න",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "භාණ්ඩාගාර",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "විදුලි ගාස්තු සංශෝධනය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "මත්පැන් පනත",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ලබන සඳුදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජාත්‍යන්තර මුල්‍ය අරමුදල",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ජාත්යන්තර මූල්ය අරමුදල",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඊයේ",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ලබන බදාදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "පීටර් බෲවර්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජාත්‍යන්තර මුල්‍ය අරමුදලේ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "උපදේශක සභාව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Osiro Kosaigo",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "IMF නිත්‍ය නියෝජිත",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ටොබගන්ස්",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජාතික ආරක්ෂාව සාගල රත්නායක",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "සමන් ඒකනායක",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "මහ බැංකුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "නන්දලාල් වීරසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "මහ බැංකුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "භාණ්ඩාගාර",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "ஜனாதிபதியுடன் ஐ.எம்.எப். பேச்சுவார்த்தை",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "நாட்டில் தற்போது நிலவும் நிதி நெருக்கடிக்கு தீர்வு காண்பதற்காக ஜனாதிபதி ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க அவர்களுக்கும் சர்வதேச நாணய நிதியப் பிரதிநிதிகளுக்கும் இடையில் மற்றுமொரு சுற்றுப் பேச்சுவார்த்தை நேற்று (26) பிற்பகல் நடைபெற்றது.",
        "ஜனாதிபதி அலுவலகத்தில் நடைபெற்ற இந்தச் சந்திப்பில், ஜனாதிபதி ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க Zoom தொழில்நுட்பத்தின் ஊடாக கலந்துரையாடலில் இணைந்துகொண்டதுடன், இரு தரப்பிலும் சாதகமான கருத்துக்கள் பரிமாறிக் கொள்ளப்பட்டன.",
        "மின் கட்டணத் திருத்தம் மற்றும் மதுவரிச் சட்டம் உள்ளிட்ட திறைசேரி தொடர்பான இன்றைய கலந்துரையாடலில், தேவையான மேலதிக தகவல்களை வழங்குமாறு சர்வதேச நாணய நிதியத்தின் பிரதிநிதிகள் முன்வைத்த கோரிக்கைக்கு இணங்க, எதிர்வரும் திங்கட்கிழமைக்குள் தகவல்களை வழங்குவதற்கு இணக்கம் காணப்பட்டது.",
        "சர்வதேச நாணய நிதியத்தின் நிதி ஆலோசகர்கள், சட்ட ஆலோசகர்கள் நேற்றைய பேச்சுவார்த்தையில் கலந்துகொண்டதுடன், எதிர்வரும் புதன்கிழமை (31) அடுத்தச் சுற்றுப் பேச்சுவார்த்தையை நடத்துவதற்குத் தீர்மானிக்கப்பட்டது.",
        "சர்வதேச நாணய நிதியத்தின் கலந்துரையாடல் சபையின் தலைவர் பீட்டர் ப்ரூயர் (Peter Breuer), பிரதித் தலைவர் ஒசைரோ கொசைகோ, சர்வதேச நாணய நிதியத்தின் இலங்கைக்கான நிரந்தரப் பிரதிநிதி டொபாகன்ஸ், ஜனாதிபதியின் பணிக்குழாம் பிரதானியும் தேசிய பாதுகாப்பு தொடர்பான ஜனாதிபதியின் சிரேஷ்ட ஆலோசகருமான சாகல ரத்நாயக்க, ஜனாதிபதியின் செயலாளர் சமன் ஏக்கநாயக்க, மத்திய வங்கியின் ஆளுநர் கலாநிதி நந்தலால் வீரசிங்க, திறைசேரி செயலாளர் உட்பட மத்திய வங்கியின் சிரேஷ்ட அதிகாரிகள் இந்த கலந்துரையாடலில் பங்கேற்றனர். (a)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "சர்வதேச நாணய நிதியம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "நேற்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "26) பிற்பகல்",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "பெரிதாக்கு",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "கருவூலம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "மின் கட்டண திருத்தம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "மதுபான சட்டம்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "அடுத்த திங்கள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சர்வதேச நாணய நிதியம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "சர்வதேச நாணய நிதியம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "நேற்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "அடுத்த புதன்கிழமை",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பீட்டர் ப்ரூயர்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "சர்வதேச நாணய நிதியம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆலோசனைக் குழு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Osiro Kosaigo",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "IMF நிரந்தரப் பிரதிநிதி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "டோபகன்ஸ்",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "தேசிய பாதுகாப்பு சாகல ரத்நாயக்க",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "சமன் ஏக்கநாயக்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "மத்திய வங்கி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "நந்தலால் வீரசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "மத்திய வங்கி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "கருவூலம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}