{
  "newspaper_id": "daily-mirror-lk",
  "url": "https://www.dailymirror.lk/top_story/President-a-prisoner-of-the-SLPP-Jayasekara/155-243035",
  "time_ut": 1660527192,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "President a prisoner of the SLPP: Jayasekara",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "President a prisoner of the SLPP: Jayasekara",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "With the pledge given by President Ranil Wickremesinghe to the Sri Lanka Podu Jana Peramuna (SLPP) for his survival that he would not dissolve Parliament as long as the current regime completes its full term in 2025, he will become a prisoner of the SLPP, General Secretary of the SLFP, former Minister Dayasiri Jayasekara said.",
        "The deal between the executive and the SLPP would not bring solutions to the burning problems of 22 million people of the country or restore economic, political and social stability but make them worse, he added.",
        "Therefore, any relief to Sri Lanka from the global financial agencies like the IMF, the World Bank or the ADB and donor countries like China, India, the EU or the US and a debt restructuring programme to bail out Sri Lanka from the current predicament was extremely doubtful, Jayasekara told Daily Mirror yesterday.",
        "“We are still in the dark about the composition and the road map of the proposed multi-party or all-party government. We submitted two documents containing 9 and 11 points related to the formation of the inclusive government at the talks we had with President Wickremesinghe. But the SLFP is not ready to support any administration that attempts to further the political agenda of the SLPP. Ranil does not have the mandate to rejuvenate the SLPP. Sri Lanka needs a system change through a new government sooner than later as demanded by the aragalists and the entire nation to rebuild the confidence among the global community, international financial agencies and donor countries in Sri Lanka” Jayasekara stressed.(Sandun A Jayasekera)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Sri Lanka Podu",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Jana Peramuna",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "2025",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "SLFP",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Dayasiri Jayasekara",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "22 million",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "IMF",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the World Bank",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "China",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "India",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "EU",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "US",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Jayasekara",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Daily Mirror",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "yesterday",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "two",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "11",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "SLFP",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Jayasekara",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "ජනාධිපතිතුමා ශ්‍රී ලංකා පොදුජන පෙරමුණේ සිරකරුවෙක්: ජයසේකර",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "වත්මන් පාලනය 2025 දී සම්පූර්ණ ධුර කාලය සම්පූර්ණ කරන තුරු පාර්ලිමේන්තුව විසුරුවා නොහරින බවට ජනාධිපති රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතා ශ්‍රී ලංකා පොදුජන පෙරමුණට (SLPP) ලබාදුන් ප්‍රතිඥාව මත ශ්‍රී ලංකා පොදුජන පෙරමුණේ සිරකරුවෙකු වනු ඇත. ශ්‍රීලනිප ලේකම්, හිටපු අමාත්‍ය දයාසිරි ජයසේකර මහතා පැවසීය.",
        "විධායකය සහ ශ්‍රී ලංකා පොදුජන පෙරමුණ අතර ගනුදෙනුවෙන් රටේ මිලියන 22ක ජනතාවගේ දැවෙන ප්‍රශ්නවලට විසඳුම් හෝ ආර්ථික, දේශපාලන හා සමාජීය ස්ථාවරත්වය යථා තත්ත්වයට පත් කිරීම හෝ ඔවුන් වඩාත් නරක අතට හැරෙන්නේ නැත.",
        "එබැවින්, ජාත්‍යන්තර මූල්‍ය අරමුදල, ලෝක බැංකුව හෝ ADB වැනි ගෝලීය මූල්‍ය ආයතන සහ චීනය, ඉන්දියාව, යුරෝපා සංගමය හෝ එක්සත් ජනපදය වැනි පරිත්‍යාගශීලී රටවලින් ශ්‍රී ලංකාවට යම් සහනයක් සහ ශ්‍රී ලංකාව වත්මන් අර්බුදයෙන් මුදා ගැනීම සඳහා ණය ප්‍රතිව්‍යුහගත කිරීමේ වැඩසටහනක් ජයසේකර ඊයේ ඩේලි මිරර් වෙත පැවසුවේ අතිශය සැක සහිත බවයි.",
        "“යෝජිත බහු-පක්ෂ හෝ සර්ව පාක්ෂික ආණ්ඩුවේ සංයුතිය සහ මාර්ග සිතියම පිළිබඳව අප තවමත් සිටින්නේ අඳුරේය. අපි ජනාධිපති වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතා සමඟ කළ සාකච්ඡාවලදී ඇතුළත් ආණ්ඩුව පිහිටුවීමට අදාළ කරුණු 9 සහ 11 ඇතුළත් ලේඛන දෙකක් ඉදිරිපත් කළා. එහෙත් ශ්‍රී ලංකා පොදුජන පෙරමුණේ දේශපාලන න්‍යාය පත්‍රය ඉදිරියට ගෙන යාමට උත්සාහ කරන කිසිදු පාලනයකට සහාය දීමට ශ්‍රීලනිපය සූදානම් නැත. ශ්‍රී ලංකා පොදුජන පෙරමුණට පණ දීමට රනිල්ට ජනවරමක් නැත. ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ ගෝලීය ප්‍රජාව, ජාත්‍යන්තර මූල්‍ය ආයතන සහ පරිත්‍යාගශීලී රටවල් අතර විශ්වාසය යළි ගොඩනැංවීම සඳහා අරගලවාදීන් සහ සමස්ත ජාතියම ඉල්ලා සිටින පරිදි ශ්‍රී ලංකාවට ඉක්මනින් නව රජයක් හරහා ක්‍රම වෙනසක් අවශ්‍ය වේ” යනුවෙන් ජයසේකර මහතා අවධාරණය කළේය.(සඳුන් ඒ ජයසේකර)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකා පොදු",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජන පෙරමුණ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "2025",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රීලනිප",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "දයාසිරි ජයසේකර",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "මිලියන 22 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "IMF",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ලෝක බැංකුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "චීනය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "EU",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "එක්සත් ජනපදය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජයසේකර",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඩේලි මිරර්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඊයේ",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "දෙක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "11",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රීලනිප",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජයසේකර",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "ஜனாதிபதி ஸ்ரீலங்கா பொதுஜன பெரமுனவின் கைதி: ஜயசேகர",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "தற்போதைய ஆட்சி 2025ஆம் ஆண்டு நிறைவடையும் வரை நாடாளுமன்றத்தை கலைக்க மாட்டோம் என ஜனாதிபதி ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க ஸ்ரீலங்கா பொதுஜன பெரமுனவுக்கு வழங்கிய உறுதிமொழியுடன், அவர் SLPP யின் கைதியாக மாறுவார். ஸ்ரீலங்கா சுதந்திரக் கட்சியின் செயலாளர், முன்னாள் அமைச்சர் தயாசிறி ஜயசேகர தெரிவித்துள்ளார்.",
        "நிறைவேற்று மற்றும் SLPP க்கு இடையிலான ஒப்பந்தம் நாட்டின் 22 மில்லியன் மக்களின் எரியும் பிரச்சினைகளுக்கு தீர்வைக் கொண்டு வராது அல்லது பொருளாதார, அரசியல் மற்றும் சமூக ஸ்திரத்தன்மையை மீட்டெடுக்காது, ஆனால் அவர்களை மேலும் மோசமாக்கும்.",
        "எனவே, IMF, உலக வங்கி அல்லது ADB போன்ற உலகளாவிய நிதி நிறுவனங்களிலிருந்தும் சீனா, இந்தியா, ஐரோப்பிய ஒன்றியம் அல்லது அமெரிக்கா போன்ற நன்கொடை நாடுகளிலிருந்தும் இலங்கைக்கு ஏதேனும் நிவாரணம் மற்றும் தற்போதைய இக்கட்டான சூழ்நிலையில் இருந்து இலங்கையை மீட்க கடன் மறுசீரமைப்பு வேலைத்திட்டம் ஜெயசேகர நேற்று டெய்லி மிரருக்குத் தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "“உத்தேச பல கட்சி அல்லது அனைத்துக் கட்சி அரசாங்கத்தின் அமைப்பு மற்றும் சாலை வரைபடம் குறித்து நாங்கள் இன்னும் இருட்டில் இருக்கிறோம். ஜனாதிபதி விக்கிரமசிங்கவுடன் நாம் நடத்திய பேச்சுவார்த்தையில் உள்ளடங்கிய அரசாங்கத்தை அமைப்பது தொடர்பான 9 மற்றும் 11 விடயங்கள் அடங்கிய இரண்டு ஆவணங்களை சமர்பித்தோம். ஆனால் ஸ்ரீலங்கா பொதுஜன பெரமுனவின் அரசியல் நிகழ்ச்சி நிரலை முன்னெடுப்பதற்கு முயற்சிக்கும் எந்தவொரு நிர்வாகத்திற்கும் ஆதரவளிக்க ஸ்ரீலங்கா சுதந்திரக் கட்சி தயாராக இல்லை. ஸ்ரீலங்கா பொதுஜன பெரமுனவிற்கு புத்துயிரூட்டும் ஆணை ரணிலுக்கு இல்லை. இலங்கையில் உலகளாவிய சமூகம், சர்வதேச நிதி நிறுவனங்கள் மற்றும் நன்கொடை நாடுகள் மத்தியில் நம்பிக்கையை மீளக் கட்டியெழுப்ப அரகாலிஸ்டுகள் மற்றும் முழு நாட்டினதும் கோரிக்கைக்கு அமைவாக இலங்கைக்கு விரைவில் புதிய அரசாங்கத்தின் ஊடாக ஒரு அமைப்பு மாற்றம் தேவை” என ஜயசேகர வலியுறுத்தினார்.(சந்துன் ஏ ஜயசேகர)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை பொது",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜன பெரமுன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "2025",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஸ்ரீ.ல.சு.க",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "தயாசிறி ஜயசேகர",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "22 மில்லியன்",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "IMF",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "உலக வங்கி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "சீனா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்தியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "EU",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "எங்களுக்கு",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜெயசேகர",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "டெய்லி மிரர்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "நேற்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இரண்டு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "11",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஸ்ரீ.ல.சு.க",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜெயசேகர",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}