{
  "newspaper_id": "virakesari-lk",
  "url": "http://www.virakesari.lk/article/130829",
  "time_ut": 1657007325,
  "original_lang": "ta",
  "original_title": "சர்சையை கிளப்பிய 'காளி' ஆவணப்படம்",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "'Kali' Documentary That Raised Controversy",
      "author": "T. Saranya",
      "body_lines": [
        "The Indian Embassy in Canada has said that the documentary 'Kali', which has been released as an insult to the Hindu God, should be withdrawn.",
        "The poster of documentary film 'Kali', directed by documentary film director Leena Manimekala, has created a lot of controversy.",
        "The poster depicts Hindu deity Maha Kali smoking a cigarette and holding the flag of the LGBT community in one hand.",
        "People are strongly protesting against this poster which has been published as an insult to the Hindu God.",
        "A festival called \"Rhythms of Canada\" was held at the Aga Khan Museum in Toronto, Canada to celebrate multiculturalism.",
        "A documentary film 'Kali' was screened as part of the festival. In this situation, the Indian Embassy in Ottawa has requested the withdrawal of the controversial 'Kali' documentary.",
        "In a statement, Hindu religious leaders in Canada have received complaints that a poster for a documentary screened as part of the 'Under the Tent' program at the Aga Khan Museum insulted a Hindu god."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Kali",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "The Indian Embassy",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Canada",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kali",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Hindu",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Kali",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Leena Manimekala",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Hindu",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Maha Kali",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Hindu",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Rhythms of Canada",
            "label": "WORK_OF_ART"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Aga Khan Museum",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "Toronto",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Canada",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Kali",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Indian Embassy",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ottawa",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kali",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Hindu",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Canada",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Tent",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Aga Khan Museum",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Hindu",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "ආන්දෝලනයක් ඇති කළ 'කාලි' වාර්තා චිත්‍රපටය",
      "author": "T. Saranya",
      "body_lines": [
        "හින්දු දෙවියන්ට අපහාසයක් ලෙස නිකුත් කර ඇති ‘කාලි’ වාර්තා චිත්‍රපටය ඉවත් කර ගත යුතු බව කැනඩාවේ ඉන්දීය තානාපති කාර්යාලය පවසයි.",
        "වාර්තා චිත්‍රපට අධ්‍යක්ෂිකා ලීනා මනිමේකලා විසින් අධ්‍යක්ෂණය කරන ලද ‘කාලි’ වාර්තා චිත්‍රපටයේ පෝස්ටරය දැඩි ආන්දෝලනයකට තුඩු දී තිබේ.",
        "හින්දු දේවතාවිය වන මහා කාලි සිගරට්ටුවක් උරමින් සහ LGBT ප්‍රජාවගේ ධජය එක් අතකින් අල්ලාගෙන සිටින ආකාරය පෝස්ටරයේ දැක්වේ.",
        "හින්දු දෙවියන්ට අපහාසයක් ලෙස පළ කර ඇති මෙම පෝස්ටරයට ජනතාව දැඩි විරෝධය පළ කරනවා.",
        "බහු සංස්කෘතිකත්වය සැමරීම සඳහා කැනඩාවේ ටොරොන්ටෝ හි Aga Khan කෞතුකාගාරයේ \"Rhythms of Canada\" නමින් උත්සවයක් පැවැත්විණි.",
        "උළෙලේ කොටසක් ලෙස ‘කාලි’ වාර්තා චිත්‍රපටයක් ප්‍රදර්ශනය කෙරිණි. මේ තත්ත්වය තුළ මතභේදයට තුඩු දී ඇති ‘කාලි’ වාර්තා චිත්‍රපටය ඉවත් කර ගන්නා ලෙස ඔටාවා හි ඉන්දීය තානාපති කාර්යාලය ඉල්ලා තිබේ.",
        "නිවේදනයක් නිකුත් කරමින් කැනඩාවේ හින්දු ආගමික නායකයින් විසින් අගා ඛාන් කෞතුකාගාරයේ ‘කුඩාරමක් යට’ වැඩසටහනේ කොටසක් ලෙස ප්‍රදර්ශනය කරන ලද වාර්තා චිත්‍රපටයක පෝස්ටරයක් ​​හින්දු දෙවියෙකුට අපහාස වන බවට පැමිණිලි ලැබී තිබේ."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "කාලි",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දීය තානාපති කාර්යාලය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "කැනඩාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "කාලි",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "හින්දු",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "කාලි",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ලීනා මනිමේකලා",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "හින්දු",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "මහා කාලි",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "හින්දු",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "කැනඩාවේ රිද්මයන්",
            "label": "WORK_OF_ART"
          },
          {
            "text": "Aga Khan කෞතුකාගාරය",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "Toronto",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "කැනඩාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "කාලි",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දීය තානාපති කාර්යාලය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඔටාවා",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "කාලි",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "හින්දු",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "කැනඩාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "කූඩාරම",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Aga Khan කෞතුකාගාරය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "හින්දු",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "சர்சையை கிளப்பிய 'காளி' ஆவணப்படம்",
      "author": "T. Saranya",
      "body_lines": [
        "இந்து மத கடவுளை அவமதிக்கும் விதமாக வெளியிடப்பட்டுள்ள 'காளி' ஆவணப்படத்தை திரும்ப பெற வேண்டும் என கனடாவில் உள்ள இந்திய தூதரகம் தெரிவித்துள்ளது.",
        "ஆவணப்பட இயக்குனர் லீனா மணிமேகலை தான் இயக்கி உள்ள 'காளி' என்ற ஆவணப்படத்தின் போஸ்டர் கடும் சர்ச்சையை ஏற்படுத்தி உள்ளது.",
        "அந்த போஸ்டரில் இந்துக்களின் கடவுளான மகா காளி, சிகரெட் புகைப்பது போன்றும், ஒரு கையில் எல்ஜிபிடி சமூகத்தின் கொடியை ஏந்தியபடியும் இருப்பதாக சித்தரிக்கப்பட்டுள்ளது.",
        "இந்து கடவுளை அவமதிக்கும் விதமாக வெளியிடப்பட்டுள்ள இந்த போஸ்டருக்கு மக்கள் கடும் எதிர்ப்பு தெரிவித்து வருகின்றனர்.",
        "கனடா நாட்டின் டொராண்டோவில் உள்ள ஆகா கான் அருங்காட்சியகத்தில் பன்முக கலாச்சாரத்தை கொண்டாடும் வகையில் \"ரிதம்ஸ் ஆஃப் கனடா\" என்ற திருவிழா நடைபெற்றது.",
        "இந்த திருவிழாவின் ஒரு பகுதியாக 'காளி' ஆவணப்படம் திரையிடப்பட்டது. இந்த நிலையில், சர்ச்சைக்குரிய 'காளி' ஆவணப்படத்தை திரும்ப பெற வேண்டும் என ஒட்டாவா இந்திய தூதரகம் கேட்டுக்கொண்டுள்ளது.",
        "இதுதொடர்பாக வெளியிட்டுள்ள அறிக்கையில், ஆகா கான் அருங்காட்சியகத்தில் நடைபெற்ற 'அண்டர் தி டெண்ட்' நிகழ்ச்சியின் ஒரு பகுதியாக திரையிடப்பட்ட ஒரு ஆவணப்படத்தின் போஸ்டரில் இந்து கடவுளை அவமதித்ததாக கனடாவில் உள்ள இந்து மத தலைவர்களிடம் இருந்து புகார்கள் வந்துள்ளன."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "காளி",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "இந்திய தூதரகம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "கனடா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "காளி",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்து",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "காளி",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "லீனா மணிமேகலை",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இந்து",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "மகா காளி",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இந்து",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "கனடாவின் தாளங்கள்",
            "label": "WORK_OF_ART"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆகா கான் அருங்காட்சியகம்",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "Toronto",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "கனடா",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "காளி",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்திய தூதரகம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஒட்டாவா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "காளி",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இந்து",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "கனடா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "கூடாரம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆகா கான் அருங்காட்சியகம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்து",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}