{
  "newspaper_id": "ada-lk",
  "url": "https://www.ada.lk/breaking_news/රටින්-පැනීමට-තැත්-කළ-47ක්-කොටුවෙයි/11-395919",
  "time_ut": 1659334271,
  "original_lang": "si",
  "original_title": "රටින් පැනීමට තැත් කළ 47ක් කොටුවෙයි",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "47 people who tried to flee the country are imprisoned",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "In a special search operation carried out by the Sri Lanka Navy in collaboration with the Wennappuwa Police yesterday (31st) in the city of Wennappuwa, 47 people were arrested who were suspected of illegally trying to migrate to a foreign country by sea.",
        "Based on the information received by the Sri Lanka Navy, the Western Naval Command together with the Wennappuwa Police observed and inspected 03 suspicious vans in this special search operation in Wennappuwa city yesterday (31st) night. There, the vans with 47 persons including 37 males above 18 years of age, 06 females and 04 below 18 years of age who were suspected of illegally trying to migrate to a foreign country by sea. 03 Arrests were made.",
        "The people taken into custody by the Navy during this search operation were identified as residents of Jaffna, Vavuniya, Trincomalee, Kalmune, Batticaloa, Puttalam, Halawatha, Marawila, Mahawewa, Mundalama and Wellawatta, and arrangements were made to hand them over to Wennappuwa Police for further investigations. done"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "47",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "the Sri Lanka Navy",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "yesterday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Wennappuwa",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "47",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the Sri Lanka Navy",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Western Naval Command",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Wennappuwa Police",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Wennappuwa city",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "yesterday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "night",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "47",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "37 males",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "18 years of age",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "04",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "18 years of age",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "03",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Navy",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Jaffna, Vavuniya",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Trincomalee",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kalmune, Batticaloa",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Puttalam",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Halawatha",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Mahawewa",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Mundalama",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Wellawatta",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "රටින් පැනීමට තැත් කළ 47ක් කොටුවෙයි",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකා නාවික හමුදාව වෙන්නප්පුව පොලිසිය හා එක්ව වෙන්නප්පුව නගරයේ ඊයේ (31දා) රාත්‍රී කාලයේ සිදුකළ විශේෂ සෝදිසි මෙහෙයුමක් මඟින්, නීති විරෝධී ලෙස මුහුදු මාර්ගයෙන් මෙරටින් විදෙස් රටකට සංක්‍රමණය වීමට උත්සහ කළ බවට සැකකෙරෙන පුද්ගලයන් 47 දෙනෙකු අත්අඩංගුවට ගැනීමට කටයුතු කෙරිණි.",
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකා නාවික හමුදාවට ලද තොරතුරක් මත බටහිර නාවික විධානය විසින් වෙන්නප්පුව පොලිසිය හා එක්ව ඊයේ (31දා) රාත්‍රී කාලයේ වෙන්නප්පුව නගරයේ සිදුකළ මෙම විශේෂ සෝදිසි මෙහෙයුමේදි සැකකටයුතු වෑන් රථ 03 ක් නිරීක්‍ෂණය කර පරීක්‍ෂාවට ලක් කරන ලදී. එහිදී, එම වෑන් රථ තුළ සිටි නීති විරෝධී ලෙස මුහුදු මාර්ගයෙන් මෙරටින් විදෙස් රටකට සංක්‍රමණය වීමට උත්සාහ කළ බවට සැකකෙරෙන වයස අවුරුදු 18 ට වැඩි පිරිමි පුද්ගලයන් 37 ක්, කාත්තාවන් 06 ක් සහ වයස අවුරුදු 18 ට අඩු 04 දෙනෙක් ඇතුළුව පුද්ගලයන් 47 දෙනෙකු සමඟ එම වෑන් රථ 03 අත්අඩංගුවට ගැනීමට කටයුතු කෙරිණි.",
        "මෙම සෝදිසි මෙහෙයුමේදි නාවික හමුදා භාරයට ගත්  පිරිස යාපනය, වව්නියාව, ත්‍රිකුණාමලය, කල්මුනේ, මඩකලපුව, පුත්තලම, හලාවත, මාරවිල, මහවැව, මුන්දලම සහ වැල්ලවත්ත යන ප්‍රදේශයන්හී පදිංචිකරුවන් බවට හඳුනා ගන්නා ලද අතර, එම පිරිස ඉදිරි විමර්ශන කටයුතු සඳහා වෙන්නප්පුව පොලීසිය වෙත භාර දීමට කටයුතු කෙරිණි."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "47",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකා නාවික හමුදාව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඊයේ",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "වෙන්නප්පුව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "47",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකා නාවික හමුදාව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "බටහිර නාවික විධානය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "වෙන්නප්පුව පොලිසිය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "වෙන්නප්පුව නගරය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඊයේ",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "රෑ",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "47",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "පිරිමි 37යි",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "වයස අවුරුදු 18 යි",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "04",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "වයස අවුරුදු 18 යි",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "03",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "නාවික",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "යාපනය, වවුනියාව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ත්රිකුණාමලය",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "කල්මුණේ, මඩකලපුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "පුත්තලම",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "හලවත",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මහවැව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මුන්දලම",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "වැල්ලවත්ත",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "நாட்டை விட்டு தப்பிச் செல்ல முயன்ற 47 பேர் சிறையில் அடைக்கப்பட்டுள்ளனர்",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "வென்னப்புவ நகரில் நேற்று (31) வென்னப்புவ பொலிஸாருடன் இணைந்து இலங்கை கடற்படையினர் மேற்கொண்ட விசேட தேடுதல் நடவடிக்கையில் கடல் மார்க்கமாக வெளிநாடுகளுக்கு சட்டவிரோதமாக இடம்பெயர முயன்றதாக சந்தேகிக்கப்படும் 47 பேர் கைது செய்யப்பட்டுள்ளனர்.",
        "இலங்கை கடற்படையினருக்கு கிடைத்த தகவலின் அடிப்படையில் மேற்கு கடற்படை கட்டளை அதிகாரிகள் வென்னப்புவ பொலிஸாருடன் இணைந்து நேற்று (31) இரவு வென்னப்புவ நகரில் இந்த விசேட தேடுதல் நடவடிக்கையில் சந்தேகத்திற்கிடமான 03 வேன்களை அவதானித்து சோதனையிட்டனர். அங்கு சட்டவிரோதமான முறையில் கடல் மார்க்கமாக வெளிநாட்டுக்கு செல்ல முயன்றதாக சந்தேகிக்கப்படும் 18 வயதுக்கு மேற்பட்ட 37 ஆண்கள், 06 பெண்கள், 04 வயதுக்குட்பட்ட 04 பேர் உட்பட 47 பேருடன் வேன்களில் 03 பேர் கைது செய்யப்பட்டுள்ளனர்.",
        "இந்த தேடுதல் நடவடிக்கையின் போது கடற்படையினரால் கைது செய்யப்பட்டவர்கள் யாழ்ப்பாணம், வவுனியா, திருகோணமலை, கல்முனை, மட்டக்களப்பு, புத்தளம், ஹலவத்தை, மாரவில, மஹாவெவ, முந்தளம மற்றும் வெள்ளவத்தை ஆகிய பகுதிகளைச் சேர்ந்தவர்கள் என அடையாளம் காணப்பட்டு, அவர்களை வென்னப்புவ பொலிஸாரிடம் ஒப்படைப்பதற்கான நடவடிக்கைகள் மேற்கொள்ளப்பட்டன. மேலதிக விசாரணைகளுக்காக"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "47",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை கடற்படை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "நேற்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "வென்னப்புவ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "47",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை கடற்படை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "மேற்கு கடற்படை கட்டளை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "வென்னப்புவ பொலிஸ்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "வென்னப்புவ நகரம்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "நேற்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இரவு",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "47",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "37 ஆண்கள்",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "18 வயது",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "04",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "18 வயது",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "03",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "கடற்படை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "யாழ்ப்பாணம், வவுனியா",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "திருகோணமலை",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "கல்முனை, மட்டக்களப்பு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "புத்தளம்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஹலவதா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "மஹாவெவ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "முண்டலமா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "வெள்ளவத்தை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}