{
  "newspaper_id": "virakesari-lk",
  "url": "http://www.virakesari.lk/article/131873",
  "time_ut": 1658309996,
  "original_lang": "ta",
  "original_title": "காலிமுகத்திடலில் உள்ள பண்டாரநாயக்கா சிலைக்கு அருகில் செல்லத் தடை",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Prohibition to go near the Bandaranayak statue at Kalimugathidal",
      "author": "T. Saranya",
      "body_lines": [
        "The Fort Justice Court has issued a restraining order against entering the 50-meter circle around the statue of Bandaranaike in the Kalimugattidal area.",
        "Colombo - The Fort Magistrate Court has issued a restraining order against the Kalimugattidal Kota Go Kama protestors from entering the 50 meter circle around the Bandaranaike statue there.",
        "Colombo Fort Magistrate Dilina Gamage has issued this order following a request made by the Fort Police that there is a possibility of damage to the statue."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Bandaranayak",
          "label": "PRODUCT"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "The Fort Justice Court",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "50-meter",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Kama",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "50 meter",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "Bandaranaike",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Dilina Gamage",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Fort Police",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "කලිමුගතිඩාල් බණ්ඩාරනායක පිළිරුව අසලට යාම තහනම්",
      "author": "T. Saranya",
      "body_lines": [
        "කලිමුගට්ටිඩාල් ප්‍රදේශයේ පිහිටි බණ්ඩාරනායක ප්‍රතිමාව අවට මීටර් 50 ක රවුමට ඇතුළුවීම වළක්වමින් කොටුව අධිකරණ අධිකරණය විසින් තහනම් නියෝගයක් නිකුත් කර තිබේ.",
        "කොළඹ - කලිමුගට්ටිඩාල් කොට ගෝ කම විරෝධතාකරුවන්ට එහි බණ්ඩාරනායක පිළිරුව අවට මීටර් 50 කවයට ඇතුළුවීම වළක්වමින් කොටුව මහේස්ත්‍රාත් අධිකරණය විසින් තහනම් නියෝගයක් නිකුත් කර තිබෙනවා.",
        "කොළඹ කොටුව මහේස්ත්‍රාත් දිලින ගමගේ මහතා මෙම නියෝගය නිකුත් කර ඇත්තේ ප්‍රතිමාවට හානි වීමට ඉඩ ඇති බවට කොටුව පොලිසිය කළ ඉල්ලීමකට අනුවය."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "බණ්ඩාරනායක",
          "label": "PRODUCT"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "කොටුව අධිකරණ අධිකරණය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "මීටර් 50",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "කාම",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "මීටර් 50",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "බණ්ඩාරනායක",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "දිලින ගමගේ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "කොටුව පොලිසිය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "காலிமுகத்திடலில் உள்ள பண்டாரநாயக்கா சிலைக்கு அருகில் செல்லத் தடை",
      "author": "T. Saranya",
      "body_lines": [
        "காலிமுகத்திடல் பகுதியில் உள்ள பண்டாரநாயக்கவின் உருவச்சிலையை சுற்றியுள்ள 50 மீற்றர் சுற்றுவட்டத்திற்குள் நுழையக்கூடாது என கோட்டை நீதிவான் நீதிமன்றம் தடையுத்தரவு பிறப்பித்துள்ளது.",
        "கொழும்பு - காலிமுகத்திடல் கோட்டா கோ கம போராட்டக்காரர்கள் அங்குள்ள பண்டாரநாயக்க உருவச்சிலையை சுற்றியுள்ள 50 மீற்றர் சுற்றுவட்டத்திற்குள் நுழையக்கூடாது என கோட்டை நீதிவான் நீதிமன்றம் இவ்வாறு தடையுத்தரவு பிறப்பித்துள்ளது.",
        "சிலைக்கு சேதம் விளைவிப்பதற்கான சாத்தியக்கூறுகள் இருப்பதாக தகவல் கிடைத்துள்ளதாக கோட்டை பொலிஸார் விடுத்த கோரிக்கைக்கு அமைய கொழும்பு கோட்டை நீதவான் திலின கமகே இந்த உத்தரவை பிறப்பித்துள்ளார்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "பண்டாரநாயக்க",
          "label": "PRODUCT"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "கோட்டை நீதி நீதிமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "50-மீட்டர்",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "காமா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "50 மீட்டர்",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "பண்டாரநாயக்கா",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "திலின கமகே",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "கோட்டை போலீஸ்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}