{
  "newspaper_id": "daily-mirror-lk",
  "url": "https://www.dailymirror.lk/latest_news/Textbooks-for-2023-to-reach-students-on-time/342-244015",
  "time_ut": 1661860809,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Textbooks for 2023 to reach students on time",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Textbooks for 2023 to reach students on time",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "The Education Ministry has taken the necessary measures to print the required school textbooks for the coming year.",
        "They said the ministry had allocated Rs. 16,483 million for the printing of the text books for the year 2023.",
        "The paper requirement for the printing of text books, examination papers and to use for answer scripts will be imported under the Indian credit line facility.",
        "The steps related to inviting bids, opening, etc., have already been completed.",
        "Cabinet approval has already been granted to get 45% of the total number of textbooks printed by the State Printing Corporation under the direction of the Education Ministry. (Chaturanga Samarawickrama)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "2023",
          "label": "DATE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "The Education Ministry",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the coming year",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "16,483 million",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "the year 2023",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Indian",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "Cabinet",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "45%",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "the State Printing Corporation",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Education Ministry",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Chaturanga Samarawickrama",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "නියමිත වේලාවට සිසුන් වෙත ළඟා වීමට 2023 සඳහා පෙළපොත්",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "ඉදිරි වසර සඳහා අවශ්‍ය පාසල් පෙළපොත් මුද්‍රණය කිරීමට අධ්‍යාපන අමාත්‍යාංශය අවශ්‍ය පියවර ගෙන ඇත.",
        "ඔවුන් කීවේ අමාත්‍යාංශයෙන් රු. 2023 වසර සඳහා පෙළ පොත් මුද්‍රණය සඳහා රුපියල් මිලියන 16,483 කි.",
        "පෙළ පොත් මුද්‍රණයට, විභාග ප්‍රශ්න පත්‍ර මුද්‍රණයට සහ පිළිතුරු පත්‍ර සඳහා භාවිත කිරීමට අවශ්‍ය කඩදාසි ඉන්දියානු ණය පහසුකම් යටතේ ආනයනය කෙරේ.",
        "ලංසු කැඳවීම, විවෘත කිරීම යනාදී කටයුතු දැනටමත් අවසන් කර ඇත.",
        "අධ්‍යාපන අමාත්‍යාංශයේ මෙහෙයවීම යටතේ රාජ්‍ය මුද්‍රණ නීතිගත සංස්ථාව මඟින් මුද්‍රණය කරන මුළු පෙළපොත් සංඛ්‍යාවෙන් 45%ක් ලබා ගැනීමට මේ වන විටත් අමාත්‍ය මණ්ඩල අනුමැතිය හිමිව තිබේ. (චතුරංග සමරවික්‍රම)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "2023",
          "label": "DATE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "අධ්‍යාපන අමාත්‍යාංශය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉදිරි වසර",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "මිලියන 16,483 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "වසර 2023",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දීය",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "මණ්ඩල",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "45%",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "රාජ්ය මුද්රණ සංස්ථාව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "අධ්යාපන අමාත්යාංශය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "චතුරංග සමරවික්‍රම",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "2023 ஆம் ஆண்டிற்கான பாடப்புத்தகங்கள் மாணவர்களுக்கு சரியான நேரத்தில் சென்றடையும்",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "எதிர்வரும் ஆண்டிற்கு தேவையான பாடசாலை பாடப்புத்தகங்களை அச்சிடுவதற்கு தேவையான நடவடிக்கைகளை கல்வி அமைச்சு மேற்கொண்டுள்ளது.",
        "அமைச்சகம் ரூ. 2023 ஆம் ஆண்டிற்கான பாடப் புத்தகங்களை அச்சிடுவதற்கு 16,483 மில்லியன் ரூபாய்.",
        "பாடப் புத்தகங்கள், தேர்வுத் தாள்கள் அச்சிடுவதற்கும், விடைத்தாள்களுக்குப் பயன்படுத்துவதற்குமான காகிதத் தேவைகள் இந்திய கடன் வரி வசதியின் கீழ் இறக்குமதி செய்யப்படும்.",
        "ஏலம் அழைப்பது, திறப்பது போன்ற நடவடிக்கைகள் ஏற்கனவே முடிந்துவிட்டன.",
        "கல்வி அமைச்சின் வழிகாட்டுதலின் கீழ் அரச அச்சகக் கூட்டுத்தாபனத்தினால் அச்சிடப்பட்ட மொத்த பாடப்புத்தகங்களில் 45% பெறுவதற்கு அமைச்சரவை அங்கீகாரம் ஏற்கனவே வழங்கப்பட்டுள்ளது. (சதுரங்க சமரவிக்ரம)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "2023",
          "label": "DATE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "கல்வி அமைச்சு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "வரும் ஆண்டு",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "16,483 மில்லியன்",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "2023 ஆம் ஆண்டு",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இந்தியன்",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "மந்திரி சபை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "45%",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "மாநில அச்சு கழகம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "கல்வி அமைச்சு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "சதுரங்க சமரவிக்ரம",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}