{
  "newspaper_id": "lankadeepa-lk",
  "url": "https://www.lankadeepa.lk/news/ගම්බද-දරුවන්ට-බස්-නැතිවුවහොත්-‘සිපෙට්කෝ’-වගකිව-යුතුයි/101-618077",
  "time_ut": 1660483070,
  "original_lang": "si",
  "original_title": "ගම්බද දරුවන්ට බස් නැතිවුවහොත් ‘සිපෙට්කෝ’ වගකිව යුතුයි",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "If rural children miss buses, 'Sipetco' should be held responsible",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "Mr. Gemunu Wijeratne, President of the Private Bus Owners' Association, said today (14) in the morning that filling stations should be provided for buses to get fuel in the rural areas that are not near the Langama depot and if the children are inconvenienced by the non-running of the buses in the rural areas, the 'Sipetco' should take responsibility.",
        "Since there are no Langama depots near Hakmana, Deniya, Dikwella, Middeniya, Beliaatta, Hambantota, Suriyawewa and Tissamaharama in the southern province, several petrol stations have been named by KR. Mr. Gemunu Wijeratne said that although he requested to increase the fuel limit in the code, Cipetco failed to do so, as there is no Hakmana depot, he has to travel 27 km to go to Depole and 40 km to get diesel for buses in Maoya area of ​​Ampara district.",
        "Mr. Gemunu Wijeratne said that 90 percent of the private buses or 12,000 buses are expected to run tomorrow and then between 15,000 and 16,000 buses."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Sipetco",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Gemunu Wijeratne",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Private Bus Owners' Association",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "14",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Langama",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sipetco",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Langama",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Hakmana",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Deniya",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Dikwella, Middeniya",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Beliaatta",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Hambantota",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Suriyawewa and Tissamaharama",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Gemunu Wijeratne",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Cipetco",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Hakmana",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "27 km",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "Depole",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "40 km",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "Maoya",
            "label": "LOC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Gemunu Wijeratne",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "90 percent",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "12,000",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "tomorrow",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "between 15,000 and 16,000",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "ගම්බද දරුවන්ට බස් නැතිවුවහොත් ‘සිපෙට්කෝ’ වගකිව යුතුයි",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "ලංගම ඩිපෝ ආසන්නයේ නොමැති ගම්බද ප්‍රදේශවල බස් රථවලට ඉන්ධන ලබාගැනීම සඳහා පිරවුම්හල් ලබාදිය යුතු බවත් ගම්බද ප්‍රදේශවල බස් රථ ධාවය නොවීමෙන් දරුවන් අපහසුතාවට පත්වුවහොත් එහි වගකීම ‘සිපෙට්කෝ’ ආයතනය භාරගත යුතු බවත් පෞද්ගලික බස් රථ හිමියන්ගේ සංගමයේ සභාපති ගැමුණු විජේරත්න මහතා අද (14) පෙරවරුවේ පැවසීය.",
        "දකුණු පළාතේ හක්මන, දෙණියාය, දික්වැල්ල, මිද්දෙණිය, බෙලිඅත්ත, හම්බන්තොට, සූරියවැව සහ තිස්සමාහාරාම යන ප්‍රදේශ ආසන්නයේ ලංගම ඩිපෝ නොමැති නිසා ඉන්ධන පිරවුම්හල් කීපයක් නම් කර කිව්.ආර්. කේතයේ ඉන්ධන සීමාව වැඩි කර ලබාදෙන ලෙස ඉල්ලා සිටිය ද ‘සිපෙට්කෝ’ ආයතනය එය මඟහැරි බව කී ගැමුණු විජේරත්න මහතා හක්මන ඩිපෝවක් නොමැති නිසා ඩීපෝලට යෑමට කිලෝමීටර 27 ක් දුර යා යුතු අතර අම්පාර දිස්ත්‍රික්කයේ මාඔය ප්‍රදේශයේ බස් රථවලට ඩීසල් ලබාගැනීමට කිලෝමීටර 40 ක් යායුතු බවත්ය.",
        "පෞද්ගලික බස් රථ ධාවනය සියයට 90 ක් හෙවත් බස් රථ 12,000 ක් හෙට දිනයේ ධාවනය කිරීමට බලාපොරොත්තු වන බවත් පසුව බස් රථ 15,000 ත් 16,000 ත් අතර ධාවනය කිරීමට බලාපොරොත්තු වන බවත් ගැමුණු විජේරත්න මහතා කීය."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "සිපෙට්කෝ",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ගැමුණු විජේරත්න",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "පෞද්ගලික බස් හිමියන්ගේ සංගමය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "14",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ලංගම",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "සිපෙට්කෝ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ලංගම",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "හක්මන",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "දෙණිය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "දික්වැල්ල, මිද්දෙණිය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "බෙලිඅත්ත",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "හම්බන්තොට",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "සූරියවැව සහ තිස්සමහාරාමය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගැමුණු විජේරත්න",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "සිපෙට්කෝ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "හක්මන",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "27 කි.මී",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඩිපෝල්",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "කිලෝමීටර 40 කි",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "Maoya",
            "label": "LOC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ගැමුණු විජේරත්න",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "සියයට 90 යි",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "12,000 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "හෙට",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "15,000 සහ 16,000 අතර",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "கிராமப்புற குழந்தைகள் பஸ்களை தவறவிட்டால், 'சிபெட்கோ' தான் பொறுப்பேற்க வேண்டும்",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "லங்காம டிப்போவிற்கு அருகாமையில் உள்ள கிராமப்புறங்களில் மற்றும் சிறுவர்கள் அசௌகரியங்களுக்கு உள்ளானால் பேருந்துகளுக்கு எரிபொருள் பெறுவதற்கு எரிபொருள் நிரப்பும் நிலையங்கள் வழங்கப்பட வேண்டுமென தனியார் பேருந்து உரிமையாளர்கள் சங்கத்தின் தலைவர் கெமுனு விஜேரத்ன இன்று (14) காலை தெரிவித்தார். கிராமப்புறங்களில் பேருந்துகள் இயக்கப்படாததற்கு, 'சிபெட்கோ' நிறுவனம் பொறுப்பேற்க வேண்டும்.",
        "தென் மாகாணத்தில் ஹக்மன, தெனிய, திக்வெல்ல, மித்தெனிய, பெலியஅத்த, ஹம்பாந்தோட்டை, சூரியவெவ மற்றும் திஸ்ஸமஹாராம ஆகிய இடங்களில் லங்காம டிப்போக்கள் இல்லாததால், பல எரிபொருள் நிரப்பு நிலையங்களுக்கு கே.ஆர். கோட்பாட்டில் எரிபொருள் வரம்பை அதிகரிக்குமாறு கோரிய போதிலும், சிபெட்கோ, ஹக்மன டிப்போ இல்லாததால், 27 கிலோமீற்றர் பயணித்து டெப்போலுக்குச் செல்ல வேண்டியுள்ளதாகவும், 40 கிலோமீற்றர் தூரம் பயணித்து, பஸ்ஸுக்கு டீசல் பெற வேண்டுமெனவும் கெமுனு விஜேரத்ன தெரிவித்தார். அம்பாறை மாவட்டத்தின் மாஓயா பிரதேசம்.",
        "90 வீதமான தனியார் பேருந்துகள் அல்லது 12,000 பேருந்துகள் நாளை இயக்கப்படும் எனவும் அதன் பின்னர் 15,000 முதல் 16,000 வரையிலான பேருந்துகள் இயக்கப்படும் எனவும் எதிர்பார்க்கப்படுவதாக திரு.கெமுனு விஜேரத்ன தெரிவித்தார்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "சிபெட்கோ",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "கெமுனு விஜேரத்ன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "தனியார் பேருந்து உரிமையாளர்கள் சங்கம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "14",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "லங்காமா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "சிபெட்கோ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "லங்காமா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஹக்மனா",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "தெனியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "திக்வெல்ல, மித்தெனிய",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "பெலியாட்டா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஹம்பாந்தோட்டை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சூரியவெவ மற்றும் திஸ்ஸமஹாராம",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "கெமுனு விஜேரத்ன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "சிபெட்கோ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஹக்மனா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "27 கி.மீ",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "டிபோல்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "40 கி.மீ",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "Maoya",
            "label": "LOC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "கெமுனு விஜேரத்ன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "90 சதவீதம்",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "12,000",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "நாளை",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "15,000 முதல் 16,000 வரை",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}