{
  "newspaper_id": "news-first-lk",
  "url": "https://www.newsfirst.lk/2022/08/28/protest-held-in-geneva-against-state-suppression/",
  "time_ut": 1661694660,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Protest held in Geneva against state suppression",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Protest held in Geneva against state suppression",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); A protest was held opposite the United Nations Human Rights Commission in Geneva, Switzerland, opposing state supression.",
        "The protestors also demanded for the people to be given the opportunity to choose a leader of their choice by holding an election.",
        "The protestors who staged the protest opposite the Geneva Human Rights Commission emphasized that the Government which does not have the people's mandate, should leave.",
        "A large number of Sri Lankans residing in Europe joined this protest.",
        "Late fees to be charged from State institutions that fail to pay water bills"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Geneva",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "News 1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the United Nations Human Rights Commission",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Geneva",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Switzerland",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "the Geneva Human Rights Commission",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lankans",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Europe",
            "label": "LOC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "State",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "රාජ්‍ය මර්දනයට එරෙහිව ජිනීවා නුවර විරෝධතාවක්",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); රාජ්‍ය මර්දනයට එරෙහිව ස්විට්සර්ලන්තයේ ජිනීවා නුවර එක්සත් ජාතීන්ගේ මානව හිමිකම් කොමිසම ඉදිරිපිට විරෝධතාවක් පැවැත්විණි.",
        "මැතිවරණයක් පවත්වා තමන්ට කැමති නායකයෙකු තෝරා ගැනීමට ජනතාවට අවස්ථාව ලබාදෙන ලෙසද විරෝධතාකරුවන් ඉල්ලා සිටියා.",
        "ජිනීවා මානව හිමිකම් කොමිසම ඉදිරිපිට විරෝධතාවයේ නිරත වූ පිරිස් අවධාරණය කළේ ජනවරමක් නොමැති ආණ්ඩුව ඉවත් විය යුතු බවයි.",
        "යුරෝපයේ වෙසෙන ශ්‍රී ලාංකිකයින් විශාල පිරිසක් මෙම විරෝධතාවයට එක්ව සිටියා.",
        "ජල බිල්පත් ගෙවීමට අපොහොසත් වන රාජ්‍ය ආයතනවලින් ප්‍රමාද ගාස්තු අය කෙරේ"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ජිනීවා",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "News 1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "එක්සත් ජාතීන්ගේ මානව හිමිකම් කොමිසම",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජිනීවා",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ස්විට්සර්ලන්තය",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "ජිනීවා මානව හිමිකම් කොමිසම",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලාංකිකයන්",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "යුරෝපය",
            "label": "LOC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "රජයේ",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "அரசின் அடக்குமுறைக்கு எதிராக ஜெனிவாவில் போராட்டம்",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); சுவிட்சர்லாந்தின் ஜெனீவாவில் உள்ள ஐக்கிய நாடுகளின் மனித உரிமைகள் ஆணைக்குழுவிற்கு எதிரே அரச அடக்குமுறையை எதிர்த்து போராட்டம் நடத்தப்பட்டது.",
        "தேர்தலை நடத்தி மக்கள் தங்களுக்கு விருப்பமான தலைவரை தெரிவு செய்வதற்கான வாய்ப்பை வழங்குமாறும் ஆர்ப்பாட்டக்காரர்கள் கோரிக்கை விடுத்துள்ளனர்.",
        "மக்கள் ஆணையைப் பெறாத அரசாங்கம் வெளியேற வேண்டும் என ஜெனிவா மனித உரிமைகள் ஆணைக்குழுவுக்கு முன்பாக ஆர்ப்பாட்டத்தில் ஈடுபட்டவர்கள் வலியுறுத்தினர்.",
        "ஐரோப்பாவில் வசிக்கும் பெருமளவான இலங்கையர்கள் இந்தப் போராட்டத்தில் கலந்துகொண்டனர்.",
        "தண்ணீர் கட்டணத்தை செலுத்தத் தவறும் அரச நிறுவனங்களிடமிருந்து தாமதக் கட்டணம் அறவிடப்படும்"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ஜெனீவா",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "News 1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஐக்கிய நாடுகளின் மனித உரிமைகள் ஆணையம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜெனீவா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சுவிட்சர்லாந்து",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஜெனிவா மனித உரிமைகள் ஆணையம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கையர்கள்",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஐரோப்பா",
            "label": "LOC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "நிலை",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}