{
  "newspaper_id": "daily-ft-lk",
  "url": "https://www.ft.lk/news/Chinese-research-ship-Yuan-Wang-5-leaves-Sri-Lanka/56-739000",
  "time_ut": 1661201962,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Chinese research ship Yuan Wang 5 leaves Sri Lanka",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Chinese research ship Yuan Wang 5 leaves Sri Lanka",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "AFP: A Chinese research vessel accused by India and the United States of spying activities, left Sri Lanka’s Chinese-run Port of Hambantota on Monday after a week-long stay.",
        "Colombo allowed the Yuan Wang 5 to visit the deep-sea port on the condition that it would not engage in research in Sri Lankan waters.",
        "Both India and the US had raised security concerns over the ship’s visit to Sri Lanka, with New Delhi lodging a complaint -- a move that delayed the visit by a week before Colombo announced a U-turn.",
        "“Our pilot is onboard and the ship is leaving port,” a harbour official told AFP as the vessel was being guided out by tug boats.",
        "“They have given the port of Jiangyin as their next destination.” The vessel said to be carrying about 400 crew had set off from Jiangyin, in China’s Jiangsu province, in mid-July.",
        "Shipping analytics websites describe the Yuan Wang 5 as a research and survey vessel, but according to Indian media it is a dual-use spy ship.",
        "When the vessel arrived last week, Chinese ambassador to Sri Lanka Qi Zhenhong said the port call was part of “normal exchanges between the two countries”.",
        "There was no send-off ceremony at the Hambantota Port, which has been run since 2017 by a Chinese State-owned company that took out a 99-year lease on it for $ 1.12 billion, less than the $ 1.4 billion Sri Lanka paid a Chinese firm to build it.",
        "New Delhi is suspicious of Beijing’s increasing presence in the Indian Ocean and activities in Sri Lanka, seeing both as firmly within its sphere of influence."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Chinese",
          "label": "NORP"
        },
        {
          "text": "Yuan Wang",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "Sri Lanka",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Chinese",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "India",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the United States",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka’s",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Chinese",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Port of Hambantota",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "Monday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "week-long",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lankan",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "India",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "US",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "New Delhi",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Colombo",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "AFP",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "about 400",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Jiangyin",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "China",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Jiangsu",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "mid-July",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Indian",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "last week",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Chinese",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Qi Zhenhong",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "two",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the Hambantota Port",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "2017",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Chinese",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "99-year",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "$ 1.12 billion",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "$ 1.4 billion",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "Chinese",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "New Delhi",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Beijing",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Indian Ocean",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "චීන පර්යේෂණ නෞකාවක් වන යුවාන් වැන්ග් 5 ශ්‍රී ලංකාවෙන් පිටත්ව යයි",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "AFP: ඔත්තු බැලීමේ ක්‍රියාකාරකම් සම්බන්ධයෙන් ඉන්දියාව සහ එක්සත් ජනපදය විසින් චෝදනා කරන ලද චීන පර්යේෂණ නෞකාවක් සතියක කාලයක් රැඳී සිටීමෙන් පසු සඳුදා ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ චීනයේ හම්බන්තොට වරායෙන් පිටත් විය.",
        "යුවාන් වැන්ග් 5 නෞකාවට ගැඹුරු මුහුදේ වරාය නැරඹීමට කොළඹ අවසර දුන්නේ එය ශ්‍රී ලංකා මුහුදේ පර්යේෂණවල නිරත නොවන බවට වන කොන්දේසිය මතය.",
        "ඉන්දියාව සහ එක්සත් ජනපදය යන දෙකම නෞකාවේ ශ්‍රී ලංකා සංචාරය සම්බන්ධයෙන් ආරක්ෂක ගැටළු මතු කර ඇති අතර, නව දිල්ලිය පැමිණිල්ලක් ගොනු කිරීමත් සමඟ -- කොළඹ U-හැරීමක් ප්‍රකාශ කිරීමට සතියකට පෙර සංචාරය ප්‍රමාද කළ පියවරක්.",
        "“අපේ නියමුවා නැවෙහි සිටින අතර නැව වරායෙන් පිටව යයි,” වරාය නිලධාරියෙක් AFP වෙත පැවසුවේ යාත්‍රාව ටග් බෝට්ටු මගින් මඟ පෙන්වමින් සිටියදී ය.",
        "\"ඔවුන් ඔවුන්ගේ මීළඟ ගමනාන්තය ලෙස Jiangyin වරාය ලබා දී ඇත.\" කාර්ය මණ්ඩලය 400 ක් පමණ රැගත් යාත්‍රාව චීනයේ ජියැන්ග්සු පළාතේ ජියැන්ග්යින් සිට ජූලි මැද භාගයේදී පිටත්ව ගොස් ඇත.",
        "නාවික විශ්ලේෂණ වෙබ් අඩවි යුවාන් වැන්ග් 5 විස්තර කරන්නේ පර්යේෂණ සහ සමීක්ෂණ යාත්‍රාවක් ලෙසයි, නමුත් ඉන්දියානු මාධ්‍යවලට අනුව එය ද්විත්ව භාවිත ඔත්තු නෞකාවකි.",
        "පසුගිය සතියේ යාත්‍රාව පැමිණි විට ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ චීන තානාපති Qi Zhenhong පැවසුවේ වරාය ඇමතුම “දෙරට අතර සාමාන්‍ය හුවමාරුවල” කොටසක් බවයි.",
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකාව ගෙවූ ඩොලර් බිලියන 1.4 ට වඩා අඩුවෙන් ඩොලර් බිලියන 1.12 කට වසර 99 ක බදු දී චීන රජයට අයත් සමාගමක් විසින් 2017 වසරේ සිට පවත්වාගෙන යනු ලබන හම්බන්තොට වරායට යැවීමේ උත්සවයක් නොතිබුණි. එය ඉදිකිරීමට චීන සමාගමක්.",
        "බීජිං ඉන්දියන් සාගරයේ වැඩි වෙමින් පවතින බව සහ ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ ක්‍රියාකාරකම් පිළිබඳව නව දිල්ලිය සැක පහළ කරයි."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "චීන",
          "label": "NORP"
        },
        {
          "text": "Yuan Wang",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "චීන",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "එක්සත් ජනපදය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "චීන",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "හම්බන්තොට වරාය",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "සඳුදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "සතියක් පුරාවට",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලාංකික",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "එක්සත් ජනපදය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "නව දිල්ලි",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "කොළඹ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "AFP",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "400 ක් පමණ",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජියැන්ග්යින්",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "චීනය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජියැංසු",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජූලි මැද",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දීය",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ගිය සතිය",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "චීන",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Qi Zhenhong",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "දෙක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "හම්බන්තොට වරාය",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "2017",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "චීන",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "අවුරුදු 99",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඩොලර් බිලියන 1.12 කි",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඩොලර් බිලියන 1.4 කි",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "චීන",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "නව දිල්ලි",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "බීජිං",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දියන් සාගරය",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "சீன ஆராய்ச்சிக் கப்பல் யுவான் வாங் 5 இலங்கையிலிருந்து புறப்பட்டது",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "AFP: இந்தியா மற்றும் அமெரிக்கா உளவு நடவடிக்கைகளில் ஈடுபட்டதாக குற்றம் சாட்டப்பட்ட சீன ஆராய்ச்சிக் கப்பல், ஒரு வார காலம் தங்கியிருந்த இலங்கையின் சீனாவின் ஹம்பாந்தோட்டை துறைமுகத்தில் இருந்து திங்கள்கிழமை புறப்பட்டது.",
        "இலங்கை கடற்பரப்பில் ஆராய்ச்சியில் ஈடுபடக்கூடாது என்ற நிபந்தனையின் பேரில் யுவான் வாங் 5 கப்பல் ஆழ்கடல் துறைமுகத்தை பார்வையிட கொழும்பு அனுமதித்தது.",
        "இந்தியா மற்றும் அமெரிக்கா ஆகிய இரு நாடுகளும் கப்பலின் இலங்கை வருகை குறித்து பாதுகாப்புக் கவலைகளை எழுப்பியுள்ளன, புது டெல்லியில் புகார் அளித்தது -- கொழும்பு யூ-டர்ன் அறிவிப்பதற்கு ஒரு வாரத்திற்கு முன்பே இந்த பயணத்தை தாமதப்படுத்தியது.",
        "\"எங்கள் விமானி கப்பலில் இருக்கிறார், கப்பல் துறைமுகத்தை விட்டு வெளியேறுகிறது,\" என்று துறைமுக அதிகாரி ஒருவர் AFP இடம் கூறினார், கப்பல் இழுவை படகுகள் மூலம் வழிநடத்தப்பட்டது.",
        "\"அவர்கள் ஜியாங்யின் துறைமுகத்தை தங்கள் அடுத்த இலக்காகக் கொடுத்துள்ளனர்.\" சுமார் 400 பணியாளர்களை ஏற்றிச் சென்றதாகக் கூறப்படும் கப்பல் ஜூலை நடுப்பகுதியில் சீனாவின் ஜியாங்சு மாகாணத்தில் உள்ள ஜியாங்யினிலிருந்து புறப்பட்டது.",
        "கப்பல் பகுப்பாய்வு வலைத்தளங்கள் யுவான் வாங் 5 ஐ ஒரு ஆராய்ச்சி மற்றும் ஆய்வுக் கப்பல் என்று விவரிக்கின்றன, ஆனால் இந்திய ஊடகங்களின்படி இது இரட்டை பயன்பாட்டு உளவுக் கப்பல்.",
        "கடந்த வாரம் கப்பல் வந்தபோது, ​​இலங்கைக்கான சீனத் தூதுவர் Qi Zhenhong, துறைமுக அழைப்பு \"இரு நாடுகளுக்கும் இடையிலான இயல்பான பரிமாற்றத்தின்\" ஒரு பகுதியாகும் என்றார்.",
        "அம்பாந்தோட்டை துறைமுகத்தில் 2017 ஆம் ஆண்டு முதல் நடத்தப்பட்டு வரும் சீன அரசுக்கு சொந்தமான நிறுவனம் 1.12 பில்லியன் டொலர்களுக்கு 99 வருட குத்தகைக்கு எடுத்துள்ள ஹம்பாந்தோட்டை துறைமுகத்தில் இலங்கை செலுத்திய 1.4 பில்லியன் டொலர்களை விட குறைவானது. சீன நிறுவனம் இதை உருவாக்க உள்ளது.",
        "இந்தியப் பெருங்கடலில் பெய்ஜிங்கின் அதிகரித்துவரும் இருப்பு மற்றும் இலங்கையின் செயல்பாடுகள் குறித்து புது டெல்லி சந்தேகம் கொள்கிறது."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "சீன",
          "label": "NORP"
        },
        {
          "text": "Yuan Wang",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "இலங்கை",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "சீன",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்தியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஐக்கிய நாடுகள்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கையின்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சீன",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஹம்பாந்தோட்டை துறைமுகம்",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "திங்கட்கிழமை",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "வாரம் முழுவதும்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இந்தியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "எங்களுக்கு",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "புது தில்லி",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "கொழும்பு",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "AFP",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "சுமார் 400",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜியாங்யின்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சீனா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜியாங்சு",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜூலை நடுப்பகுதி",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இந்தியன்",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "கடந்த வாரம்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சீன",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Qi Zhenhong",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இரண்டு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "அம்பாந்தோட்டை துறைமுகம்",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "2017",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சீன",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "99-ஆண்டு",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "$ 1.12 பில்லியன்",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "$ 1.4 பில்லியன்",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "சீன",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "புது தில்லி",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "பெய்ஜிங்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்தியப் பெருங்கடல்",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}