{
  "newspaper_id": "economy-next-com",
  "url": "https://economynext.com/sri-lanka-telephone-data-tariffs-up-by-20-pct-99415/",
  "time_ut": 1662274860,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Sri Lanka telephone, data tariffs up by 20-pct",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Sri Lanka telephone, data tariffs up by 20-pct",
      "author": "",
      "body_lines": [
        "ECONOMYNEXT – All three mobile service providers in Sri Lanka increased call and data tariffs by 20 percent following the 15 percent value added tax (VAT) with effect from September 05, data providers said.",
        "SLTC Mobitel, the local mobile service provider and Dialog Axiata announced it will increase the Mobile Broadband Plans and value added services by 20 percent and Pay TV by 25 percent.",
        "“We the licensed telecommunication service providers wish to inform due to escalation of operational costs resulting from the devaluation of the rupee, we are compelled to increase tariffs,” both the operators announced on their websites.",
        "“Accordingly, as approved by the Telecommunications Regulatory Commission of Sri Lanka (TRCSL), tariffs on Mobile, Fixed Telephone, Broadband Plans and Value Added Services (Prepaid and Postpaid) will be increased by 20%, while tariffs on all Pay Television Services will be increased by 25%.”",
        "Sri Lanka’s president announced in his interim budget for 2022 that value-added tax (VAT) will be increased to 15 percent from 12 percent starting September 01.",
        "Other telephony and broadband providers too announced they had increased their tariffs.",
        "The Indian mobile service provider Airtel said calll, sms, data and VAS would be increased. (Colombo/Sept04/2022)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Sri Lanka",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "20",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "three",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "20 percent",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "the 15 percent",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "September 05",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Mobitel",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Axiata",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "20 percent",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "25 percent",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "the Telecommunications Regulatory Commission of Sri Lanka",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Mobile",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Fixed Telephone",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "20%",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "25%",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka’s",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "2022",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "15 percent",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "12 percent",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "September 01",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "Indian",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Airtel",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "VAS",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ දුරකථන, දත්ත ගාස්තු සියයට 20කින් ඉහළට",
      "author": "",
      "body_lines": [
        "ECONOMYNEXT – සැප්තැම්බර් 05 වැනිදා සිට ක්‍රියාත්මක වන පරිදි සියයට 15ක එකතු කළ අගය මත බද්දෙන් (වැට්) පසු ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ ජංගම දුරකථන සේවා සපයන්නන් තිදෙනාම ඇමතුම් සහ දත්ත ගාස්තු සියයට 20කින් වැඩි කළ බව දත්ත සපයන්නන් පවසයි.",
        "දේශීය ජංගම දුරකථන සේවා සපයන්නා වන SLTC Mobitel සහ Dialog Axiata නිවේදනය කළේ ජංගම බ්‍රෝඩ්බෑන්ඩ් සැලසුම් සහ අගය එකතු කළ සේවාවන් සියයට 20 කින් සහ Pay TV සියයට 25 කින් වැඩි කරන බවයි.",
        "“රුපියල අවප්‍රමාණය වීම නිසා ඇති වන මෙහෙයුම් පිරිවැය ඉහළ යාම හේතුවෙන් බලපත්‍රලාභී විදුලි සංදේශ සේවා සපයන්නන් වන අපි තීරුබදු වැඩි කිරීමට බලකෙරෙන බව දැනුම් දීමට කැමැත්තෙමු,” ක්‍රියාකරුවන් දෙදෙනාම ඔවුන්ගේ වෙබ් අඩවිවල නිවේදනය කළහ.",
        "“ඒ අනුව, ශ්‍රී ලංකා විදුලි සංදේශ නියාමන කොමිෂන් සභාව (TRCSL) විසින් අනුමත කරන ලද පරිදි, ජංගම දුරකථන, ස්ථාවර දුරකථන, බ්‍රෝඩ්බෑන්ඩ් සැලසුම් සහ අගය එකතු කළ සේවාවන් සඳහා (පෙරගෙවුම් සහ පසුගෙවුම්) ගාස්තු 20% කින් වැඩි කරනු ලබන අතර, සියලුම ගෙවන රූපවාහිනී සේවා සඳහා ගාස්තු 20% කින් ඉහළ යනු ඇත. 25% කින් වැඩි කරන්න.\"",
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ ජනාධිපතිවරයා 2022 වසර සඳහා වන සිය අතුරු අයවැයෙන් ප්‍රකාශ කළේ අගය එකතු කළ බද්ද (වැට්) සැප්තැම්බර් 01 වැනිදා සිට සියයට 12 සිට සියයට 15 දක්වා වැඩි කරන බවයි.",
        "අනෙකුත් දුරකථන සහ බ්‍රෝඩ්බෑන්ඩ් සපයන්නන් ද තම ගාස්තු ඉහළ දැමූ බව නිවේදනය කළහ.",
        "ඉන්දියානු ජංගම දුරකථන සේවා සපයන්නා වන එයාර්ටෙල් පැවසුවේ ඇමතුම්, කෙටි පණිවුඩ, දත්ත සහ VAS වැඩි කරන බවයි. (කොළඹ/සැප්තැම්බර්04/2022)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "20",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "තුන්",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "සියයට 20 කි",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "සියයට 15 යි",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "සැප්තැම්බර් 05",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "මොබිටෙල්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Axiata",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "සියයට 20 කි",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "සියයට 25 කි",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකා විදුලි සංදේශ නියාමන කොමිෂන් සභාව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජංගම",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ස්ථාවර දුරකථන",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "20%",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "25%",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "2022",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "සියයට 15 කි",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "සියයට 12 කි",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "සැප්තැම්බර් 01",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දීය",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "එයාර්ටෙල්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "VAS",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "இலங்கை தொலைபேசி, தரவு கட்டணங்கள் 20-சதவீதம்",
      "author": "",
      "body_lines": [
        "ECONOMYNEXT – செப்டெம்பர் 05 முதல் நடைமுறைக்கு வரும் 15 சதவீத பெறுமதி சேர் வரியை (VAT) தொடர்ந்து இலங்கையில் உள்ள மூன்று மொபைல் சேவை வழங்குநர்களும் அழைப்பு மற்றும் தரவு கட்டணங்களை 20 சதவீதத்தால் அதிகரித்துள்ளதாக தரவு வழங்குநர்கள் தெரிவித்தனர்.",
        "SLTC Mobitel, உள்ளூர் மொபைல் சேவை வழங்குனர் மற்றும் Dialog Axiata ஆனது மொபைல் பிராட்பேண்ட் திட்டங்கள் மற்றும் மதிப்பு கூட்டப்பட்ட சேவைகளை 20 சதவீதத்தாலும், Pay TV 25 சதவீதத்தாலும் அதிகரிக்கப்படும் என அறிவித்தது.",
        "உரிமம் பெற்ற தொலைத்தொடர்பு சேவை வழங்குநர்களான நாங்கள் ரூபாய் மதிப்பிழப்பால் ஏற்படும் செயல்பாட்டுச் செலவுகள் அதிகரித்து வருவதால், கட்டணத்தை அதிகரிக்க வேண்டிய கட்டாயத்தில் உள்ளோம் என்று இரு ஆபரேட்டர்களும் தங்கள் இணையதளங்களில் அறிவித்துள்ளனர்.",
        "\"இதன்படி, இலங்கை தொலைத்தொடர்பு ஒழுங்குமுறை ஆணையம் (TRCSL) அங்கீகரித்தபடி, மொபைல், நிலையான தொலைபேசி, அகல அலைவரிசை திட்டங்கள் மற்றும் மதிப்பு கூட்டப்பட்ட சேவைகள் (முற்கொடுப்பனவு மற்றும் போஸ்ட்பெய்ட்) மீதான கட்டணங்கள் 20% அதிகரிக்கப்படும் அதேவேளை அனைத்து கட்டண தொலைக்காட்சி சேவைகளுக்கான கட்டணங்களும் அதிகரிக்கப்படும். 25% அதிகரிக்கப்படும்.",
        "2022ஆம் ஆண்டுக்கான இடைக்கால வரவு செலவுத் திட்டத்தில் இலங்கையின் ஜனாதிபதி, பெறுமதி சேர் வரி (VAT) செப்டெம்பர் 01ஆம் திகதி தொடக்கம் 12 சதவீதத்திலிருந்து 15 சதவீதமாக அதிகரிக்கப்படும் என அறிவித்துள்ளார்.",
        "மற்ற டெலிபோனி மற்றும் பிராட்பேண்ட் வழங்குநர்களும் தங்கள் கட்டணங்களை அதிகரித்துள்ளதாக அறிவித்தனர்.",
        "இந்திய மொபைல் சேவை வழங்குநரான ஏர்டெல், அழைப்பு, எஸ்எம்எஸ், டேட்டா மற்றும் VAS ஆகியவை அதிகரிக்கப்படும் என்று கூறியுள்ளது. (கொழும்பு/செப்டம்பர்04/2022)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "இலங்கை",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "20",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "மூன்று",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "20 சதவீதம்",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "15 சதவீதம்",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "செப்டம்பர் 05",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "மொபிடெல்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆக்சியாட்டா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "20 சதவீதம்",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "25 சதவீதம்",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கையின் தொலைத்தொடர்பு ஒழுங்குமுறை ஆணைக்குழு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "கைபேசி",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "நிலையான தொலைபேசி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "20%",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "25%",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கையின்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "2022",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "15 சதவீதம்",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "12 சதவீதம்",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "செப்டம்பர் 01",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "இந்தியன்",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஏர்டெல்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "VAS",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}