{
  "newspaper_id": "news-first-lk",
  "url": "https://www.newsfirst.lk/2022/07/20/india-all-party-meet-heats-up-on-sri-lanka-crisis/",
  "time_ut": 1658305440,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "India All-Party meet heats up on Sri Lanka Crisis",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "India All-Party meet heats up on Sri Lanka Crisis",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "(NDTV / The Hindu): The Indian Government has told the all-party meeting on the situation in Sri Lanka that “fiscal prudence and responsible governance” are the lessons the country has to learn from the crisis in the neighboring country and that there should not be a “culture of freebies”.",
        "Addressing the meeting on Tuesday (19), Indian External Affairs Minister S. Jaishankar also clarified that India had not in any way “facilitated” former Sri Lankan President Gotabaya Rajapaksa’s exit from Sri Lanka to the Maldives and then to Singapore, saying that this was decided by those countries.",
        "However, he said that no other country has supported Sri Lanka as India has in terms of food, fuel, medicines, and other essentials.",
        "Jaishankar also denied that any formal request had been made for help earlier, when asked about whether India’s assistance had been “too little too late”, referring to a report in The Hindu from Colombo 2020.",
        "Jaishankar said that the numbers had been shown without any “political intent” and to show any comparison of the crisis in Sri Lanka and India’s economic situation was part of a “misinformed campaign”, and this would “never happen” in India. However, members protested as they said the meeting had been called to discuss Sri Lanka, not India.",
        "Telangana Rashtra Samithi (TRS) leader Nama Nageshwara Rao said the Centre should have spoken about its fiscal health instead. “RBI data says the debt-GDP and the borrowing-revenue ratio of the Centre are much worse than the States.",
        "The Centre was trying to score political brownie points even from a discussion on Sri Lanka,” Rao said. The Dravida Munnetra Kazhagam (DMK), Trinamool Congress (TMC), and Left parties too questioned the presentation.",
        "When asked about whether the aid to Sri Lanka was being equitably distributed in the country’s northern areas as well, Jaishankar said that the government had been coordinating to ensure this. To other questions on whether India’s assistance to Sri Lanka had come too late, Jaishankar stressed that the government had warned the Rajapaksas about the economic slide on several occasions, but that Colombo had not been “fiscally prudent” or responsible in the crisis.",
        "Listing India’s assistance of about $3.8 billion since January 2022, Jaishankar said India had provided Sri Lanka with a currency swap of $400 million, a debt deferral of more than $1.5 billion, Lines of Credit totaling $1.55 billion for food, fuel, fertilizers, and other essentials, and listed gifts from the Central government and the Tamil Nadu Government of medicines, kerosene, rice, and milk powder.",
        "He said that the way out of the crisis for Sri Lanka would require both political stability, with a parliamentary vote for the next President to be held on Wednesday, as well as the need for debt restructuring by Sri Lankan lenders to allow for an economic recovery, once the government is in place.",
        "“In our history, we haven’t taken such a proactive step for a neighboring country,” Jaishankar told members, adding that no other country had done as much for Sri Lanka at this time.",
        "India is naturally worried over the “very serious crisis” in Sri Lanka and there are “very strong” lessons of fiscal prudence, responsible governance and not having “a culture of freebies” to be learnt, External Affairs Minister S Jaishankar told an all-party meeting on Tuesday (19), according to NDTV.",
        "“It is a matter which pertains to a very close neighbour and given the proximity, we naturally worry about the consequences, the spillover it has for us,” he added.",
        "Sri Lanka is facing its worst economic crisis in seven decades, with a severe foreign exchange shortage hampering the import of essentials, including food, fuel and medicines.",
        "The economic downturn has also sparked a political crisis in the island nation after a popular uprising against the government. Acting president Ranil Wickremesinghe has declared a state of emergency in the country.",
        "Sri Lanka gets a new President: Ranil Wickremesinghe wins with 134 votes"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "India All-Party",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "Sri Lanka Crisis",
          "label": "LOC"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Hindu",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "The Indian Government",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Tuesday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "19",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Indian",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "S. Jaishankar",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "India",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lankan",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Gotabaya Rajapaksa’s",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Maldives",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Singapore",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "India",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Jaishankar",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "India",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Hindu",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Jaishankar",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "India",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "India",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "India",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Telangana Rashtra Samithi",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Nama Nageshwara Rao",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Centre",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "RBI",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Centre",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "States",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Rao",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "The Dravida Munnetra Kazhagam",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "DMK",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Trinamool Congress",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "TMC",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Jaishankar",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "India",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Jaishankar",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Rajapaksas",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Colombo",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "India",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "about $3.8 billion",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "January 2022",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Jaishankar",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "India",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "$400 million",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "more than $1.5 billion",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "Lines of Credit",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "$1.55 billion",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "Central",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Tamil Nadu Government",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Wednesday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lankan",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Jaishankar",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "India",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "S Jaishankar",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Tuesday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "19",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "NDTV",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "seven decades",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "134",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "ශ්‍රී ලංකා අර්බුදය සම්බන්ධයෙන් ඉන්දීය සර්ව පාක්ෂික හමුව උණුසුම් වෙයි",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "(NDTV / The Hindu): අසල්වැසි රටේ අර්බුදයෙන් රටට උගත යුතු පාඩම් “මූල්‍ය විචක්ෂණභාවය සහ වගකිවයුතු පාලනය” බව ඉන්දීය රජය ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ තත්ත්වය පිළිබඳ සර්ව පාක්ෂික රැස්වීමට පවසා තිබේ. \"නිදහස් සංස්කෘතියක්\" නොවන්න.",
        "අඟහරුවාදා (19) පැවති රැස්වීම අමතමින් ඉන්දීය විදේශ කටයුතු අමාත්‍ය එස්.ජයිශංකර් ද පැහැදිලි කළේ ශ්‍රී ලංකා හිටපු ජනාධිපති ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ මහතා ශ්‍රී ලංකාවෙන් මාලදිවයිනට සහ සිංගප්පූරුවට පිටත්ව යාමට ඉන්දියාව කිසිදු ආකාරයකින් “පහසුකම්” කර නොමැති බවයි. එම රටවල් විසින් තීරණය කරන ලදී.",
        "කෙසේ වෙතත්, ආහාර, ඉන්ධන, ඖෂධ සහ අනෙකුත් අත්‍යාවශ්‍ය ද්‍රව්‍ය සම්බන්ධයෙන් ඉන්දියාව දක්වන සහයෝගය වෙනත් කිසිදු රටක් ශ්‍රී ලංකාවට ලබා දී නොමැති බව ඔහු පැවසීය.",
        "2020 කොළඹින් ද හින්දු පුවත්පතේ පළ වූ වාර්තාවක් ගැන සඳහන් කරමින්, ඉන්දියාවේ සහය “ප්‍රමාද වැඩියි” දැයි විමසූ විට, මීට පෙර උදව් සඳහා කිසිදු විධිමත් ඉල්ලීමක් කර නොතිබූ බව ජයශංකර් ප්‍රතික්ෂේප කළේය.",
        "කිසිදු “දේශපාලන චේතනාවකින්” තොරව එම සංඛ්‍යා පෙන්වා දී ඇති බවත් ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ අර්බුදය සහ ඉන්දියාවේ ආර්ථික තත්ත්වය සංසන්දනය කිරීම “වැරදි තොරතුරු ප්‍රචාරණ ව්‍යාපාරයක” කොටසක් බවත්, මෙය ඉන්දියාවේ “කවදාවත් සිදු නොවන” බවත් ජයශංකර් පැවසීය. කෙසේ වෙතත්, මෙම රැස්වීම කැඳවා ඇත්තේ ඉන්දියාව ගැන නොව ශ්‍රී ලංකාව ගැන සාකච්ඡා කිරීමට බව පැවසීම නිසා මන්ත්‍රීවරු විරෝධය පළ කළහ.",
        "තෙලන්ගානා රාෂ්ට්‍ර සමිති (TRS) නායක නාම නාගේශ්වර රාඕ පැවසුවේ ඒ වෙනුවට මධ්‍යස්ථානය එහි මූල්‍ය සෞඛ්‍යය ගැන කතා කළ යුතුව තිබූ බවයි. “RBI දත්ත පවසන්නේ මධ්‍යයේ ණය-දළ දේශීය නිෂ්පාදිතය සහ ණය ගැනීම්-ආදායම් අනුපාතය ප්‍රාන්තවලට වඩා බෙහෙවින් නරක බවයි.",
        "මධ්‍යස්ථානය ශ්‍රී ලංකාව පිළිබඳ සාකච්ඡාවකින් පවා දේශපාලන බ්‍රව්නි ලකුණු ලබා ගැනීමට උත්සාහ කරමින් සිටියේය, ”රාඕ පැවසීය. ද්‍රවිඩ මුන්නේත්‍ර කසාගම් (ඩීඑම්කේ), ත්‍රිනාමුල් කොංග්‍රසය (ටීඑම්සී) සහ වාම පක්ෂ ද ඉදිරිපත් කිරීම ප්‍රශ්න කළහ.",
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවට ලැබෙන ආධාර රටේ උතුරු ප්‍රදේශවල ද සාධාරණ ලෙස බෙදා හරින්නේ දැයි ඇසූ විට ජයිශංකර් පැවසුවේ එය සහතික කිරීම සඳහා රජය සම්බන්ධීකරණය වෙමින් පවතින බවයි. ශ්‍රී ලංකාවට ඉන්දියාවේ සහය ප්‍රමාද වී තිබේද යන්න පිළිබඳ අනෙකුත් ප්‍රශ්නවලට, ජයශංකර් අවධාරණය කළේ, ආර්ථික කඩාවැටීම ගැන රජය අවස්ථා කිහිපයකදී රාජපක්ෂවරුන්ට අනතුරු ඇඟවූ නමුත්, කොළඹ “මූල්‍යමය වශයෙන් දූරදර්ශී” හෝ අර්බුදයට වගකිව යුතු නොවූ බවයි.",
        "2022 ජනවාරි සිට ඉන්දියාවේ ඩොලර් බිලියන 3.8 ක පමණ ආධාර ලැයිස්තුගත කරමින්, ජයිශංකර් පැවසුවේ ඉන්දියාව ශ්‍රී ලංකාවට ඩොලර් මිලියන 400 ක මුදල් හුවමාරුවක්, ඩොලර් බිලියන 1.5 කට වඩා ණය කල්දැමීමක්, ආහාර, ඉන්ධන, පොහොර සහ වෙනත් සඳහා ඩොලර් බිලියන 1.55 ක ණයක් ලබා දී ඇති බවයි. අත්‍යවශ්‍ය ද්‍රව්‍ය, සහ මධ්‍යම රජයෙන් සහ තමිල්නාඩු රජයෙන් ඖෂධ, භූමිතෙල්, සහල් සහ කිරිපිටි ලැයිස්තුගත තෑගි.",
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකාව සඳහා අර්බුදයෙන් මිදීම සඳහා දේශපාලන ස්ථාවරත්වය යන දෙකම අවශ්‍ය වනු ඇති බවත්, මීළඟ ජනාධිපතිවරයා සඳහා පාර්ලිමේන්තු ඡන්දයක් බදාදා පැවැත්වීමට නියමිත බවත්, ආර්ථික ප්‍රකෘතියක් සඳහා ඉඩ සැලසීම සඳහා ශ්‍රී ලංකා ණය දෙන්නන් විසින් ණය ප්‍රතිව්‍යුහගත කිරීමේ අවශ්‍යතාවය බවත් ඔහු පැවසීය. , රජය පිහිට වූ පසු.",
        "\"අපගේ ඉතිහාසයේ, අපි අසල්වැසි රටක් සඳහා එවැනි ක්‍රියාකාරී පියවරක් ගෙන නැත,\" ජයිශංකර් සාමාජිකයින්ට පැවසුවේ, මේ අවස්ථාවේ ශ්‍රී ලංකාව වෙනුවෙන් වෙනත් කිසිම රටක් කර නොමැති බවයි.",
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ \"ඉතා බරපතල අර්බුදය\" සම්බන්ධයෙන් ඉන්දියාව ස්වභාවිකවම කනස්සල්ලට පත්ව සිටින අතර මූල්‍ය විචක්ෂණභාවය, වගකිවයුතු පාලනය සහ \"නොමිලේ ලබා දෙන සංස්කෘතියක්\" නොමැති \"ඉතා ශක්තිමත්\" පාඩම් ඉගෙන ගත යුතු බව විදේශ කටයුතු අමාත්‍ය එස් ජයශංකර් සියල්ලන්ටම පැවසීය. පක්ෂ රැස්වීම අඟහරුවාදා (19) එන්.ඩී.ටී.වී.",
        "\"එය ඉතා සමීප අසල්වැසියෙකුට අදාළ කාරණයක් වන අතර සමීපත්වය සැලකිල්ලට ගනිමින්, අපි ස්වභාවිකවම එහි ප්‍රතිවිපාක ගැන කරදර වෙමු, එයින් අපට ඇති වන කාන්දුව,\" ඔහු තවදුරටත් පැවසීය.",
        "ආහාර, ඉන්ධන සහ ඖෂධ ඇතුළු අත්‍යාවශ්‍ය ද්‍රව්‍ය ආනයනයට බාධා පමුණුවමින් පවතින දැඩි විදේශ විනිමය හිඟයක් සමඟ ශ්‍රී ලංකාව දශක හතකට පසු ඇති වූ දරුණුතම ආර්ථික අර්බුදයට මුහුණ දී සිටී.",
        "රජයට එරෙහි ජනතා නැගිටීමෙන් පසු ආර්ථික පසුබෑම දිවයිනේ දේශපාලන අර්බුදයක් ද ඇති කර තිබේ. වැඩබලන ජනාධිපති රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතා විසින් රට තුළ හදිසි තත්ත්වයක් ප්‍රකාශයට පත් කර තිබේ.",
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවට නව ජනාධිපතිවරයෙක් ලැබේ: රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ ඡන්ද 134 කින් ජයග්‍රහණය කරයි"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ඉන්දීය සර්ව පාක්ෂිකයා",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකා අර්බුදය",
          "label": "LOC"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "හින්දු",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දීය රජය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "අඟහරුවාදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "19",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දීය",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "එස්. ජයශංකර්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලාංකික",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂගේ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මාලදිවයින",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "සිංගප්පූරුව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ජයශංකර්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "හින්දු",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ජයශංකර්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "තෙලන්ගානා රාෂ්ට්‍ර සමිතිය",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Nama Nageshwara Rao",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "මධ්යස්ථානය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "RBI",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "මධ්යස්ථානය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජනපදය",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "රාඕ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ද්‍රවිඩ මුන්නේත්‍ර කසාගම්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඩී.එම්.කේ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ත්‍රිනාමුල් කොංග්‍රසය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ටී.එම්.සී",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජයශංකර්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජයශංකර්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "රාජපක්ෂලා",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "කොළඹ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඩොලර් බිලියන 3.8 ක් පමණ",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "2022 ජනවාරි",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජයශංකර්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඩොලර් මිලියන 400 කි",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඩොලර් බිලියන 1.5 කට වඩා",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "ණය රේඛා",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඩොලර් බිලියන 1.55 කි",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "මධ්යම",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "තමිල්නාඩු රජය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "බදාදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලාංකික",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ජයශංකර්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "එස් ජයශංකර්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "අඟහරුවාදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "19",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "NDTV",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "දශක හතක්",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "134",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "இலங்கை நெருக்கடி தொடர்பாக இந்திய சர்வகட்சி கூட்டம் சூடுபிடித்துள்ளது",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "(என்.டி.டி.வி / தி இந்து): இலங்கையின் நிலைமை குறித்த அனைத்துக் கட்சிக் கூட்டத்தில் இந்திய அரசாங்கம், “நிதி விவேகம் மற்றும் பொறுப்பான நிர்வாகம்” என்பது அண்டை நாட்டில் ஏற்பட்டுள்ள நெருக்கடியிலிருந்து நாடு கற்றுக்கொள்ள வேண்டிய பாடங்கள் என்றும், அது இருக்க வேண்டும் என்றும் கூறியுள்ளது. \"இலவச கலாச்சாரமாக\" இருக்கக்கூடாது.",
        "செவ்வாய்க்கிழமை (19) நடைபெற்ற கூட்டத்தில் உரையாற்றிய இந்திய வெளிவிவகார அமைச்சர் எஸ். ஜெய்சங்கரும், இலங்கையின் முன்னாள் ஜனாதிபதி கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ச இலங்கையிலிருந்து மாலைதீவுக்கும் பின்னர் சிங்கப்பூருக்கும் செல்வதற்கு இந்தியா எந்த வகையிலும் \"வசதி செய்யவில்லை\" என்று தெளிவுபடுத்தினார். அந்த நாடுகளால் முடிவு செய்யப்பட்டது.",
        "எவ்வாறாயினும், உணவு, எரிபொருள், மருந்துகள் மற்றும் பிற அத்தியாவசியப் பொருட்களில் இந்தியாவைப் போன்று வேறு எந்த நாடும் இலங்கைக்கு ஆதரவளிக்கவில்லை என்றும் அவர் கூறினார்.",
        "கொழும்பில் 2020 இல் இருந்து தி இந்து நாளிதழில் வெளியான செய்தியைக் குறிப்பிடுகையில், இந்தியாவின் உதவி “மிகவும் தாமதமாகிவிட்டதா” என்று கேட்கப்பட்டபோது, ​​இதற்கு முன்னர் உதவிக்காக முறையான கோரிக்கை எதுவும் விடுக்கப்படவில்லை என்றும் ஜெய்சங்கர் மறுத்தார்.",
        "எந்த ஒரு \"அரசியல் நோக்கமும்\" இன்றி இந்த எண்கள் காட்டப்பட்டுள்ளன என்றும், இலங்கை மற்றும் இந்தியாவின் பொருளாதார சூழ்நிலையில் ஏற்பட்டுள்ள நெருக்கடியை ஒப்பிடுவது \"தவறான தகவல் பிரச்சாரத்தின்\" ஒரு பகுதி என்றும், இந்தியாவில் இது \"ஒருபோதும் நடக்காது\" என்றும் ஜெய்சங்கர் கூறினார். ஆனால், இந்தியாவைப் பற்றி அல்ல, இலங்கையைப் பற்றி விவாதிக்கவே கூட்டத்திற்கு அழைப்பு விடுக்கப்பட்டுள்ளதாகக் கூறி உறுப்பினர்கள் எதிர்ப்புத் தெரிவித்தனர்.",
        "தெலுங்கானா ராஷ்டிர சமிதி (டிஆர்எஸ்) தலைவர் நமா நாகேஸ்வர ராவ், அதற்கு பதிலாக மத்திய அரசு தனது நிதி ஆரோக்கியம் பற்றி பேசியிருக்க வேண்டும் என்றார். “கடன்-ஜிடிபி மற்றும் மத்திய அரசின் கடன்-வருவாய் விகிதம் மாநிலங்களை விட மோசமாக இருப்பதாக ஆர்பிஐ தரவு கூறுகிறது.",
        "இலங்கை பற்றிய விவாதத்தில் இருந்தும் அரசியல் பிரவுனி புள்ளிகளைப் பெறுவதற்கு மத்திய அரசு முயற்சிக்கிறது,” என்று ராவ் கூறினார். திராவிட முன்னேற்றக் கழகம் (திமுக), திரிணாமுல் காங்கிரஸ் (டிஎம்சி) மற்றும் இடதுசாரிக் கட்சிகளும் இந்த விளக்கக்காட்சியை கேள்வி எழுப்பின.",
        "இலங்கைக்கான உதவிகள் நாட்டின் வடக்குப் பகுதிகளிலும் சமமாக விநியோகிக்கப்படுகிறதா என்று கேட்டபோது, ​​இதை உறுதிப்படுத்த அரசாங்கம் ஒருங்கிணைத்து வருவதாக ஜெய்சங்கர் கூறினார். இலங்கைக்கான இந்தியாவின் உதவி மிகவும் தாமதமாக வந்ததா என்ற மற்ற கேள்விகளுக்கு, பொருளாதார சரிவு குறித்து ராஜபக்சேக்களை அரசாங்கம் பல சந்தர்ப்பங்களில் எச்சரித்துள்ளது, ஆனால் கொழும்பு \"நிதி விவேகமாக\" அல்லது நெருக்கடிக்கு பொறுப்பாக இருக்கவில்லை என்று ஜெய்சங்கர் வலியுறுத்தினார்.",
        "ஜனவரி 2022 முதல் இந்தியாவின் உதவியைப் பட்டியலிட்ட ஜெய்சங்கர், இந்தியா இலங்கைக்கு 400 மில்லியன் டாலர் நாணயப் பரிமாற்றம், 1.5 பில்லியன் டாலருக்கும் அதிகமான கடன் ஒத்திவைப்பு, உணவு, எரிபொருள், உரங்கள் மற்றும் பிறவற்றிற்காக மொத்தம் 1.55 பில்லியன் டாலர் கடன் வழங்கியுள்ளது என்றார். அத்தியாவசிய பொருட்கள் மற்றும் மத்திய அரசு மற்றும் தமிழ்நாடு அரசு வழங்கும் மருந்துகள், மண்ணெண்ணெய், அரிசி மற்றும் பால் பவுடர் பட்டியலிடப்பட்ட பரிசுகள்.",
        "இலங்கைக்கான நெருக்கடியிலிருந்து மீள்வதற்கு அரசியல் ஸ்திரத்தன்மையும், அடுத்த ஜனாதிபதிக்கான பாராளுமன்ற வாக்கெடுப்பும் புதன் கிழமை நடைபெறவுள்ளதாகவும், அத்துடன் பொருளாதார மீட்சிக்கு அனுமதிக்க இலங்கை கடன் வழங்குபவர்களின் கடன் மறுசீரமைப்பு தேவை எனவும் அவர் கூறினார். , அரசாங்கம் அமைந்தவுடன்.",
        "\"எங்கள் வரலாற்றில், அண்டை நாட்டிற்கு இதுபோன்ற ஒரு செயலூக்கமான நடவடிக்கையை நாங்கள் எடுக்கவில்லை,\" என்று ஜெய்சங்கர் உறுப்பினர்களிடம் கூறினார், இந்த நேரத்தில் வேறு எந்த நாடும் இலங்கைக்கு செய்திருக்கவில்லை என்று கூறினார்.",
        "இலங்கையில் ஏற்பட்டுள்ள \"மிகக் கடுமையான நெருக்கடி\" குறித்து இந்தியா இயல்பாகவே கவலை கொண்டுள்ளது, மேலும் நிதி விவேகம், பொறுப்பான நிர்வாகம் மற்றும் \"இலவசக் கலாசாரம்\" இல்லாத \"மிக வலிமையான\" படிப்பினைகள் உள்ளன என்று வெளிவிவகார அமைச்சர் எஸ் ஜெய்சங்கர் அனைவருக்கும் தெரிவித்தார். கட்சி கூட்டம் செவ்வாய்க்கிழமை (19) என என்.டி.டி.வி.",
        "\"இது மிகவும் நெருங்கிய அண்டை வீட்டாரைப் பற்றிய ஒரு விஷயம் மற்றும் அருகாமையில் இருப்பதால், அதன் விளைவுகள், அது நமக்கு ஏற்படுத்தும் கசிவு பற்றி இயல்பாகவே கவலைப்படுகிறோம்,\" என்று அவர் மேலும் கூறினார்.",
        "இலங்கை ஏழு தசாப்தங்களில் மிக மோசமான பொருளாதார நெருக்கடியை எதிர்கொள்கிறது, கடுமையான அந்நிய செலாவணி பற்றாக்குறை உணவு, எரிபொருள் மற்றும் மருந்துகள் உட்பட அத்தியாவசிய பொருட்களின் இறக்குமதிக்கு தடையாக உள்ளது.",
        "அரசாங்கத்திற்கு எதிரான மக்கள் எழுச்சிக்குப் பின்னர் பொருளாதார வீழ்ச்சி தீவு நாட்டில் அரசியல் நெருக்கடியையும் தூண்டியுள்ளது. ஜனாதிபதி ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க நாட்டில் அவசரகால நிலையை பிரகடனப்படுத்தியுள்ளார்.",
        "இலங்கைக்கு புதிய ஜனாதிபதி: ரணில் விக்ரமசிங்கே 134 வாக்குகள் பெற்று வெற்றி பெற்றார்"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "இந்திய அனைத்துக் கட்சி",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "இலங்கை நெருக்கடி",
          "label": "LOC"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "இந்து",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்திய அரசு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "செவ்வாய்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "19",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்தியன்",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "எஸ். ஜெய்சங்கர்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்தியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்சவின்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "மாலத்தீவுகள்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "சிங்கப்பூர்",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்தியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஜெய்சங்கர்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்தியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்து",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஜெய்சங்கர்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்தியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்தியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்தியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "தெலுங்கானா ராஷ்டிர சமிதி",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Nama Nageshwara Rao",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "மையம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆர்பிஐ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "மையம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "மாநிலங்களில்",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ராவ்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "திராவிட முன்னேற்றக் கழகம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "தி.மு.க",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "திரிணாமுல் காங்கிரஸ்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "டி.எம்.சி",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜெய்சங்கர்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்தியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜெய்சங்கர்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ராஜபக்சேக்கள்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "கொழும்பு",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இந்தியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சுமார் $3.8 பில்லியன்",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜனவரி 2022",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜெய்சங்கர்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்தியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "$400 மில்லியன்",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "$1.5 பில்லியனுக்கும் அதிகமாக",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "கடன் வரிகள்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "$1.55 பில்லியன்",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "மத்திய",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "தமிழ்நாடு அரசு",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "புதன்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஜெய்சங்கர்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இந்தியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "எஸ் ஜெய்சங்கர்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "செவ்வாய்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "19",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "என்டிடிவி",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஏழு தசாப்தங்கள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "134",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}