{
  "newspaper_id": "lankadeepa-lk",
  "url": "https://www.lankadeepa.lk/world_news/ලීස්-ට්‍රස්-මහා-බ්‍රිතාන්‍ය-අගමැති-පුටුවට/14-619346",
  "time_ut": 1662380580,
  "original_lang": "si",
  "original_title": "ලීස් ට්‍රස් මහා බ්‍රිතාන්‍ය අගමැති පුටුවට",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Lees Truss to the Chair of Prime Minister of Great Britain",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "British Foreign Minister Liz Truss won the new Prime Minister post.",
        "She got 81,326 votes from Tory members, while Rishi Sunak got almost 60,399.",
        "Accordingly, 47-year-old Liz Truss became the prime minister after she became the party leader.",
        "The Prime Minister of Britain is held by the leader of the ruling party. Currently, the ruling party is the Conservative Party.",
        "The race for the leadership of the Conservative Party was between Liz Truss and Di Rishi Sunak.",
        "Rishi Sunak is the former Chancellor of the Exchequer. Rishi Sunak is of Indian origin. If he were to become British Prime Minister, Sunak would be the first Briton of Indian origin to hold the post.",
        "The party leader is elected by the party's internal vote. The poll was conducted among Conservative Party representatives, party activists and party members and the results were announced today.",
        "Accordingly, if Liz Truss wins the party leadership and becomes the Prime Minister, Liz Truss will be the third woman to become British Prime Minister after Theresa May and Margaret Thatcher."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Lees Truss",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "Great Britain",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "British",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Liz Truss",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "81,326",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Tory",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Rishi Sunak",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "almost 60,399",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "47-year-old",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Liz Truss",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Britain",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Conservative Party",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the Conservative Party",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Liz Truss",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Di Rishi Sunak",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Rishi Sunak",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Exchequer",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Rishi Sunak",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Indian",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "British",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "first",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Briton of Indian",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Conservative Party",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Liz Truss",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Liz Truss",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "third",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "British",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Theresa May",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Margaret Thatcher",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "ලීස් ට්‍රස් මහා බ්‍රිතාන්‍ය අගමැති පුටුවට",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "මහා බි‍්‍රතාන්‍යයේ නව අග‍්‍රාමාත්‍ය ධුරය එරට විදෙස් ඇමැතිනී ලිස් ට‍්‍රස් දිනා ගත්තාය.",
        "ඇයට ටෝරි සාමාජිකයන් 81326 දෙනකුගේ ඡන්දය ලබා ගත් අතර රිෂී සුනාක් හිමි වූයේ 60,399කට ආසන්න ගණනකි.",
        "ඒ අනුව 47 හැවිරිදි ලිස් ට‍්‍රස් ට අග‍්‍රාමාත්‍ය ධුරය හිමිවූයේ ඇයට පක්ෂ නායකත්වය හිමිවීමෙන් අනතුරුවය.",
        "බි‍්‍රතාන්‍යයේ අග‍්‍රාමාත්‍ය ධුරය හිමිවන්නේ, පාලක පක්ෂයේ නායකයාටය. වර්තමානයේ පාලක පක්ෂය ලෙස කටයුතු කරන්නේ කොන්සවර්ටිව් පක්ෂයයි.",
        "කොන්සවර්ටිව් පක්ෂ නායකත්වය සඳහා තරගය පැවැතියේ ලිස් ට‍්‍රස් සහ දි රිෂී සුනාක් අතරේය.",
        "රිෂී සුනාක් බි‍්‍රතාන්‍යයේ හිටපු මුදල් අමාත්‍යවරයා (චාන්සලර්)යි. රිෂී සුනාක් ඉන්දීය සම්භවයක් ඇත්තෙකි. ඔහුට බි‍්‍රතාන්‍ය අග‍්‍රාමාත්‍ය ධුරය හිමිවූයේ නම්, එම ධුරයට පත් වූ පළමු ඉන්දීය සම්භවයක් ඇති බි‍්‍රතාන්‍ය ජාතිකයා සුනාක් වනු ඇත.",
        "පක්ෂ නායකයා තෝරා ගැනීම සිදුවන්නේ පක්ෂ අභ්‍යන්තරයේ ඡන්දයෙනි. කොන්සවර්ටිව් පක්ෂ නියෝජිතයන්, පක්ෂ ක‍්‍රියාකාරීන් සහ පක්ෂ සාමාජිකයන් අතරේ ඡන්ද විමසුම පැවැත්වුණු අතර එහි ප‍්‍රතිඵල අද ප‍්‍රකාශයට පත් කෙරුණි.",
        "ඒ අනුව, ලිස් ට‍්‍රස් පක්ෂ නායකත්වය හිමිවී, අග‍්‍රාමාත්‍ය ධුරයට පත්වුවහොත්, තරේසා මේ සහ මාග‍්‍රට් තැචර්ගෙන් පසු බි‍්‍රතාන්‍ය අග‍්‍රාමාත්‍ය ධුරයට පත්වන තෙවැනි කාන්තාව ලිස් ට‍්‍රස්ය ."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ලීස් ට්‍රස්",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "මහා බ්‍රිතාන්‍යය",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "බ්රිතාන්ය",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ලිස් ට්‍රස්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "81,326 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ටෝරි",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "රිෂි සුනක්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ආසන්න වශයෙන් 60,399",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "47 හැවිරිදිය",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ලිස් ට්‍රස්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "බ්රිතාන්යය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "කොන්සර්වේටිව් පක්ෂය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "කොන්සර්වේටිව් පක්ෂය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ලිස් ට්‍රස්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "දි රිෂි සුනක්",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "රිෂි සුනක්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "භාණ්ඩාගාරය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "රිෂි සුනක්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දීය",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "බ්රිතාන්ය",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "පළමුවන",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දියානු බ්‍රිතාන්‍ය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "කොන්සර්වේටිව් පක්ෂය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ලිස් ට්‍රස්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ලිස් ට්‍රස්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "තෙවන",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "බ්රිතාන්ය",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "තෙරේසා මේ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "මාග්රට් තැචර්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "கிரேட் பிரிட்டனின் பிரதமர் தலைவராக லீஸ் டிரஸ்",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "பிரித்தானிய வெளியுறவு அமைச்சர் லிஸ் ட்ரஸ் புதிய பிரதமர் பதவியை வென்றார்.",
        "அவர் டோரி உறுப்பினர்களிடமிருந்து 81,326 வாக்குகளைப் பெற்றார், அதே நேரத்தில் ரிஷி சுனக் கிட்டத்தட்ட 60,399 வாக்குகளைப் பெற்றார்.",
        "அதன்படி, 47 வயதான லிஸ் ட்ரஸ் கட்சித் தலைவரான பிறகு பிரதமரானார்.",
        "பிரிட்டன் பிரதமர் ஆளும் கட்சியின் தலைவரால் நடத்தப்படுகிறார். தற்போது ஆளும் கட்சியாக கன்சர்வேட்டிவ் கட்சி உள்ளது.",
        "கன்சர்வேடிவ் கட்சியின் தலைமைப் பதவிக்கான போட்டி லிஸ் டிரஸ் மற்றும் டி ரிஷி சுனக் இடையே இருந்தது.",
        "ரிஷி சுனக் கருவூலத்தின் முன்னாள் அதிபர் ஆவார். ரிஷி சுனக் இந்திய வம்சாவளியைச் சேர்ந்தவர். அவர் பிரிட்டிஷ் பிரதமரானால், அந்தப் பதவியை வகிக்கும் முதல் இந்திய வம்சாவளியைச் சேர்ந்த பிரிட்டன் சுனக் ஆவார்.",
        "கட்சியின் உள் வாக்கு மூலம் கட்சியின் தலைவர் தேர்ந்தெடுக்கப்படுகிறார். கன்சர்வேட்டிவ் கட்சி பிரதிநிதிகள், கட்சி ஆர்வலர்கள் மற்றும் கட்சி உறுப்பினர்கள் மத்தியில் கருத்துக்கணிப்பு நடத்தப்பட்டு முடிவுகள் இன்று அறிவிக்கப்பட்டன.",
        "அதன்படி, லிஸ் ட்ரஸ் கட்சித் தலைமைப் பதவியை வென்று பிரதமரானால், தெரசா மே மற்றும் மார்கரெட் தாட்சருக்குப் பிறகு பிரிட்டன் பிரதமராகும் மூன்றாவது பெண் லிஸ் ட்ரஸ் ஆவார்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "லீஸ் டிரஸ்",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "இங்கிலாந்து",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "பிரிட்டிஷ்",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "லிஸ் டிரஸ்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "81,326",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "டோரி",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரிஷி சுனக்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "கிட்டத்தட்ட 60,399",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "47 வயது",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "லிஸ் டிரஸ்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பிரிட்டன்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "கன்சர்வேடிவ் கட்சி",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "கன்சர்வேடிவ் கட்சி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "லிஸ் டிரஸ்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "தி ரிஷி சுனக்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ரிஷி சுனக்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "கருவூலம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரிஷி சுனக்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்தியன்",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "பிரிட்டிஷ்",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "முதலில்",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்தியன் பிரிட்டன்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "கன்சர்வேடிவ் கட்சி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "லிஸ் டிரஸ்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "லிஸ் டிரஸ்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "மூன்றாவது",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "பிரிட்டிஷ்",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "தெரசா மே",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "மார்கரெட் தாட்சர்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}