{
  "newspaper_id": "daily-mirror-lk",
  "url": "https://www.dailymirror.lk/breaking_news/India-should-allow-star-players-to-take-part-in-T20-leagues-overseas-Aravinda/108-240476",
  "time_ut": 1657118640,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "India should allow star players to take part in T20 leagues overseas: Aravinda",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "India should allow star players to take part in T20 leagues overseas: Aravinda",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "Former Sri Lanka captain Aravinda de Silva acknowledged that the IPL and other T20 leagues have benefited cricket, but urged India to allow star players to take part in tournaments overseas.",
        "The Indian Premier League has grown into cricket's hottest property attracting top foreign talent such as England's Jos Buttler and Australia's David Warner for millions of dollars to play in the high-octane two-month jamboree.",
        "Aravinda, known for aggressive batting during an illustrious career that included a 1996 World Cup triumph, likened the current T20 leagues to English domestic cricket in the latter part of the last century, which attracted top players from all around the world to learn their craft and gain experience.",
        "\"It's like the county cricket of those days which gave the English cricketers the advantage,\" the 56-year-old, who played for English county Kent in the 1990s, told AFP.",
        "\"The IPL, Big Bash or in England the Hundred and T20 Blitz, those are tournaments which allow players to develop.\"",
        "The Indian Premier League started in 2008 and has spawned copycat tournaments around the world.",
        "But it remains the biggest draw with a recent media rights auction valuing the IPL at a whopping $6.2 billion, or $15 million per match, making it bigger in those terms than football's English Premier League which is valued at $11 million per match.",
        "Aravinda said India should enable smaller nations to share in the riches generated to grow the game, raise global playing standards and improve skill levels, something that would ultimately benefit the IPL.",
        "\"If you have one dominating country, you can see from the IPL, they basically run a monopoly on the premier leagues because the Indian cricketers are not allowed to play in other leagues,\" Aravinda said.",
        "\"So what will probably happen is that the standard -- if it keeps dropping and if there is no real competition -- at some point it's going to affect the global game.",
        "\"Unless (India) find a way to support the other countries and get them up to grips with the kind of support levels which the game requires nowadays, it's a negative for the cricket world.",
        "\"It's the (world governing body) ICC's responsibility to make sure that it's done in a manner where these countries keep developing, otherwise we don't want a situation like Zimbabwe and South Africa, how they dipped from their standard of cricket.\"",
        "Sri Lankan players have individually reaped rewards from the IPL. Leg-spinner Wanindu Hasaranga was bought by Royal Challengers Bangalore for $1.42 million and was the second-highest wicket taker in this year's 10-team tournament.",
        "Sri Lanka's version, the LPL, was last played in 2021, with five teams captained by Sri Lanka stars including Angelo Mathews and Niroshan Dickwella and Aravinda also praised Pakistan for putting up a great show with the Pakistan Super League despite a lack of publicity and resources.",
        "Sri Lanka are currently 1-0 down to Australia in a two-match series but Aravinda was confident the hosts can fight back in the second Test beginning on Friday in Galle.",
        "And he was grateful to Australia for touring the island nation for a five-match one-day international series and two Tests, bringing some joy to Sri Lankan people who are suffering from an unprecedented economic crisis.",
        "\"We definitely saw the passion even with all these issues, we had some full houses during the one-day series,\" said Aravinda.",
        "\"(I am) thankful to the Australians who decided to come and bring some smiles to the Sri Lankan people. It was amazing. My heartfelt gratitude goes to them.(AFP)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "India",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "Aravinda",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Aravinda de Silva",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "India",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Indian",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "League",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "England",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Jos Buttler",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Australia",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "David Warner",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "millions of dollars",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "two-month",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Aravinda",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "1996",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "World Cup",
            "label": "EVENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "English",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "the last century",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "those days",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "English",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "56-year-old",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "English",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "the 1990s",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "AFP",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "England",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Blitz",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Indian",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "2008",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "$6.2 billion",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "$15 million",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "English",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "League",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "$11 million",
            "label": "MONEY"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Aravinda",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "India",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Indian",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Aravinda",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "India",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ICC",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Zimbabwe",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "South Africa",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lankan",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Wanindu Hasaranga",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Royal Challengers Bangalore",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "$1.42 million",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "second",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "year",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "10",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka's",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "LPL",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "2021",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "five",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Angelo Mathews",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Niroshan Dickwella",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Aravinda",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Pakistan",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Pakistan Super League",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "1",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Australia",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "two",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Aravinda",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "second",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Friday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Galle",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Australia",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "five",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "one-day",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "two",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lankan",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "one-day",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Aravinda",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Australians",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lankan",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "ඉන්දියාව තරු ක්‍රීඩකයන්ට විදෙස් විස්සයි20 ලීගවලට සහභාගි වීමට ඉඩ දිය යුතුයි: අරවින්ද",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "හිටපු ශ්‍රී ලංකා නායක අරවින්ද ද සිල්වා IPL සහ අනෙකුත් T20 ලීග් ක්‍රිකට් ක්‍රීඩාවට ප්‍රතිලාභ ලබා දී ඇති බව පිළිගත් නමුත් තරු ක්‍රීඩකයින්ට විදේශීය තරඟාවලි සඳහා සහභාගී වීමට ඉඩ දෙන ලෙස ඉන්දියාවෙන් ඉල්ලා සිටියේය.",
        "ඉන්දියන් ප්‍රිමියර් ලීගය ක්‍රිකට් ක්‍රීඩාවේ උණුසුම්ම දේපල බවට වර්ධනය වී ඇති අතර එංගලන්තයේ ජොස් බට්ලර් සහ ඕස්ට්‍රේලියාවේ ඩේවිඩ් වෝනර් වැනි ඉහළම විදේශීය දක්ෂයින් ඩොලර් මිලියන ගණනින් ඉහළ ඔක්ටේන් දෙකේ ජම්බෝරියේ ක්‍රීඩා කිරීමට ආකර්ෂණය කර ඇත.",
        "1996 ලෝක කුසලාන ජයග්‍රහණයක් ඇතුළත් කීර්තිමත් වෘත්තීය ජීවිතයක් තුළ ආක්‍රමණශීලී පිතිකරණයට ප්‍රසිද්ධ අරවින්ද, වත්මන් විස්සයි20 ලීග් පසුගිය ශතවර්ෂයේ අග භාගයේ ඉංග්‍රීසි දේශීය ක්‍රිකට් වලට සමාන කළේය, එය ලොව පුරා සිටින ප්‍රමුඛ ක්‍රීඩකයින් ඔවුන්ගේ ශිල්ප ඉගෙන ගැනීමට ආකර්ෂණය කර ගත්තේය. අත්දැකීම් ලබාගන්න.",
        "\"එය හරියට ඉංග්‍රීසි ක්‍රිකට් ක්‍රීඩකයින්ට වාසිය ලබා දුන් ඒ දවස්වල ප්‍රාන්ත ක්‍රිකට් වැනිය,\" 1990 දශකයේ එංගලන්ත ප්‍රාන්ත කෙන්ට් වෙනුවෙන් ක්‍රීඩා කළ 56 හැවිරිදි ඔහු AFP වෙත පැවසීය.",
        "\"අයිපීඑල්, ​​බිග් බෑෂ් හෝ එංගලන්තයේ සියය සහ විස්සයි20 බ්ලිට්ස්, ඒවා ක්‍රීඩකයින්ට දියුණු වීමට ඉඩ සලසන තරඟාවලි වේ.\"",
        "ඉන්දීය ප්‍රිමියර් ලීගය 2008 දී ආරම්භ වූ අතර ලොව පුරා කොපිකැට් තරඟාවලි බිහි කර ඇත.",
        "නමුත් එය IPL ඩොලර් බිලියන 6.2 ක් හෝ එක් තරගයකට ඩොලර් මිලියන 15 ක් වැනි විශාල මිලකට මෑත කාලීන මාධ්‍ය හිමිකම් වෙන්දේසියක් සමඟින් සිදු වූ විශාලතම දිනුම් ඇදීම ලෙස පවතී, එය එක් තරගයකට ඩොලර් මිලියන 11 ක් වන පාපන්දු ඉංග්‍රීසි ප්‍රිමියර් ලීගයට වඩා විශාල වේ.",
        "ක්‍රීඩාව වර්ධනය කිරීමට, ගෝලීය ක්‍රීඩා ප්‍රමිතීන් ඉහළ නැංවීමට සහ කුසලතා මට්ටම් වැඩිදියුණු කිරීමට උත්පාදනය කරන ධනයෙන් කුඩා ජාතීන්ට බෙදා ගැනීමට ඉන්දියාව හැකි විය යුතු බව අරවින්ද පැවසීය, එය අවසානයේ IPL සඳහා ප්‍රතිලාභ ලබා දෙනු ඇත.",
        "\"ඔබට එක ආධිපත්‍යය දරන රටක් තිබේ නම්, ඔබට IPL වෙතින් දැක ගත හැකිය, ඔවුන් මූලික වශයෙන් ප්‍රිමියර් ලීගවල ඒකාධිකාරයක් පවත්වාගෙන යනු ලබන්නේ ඉන්දීය ක්‍රිකට් ක්‍රීඩකයින්ට වෙනත් ලීගවලට ක්‍රීඩා කිරීමට ඉඩ නොදෙන බැවිනි,\" අරවින්ද පැවසීය.",
        "“එබැවින් බොහෝ විට සිදුවනු ඇත්තේ සම්මතය - එය දිගටම පහත වැටෙන්නේ නම් සහ සැබෑ තරඟයක් නොමැති නම් - යම් අවස්ථාවක දී එය ගෝලීය ක්‍රීඩාවට බලපානු ඇත.",
        "“(ඉන්දියාව) අනෙකුත් රටවලට සහාය වීමට ක්‍රමයක් සොයා නොගන්නේ නම් සහ වර්තමානයේ ක්‍රීඩාවට අවශ්‍ය ආකාරයේ ආධාරක මට්ටම් සමඟ ඔවුන් ග්‍රහණය කර නොගන්නේ නම්, එය ක්‍රිකට් ලෝකයට අහිතකර ය.",
        "\"මෙම රටවල් සංවර්ධනය වෙමින් පවතින ආකාරයට එය සිදු කිරීමට වග බලා ගැනීම (ලෝක පාලක මණ්ඩලයේ) ICC හි වගකීමයි, එසේ නොමැතිනම් සිම්බාබ්වේ සහ දකුණු අප්‍රිකාව වැනි තත්වයක් අපට අවශ්‍ය නැත, ඔවුන් ඔවුන්ගේ ක්‍රිකට් මට්ටමෙන් ගිලී ගිය ආකාරය.\"",
        "IPL තරඟාවලියෙන් ශ්‍රී ලංකා ක්‍රීඩකයින් තනි තනිව ත්‍යාග ලබාගෙන තිබෙනවා. පා දඟ පන්දු යවන වනිඳු හසරංග රෝයල් චැලෙන්ජර්ස් බැංගලෝර් කණ්ඩායම විසින් ඩොලර් මිලියන 1.42කට මිලදී ගත් අතර කණ්ඩායම් 10කින් සමන්විත මෙවර තරගාවලියේ දෙවැනි වැඩිම කඩුලු ලාභියා විය.",
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකා අනුවාදය වන LPL අවසන් වරට 2021 දී ක්‍රීඩා කරන ලද අතර ඇන්ජලෝ මැතිව්ස් ඇතුළු ශ්‍රී ලංකා ක්‍රීඩකයින් ඇතුළු කණ්ඩායම් පහක් නායකත්වය දුන් අතර නිරෝෂන් දික්වැල්ල සහ අරවින්ද ද ප්‍රචාරණ සහ සම්පත් හිඟයක් තිබියදීත් පාකිස්තාන සුපර් ලීග් සමඟ විශිෂ්ට දස්කම් දැක්වීම ගැන පාකිස්තානයට ප්‍රශංසා කළහ. .",
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකාව මේ වන විට ඔස්ට්‍රේලියාවට එරෙහිව තරග දෙකකින් සමන්විත තරගාවලිය 1-0ක් ලෙසින් පහතින් සිටින නමුත් සිකුරාදා ගාල්ලේදී ආරම්භ වන දෙවැනි ටෙස්ට් තරගයේදී සත්කාරක කණ්ඩායමට ප්‍රතිප්‍රහාර එල්ල කළ හැකි බව අරවින්ද විශ්වාස කළේය.",
        "පෙර නොවූ විරූ ආර්ථික අර්බුදයකින් පෙළෙන ශ්‍රී ලාංකික ජනතාවට යම් සතුටක් ගෙන දෙමින් තරග පහකින් සමන්විත එක්දින ජාත්‍යන්තර තරගාවලියක් සහ ටෙස්ට් තරග දෙකක් සඳහා දිවයිනේ සංචාරය කිරීම පිළිබඳව ඔස්ට්‍රේලියාවට කෘතඥතාව පළ කළේය.",
        "“මේ සියලු ප්‍රශ්න සමඟ පවා අපි ආශාව නිසැකවම දුටුවෙමු, එක්දින තරඟාවලියේදී අපට සම්පූර්ණ නිවාස කිහිපයක් තිබුණා,” අරවින්ද පැවසීය.",
        "\"(මම) පැමිණ ශ්‍රී ලාංකික ජනතාවට සිනහවක් ගෙන ඒමට තීරණය කළ ඕස්ට්‍රේලියානුවන්ට ස්තූතිවන්ත වෙමි. එය පුදුම සහගතයි. ඔවුන්ට මගේ හෘදයාංගම ස්තුතිය පුද කරනවා.(AFP)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ඉන්දියාව",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "අරවින්ද",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "අරවින්ද ද සිල්වා",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දීය",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ලීගය",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "එංගලන්තය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජොස් බට්ලර්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඕස්ට්රේලියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඩේවිඩ් වෝනර්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඩොලර් මිලියන ගණනක්",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "මාස දෙකක",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "අරවින්ද",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "1996",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ලෝක කුසලානය",
            "label": "EVENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉංග්රීසි",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "පසුගිය සියවස",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ඒ දවස්වල",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉංග්රීසි",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "56 හැවිරිදිය",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉංග්රීසි",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "1990 ගණන්වල",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "AFP",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "එංගලන්තය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "බ්ලිට්ස්",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දීය",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "2008",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ඩොලර් බිලියන 6.2 කි",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඩොලර් මිලියන 15 කි",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉංග්රීසි",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ලීගය",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඩොලර් මිලියන 11 කි",
            "label": "MONEY"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "අරවින්ද",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දීය",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "අරවින්ද",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "අයි.සී.සී",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "සිම්බාබ්වේ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "දකුණු අප්රිකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලාංකික",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "වනිඳු හසරංග",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "රෝයල් චැලෙන්ජර්ස් බැංගලෝර්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඩොලර් මිලියන 1.42 කි",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "දෙවැනි",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "වර්ෂය",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "10",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "LPL",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "2021",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "පහ",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඇන්ජලෝ මැතිව්ස්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "නිරෝෂන් දික්වැල්ල",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "අරවින්ද",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "පකිස්ථානය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාකිස්තාන සුපර් ලීගය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "1",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඕස්ට්රේලියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "දෙක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "අරවින්ද",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "දෙවැනි",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "සිකුරාදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගාල්ල",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ඕස්ට්රේලියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "පහ",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "එක දවසක්",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "දෙක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලාංකික",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "එක දවසක්",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "අරවින්ද",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ඕස්ට්රේලියානුවන්",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලාංකික",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "வெளிநாடுகளில் நடைபெறும் டி20 லீக்கில் நட்சத்திர வீரர்களை பங்கேற்க இந்தியா அனுமதிக்க வேண்டும்: அரவிந்தா",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "இலங்கையின் முன்னாள் கேப்டன் அரவிந்த டி சில்வா, ஐபிஎல் மற்றும் பிற டி20 லீக்குகள் கிரிக்கெட்டுக்கு பலனளித்தன என்பதை ஒப்புக்கொண்டார், ஆனால் நட்சத்திர வீரர்களை வெளிநாட்டு போட்டிகளில் பங்கேற்க அனுமதிக்குமாறு இந்தியாவை வலியுறுத்தினார்.",
        "இந்தியன் பிரீமியர் லீக், இங்கிலாந்தின் ஜோஸ் பட்லர் மற்றும் ஆஸ்திரேலியாவின் டேவிட் வார்னர் போன்ற சிறந்த வெளிநாட்டு திறமைகளை ஈர்க்கும் வகையில் கிரிக்கெட்டின் வெப்பமான சொத்தாக வளர்ந்துள்ளது.",
        "1996 உலகக் கோப்பை வெற்றியை உள்ளடக்கிய புகழ்பெற்ற வாழ்க்கையில் ஆக்ரோஷமான பேட்டிங்கிற்கு பெயர் பெற்ற அரவிந்தா, தற்போதைய டி20 லீக்குகளை கடந்த நூற்றாண்டின் பிற்பகுதியில் இங்கிலாந்து உள்நாட்டு கிரிக்கெட்டுடன் ஒப்பிட்டார், இது உலகெங்கிலும் உள்ள சிறந்த வீரர்களை தங்கள் கைவினைக் கற்றுக்கொள்வதற்காக ஈர்த்தது மற்றும் அனுபவம் பெற.",
        "1990 களில் இங்கிலாந்து கவுண்டி கென்ட் அணிக்காக விளையாடிய 56 வயதான 56 வயதான அவர், \"இது அந்த நாட்களில் உள்ள கவுண்டி கிரிக்கெட் போன்றது\" என்று கூறினார்.",
        "\"ஐபிஎல், பிக் பாஷ் அல்லது இங்கிலாந்தில் நடக்கும் சதம் மற்றும் டி20 பிளிட்ஸ், அவை வீரர்களை உருவாக்க அனுமதிக்கும் போட்டிகள்.\"",
        "இந்தியன் பிரீமியர் லீக் 2008 இல் தொடங்கியது மற்றும் உலகம் முழுவதும் காபிகேட் போட்டிகளை உருவாக்கியுள்ளது.",
        "ஆனால் ஒரு போட்டிக்கு $11 மில்லியன் மதிப்பிலான கால்பந்தின் இங்கிலீஷ் பிரீமியர் லீக்கை விட, ஐபிஎல்லின் மதிப்பு $6.2 பில்லியன் அல்லது $15 மில்லியன் என சமீபத்திய ஊடக உரிமை ஏலத்தில் இது மிகப்பெரிய டிராவாக உள்ளது.",
        "விளையாட்டை வளர்ப்பதற்கும், உலகளாவிய விளையாட்டுத் தரத்தை உயர்த்துவதற்கும், திறன் நிலைகளை மேம்படுத்துவதற்கும், இறுதியில் ஐபிஎல்-க்கு பயனளிக்கும் வகையில், சிறிய நாடுகளுக்குச் செல்வத்தைப் பகிர்ந்து கொள்ள இந்தியா உதவ வேண்டும் என்று அரவிந்தா கூறினார்.",
        "\"உங்களிடம் ஒரு ஆதிக்கம் செலுத்தும் நாடு இருந்தால், ஐபிஎல்லில் இருந்து நீங்கள் பார்க்க முடியும், அவர்கள் அடிப்படையில் பிரீமியர் லீக்குகளில் ஏகபோகத்தை நடத்துகிறார்கள், ஏனெனில் இந்திய கிரிக்கெட் வீரர்கள் மற்ற லீக்குகளில் விளையாட அனுமதிக்கப்படுவதில்லை,\" என்று அரவிந்தா கூறினார்.",
        "\"எனவே ஒருவேளை என்ன நடக்கும் என்றால், நிலையானது - அது தொடர்ந்து வீழ்ச்சியடைந்தால் மற்றும் உண்மையான போட்டி இல்லை என்றால் - ஒரு கட்டத்தில் அது உலகளாவிய விளையாட்டை பாதிக்கப் போகிறது.",
        "\"(இந்தியா) மற்ற நாடுகளை ஆதரிப்பதற்கான வழியைக் கண்டுபிடித்து, இப்போதெல்லாம் விளையாட்டிற்குத் தேவைப்படும் ஆதரவு நிலைகளுடன் அவர்களைப் பிடிக்காத வரை, அது கிரிக்கெட் உலகிற்கு எதிர்மறையானது.",
        "\"இந்த நாடுகள் தொடர்ந்து வளரும் விதத்தில் செய்யப்படுவதை உறுதி செய்வது (உலக ஆளும் குழு) ஐசிசியின் பொறுப்பாகும், இல்லையெனில் ஜிம்பாப்வே மற்றும் தென்னாப்பிரிக்கா போன்ற ஒரு சூழ்நிலையை நாங்கள் விரும்பவில்லை.",
        "ஐபிஎல்லில் இருந்து இலங்கை வீரர்கள் தனித்தனியாக வெகுமதிகளை அறுவடை செய்துள்ளனர். லெக்-ஸ்பின்னர் வனிந்து ஹசரங்க ராயல் சேலஞ்சர்ஸ் பெங்களூர் அணியால் 1.42 மில்லியன் டாலர்களுக்கு வாங்கப்பட்டார் மற்றும் இந்த ஆண்டு 10 அணிகள் பங்கேற்ற போட்டியில் இரண்டாவது அதிக விக்கெட் எடுத்தவர் ஆவார்.",
        "இலங்கையின் பதிப்பு, LPL, கடைசியாக 2021 இல் விளையாடப்பட்டது, இதில் ஏஞ்சலோ மேத்யூஸ் மற்றும் நிரோஷன் டிக்வெல்லா மற்றும் அரவிந்த உட்பட இலங்கை நட்சத்திரங்கள் தலைமையிலான ஐந்து அணிகள், விளம்பரம் மற்றும் ஆதாரங்கள் இல்லாத போதிலும் பாகிஸ்தான் சூப்பர் லீக்குடன் சிறந்த ஆட்டத்தை வெளிப்படுத்தியதற்காக பாகிஸ்தானைப் பாராட்டினர். .",
        "இரண்டு போட்டிகள் கொண்ட தொடரில் இலங்கை தற்போது 1-0 என ஆஸ்திரேலியாவுக்கு எதிராக உள்ளது, ஆனால் காலியில் வெள்ளிக்கிழமை தொடங்கும் இரண்டாவது டெஸ்டில் புரவலன்கள் மீண்டும் போராட முடியும் என்று அரவிந்த நம்பினார்.",
        "அவுஸ்திரேலியாவில் ஐந்து போட்டிகள் கொண்ட ஒரு நாள் சர்வதேச தொடர் மற்றும் இரண்டு டெஸ்ட் போட்டிகளுக்காக சுற்றுப்பயணம் மேற்கொண்டமைக்காக அவுஸ்திரேலியாவிற்கு அவர் நன்றி தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "\"இந்த எல்லா பிரச்சனைகளிலும் கூட நாங்கள் நிச்சயமாக ஆர்வத்தை பார்த்தோம், ஒரு நாள் தொடரின் போது எங்களுக்கு சில முழு வீடுகள் இருந்தன,\" என்று அரவிந்தா கூறினார்.",
        "\"(நான்) இலங்கை மக்களுக்குச் சில புன்னகைகளை வரவழைக்கத் தீர்மானித்த அவுஸ்திரேலியர்களுக்கு நன்றியைத் தெரிவித்துக் கொள்கிறேன். இது ஆச்சரியமாக இருந்தது. அவர்களுக்கு எனது மனமார்ந்த நன்றிகள் உரித்தாகுக.(AFP)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "இந்தியா",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "அரவிந்தா",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "அரவிந்த டி சில்வா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்தியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இந்தியன்",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "லீக்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இங்கிலாந்து",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜோஸ் பட்லர்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆஸ்திரேலியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "டேவிட் வார்னர்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "மில்லியன் டாலர்கள்",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "இரண்டு மாதங்கள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "அரவிந்தா",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "1996",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "உலகக் கோப்பை",
            "label": "EVENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆங்கிலம்",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "கடந்த நூற்றாண்டு",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "அந்த நாட்கள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆங்கிலம்",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "56 வயது",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆங்கிலம்",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "1990கள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "AFP",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இங்கிலாந்து",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "பிளிட்ஸ்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இந்தியன்",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "2008",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "$6.2 பில்லியன்",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "$15 மில்லியன்",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆங்கிலம்",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "லீக்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "$11 மில்லியன்",
            "label": "MONEY"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "அரவிந்தா",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்தியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இந்தியன்",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "அரவிந்தா",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "இந்தியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஐ.சி.சி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜிம்பாப்வே",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "தென்னாப்பிரிக்கா",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "வனிந்து ஹசரங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ராயல் சேலஞ்சர்ஸ் பெங்களூர்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "$1.42 மில்லியன்",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "இரண்டாவது",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆண்டு",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "10",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கையின்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "LPL",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "2021",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஐந்து",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஏஞ்சலோ மேத்யூஸ்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "நிரோஷன் டிக்வெல்ல",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "அரவிந்தா",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாகிஸ்தான்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாகிஸ்தான் சூப்பர் லீக்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "1",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆஸ்திரேலியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இரண்டு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "அரவிந்தா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இரண்டாவது",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "வெள்ளி",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "காலி",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஆஸ்திரேலியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஐந்து",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஒரு நாள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இரண்டு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஒரு நாள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "அரவிந்தா",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஆஸ்திரேலியர்கள்",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}