{
  "newspaper_id": "tamil-mirror-lk",
  "url": "https://www.tamilmirror.lk/செய்திகள்/இந்திய-மாநிலங்களவை-உறுப்பினரானார்-இளையராஜா/175-299878",
  "time_ut": 1657159613,
  "original_lang": "ta",
  "original_title": "இந்திய மாநிலங்களவை உறுப்பினரானார் இளையராஜா",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Ilayaraja became a member of Rajya Sabha of India",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "The President of India can appoint 12 MPs to the Rajya Sabha who excel in various fields including sports, social service, art and literature.",
        "Accordingly, along with music composer Ilayaraja, India's former athlete PT Usha, who excelled in the field of sports, and film scriptwriter Vijayendra Prasad from Andhra have been selected and appointed as MPs.",
        "Indian Prime Minister Narendra Modi has congratulated Ilayaraja, PT Usha, who has been elected as a member of the Rajya Sabha. (a)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Rajya Sabha",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "India",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "India",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "12",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Rajya Sabha",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Ilayaraja",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "India",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Usha",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Vijayendra Prasad",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Indian",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Narendra Modi",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ilayaraja",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Usha",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Rajya Sabha",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "ඉලයරාජා ඉන්දියාවේ රාජ්‍ය සභාවේ මන්ත්‍රීවරයෙකු බවට පත් විය",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "ක්‍රීඩාව, සමාජ සේවය, කලාව, සාහිත්‍යය ඇතුළු විවිධ ක්ෂේත්‍රවල දස්කම් දක්වන මන්ත්‍රීවරුන් 12 දෙනෙකු ඉන්දීය ජනාධිපතිවරයාට රාජ්‍ය සභාවට පත් කළ හැකියි.",
        "ඒ අනුව සංගීත නිර්මාපකයෙකු වන ඉලයරාජා සමඟින් ක්‍රීඩා ක්ෂේත්‍රයේ දස්කම් දැක්වූ ඉන්දියාවේ හිටපු මලල ක්‍රීඩිකා පී.ටී.උෂා සහ චිත්‍රපට පිටපත් රචක විජයේන්ද්‍ර ප්‍රසාද් ආන්ද්‍රා ප්‍රදේශයෙන් තෝරාගෙන මන්ත්‍රීවරුන් ලෙස පත් කර තිබෙනවා.",
        "ඉන්දීය අග්‍රාමාත්‍ය නරේන්ද්‍ර මෝදි රාජ්‍ය සභා මන්ත්‍රීවරයෙකු ලෙස තේරී පත් වූ ඉලයරාජා, පී.ටී.උෂාට සුබ පැතුම් එක්කර තිබෙනවා. (ඒ)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "රාජ්ය සභාව",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "ඉන්දියාව",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "12",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "රාජ්ය සභාව",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ඉලයරාජා",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඌෂා",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "විජයේන්ද්‍ර ප්‍රසාද්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දීය",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "නරේන්ද්‍ර මෝදි",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉලයරාජා",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඌෂා",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "රාජ්ය සභාව",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "இந்திய மாநிலங்களவை உறுப்பினரானார் இளையராஜா",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "விளையாட்டு, சமூக சேவை,கலை, இலக்கியம் உள்ளிட்ட பல்வேறு துறைகளில் சிறந்து விளங்குபவர்களை மாநிலங்களவைக்கு 12 பேரை நியமன எம்.பி.க்களாக இந்திய ஜனாதிபதி நியமிக்கலாம்.",
        "அதன்படி, இசையமைப்பாளர் இளையராஜாவுடன், விளையாட்டுத்துறையில் சிறந்து விளங்கிய இந்தியாவின் முன்னாள் தடகள வீராங்கனை பி.டி.உஷா, ஆந்திராவை சேர்ந்த திரைப்பட கதாசிரியர் விஜயேந்திர பிரசாத் ஆகியோர் தேர்வு செய்யப்பட்டு எம்.பி.யாக நியமிக்கப்பட்டுள்ளனர்.",
        "மாநிலங்களவை உறுப்பினராக தேர்வு செய்யப்பட்டுள்ள இளையராஜா, பி.டி.உஷாவிற்கு இந்திய பிரதமர் நரேந்திர மோடி வாழ்த்து தெரிவித்துள்ளார். (a)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ராஜ்யசபா",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "இந்தியா",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "இந்தியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "12",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ராஜ்யசபா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இளையராஜா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்தியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "உஷா",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "விஜயேந்திர பிரசாத்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இந்தியன்",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "நரேந்திர மோடி",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இளையராஜா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "உஷா",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ராஜ்யசபா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}