{
  "newspaper_id": "news-first-lk",
  "url": "https://www.newsfirst.lk/2022/09/03/conspiracy-against-cbsl-governor-sajith-questions-ulterior-motives/",
  "time_ut": 1662215940,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Conspiracy against CBSL Governor: Sajith questions ulterior motives",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Conspiracy against CBSL Governor: Sajith questions ulterior motives",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); Opposition Leader Sajith Premadasa demanded whether the 'conspiracy' against the current CBSL Governor is a move to reinstate the former Governor Ajith Nivard Cabraal, who fled the country.",
        "Participating at a Constituency Committee meeting in Akmeemana, Galle, the Opposition Leader alleged that there is a conspiracy to remove Dr. Nandalal Weerasinghe, who was retired and living in Australia initially, when the Government invited him to take up the Governor position of the Central Bank.",
        "Stating that the relevant conspiracy started on Wednesday, the Opposition Leader said that an MP who entered Parliament through the SLPP and is now a supporter of the UNP continued inquiring from Dr. Nandalal Weerasinghe whether he is a dual citizen.",
        "\"He is not a dual citizen. What are they trying to do? They are trying to spread gossip about him hoping to chase him away from his post so that they can appoint one of their close associates to that position,\" he alleged.",
        "\"Is the duel citizen who fled the country trying to the re-appoint the Governor who robbed the Central Bank? Is that why attempts are afoot to remove Nandalal Weerasinghe?\" demanded the Opposition Leader.",
        "Premadasa further said that the first move to remove Dr. Weerasinghe was made at the meeting between the Governor of the Central Bank and the Parliamentarians, as the very next day, speaking in Parliament for 20 minutes, an MP from Galle indirectly created a backdrop to remove the Governor from his position.",
        "Pointing out that the country has become bankrupt along with 22 million people, the Opposition Leader added, the Government is attempting to play games giving prominence to close associates.",
        "Electricity, petroleum production, fuel supply, and health, declared as essential services.- PMD"
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "News 1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sajith Premadasa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ajith Nivard Cabraal",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Constituency Committee",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Akmeemana",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Galle",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Nandalal Weerasinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Australia",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Central Bank",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Wednesday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "UNP",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Nandalal Weerasinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "the Central Bank",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Nandalal Weerasinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "first",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Weerasinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Central Bank",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliamentarians",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "next day",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "20 minutes",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "Galle",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "22 million",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        []
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "මහ බැංකු අධිපතිට එරෙහි කුමන්ත්‍රණයක්: සජිත් යටි අරමුණු ගැන ප්‍රශ්න කරයි",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); වත්මන් මහ බැංකු අධිපතිවරයාට එරෙහි කුමන්ත්‍රණය රටින් පැන ගිය හිටපු ආණ්ඩුකාර අජිත් නිවාඩ් කබ්රාල් යළි සේවයේ පිහිටුවීමේ ක්‍රියාමාර්ගයක් දැයි විපක්ෂ නායක සජිත් ප්‍රේමදාස මහතා ඉල්ලා සිටියේය.",
        "ගාල්ල, අක්මීමන ප්‍රදේශයේ පැවති මැතිවරණ කොට්ඨාස කමිටු රැස්වීමකට එක්වෙමින් විපක්ෂ නායකවරයා චෝදනා කළේ විශ්‍රාම ගොස් ඕස්ට්‍රේලියාවේ මුලින් පදිංචිව සිටි වෛද්‍ය නන්දලාල් වීරසිංහට මධ්‍යම ආණ්ඩුකාර ධුරයේ වැඩ භාර ගන්නා ලෙස රජය ආරාධනා කළ අවස්ථාවේදී ඔහු ඉවත් කිරීමේ කුමන්ත්‍රණයක් පවතින බවයි. බැංකුව.",
        "අදාළ කුමන්ත්‍රණය බදාදා ආරම්භ වූ බව සඳහන් කළ විපක්ෂ නායකවරයා කියා සිටියේ ශ්‍රී ලංකා පොදුජන පෙරමුණ හරහා පාර්ලිමේන්තුවට පැමිණ මේ වනවිට එක්සත් ජාතික පක්ෂයේ ආධාරකරුවෙකු වන මන්ත්‍රීවරයෙකු ද්විත්ව පුරවැසියෙකුද යන්න වෛද්‍ය නන්දලාල් වීරසිංහගෙන් දිගින් දිගටම විමසා සිටි බවයි.",
        "\"ඔහු ද්විත්ව පුරවැසියෙක් නෙවෙයි. මොකද මේ කරන්න හදන්නේ. තමන්ගෙ සමීපතමයෙක්ව ඒ තනතුරට පත් කරන්න පුළුවන් විදියට ඔහුව තනතුරෙන් එළවන්න බලාපොරොත්තුවෙන් තමයි මෙයා ගැන ඕපාදූප පතුරුවන්න හදන්නේ,\" ඔහු චෝදනා කළේය.",
        "\"රට පැන්න ද්වන්ද පුරවැසියා හදන්නේ මහබැංකුව කොල්ල කාපු අධිපතිව ආපහු පත්කරන්නද? නන්දලාල් වීරසිංහ අයින් කරන්න හදන්නේ ඒ නිසාද?\" විපක්ෂ නායකවරයාගෙන් ඉල්ලා සිටියේය.",
        "මහ බැංකු අධිපතිවරයා සහ පාර්ලිමේන්තු මන්ත්‍රීවරුන් අතර පැවැති සාකච්ඡාවේදී ආචාර්ය වීරසිංහ මහතා ඉවත් කිරීමේ පළමු පියවර ගත් බවත් ඊට පසුදිනම විනාඩි 20ක් පාර්ලිමේන්තුවේ කතා කළ ගාල්ලේ මන්ත්‍රීවරයකු ඊට වක්‍ර පසුබිමක් නිර්මාණය කළ බවත් ප්‍රේමදාස වැඩිදුරටත් පැවසීය. ආණ්ඩුකාරවරයා ඔහුගේ තනතුරෙන් ඉවත් කරන්න.",
        "මිලියන 22 ක ජනතාවක් සමඟ රට බංකොලොත් වී ඇති බව පෙන්වා දුන් විපක්ෂ නායකවරයා, රජය සමීප හිතවතුන්ට ප්‍රමුඛත්වය දෙමින් සෙල්ලම් කිරීමට උත්සාහ කරන බව ද පැවසීය.",
        "විදුලිය, ඛනිජ තෙල් නිෂ්පාදනය, ඉන්ධන සැපයීම සහ සෞඛ්‍යය අත්‍යවශ්‍ය සේවා ලෙස ප්‍රකාශයට පත් කර ඇත.- PMD"
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "News 1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "සජිත් ප්‍රේමදාස",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "අජිත් නිවාඩ් කබ්රාල්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ආසන කාරක සභාව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "අක්මීමන",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගාල්ල",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "නන්දලාල් වීරසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඕස්ට්රේලියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මහ බැංකුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "බදාදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "එජාප",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "නන්දලාල් වීරසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "මහ බැංකුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "නන්දලාල් වීරසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "පළමුවන",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "වීරසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "මහ බැංකුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තු මන්ත්‍රීවරු",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඊළඟ දවසේ",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "විනාඩි 20",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගාල්ල",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "මිලියන 22 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        []
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "CBSL ஆளுநருக்கு எதிரான சதி: சஜித் உள்நோக்கம் குறித்து கேள்வி",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); தற்போதைய CBSL ஆளுநருக்கு எதிரான 'சதி' நாட்டை விட்டு வெளியேறிய முன்னாள் ஆளுநர் அஜித் நிவாட் கப்ராலை மீண்டும் பதவியில் அமர்த்துவதற்கான நடவடிக்கையா என எதிர்க்கட்சித் தலைவர் சஜித் பிரேமதாச கோரியுள்ளார்.",
        "காலி அக்மீமன பிரதேச சபைக் கூட்டத்தில் கலந்து கொண்ட எதிர்க்கட்சித் தலைவர், ஓய்வுபெற்று ஆரம்பத்தில் அவுஸ்திரேலியாவில் வசித்து வந்த கலாநிதி நந்தலால் வீரசிங்கவை அரசாங்கம் மத்திய ஆளுநராகப் பதவியேற்குமாறு அழைப்பு விடுத்த போது அவரை பதவி நீக்கம் சதி நடப்பதாக குற்றம் சுமத்தினார். வங்கி.",
        "இது தொடர்பான சதி புதன்கிழமை ஆரம்பமாகியுள்ளதாக தெரிவித்த எதிர்க்கட்சித் தலைவர், SLPP ஊடாக பாராளுமன்றத்திற்கு பிரவேசித்து தற்போது ஐ.தே.க ஆதரவாளராக உள்ள பாராளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர் ஒருவர், இரட்டைக் குடியுரிமை உள்ளவரா என கலாநிதி நந்தலால் வீரசிங்கவிடம் தொடர்ந்தும் வினவினார்.",
        "\"அவர் இரட்டைக் குடியுரிமை பெற்றவர் அல்ல. என்ன செய்யப் பார்க்கிறார்கள்? அவரைப் பதவியில் இருந்து துரத்தலாம் என்ற நம்பிக்கையில் அவரைப் பற்றி கிசுகிசுக்களைப் பரப்ப முயற்சிக்கிறார்கள், இதனால் அவர்கள் அந்த பதவிக்கு தங்கள் நெருங்கிய கூட்டாளிகளில் ஒருவரை நியமிக்கலாம்,\" என்று அவர் குற்றம் சாட்டினார்.",
        "\"நாட்டை விட்டு ஓடிய இரட்டைக் குடிமகன் மத்திய வங்கியைக் கொள்ளையடித்த ஆளுநரை மீண்டும் நியமிக்க முயற்சிக்கின்றாரா? அதனால்தான் நந்தலால் வீரசிங்கவை பதவி நீக்கம் செய்ய முயற்சிகள் நடக்கின்றனவா?\" எதிர்க்கட்சித் தலைவரிடம் கோரிக்கை விடுத்துள்ளார்.",
        "கலாநிதி வீரசிங்கவை நீக்குவதற்கான முதல் நடவடிக்கை மத்திய வங்கி ஆளுநருக்கும் பாராளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர்களுக்கும் இடையிலான சந்திப்பிலேயே மேற்கொள்ளப்பட்டதாகவும், மறுநாள் 20 நிமிடம் பாராளுமன்றத்தில் பேசிய காலி எம்.பி. ஆளுநரை பதவியில் இருந்து நீக்க வேண்டும்.",
        "22 மில்லியன் மக்களுடன் நாடு திவாலாகிவிட்டதாக சுட்டிக்காட்டிய எதிர்க்கட்சித் தலைவர், அரசாங்கம் நெருங்கிய கூட்டாளிகளுக்கு முக்கியத்துவம் கொடுத்து விளையாட முயற்சிக்கிறது.",
        "மின்சாரம், பெட்ரோலியம் உற்பத்தி, எரிபொருள் விநியோகம் மற்றும் சுகாதாரம், அத்தியாவசிய சேவைகளாக அறிவிக்கப்பட்டது.- PMD"
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "News 1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சஜித் பிரேமதாச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "அஜித் நிவார்ட் கப்ரால்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "தொகுதிக் குழு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "அக்மீமன",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "காலி",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "நந்தலால் வீரசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆஸ்திரேலியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "மத்திய வங்கி",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "புதன்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஐ.தே.க",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "நந்தலால் வீரசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "மத்திய வங்கி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "நந்தலால் வீரசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "முதலில்",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "வீரசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "மத்திய வங்கி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர்கள்",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "மறுநாள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "20 நிமிடங்கள்",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "காலி",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "22 மில்லியன்",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        []
      ]
    }
  }
}