{
  "newspaper_id": "virakesari-lk",
  "url": "http://www.virakesari.lk/article/130525",
  "time_ut": 1656646301,
  "original_lang": "ta",
  "original_title": "இலங்கைக்கு கடத்துவதற்காக பதுக்கி வைக்கப்பட்டிருந்த கடல் அட்டைகள் மீட்பு",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Recovery of sea cards hoarded for smuggling to Sri Lanka",
      "author": "T. Saranya",
      "body_lines": [
        "480 kg of sea cards, which were hoarded to be smuggled to Sri Lanka, were recovered near the Mandapam camp in Tamil Nadu yesterday (30) evening.",
        "Forest Department officials have received confidential information that sea cards are being stored near Mandapam from Vedalai beach area to be smuggled to Sri Lanka.",
        "Following this, the forest department rushed to the area and confiscated about 480 kg of sea card stored for smuggling to Sri Lanka and are conducting an investigation.",
        "According to the forest department, the seized sea card has an international value of Rs 50 lakh."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Sri Lanka",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "480 kg",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Mandapam",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Tamil Nadu",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "yesterday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "30) evening",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Forest Department",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Mandapam",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Vedalai beach",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "about 480 kg",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "50",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවට හොර රහසේ ගෙන ඒම සඳහා ගබඩා කර තිබූ මුහුදු කාඩ්පත් සොයා ගැනීම",
      "author": "T. Saranya",
      "body_lines": [
        "නීතිවිරෝධී ලෙස ශ්‍රී ලංකාවට රැගෙන ඒම සඳහා ගොඩගසා තිබූ මුහුදු කාඩ්පත් කිලෝග්‍රෑම් 480 ක් තමිල්නාඩුවේ මණ්ඩපම් කඳවුර අසලදී ඊයේ (30) සවස සොයා ගැනුණා.",
        "වේදාලෙයි වෙරළ තීරයේ සිට ශ්‍රී ලංකාවට රැගෙන ඒම සඳහා මණ්ඩපය අසල මුහුදු කාඩ්පත් ගබඩා කරන බවට වන සංරක්ෂණ දෙපාර්තමේන්තුවේ නිලධාරීන්ට රහසිගත තොරතුරක් ලැබී ඇත.",
        "ඒ අනුව වන සංරක්ෂණ දෙපාර්තමේන්තුව කඩිනමින් එම ප්‍රදේශයට ගොස් නීතිවිරෝධී ලෙස ශ්‍රී ලංකාවට රැගෙන ඒම සඳහා ගබඩා කර තිබූ මුහුදු කාඩ්පත් කිලෝග්‍රෑම් 480ක් පමණ රාජසන්තක කර පරීක්ෂණ පවත්වයි.",
        "අත්අඩංගුවට ගත් මුහුදු පත‍්‍රයේ ජාත්‍යන්තර වටිනාකම රුපියල් ලක්ෂ 50ක් බව වන සංරක්ෂණ දෙපාර්තමේන්තුව පවසයි."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "කිලෝ ග්රෑම් 480 කි",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මණ්ඩපය",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "තමිල්නාඩුව",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඊයේ",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "30) සවස",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "වන සංරක්ෂණ දෙපාර්තමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "මණ්ඩපය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "වෙදලෙයි වෙරළ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "480 kg පමණ",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "50",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "இலங்கைக்கு கடத்துவதற்காக பதுக்கி வைக்கப்பட்டிருந்த கடல் அட்டைகள் மீட்பு",
      "author": "T. Saranya",
      "body_lines": [
        "இலங்கைக்கு கடத்துவதற்காக பதுக்கி வைக்கப்பட்டிருந்த 480 கிலோ கடல் அட்டைகள் தமிழகத்தில் உள்ள மண்டபம் முகாம் அருகே நேற்று (30) மாலை மீட்கப்பட்டுள்ளது.",
        "மண்டபம் அருகே வேதாளை கடற்கரை  பகுதியில் இருந்து இலங்கைக்கு கடத்துவதற்காக கடல் அட்டைகள் பதுக்கி வைக்கப்பட்டுள்ளதாக வனத்துறை அதிகாரிகளுக்கு  இரகசிய தகவல் கிடைத்துள்ளது.",
        "இதையடுத்து அப்பகுதிக்கு விரைந்து  சென்ற வனத்துறையினர் இலங்கைக்கு  கடத்துவதற்காக பதுக்கி வைக்கப்பட்டிருந்த  சுமார் 480 கிலோ எடை கொண்ட கடல் அட்டையை பறிமுதல் செய்து விசாரணை நடத்தி வருகின்றனர்.",
        "மேலும் பறிமுதல் செய்யப்பட்ட கடல் அட்டையில் சர்வதேச மதிப்பு 50 இலட்சம் இருக்கும் என வனத்துறை  தெரிவித்துள்ளனர்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "இலங்கை",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "480 கிலோ",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "மண்டபம்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "தமிழ்நாடு",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "நேற்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "30) மாலை",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "வனத்துறை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "மண்டபம்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "வேதாளை கடற்கரை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "சுமார் 480 கிலோ",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "50",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}