{
  "newspaper_id": "island-lk",
  "url": "http://island.lk/gallup-polls-and-g-strings/",
  "time_ut": 1660143300,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Gallup polls and G-strings",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Gallup polls and G-strings",
      "author": "Sahan Weerasooriya",
      "body_lines": [
        "The results of an opinion survey, released recently, indicate that JVP leader Anura Kumara Dissanayake is leading where the public approval ratings of the candidates who vied for the presidency in Parliament last month are concerned. Dissanayake leads the survey on trust in leaders to do the right thing to resolve the economic crisis, with 48.5%, followed by Ranil Wickremesinghe (36.6%), Opposition leader Sajith Premadasa (29.1%) and Dullas Alahapperuma (23.7%).",
        "The outcome of the aforesaid opinion poll is likely to make the JVP believe that it stands a better chance of shoring up its image and improving its electoral performance if it remains independent of the grand alliance thought to be in the making, and acts as the Opposition. If all other parties represented in Parliament join forces with the SLPP to form a unity government officially, then the post of the Opposition Leader will have to go to the JVP; that is the basis on which TNA leader R. Sampanthan became the Opposition Leader in 2015.",
        "However, it is not advisable for anyone to go solely by opinion/polls survey results in making vital decisions, for public opinion could be as elusive as the weather; forecasts thereof could go wrong, and some politicians who disregard this fact have found themselves up the creek without a paddle. What befell Keith James Locke, a New Zealand Green Party member, may serve as an example. In the run-up to the 2005 election, he was so confident of victory in his electorate because of Gallup polls predictions favourable to him that he undertook to run across Epsom, in the buff, if his rival won. Unfortunately for him, the pollsters’ predictions went wrong, and he lost! Under pressure from the media and his political rivals, he carried out his promise; he made a dash across the Auckland suburb, wearing a G-string with bodypainting depicting a full suit!",
        "Even in the US, where pollsters employ advanced methods to gather data and analyse them, the Gallup polls results went wrong as regards the outcome of the 2016 presidential election. Polls forecasters confidently placed Hillary Clinton’s chance of winning at between 70% to 99%! But Donald Trump came from behind to beat her. It may be argued that Clinton won the popular vote, but the fact remains that Trump secured the presidency. Pollsters also failed to predict the outcome of the British general election in 2015.",
        "One may recall that in Sri Lanka, too, something similar happened at the 2015 presidential election. All secret opinion surveys commissioned by the Mahinda Rajapaksa government ahead of that election predicted a landslide win for the sitting President, but his main rival, Maithripala Sirisena proved to be a dark horse. Rajapaksa did not know what hit him. Even Sirisena may not have expected to pull off such an upset victory.",
        "Sri Lankan pollsters may be familiar with the idea of ‘shy Trumpers’, which came into being during the 2016 US presidential election; many Americans did not want to identify themselves as the supporters of Trump, during surveys, due to his undesirable behaviour but approved his policies and voted for him. Likewise, there may not be a dearth of ‘shy Rajapaksers’ in the Sri Lanka polity, and the beleaguered Family may be planning a comeback a la Bongbong Marcos of the Philippines. This may be the reason why they enabled two non-SLPP members, Wickremesinghe (UNP) and Dinesh Gunawardena (MEP) to secure the presidency and the premiership respectively and function as placeholders, while enjoying life, until the time is opportune for the Family members to crawl out of the woodwork.",
        "President Wickremesinghe has likened his unenviable task to that of Grusha, who carries a baby across a collapsing rope bridge, in The Caucasian Chalk Circle. That, we believe, is an understatement of his daunting mission; he is carrying a much heavier burden—a full-grown, former ruggerite, who is the son of not just a former Governor but an ex-President, no less!",
        "As for surveys and statistical analysis of public opinion, it behoves politicians to tread cautiously. Prudence demands that they keep an ear to the ground, and factor in all political developments and trends in making crucial decisions, instead of being carried away by survey results.",
        "Leave a Reply Cancel replyYour email address will not be published. Required fields are marked *Comment Name *",
        "Save my name, email, and website in this browser for the next time I comment."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Gallup",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "JVP",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Anura Kumara Dissanayake",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "last month",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Dissanayake",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "48.5%",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "36.6%",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sajith Premadasa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "29.1%",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "Dullas Alahapperuma",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "23.7%",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Opposition",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "JVP",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "TNA",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "R. Sampanthan",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "2015",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Keith James Locke",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "New Zealand",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Green Party",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "2005",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Gallup",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Epsom",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Auckland",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "US",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Gallup",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "2016",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Hillary Clinton’s",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "between 70% to 99%",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "Donald Trump",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Clinton",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Trump",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "British",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "2015",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "One",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "2015",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Mahinda Rajapaksa",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Maithripala Sirisena",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sirisena",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lankan",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "2016",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "US",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Americans",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Trump",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Family",
            "label": "PRODUCT"
          },
          {
            "text": "Bongbong Marcos",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Philippines",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "two",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "UNP",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Dinesh Gunawardena",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "MEP",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Family",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "The Caucasian Chalk Circle",
            "label": "LOC"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [],
        []
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "Gallup polls සහ G-strings",
      "author": "සහන් වීරසූරිය",
      "body_lines": [
        "පසුගිය මාසයේ නිකුත් වූ මත විමසුමක ප්‍රතිඵලවලින් පෙනී යන්නේ පසුගිය මාසයේ පාර්ලිමේන්තුවට ඉදිරිපත් වූ ජනාධිපතිවරණයට ඉදිරිපත් වූ අපේක්ෂකයන්ගේ මහජන ප්‍රසාදය ගැන සැලකීමේදී ජවිපෙ නායක අනුර කුමාර දිසානායක ඉදිරියෙන් සිටින බවයි. ආර්ථික අර්බුදය විසඳීම සඳහා නිවැරදි දේ කිරීම සඳහා නායකයින් කෙරෙහි ඇති විශ්වාසය පිළිබඳ සමීක්ෂණයට දිසානායක නායකත්වය දෙන අතර 48.5% ක් සමඟින් රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ (36.6%), විපක්ෂ නායක සජිත් ප්‍රේමදාස (29.1%) සහ ඩලස් අලහප්පෙරුම (23.7%).",
        "පෙර කී ජනමත විමසුමේ ප්‍රතිඵලය අනුව ජනතා විමුක්ති පෙරමුණට තම ප්‍රතිරූපය ඉහළ නංවා ගැනීමටත් මැතිවරණ කාර්ය සාධනය වැඩි දියුණු කර ගැනීමටත් වඩා හොඳ අවස්ථාවක් ඇති බව විශ්වාස කිරීමට ඉඩ ඇත්තේ තමන් හදනවා යැයි සිතන මහා සන්ධානයෙන් ස්වාධීනව විපක්ෂය ලෙස කටයුතු කරන්නේ නම් ය. . පාර්ලිමේන්තුව නියෝජනය කරන අනෙකුත් සියලුම පක්ෂ ශ්‍රී ලංකා පොදුජන පෙරමුණ සමග එක්ව නිල වශයෙන් සමගි ආණ්ඩුවක් පිහිටුවීමට ගියහොත් විපක්ෂ නායක ධූරය හිමිවන්නේ ජනතා විමුක්ති පෙරමුණටය. 2015 දී දෙමළ ජාතික සන්ධානයේ නායක ආර්.සම්බන්ධන් විපක්ෂ නායක ධුරයට පත්වූයේ එම පදනම මතය.",
        "කෙසේ වෙතත්, වැදගත් තීරණ ගැනීමේදී කිසිවකුට මත/මත විමසුම් සමීක්ෂණ ප්‍රතිඵල මත පමණක් යෑම සුදුසු නොවේ, මන්ද මහජන මතය කාලගුණය මෙන් නොපැහැදිලි විය හැකි බැවිනි. එහි අනාවැකි වැරදී යා හැකි අතර, මෙම කරුණ නොසලකා හරින ඇතැම් දේශපාලකයින් තොටිල්ලක් නොමැතිව දිය පහරට ගොඩ වී ඇත. නවසීලන්ත හරිත පක්ෂයේ සාමාජිකයෙකු වන කීත් ජේම්ස් ලොක්ට සිදු වූ දේ උදාහරණයක් ලෙස ගත හැකිය. 2005 මැතිවරණයට පෙර, ඔහුට හිතකර Gallup මත විමසුම් අනාවැකි නිසා ඔහුගේ ඡන්දදායකයින්ගේ ජයග්‍රහණය ගැන ඔහුට කෙතරම් විශ්වාසයක් තිබුණාද යත්, ඔහුගේ ප්‍රතිවාදියා ජයග්‍රහණය කළහොත්, Epsom හරහා තරඟ කිරීමට ඔහු භාර ගත්තේය. අවාසනාවකට ඔහුට, ඡන්ද විමසන්නන්ගේ අනාවැකි වැරදියි, ඔහු පැරදුණා! මාධ්‍ය සහ ඔහුගේ දේශපාලන ප්‍රතිවාදීන්ගේ පීඩනය යටතේ ඔහු තම පොරොන්දුව ඉටු කළේය; ඔහු ඕක්ලන්ඩ් තදාසන්න ප්‍රදේශය හරහා ගමන් කළේය, සම්පූර්ණ ඇඳුමක් නිරූපණය කරන ශරීර පින්තාරු කිරීම සහිත G-නූලක් පැළඳ සිටියේය!",
        "දත්ත රැස් කිරීමට සහ ඒවා විශ්ලේෂණය කිරීමට ඡන්ද විමසන්නන් උසස් ක්‍රම භාවිත කරන එක්සත් ජනපදයේ පවා, 2016 ජනාධිපතිවරණ ප්‍රතිඵලය සම්බන්ධයෙන් Gallup මත විමසුම් ප්‍රතිඵල වැරදි විය. මත විමසුම් අනාවැකිකරුවන් විශ්වාසයෙන් හිලරි ක්ලින්ටන්ගේ ජයග්‍රහණයේ අවස්ථාව 70% සිට 99% දක්වා තබා ඇත! නමුත් ඩොනල්ඩ් ට්‍රම්ප් ඇයට පහර දීමට පිටුපසින් පැමිණියේය. ක්ලින්ටන් ජනප්‍රිය ඡන්දයෙන් ජයග්‍රහණය කළ බවට තර්ක කළ හැකි නමුත් ට්‍රම්ප් ජනාධිපති ධුරය තහවුරු කර ගත් බව සත්‍යයකි. 2015 බ්‍රිතාන්‍ය මහ මැතිවරණයේ ප්‍රතිඵලය අනාවැකි කීමට ද ඡන්ද විමසුම්කරුවන් අසමත් විය.",
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ ද 2015 ජනාධිපතිවරණයේ දී ද එවැනිම දෙයක් සිදු වූ බව කෙනෙකුට මතක ඇති. එම මැතිවරණයට පෙර මහින්ද රාජපක්ෂ රජය විසින් පත් කරන ලද සියලුම රහස්‍ය මත සමීක්ෂණවලින් පෙනී සිටින ජනාධිපතිවරයාට විශිෂ්ට ජයග්‍රහණයක් ගැන අනාවැකි පළ වූ නමුත් ඔහුගේ ප්‍රධාන ප්‍රතිවාදියා වූ මෛත්‍රීපාල සිරිසේන අඳුරු අශ්වයෙකු බව ඔප්පු විය. ඔහුට පහර දුන්නේ කුමක් දැයි රාජපක්ෂ දන්නේ නැත. මෙතරම් කැළඹුණු ජයග්‍රහණයක් ලබා ගැනීමට සිරිසේන පවා බලාපොරොත්තු නොවන්නට ඇත.",
        "2016 එක්සත් ජනපද ජනාධිපතිවරණ සමයේදී ඇති වූ ‘ලැජ්ජ ට්‍රම්ප්ස්’ අදහස ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ ඡන්ද විමසුම්කරුවන්ට හුරුපුරුදු විය හැකිය; බොහෝ ඇමරිකානුවන් ට්‍රම්ප්ගේ අනවශ්‍ය හැසිරීම හේතුවෙන් සමීක්ෂණ අතරතුර ට්‍රම්ප්ගේ ආධාරකරුවන් ලෙස හඳුනා ගැනීමට අවශ්‍ය නොවූ නමුත් ඔහුගේ ප්‍රතිපත්ති අනුමත කර ඔහුට ඡන්දය දුන්හ. එලෙසම, ශ්‍රී ලංකා දේශපාලනයේ ‘ලැජ්ජාශීලී රාජපක්ෂලා’ හිඟයක් නොතිබිය හැකි අතර, පැටලී සිටින පවුල පිලිපීනයේ ලා බොංබොං මාකෝස් සමඟ නැවත පැමිණීමට සැලසුම් කරයි. ශ්‍රී ලංකා පොදුජන පෙරමුණේ සාමාජිකයන් නොවන දෙදෙනකු වන වික්‍රමසිංහ (එජාප) සහ දිනේෂ් ගුණවර්ධන (මඑපෙ) යන දෙදෙනාට පිළිවෙළින් ජනාධිපතිකමත් අගමැතිකමත් හිමිකර ගැනීමටත්, පවුලේ සාමාජිකයන්ට සුදුසු කාලය එනතුරු ජීවිතය භුක්ති විඳිමින් ස්ථාන දරන්නා ලෙස කටයුතු කිරීමටත් ඔවුන් ඉඩ දුන්නේ මේ නිසා විය හැකිය. ලී වැඩවලින් බඩගා යාමට.",
        "ජනාධිපති වික්‍රමසිංහ තමාගේ අප්‍රාණික කර්තව්‍යය කොකේසියානු හුණු කවයේ කඩා වැටෙන කඹ පාලමක් හරහා ළදරුවෙකු රැගෙන යන ගෲෂාගේ කාර්යයට සමාන කර ඇත. එය, ඔහුගේ භයංකර මෙහෙවර අවතක්සේරු කිරීමකි; ඔහු වඩා බර බරක් උසුලාගෙන සිටී - පූර්ණ වැඩුණු, හිටපු රගර් ක්‍රීඩකයෙකි, ඔහු හිටපු ආණ්ඩුකාරවරයකුගේ පමණක් නොව හිටපු ජනාධිපතිවරයකුගේ පුතෙකු ද වේ!",
        "මහජන මතය පිළිබඳ සමීක්ෂණ සහ සංඛ්‍යානමය විශ්ලේෂණ සම්බන්ධයෙන් ගත් කල, දේශපාලනඥයන් කල්පනාකාරීව ගමන් කළ යුතුය. සමීක්‍ෂණ ප්‍රතිඵලවලින් ඉවතට ගෙන යනු වෙනුවට ඔවුන් සියලු දේශපාලන වර්ධනයන් සහ තීරණාත්මක තීරණ ගැනීමේ ප්‍රවණතාවන් කෙරෙහි අවධානය යොමු කරන ලෙස විචක්ෂණභාවය ඉල්ලා සිටී.",
        "පිළිතුරක් දෙන්න පිළිතුර අවලංගු කරන්න ඔබගේ විද්‍යුත් තැපැල් ලිපිනය ප්‍රකාශයට පත් නොකෙරේ. අවශ්‍ය ක්ෂේත්‍ර සලකුණු කර ඇත *අදහස් නම *",
        "මම ඊළඟ වතාවේ අදහස් දැක්වීම සඳහා මගේ නම, විද්‍යුත් තැපෑල සහ වෙබ් අඩවිය මෙම බ්‍රවුසරයේ සුරකින්න."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ගැලප්",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ජ.වි.පෙ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "අනුර කුමාර දිසානායක",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "පසුගිය මාසයේ",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "දිසානායක",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "48.5%",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "36.6%",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "සජිත් ප්‍රේමදාස",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "29.1%",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඩලස් අලහප්පෙරුම",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "23.7%",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "විපක්ෂ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජ.වි.පෙ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ටීඑන්ඒ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ආර් සම්බන්ධන්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "2015",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "කීත් ජේම්ස් ලොක්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "නවසීලන්තය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "හරිත පක්ෂය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "2005",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගැලප්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "එප්සම්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඕක්ලන්ඩ්",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "එක්සත් ජනපදය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගැලප්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "2016",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "හිලරි ක්ලින්ටන්ගේ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "70% සිට 99% දක්වා",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඩොනල්ඩ් ට්රම්ප්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ක්ලින්ටන්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ට්රම්ප්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "බ්රිතාන්ය",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "2015",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "එක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "2015",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මහින්ද රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "මෛත්‍රීපාල සිරිසේන",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "සිරිසේන",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලාංකික",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "2016",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "එක්සත් ජනපදය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඇමරිකානුවන්",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ට්රම්ප්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "පවුලේ",
            "label": "PRODUCT"
          },
          {
            "text": "බොංබොං මාකෝස්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "පිලිපීනය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "දෙක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "එජාප",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "දිනේෂ් ගුණවර්ධන",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "MEP",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "පවුලේ",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "කොකේසියානු හුණු කවය",
            "label": "LOC"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [],
        []
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "கேலப் கருத்துக்கணிப்புகள் மற்றும் ஜி-சரங்கள்",
      "author": "சஹான் வீரசூரிய",
      "body_lines": [
        "அண்மையில் வெளியிடப்பட்ட கருத்துக் கணிப்பு முடிவுகள், கடந்த மாதம் பாராளுமன்றத்தில் ஜனாதிபதித் தேர்தலில் போட்டியிட்ட வேட்பாளர்களின் பொது அங்கீகாரத்தைப் பொறுத்த வரையில் ஜே.வி.பியின் தலைவர் அனுரகுமார திஸாநாயக்க முன்னிலை வகிக்கின்றார். பொருளாதார நெருக்கடியைத் தீர்ப்பதற்கு சரியானதைச் செய்வதற்கு தலைவர்கள் மீது நம்பிக்கை வைப்பது குறித்த கணக்கெடுப்பில் திஸாநாயக்க முன்னிலை வகிக்கிறார், 48.5% உடன், ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க (36.6%), எதிர்க்கட்சித் தலைவர் சஜித் பிரேமதாச (29.1%) மற்றும் டலஸ் அழகப்பெரும (23.7%) ஆகியோர் உள்ளனர்.",
        "மேற்கூறிய கருத்துக் கணிப்பின் முடிவுகள், ஜே.வி.பி., உருவாக்கப்படும் என்று கருதப்படும் மகா கூட்டணியில் இருந்து சுதந்திரமாக இருந்து, எதிர்க்கட்சியாகச் செயல்பட்டால், தனது இமேஜை உயர்த்திக் கொள்ளவும், தேர்தல் செயல்திறனை மேம்படுத்தவும் ஒரு சிறந்த வாய்ப்பு என்று நம்ப வைக்கும். . பாராளுமன்றத்தில் பிரதிநிதித்துவப்படுத்தும் ஏனைய அனைத்துக் கட்சிகளும் ஸ்ரீலங்கா பொதுஜன பெரமுனவுடன் இணைந்து உத்தியோகபூர்வமாக ஐக்கிய அரசாங்கத்தை உருவாக்கினால், எதிர்க்கட்சித் தலைவர் பதவியானது ஜே.வி.பி. அதன் அடிப்படையில்தான் 2015ஆம் ஆண்டு தமிழ்த் தேசியக் கூட்டமைப்பின் தலைவர் ஆர்.சம்பந்தன் எதிர்க்கட்சித் தலைவரானார்.",
        "எவ்வாறாயினும், முக்கியமான முடிவுகளை எடுப்பதில் கருத்து/வாக்கெடுப்புகளின் கருத்துக்கணிப்பு முடிவுகளின் அடிப்படையில் மட்டுமே செல்வது எவருக்கும் அறிவுறுத்தப்படுவதில்லை, ஏனெனில் பொதுமக்களின் கருத்து வானிலை போன்ற மழுப்பலாக இருக்கலாம்; அதன் கணிப்புகள் தவறாகப் போகலாம், இந்த உண்மையைப் புறக்கணிக்கும் சில அரசியல்வாதிகள் துடுப்பு இல்லாமலேயே சிற்றோடையைக் கண்டனர். நியூசிலாந்தின் பசுமைக் கட்சி உறுப்பினரான கீத் ஜேம்ஸ் லாக்கிற்கு என்ன நேர்ந்தது என்பது ஒரு உதாரணமாக இருக்கலாம். 2005 தேர்தலுக்கு முன்னதாக, அவருக்கு சாதகமான காலப் கருத்துக் கணிப்புகள் காரணமாக அவர் தனது வாக்காளர்களில் வெற்றி பெறுவார் என்ற நம்பிக்கையில் இருந்தார், அவருடைய போட்டியாளர் வெற்றி பெற்றால், எப்சம் முழுவதும் போட்டியிட அவர் உறுதியளித்தார். துரதிர்ஷ்டவசமாக அவருக்கு, கருத்துக்கணிப்பாளர்களின் கணிப்புகள் தவறாகி, அவர் தோற்றார்! ஊடகங்கள் மற்றும் அவரது அரசியல் போட்டியாளர்களின் அழுத்தத்தின் கீழ், அவர் தனது வாக்குறுதியை நிறைவேற்றினார்; அவர் ஆக்லாந்து புறநகர் முழுவதும் ஒரு கோடு போட்டார், முழு உடையை சித்தரிக்கும் பாடிபெயின்டிங்குடன் ஜி-ஸ்ட்ரிங் அணிந்திருந்தார்!",
        "வாக்கெடுப்பாளர்கள் தரவைச் சேகரித்து அவற்றைப் பகுப்பாய்வு செய்ய மேம்பட்ட வழிமுறைகளைப் பயன்படுத்தும் அமெரிக்காவில் கூட, 2016 ஜனாதிபதித் தேர்தலின் முடிவைப் பொறுத்தவரை Gallup கருத்துக்கணிப்பு முடிவுகள் தவறாகப் போயுள்ளன. கருத்துக்கணிப்பு முன்னறிவிப்பாளர்கள் நம்பிக்கையுடன் ஹிலாரி கிளிண்டனின் வெற்றி வாய்ப்பு 70% முதல் 99% வரை! ஆனால் டொனால்ட் டிரம்ப் அவளை அடிக்க பின்னால் வந்தார். கிளின்டன் மக்கள் வாக்குகளை வென்றார் என்று வாதிடலாம், ஆனால் டிரம்ப் ஜனாதிபதி பதவியை உறுதி செய்தார் என்பது உண்மை. 2015 இல் நடந்த பிரிட்டிஷ் பொதுத் தேர்தலின் முடிவைக் கணிக்க கருத்துக்கணிப்பாளர்களும் தவறிவிட்டனர்.",
        "இலங்கையிலும் 2015ஆம் ஆண்டு ஜனாதிபதித் தேர்தலின்போது இதேபோன்றதொரு சம்பவம் இடம்பெற்றது நினைவிருக்கலாம். அந்தத் தேர்தலுக்கு முன்னர் மஹிந்த ராஜபக்ஷ அரசாங்கத்தால் நியமிக்கப்பட்ட அனைத்து இரகசிய கருத்துக் கணிப்புகளும் தற்போதைய ஜனாதிபதிக்கு மகத்தான வெற்றியை முன்னறிவித்தன, ஆனால் அவரது பிரதான போட்டியாளரான மைத்திரிபால சிறிசேன ஒரு இருண்ட குதிரை என்பதை நிரூபித்தார். ராஜபக்சேவுக்கு என்ன அடித்தது என்று தெரியவில்லை. இப்படி ஒரு அதிர்ச்சிகரமான வெற்றியை சிறீசேனா கூட எதிர்பார்த்திருக்க மாட்டார்.",
        "2016 ஆம் ஆண்டு அமெரிக்க ஜனாதிபதித் தேர்தலின் போது உருவான ‘வெட்கப்பட்ட ட்ரம்பர்ஸ்’ என்ற யோசனையை இலங்கைக் கருத்துக் கணிப்பாளர்கள் நன்கு அறிந்திருக்கலாம்; டிரம்பின் விரும்பத்தகாத நடத்தை காரணமாக, கருத்துக்கணிப்புகளின் போது, ​​பல அமெரிக்கர்கள் ட்ரம்பின் ஆதரவாளர்களாக தங்களை அடையாளப்படுத்த விரும்பவில்லை, ஆனால் அவரது கொள்கைகளை அங்கீகரித்து அவருக்கு வாக்களித்தனர். அதேபோல், இலங்கை அரசியலில் ‘கூச்ச சுபாவமுள்ள ராஜபக்ஸர்களுக்கு’ பஞ்சம் இருக்காது, மேலும் பிலிப்பைன்ஸின் லா பாங்பாங் மார்கோஸால் பாதிக்கப்பட்ட குடும்பம் மீண்டும் வரத் திட்டமிட்டிருக்கலாம். SLPP அல்லாத இரண்டு உறுப்பினர்களான விக்கிரமசிங்க (UNP) மற்றும் தினேஷ் குணவர்தன (MEP) ஆகியோர் முறையே ஜனாதிபதி மற்றும் பிரதமர் பதவியைப் பெறுவதற்கும், குடும்ப உறுப்பினர்களுக்கு நேரம் கிடைக்கும் வரை, வாழ்க்கையை அனுபவிக்கும் அதே வேளையில் இடம்பிடித்தவர்களாக செயல்படுவதற்கும் இதுவே காரணமாக இருக்கலாம். மரவேலைகளில் இருந்து வலம் வர.",
        "ஜனாதிபதி விக்கிரமசிங்க, காகசியன் சாக் சர்க்கிளில், இடிந்து விழும் நிலையில் உள்ள கயிறு பாலத்தின் குறுக்கே குழந்தையை தூக்கிச் செல்லும் க்ருஷாவின் பணிக்கு, அவரது பொறாமைப்பட முடியாத பணியை ஒப்பிட்டுள்ளார். அது, அவரது கடினமான பணியை குறைத்து மதிப்பிடுவதாக நாங்கள் நம்புகிறோம்; அவர் அதிக சுமையைச் சுமக்கிறார் - முழு வளர்ச்சியடைந்த, முன்னாள் ரக்ரைட், அவர் ஒரு முன்னாள் கவர்னர் மட்டுமல்ல, ஒரு முன்னாள் ஜனாதிபதியின் மகனும் கூட!",
        "கணக்கெடுப்புகள் மற்றும் பொதுக் கருத்தின் புள்ளியியல் பகுப்பாய்வைப் பொறுத்தவரை, அரசியல்வாதிகள் எச்சரிக்கையுடன் நடக்க வேண்டும். ப்ருடென்ஸ் அவர்கள் கருத்துக்கணிப்பு முடிவுகளால் எடுத்துச் செல்லப்படுவதற்குப் பதிலாக, அனைத்து அரசியல் முன்னேற்றங்கள் மற்றும் முக்கிய முடிவுகளை எடுப்பதில் உள்ள போக்குகளுக்குக் காரணமாக இருக்க வேண்டும் என்று கோருகிறது.",
        "ஒரு பதிலை விடுங்கள் பதிலை ரத்துசெய் உங்கள் மின்னஞ்சல் முகவரி வெளியிடப்படாது. தேவையான புலங்கள் குறிக்கப்பட்டுள்ளன *கருத்து பெயர் *",
        "அடுத்த முறை நான் கருத்து தெரிவிக்க, எனது பெயர், மின்னஞ்சல் மற்றும் இணையதளத்தை இந்த உலாவியில் சேமிக்கவும்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "கால்அப்",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ஜே.வி.பி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "அனுரகுமார திஸாநாயக்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "கடந்த மாதம்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "திசாநாயக்க",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "48.5%",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "36.6%",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "சஜித் பிரேமதாச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "29.1%",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "டலஸ் அழகப்பெரும",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "23.7%",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "எதிர்ப்பு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜே.வி.பி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "TNA",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆர்.சம்பந்தன்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "2015",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "கீத் ஜேம்ஸ் லாக்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "நியூசிலாந்து",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "பசுமைக் கட்சி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "2005",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "கால்அப்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "எப்சம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆக்லாந்து",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "எங்களுக்கு",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "கால்அப்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "2016",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஹிலாரி கிளிண்டனின்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "70% முதல் 99% வரை",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "டொனால்டு டிரம்ப்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "கிளின்டன்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "டிரம்ப்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "பிரிட்டிஷ்",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "2015",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஒன்று",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "2015",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "மஹிந்த ராஜபக்ஷ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "மைத்திரிபால சிறிசேன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ராஜபக்சே",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "சிறிசேனா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "2016",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "எங்களுக்கு",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "அமெரிக்கர்கள்",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "டிரம்ப்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "குடும்பம்",
            "label": "PRODUCT"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாங்பாங் மார்கோஸ்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "பிலிப்பைன்ஸ்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இரண்டு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஐ.தே.க",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "தினேஷ் குணவர்தன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "MEP",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "குடும்பம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "காகசியன் சுண்ணாம்பு வட்டம்",
            "label": "LOC"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [],
        []
      ]
    }
  }
}