{
  "newspaper_id": "d-b-s-jeyaraj-com",
  "url": "https://dbsjeyaraj.com/dbsj/archives/79138",
  "time_ut": 1661282640,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Colombo Fort Magistrate Thilina Gamage issues  order directing the CID to conduct an investigation into a contemptuous statement allegedly  made  at a press conference by Puttalam District Parliamentarian Sanath Nishantha Following Submissions made by President’s Counsel Upul Jayasuriya",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Colombo Fort Magistrate Thilina Gamage issues  order directing the CID to conduct an investigation into a contemptuous statement allegedly  made  at a press conference by Puttalam District Parliamentarian Sanath Nishantha Following Submissions made by President’s Counsel Upul Jayasuriya",
      "author": "Administrator",
      "body_lines": [
        "The Colombo Fort Magistrate today issued an order directing the CID to conduct an investigation into a contemptuous statement alleged to have been made by Puttalam District Parliamentarian Sanath Nishantha.",
        "Colombo Fort Magistrate Thilina Gamage ordered the CID to examine the video footage of a press conference attended by Sanath Nishantha in order to determine whether remarks made by the parliamentarian are detrimental to the judiciary.",
        "President’s Counsel Upul Jayasuriya appearing for the victims of the Galle Face protest alleged that Parliamentarian Sanath Nishantha had recently made a statement criticising the judicial process.",
        "Meanwhile, parliamentarians Sanath Nishantha and Milan Jayathilake and leader of Nawa Sinhale National Organisation Dan Priyasad were ordered to surrender their mobile phones to the CID in connection with the connection with the incidents that took place at Temple Trees and Galle Face on May 9.",
        "The CID alleged that the three suspects have still failed to hand over their mobile devices to the CID in compliance with a court order. The Magistrate severely advised the suspects to be adhere with court orders and warned that bail could be cancelled if they failed to comply with the court orders."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "CID",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "Puttalam District",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "CID",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Puttalam District",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "CID",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sanath Nishantha",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Galle Face",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliamentarian Sanath Nishantha",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sanath Nishantha",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Milan Jayathilake",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Nawa Sinhale National Organisation",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Dan Priyasad",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "CID",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Galle Face",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "May 9",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "CID",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "three",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "CID",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Magistrate",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "පුත්තලම දිස්ත්‍රික් පාර්ලිමේන්තු මන්ත්‍රී සනත් නිශාන්ත මහතා මාධ්‍ය හමුවකදී කළ බව කියන අපහාසාත්මක ප්‍රකාශයක් සම්බන්ධයෙන් ජනාධිපති නීතීඥ උපුල් ජයසූරිය මහතා කළ කරුණු දැක්වීම් අනුව විමර්ශනයක් පවත්වන ලෙස කොළඹ කොටුව මහේස්ත්‍රාත් තිළිණ ගමගේ මහතා රහස් පොලිසියට නියෝග කළේය.",
      "author": "පරිපාලක",
      "body_lines": [
        "පුත්තලම දිස්ත්‍රික් පාර්ලිමේන්තු මන්ත්‍රී සනත් නිශාන්ත මහතා විසින් සිදුකළ බව කියන අපහාසාත්මක ප්‍රකාශයක් සම්බන්ධයෙන් පරීක්ෂණයක් පවත්වන ලෙස කොළඹ කොටුව මහේස්ත්‍රාත්වරයා අපරාධ පරීක්ෂණ දෙපාර්තමේන්තුවට නියෝග කරමින් අද නියෝගයක් නිකුත් කළා.",
        "සනත් නිශාන්ත මන්ත්‍රීවරයාගේ ප්‍රකාශය අධිකරණයට අහිතකර දැයි සොයා බැලීම සඳහා සනත් නිශාන්ත සහභාගි වූ මාධ්‍ය හමුවක වීඩියෝ දර්ශන පරීක්ෂා කරන ලෙස කොළඹ කොටුව මහේස්ත්‍රාත් තිළිණ ගමගේ මහතා රහස් පොලිසියට නියෝග කළේය.",
        "ගාලුමුවදොර විරෝධතාවයේ වින්දිතයින් වෙනුවෙන් පෙනී සිටි ජනාධිපති නීතීඥ උපුල් ජයසූරිය මහතා චෝදනා කළේ පාර්ලිමේන්තු මන්ත්‍රී සනත් නිශාන්ත මහතා අධිකරණ ක්‍රියාවලිය විවේචනය කරමින් පසුගියදා ප්‍රකාශයක් කළ බවයි.",
        "මේ අතර, මැයි 9 වැනිදා අරලියගහ මන්දිරයේ සහ ගාලුමුවදොර සිදුවූ සිද්ධීන් සම්බන්ධයෙන් පාර්ලිමේන්තු මන්ත්‍රීවරුන් වන සනත් නිශාන්ත, මිලාන් ජයතිලක සහ නව සිංහලේ ජාතික සංවිධානයේ නායක ඩෑන් ප්‍රියසාද් යන මහත්වරුන්ට ඔවුන්ගේ ජංගම දුරකථන අපරාධ පරීක්ෂණ දෙපාර්තමේන්තුවට භාර දෙන ලෙස නියෝග කෙරුණා.",
        "අධිකරණ නියෝගයකට අනුව සැකකරුවන් තිදෙනා තවමත් ඔවුන්ගේ ජංගම දුරකථන අපරාධ පරීක්ෂණ දෙපාර්තමේන්තුවට භාරදීමට අපොහොසත් වී ඇති බවට රහස් පොලිසිය චෝදනා කළේය. අධිකරණ නියෝග පිළිපදින ලෙස සැකකරුවන්ට තරයේ අවවාද කළ මහේස්ත්‍රාත්වරයා අධිකරණ නියෝග පිළිපැදීමට අපොහොසත් වුවහොත් ඇප අවලංගු කළ හැකි බවටද අනතුරු ඇඟවීය."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "CID",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "පුත්තලම දිස්ත්‍රික්කය",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "CID",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "පුත්තලම දිස්ත්‍රික්කය",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "CID",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "සනත් නිශාන්ත",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ගාලු මුවදොර",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තු මන්ත්‍රී සනත් නිශාන්ත",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "සනත් නිශාන්ත",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "මිලාන් ජයතිලක",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "නව සිංහලේ ජාතික සංවිධානය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඩෑන් ප්‍රියසාද්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "CID",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගාලු මුවදොර",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "මැයි 9",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "CID",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "තුන්",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "CID",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "මහේස්ත්රාත්වරයා",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "ஜனாதிபதி சட்டத்தரணி உபுல் ஜயசூரிய சமர்பித்ததையடுத்து, புத்தளம் மாவட்ட நாடாளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர் சனத் நிஷாந்த ஊடகவியலாளர் மாநாட்டில் அவமதிக்கும் வகையில் கூறியதாக கூறப்படும் கருத்து தொடர்பில் குற்றப் புலனாய்வுப் பிரிவினருக்கு விசாரணை நடத்துமாறு கொழும்பு கோட்டை நீதவான் திலின கமகே உத்தரவு பிறப்பித்துள்ளார்.",
      "author": "நிர்வாகி",
      "body_lines": [
        "புத்தளம் மாவட்ட நாடாளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர் சனத் நிஷாந்த அவமதிக்கும் வகையில் கூறியதாகக் கூறப்படும் கருத்து தொடர்பில் குற்றப் புலனாய்வுப் பிரிவினருக்கு விசாரணை நடத்துமாறு கொழும்பு கோட்டை நீதவான் இன்று உத்தரவு பிறப்பித்துள்ளார்.",
        "சனத் நிஷாந்த கலந்து கொண்ட ஊடகவியலாளர் மாநாட்டின் காணொளி காட்சிகளை ஆராய்ந்து பாராளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர் தெரிவித்த கருத்து நீதித்துறைக்கு பாதகமானதா என்பதை கண்டறியுமாறு கொழும்பு கோட்டை நீதவான் திலின கமகே குற்றப் புலனாய்வுப் பிரிவினருக்கு உத்தரவிட்டுள்ளார்.",
        "காலிமுகத்திடலில் பாதிக்கப்பட்டவர்கள் சார்பில் ஆஜரான ஜனாதிபதி சட்டத்தரணி உபுல் ஜயசூரிய, நாடாளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர் சனத் நிஷாந்த அண்மையில் நீதிமன்ற செயற்பாடுகளை விமர்சித்து கருத்து வெளியிட்டதாக குற்றம் சுமத்தினார்.",
        "இதேவேளை, மே 9ஆம் திகதி அலரிமாளிகை மற்றும் காலி முகத்திடலில் இடம்பெற்ற சம்பவங்கள் தொடர்பில் நாடாளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர்களான சனத் நிஷாந்த மற்றும் மிலன் ஜயதிலக்க மற்றும் நவ சிங்கள தேசிய அமைப்பின் தலைவர் டான் பிரியசாத் ஆகியோரின் கையடக்கத் தொலைபேசிகளை குற்றப் புலனாய்வுப் பிரிவினரிடம் ஒப்படைக்குமாறு உத்தரவிடப்பட்டுள்ளது.",
        "நீதிமன்ற உத்தரவுக்கு இணங்க சந்தேகநபர்கள் மூவரும் தமது கையடக்க சாதனங்களை இன்னமும் குற்றப் புலனாய்வுப் பிரிவினரிடம் ஒப்படைக்கத் தவறியுள்ளதாக குற்றப் புலனாய்வுப் பிரிவினர் குற்றம் சுமத்தியுள்ளனர். சந்தேகநபர்கள் நீதிமன்ற உத்தரவுகளை கடைப்பிடிக்குமாறு கடுமையாக அறிவுறுத்திய நீதவான், நீதிமன்ற உத்தரவுகளுக்கு இணங்கத் தவறினால் பிணையை இரத்து செய்ய நேரிடும் எனவும் எச்சரித்தார்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "சி.ஐ.டி",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "புத்தளம் மாவட்டம்",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சி.ஐ.டி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "புத்தளம் மாவட்டம்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "சி.ஐ.டி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "சனத் நிஷாந்த",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "காலி முகம்",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர் சனத் நிஷாந்த",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "சனத் நிஷாந்த",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "மிலன் ஜயதிலக்க",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "நவ சிங்கள தேசிய அமைப்பு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "டான் பிரியசாத்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "சி.ஐ.டி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "காலி முகம்",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "மே 9",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "சி.ஐ.டி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "மூன்று",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "சி.ஐ.டி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "மாஜிஸ்திரேட்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}