{
  "newspaper_id": "ada-derana-lk",
  "url": "http://www.adaderana.lk/news/84609/opposition-requests-for-document-granting-presidential-pardon-to-ranjan",
  "time_ut": 1661763240,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Opposition requests for document granting presidential pardon to Ranjan",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Opposition requests for document granting presidential pardon to Ranjan",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "Chief Opposition Whip, Lakshman Kiriella today requested for the document related to granting the presidential pardon to former Parliamentarian Ranjan Ramanayake, be tabled in the parliament.",
        "He made this request to the Deputy Speaker of Parliament Ajith Rajapakse when the parliament was convened this morning (29). MP Kiriella said that the document needs to be studied.",
        "In response to the request, the Deputy Speaker stated that the document can be tabled."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Ranjan",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliamentarian Ranjan Ramanayake",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Ajith Rajapakse",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "this morning",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "29",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kiriella",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        []
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "රන්ජන්ට ජනපති සමාව දෙන ලියවිල්ල විපක්ෂයෙන් ඉල්ලයි",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "හිටපු පාර්ලිමේන්තු මන්ත්‍රී රන්ජන් රාමනායක මහතාට ජනාධිපති සමාව ලබාදීමට අදාළ ලේඛනය පාර්ලිමේන්තුවට ඉදිරිපත් කරන ලෙස විපක්ෂයේ ප්‍රධාන සංවිධායක ලක්ෂ්මන් කිරිඇල්ල මහතා අද ඉල්ලීමක් කළේය.",
        "අද (29) පෙරවරුවේ පාර්ලිමේන්තුව රැස් වූ අවස්ථාවේදී නියෝජ්‍ය කථානායක අජිත් රාජපක්ෂ මහතාගෙන් ඔහු මෙම ඉල්ලීම කළේය. එම ලේඛනය අධ්‍යයනය කළ යුතු බව කිරිඇල්ල මන්ත්‍රීවරයා පැවසීය.",
        "එම ඉල්ලීමට ප්‍රතිචාර දක්වමින් නියෝජ්‍ය කථානායකවරයා කියා සිටියේ එම ලේඛනය සභාගත කළ හැකි බවයි."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "රන්ජන්",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තු මන්ත්‍රී රන්ජන් රාමනායක",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "අජිත් රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "මේ උදෑසන",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "29",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "කිරිඇල්ල",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        []
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "ரஞ்சனுக்கு ஜனாதிபதி மன்னிப்பு வழங்குவதற்கான ஆவணத்தை எதிர்க்கட்சிகள் கோருகின்றன",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "முன்னாள் நாடாளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர் ரஞ்சன் ராமநாயக்கவுக்கு ஜனாதிபதி மன்னிப்பு வழங்குவது தொடர்பான ஆவணத்தை நாடாளுமன்றத்தில் சமர்ப்பிக்குமாறு எதிர்க்கட்சியின் பிரதம கொறடா லக்ஷ்மன் கிரியெல்ல இன்று கோரிக்கை விடுத்துள்ளார்.",
        "இன்று (29) காலை பாராளுமன்றம் கூடிய போதே பிரதி சபாநாயகர் அஜித் ராஜபக்ஷவிடம் அவர் இந்தக் கோரிக்கையை முன்வைத்தார். இந்த ஆவணத்தை ஆய்வு செய்ய வேண்டும் என பாராளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர் கிரியெல்ல தெரிவித்துள்ளார்.",
        "கோரிக்கைக்கு பதிலளித்த பிரதி சபாநாயகர், ஆவணத்தை சமர்ப்பிக்கலாம் என தெரிவித்தார்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ரஞ்சன்",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர் ரஞ்சன் ராமநாயக்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "அஜித் ராஜபக்ஷ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று காலை",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "29",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "கிரியெல்ல",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        []
      ]
    }
  }
}