{
  "newspaper_id": "virakesari-lk",
  "url": "http://www.virakesari.lk/article/130354",
  "time_ut": 1656416653,
  "original_lang": "ta",
  "original_title": "இலங்கையின் எரிபொருள் நெருக்கடி - கட்டார் எரிசக்தி துறை அதிகாரிகளுடன் காஞ்சன விஜேசேகர கலந்துரையாடல்",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Sri Lanka's fuel crisis - Kanzana Wijesekera talks with Qatari energy officials",
      "author": "T Yuwaraj",
      "body_lines": [
        "Energy Minister Kansana Wijesekera has held discussions with key officials in Qatar's energy sector on resolving the fuel crisis in Sri Lanka.",
        "Chad Sheridan, Minister of State for Energy and Head of Qatar Energy and Chief Executive, met with Sheridan al-Kabi today.",
        "He added that discussions were held on supplying petroleum products, liquefied petroleum gas (LPG) and liquefied natural gas (LNG) to Sri Lanka to overcome the fuel crisis.",
        "The Minister also said that the discussion was aimed at overcoming Sri Lanka's energy crisis with the assistance of the Qatar Energy and Qatar Development Fund.",
        "In this context, it is noteworthy that Minister Kanchana Wijesekera accompanied by Environment Minister Nasir Ahmed left for Qatar this morning."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Sri Lanka's",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "Qatari",
          "label": "NORP"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Kansana Wijesekera",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Qatar",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Chad Sheridan",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Qatar Energy",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sheridan al-Kabi",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "LPG",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "LNG",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka's",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Qatar Energy",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Qatar Development Fund",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Kanchana Wijesekera",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Nasir Ahmed",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Qatar",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "this morning",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ ඉන්ධන අර්බුදය - කන්සානා විජේසේකර කටාර් බලශක්ති නිලධාරීන් සමඟ සාකච්ඡා කරයි",
      "author": "ටී යුවරාජ්",
      "body_lines": [
        "ශ‍්‍රී ලංකාවේ ඉන්ධන අර්බුදය විසඳීම සම්බන්ධයෙන් බලශක්ති අමාත්‍ය කංසානා විජේසේකර කටාර් බලශක්ති ක්ෂේත්‍රයේ ප්‍රධාන නිලධාරීන් සමඟ සාකච්ඡා කර තිබේ.",
        "බලශක්ති රාජ්‍ය අමාත්‍ය සහ කටාර් බලශක්ති ප්‍රධානී සහ ප්‍රධාන විධායක Chad Sheridan අද Sheridan al-Kabi හමුවිය.",
        "ඉන්ධන අර්බුදයෙන් ගොඩ ඒම සඳහා ශ්‍රී ලංකාවට ඛනිජ තෙල් නිෂ්පාදන, ද්‍රව පෙට්‍රෝලියම් වායු (LPG) සහ ද්‍රව ස්වභාවික වායු (LNG) සැපයීම පිළිබඳව සාකච්ඡා කළ බවද ඔහු පැවසීය.",
        "කටාර් බලශක්ති සහ කටාර් සංවර්ධන අරමුදලේ සහාය ඇතිව ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ බලශක්ති අර්බුදයෙන් මිදීම මෙම සාකච්ඡාවේ අරමුණ වී ඇති බව ද අමාත්‍යවරයා පැවසීය.",
        "මේ තත්ත්වය යටතේ පරිසර අමාත්‍ය නසීර් අහමඩ් ද කැටුව අමාත්‍ය කාංචන විජේසේකර අද පෙරවරුවේ කටාර් බලා පිටත්ව යාම විශේෂත්වයක්."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "කටාර්",
          "label": "NORP"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "කංසානා විජේසේකර",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "කටාර්",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "චැඩ් ෂෙරිඩන්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "කටාර් බලශක්ති",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ෂෙරිඩන් අල්-කබි",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "එල්.පී.ජී",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "එල්එන්ජී",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "කටාර් බලශක්තිය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "කටාර් සංවර්ධන අරමුදල",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "කාංචන විජේසේකර",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "නසීර් අහමඩ්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "කටාර්",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මේ උදෑසන",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "இலங்கையின் எரிபொருள் நெருக்கடி - கட்டார் எரிசக்தி துறை அதிகாரிகளுடன் காஞ்சன விஜேசேகர கலந்துரையாடல்",
      "author": "T Yuwaraj",
      "body_lines": [
        "இலங்கையின் எரிபொருள் நெருக்கடிக்கு தீர்வு காண்பது தொடர்பாக எரிசக்தி அமைச்சர் காஞ்சன விஜேசேகர கட்டாரின் எரிசக்தி துறையின் முக்கிய அதிகாரிகளுடன் கலந்துரையாடியுள்ளார்.",
        "எரிசக்தி விவகார இராஜாங்க அமைச்சரும் கட்டார் எரிசக்தியின் தலைவரும், பிரதம நிறைவேற்று அதிகாரியுமான சாட் ஷெரிடா அல்-காபியை இன்று சந்தித்துள்ளார்.",
        "இதன்போது எரிபொருள் நெருக்கடியை சமாளிக்க இலங்கைக்கு பெட்ரோலிய பொருட்கள், திரவமாக்கப்பட்ட பெற்றோலிய வாயு (LPG), மற்றும் திரவ இயற்கை எரிவாயு (LNG) வழங்குவது குறித்து கலந்துரையாடப்பட்டதாக அவர் மேலும் கூறினார்.",
        "அத்தோடு, கட்டார் எரிசக்தி மற்றும் கட்டார் அபிவிருத்தி நிதியத்தின் உதவியுடன் இலங்கையின் எரிசக்தி நெருக்கடியை சமாளிக்கும் நோக்கில் இந்த கலந்துரையாடல் இடம்பெற்றதாக அமைச்சர் கூறினார்.",
        "இந்நிலையில், சுற்றாடல் அமைச்சர் நசீர் அஹமட்டுடன் அமைச்சர் காஞ்சன விஜேசேகர இன்று அதிகாலை கட்டார் நோக்கிச் சென்றமை குறிப்பிடத்தக்கது."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "இலங்கையின்",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "கத்தார்",
          "label": "NORP"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "காஞ்சனா விஜேசேகர",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "கத்தார்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "சாட் ஷெரிடன்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "கத்தார் ஆற்றல்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஷெரிடன் அல்-கபி",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "எல்.பி.ஜி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "எல்என்ஜி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கையின்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "கத்தார் ஆற்றல்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "கத்தார் மேம்பாட்டு நிதி",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "காஞ்சனா விஜேசேகர",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "நசீர் அகமது",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "கத்தார்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று காலை",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}