{
  "newspaper_id": "lankadeepa-lk",
  "url": "https://www.lankadeepa.lk/latest_news/යූ-එන්-සැසියට-පිරිස-අඩු-කරන්න/1-618478",
  "time_ut": 1661070098,
  "original_lang": "si",
  "original_title": "යූ.එන් සැසියට පිරිස අඩු කරන්න",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Reduce the number of people in the UN session",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "Due to the resurgence of the Covid disease in New York City, the United Nations has informed its 193 member states to limit the number of delegates participating in the 77th session of the United Nations General Assembly starting on September 20 to between 3 and 5.",
        "The United Nations stated that the number of delegates should be between 3 and 5, especially in the United Nations headquarters and when political leaders meet and discuss face to face.",
        "Sunday Times pointed out that the most important question is whether the president, the foreign minister or the ambassador will represent Sri Lanka in the 77th session of the United Nations General Assembly.",
        "The Sunday Times newspaper reported that usually 132 delegates from Sri Lanka participate in a United Nations General Assembly session.",
        "Most of them participate as representatives in order to take a vacation with the public's tax money and they spend time visiting tourist attractions, buying goods with discounts from Sri Lankan businessmen in America and spending time whitewashing or visiting their relatives and friends in America. The Sunday Times pointed out.",
        "The newspaper also stated that if Sri Lanka decided to have a large group of delegates participate this year as well, it is not possible to tell how many of those delegations requested political asylum from the United States of America."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "UN",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Covid",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "New York City",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the United Nations",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "193",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "77th",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "the United Nations General Assembly",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "September 20 to between 3 and 5",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "The United Nations",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "between 3 and 5",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "United Nations",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sunday Times",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "77th",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "the United Nations General Assembly",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sunday Times",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "132",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "United Nations General Assembly",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lankan",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "America",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "America",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "The Sunday Times",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "this year",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the United States of America",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "යූ.එන් සැසියට පිරිස අඩු කරන්න",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "නිව් යෝර්ක් නගරයේ කොවිඩ් රෝගය නැවත හිස එසවීම හේතුවෙන් සැප්තැම්බර් 20 වෙනිදා ආරම්භ වන එක්සත් ජාතීන්ගේ මහා සම්මේලනයේ 77 වෙනි සැසිවාරයට සහභාගී වන නියෝජිතයන් පිරිස 3 ත් 5 ත් අතර ප්‍රමාණයකට සීමා කරන ලෙස එක්සත් ජාතීන්ගේ සංවිධානය තම සාමාජික රටවල් 193ට දැනුම් දුන්නේය.",
        "විශේෂයෙන් එක්සත් ජාතීන්ගේ මූලස්ථානය තුලදී සහ දේශපාලන නායකයින් මුහුණට මුහුණ හමුවී සාකච්ඡා කරන අවස්ථාවේ නියෝජිතයන් පිරිස 3 ත් 5ත් අතර විය යුතු බව එක්සත් ජාතීන්ගේ සංවිධානය ප්‍රකාශ කළේය.",
        "වැදගත්ම ප්‍රශ්නය නම් මෙවර එක්සත් ජාතීන්ගේ මහා සම්මේලනයේ 77 වෙනි සැසිවාරයේ ශ්‍රී ලංකාව නියෝජනය කරන්නේ ජනාධිපතිවරයාද,විදේශ කටයුතු අමාත්‍යවරයාද එසේත් නැතිනම් තානාපතිවරයාද යන වග සන්ඩේ ටයිම්ස් පුවත්පත පෙන්වා දුන්නේය.",
        "සාමාන්‍යයෙන් එක්සත් ජාතීන්ගේ මහා සම්මේලන සැසිවාරයක් සඳහා ශ්‍රී ලංකාවෙන් නියෝජිතයින් 132 ක් පමණ සහභාගී වන බව සන්ඩේ ටයිම්ස් පුවත්පත වාර්තා කළේය.",
        "ඉන් වැඩි පිරිස මහජනයාගේ බදු මුදල්වලින් නිවාඩුවක් ගත කිරීම පිණිස නියෝජිතයින් ලෙස සහභාගී වන බවත් ඔවුන් සංචාරක ආකර්ෂණය දිනාගත් ස්ථාන නරඹමින්,ඇමෙරිකාවේ සිටින ශ්‍රී ලාංකික ව්‍යාපාරිකයින්ගෙන් වට්ටම් සහිතව භාණ්ඩ මිලදී ගනිමින් සහ සුදු කෙළිමින් කල් ගත කරන බවත් එසේත් නැතිනම් ඇමෙරිකාවේ සිටින තම නෑදෑයින්,මිත්‍රයින් බැහැදැකීමට යන බවත් සන්ඩේ ටයිම්ස් පුවත්පත පෙන්වා දුන්නේය.",
        "මෙම වසරේත් එසේ විශාල නියෝජිතයින් පිරිසක් සහභාගී කරවීමට ශ්‍රී ලංකාව තීරණය කළහොත් එම නියෝජිත පිරිසෙන් කොපමණක් ඇමෙරිකා එක්සත් ජනපදයෙන් දේශපාලන රැකවරණ ඉල්ලා සිටි දැයි කිව නොහැකි බවට හාස්‍ය උපද්දවන සටහනක් සමාජ මාධ්‍යයන්හි සැරිසරන බවද එම පුවත්පත ප්‍රකාශ කළේය."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "එ.ජා",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "කොවිඩ්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "නිව් යෝර්ක් නගරය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "එක්සත් ජාතීන්ගේ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "193",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "77 වැනි",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "එක්සත් ජාතීන්ගේ මහා මණ්ඩලය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "සැප්තැම්බර් 20 සිට 3 සහ 5 අතර",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "එක්සත් ජාතීන්ගේ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "3 සහ 5 අතර",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "එක්සත් ජාතීන්",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ඉරිදා ටයිම්ස්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "77 වැනි",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "එක්සත් ජාතීන්ගේ මහා මණ්ඩලය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ඉරිදා ටයිම්ස්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "132",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "එක්සත් ජාතීන්ගේ මහා මණ්ඩලය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලාංකික",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඇමරිකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඇමරිකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "සන්ඩේ ටයිම්ස්",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මේ වසරේ",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඇමරිකා එක්සත් ජනපදය",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "ஐநா அமர்வில் மக்கள் எண்ணிக்கையை குறைக்கவும்",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "நியூயார்க் நகரில் கோவிட் நோய் மீண்டும் தலைதூக்கியுள்ளதால், செப்டம்பர் 20ஆம் தேதி தொடங்கும் ஐக்கிய நாடுகள் பொதுச் சபையின் 77வது அமர்வில் பங்கேற்கும் பிரதிநிதிகளின் எண்ணிக்கையை 3 முதல் 5 வரை கட்டுப்படுத்துமாறு ஐக்கிய நாடுகள் சபை தனது 193 உறுப்பு நாடுகளுக்கு அறிவித்துள்ளது.",
        "குறிப்பாக ஐக்கிய நாடுகள் சபையின் தலைமையகம் மற்றும் அரசியல் தலைவர்கள் நேருக்கு நேர் சந்தித்து கலந்துரையாடும் போது பிரதிநிதிகளின் எண்ணிக்கை 3 முதல் 5 வரை இருக்க வேண்டும் என ஐக்கிய நாடுகள் சபை தெரிவித்துள்ளது.",
        "ஐக்கிய நாடுகள் பொதுச் சபையின் 77வது அமர்வில் இலங்கையை பிரதிநிதித்துவப்படுத்துவது ஜனாதிபதியா, வெளிவிவகார அமைச்சரா அல்லது தூதுவரா என்பது மிக முக்கியமான கேள்வியாக சண்டே டைம்ஸ் சுட்டிக்காட்டியுள்ளது.",
        "ஐக்கிய நாடுகளின் பொதுச் சபை அமர்வில் பொதுவாக இலங்கையிலிருந்து 132 பிரதிநிதிகள் பங்கேற்பதாக சண்டே டைம்ஸ் செய்தித்தாள் தெரிவித்துள்ளது.",
        "அவர்களில் பெரும்பாலோர் பொதுமக்களின் வரிப்பணத்தில் விடுமுறை எடுப்பதற்காகப் பிரதிநிதிகளாகப் பங்கேற்பதுடன், சுற்றுலாத் தலங்களுக்குச் செல்வதிலும், அமெரிக்காவில் உள்ள இலங்கைத் தொழிலதிபர்களிடம் தள்ளுபடியில் பொருட்களை வாங்குவதிலும், வெள்ளையடித்தல் அல்லது அமெரிக்காவில் உள்ள உறவினர்கள், நண்பர்களைப் பார்ப்பதிலும் நேரத்தைச் செலவிடுகிறார்கள். டைம்ஸ் சுட்டிக்காட்டியுள்ளது.",
        "இந்த வருடமும் இலங்கை பிரதிநிதிகள் குழுவொன்றை பங்கேற்க வைக்க தீர்மானித்திருந்தால், அதில் எத்தனை பிரதிநிதிகள் அமெரிக்காவிடம் அரசியல் தஞ்சம் கோரியிருந்தனர் என்பதை கூற முடியாது எனவும் அந்த செய்தித்தாள் குறிப்பிட்டுள்ளது."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ஐ.நா",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "கோவிட்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "நியூயார்க் நகரம்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஐக்கிய நாடுகள்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "193",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "77வது",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஐக்கிய நாடுகளின் பொதுச் சபை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "செப்டம்பர் 20 முதல் 3 முதல் 5 வரை",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஐக்கிய நாடுகள்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "3 மற்றும் 5 இடையே",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஐக்கிய நாடுகள்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "சண்டே டைம்ஸ்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "77வது",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஐக்கிய நாடுகளின் பொதுச் சபை",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "சண்டே டைம்ஸ்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "132",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஐக்கிய நாடுகளின் பொதுச் சபை",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "அமெரிக்கா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "அமெரிக்கா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "தி சண்டே டைம்ஸ்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்த வருடம்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஐக்கிய அமெரிக்கா",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}