{
  "newspaper_id": "ada-lk",
  "url": "https://www.ada.lk/breaking_news/රාජ්‍ය-අමාත්‍යවරු-පත්කළත්-මුදල්-වෙන්-කිරීමක්-නෑ/11-396886",
  "time_ut": 1662345925,
  "original_lang": "si",
  "original_title": "රාජ්‍ය අමාත්‍යවරු පත්කළත් මුදල් වෙන් කිරීමක් නෑ",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Even if the state ministers are appointed, there is no allocation of money",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "It is reported through the sources of the ruling party that the appointment of state ministers is likely to take place tomorrow (6th). Accordingly, about 35 state ministers are to be appointed and it is reported that the party has submitted to the President a list of the names of the MPs nominated by the Sri Lanka Podujana Peramuna for the position of state ministers.",
        "It is stated that although the State Ministers are appointed, it has been decided not to gazette their respective scopes this time and that the State Minister should work under the Ministry belonging to his Cabinet Minister.",
        "It is reported that a Secretary of the State Ministry will be appointed, but it is planned not to make a separate allocation of money for the State Ministry, and to carry out the activities of the State Ministry under the Ministry's budget.",
        "Government sources also state that the appointment of a permanent cabinet will be delayed for another seven to two years.",
        "According to government sources, the opposition to some of the names submitted by the Sri Lanka Podujana Peramuna for cabinet ministerships has caused the delay in the appointment of this cabinet.",
        "However, it is reported that there will be no change in the positions of the current 18 ministers and only new cabinet ministers will join the cabinet."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "tomorrow",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "6th",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "about 35",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "Podujana Peramuna",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the State Ministers",
            "label": "EVENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "State",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Cabinet",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the State Ministry",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the State Ministry",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the State Ministry",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "another seven to two years",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "Podujana Peramuna",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "18",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "රාජ්‍ය අමාත්‍යවරු පත්කළත් මුදල් වෙන් කිරීමක් නෑ",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "රාජ්‍ය අමාත්‍යවරුන් පත්කිරීම හෙට (06දා) දිනයේ සිදුවිමට ඉඩ ඇති බව ආණ්ඩු පක්ෂයේ ආරංචි මාර්ග ඔස්සේ වාර්තා වෙයි. ඒ් අනුව රාජ්‍ය අමාත්‍යවරු 35 දෙනෙකු පමණ පත්කිරීමට නියමිත අතර ශ්‍රී ලංකා පොදුජන පෙරමුණෙන් රාජ්‍ය අමාත්‍යධුර සඳහා නම් කරන මන්ත්‍රීවරුන්ගේ නම් ලැයිස්තුවක් එම පක්ෂය විසින් ජනපතිවරයාට ඉදිරිපත් කර ඇති බව වාර්තා වෙයි.",
        "රාජ්‍ය අමාත්‍යවරු පත්කළද ඔවුනට අදාළ විෂය පථයන් ගැසට් කිරීමක් මෙවර සිදු නොකිරීමට තීරණය කර ඇති බවත් රාජ්‍ය අමාත්‍යවරයා තම කැබිනට් අමාත්‍යවරයාට අයත් අමාත්‍යාංශය යටතේ කටයුතු කළයුතු බවත් සඳහන් වෙයි.",
        "රාජ්‍ය අමාත්‍යාංශ ලේකම්වයෙක් පත්කරන නමුත් රාජ්‍ය අමාත්‍යාංශය වෙනුවෙන් වෙනම මුදල් වෙන්කිරීමක් සිදු නොකිරිමටත්, අමාත්‍යාංශ‌යේ වැය ශිර්ස්‍ය යටතේම රාජ්‍ය අමාත්‍යාංශයේ කටයුතු සිදුකිරිමටත් සැලසුම් කර ඇති බව වාර්තා වෙයි.",
        "ස්තිර කැබිනට් මණ්ඩලයක් පත්කිරීම තවත් සත් දෙකකින් පමණ කල් යනු ඇතැයිද රජ‌යේ ආරංචි මාර්ග සඳහන් කරයි.",
        "කැබිනට් අමාත්‍යධුර සඳහා ශ්‍රී ලංකා පොදුජන පෙරමුණෙන් ඉදිරිපත් කර ඇති නම් ලැයිස්තුවේ ඇති කිහිපදෙනෙකු සම්බන්ධයෙන් පවතින විරෝධය මෙම අමාත්‍ය මණ්ඩලය පත්කිරීම ප්‍රමාද විමට හේතු වී ඇතැයි රජයේ ආරංචි මාර්ග සඳහන් කරයි.",
        "කෙසේ නමුත් දැනට කටයුතු කරන අමාත්‍යවරුන් 18 දෙනාගේ ධුරයන්හි වෙනසක් සිදු නොවන බවත් නව කැබිනට් අමාත්‍යවරුන් ඇමති මණ්ඩලයට එකතුවීම පමණක් සිදුවන බවත් වාර්තා වෙයි."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "හෙට",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "6 වැනි",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "35 පමණ",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "පොදුජන පෙරමුණ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "රාජ්ය ඇමතිවරුන්",
            "label": "EVENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "රජයේ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "මණ්ඩල",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "රාජ්ය අමාත්යාංශය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "රාජ්ය අමාත්යාංශය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "රාජ්ය අමාත්යාංශය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "තවත් අවුරුදු හතක් දෙකක්",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "පොදුජන පෙරමුණ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "18",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "மாநில அமைச்சர்களை நியமித்தாலும் பண ஒதுக்கீடு இல்லை",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "இராஜாங்க அமைச்சர்கள் நியமனம் நாளை (6ம் திகதி) இடம்பெறும் என ஆளும் கட்சி வட்டாரங்கள் மூலம் தெரிவிக்கப்படுகிறது. இதன்படி, சுமார் 35 இராஜாங்க அமைச்சர்கள் நியமிக்கப்படவுள்ளதுடன், இராஜாங்க அமைச்சர்கள் பதவிக்காக ஸ்ரீலங்கா பொதுஜன பெரமுனவினால் பரிந்துரைக்கப்பட்ட பாராளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர்களின் பெயர் பட்டியலை ஜனாதிபதியிடம் கட்சி சமர்ப்பித்துள்ளதாக தெரிவிக்கப்படுகின்றது.",
        "இராஜாங்க அமைச்சர்கள் நியமிக்கப்பட்டாலும், இம்முறை அந்தந்த நோக்கங்களை வர்த்தமானியில் வெளியிட வேண்டாம் எனவும், இராஜாங்க அமைச்சர் தனது அமைச்சரவை அமைச்சருக்கு சொந்தமான அமைச்சின் கீழ் பணியாற்ற வேண்டும் எனவும் தீர்மானிக்கப்பட்டுள்ளதாக குறிப்பிடப்படுகின்றது.",
        "இராஜாங்க அமைச்சின் செயலாளர் நியமிக்கப்படவுள்ளதாகவும், ஆனால், அரச அமைச்சுக்கென தனியாக நிதி ஒதுக்கப்படாமல், அமைச்சின் வரவு செலவுத்திட்டத்தின் கீழ் இராஜாங்க அமைச்சின் செயற்பாடுகளை மேற்கொள்ளவும் திட்டமிடப்பட்டுள்ளதாக தெரிவிக்கப்படுகிறது.",
        "நிரந்தர அமைச்சரவை நியமனம் இன்னும் ஏழு அல்லது இரண்டு வருடங்கள் தாமதமாகும் எனவும் அரசாங்க தகவல்கள் தெரிவிக்கின்றன.",
        "அமைச்சரவை அமைச்சுப் பதவிகளுக்காக ஸ்ரீலங்கா பொதுஜன பெரமுன சமர்ப்பித்த சில பெயர்களுக்கு எதிர்ப்புத் தெரிவித்தமையே இந்த அமைச்சரவை நியமனத்தில் தாமதம் ஏற்பட்டுள்ளதாக அரசாங்கத் தகவல்கள் தெரிவிக்கின்றன.",
        "எவ்வாறாயினும், தற்போதுள்ள 18 அமைச்சர்களின் பதவிகளில் மாற்றம் இல்லை எனவும் புதிய அமைச்சரவை அமைச்சர்களே அமைச்சரவையில் இணைவார்கள் எனவும் தெரிவிக்கப்படுகிறது."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "நாளை",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "6வது",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "சுமார் 35",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "பொதுஜன பெரமுன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "மாநில அமைச்சர்கள்",
            "label": "EVENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "நிலை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "மந்திரி சபை",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "மாநில அமைச்சகம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "மாநில அமைச்சகம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "மாநில அமைச்சகம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "மற்றொரு ஏழு அல்லது இரண்டு ஆண்டுகள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "பொதுஜன பெரமுன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "18",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}