{
  "newspaper_id": "virakesari-lk",
  "url": "http://www.virakesari.lk/article/131981",
  "time_ut": 1658421526,
  "original_lang": "ta",
  "original_title": "பாராளுமன்றக் கூட்டத்தொடரை முடிவுறுத்த ஜனாதிபதி தீர்மானம்",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Presidential resolution to end the parliamentary session",
      "author": "T Yuwaraj",
      "body_lines": [
        "President Ranil Wickramasinghe has decided to end the parliamentary session. Opposition leader Korada Laxman Kiriella said that he informed the party leaders about this.",
        "President Ranil Wickremesinghe is having a discussion with the party leaders after taking the oath of office at the Parliament complex today. At the same time, he mentioned that the parliamentary session will be adjourned for one day.",
        "However, Lakshman Kiriella said that it has not been announced on which date the parliamentary session will be postponed.",
        "Parliament finally convened yesterday Wednesday and after the election of the President, Speaker Mahinda Yappa Abeywardana adjourned Parliament until 10 am on the 27th. According to it, the Parliament should meet on the 27th. But the president can adjourn the parliamentary session at any time, which is the power vested in the president in the constitution.",
        "However, now that Ranil Wickramasinghe has assumed office as the new president, it has been decided to postpone the second session of the 9th Parliament by one day and start the third session in a formal manner so that the president can start the parliamentary session on a formal basis. But it has not been confirmed whether it will be adjourned after Parliament convenes on the 27th or before that, said Opposition Prime Minister Korada Lakshman Kiriella.",
        "Meanwhile, Parliament is being convened on the 27th to seek the approval of the Parliament for the emergency law. Therefore, it is expected that the parliamentary session will be adjourned by the President after the 27th."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickramasinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Korada Laxman Kiriella",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "one day",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Kiriella",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "yesterday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Wednesday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Mahinda Yappa Abeywardana",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "10 am on the 27th",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the 27th",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickramasinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "second",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "one day",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "third",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Opposition",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Korada Lakshman Kiriella",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the 27th",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "පාර්ලිමේන්තු සැසිවාරය අවසන් කිරීමට ජනපතිගේ යෝජනාව",
      "author": "ටී යුවරාජ්",
      "body_lines": [
        "පාර්ලිමේන්තු සැසිවාරය අවසන් කිරීමට ජනාධිපති රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතා තීරණය කර තිබේ. විපක්ෂ නායක කොරද ලක්ෂ්මන් කිරිඇල්ල මහතා පැවසුවේ තමන් මේ පිළිබඳව පක්ෂ නායකයින් දැනුවත් කළ බවයි.",
        "ජනාධිපති රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතා අද පාර්ලිමේන්තු සංකීර්ණයේදී දිවුරුම් දීමෙන් අනතුරුව පක්ෂ නායකයින් සමඟ සාකච්ඡාවක නිරත වනවා. ඒ සමගම පාර්ලිමේන්තු සැසිවාරය දිනකට කල් තබන බවද ඔහු සඳහන් කළා.",
        "කෙසේ වෙතත්, පාර්ලිමේන්තු සැසිවාරය කුමන දිනක කල් දමනු ඇත්ද යන්න මෙතෙක් ප්‍රකාශ කර නොමැති බව ලක්ෂ්මන් කිරිඇල්ල මහතා පැවසීය.",
        "අවසානයේ පාර්ලිමේන්තුව ඊයේ බදාදා රැස් වූ අතර ජනාධිපතිවරයා තෝරා පත් කර ගැනීමෙන් පසු කථානායක මහින්ද යාප්පා අබේවර්ධන මහතා විසින් පාර්ලිමේන්තුව ලබන 27 වැනිදා පෙරවරු 10 දක්වා කල් තැබීය. ඒ අනුව ලබන 27 වැනිදා පාර්ලිමේන්තුව රැස්විය යුතුයි. එහෙත් ජනාධිපතිවරයාට ඕනෑම අවස්ථාවක පාර්ලිමේන්තු සැසිවාරය කල් තැබිය හැකි අතර එය ව්‍යවස්ථාවෙන් ජනාධිපතිවරයාට පැවරී ඇති බලයයි.",
        "කෙසේ වෙතත්, දැන් නව ජනාධිපතිවරයා ලෙස රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතා වැඩ භාරගැනීමත් සමඟ 9 වැනි පාර්ලිමේන්තුවේ දෙවැනි සැසිවාරය එක් දිනකින් කල් දමා තුන්වැනි සැසිවාරය විධිමත් ලෙස ආරම්භ කිරීමට තීරණය කර ඇති අතර එමඟින් ජනාධිපතිවරයාට පාර්ලිමේන්තු සැසිවාරය එ. විධිමත් පදනමක්. නමුත් එය 27 වැනිදා පාර්ලිමේන්තුව රැස්වීමෙන් පසුවද ඊට පෙර කල්දමන්නේද යන්න තහවුරු වී නොමැති බව විපක්ෂ අග්‍රාමාත්‍ය කෝරද ලක්ෂ්මන් කිරිඇල්ල මහතා පැවසීය.",
        "මේ අතර හදිසි නීතිය සඳහා පාර්ලිමේන්තුවේ අනුමැතිය ලබාගැනීම සඳහා ලබන 27 වැනිදා පාර්ලිමේන්තුව කැඳවනවා. එබැවින් 27 වැනිදායින් පසු ජනාධිපතිවරයා විසින් පාර්ලිමේන්තු සැසිවාරය කල්තැබෙනු ඇතැයි අපේක්ෂා කෙරේ."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "කෝරද ලක්ෂ්මන් කිරිඇල්ල",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "එක දවසක්",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "කිරිඇල්ල",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඊයේ",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "බදාදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මහින්ද යාප්පා අබේවර්ධන",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "27 වැනිදා පෙ.ව",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "27 වෙනිදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "දෙවැනි",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "එක දවසක්",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "තෙවන",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "විපක්ෂ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "කොරද ලක්ෂ්මන් කිරිඇල්ල",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "27 වෙනිදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "பாராளுமன்றக் கூட்டத்தொடரை முடிவுறுத்த ஜனாதிபதி தீர்மானம்",
      "author": "T Yuwaraj",
      "body_lines": [
        "பாராளுமன்ற கூட்டத்தொரை முடிவுறுத்த  ஜனாதிபதி ரணில் விக்ரமசிங்க தீர்மானித்துள்ளார். கட்சித் தலைவர்களுக்கு இதுதொடர்பாக அறிவித்ததாக எதிர்க்கட்சி பிரதம கொரடா லக்ஷ்மன் கிரியெல்ல தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "ஜனாதிபதி ரணில் விக்ரமசிங்க இன்று பாராளுமன்ற வளாகத்தில் பதவிப்பிரமாணம் செய்துகொண்ட பின்னர் அங்கிருந்த கட்சித் தலைவர்களுடன் கலந்துரையாடி இருக்கின்றார். இதன்போதே பாராளுமன்ற கூட்டத்தொரை ஒரு தினத்துக்கு ஒத்திவைப்பதாக குறிப்பிட்டுள்ளார்.",
        "என்றாலும் பாராளுமன்ற கூட்டத்தொடரை எந்த தினத்தில் ஒத்திவைக்கப்படும் என அறிவிக்கப்படவில்லை எனவும் லக்ஷ்மன் கிரியெல்ல தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "பாராளுமன்றம் இறுதியாக நேற்று புதன்கிழமை கூடி, ஜனாதிபதி தெரிவு இடம்பெற்றதன் பின்னர் சபாநாயகர் மஹிந்த யாப்பா அபேவர்த்தன பாராளுமன்றத்தை எதிர்வரும் 27ஆம் திகதி காலை 10மணி வரை ஒத்திவைத்தார். அதன் பிரகாரம் எதிர்வரும் 27ஆம் திகதி பாராளுமன்றம் கூடவேண்டும். ஆனால் அரசியலமைப்பில் ஜனாதிபதிக்கு இருக்கும் அதிகாரத்துக்கமைய பாராளுமன்ற கூட்டத்தொடரை எந்த வேளையும் ஜனாதிபதியால் ஒத்திவைக்க முடியும்.",
        "இருந்தபோதும் தற்போது புதிய ஜனாதிபதியாக ரணில் விக்ரமசிங்க பதவி ஏற்றுள்ள நிலையில், சம்பிரதாய அடிப்படையில் ஜனாதிபதியினால் பாராளுமன்ற கூட்டத்தொடர் ஆரம்பித்து வைக்கும் வகையில்,  9ஆவது பாராளுமன்றத்தின் இரண்டாவது கூட்டத்தொடரை  ஒரு தினத்துக்கு ஒத்திவைத்து மூன்றாவது கூட்டத்தொரை சம்பிரதாய முறைப்படி ஆரம்பித்துவைக்க தீர்மானிக்கப்பட்டிருக்கின்றது. ஆனால் இது எதிர்வரும் 27ஆம் திகதி பாராளுமன்றம் கூடிய பின்னர் ஒத்திவைக்கப்படுமா அல்லது அதற்கு முன்னர் ஒத்திவைக்கப்படுமா என உறுதியாக தெரிவிக்கப்படவில்லை எனவும் எதிர்க்கட்சி பிரதம கொரடா லக்ஷ்மன் கிரியெல்ல தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "இதேவேளை, அவசரகால சட்டத்துக்கு பாராளுமன்றத்தின் அனுமதியை பெற்றுக்கொள்ளும் நோக்கிலே எதிர்வரும் 27ஆம் திகதி பாராளுமன்றம் கூட்டப்படுகின்றது. அதனால் பெரும்பாலும் 27ஆம் திகதிக்கு பின்னரே ஜனாதிபதியால் பாராளுமன்ற கூட்டத்தொடர் ஒத்திவைக்கப்படும் என எதிர்பார்க்கப்படுகின்றது."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "கொறடா லக்ஸ்மன் கிரியெல்ல",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஒரு நாள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "கிரியெல்ல",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "நேற்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "புதன்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "மஹிந்த யாப்பா அபேவர்தன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "27ம் தேதி காலை 10 மணி",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "27 ஆம் தேதி",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இரண்டாவது",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஒரு நாள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "மூன்றாவது",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "எதிர்ப்பு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "கொறடா லக்ஷ்மன் கிரியெல்ல",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "27 ஆம் தேதி",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}