{
  "newspaper_id": "ada-lk",
  "url": "https://www.ada.lk/breaking_news/පෙට්‍රල්-ඉල්ලූ-දෙදරු-පියාට-පොලිසියෙන්-ප්‍රහාරයක්/11-395750",
  "time_ut": 1658818285,
  "original_lang": "si",
  "original_title": "පෙට්‍රල් ඉල්ලූ දෙදරු පියාට පොලිසියෙන් ප්‍රහාරයක්",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "The father of two who asked for petrol was attacked by the police",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "A hospital spokesperson said that a father of two children was admitted to the Panadura Basic Hospital yesterday afternoon (25th) after he was brutally assaulted by the police after a conversation with the police asking for petrol.",
        "Samantha Rajapaksa, a 49-year-old father of two, a resident of Wavulugala, Maggona, was assaulted and taken to hospital.",
        "Bruises, scratches and swelling injuries could be seen in about 15 places including his ankle, buttocks, feet, shoulder, sandalwood, lip and near the ear.",
        "His 14-year-old son, who is being treated in Panadura Base Hospital, was seen holding the parcel of rice brought to his father and crying with tears in his eyes.",
        "I am a taxi driver. Maggona was in the queue at Sipetco filling station since 20th, there was no petrol in the filling station. But on the night of the 24th, a police jeep was parked to cover the pump and got petrol for cans and other motorcycles. I also asked for 2 liters of oil. Later, the police beat me and put me in the jeep and took me to the Payagala police station and brutally beat me.",
        "Later that night, two police officers took me out of the cell, handcuffed me to the teeth, and kicked me with a stick and hand. I have about 20 wounds on my body.",
        "Yesterday evening (25th), I was granted bail after being presented before the Kalutara Magistrate under the charge of being an unlawful mass in the cell.",
        "In this regard, he has also complained to the Panadura Human Rights Office. Panadura Hospital Police took statements."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "two",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "two",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Panadura Basic Hospital",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "yesterday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "afternoon",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "25th",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Samantha Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "49-year-old",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "two",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Wavulugala",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Maggona",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "about 15",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "14-year-old",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Panadura Base Hospital",
            "label": "FAC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Maggona",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sipetco",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "20th",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "the night of the 24th",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "2",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Payagala",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "two",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "about 20",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Yesterday evening",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "25th",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Kalutara Magistrate",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the Panadura Human Rights Office",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Panadura Hospital Police",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "පෙට්‍රල් ඉල්ලූ දෙදරු පියාට පොලිසියෙන් ප්‍රහාරයක්",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "පෙට්‍රල් ඉල්ලා පොලිසිය සමග ඇතිවූ කතාබහකින් පසු පොලිසියේ අමානුෂික පහරදීමක්  හේතුවෙන් ශරීරයේ ස්ථාන  15 කට පමණ තුවාල සිදු වූ දෙදරු පියෙකු පානදුර මූලික රෝහලට ඊයේ (25දා) පස්වරුවේ ඇතුලත් වූ බව රෝහල් ප්‍රකාශයකයෙක් පැවසීය .",
        "මෙසේ පහරකෑමට ලක්ව රෝහල් ගතකර ඇත්තේ මග්ගොන , වවුලුගල ප්‍රදේශයේ පදිංචි සමන්ත රාජපක්ෂ නමැති 49 දෙදරු පියෙකි.",
        "ඔහුගේ තුනටිය, තට්ටම, පාද, උරහිස, වැලිමිට, තොල සහ කන අසල ඇතුළු ස්ථාන 15 ක පමණ තැලීම් සීරිම් සහ ඉදිමීම් තුවාල දැකගත හැකිවිය .",
        "පානදුර මූලික රෝහලේහි  නේවාසිකව ප්‍රතිකාර ලබන සමන්ත රාජපක්ෂ මහතා අසල ඔහුගේ 14  හැවිරිදි වියේ පසුවන පුතු පියාට රැගෙන ආ බත් පාර්සලය ඇතැතිව කදුළු පිරි දෙනතින් ඉකිගසන අයුරුද දැකගත හැකිවිය.",
        "මම කුලී ත්‍රීරෝද රථ රියදුරෙක්. 20 දා සිට මග්ගොන සිපෙට්කෝ පිරවුම්හලේ පෝලිමේ සිටියා , පිරවුම්හලේ පෙට්‍රල්  තිබුනේ නෑ. ඒත් 24දා රාත්‍රි පොලිස් ජීප් රථයක් පොම්පය ආවරණය වන පරිදි නවතා කෑන් වලට සහ තවත් යතුරුපැදි වලට පෙට්‍රල් ලබාගත්තා. මමත් තෙල් ලීටර් 2 ක් හෝ ඉල්ලුවා.   පසුව පොලිසිය මට පහරදී ජීප් රථයට නංවාගෙන පයාගල පොලිසියට රැගෙන විත්  අමානුෂික ලෙස පහර දුන්නා.",
        "පසුව රාත්‍රි පොලිස් නිලධාරීන් දෙදෙනෙක් මාව සිරමැදිරියෙන් ඉවතට ගෙන දැත් වලට මාංචු දමා ලීයකින් සහ අතින් පයින් පහර දුන්නා. මගේ ශරීරයේ තුවාල 20 ක් විතර තියෙනවා .",
        "සිරමැදිරියේ රදවා අයුතු ජනරාශී යන චෝදනාව යටතේ ඊයේ (25දා) සවස කළුතර මහේස්ත්‍රාත් තුමිය හමුවට  ඉදිරිපත් කිරීමෙන් පසු මට ඇප ලබාදුන්නා.",
        "මේ සම්බන්ධයෙන් ඔහු පානදුර මානව හිමිකම් කාර්යාලයටද පැමිණිලි කර තිබේ. පානදුර රෝහල් පොලිසිය ප්‍රකාශ ලබාගත්තේය."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "දෙක",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "දෙක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "පානදුර මූලික රෝහල",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඊයේ",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "දහවල්",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "25 වැනි",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "සමන්ත රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "49 හැවිරිදිය",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "දෙක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "වවුළුගල",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මග්ගොන",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "15 පමණ",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "14 හැවිරිදි",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "පානදුර මූලික රෝහල",
            "label": "FAC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "මග්ගොන",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "සිපෙට්කෝ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "20 වැනි",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "24 වෙනිදා රෑ",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "2",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "පයාගල",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "දෙක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "20 ක් පමණ",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ඊයේ සවස",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "25 වැනි",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "කළුතර මහේස්ත්‍රාත්",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "පානදුර මානව හිමිකම් කාර්යාලය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "පානදුර රෝහල් පොලිසිය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "பெற்றோல் கேட்ட இரு பிள்ளைகளின் தந்தை பொலிஸாரால் தாக்கப்பட்டுள்ளார்",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "இரண்டு பிள்ளைகளின் தந்தையொருவர் நேற்று (25) பிற்பகல், பெற்றோல் கேட்டு பொலிஸாருடன் உரையாடியதையடுத்து, பொலிஸாரால் கொடூரமான முறையில் தாக்கப்பட்டதையடுத்து, பாணந்துறை அடிப்படை வைத்தியசாலையில் அனுமதிக்கப்பட்டுள்ளதாக வைத்தியசாலைப் பேச்சாளர் தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "மகொன, வவுலுகல பகுதியைச் சேர்ந்த சமந்த ராஜபக்ஷ என்ற 49 வயதுடைய இரண்டு பிள்ளைகளின் தந்தையே தாக்கப்பட்டு வைத்தியசாலையில் அனுமதிக்கப்பட்டுள்ளார்.",
        "அவரது கணுக்கால், பிட்டம், பாதங்கள், தோள்பட்டை, சந்தனம், உதடு மற்றும் காதுக்கு அருகில் சுமார் 15 இடங்களில் காயங்கள், கீறல்கள் மற்றும் வீக்க காயங்கள் காணப்படுகின்றன.",
        "பாணந்துறை ஆதார வைத்தியசாலையில் சிகிச்சை பெற்று வரும் அவரது 14 வயது மகன் தனது தந்தைக்கு கொண்டு வந்த அரிசி பொட்டலத்தை கையில் வைத்துக்கொண்டு கண்ணீருடன் கதறி அழுதுள்ளார்.",
        "நான் ஒரு டாக்ஸி டிரைவர். கடந்த 20ம் தேதி முதல் சிபெட்கோ எரிபொருள் நிரப்பும் நிலையத்தில் பெட்ரோல் வராமல் வரிசையில் நின்று கொண்டிருந்தார். ஆனால், கடந்த 24ம் தேதி இரவு, பம்பை மூடுவதற்காக போலீஸ் ஜீப் நிறுத்தப்பட்டு, கேன் மற்றும் பிற மோட்டார் சைக்கிள்களுக்கு பெட்ரோல் கிடைத்தது. நானும் 2 லிட்டர் எண்ணெய் கேட்டேன். பின்னர், போலீசார் என்னை அடித்து ஜீப்பில் ஏற்றி, பயாகலா காவல் நிலையத்திற்கு அழைத்துச் சென்று கொடூரமாக தாக்கினர்.",
        "அன்றிரவு, இரண்டு போலீஸ் அதிகாரிகள் என்னை அறையிலிருந்து வெளியே அழைத்துச் சென்று, என்னைப் பற்களில் கைவிலங்கிட்டு, தடி மற்றும் கையால் உதைத்தனர். என் உடலில் சுமார் 20 காயங்கள் உள்ளன.",
        "நேற்று மாலை (25ஆம் திகதி), களுத்துறை நீதவான் முன்னிலையில் சட்டத்திற்குப் புறம்பாக சிறைச்சாலையில் கும்பலாக இருந்த குற்றச்சாட்டின் கீழ் ஆஜர்படுத்தப்பட்ட பின்னர் எனக்கு பிணை வழங்கப்பட்டது.",
        "இது தொடர்பில், பாணந்துறை மனித உரிமைகள் அலுவலகத்திலும் முறைப்பாடு செய்துள்ளார். பாணந்துறை வைத்தியசாலை பொலிஸார் வாக்குமூலங்களை பெற்றுக்கொண்டனர்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "இரண்டு",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "இரண்டு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாணந்துறை அடிப்படை வைத்தியசாலை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "நேற்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "பிற்பகல்",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "25 ஆம் தேதி",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "சமந்தா ராஜபக்ச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "49 வயது",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இரண்டு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "வவுலுகல",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "மகோனா",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "சுமார் 15",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "14 வயது",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாணந்துறை ஆதார வைத்தியசாலை",
            "label": "FAC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "மகோனா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சிபெட்கோ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "20வது",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "24ம் தேதி இரவு",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "2",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "பயாகலா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இரண்டு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "சுமார் 20",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "நேற்று மாலை",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "25 ஆம் தேதி",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "களுத்துறை நீதவான்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பாணந்துறை மனித உரிமைகள் அலுவலகம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாணந்துறை வைத்தியசாலை பொலிஸ்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}