{
  "newspaper_id": "lankadeepa-lk",
  "url": "https://www.lankadeepa.lk/latest_news/‘‘වත්මන්-ආණ්ඩුවට-ජනතා-හඬට-මුහුණ-දෙන්න-බෑ‘‘/1-616075",
  "time_ut": 1657275321,
  "original_lang": "si",
  "original_title": "‘‘වත්මන් ආණ්ඩුවට ජනතා හඬට මුහුණ දෙන්න බෑ‘‘",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "\"The current government cannot face the voice of the people\"",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "The National Movement for a Just Society says in a statement that by arresting Mrs. Hirunika Premachandra along with a group of women, Rehan Jayawickrama and a group of other political activists in front of the President's residence in Colombo Fort, the current government has shown to the world the level of fear it is expressing without being able to face the voice of the people.",
        "Also, the statement issued by the President of the National Movement for a Just Society Mr. Karu Jayasuriya states that the level of hatred that the government is showing towards those who stand for the real issues of the people is also well displayed and Sri Lanka's dislike for democratic rights and freedom is also displayed. .",
        "The announcement has further emphasized that the National Movement for a Fair Society strongly condemns the incident and the government must understand that the people are not silent in the face of the enormous pressure they are facing."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "The National Movement for a Just",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Society",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Hirunika Premachandra",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Rehan Jayawickrama",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Colombo Fort",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the National Movement for a Just",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Society",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Karu Jayasuriya",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka's",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the National Movement for a Fair Society",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "‘‘වත්මන් ආණ්ඩුවට ජනතා හඬට මුහුණ දෙන්න බෑ‘‘",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "හිරුණිකා ප්‍රේමචන්ද්‍ර මහත්මිය ඇතුළු කාන්තාවන් පිරිසක් ද සමග රෙහාන් ජයවික්‍රම හා තවත්ම දේශපාලන ක්‍රියාකාරීන් පිරිසක් කොළඹ කොටුව ජනාධිපති නිල නිවස ඉදිරිපිටදී අත්අඩංගුවට ගැනීම මගින් වර්තමාන ආණ්ඩුව ලොවටම ප්‍රදර්ශණය කර ඇත්තේ ජනතා හඬට මුහුණදීගත නොහැකිව පළකරමින් තිබෙන භීතියේ තරම බව සාධාරණ සමාජයක් සඳහා වන ජාතික ව්‍යාපාරය නිවේදනයක් නිකුත් කරමින් පවසයි.",
        "එසේම ජනතාවගේ සැබෑ ප්‍රශ්ණ වෙනුවෙන් පෙනී සිටින්නන් කෙරෙහි ආණ්ඩුව දක්වමින් සිටින වෛරයේ ප්‍රමාණය ද ඒ තුළින් මැනවින් ප්‍රදර්ශනය කරන බවත් ශ්‍රී ලංකාව ප්‍රජාතන්ත්‍රවාදී අයිතිවාසිකම් සහ නිදහසට දක්වන අකමැත්ත ද ඉන් ප්‍රදර්ශනය කරන බව එම සාධාරණ සමාජයක් සඳහා වන ජාතික ව්‍යාපාරයේ සභාපති කරු ජයසූරිය මහතා නිකුත් කර ඇති නිවේදනයේ සඳහන් වේ.",
        "සාධාරණ සමාජයක් සඳහා වන ජාතික ව්‍යාපාරය එම සිදුවීම තරයේ හෙළා දකින බවත් ජනතාව මුහුණ දී සිටින දැවැන්ත පීඩනය හමුවේ නිහඩව නොසිටින බව රජය තේරුම්ගත යුතු බවත් එම නිවේදනයෙන් වැඩි දුරටත් අවධාරණය කර තිබේ."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "සාධාරණයක් සඳහා වූ ජාතික ව්‍යාපාරය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "සමාජය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "හිරුණිකා ප්‍රේමචන්ද්‍ර",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "රෙහාන් ජයවික්‍රම",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "කොළඹ කොටුව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "සාධාරණයක් සඳහා වූ ජාතික ව්‍යාපාරය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "සමාජය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "කරු ජයසූරිය",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "සාධාරණ සමාජයක් සඳහා වූ ජාතික ව්‍යාපාරය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "தற்போதைய அரசாங்கத்தால் மக்களின் குரலுக்கு முகம் கொடுக்க முடியாது.",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "திருமதி ஹிருணிகா பிரேமச்சந்திர, ரெஹான் ஜயவிக்ரம மற்றும் அரசியல் செயற்பாட்டாளர்கள் சிலருடன் கொழும்பு கோட்டையில் உள்ள ஜனாதிபதியின் இல்லத்திற்கு முன்னால் வைத்து கைது செய்ததன் மூலம் தற்போதைய அரசாங்கம் அதனை வெளிப்படுத்தியுள்ளதாக நீதியான சமூகத்திற்கான தேசிய இயக்கம் விடுத்துள்ள அறிக்கையில் தெரிவிக்கப்பட்டுள்ளது. மக்களின் குரலை எதிர்கொள்ள முடியாமல் உலகம் வெளிப்படுத்தும் அச்சத்தின் நிலை.",
        "அத்துடன், மக்களின் உண்மையான பிரச்சினைகளுக்காக நிற்பவர்கள் மீது அரசாங்கம் காட்டும் வெறுப்பு நிலையும் இலங்கையின் வெறுப்புணர்ச்சியை நன்கு வெளிப்படுத்துவதாக நீதியான சமூகத்திற்கான தேசிய இயக்கத்தின் தலைவர் திரு.கரு ஜயசூரிய விடுத்துள்ள அறிக்கையில் குறிப்பிடப்பட்டுள்ளது. ஜனநாயக உரிமைகள் மற்றும் சுதந்திரத்திற்காகவும் காட்டப்படுகிறது. .",
        "இந்தச் சம்பவத்தை நியாயமான சமூகத்திற்கான தேசிய இயக்கம் வன்மையாகக் கண்டிப்பதாகவும், மக்கள் எதிர்கொள்ளும் பாரிய அழுத்தங்களுக்கு முகம் கொடுக்காமல் அமைதியாக இருப்பதை அரசாங்கம் புரிந்து கொள்ள வேண்டும் என்றும் அந்த அறிவிப்பில் மேலும் வலியுறுத்தப்பட்டுள்ளது."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "நீதிக்கான தேசிய இயக்கம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "சமூகம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஹிருணிகா பிரேமச்சந்திர",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரெஹான் ஜெயவிக்ரம",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "கொழும்பு கோட்டை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "நீதிக்கான தேசிய இயக்கம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "சமூகம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "கரு ஜயசூரிய",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கையின்",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஒரு நியாயமான சமுதாயத்திற்கான தேசிய இயக்கம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}