{
  "newspaper_id": "ada-derana-lk",
  "url": "http://www.adaderana.lk/news/84693/child-critically-injured-in-brutal-stabbing-suspect-arrested",
  "time_ut": 1662039960,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Child critically injured in brutal stabbing; suspect arrested",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Child critically injured in brutal stabbing; suspect arrested",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "The man who critically injured a child after brutally stabbing him in Badulla earlier today (Sep 01) has been placed under arrest.",
        "The suspect was taken into custody by the police and the residents of the area after tracking him down to nearby woods.",
        "According to the police, the suspect had attempted to escape while hurling stones at the group who came for his arrest. He has sustained injuries after tripping on a rock.",
        "The suspect, who is believed to be suffering from a mental illness, was subsequently admitted to the Meegahakivula Hospital for treatment.",
        "A seven-year-old boy suffered severe cut wounds to his shoulders in a brutal stabbing attack reported at a shop in Kandaketiya area of Badulla this morning.",
        "The child, who was rushed to the Badulla Provincial Hospital with critical injuries, was rescued after a 7-hour surgery.",
        "It was reported that the incident had taken place when the child visited a nearby shop last evening (Aug 31) with Rs. 100 in his hands to buy a mobile card for his father.",
        "The child’s mother says that the perpetrator may have initiated the attack demanding the money that the child was holding.",
        "Dr. Palitha Rajapaksa, the senior medical officer of Badulla Provincial Hospital’s emergency treatment unit, said the child was transferred to the Intensive Care Unit (ICU) following a successful surgery of about 7 hours.",
        "Kandeketiya police, who conducts further probes into the incident, stated it is suspected that the child was assaulted by one of his relatives."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Badulla",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "earlier today",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sep 01",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "the Meegahakivula Hospital",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "seven-year-old",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kandaketiya",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Badulla",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "this morning",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the Badulla Provincial Hospital",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "7-hour",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "last evening",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "100",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "Palitha Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Badulla Provincial Hospital’s",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Intensive Care Unit",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ICU",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "about 7 hours",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Kandeketiya",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "one",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "ම්ලේච්ඡ පිහි ඇනුමකින් බරපතළ තුවාල ලැබූ දරුවා; සැකකරු අත්අඩංගුවට",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "අද (සැප් 01) අලුයම බදුල්ලේදී කුඩා දරුවෙකුට අමානුෂික ලෙස පිහියෙන් ඇන බරපතළ තුවාල සිදු කළ පුද්ගලයා අත්අඩංගුවට ගෙන තිබේ.",
        "පොලිසිය සහ ප්‍රදේශවාසීන් එක්ව සැකකරු අසල කැලෑවට ගොස් ලුහුබැඳ ගොස් අත්අඩංගුවට ගෙන ඇත.",
        "සැකකරු අත්අඩංගුවට ගැනීමට පැමිණි පිරිසට ගල්මුල් ප්‍රහාරයක් එල්ල කරමින් සිටියදී පැන යාමට උත්සාහ කර ඇති බවයි පොලිසිය පවසන්නේ. ගලක් මත පැටලීමෙන් ඔහු තුවාල ලබා ඇත.",
        "මානසික රෝගයකින් පෙළෙන බවට සැලකෙන සැකකරු ඉන් අනතුරුව ප්‍රතිකාර සඳහා මීගහකිවුල රෝහලට ඇතුළත් කර තිබේ.",
        "බදුල්ල - කන්දකැටිය ප්‍රදේශයේ වෙළඳසැලක අද උදෑසන සිදුවූ පිහි ඇනුමකින් හත් හැවිරිදි පිරිමි දරුවෙකුගේ උරහිසට බරපතල කැපුම් තුවාල සිදුව ඇති බව වාර්තා වේ.",
        "බරපතළ තුවාල ලබා බදුල්ල පළාත් රෝහලට රැගෙන ගිය දරුවා පැය 7ක ශල්‍යකර්මයකින් පසු බේරාගෙන ඇත.",
        "මෙම දරුවා ඊයේ (අගෝස්තු 31) සවස රුපියල් 1000ක් රැගෙන අසල වෙළෙඳසලකට ගිය අවස්ථාවේදී මෙම සිද්ධිය සිදුව ඇති බව වාර්තා විය. ඔහුගේ පියාට ජංගම කාඩ්පතක් මිලදී ගැනීමට ඔහුගේ අතේ රුපියල් 100 ක්.",
        "දරුවා සන්තකයේ තිබූ මුදල් ඉල්ලා අපරාධකරු මෙම පහරදීම ආරම්භ කරන්නට ඇති බව දරුවාගේ මව පවසයි.",
        "බදුල්ල පළාත් රෝහලේ හදිසි ප්‍රතිකාර ඒකකයේ ජ්‍යෙෂ්ඨ වෛද්‍ය නිලධාරී වෛද්‍ය පාලිත රාජපක්ෂ මහතා පැවසුවේ, පැය 7ක පමණ සාර්ථක සැත්කමකින් පසු දරුවා දැඩි සත්කාර ඒකකයට (ICU) මාරු කළ බව ය.",
        "සිද්ධිය සම්බන්ධයෙන් වැඩිදුර පරීක්ෂණ පවත්වන කන්දකැටිය පොලිසිය සඳහන් කළේ දරුවාට පහර දී ඇත්තේ ඔහුගේ ඥාතියෙකු විසින් බවට සැක කරන බවයි."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "බදුල්ල",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "අද කලින්",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "සැප් 01",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "මීගහකිවුල රෝහල",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "අවුරුදු හතක් වයසැති",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "කන්දකැටිය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "බදුල්ල",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "මේ උදෑසන",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "බදුල්ල පළාත් රෝහල",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "7-පැය",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ඊයේ සවස",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "100",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "පාලිත රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "බදුල්ල පළාත් රෝහලේ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "දැඩි සත්කාර ඒකකය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "දැඩි සත්කාර ඒකකය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "පැය 7 ක් පමණ",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "කන්දෙකැටිය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "එක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "கொடூரமாக கத்தியால் குத்தியதில் குழந்தை படுகாயம்; சந்தேக நபர் கைது",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "பதுளையில் இன்று (செப். 01) முற்பகல் குழந்தையை கொடூரமாக கத்தியால் குத்தி படுகாயப்படுத்திய நபர் கைது செய்யப்பட்டுள்ளார்.",
        "சந்தேக நபரை பொலிசார் மற்றும் பிரதேசவாசிகள் அருகில் உள்ள காடுகளில் வைத்து அவரை கைது செய்துள்ளனர்.",
        "கைது செய்ய வந்த குழுவினர் மீது கற்களை வீசி சந்தேக நபர் தப்பிச் செல்ல முற்பட்டுள்ளதாக பொலிஸார் தெரிவித்துள்ளனர். பாறையில் தவறி விழுந்ததில் அவருக்கு காயம் ஏற்பட்டது.",
        "மனநலம் பாதிக்கப்பட்டவர் என நம்பப்படும் சந்தேக நபர், மீகஹகிவுல வைத்தியசாலையில் சிகிச்சைக்காக அனுமதிக்கப்பட்டுள்ளார்.",
        "பதுளை, கந்தகெட்டிய பிரதேசத்தில் உள்ள கடையொன்றில் இன்று காலை இடம்பெற்ற வாள்வெட்டுத் தாக்குதலில் ஏழு வயது சிறுவன் ஒருவன் தோள்களில் பலத்த வெட்டுக் காயங்களுக்கு உள்ளாகியுள்ளான்.",
        "பலத்த காயங்களுடன் பதுளை மாகாண வைத்தியசாலைக்கு கொண்டு செல்லப்பட்ட குழந்தை 7 மணித்தியால சத்திரசிகிச்சையின் பின்னர் மீட்கப்பட்டது.",
        "நேற்று (ஆகஸ்ட் 31) மாலை, குழந்தை ரூ.300 பணத்துடன் அருகில் உள்ள கடைக்கு சென்றபோது இந்தச் சம்பவம் நடந்துள்ளதாக தெரிவிக்கப்பட்டுள்ளது. அப்பாவுக்கு மொபைல் கார்டு வாங்க அவன் கையில் 100.",
        "குழந்தை வைத்திருந்த பணத்தைக் கோரி குற்றவாளி இந்தத் தாக்குதலைத் தொடங்கியிருக்கலாம் என்று குழந்தையின் தாய் கூறுகிறார்.",
        "பதுளை மாகாண வைத்தியசாலையின் அவசர சிகிச்சைப் பிரிவின் சிரேஷ்ட வைத்திய அதிகாரி டொக்டர் பாலித ராஜபக்ஷ, சுமார் 7 மணித்தியாலங்கள் வெற்றிகரமான சத்திரசிகிச்சைக்கு பின்னர் குழந்தை அதிதீவிர சிகிச்சைப் பிரிவுக்கு (ICU) மாற்றப்பட்டுள்ளதாக தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "சம்பவம் தொடர்பிலான மேலதிக விசாரணைகளை மேற்கொண்டு வரும் கந்தேகெட்டிய பொலிஸார், குழந்தையின் உறவினர் ஒருவரினால் தாக்கப்பட்டிருக்கலாம் என சந்தேகம் வெளியிடப்பட்டுள்ளது."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "பதுளை",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "முன்னதாக இன்று",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "செப் 01",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "மீகஹகிவுல வைத்தியசாலை",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஏழு வயது",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "கந்தகெட்டிய",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "பதுளை",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று காலை",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பதுளை மாகாண வைத்தியசாலை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "7-மணிநேரம்",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "நேற்று மாலை",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "100",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "பாலித ராஜபக்ஷ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "பதுளை மாகாண வைத்தியசாலை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "தீவிர சிகிச்சை பிரிவு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஐ.சி.யு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "சுமார் 7 மணி நேரம்",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "கண்டெகெட்டிய",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஒன்று",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}