{
  "newspaper_id": "ada-lk",
  "url": "https://www.ada.lk/breaking_news/නව-ජනපති-තිරණය-අද-පාර්ලිමේන්තුවේදී/11-395560",
  "time_ut": 1658281451,
  "original_lang": "si",
  "original_title": "නව ජනපති තිරණය අද පාර්ලිමේන්තුවේදී",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Election of the new president today in parliament",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "The election of a member of parliament for the presidency vacated by the resignation of former president Gotabhaya Rajapaksa is scheduled to begin today (20th) at 10.00 am in parliament.",
        "Acting President Ranil Wickremesinghe, leader of United National Party, Dallas Alahapperuma of Sri Lanka Podujana Peramuna, Anura Kumara Dissanayake of National People's Force are joining the presidential battle.",
        "Since there is more than one candidate for the presidency, the new president will be elected by secret ballot.",
        "Also, each party has announced the candidate they are supporting. However, since there is a secret ballot, there is also an opportunity to vote outside the party decisions.",
        "The Speaker has asked all the MPs not to record who voted for whom."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "today",
          "label": "DATE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Gotabhaya Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "20th",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "10.00",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "United National Party",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Dallas Alahapperuma",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Podujana Peramuna",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Anura",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kumara Dissanayake",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "National People's Force",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "more than one",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [],
        []
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "නව ජනපති තිරණය අද පාර්ලිමේන්තුවේදී",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "හිටපු ජනපති ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ මහතා ජනපතිධුරයෙන් ඉල්ලා අස්වීමත් සමග හිස්වූ ජනපතිධුරය සඳහා පාර්ලිමේන්තුව තුළින් මන්ත්‍රීවරයෙක් තෝරා පත්කර ගැනීම අද (20දා) පෙරවරු 10.00 පාර්ලිමේන්තුවේදී ආරම්භ කිරීමට නියමිතය.",
        "එක්සත් ජාතික පක්ෂයේ නායක වැඩබලන ජනපති රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ, ශ්‍රී ලංකා පොදුජන පෙරමුණේ ඩලස් අලහප්පෙරුම, ජාතික ජනබලවේගයේ අනුර කුමාර දිසානායක ජනපති සටනට එක්ව සිටියි.",
        "ජනපතිධුරය සඳහා එක් මන්ත්‍රීවරයෙකුට වඩා වැඩියෙන් ඉදිරිපත්ව ඇති හෙයින් රහස් ඡන්දයකින් නව ජනපති තෝරා පත්කර ගැනීමට නියමිතය.",
        "එසේම ඒ ඒ පක්ෂ මේ වන විට තම තමන් සහාය දෙන අපේක්ෂකයා කවුරුන්ද යන්න පිළිබඳව ප්‍රකාශයට පත්කර තිබේ. කෙසේ වෙතත් රහස් ඡන්දයක් පවතින හෙයින් පක්ෂ තීරණවලට පිටින් ගොස් ඡන්දය ප්‍රකාශ කිරීමේදී අවස්ථාවක්ද උදාවී තිබේ.",
        "සිය ඡන්දය භාවිත කළේ කවුරුන්ටද යන්න පටිගත කිරීමට කටයුතු නොකරන ලෙස කතානායකවරයා සියලුම මන්ත්‍රීවරුන්ගෙන් ඉල්ලා තිබේ."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "අද",
          "label": "DATE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "20 වැනි",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "10.00",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "එක්සත් ජාතික පක්ෂය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඩලස් අලහප්පෙරුම",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "පොදුජන පෙරමුණ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "අනුර",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "කුමාර දිසානායක",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජාතික ජනතා බලවේගය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "එකකට වඩා",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [],
        []
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "பாராளுமன்றத்தில் இன்று புதிய ஜனாதிபதி தேர்தல்",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "முன்னாள் ஜனாதிபதி கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்சவின் இராஜினாமாவால் வெற்றிடமடைந்த ஜனாதிபதி பதவிக்கான நாடாளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர் தேர்தல் இன்று (20ஆம் திகதி) முற்பகல் 10.00 மணிக்கு நாடாளுமன்றத்தில் ஆரம்பமாகவுள்ளது.",
        "ஐக்கிய தேசியக் கட்சியின் தலைவர் ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க, ஸ்ரீலங்கா பொதுஜன பெரமுனவின் டலஸ் அழகப்பெரும, தேசிய மக்கள் சக்தியின் அனுரகுமார திஸாநாயக்க ஆகியோர் ஜனாதிபதித் தேர்தலில் போட்டியிடுகின்றனர்.",
        "அதிபர் பதவிக்கு ஒன்றுக்கும் மேற்பட்ட வேட்பாளர்கள் இருப்பதால், ரகசிய வாக்கெடுப்பு மூலம் புதிய அதிபர் தேர்ந்தெடுக்கப்படுவார்.",
        "மேலும், ஒவ்வொரு கட்சியும் தாங்கள் ஆதரிக்கும் வேட்பாளரை அறிவித்துள்ளன. எனினும், ரகசிய வாக்கெடுப்பு நடைபெறுவதால், கட்சி முடிவுகளுக்கு புறம்பாக வாக்களிக்கவும் வாய்ப்பு உள்ளது.",
        "யார் யாருக்கு வாக்களித்தார்கள் என்பதை பதிவு செய்ய வேண்டாம் என அனைத்து எம்பிக்களையும் சபாநாயகர் கேட்டுக் கொண்டுள்ளார்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "இன்று",
          "label": "DATE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "கோத்தபாய ராஜபக்ச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "20வது",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "10.00",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஐக்கிய தேசிய கட்சி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "டலஸ் அழகப்பெரும",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "பொதுஜன பெரமுன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "அனுர",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "குமார திஸாநாயக்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "தேசிய மக்கள் படை",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஒன்றுக்கு மேற்பட்ட",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [],
        []
      ]
    }
  }
}