{
  "newspaper_id": "news-first-lk",
  "url": "https://www.newsfirst.lk/2022/08/18/ranil-basil-meeting-today-17/",
  "time_ut": 1660805100,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Ranil – Basil meeting today (17)",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Ranil – Basil meeting today (17)",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); Sri Lankan President Ranil Wickremesinghe and Former Minister Basil Rajapaksa, who is also the National Organizer of the Sri Lanka Podujana Peramuna are expected to meet on Thursday (18).",
        "A senior spokesman of the SLPP told News First that the meeting is set to take place at the President's Office.",
        "It is reported that the current situation in the country, as well as plans to implement a new government in the future, are among the topics to be discussed."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Basil",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "today",
          "label": "DATE"
        },
        {
          "text": "17",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "News 1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lankan",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Basil Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the National Organizer of the Sri Lanka",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Podujana Peramuna",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Thursday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "18",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "First",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          }
        ],
        []
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "රනිල් - බැසිල් හමුව අද (17)",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); ශ්‍රී ලංකා ජනාධිපති රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතා සහ ශ්‍රී ලංකා පොදුජන පෙරමුණේ ජාතික සංවිධායක හිටපු අමාත්‍ය බැසිල් රාජපක්ෂ මහතා බ්‍රහස්පතින්දා (18) හමුවීමට නියමිතය.",
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකා පොදුජන පෙරමුණේ ජ්‍යෙෂ්ඨ ප්‍රකාශකයෙකු නිව්ස් ෆස්ට් වෙත කියා සිටියේ මෙම හමුව ජනාධිපති කාර්යාලයේදී පැවැත්වීමට නියමිත බවයි.",
        "රටේ වත්මන් තත්ත්වය මෙන්ම ඉදිරියේදී නව රජයක් කි‍්‍රයාත්මක කිරීමට සැලසුම් කර ඇති බව ද මෙහිදී සාකච්ඡා කිරීමට නියමිත බව වාර්තා වේ."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "බැසිල්",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "අද",
          "label": "DATE"
        },
        {
          "text": "17",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "News 1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලාංකික",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "බැසිල් රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකා ජාතික සංවිධායක",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "පොදුජන පෙරමුණ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "බ්රහස්පතින්දා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "18",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "පළමුවන",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          }
        ],
        []
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "ரணில் – பசில் சந்திப்பு இன்று (17)",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); இலங்கை ஜனாதிபதி ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க மற்றும் ஸ்ரீலங்கா பொதுஜன பெரமுனவின் தேசிய அமைப்பாளரும் முன்னாள் அமைச்சருமான பசில் ராஜபக்ஷ ஆகியோர் வியாழக்கிழமை (18) சந்திப்பார்கள் என எதிர்பார்க்கப்படுகிறது.",
        "ஜனாதிபதி செயலகத்தில் இந்த சந்திப்பு இடம்பெறவுள்ளதாக ஸ்ரீலங்கா பொதுஜன பெரமுனவின் சிரேஷ்ட பேச்சாளர் ஒருவர் நியூஸ் ஃபர்ஸ்டுக்கு தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "நாட்டின் தற்போதைய நிலைமை, எதிர்காலத்தில் புதிய அரசாங்கமொன்றை அமுல்படுத்துவதற்கான திட்டங்கள் என்பனவும் இதில் கலந்துரையாடப்பட உள்ளதாகத் தெரிவிக்கப்படுகிறது."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "துளசி",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "இன்று",
          "label": "DATE"
        },
        {
          "text": "17",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "News 1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "பசில் ராஜபக்ஷ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கையின் தேசிய அமைப்பாளர்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "பொதுஜன பெரமுன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "வியாழன்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "18",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "முதலில்",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          }
        ],
        []
      ]
    }
  }
}