{
  "newspaper_id": "news-first-lk",
  "url": "https://www.newsfirst.lk/2022/07/29/chinese-research-vessel-to-hambantota/",
  "time_ut": 1659103020,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Chinese Research Vessel to Hambantota?",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Chinese Research Vessel to Hambantota?",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); India on Thursday said it was aware of reports about the planned visit of a Chinese vessel to a Sri Lankan port built with money from Beijing.",
        "However, according to The Hindu website, Sri Lanka’s Defence Ministry has denied reports that a Chinese research vessel would enter the Hambantota Port in August this year.",
        "The Hindu said that the Belt & Road Initiative Sri Lanka, a Colombo-based organization studying China’s ambitious connectivity project, on its website said that the research and survey vessel Yuan Wang 5 which set sail from the Chinese port of Jiangyin on July 13, is now in the East China Sea, and was expected to dock in Sri Lanka’s Hambantota port from August 11-17 for ‘replenishment’ while it continues to conduct Space and Satellite control and research activities in the north-western part of the Indian Ocean Region.",
        "India's foreign ministry spokesperson Arindam Bagchi told a weekly media briefing \"The government carefully monitors any developments having a bearing on India's security and economic interests, and takes all necessary measures to safeguard them,\" I",
        "The Hindu quoted a spokesperson from Sri Lanka’s Defence Ministry who denied reports that a Chinese research vessel involved in space and satellite tracking would enter the Hambantota port in August this year, even as India sent a “clear message” that it was monitoring the ship’s progress “carefully”.",
        "A Defence Ministry spokesman told The Hindu in Colombo “We have no confirmation of such a vessel calling at the Hambantota port,”",
        "India has long been worried about dual-use facilities of Chinese infrastructure projects spanning Myanmar to Eastern African states in what comes as a direct challenge to New Delhi's interests.",
        "This is the first time since 2014 that such a Chinese naval vessel is visiting Lanka. In 2014, a Chinese submarine had docked at Colombo drawing India's ire and the matter was raised at the highest level."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Chinese Research Vessel",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "Hambantota",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "News 1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "India",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Thursday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Chinese",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lankan",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "Beijing",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Hindu",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka’s",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Defence Ministry",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Chinese",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Hambantota Port",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "August this year",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Hindu",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Belt & Road Initiative Sri Lanka",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Colombo",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "China",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Yuan Wang",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Chinese",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Jiangyin",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "July 13",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the East China Sea",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "August 11-17",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Satellite",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Indian Ocean Region",
            "label": "LOC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "India",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Arindam Bagchi",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "weekly",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "India",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Hindu",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka’s",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Defence Ministry",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Chinese",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Hambantota",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "August this year",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "India",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Defence Ministry",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Hindu",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Hambantota",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "India",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Chinese",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Myanmar",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Eastern African",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "New Delhi's",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "first",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "2014",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Chinese",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "2014",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Chinese",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Colombo",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "India",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "චීන පර්යේෂණ යාත්‍රාවක් හම්බන්තොටට?",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); ඉන්දියාව බ්‍රහස්පතින්දා ප්‍රකාශ කළේ බීජිං සිට මුදලින් ඉදිකරන ලද ශ්‍රී ලංකා වරායකට චීන යාත්‍රාවක් පැමිණීමට සැලසුම් කර ඇති බවට වාර්තා වන බව තමන් දන්නා බවයි.",
        "කෙසේ වෙතත්, ද හින්දු වෙබ් අඩවියට අනුව, මේ වසරේ අගෝස්තු මාසයේදී චීන පර්යේෂණ නෞකාවක් හම්බන්තොට වරායට ඇතුළු වන බවට පළ වන වාර්තා ශ්‍රී ලංකා ආරක්ෂක අමාත්‍යාංශය ප්‍රතික්ෂේප කරයි.",
        "ද හින්දු පැවසුවේ, චීනයේ අභිලාෂකාමී සම්බන්ධතා ව්‍යාපෘතිය පිළිබඳව අධ්‍යයනය කරන කොළඹ පදනම් වූ සංවිධානයක් වන බෙල්ට් ඇන්ඩ් රෝඩ් ඉනිෂියේටිව් ශ්‍රී ලංකා සිය වෙබ් අඩවියේ සඳහන් කර ඇත්තේ ජූලි 13 වන දින චීනයේ ජියැන්ග්යින් වරායෙන් යාත්‍රා කළ පර්යේෂණ සහ සමීක්ෂණ යාත්‍රාව යුවාන් වැන්ග් 5 ය. දැන් නැගෙනහිර චීන මුහුදේ, සහ ඉන්දියන් සාගර කලාපයේ වයඹ දෙසින් අභ්‍යවකාශ සහ චන්ද්‍රිකා පාලනය සහ පර්යේෂණ කටයුතු දිගටම කරගෙන යන අතරම එය නැවත පිරවීම සඳහා අගෝස්තු 11-17 දක්වා ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ හම්බන්තොට වරායේ නැව්ගත කිරීමට බලාපොරොත්තු විය.",
        "ඉන්දියාවේ විදේශ අමාත්‍යාංශයේ ප්‍රකාශක Arindam Bagchi සතිපතා මාධ්‍ය හමුවකදී පැවසුවේ \"ඉන්දියාවේ ආරක්ෂාව සහ ආර්ථික අවශ්‍යතා කෙරෙහි බලපාන ඕනෑම වර්ධනයක් රජය හොඳින් නිරීක්ෂණය කරන අතර ඒවා ආරක්ෂා කිරීමට අවශ්‍ය සියලු ක්‍රියාමාර්ග ගන්නා\" මම",
        "ඉන්දියාව නෞකාවේ ප්‍රගතිය නිරීක්ෂණය කරන බවට “පැහැදිලි පණිවිඩයක්” යවා තිබියදීත්, අභ්‍යවකාශ සහ චන්ද්‍රිකා ලුහුබැඳීමේ යෙදෙන චීන පර්යේෂණ යාත්‍රාවක් මේ වසරේ අගෝස්තු මාසයේදී හම්බන්තොට වරායට ඇතුළු වන බවට පළ වූ වාර්තා ප්‍රතික්ෂේප කළ ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ ආරක්ෂක අමාත්‍යාංශයේ ප්‍රකාශකයෙකු උපුටා දක්වමින් හින්දු පුවත්පත වාර්තා කළේය. \"ප්රවේශමෙන්\".",
        "ආරක්‍ෂක අමාත්‍යාංශයේ ප්‍රකාශකයෙක් කොළඹ ද හින්දු පුවත්පතට පැවසුවේ “එවැනි යාත්‍රාවක් හම්බන්තොට වරායට පැමිණෙන බවට අපට තහවුරු කිරීමක් නැහැ,”",
        "මියන්මාරය නැගෙනහිර අප්‍රිකානු ප්‍රාන්ත දක්වා විහිදෙන චීන යටිතල පහසුකම් ව්‍යාපෘති ද්විත්ව භාවිත පහසුකම් ගැන ඉන්දියාව දිගු කලක් තිස්සේ කනස්සල්ලට පත්ව සිටී.",
        "2014 වසරෙන් පසු මෙවැනි චීන නාවික යාත්‍රාවක් මෙරටට පැමිණෙන පළමු අවස්ථාව මෙයයි. 2014 වසරේදී චීන සබ්මැරීනයක් කොළඹට නැංගේ ඉන්දියාවේ කෝපයට හේතු වූ අතර එය ඉහළම මට්ටමින් මතු විය."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "චීන පර්යේෂණ යාත්රාව",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "හම්බන්තොට",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "News 1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "බ්රහස්පතින්දා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "චීන",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලාංකික",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "බීජිං",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "හින්දු",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ආරක්ෂක අමාත්යාංශය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "චීන",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "හම්බන්තොට වරාය",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "මේ වසරේ අගෝස්තු",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "හින්දු",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "තීරය සහ මාර්ග මුලපිරීම ශ්‍රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "කොළඹ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "චීනය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Yuan Wang",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "චීන",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජියැන්ග්යින්",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජූලි 13",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "නැගෙනහිර චීන මුහුද",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "අගෝස්තු 11-17",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "චන්ද්රිකාව",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දියානු සාගර කලාපය",
            "label": "LOC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Arindam Bagchi",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "සතිපතා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "හින්දු",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ආරක්ෂක අමාත්යාංශය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "චීන",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "හම්බන්තොට",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "මේ වසරේ අගෝස්තු",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ආරක්ෂක අමාත්යාංශය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "හින්දු",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "හම්බන්තොට",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "චීන",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "මියන්මාරය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "නැගෙනහිර අප්රිකානු",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "නවදිල්ලියේ",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "පළමුවන",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "2014",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "චීන",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ලංකා",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "2014",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "චීන",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "කොළඹ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "அம்பாந்தோட்டைக்கு சீன ஆராய்ச்சிக் கப்பல்?",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); பெய்ஜிங்கில் இருந்து பணத்தில் கட்டப்பட்ட இலங்கை துறைமுகத்திற்கு சீனக் கப்பல் ஒன்று திட்டமிட்டுள்ளதாகத் தகவல்கள் வெளியாகியுள்ளன என்று இந்தியா வியாழக்கிழமை தெரிவித்துள்ளது.",
        "எவ்வாறாயினும், தி ஹிந்து இணையத்தளத்தின்படி, இந்த ஆண்டு ஆகஸ்ட் மாதம் அம்பாந்தோட்டை துறைமுகத்திற்குள் சீன ஆய்வுக் கப்பல் ஒன்று நுழையும் என்ற செய்தியை இலங்கையின் பாதுகாப்பு அமைச்சகம் மறுத்துள்ளது.",
        "சீனாவின் ஜியாங்யின் துறைமுகத்தில் இருந்து ஜூலை 13ஆம் தேதி புறப்பட்ட ஆராய்ச்சி மற்றும் ஆய்வுக் கப்பல் யுவான் வாங் 5 என்று கொழும்பை தளமாகக் கொண்ட பெல்ட் அண்ட் ரோட் இனிஷியேட்டிவ் ஸ்ரீலங்கா என்ற அமைப்பு, சீனாவின் லட்சிய இணைப்புத் திட்டத்தை ஆய்வு செய்து தனது இணையதளத்தில் கூறியுள்ளதாக தி ஹிந்து தெரிவித்துள்ளது. இப்போது கிழக்கு சீனக் கடலில், இந்தியப் பெருங்கடல் பிராந்தியத்தின் வடமேற்குப் பகுதியில் விண்வெளி மற்றும் செயற்கைக்கோள் கட்டுப்பாடு மற்றும் ஆராய்ச்சி நடவடிக்கைகளைத் தொடர்ந்து நடத்தும் அதே வேளையில், 'மறு நிரப்புதலுக்காக' ஆகஸ்ட் 11-17 வரை இலங்கையின் அம்பாந்தோட்டை துறைமுகத்தில் கப்பல்துறை எதிர்பார்க்கப்படுகிறது.",
        "இந்தியாவின் வெளியுறவு அமைச்சக செய்தித் தொடர்பாளர் அரிந்தம் பாக்சி வாராந்திர செய்தியாளர் சந்திப்பில், \"இந்தியாவின் பாதுகாப்பு மற்றும் பொருளாதார நலன்களை பாதிக்கும் எந்தவொரு முன்னேற்றத்தையும் அரசாங்கம் கவனமாகக் கண்காணித்து, அவற்றைப் பாதுகாக்க தேவையான அனைத்து நடவடிக்கைகளையும் எடுக்கும்\" என்று கூறினார்.",
        "விண்வெளி மற்றும் செயற்கைக்கோள் கண்காணிப்பில் ஈடுபட்டுள்ள சீன ஆய்வுக் கப்பல் இந்த ஆண்டு ஆகஸ்ட் மாதம் அம்பாந்தோட்டை துறைமுகத்திற்குள் நுழையும் என்ற செய்தியை மறுத்த இலங்கையின் பாதுகாப்பு அமைச்சின் செய்தித் தொடர்பாளர் ஒருவரை மேற்கோள் காட்டி தி ஹிந்து, கப்பலின் முன்னேற்றத்தை இந்தியா கண்காணித்து வருவதாக \"தெளிவான செய்தியை\" அனுப்பியுள்ளது. \"கவனமாக\".",
        "பாதுகாப்பு அமைச்சின் பேச்சாளர் கொழும்பில் உள்ள தி ஹிந்துவிடம், \"அம்பாந்தோட்டை துறைமுகத்திற்கு அத்தகைய கப்பல் வருவதை எங்களிடம் உறுதிப்படுத்தவில்லை\" என்று கூறினார்.",
        "புதுடெல்லியின் நலன்களுக்கு நேரடி சவாலாக வரும் மியான்மர் வரை கிழக்கு ஆப்பிரிக்க மாநிலங்கள் வரையிலான சீன உள்கட்டமைப்பு திட்டங்களின் இரட்டை பயன்பாட்டு வசதிகள் குறித்து இந்தியா நீண்டகாலமாக கவலை கொண்டுள்ளது.",
        "2014ஆம் ஆண்டுக்குப் பின்னர் இவ்வாறானதொரு சீனக் கடற்படைக் கப்பல் இலங்கைக்கு விஜயம் செய்வது இதுவே முதல் தடவையாகும். 2014 ஆம் ஆண்டில், ஒரு சீன நீர்மூழ்கிக் கப்பல் கொழும்பில் நிறுத்தப்பட்டது இந்தியாவின் கோபத்தை ஈர்த்தது மற்றும் இந்த விஷயம் மிக உயர்ந்த மட்டத்தில் எழுப்பப்பட்டது."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "சீன ஆராய்ச்சிக் கப்பல்",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "ஹம்பாந்தோட்டை",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "News 1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்தியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "வியாழன்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சீன",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "பெய்ஜிங்",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இந்து",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கையின்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாதுகாப்பு அமைச்சகம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "சீன",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "அம்பாந்தோட்டை துறைமுகம்",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்த ஆண்டு ஆகஸ்ட்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இந்து",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "பெல்ட் & ரோடு முன்முயற்சி இலங்கை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "கொழும்பு",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சீனா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Yuan Wang",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "சீன",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜியாங்யின்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜூலை 13",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "கிழக்கு சீன கடல்",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆகஸ்ட் 11-17",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "செயற்கைக்கோள்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்தியப் பெருங்கடல் பகுதி",
            "label": "LOC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இந்தியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "அரிந்தம் பாக்சி",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "வாரந்தோறும்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்தியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இந்து",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கையின்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாதுகாப்பு அமைச்சகம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "சீன",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஹம்பாந்தோட்டை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்த ஆண்டு ஆகஸ்ட்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்தியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பாதுகாப்பு அமைச்சகம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்து",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஹம்பாந்தோட்டை",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இந்தியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சீன",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "மியான்மர்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "கிழக்கு ஆப்பிரிக்க",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "புது தில்லியின்",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "முதலில்",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "2014",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சீன",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "2014",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சீன",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "கொழும்பு",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்தியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}