{
  "newspaper_id": "economy-next-com",
  "url": "https://economynext.com/abeywardana-fills-vacant-seat-of-wickremesinghe-after-sri-lanka-president-vote-97832/",
  "time_ut": 1658560680,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Abeywardana fills vacant seat of Wickremesinghe after Sri Lanka president vote",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Abeywardana fills vacant seat of Wickremesinghe after Sri Lanka president vote",
      "author": "",
      "body_lines": [
        "ECONOMYNEXT –  Sri Lanka’s center-right United National Party (UNP) Chairman Wajira Abeywardana has been appointed for the vacant Member of Parliament seat after UNP leader Ranil Wickremesinghe was elected as the New President of Sri Lanka.",
        "Wickremesinghe entered the parliament as the only lawmaker of the party for the seat obtained through the national list. He was appointed as the prime minister on May 12 and this week he was elected as the new President of Sri Lanka by through a parliament vote.",
        "A gazette notice was issued on July 22 by the Election Commission said that Wajira Abeywardana will be a Member of Parliament to fill the vacancy after the resignation of Wickremesinghe.",
        "Abeywardana was the former cabinet Minister of Internal and Home Affairs and Provincial Councils and Local Government during the President Maithripala Sirisena’s government in which Wickremesinghe held the Prime Minister’s position.",
        "Abeywardana also previously served as Minister of Public Administration, Management and Reforms in the UNP government led by Ranil Wickramasinghe in 2001. He lost in the August 2020 election when he contested in Sri Lanka’s southern Galle district.",
        "He was the Secretary and Chair person of United socialist students front at University of Moratuwa from 1989 – 1994 and was Elected thrice as a Member of the Southern Provincial Council.",
        "He also was a working committee member of UNP Youth front from 1982-1994 and the Assistant Secretary of UNP in 1994. (Colombo/ July 23/2022)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Abeywardana",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "Wickremesinghe after Sri Lanka",
          "label": "WORK_OF_ART"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka’s",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "United National Party",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "UNP",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Wajira Abeywardana",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "UNP",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "May 12",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "this week",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "July 22",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Election Commission",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Wajira Abeywardana",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Abeywardana",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Provincial Councils and Local Government",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Maithripala Sirisena",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Abeywardana",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Minister of Public Administration",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Management and Reforms",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "UNP",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickramasinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "2001",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "August 2020",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka’s",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Galle",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Chair",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "United",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "University of Moratuwa",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "1989 – 1994",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Southern Provincial Council",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "UNP Youth",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "1982-1994",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "UNP",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "1994",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "ශ්‍රී ලංකා ජනාධිපතිවරයාගේ ඡන්දයෙන් පසු පුරප්පාඩු වූ වික්‍රමසිංහ අසුන අබේවර්ධන විසින් පුරවයි",
      "author": "",
      "body_lines": [
        "ECONOMYNEXT -  ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ නව ජනාධිපතිවරයා ලෙස එජාප නායක රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ තේරී පත්වීමෙන් පසු පුරප්පාඩු වූ පාර්ලිමේන්තු මන්ත්‍රී අසුන සඳහා ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ මධ්‍ය-දක්ෂිණාංශික එක්සත් ජාතික පක්ෂයේ (එජාප) සභාපති වජිර අබේවර්ධන පත් කර ඇත.",
        "ජාතික ලැයිස්තුවෙන් ලබාගත් මන්ත්‍රී ධුරය සඳහා පක්ෂයේ එකම මන්ත්‍රීවරයා ලෙස වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතා පාර්ලිමේන්තුවට පිවිසියේය. ඔහු මැයි 12 වන දින අගමැති ලෙස පත් කරන ලද අතර මේ සතියේ ඔහු පාර්ලිමේන්තුවේ ඡන්දයෙන් ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ නව ජනාධිපතිවරයා ලෙස තේරී පත් විය.",
        "වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතා ඉල්ලා අස්වීමෙන් පසු පුරප්පාඩු වන පාර්ලිමේන්තු මන්ත්‍රී ධූරය සඳහා වජිර අබේවර්ධන මහතා කටයුතු කරන බව මැතිවරණ කොමිෂන් සභාව විසින් ජූලි 22 වැනිදා ගැසට් නිවේදනයක් නිකුත් කර තිබිණි.",
        "වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතා අගමැති ධුරය දැරූ ජනාධිපති මෛත්‍රීපාල සිරිසේන මහතාගේ රජය සමයේ අභ්‍යන්තර හා ස්වදේශ කටයුතු සහ පළාත් සභා සහ පළාත් පාලන අමාත්‍යවරයා වූයේ අබේවර්ධනය.",
        "අබේවර්ධන මීට පෙර 2001 රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහගේ නායකත්වයෙන් යුත් එක්සත් ජාතික පක්ෂ ආණ්ඩුවේ රාජ්‍ය පරිපාලන, කළමනාකරණ සහ ප්‍රතිසංස්කරණ අමාත්‍යවරයා ලෙස ද කටයුතු කළේය. ඔහු ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ දකුණු ගාල්ල දිස්ත්‍රික්කයට තරඟ කර 2020 අගෝස්තු මැතිවරණයේදී පරාජයට පත් විය.",
        "ඔහු 1989 - 1994 කාලය තුළ මොරටුව විශ්වවිද්‍යාලයේ එක්සත් සමාජවාදී ශිෂ්‍ය පෙරමුණේ ලේකම් සහ සභාපතිවරයා වූ අතර දකුණු පළාත් සභා මන්ත්‍රීවරයෙකු ලෙස තෙවරක් තේරී පත් විය.",
        "ඔහු 1982-1994 UNP තරුණ පෙරමුණේ කෘත්‍යාධිකාරී මණ්ඩල සභිකයෙකු ද 1994 දී UNP සහකාර ලේකම්වරයා ද විය. (කොළඹ/ ජූලි 23/2022)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "අබේවර්ධන ය",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "ලංකාවට පස්සේ වික්‍රමසිංහ",
          "label": "WORK_OF_ART"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "එක්සත් ජාතික පක්ෂය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "එජාප",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "වජිර අබේවර්ධන",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "එජාප",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "මැයි 12",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මෙම සතිය",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ජූලි 22",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මැතිවරණ කොමිසම",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "වජිර අබේවර්ධන",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "අබේවර්ධන ය",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "පළාත් සභා සහ පළාත් පාලන",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "මෛත්‍රීපාල සිරිසේන",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "අබේවර්ධන ය",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "රාජ්‍ය පරිපාලන ඇමැති",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "කළමනාකරණය සහ ප්රතිසංස්කරණ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "එජාප",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "2001",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "2020 අගෝස්තු",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගාල්ල",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "පුටුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "එක්සත්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "මොරටුව විශ්වවිද්‍යාලය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "1989 - 1994",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "දකුණු පළාත් සභාව",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "එජාප තරුණ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "1982-1994",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "එජාප",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "1994",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "சிறிலங்கா அதிபர் வாக்களித்ததையடுத்து, விக்ரமசிங்கேவின் வெற்றிடத்தை அபேவர்தன நிரப்புகிறார்",
      "author": "",
      "body_lines": [
        "பொருளாதாரம் -  இலங்கையின் புதிய அதிபராக UNP தலைவர் ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க தேர்ந்தெடுக்கப்பட்டதையடுத்து வெற்றிடமான நாடாளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர் பதவிக்கு இலங்கையின் மத்திய-வலது ஐக்கிய தேசியக் கட்சியின் (UNP) தலைவர் வஜிர அபேவர்தன நியமிக்கப்பட்டுள்ளார்.",
        "தேசியப்பட்டியல் மூலம் பெறப்பட்ட ஆசனத்திற்கான கட்சியின் ஒரேயொரு நாடாளுமன்ற உறுப்பினராக விக்ரமசிங்க நாடாளுமன்றம் நுழைந்தார். அவர் மே 12 அன்று பிரதமராக நியமிக்கப்பட்டார், இந்த வாரம் அவர் பாராளுமன்ற வாக்கெடுப்பு மூலம் இலங்கையின் புதிய ஜனாதிபதியாக தேர்ந்தெடுக்கப்பட்டார்.",
        "விக்ரமசிங்கவின் பதவி விலகலின் பின்னர் வெற்றிடத்திற்கு வஜிர அபேவர்தன பாராளுமன்ற உறுப்பினராக இருப்பார் என தேர்தல்கள் ஆணைக்குழுவினால் ஜூலை 22 ஆம் திகதி வர்த்தமானி அறிவித்தல் வெளியிடப்பட்டது.",
        "விக்கிரமசிங்க பிரதமராக பதவி வகித்த ஜனாதிபதி மைத்திரிபால சிறிசேனவின் அரசாங்கத்தின் போது அபேவர்தன, முன்னாள் உள்துறை மற்றும் உள்நாட்டு அலுவல்கள் மற்றும் மாகாண சபைகள் மற்றும் உள்ளூராட்சி அமைச்சராக இருந்தார்.",
        "அபேவர்தன முன்னர் 2001 இல் ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க தலைமையிலான UNP அரசாங்கத்தில் பொது நிர்வாகம், முகாமைத்துவம் மற்றும் சீர்திருத்த அமைச்சராகவும் பணியாற்றினார். ஆகஸ்ட் 2020 தேர்தலில் அவர் இலங்கையின் தெற்கு காலி மாவட்டத்தில் போட்டியிட்டபோது தோல்வியடைந்தார்.",
        "1989 – 1994 வரை மொரட்டுவைப் பல்கலைக்கழகத்தின் ஐக்கிய சோசலிச மாணவர் முன்னணியின் செயலாளராகவும் தலைவராகவும் இருந்த அவர் மூன்று முறை தென் மாகாண சபை உறுப்பினராகத் தெரிவு செய்யப்பட்டார்.",
        "அவர் 1982-1994 வரை UNP இளைஞர் முன்னணியின் செயற்குழு உறுப்பினராகவும், 1994 இல் UNP இன் உதவிச் செயலாளராகவும் இருந்தார். (கொழும்பு/ ஜூலை 23/2022)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "அபேவர்தன",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "இலங்கைக்குப் பிறகு விக்கிரமசிங்கே",
          "label": "WORK_OF_ART"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கையின்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஐக்கிய தேசிய கட்சி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஐ.தே.க",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "வஜிர அபேவர்தன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஐ.தே.க",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "மே 12",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்த வாரம்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஜூலை 22",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "தேர்தல் ஆணையம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "வஜிர அபேவர்தன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "அபேவர்தன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "மாகாண சபைகள் மற்றும் உள்ளூராட்சி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "மைத்திரிபால சிறிசேன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "அபேவர்தன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "பொது நிர்வாக அமைச்சர்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "மேலாண்மை மற்றும் சீர்திருத்தங்கள்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஐ.தே.க",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "2001",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆகஸ்ட் 2020",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கையின்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "காலி",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "நாற்காலி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஐக்கிய",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "மொரட்டுவ பல்கலைக்கழகம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "1989 – 1994",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "தென் மாகாண சபை",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "UNP இளைஞர்கள்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "1982-1994",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஐ.தே.க",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "1994",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}