{
  "newspaper_id": "ada-lk",
  "url": "https://www.ada.lk/breaking_news/කන්දකාඩු-පුනුරුත්ථාපන-කඳවුර-උණුසුම්--රැඳවියන්-250ක්-පැන-යයි/11-394939",
  "time_ut": 1656482099,
  "original_lang": "si",
  "original_title": "කන්දකාඩු පුනුරුත්ථාපන කඳවුර උණුසුම්- රැඳවියන් 250ක් පැන යයි",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Kandakadu Rehabilitation Center Hot - 250 inmates escape",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "A tense situation has arisen between the inmates of the Welikanda Kandakadu Drug Rehabilitation Center and the Army following the mysterious death of an inmate this morning (29).",
        "The Army and the Police have been called in to control the situation, Welikanda Police said.",
        "The detainees managed to keep the body of the suspect in the same place as the police or the army could not get it."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "250",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "the Welikanda Kandakadu Drug Rehabilitation Center",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Army",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "this morning",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "29",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Army",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Welikanda Police",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        []
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "කන්දකාඩු පුනුරුත්ථාපන කඳවුර උණුසුම්- රැඳවියන් 250ක් පැන යයි",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "වැලිකන්ද කන්දකාඩු  මත්ද්‍රව්‍ය පුනුරුත්ථාපන කඳවුරේ රැඳවියෙකු අද (29දා) උදෑසන  අභිරහස් ලෙස මරණයට පත් වීමත් සමග   එම කඳවුරේ සිටින රැඳිවියන් සහ හමුදාව අතර  අතර උණුසුම් තත්ත්වයක් ඇති වී තිබේ .",
        "උණුසුම්කාරී තත්වය පාලනය කිරීමට යුද හමුදාව සහ පොලිසිය කැඳවා ඇති බව වැලිකන්ද පොලීසිය පවසයි.",
        "සැකකටයුතු ලෙස මියගිය රැඳවියාගේ මළ සිරුර පොලිසියට හෝ හමුදාවට   ලබා ගැනීමට නොහැකිව එම ස්ථානයේම තබාගෙන සිටීමට රැඳවියන් කටයුතු කර ඇත."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "250",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "වැලිකන්ද කන්දකාඩු මත්ද්‍රව්‍ය පුනරුත්ථාපන මධ්‍යස්ථානය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "හමුදා",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "මේ උදෑසන",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "29",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "හමුදා",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "වැලිකන්ද පොලිසිය",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        []
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "கந்தகாடு புனர்வாழ்வு மையம் சூடு - 250 கைதிகள் தப்பினர்",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "வெலிகந்த கந்தகாடு போதைப்பொருள் மறுவாழ்வு நிலையத்தில் கைதி ஒருவர் இன்று (29) காலை மர்மமான முறையில் உயிரிழந்ததையடுத்து அங்குள்ள சிறைவாசிகளுக்கும் இராணுவத்தினருக்கும் இடையில் முறுகல் நிலை ஏற்பட்டுள்ளது.",
        "நிலைமையை கட்டுப்படுத்த இராணுவம் மற்றும் பொலிசார் வரவழைக்கப்பட்டுள்ளதாக வெலிகந்த பொலிஸார் தெரிவித்தனர்.",
        "சந்தேக நபரின் சடலத்தை பொலிஸாரோ அல்லது இராணுவத்தினரோ பெற்றுக்கொள்ள முடியாத நிலையில் கைதிகள் அதே இடத்தில் வைத்து சமாளித்தனர்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "250",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "வெலிகந்த கந்தகாடு போதைப்பொருள் மறுவாழ்வு மையம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இராணுவம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று காலை",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "29",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இராணுவம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "வெலிகந்த பொலிஸ்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        []
      ]
    }
  }
}