{
  "newspaper_id": "daily-mirror-lk",
  "url": "https://www.dailymirror.lk/breaking_news/CB-Governor-signals-he-will-stay-in-job-warns-turmoil-impedes-IMF-talks/108-240895",
  "time_ut": 1657571248,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "CB Governor signals he will stay in job, warns turmoil impedes IMF talks",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "CB Governor signals he will stay in job, warns turmoil impedes IMF talks",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "REUTERS: Sri Lanka’s Central Bank Governor signalled yesterday he would stay in the job but warned that prolonged political instability in the country may delay progress on negotiations with the International Monetary Fund (IMF) for a bailout package.",
        "Governor Dr. P. Nandalal Weerasinghe, who has been holding bailout talks with the IMF since taking office in April, had told reporters in May he could resign if there was no political stability in the island nation of 22 million that is facing its worst economic crisis in seven decades.",
        "President Gotabaya Rajapaksa plans to resign on Wednesday while Prime Minister Ranil Wickremesinghe has also offered to quit, without specifying a date, to make way for a unity government. Thousands of protesters stormed their residences on Saturday and have vowed to stay put until the two leaders resigned.",
        "“Political instability might delay the progress we have been making so far,” Dr. Weerasinghe said of the talks with the IMF during an interview with Reuters in his office, where chants from protesters occupying the president’s house nearby could be heard.",
        "“I would like to have a stable political administration, the sooner the better, for us to make progress, mainly on the programmes we are negotiating with the IMF, bridging finance and also to address shortages of fuel, gas and other things.”",
        "Asked if he would continue to steer the Central Bank, Dr. Weerasinghe said, “I have the responsibility once I have been appointed to serve for (a) six-year term.”",
        "He also said negotiations were on for a US $ 1 billion swap with the Reserve Bank of India. Sri Lanka received a US $ 400 million swap from India in January and US $ 1.5 billion in two credit lines after that.",
        "“We have made a request for another US $ 1 billion,” he said, adding the country was also in talks with India for an additional credit line of US $ 500 million to import fuel.",
        "Since Dr. Weerasinghe, 61, took over, the Central Bank has raised interest rates twice, including by an unprecedented 700 basis points in April, as inflation touched a year-on-year record of 54.6 percent in June and could soar to 70 percent in the coming months. The IMF said on Sunday it was hoping for a resolution to the political turmoil to allow a resumption of talks for a bailout package. The government said last week it would present a debt restructuring plan to the fund by the end of August, in a bid to win approval for a four-year funding programme. “At technical level we have almost agreed (with the IMF) but at policy level we need a higher-level commitment from a stable administration,” the governor said.",
        "Sri Lanka suspended repayments on about US $ 12 billion of foreign debt in April and it still had payments of nearly US $ 21 billion due by the end of 2025."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka’s",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Central Bank",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "yesterday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the International Monetary Fund",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "P. Nandalal Weerasinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "IMF",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "April",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "May",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "22 million",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "seven decades",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Gotabaya Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Wednesday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Thousands",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Saturday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "two",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Weerasinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "IMF",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Reuters",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "the Central Bank",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Weerasinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "six-year",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "US",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "$ 1 billion",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Reserve Bank of India",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "US",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "$ 400 million",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "India",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "January",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "US",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "$ 1.5 billion",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "two",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "US",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "$ 1 billion",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "India",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "US",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "$ 500 million",
            "label": "MONEY"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Weerasinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "61",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Central Bank",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "700",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "April",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "54.6 percent",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "June",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "70 percent",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "the coming months",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "IMF",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sunday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "last week",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the end of August",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "four-year",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "IMF",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "about US $ 12 billion",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "April",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "US",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "$ 21 billion",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "the end of 2025",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "CB ආණ්ඩුකාරවරයා ඔහු රැකියාවේ රැඳී සිටින බවට සංඥා කරයි, කැලඹීම IMF සාකච්ඡා වලට බාධා කරයි",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "REUTERS: ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ මහ බැංකු අධිපතිවරයා ඊයේ තමා රැකියාවේ රැඳී සිටින බවට සංඥා කළ නමුත්, රට තුළ දිගුකාලීන දේශපාලන අස්ථාවරත්වය, ඇපදීමේ පැකේජයක් සඳහා ජාත්‍යන්තර මූල්‍ය අරමුදල (IMF) සමඟ කෙරෙන සාකච්ඡා වල ප්‍රගතිය ප්‍රමාද කළ හැකි බවට අනතුරු ඇඟවීය.",
        "අපේ‍්‍රල් මාසයේ බලයට පත් වූ දා සිට IMF සමඟ ඇපදීමේ සාකච්ඡා පවත්වමින් සිටින ආණ්ඩුකාර ආචාර්ය පී. නන්දලාල් වීරසිංහ, නරකම ආර්ථිකයට මුහුණ දී සිටින මිලියන 22 ක දිවයිනේ දේශපාලන ස්ථාවරත්වයක් නොමැති නම් තමාට ඉල්ලා අස්විය හැකි බව මැයි මාසයේදී වාර්තාකරුවන්ට පවසා තිබුණි. දශක හතක අර්බුදය.",
        "ජනාධිපති ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ මහතා බදාදා ඉල්ලා අස්වීමට සැලසුම් කර ඇති අතර අගමැති රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතා ද දින නියමයකින් තොරව ඉල්ලා අස්වීමට ඉදිරිපත් වී සමගි ආණ්ඩුවක් පිහිටුවීමට කටයුතු කර තිබේ. විරෝධතාකරුවන් දහස් ගණනක් සෙනසුරාදා ඔවුන්ගේ නිවෙස්වලට කඩා වැදුණු අතර නායකයන් දෙදෙනා ඉල්ලා අස්වන තුරු රැඳී සිටින බවට ප්‍රතිඥා දී ඇත.",
        "“දේශපාලන අස්ථාවරත්වය අප මෙතෙක් ලබා ඇති ප්‍රගතිය ප්‍රමාද කළ හැකිය,” ආචාර්ය වීරසිංහ සිය කාර්යාලයේ රොයිටර් සමඟ සම්මුඛ සාකච්ඡාවකට එක්වෙමින් ජාත්‍යන්තර මූල්‍ය අරමුදල සමඟ සාකච්ඡා ගැන පැවසීය, එහිදී ජනාධිපතිවරයාගේ නිවස අසල වාඩි වී සිටින විරෝධතාකරුවන්ගේ කෑගැසීම් ඇසෙනු ඇත.",
        "\"ප්‍රධාන වශයෙන්ම IMF සමඟ සාකච්ඡා කරන වැඩසටහන්, මූල්‍ය හා ඉන්ධන, ගෑස් සහ අනෙකුත් ද්‍රව්‍ය හිඟය විසඳීම සඳහා අපි ප්‍රගතියක් ලබා ගැනීම සඳහා, ස්ථාවර දේශපාලන පරිපාලනයක් ඇති කර ගැනීමට මම කැමතියි.\"",
        "ඔබ දිගටම මහ බැංකුව මෙහෙයවන්නේ දැයි ඇසූ විට ආචාර්ය වීරසිංහ පැවසුවේ, \"(අ) වසර හයක ධුර කාලයක් සඳහා මා පත් කළ පසු මට වගකීම පැවරී ඇති බවයි.",
        "ඉන්දියානු සංචිත බැංකුව සමඟ ඇමරිකානු ඩොලර් බිලියන 1 ක හුවමාරුවක් සඳහා සාකච්ඡා පැවැත්වෙන බව ද ඔහු පැවසීය. ශ්‍රී ලංකාවට ජනවාරි මාසයේදී ඉන්දියාවෙන් ඩොලර් මිලියන 400 ක හුවමාරුවක් ලැබුණු අතර ඉන් පසුව ණය මාර්ග දෙකකින් ඩොලර් බිලියන 1.5 ක් ලැබුණි.",
        "\"අපි තවත් ඇමරිකානු ඩොලර් බිලියන 1 ක් සඳහා ඉල්ලීමක් කර තිබෙනවා,\" ඔහු කියා සිටියේ, ඉන්ධන ආනයනය කිරීම සඳහා එක්සත් ජනපද ඩොලර් මිලියන 500 ක අතිරේක ණය මාර්ගයක් සඳහා රට ඉන්දියාව සමඟ සාකච්ඡා කරමින් සිටින බවයි.",
        "61 හැවිරිදි ආචාර්ය වීරසිංහ මහතා වැඩ භාරගැනීමෙන් පසු, ජූනි මාසයේදී උද්ධමනය සියයට 54.6ක වාර්ෂික වාර්තාවකට ළඟා වූ අතර, එය සියයට 70 දක්වා ඉහළ යා හැකි බැවින්, මහ බැංකුව අප්‍රේල් මාසයේ පෙර නොවූ විරූ ලෙස පදනම් ලකුණු 700කින් ද ඇතුළුව දෙවරක් පොලී අනුපාත ඉහළ නංවා ඇත. ඉදිරි මාසවලදී. ඇපදීමේ පැකේජයක් සඳහා සාකච්ඡා නැවත ආරම්භ කිරීමට ඉඩ දීම සඳහා දේශපාලන කැලඹීම සඳහා විසඳුමක් බලාපොරොත්තු වන බව IMF ඉරිදා පැවසීය. වසර හතරක අරමුදල් වැඩසටහනක් සඳහා අනුමැතිය දිනා ගැනීමේ උත්සාහයක් ලෙස, අගෝස්තු අග වන විට අරමුදලට ණය ප්‍රතිව්‍යුහගත කිරීමේ සැලැස්මක් ඉදිරිපත් කරන බව රජය පසුගිය සතියේ ප්‍රකාශ කළේය. \"තාක්ෂණික මට්ටමින් අපි (ජාමූඅ සමග) බොහෝ දුරට එකඟ වී ඇති නමුත් ප්‍රතිපත්ති මට්ටමේදී අපට ස්ථාවර පරිපාලනයකින් ඉහළ මට්ටමේ කැපවීමක් අවශ්‍ය වේ,\" ආණ්ඩුකාරවරයා පැවසීය.",
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකාව අප්‍රේල් මාසයේදී ඇමරිකානු ඩොලර් බිලියන 12 ක පමණ විදේශ ණය සඳහා ආපසු ගෙවීම අත්හිටුවන ලද අතර 2025 අවසන් වන විට ඩොලර් බිලියන 21 කට ආසන්න මුදලක් ගෙවිය යුතුව තිබුණි."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මහ බැංකුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඊයේ",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජාත්‍යන්තර මුල්‍ය අරමුදල",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "පී.නන්දලාල් වීරසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "IMF",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "අප්රේල්",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මැයි",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මිලියන 22 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "දශක හතක්",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "බදාදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "දහස්",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "සෙනසුරාදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "දෙක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "වීරසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "IMF",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "රොයිටර්",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "මහ බැංකුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "වීරසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "හය වසර",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "එක්සත් ජනපදය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඩොලර් බිලියන 1",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දියානු සංචිත බැංකුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "එක්සත් ජනපදය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඩොලර් මිලියන 400 කි",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජනවාරි",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "එක්සත් ජනපදය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඩොලර් බිලියන 1.5 කි",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "දෙක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "එක්සත් ජනපදය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඩොලර් බිලියන 1",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "එක්සත් ජනපදය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඩොලර් මිලියන 500 කි",
            "label": "MONEY"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "වීරසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "61",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මහ බැංකුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "700",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "අප්රේල්",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "සියයට 54.6 කි",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජූනි",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "සියයට 70 කි",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉදිරි මාස",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "IMF",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉරිදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගිය සතිය",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "අගෝස්තු අග",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "අවුරුදු හතරක්",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "IMF",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඇමරිකානු ඩොලර් බිලියන 12 ක් පමණ",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "අප්රේල්",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "එක්සත් ජනපදය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඩොලර් බිලියන 21 කි",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "2025 අවසානයේ",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "சிபி கவர்னர் அவர் வேலையில் இருப்பார் என்று சமிக்ஞை செய்தார், கொந்தளிப்பு IMF பேச்சுவார்த்தைகளைத் தடுக்கிறது",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "REUTERS: இலங்கையின் மத்திய வங்கி ஆளுநர் நேற்று தான் பணியில் இருப்பார் என்று சமிக்ஞை செய்தார், ஆனால் நாட்டில் நீடித்து வரும் அரசியல் ஸ்திரமின்மை, பிணை எடுப்புப் பொதிக்கான சர்வதேச நாணய நிதியத்துடன் (IMF) பேச்சுவார்த்தைகளில் முன்னேற்றத்தை தாமதப்படுத்தலாம் என்று எச்சரித்தார்.",
        "ஏப்ரலில் பதவியேற்றதில் இருந்து சர்வதேச நாணய நிதியத்துடன் பிணை எடுப்புப் பேச்சுக்களை நடத்தி வரும் ஆளுநர் கலாநிதி பி. நந்தலால் வீரசிங்க, மோசமான பொருளாதாரத்தை எதிர்கொண்டுள்ள 22 மில்லியன் தீவு நாட்டில் அரசியல் ஸ்திரத்தன்மை இல்லாவிட்டால் பதவி விலகலாம் என மே மாதம் செய்தியாளர்களிடம் தெரிவித்திருந்தார். ஏழு தசாப்தங்களில் நெருக்கடி.",
        "ஜனாதிபதி கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ஷ புதன்கிழமை இராஜினாமா செய்யத் திட்டமிட்டுள்ள நிலையில், பிரதமர் ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்கவும் ஐக்கிய அரசாங்கத்திற்கு வழி வகுக்கும் தேதி குறிப்பிடாமல் பதவி விலக முன்வந்துள்ளார். சனிக்கிழமையன்று ஆயிரக்கணக்கான எதிர்ப்பாளர்கள் தங்கள் வீடுகளை முற்றுகையிட்டனர் மற்றும் இரு தலைவர்களும் ராஜினாமா செய்யும் வரை தங்கியிருப்போம் என்று உறுதியளித்தனர்.",
        "\"அரசியல் ஸ்திரமின்மை நாம் இதுவரை செய்து வரும் முன்னேற்றத்தை தாமதப்படுத்தலாம்,\" என்று டாக்டர் வீரசிங்க தனது அலுவலகத்தில் ராய்ட்டர்ஸுக்கு அளித்த பேட்டியின் போது IMF உடனான பேச்சுக்கள் பற்றி கூறினார், அங்கு ஜனாதிபதியின் வீட்டை அருகில் ஆக்கிரமித்துள்ள எதிர்ப்பாளர்களின் கோஷங்கள் கேட்கப்பட்டன.",
        "\"ஒரு நிலையான அரசியல் நிர்வாகத்தை நான் விரும்புகிறேன், விரைவில் நாங்கள் முன்னேற்றம் அடைய விரும்புகிறேன், முக்கியமாக IMF உடன் நாங்கள் பேச்சுவார்த்தை நடத்தும் திட்டங்கள், பாலம் நிதி மற்றும் எரிபொருள், எரிவாயு மற்றும் பிற பொருட்களின் பற்றாக்குறையை நிவர்த்தி செய்வதற்கு.\"",
        "மத்திய வங்கியை தொடர்ந்து வழிநடத்துவீர்களா என்று கேட்கப்பட்ட கேள்விக்கு, கலாநிதி வீரசிங்க, \"(அ) ஆறு வருட காலத்திற்கு நான் பதவியேற்றவுடன் எனக்கு பொறுப்பு உள்ளது\" என்றார்.",
        "இந்திய ரிசர்வ் வங்கியுடன் 1 பில்லியன் டாலர் பரிமாற்றத்திற்கான பேச்சுவார்த்தை நடந்து வருவதாகவும் அவர் கூறினார். இலங்கை ஜனவரியில் இந்தியாவிடமிருந்து 400 மில்லியன் அமெரிக்க டொலர்களை மாற்றியமைத்தது மற்றும் அதன் பின்னர் இரண்டு கடன் வரிகளில் 1.5 பில்லியன் அமெரிக்க டொலர்களை இலங்கை பெற்றது.",
        "\"நாங்கள் மற்றொரு 1 பில்லியன் அமெரிக்க டாலர்களுக்கு கோரிக்கை வைத்துள்ளோம்,\" என்று அவர் கூறினார், மேலும் எரிபொருளை இறக்குமதி செய்ய 500 மில்லியன் அமெரிக்க டாலர் கூடுதல் கடன் வரிக்கு இந்தியாவுடன் நாடு பேச்சுவார்த்தை நடத்தி வருகிறது.",
        "61 வயதான கலாநிதி வீரசிங்க பதவியேற்றதிலிருந்து, மத்திய வங்கி இரண்டு முறை வட்டி விகிதங்களை உயர்த்தியுள்ளது, ஏப்ரலில் முன்னோடியில்லாத வகையில் 700 அடிப்படை புள்ளிகள் உட்பட, ஜூன் மாதத்தில் பணவீக்கம் ஆண்டுக்கு ஆண்டு சாதனையாக 54.6 சதவீதத்தைத் தொட்டது மற்றும் 70 சதவீதமாக உயரக்கூடும். வரும் மாதங்களில். பிணை எடுப்புப் பொதிக்கான பேச்சுவார்த்தைகளை மீண்டும் தொடங்க அனுமதிக்கும் அரசியல் கொந்தளிப்புக்கு ஒரு தீர்வு கிடைக்கும் என்று நம்புவதாக IMF ஞாயிற்றுக்கிழமை கூறியது. நான்கு வருட நிதியுதவி திட்டத்திற்கான ஒப்புதலைப் பெறும் முயற்சியில், ஆகஸ்ட் மாத இறுதிக்குள் நிதியத்திற்கு கடன் மறுசீரமைப்புத் திட்டத்தை முன்வைப்பதாக அரசாங்கம் கடந்த வாரம் கூறியது. \"தொழில்நுட்ப மட்டத்தில் நாங்கள் (IMF உடன்) ஏறக்குறைய ஒப்புக்கொண்டோம், ஆனால் கொள்கை அளவில் எங்களுக்கு நிலையான நிர்வாகத்தின் உயர் மட்ட அர்ப்பணிப்பு தேவை\" என்று ஆளுநர் கூறினார்.",
        "இலங்கை ஏப்ரல் மாதத்தில் சுமார் 12 பில்லியன் அமெரிக்க டொலர் வெளிநாட்டுக் கடனைத் திருப்பிச் செலுத்துவதை இடைநிறுத்தியது மற்றும் 2025 ஆம் ஆண்டின் இறுதிக்குள் கிட்டத்தட்ட 21 பில்லியன் அமெரிக்க டொலர்களை செலுத்த வேண்டியிருந்தது."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கையின்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "மத்திய வங்கி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "நேற்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சர்வதேச நாணய நிதியம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பி.நந்தலால் வீரசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "IMF",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஏப்ரல்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "மே",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "22 மில்லியன்",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஏழு தசாப்தங்கள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "புதன்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆயிரக்கணக்கில்",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "சனிக்கிழமை",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இரண்டு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "வீரசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "IMF",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ராய்ட்டர்ஸ்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "மத்திய வங்கி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "வீரசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆறு ஆண்டுகள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "எங்களுக்கு",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "$ 1 பில்லியன்",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்திய ரிசர்வ் வங்கி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "எங்களுக்கு",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "$ 400 மில்லியன்",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்தியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜனவரி",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "எங்களுக்கு",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "$ 1.5 பில்லியன்",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "இரண்டு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "எங்களுக்கு",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "$ 1 பில்லியன்",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்தியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "எங்களுக்கு",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "$ 500 மில்லியன்",
            "label": "MONEY"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "வீரசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "61",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "மத்திய வங்கி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "700",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஏப்ரல்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "54.6 சதவீதம்",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜூன்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "70 சதவீதம்",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "வரும் மாதங்கள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "IMF",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஞாயிற்றுக்கிழமை",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "கடந்த வாரம்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆகஸ்ட் இறுதியில்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "நான்கு ஆண்டுகள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "IMF",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சுமார் 12 பில்லியன் அமெரிக்க டாலர்கள்",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஏப்ரல்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "எங்களுக்கு",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "$ 21 பில்லியன்",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "2025 இறுதியில்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}