{
  "newspaper_id": "lankadeepa-lk",
  "url": "https://www.lankadeepa.lk/news/ගේ-මැද-නිධාන්-හෑරූ-පහක්-සැකපිට/101-618896",
  "time_ut": 1661741392,
  "original_lang": "si",
  "original_title": "ගේ මැද නිධාන් හෑරූ පහක් සැකපිට",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Five suspected to have dug up treasures in the middle of the house",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "Five persons who were digging for treasures in a house in Menikhinna area of ​​Kandy were arrested by a troop of the Kandy Special Task Force base, the Special Task Force said.",
        "According to information that these suspects are digging for treasures in the house, the troops have conducted this raid.",
        "The Special Task Force says that the arrested suspects are aged between 32-47 years and are residents of Kandy, Colombo and other areas.",
        "The arrested suspects have been handed over to the Menikhinna Police along with the equipment used to dig for treasure."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Five",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Five",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Menikhinna",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Kandy Special Task Force",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Special Task Force",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "between 32-47 years",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kandy, Colombo",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the Menikhinna Police",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "ගේ මැද නිධාන් හෑරූ පහක් සැකපිට",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "මහනුවර මැණික්හින්න ප්‍රදේශයේ නිවසක නිධන් හාරමින් සිටි පුද්ගලයන් පස් දෙනකු මහනුවර විශේෂ කාර්ය බළකා කඳවුරේ භට කණ්ඩායමක් මගින් අත්අඩංගුවට ගත් බව විශේෂ කාර්ය බලකාය පවසයි.",
        "මෙම සැකකරුවන්  නිවස තුළ නිදන් නිධන් හාරමින් සිටින බවට ලද තොරතුරකට අනුව භට පිරිස් මෙම වැටලීම සිදුකර ඇත.",
        "අත්අඩංගුවට ගත් සැකකරුවන් වයස අවුරුදු 32-47 අතර වයසේ පසු වන මහනුවර කොළඹ ඇතුළු ප්‍රදේශ වල ප්‍රදේශවල පදිංචිකරුවන් බව විශේෂ කාර්ය බලකාය පවසයි.",
        "අත්අඩංගුවට ගත් සැකකරුවන් නිධන් හෑරීමට භාවිතා කර කළ උපකරණ ද සමග මැණික්හින්න පොලිසියට පොලීසියට බාර දී ඇත."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "පහ",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "පහ",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "මැණික්හින්න",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "මහනුවර විශේෂ කාර්ය බලකාය",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "විශේෂ කාර්ය බලකාය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "අවුරුදු 32-47 අතර",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මහනුවර, කොළඹ",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "මැණික්හින්න පොලිසිය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "வீட்டின் நடுப்பகுதியில் ஐவர் புதையல் தோண்டியிருக்கலாம் என சந்தேகிக்கப்படுகிறது",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "கண்டி, மெனிக்ஹின்ன பிரதேசத்தில் வீடொன்றில் புதையல் தோண்டிய 5 பேர் கண்டி விசேட அதிரடிப்படையினரால் கைது செய்யப்பட்டதாக விசேட அதிரடிப்படையினர் தெரிவித்துள்ளனர்.",
        "குறித்த சந்தேகநபர்கள் வீட்டில் புதையல் தோண்டுவதாக கிடைத்த தகவலுக்கு அமைய, படையினர் இந்த சுற்றிவளைப்பை மேற்கொண்டுள்ளனர்.",
        "கைது செய்யப்பட்ட சந்தேகநபர்கள் 32 – 47 வயதுக்கு இடைப்பட்டவர்கள் எனவும், கண்டி, கொழும்பு மற்றும் ஏனைய பிரதேசங்களை வசிப்பிடமாகக் கொண்டவர்கள் எனவும் விசேட அதிரடிப்படை தெரிவித்துள்ளது.",
        "கைது செய்யப்பட்ட சந்தேகநபர்கள் புதையல் தோண்டுவதற்கு பயன்படுத்திய உபகரணங்களுடன் மெனிக்கின்ன பொலிஸாரிடம் ஒப்படைக்கப்பட்டுள்ளனர்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ஐந்து",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ஐந்து",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "மெனிகின்ன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "கண்டி சிறப்பு அதிரடிப்படை",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "சிறப்பு அதிரடிப்படை",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "32-47 ஆண்டுகளுக்கு இடையில்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "கண்டி, கொழும்பு",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "மெனிகின்ன பொலிஸ்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}