{
  "newspaper_id": "ada-lk",
  "url": "https://www.ada.lk/breaking_news/පියා-කැඩු-පොල්-ගෙඩිය-හිසට-වැටී-පුතා-මරුට/11-396784",
  "time_ut": 1661939639,
  "original_lang": "si",
  "original_title": "පියා කැඩු පොල් ගෙඩිය හිසට වැටී පුතා මරුට",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "The father broke the coconut and fell on his head, killing the son",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "Namunukula police said that a coconut cut by the father fell on his son's head and the son died.",
        "A student named H.M. Samira who studied in the 10th grade of Mianakandura Maha Vidyalaya, who was a resident of Namunukula Mianakandura, has died.",
        "Recently (29th) at around 6.30 in the evening, when the father climbed a 50 feet high tree in the garden and broke a coconut, the police said that during the investigations, it was revealed that the son had left the house and was returning home and at that moment, a coconut cut by the father had fallen on the son's head. .",
        "The seriously injured deceased was being treated at Badulla General Hospital and passed away this morning (31st).",
        "The police also mentioned that legal action will be taken against the 55-year-old father under the charge of breaking coconut due to negligence."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Namunukula",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "H.M. Samira",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "10th",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Mianakandura Maha Vidyalaya",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Namunukula Mianakandura",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "29th",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "6.30",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "50 feet",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Badulla General Hospital",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "this morning",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "55-year-old",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "පියා කැඩු පොල් ගෙඩිය හිසට වැටී පුතා මරුට",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "පියා විසින් කඩන ලද පොල් ගෙඩියක්  සිය පුතුගේ හිස මතට වැටී පුතා මියගොස් ඇතැයි නමුණුකුල පොලිසිය  පවසයි .",
        "මෙසේ මරණයට පත්ව ඇත්තේ නමුණුකුල මියනකඳුර පදිංචිව සිටි මියනකඳුර  මහා විද්‍යාලයේ 10 වන ශ්‍රේණියේ ‍ ඉගෙනුම ලැබූ එච්.එම්.සමීර නමැති ශීෂ්‍ය යෙකි .",
        "පසුගියදා (29දා) සවස 6.30ට  පමණ  පියා ගෙවත්තේ අඩි 50 ක් පමණ උසැති  ගසකට නැග පොල් කඩද්දී  මෙම පුත්‍රයා  නිවසින් බැහැරව ගොස් නැවත නිවසට පැමිනෙමින් සිට ඇති බවත් ඒ මොහොතේ  පියා විසින් කඩන ලද පොල් ගෙඩියක් පුතුගේ හිස මතට වැටී ඇතිබවත්  විමර්ශන වලදී අනාවරණය වූ බව පොලිසිය සඳහන්කළේය .",
        "බරපතල තුවාල ලැබූ මරණකරු  බදුල්ල මහ රෝහලේ ප්‍රතිකාර ලබමින් සිටියදී අද (31දා)  උදෑසන  ජීවිතක්ෂයට පත්වී තිබේ .",
        "55 හැවිරිදි පියාට එරෙහිව නොසැලකිලි මත්ව  පොල් කැඩීමේ  චෝදනාව යටතේ නීතිමය  පියවර ගන්නා බවද පොලිසිය සඳහන්කළේය ."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "නමුණුකුල",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "එච්.එම්. සමිර",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "10 වැනි",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "මියනකඳුර මහා විද්‍යාලය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "නමුණුකුල මියනකඳුර",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "29 වැනි",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "6.30",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "අඩි 50 යි",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "බදුල්ල මහ රෝහල",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "මේ උදෑසන",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "55 හැවිරිදිය",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "தந்தை தேங்காய் உடைத்து தலையில் விழுந்து மகன் உயிரிழந்தார்",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "தந்தை வெட்டிய தேங்காய் மகனின் தலையில் விழுந்து மகன் உயிரிழந்துள்ளதாக நமுனுகுள பொலிஸார் தெரிவித்தனர்.",
        "நமுனுகுல மியானகந்துறையை வசிப்பிடமாகக் கொண்ட மியானகந்துர மகா வித்தியாலயத்தில் 10ஆம் தரத்தில் கல்வி கற்கும் எச்.எம்.சமீரா என்ற மாணவியே உயிரிழந்துள்ளார்.",
        "அண்மையில் (29ஆம் திகதி) மாலை 6.30 மணியளவில் தந்தை தோட்டத்திலுள்ள 50 அடி உயர மரத்தில் ஏறி தேங்காய் உடைத்த போது, ​​மகன் வீட்டை விட்டு வெளியேறி வீடு திரும்பிக் கொண்டிருந்தமை விசாரணைகளின் போது தெரியவந்ததாக பொலிஸார் தெரிவித்தனர். அப்போது தந்தையால் வெட்டப்பட்ட தேங்காய் மகனின் தலையில் விழுந்தது.",
        "படுகாயமடைந்த அவர் பதுளை பொது வைத்தியசாலையில் சிகிச்சை பெற்று வந்த நிலையில் இன்று (31) காலை உயிரிழந்துள்ளார்.",
        "அலட்சியம் காரணமாக தேங்காய் உடைத்த குற்றச்சாட்டின் கீழ் 55 வயதுடைய தந்தைக்கு எதிராக சட்ட நடவடிக்கை எடுக்கப்படும் எனவும் பொலிஸார் குறிப்பிட்டுள்ளனர்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "நமுனுகுல",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "எச்.எம். சமீரா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "10வது",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "மியானகந்துர மகா வித்தியாலயம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "நமுனுகுல மியானகந்துரா",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "29 ஆம் தேதி",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "6.30",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "50 அடி",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பதுளை பொது வைத்தியசாலை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று காலை",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "55 வயது",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}