{
  "newspaper_id": "ada-lk",
  "url": "https://www.ada.lk/technology/Singapore-Space-Challenge-තරඟාවලියේ-ජයග්‍රහණයක්-ලංකාවටත්/5-375544",
  "time_ut": 1614676389,
  "original_lang": "si",
  "original_title": "Singapore Space Challenge තරඟාවලියේ ජයග්‍රහණයක් ලංකාවටත්",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Sri Lanka also won the Singapore Space Challenge",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "The SEDS_LunarBot team from Sri Lanka managed to be among the top three teams in the Singapore Space Challenge 2021 tournament.",
        "The task given to the teams at this year's Singapore Space Challenge 2021 was to \"design a rover that would be able to perform excavations on the Moon and use local resources.\"",
        "The SEDS_LunarBot team's design managed to be among the 03 best products in this tournament. The SEDS_LunarBot team also won the Distinction Award given to the two best emerging teams and won a cash prize of 1,000 Singapore dollars. The first place in this tournament was won by a New Zealand team made up of experts in the fields related to space exploration.",
        "America, England, United Arab Emirates, Australia, Canada are participating in this international competition organized by Singapore Space Technologies LTD with the support of the American Embassy in Singapore, AWS Educate, Office for Space Technology and Industry - Singapore, Singapore Digital, and Shiseido Japan. , and more than 140 teams participated representing 18 countries, including Belgium. About 600 students between the ages of 15-25 years represented these teams and several teams consisting of university students and the SEDS_LunarBot team representing Sri Lanka also appeared.",
        "The SEDS_LunarBot team consisted of three 18-year-old high school students and a first-year university student. They are Colombo DS. They are Viduranga Landes studying at Senanayake College, Jude Peiris and Oshadha Pathirana studying at St. Benedict's College Colombo and Samitha Ranasinghe studying at Purdue University in the United States of America."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Sri Lanka",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "the Singapore Space Challenge",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "three",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Singapore",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "2021",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "year",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Singapore Space Challenge 2021",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Moon",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "03",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Distinction Award",
            "label": "WORK_OF_ART"
          },
          {
            "text": "two",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "1,000 Singapore dollars",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "first",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "New Zealand",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "America",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "England",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "United Arab Emirates",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Australia",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Canada",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Singapore Space Technologies LTD",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the American Embassy",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Singapore",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "AWS Educate,",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Office for Space Technology and Industry - Singapore",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Singapore Digital",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Shiseido Japan",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "more than 140",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "18",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Belgium",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "About 600",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "between the ages of 15-25 years",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "three",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "18-year-old",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "first-year",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Colombo DS",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Viduranga Landes",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Senanayake College",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Jude Peiris",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "St. Benedict's",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "Samitha Ranasinghe",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Purdue University",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the United States of America",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "Singapore Space Challenge තරඟාවලියේ ජයග්‍රහණයක් ලංකාවටත්",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "Singapore Space Challenge 2021 තරඟාවලියේ හොඳම කණ්ඩායම් තුන අතරට පැමිණීමට ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ SEDS_LunarBot කණ්ඩායම සමත් විය.",
        "මෙවර Singapore Space Challenge 2021 තරඟාවලියේදී කණ්ඩායම් සඳහා ලබාදුන් කාර්යය වුයේ, \"සඳ මත කැණීම් සිදු කිරීමට හා ස්ථානීය සම්පත් භාවිතා කිරීමට හැකි වන පරිදි රෝවර් යානයක් සැලසුම් කිරීම\" යි.",
        "මෙම තරඟාවලියේ හොඳම නිපැයුම් 03 අතරට එක්වීමට SEDS_LunarBot කණ්ඩායමේ නිර්මාණය සමත් විය. එමෙන්ම හොඳම නැගී එන කණ්ඩායම් දෙක සදහා ලබාදුන් Distinction Award සම්මානයෙන්ද පිදුම් ලැබූ අතර සිංගප්පුරු ඩොලර් 1,000 මුදල් ත්‍යාගයක් දිනා ගැනීමට ද SEDS_LunarBot කණ්ඩායම සමත් විය. මෙම තරඟාවලියේ පළමු ස්ථානය අභ්‍යවකාශ ගවේෂණයට සම්බන්ධ ක්ෂේත්‍රයන්හි ප්‍රවීණයන්ගෙන් සැදුම්ලත් නවසීලන්ත කණ්ඩායමක් හිමි කරගත්හ.",
        "Singapore Space Technologies LTD  ආයතනය විසින් සිංගප්පූරුවේ ඇමෙරිකානු තානාපති කාර්යාලය, AWS Educate, Office for Space Technology and Industry - Singapore, Singapore Digital, සහ Shiseido Japan යන ආයතන වල අනුග්‍රහයෙන් සංවිධානය කරන මෙම අන්තර්ජාතික තරඟාවලිය සඳහා මෙවර ඇමරිකාව, එංගලන්තය, එක්සත් අරාබිය, ඕස්ට්‍රේලියාව, කැනඩාව, සහ බෙල්ජියම ඇතුලු රටවල් 18 ක් නියෝජනය කරමින් කණ්ඩායම් 140 කට වැඩි ප්‍රමාණයක් සහභාගී විය. වයස අවුරුදු 15 – 25 ත් අතර සිසුන් 600 ක් පමණ මෙම කණ්ඩායම් නියෝජනය කළ අතර ශ්‍රී ලංකාව නියෝජනය කරමින් SEDS_LunarBot කණ්ඩායම හා විශ්වවිද්‍යාල සිසුන්ගෙන් සමන්විත කණ්ඩායම් කිහිපයක් ද ඉදිරිපත් විය.",
        "SEDS_LunarBot කණ්ඩායම සඳහා 18 හැවිරිදි වියේ පසුවන උසස්පෙළ සිසුන් තිදෙනෙකු හා විශ්වවිද්‍යාල පළමු වසරේ සිසුවෙක් ඇතුලත් විය. ඔවුන් නම්, කොළඹ ඩී.එස්. සේනානායක විද්‍යාලයේ ඉගෙනුම ලබන විදුරංග ලෑන්ඩස්, කොළඹ ශාන්ත බෙනඩික් විද්‍යාලයේ ඉගෙනුම ලබන ජූඩ් පීරිස් හා ඕෂධ පතිරණ සහ අමෙරිකා එක්සත් ජනපදයේ පර්ඩියු විශ්වවිද්‍යාලයේ ඉගෙනුම ලබන සමිත රණසිංහ යන අයයි."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "සිංගප්පූරු අභ්‍යවකාශ අභියෝගය",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "තුන්",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "සිංගප්පූරුව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "2021",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "වර්ෂය",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "සිංගප්පූරු අභ්‍යවකාශ අභියෝගය 2021",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "සඳ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "03",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "විශිෂ්ඨ සම්මානය",
            "label": "WORK_OF_ART"
          },
          {
            "text": "දෙක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "1,000 සිංගප්පූරු ඩොලර්",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "පළමුවන",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "නවසීලන්තය",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ඇමරිකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "එංගලන්තය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "එක්සත් අරාබි එමීර් රාජ්‍යය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඕස්ට්රේලියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "කැනඩාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "සීමාසහිත සිංගප්පූරු අභ්‍යවකාශ තාක්ෂණ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඇමරිකානු තානාපති කාර්යාලය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "සිංගප්පූරුව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "AWS අධ්‍යාපනය,",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "අභ්‍යවකාශ තාක්ෂණය සහ කර්මාන්ත සඳහා කාර්යාලය - සිංගප්පූරුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "සිංගප්පූරු ඩිජිටල්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Shiseido Japan",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "140 ට වැඩි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "18",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "බෙල්ජියම",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "600 ක් පමණ වේ",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "වයස අවුරුදු 15-25 අතර",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "තුන්",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "18 හැවිරිදිය",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "පළමු වසර",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "කොළඹ ඩී.එස්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "විදුරංග ලෑන්ඩස්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "සේනානායක විද්‍යාලය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජූඩ් පීරිස්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශාන්ත බෙනඩික්ට්",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "සමිත රණසිංහ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "පර්ඩියු විශ්ව විද්‍යාලය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඇමරිකා එක්සත් ජනපදය",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "சிங்கப்பூர் விண்வெளி சவாலிலும் இலங்கை வெற்றி பெற்றது",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "சிங்கப்பூர் ஸ்பேஸ் சேலஞ்ச் 2021 போட்டியில் இலங்கையைச் சேர்ந்த SEDS_LunarBot அணி முதல் மூன்று அணிகளில் ஒன்றாக இருக்க முடிந்தது.",
        "இந்த ஆண்டு சிங்கப்பூர் ஸ்பேஸ் சேலஞ்ச் 2021 இல் குழுக்களுக்கு வழங்கப்பட்ட பணி, \"நிலவில் அகழ்வாராய்ச்சி செய்யக்கூடிய மற்றும் உள்ளூர் வளங்களைப் பயன்படுத்தக்கூடிய ரோவரை வடிவமைத்தல்\" ஆகும்.",
        "SEDS_LunarBot அணியின் வடிவமைப்பு இந்தப் போட்டியில் 03 சிறந்த தயாரிப்புகளில் ஒன்றாக இருக்க முடிந்தது. SEDS_LunarBot குழு இரண்டு சிறந்த வளர்ந்து வரும் அணிகளுக்கு வழங்கப்படும் சிறப்பு விருதையும் வென்றது மற்றும் 1,000 சிங்கப்பூர் டாலர்கள் ரொக்கப் பரிசையும் வென்றது. இந்தப் போட்டியில் விண்வெளி ஆய்வு தொடர்பான துறைகளில் வல்லுநர்களைக் கொண்ட நியூசிலாந்து அணி முதல் இடத்தைப் பெற்றது.",
        "சிங்கப்பூரில் உள்ள அமெரிக்க தூதரகம், AWS கல்வி, விண்வெளி தொழில்நுட்பம் மற்றும் தொழில்துறை அலுவலகம் - சிங்கப்பூர், சிங்கப்பூர் டிஜிட்டல் மற்றும் ஷிசிடோ ஆகியவற்றின் ஆதரவுடன் சிங்கப்பூர் ஸ்பேஸ் டெக்னாலஜிஸ் லிமிடெட் நடத்தும் இந்த சர்வதேசப் போட்டியில் அமெரிக்கா, இங்கிலாந்து, ஐக்கிய அரபு எமிரேட்ஸ், ஆஸ்திரேலியா, கனடா ஆகிய நாடுகள் பங்கேற்கின்றன. ஜப்பான்., மற்றும் பெல்ஜியம் உட்பட 18 நாடுகளை பிரதிநிதித்துவப்படுத்தி 140க்கும் மேற்பட்ட அணிகள் பங்கேற்றன. 15-25 வயதுக்கு இடைப்பட்ட சுமார் 600 மாணவர்கள் இந்தக் குழுக்களைப் பிரதிநிதித்துவப்படுத்தியதுடன் பல்கலைக்கழக மாணவர்களைக் கொண்ட பல அணிகள் மற்றும் இலங்கையைப் பிரதிநிதித்துவப்படுத்தும் SEDS_LunarBot அணியும் தோன்றின.",
        "SEDS_LunarBot குழுவில் மூன்று 18 வயது உயர்நிலைப் பள்ளி மாணவர்கள் மற்றும் ஒரு முதல் ஆண்டு பல்கலைக்கழக மாணவர் இருந்தனர். அவர்கள் கொழும்பு டி.எஸ். சேனநாயக்க கல்லூரியில் கல்வி கற்கும் விதுரங்க லண்டேஸ், ஜூட் பீரிஸ் மற்றும் கொழும்பு புனித பெனடிக்ட் கல்லூரியில் கல்வி கற்கும் ஓஷத பத்திரன மற்றும் அமெரிக்காவில் உள்ள பர்டூ பல்கலைக்கழகத்தில் கல்வி கற்கும் சமிதா ரணசிங்க ஆகியோர் ஆவர்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "இலங்கை",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "சிங்கப்பூர் விண்வெளி சவால்",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "மூன்று",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "சிங்கப்பூர்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "2021",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஆண்டு",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சிங்கப்பூர் விண்வெளி சவால் 2021",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "நிலா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "03",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "சிறப்பு விருது",
            "label": "WORK_OF_ART"
          },
          {
            "text": "இரண்டு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "1,000 சிங்கப்பூர் டாலர்கள்",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "முதலில்",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "நியூசிலாந்து",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "அமெரிக்கா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இங்கிலாந்து",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஐக்கிய அரபு நாடுகள்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆஸ்திரேலியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "கனடா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சிங்கப்பூர் ஸ்பேஸ் டெக்னாலஜிஸ் லிமிடெட்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "அமெரிக்க தூதரகம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "சிங்கப்பூர்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "AWS கல்வி,",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "விண்வெளி தொழில்நுட்பம் மற்றும் தொழில்துறை அலுவலகம் - சிங்கப்பூர்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "சிங்கப்பூர் டிஜிட்டல்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Shiseido Japan",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "140க்கு மேல்",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "18",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "பெல்ஜியம்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சுமார் 600",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "15-25 வயதுக்குள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "மூன்று",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "18 வயது",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "முதலாமாண்டு",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "கொழும்பு டி.எஸ்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "விதுரங்க லேண்ட்ஸ்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "சேனநாயக்க கல்லூரி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜூட் பீரிஸ்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "புனித பெனடிக்ட்",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "சமிதா ரணசிங்க",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "பர்டூ பல்கலைக்கழகம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஐக்கிய அமெரிக்கா",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}