{
  "newspaper_id": "virakesari-lk",
  "url": "http://www.virakesari.lk/article/131256",
  "time_ut": 1657549722,
  "original_lang": "ta",
  "original_title": "ஜனாதிபதி, பிரதமர் பதவி விலகாவிடின் வியாழக்கிழமை நாடு தழுவிய ரீதியில் ஹர்தால் - வசந்த சமரசிங்க",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Nationwide hartal on Thursday after the resignation of the President and Prime Minister - Vasantha Samarasinghe",
      "author": "T. Saranya",
      "body_lines": [
        "If President Gotabaya Rajapaksa and Prime Minister Ranil Wickremesinghe step down on the 13th tomorrow, we will engage in nationwide hartal action from Thursday.",
        "Vasantha Samarasinghe, head of the united trade union, said that both the heads of state should step down respecting the aspirations of the people of the country.",
        "He said the above while attending a press conference held in Colombo on Monday (11).",
        "President Gotabaya Rajapaksa and Prime Minister Ranil Wickremesinghe have no moral right to continue in office.",
        "In the political history of Sri Lanka, no head of state has been so hated by the people. People are very critical of President Gotabaya Rajapaksa.",
        "The President is looking for an auspicious time to step down when the people of the country are urging him to step down.",
        "President Gotabaya Rajapaksa and Prime Minister Ranil Wickremesinghe must resign tomorrow. We will go on a massive nationwide hartal from Thursday after the resignation.",
        "Prime Minister Ranil Wickremesinghe should abandon the government maneuver to become the next President once President Gotabaya Rajapaksa steps down.",
        "Prime Minister Ranil Wickremesinghe does not have a Lok Sabha. Respect the aspirations of the people and resign.",
        "If the President and the Prime Minister carry out political maneuvers without resigning, both will face more serious consequences.",
        "He said that until the President formally announced his resignation and communicated the letter to the Speaker and the Speaker made it public to the people, there could be no confidence in the President's resignation."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Thursday",
          "label": "DATE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Gotabaya Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the 13th tomorrow",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Thursday",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Vasantha Samarasinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the united trade union",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Monday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "11",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Gotabaya Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Gotabaya Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "Gotabaya Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "tomorrow",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Thursday",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Gotabaya Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "a Lok Sabha",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [],
        []
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "ජනපති සහ අගමැති ඉල්ලා අස්වීමෙන් පසු බ්‍රහස්පතින්දා රටපුරා හර්තාලය - වසන්ත සමරසිංහ",
      "author": "T. Saranya",
      "body_lines": [
        "හෙට 13 වැනිදා ජනාධිපති ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ මහතා සහ අගමැති රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතා ඉල්ලා අස් වුවහොත් බ්‍රහස්පතින්දා සිට අපි රටපුරා හර්තාල් ව්‍යාපාරයක නිරත වෙනවා.",
        "රටේ ජනතාවගේ අපේක්ෂාවන්ට ගරු කරමින් රාජ්‍ය නායකයින් දෙදෙනාම ඉල්ලා අස්විය යුතු බව ඒකාබද්ධ වෘත්තීය සමිති ප්‍රධානී වසන්ත සමරසිංහ මහතා පැවසීය.",
        "ඔහු මේ බව කියා සිටියේ සඳුදා (11) කොළඹ පැවති මාධ්‍ය හමුවකට එක්වෙමින්.",
        "ජනාධිපති ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ මහතාට සහ අග්‍රාමාත්‍ය රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතාට තවදුරටත් එම ධුරයේ කටයුතු කිරීමට සදාචාරාත්මක අයිතියක් නැහැ.",
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකා දේශපාලන ඉතිහාසය තුළ කිසිදු රාජ්‍ය නායකයකු මෙතරම් ජනතා වෛරයට පාත්‍ර වී නැත. ජනතාව ජනාධිපති ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ මහතා දැඩි ලෙස විවේචනය කරනවා.",
        "රටේ ජනතාව තමාට ඉවත් වන්නැයි කියද්දී ජනාධිපතිවරයා ඉවත් වීමට නැකතක් සොයමින් සිටී.",
        "ජනාධිපති ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ සහ අගමැති රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ හෙට ඉල්ලා අස්විය යුතුයි. ඉල්ලා අස්වීමෙන් පසු බ්‍රහස්පතින්දා සිට අපි රටපුරා දැවැන්ත හර්තාලයක් කරනවා.",
        "ජනාධිපති ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ මහතා ධූරයෙන් ඉවත් වූ පසු මීළඟ ජනාධිපතිවරයා වීමේ රජයේ උපාමාරුව අග්‍රාමාත්‍ය රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතා අත්හැරිය යුතුය.",
        "අගමැති රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහට ලෝක් සභාවක් නැහැ. ජනතා අභිලාෂයට ගරු කර ඉල්ලා අස්වෙන්න.",
        "ජනාධිපතිවරයා සහ අගමැතිවරයා ඉල්ලා අස් නොවී දේශපාලන උපාමාරු ගෙන ගියහොත් දෙදෙනාටම වඩා බරපතළ ප්‍රතිවිපාකවලට මුහුණ දීමට සිදුවනු ඇත.",
        "ජනාධිපතිවරයා සිය ඉල්ලා අස්වීම නිල වශයෙන් ප්‍රකාශ කර එම ලිපිය කථානායකවරයාට දන්වා කථානායකවරයා විසින් එය ජනතාවට ප්‍රසිද්ධ කරන තුරු ජනාධිපතිවරයාගේ ඉල්ලා අස්වීම පිළිබඳව විශ්වාසයක් තැබිය නොහැකි බවද ඔහු කියා සිටියේය."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "බ්රහස්පතින්දා",
          "label": "DATE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "හෙට 13 වෙනිදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "බ්රහස්පතින්දා",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "වසන්ත සමරසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "එක්සත් වෘත්තීය සමිතිය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "සඳුදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "11",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "හෙට",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "බ්රහස්පතින්දා",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ලෝක් සභාවක්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [],
        []
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "ஜனாதிபதி, பிரதமர் பதவி விலகாவிடின் வியாழக்கிழமை நாடு தழுவிய ரீதியில் ஹர்தால் - வசந்த சமரசிங்க",
      "author": "T. Saranya",
      "body_lines": [
        "ஜனாதிபதி கோட்டபய ராஜபக்ஷ, பிரதமர் ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க நாளை 13 ஆம் திகதி பதவி விலகாவிடின் வியாழக்கிழமை முதல் நாடு தழுவிய ரீதியில் ஹர்தால் நடவடிக்கையில் ஈடுபடுவோம்.",
        "நாட்டு மக்களின் அபிலாஷைகளுக்கு மதிப்பளித்து அரச தலைவர்கள் இருவரும் பதவி விலக வேண்டும் என ஒன்றிணைந்த தொழிற்சங்கத்தின் தலைவர் வசந்த சமரசிங்க தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "கொழும்பில் திங்கட்கிழமை (11) இடம்பெற்ற ஊடகவியலாளர் சந்திப்பில் கலந்துக்கொண்டு கருத்துரைக்கையில் மேற்கண்டவாறு குறிப்பிட்டார்.",
        "ஜனாதிபதி கோட்டபய ராஜபக்ஷ,பிரதமர் ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க ஆகியோர் தொடர்ந்து பதவி வகிப்பதற்கு எவ்வித தார்மீக உரிமையும் அவர்களுக்கு கிடையாது.",
        "இலங்கை அரசியல் வரலாற்றில் எந்த அரச தலைவரையும் நாட்டு மக்கள் இந்தளவிற்கு வெறுக்கவில்லை. ஜனாதிபதி கோட்டபய ராஜபக்ஷவை மக்கள் கடுமையாக விமர்சிக்கிறார்கள்.",
        "நாட்டு மக்கள் ஒன்றினைந்து பதவி விலகுமாறு வலியுறுத்தும் போது ஜனாதிபதி பதவி விலகலுக்காக சுபவேளை பார்த்துக்கொண்டிருக்கிறார்.",
        "ஜனாதிபதி கோட்டபய ராஜபக்ஷ, பிரதமர் ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க நாளை நிச்சயம் பதவி விலக வேண்டும். பதவி விலகாவிடின் வியாழக்கிழமை முதல் நாடு தழுவிய ரீதியில் பாரிய ஹர்த்தால் நடவடிக்கையில் ஈடுப்படுவோம்.",
        "ஜனாதிபதி கோட்டபய ராஜபக்ஷ பதவி விலகியவுடன், பதில் ஜனாதிபதியாகலாம் என முன்னெடுக்கும் அரச சூழ்ச்சியை பிரதமர் ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க கைவிட வேண்டும்.",
        "பிரதமர் ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்கவிற்கு மக்களாணை கிடையாது. மக்களின் அபிலாசைக்கு மதிப்பளித்து பதவி விலக வேண்டும்.",
        "ஜனாதிபதி, பிரதமர் ஆகியோர் பதவி விலகாமல் அரசியல் சூழ்ச்சியை முன்னெடுத்தால் மேலும் பாரதூரமான விளைவுகளை இருவரும் எதிர்கொள்ள நேரிடும்.",
        "ஜனாதிபதி பதவி விலகலை உத்தியோகப்பூர்வமாக அறிவித்து, அதற்கான கடிதத்தை சபாநாயகருக்கு அறிவித்து, சபாநாயகர் அதனை நாட்டு மக்களுக்கு பகிரங்கப்படுத்தும் வரை ஜனாதிபதியின் பதவி விலகல் மீது நம்பிக்கை கொள்ள முடியாது என்றார்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "வியாழன்",
          "label": "DATE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "நாளை 13ம் தேதி",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "வியாழன்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "வசந்த சமரசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஐக்கிய தொழிற்சங்கம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "திங்கட்கிழமை",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "11",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "நாளை",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "வியாழன்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஒரு மக்களவை",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [],
        []
      ]
    }
  }
}