{
  "newspaper_id": "daily-mirror-lk",
  "url": "https://www.dailymirror.lk/latest_news/Bus-fares-to-hike-by-50-if-CPC-diesel-prices-increased/342-232865",
  "time_ut": 1646987871,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Bus fares to hike by 50% if CPC diesel prices increased",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Bus fares to hike by 50% if CPC diesel prices increased",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "The Lanka Private Bus Owners’ Association (LPBOA)and the Inter Provincial Private Bus Owners’ Association (IPPBOA) today claimed that they will go for a bus fare increase if the Ceylon Petroleum Corporation (CPC) increases their diesel prices.",
        "The LPBOA and IPPBOA said the government should seek immediate solutions to the price increase of these essential commodities.",
        "LPBOA Chairman Gemunu Wijerathe and IPPBA Secretary Anjana Priyanjith said that they could not refuel their buses from Lanka IOC filling stations due to the increase in fuel prices.",
        "The government should immediately implement the program allowing people to get the required diesel from the depots owned by the Sri Lanka Transport Board (SLTB).",
        "According to Anjana Priyanjith, if diesel prices rise, total bus fares, including the minimum bus fare, should rise by 50%.",
        "Meanwhile, Gemunu Wijeratne said that he had informed the ministry in this regard. (Chaturanga Samarawickrama)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "50%",
          "label": "PERCENT"
        },
        {
          "text": "CPC",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "The Lanka Private Bus Owners’ Association",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Inter Provincial Private Bus Owners’ Association",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Ceylon Petroleum Corporation",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "CPC",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "LPBOA",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "IPPBOA",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "LPBOA",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Gemunu Wijerathe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "IPPBA",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Anjana Priyanjith",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the Sri Lanka Transport Board",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "SLTB",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Anjana Priyanjith",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "50%",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Gemunu Wijeratne",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Chaturanga Samarawickrama",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "CPC ඩීසල් මිල වැඩි කළහොත් බස් ගාස්තු 50% කින් ඉහළ යනු ඇත",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "ලංකා ඛණිජ තෙල් නීතිගත සංස්ථාව (CPC) ඩීසල් මිල වැඩි කළහොත් තමන් බස් ගාස්තු වැඩි කිරීමට යන බව ලංකා පෞද්ගලික බස් හිමියන්ගේ සංගමය (LPBOA) සහ අන්තර් පළාත් පෞද්ගලික බස් හිමියන්ගේ සංගමය (IPPBOA) අද ප්‍රකාශ කළහ.",
        "LPBOA සහ IPPBOA කියා සිටියේ මෙම අත්‍යාවශ්‍ය භාණ්ඩවල මිල වැඩිවීම සම්බන්ධයෙන් රජය වහා විසඳුම් සෙවිය යුතු බවයි.",
        "LPBOA සභාපති ගැමුණු විජේරතේ සහ IPPBA ලේකම් අංජන ප්‍රියන්ජිත් පැවසුවේ ඉන්ධන මිල ඉහළ යාම හේතුවෙන් ලංකා IOC ඉන්ධන පිරවුම්හල්වලින් තම බස් රථවලට ඉන්ධන ලබා ගැනීමට නොහැකි වූ බවයි.",
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකා ගමනාගමන මණ්ඩලයට අයත් ඩිපෝවලින් ජනතාවට අවශ්‍ය ඩීසල් ලබා ගැනීමේ වැඩපිළිවෙළ රජය වහා ක්‍රියාත්මක කළ යුතුය.",
        "අංජන ප්‍රියන්ජිත්ට අනුව ඩීසල් මිල ඉහළ ගියහොත් අවම බස් ගාස්තුව ඇතුළුව මුළු බස් ගාස්තුව 50% කින් ඉහළ යා යුතුය.",
        "මේ අතර ගැමුණු විජේරත්න කියා සිටියේ තමන් මේ සම්බන්ධයෙන් අමාත්‍යාංශය දැනුවත් කළ බවයි. (චතුරංග සමරවික්‍රම)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "50%",
          "label": "PERCENT"
        },
        {
          "text": "CPC",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ලංකා පෞද්ගලික බස් හිමියන්ගේ සංගමය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "අන්තර් පළාත් පෞද්ගලික බස් හිමියන්ගේ සංගමය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ලංකා ඛනිජ තෙල් නීතිගත සංස්ථාව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "CPC",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "LPBOA",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "IPPBOA",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "LPBOA",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගැමුණු විජේරතෙ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "IPPBA",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "අංජන ප්‍රියන්ජිත්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ලංකා",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකා ගමනාගමන මණ්ඩලය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ලංගම",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "අංජන ප්‍රියන්ජිත්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "50%",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ගැමුණු විජේරත්න",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "චතුරංග සමරවික්‍රම",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "சிபிசி டீசல் விலையை உயர்த்தினால் பேருந்து கட்டணம் 50% உயரும்",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "இலங்கை பெற்றோலியக் கூட்டுத்தாபனம் (CPC) டீசல் விலையை உயர்த்தினால், பேருந்துக் கட்டணத்தை அதிகரிக்கப் போவதாக இலங்கை தனியார் பேருந்து உரிமையாளர்கள் சங்கமும் (LPBOA) மற்றும் மாகாணங்களுக்கு இடையிலான தனியார் பேருந்து உரிமையாளர்கள் சங்கமும் (IPPBOA) இன்று தெரிவித்துள்ளன.",
        "இந்த அத்தியாவசியப் பொருட்களின் விலையேற்றத்திற்கு அரசாங்கம் உடனடி தீர்வைக் காண வேண்டும் என LPBOA மற்றும் IPPBOA தெரிவித்துள்ளன.",
        "எரிபொருள் விலையேற்றம் காரணமாக லங்கா ஐஓசி எரிபொருள் நிரப்பும் நிலையங்களில் இருந்து தமது பஸ்களுக்கு எரிபொருள் நிரப்ப முடியவில்லை என LPBOA தலைவர் கெமுனு விஜேரத்தே மற்றும் IPPBA செயலாளர் அஞ்சன பிரியஞ்சித் ஆகியோர் தெரிவித்தனர்.",
        "இலங்கை போக்குவரத்து சபைக்கு (SLTB) சொந்தமான டிப்போக்களில் இருந்து மக்களுக்கு தேவையான டீசலை பெற்றுக்கொள்ளும் திட்டத்தை அரசாங்கம் உடனடியாக நடைமுறைப்படுத்த வேண்டும்.",
        "அஞ்சனா பிரியஞ்சித் கூறுகையில், டீசல் விலை உயர்ந்தால், குறைந்தபட்ச பஸ் கட்டணம் உட்பட மொத்த பஸ் கட்டணம் 50% உயர வேண்டும்.",
        "இதேவேளை, இது தொடர்பில் அமைச்சுக்கு அறிவித்துள்ளதாக கெமுனு விஜேரத்ன தெரிவித்துள்ளார். (சதுரங்க சமரவிக்ரம)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "50%",
          "label": "PERCENT"
        },
        {
          "text": "CPC",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை தனியார் பஸ் உரிமையாளர்கள் சங்கம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "மாகாணங்களுக்கு இடையிலான தனியார் பேருந்து உரிமையாளர்கள் சங்கம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை பெற்றோலியக் கூட்டுத்தாபனம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "CPC",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "LPBOA",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "IPPBOA",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "LPBOA",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "கெமுனு விஜேரதே",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "IPPBA",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "அஞ்சனா பிரியஞ்சித்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை போக்குவரத்து சபை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "SLTB",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "அஞ்சனா பிரியஞ்சித்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "50%",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "கெமுனு விஜேரத்ன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "சதுரங்க சமரவிக்ரம",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}