{
  "newspaper_id": "news-first-lk",
  "url": "https://www.newsfirst.lk/2022/08/22/poultry-industry-to-meet-minister-today-22/",
  "time_ut": 1661144040,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Poultry industry to meet Minister today (22)",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Poultry industry to meet Minister today (22)",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); The All Ceylon Poultry Businessmen's Association will meet with the Minister of Trade, Commerce, and Food Security for talks on Monday (22).",
        "Minister Nalin Fernando told News 1st that the meeting will take place as per a request forwarded by the All Ceylon Poultry Businessmen's Association.",
        "However, the All Ceylon Poultry Businessmen's Association says that eggs will NOT be released to the local market today (22), in protest to the decision taken to impose a Maximum Retail Price.",
        "On the 19th of August 2022, An Extraordinary gazette notification was issued declaring maximum retail price for eggs.",
        "Accordingly, the maximum retail price of a white egg has been set at 43 rupees and a brown egg at 45 rupees.",
        "Consumer Affairs Authority orders that no Manufacturer, Producer, Supplier, Distributor or Trader shall Sell, Supply, Expose or Offer for sale, Display for sale the listed variety of eggs, exceeding the Maximum Retail Price.",
        "Chinese missile and satellite tracking vessel Yuan Wang 5 to depart Sri Lanka on Monday (22)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "today",
          "label": "DATE"
        },
        {
          "text": "22",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "News 1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Food Security",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Monday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "22",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Nalin Fernando",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "News 1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "22",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the 19th of August 2022",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "43",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "45",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Consumer Affairs Authority",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Manufacturer",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Supplier",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Maximum Retail Price",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Chinese",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Yuan Wang",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Monday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "22",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "කුකුළු කර්මාන්තය අද (22) ඇමති හමුවෙයි",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); සමස්ත ලංකා කුකුළු ව්‍යාපාරිකයන්ගේ සංගමය සඳුදා (22) වෙළෙඳ, වාණිජ හා ආහාර සුරක්ෂිතතා අමාත්‍යවරයා හමුවී සාකච්ඡා කිරීමට නියමිතය.",
        "සමස්ත ලංකා කුකුළු ව්‍යාපාරිකයන්ගේ සංගමය විසින් කරන ලද ඉල්ලීමකට අනුව මෙම හමුව සිදුවන බවයි අමාත්‍ය නලින් ප්‍රනාන්දු මහතා News 1st වෙත කියා සිටියේ.",
        "කෙසේ වෙතත්, උපරිම සිල්ලර මිලක් පැනවීමට ගත් තීරණයට විරෝධය පළ කරමින් අද (22) දේශීය වෙළඳපොළට බිත්තර නිකුත් නොකරන බව සමස්ත ලංකා කුකුළු ව්‍යාපාරිකයන්ගේ සංගමය පවසයි.",
        "2022 අගෝස්තු 19 වැනි දින බිත්තර සඳහා උපරිම සිල්ලර මිල ප්‍රකාශයට පත් කරමින් අතිවිශේෂ ගැසට් නිවේදනයක් නිකුත් කරන ලදී.",
        "ඒ අනුව සුදු බිත්තරයක උපරිම සිල්ලර මිල රුපියල් 43ක් ලෙසත් දුඹුරු බිත්තරයක උපරිම සිල්ලර මිල රුපියල් 45ක් ලෙසත් නියම කර ඇත.",
        "කිසිදු නිෂ්පාදකයෙකු, නිෂ්පාදකයෙකු, සැපයුම්කරුවෙකු, බෙදාහරින්නෙකු හෝ වෙළෙන්දෙකු විසින් ලැයිස්තුගත කර ඇති බිත්තර වර්ග උපරිම සිල්ලර මිලට වඩා විකිණීම, සැපයීම, හෙළිදරව් කිරීම හෝ විකිණීමට, විකිණීම සඳහා ප්‍රදර්ශනය නොකළ යුතු බවට පාරිභෝගික කටයුතු අධිකාරිය නියෝග කරයි.",
        "චීන මිසයිල සහ චන්ද්‍රිකා ලුහුබැඳීමේ යාත්‍රාව යුවාන් වැන්ග් 5 සඳුදා (22) ශ්‍රී ලංකාවෙන් පිටත් වේ."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "අද",
          "label": "DATE"
        },
        {
          "text": "22",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "News 1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ආහාර සුරක්ෂිතතාව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "සඳුදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "22",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "නලින් ප්‍රනාන්දු",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "News 1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "22",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "2022 අගෝස්තු 19 වෙනිදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "43",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "45",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "පාරිභෝගික කටයුතු අධිකාරිය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "නිෂ්පාදක",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "සැපයුම්කරු",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "උපරිම සිල්ලර මිල",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "චීන",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Yuan Wang",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "සඳුදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "22",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "கோழிப்பண்ணை தொழில்துறை அமைச்சரை இன்று (22) சந்திக்கவுள்ளது.",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); அகில இலங்கை கோழிப்பண்ணை வியாபாரிகள் சங்கம் வர்த்தக, வர்த்தக மற்றும் உணவு பாதுகாப்பு அமைச்சரை திங்கட்கிழமை (22) சந்தித்து பேச்சுவார்த்தை நடத்தவுள்ளது.",
        "அகில இலங்கை கோழிப்பண்ணை வியாபாரிகள் சங்கத்தினால் முன்வைக்கப்பட்ட கோரிக்கைக்கு அமைய இந்த சந்திப்பு இடம்பெறவுள்ளதாக அமைச்சர் நளின் பெர்னாண்டோ நியூஸ் 1ஸ்டுக்கு தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "எவ்வாறாயினும், அதிகபட்ச சில்லறை விலையை நிர்ணயிக்கும் தீர்மானத்திற்கு எதிர்ப்புத் தெரிவிக்கும் வகையில் இன்று (22) உள்ளூர் சந்தைக்கு முட்டைகள் வெளியிடப்பட மாட்டாது என அகில இலங்கை கோழிப்பண்ணை வியாபாரிகள் சங்கம் தெரிவித்துள்ளது.",
        "ஆகஸ்ட் 19, 2022 அன்று, முட்டைக்கான அதிகபட்ச சில்லறை விலையை அறிவிக்கும் அசாதாரண வர்த்தமானி அறிவிப்பு வெளியிடப்பட்டது.",
        "இதன்படி, வெள்ளை முட்டை ஒன்றின் அதிகபட்ச சில்லறை விலை 43 ரூபாவாகவும் பழுப்பு நிற முட்டை ஒன்றின் விலை 45 ரூபாவாகவும் நிர்ணயிக்கப்பட்டுள்ளது.",
        "உற்பத்தியாளர், உற்பத்தியாளர், சப்ளையர், விநியோகஸ்தர் அல்லது வர்த்தகர் எவரும் பட்டியலிடப்பட்ட முட்டை வகைகளை அதிகபட்ச சில்லறை விலையை விட அதிகமாக விற்கவோ, வழங்கவோ, வெளிப்படுத்தவோ அல்லது விற்பனை செய்யவோ, விற்பனைக்குக் காட்சிப்படுத்தவோ கூடாது என்று நுகர்வோர் விவகார ஆணையம் உத்தரவு பிறப்பிக்கிறது.",
        "சீன ஏவுகணை மற்றும் செயற்கைக்கோள் கண்காணிப்பு கப்பல் யுவான் வாங் 5 திங்கட்கிழமை (22) இலங்கையிலிருந்து புறப்படவுள்ளது."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "இன்று",
          "label": "DATE"
        },
        {
          "text": "22",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "News 1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "உணவு பாதுகாப்பு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "திங்கட்கிழமை",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "22",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "நளின் பெர்னாண்டோ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "News 1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "22",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஆகஸ்ட் 19, 2022",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "43",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "45",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "நுகர்வோர் விவகார ஆணையம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "உற்பத்தியாளர்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "சப்ளையர்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "அதிகபட்ச சில்லறை விலை",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "சீன",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Yuan Wang",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "திங்கட்கிழமை",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "22",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}