{
  "newspaper_id": "virakesari-lk",
  "url": "http://www.virakesari.lk/article/132551",
  "time_ut": 1659162847,
  "original_lang": "ta",
  "original_title": "இலங்கை சர்வதேச நாணயநிதியத்துடன் பேச்சுவார்த்தைகளை மீள ஆரம்பித்துள்ளது – நிதியமைச்சு",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Sri Lanka resumes talks with IMF - Finance Ministry",
      "author": "Rajeeban",
      "body_lines": [
        "Sri Lanka has started negotiations with the International Monetary Fund to recover from the economic crisis after the new government took office, the Ministry of Finance said.",
        "Negotiations with the International Monetary Fund began in April under the Gotabaya Rajapaksa government.",
        "The Sri Lankan government is seeking much-needed EV aid to tackle the country's worst economic crisis since 1948 - a condition the government will have to carry out economic reforms.",
        "Ranil Wickremesinghe was appointed President after President Rajapaksa was ousted by a popular uprising caused by a months-long shortage of medicines, food and fuel.",
        "Wickremesinghe, who served as Prime Minister six times, intends to engage in debt restructuring.",
        "Negotiations with the International Monetary Fund appear to have been largely successful and Sri Lanka is working with consultants to reach a compromise agreement with creditors, the government said."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Sri Lanka",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "IMF - Finance Ministry",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the International Monetary Fund",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Ministry of Finance",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the International Monetary Fund",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "April",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Gotabaya Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lankan",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "EV",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "1948",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "months",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "six",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the International Monetary Fund",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "ශ්‍රී ලංකාව IMF - මුදල් අමාත්‍යාංශය සමඟ යළි සාකච්ඡා අරඹයි",
      "author": "රජීබන්",
      "body_lines": [
        "නව රජය බලයට පත්වීමෙන් පසු ආර්ථික අර්බුදයෙන් ගොඩ ඒම සඳහා ශ්‍රී ලංකාව ජාත්‍යන්තර මූල්‍ය අරමුදල සමඟ සාකච්ඡා ආරම්භ කර ඇති බව මුදල් අමාත්‍යාංශය පවසයි.",
        "ජාත්‍යන්තර මුල්‍ය අරමුදල සමග සාකච්ජා ආරම්භ වූයේ පසුගිය අප්‍රේල් මාසයේදී ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ රජය යටතේය.",
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකා රජය 1948 න් පසු රටේ ඇති වූ දරුණුතම ආර්ථික අර්බුදයට මුහුණ දීම සඳහා බෙහෙවින් අවශ්‍ය EV ආධාර අපේක්ෂා කරයි - රජයට ආර්ථික ප්‍රතිසංස්කරණ සිදු කිරීමට සිදුවනු ඇති කොන්දේසියකි.",
        "මාස ගණනක ඖෂධ, ආහාර සහ ඉන්ධන හිඟයක් හේතුවෙන් ඇති වූ ජනතා නැගිටීමකින් රාජපක්ෂ ජනාධිපතිවරයා බලයෙන් පහකිරීමෙන් පසු රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතා ජනාධිපති ධුරයට පත් විය.",
        "හය වතාවක් අගමැති ලෙස කටයුතු කළ වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතා ණය ප්‍රතිව්‍යුහගත කිරීමේ කටයුතුවල නිරත වීමට අදහස් කරයි.",
        "ජාත්‍යන්තර මූල්‍ය අරමුදල සමඟ පැවති සාකච්ඡා බොහෝ දුරට සාර්ථක වී ඇති බව පෙනෙන අතර ණයහිමියන් සමඟ සම්මුති ගිවිසුමකට එළැඹීමට ශ්‍රී ලංකාව උපදේශකයින් සමඟ කටයුතු කරමින් සිටින බව රජය පවසයි."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "IMF - මුදල් අමාත්යාංශය",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජාත්‍යන්තර මුල්‍ය අරමුදල",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "මුදල් අමාත්යාංශය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ජාත්‍යන්තර මුල්‍ය අරමුදල",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "අප්රේල්",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලාංකික",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "EV",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "1948",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "මාස",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "හය",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ජාත්‍යන්තර මුල්‍ය අරමුදල",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "இலங்கை சர்வதேச நாணயநிதியத்துடன் பேச்சுவார்த்தைகளை மீள ஆரம்பித்துள்ளது – நிதியமைச்சு",
      "author": "Rajeeban",
      "body_lines": [
        "புதிய அரசாங்கம் பதவியேற்ற பின்னர் இலங்கை சர்வதேச நாணயநிதியத்துடன்  பொருளாதார நெருக்கடியிலிருந்து மீள்வதற்கான பேச்சுவார்த்தைகளை ஆரம்பித்துள்ளது என நிதியமைச்சு தெரிவித்துள்ளது.",
        "சர்வதேச நாணயநிதியத்துடனான பேச்சுவார்த்தைகள் கடந்த கோத்தபாய ராஜபக்ச அரசாங்கத்தின் கீழ் ஏப்பிரல் மாதம் ஆரம்பமாகியிருந்தன.",
        "இலங்கை அரசாங்கம் 1948 இன் பின்னர் நாடு எதிர்கொண்டுள்ள மோசமான பொருளாதார நெருக்கடியை எதிர்கொள்வதற்கு அவசியமான ஈஎவ்எவ் உதவியை பெற முயல்கின்றது - இதனை பெறுவதற்கு பொருளாதார சீர்திருத்தங்களை முன்னெடுக்கவேண்டிய நிபந்தனையை அரசாங்கம் எதிர்கொள்கின்றது.",
        "பலமாதகாலமாகநீடிக்கும் மருந்து உணவு எரிபொருட்களிற்கான தட்டுப்பாட்டின் காரணமாக உருவான மக்கள் எழுச்சியால் ஜனாதிபதி ராஜபக்ச பதவியிலிருந்து அகற்றப்பட்டதை தொடர்ந்து ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க ஜனாதிபதியாக நியமிக்கப்பட்டார்.",
        "ஆறு தடவைகள் பிரதமராக பதவி வகித்த விக்கிரமசிங்க கடன் மறுசீரமைப்பில் ஈடுபட எண்ணியுள்ளார்.",
        "சர்வதேச நாணயநிதியத்துடனான பேச்சுவார்த்தைகள் பெரும்வெற்றிகரமானவையாக காணப்படுகின்றன கடன்வழங்கியவர்களுடன் கருத்தொருமைப்பாட்டு உடன்படிக்கைக்கு வருவதற்கு இலங்கை ஆலோசகர்களுடன் இணைந்து நடவடிக்கயில் ஈடுபட்டுள்ளது என அரசாங்கம் தெரிவித்துள்ளது,"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "இலங்கை",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "IMF - நிதி அமைச்சகம்",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சர்வதேச நாணய நிதியம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "நிதி அமைச்சகம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "சர்வதேச நாணய நிதியம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஏப்ரல்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஈ.வி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "1948",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ராஜபக்சே",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "மாதங்கள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆறு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "சர்வதேச நாணய நிதியம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}