{
  "newspaper_id": "lankadeepa-lk",
  "url": "https://www.lankadeepa.lk/latest_news/රංජන්ට-පූර්ණ-නිදහස-දෙන්න/1-617307",
  "time_ut": 1659247194,
  "original_lang": "si",
  "original_title": "රංජන්ට පූර්ණ නිදහස දෙන්න",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Give Ranjan full freedom",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "Mr. Sajith Premadasa, the leader of the opposition, said that he expects that Mr. Ranjan Ramanayake, who is the expectation of everyone, will get full freedom and is waiting for that day.",
        "The opposition leader said that it is his sole objective to see Mr. Ranjan Ramanayake, who has continued popularity as a philanthropic politician as well as a folk artist, come back to the society as a free citizen and work energetically for social justice.",
        "Mr. Sajith Premadasa, the opposition leader, who went to the Welikada prison to check on the well-being of Mr. Ranjan Ramanayake, who is incarcerated in the Welikada prison, said this while speaking to the media.",
        "The opposition leader also exchanged views with Mr. Ranjan Ramanayake there for a long time."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Ranjan",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Sajith Premadasa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ranjan Ramanayake",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "that day",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Ranjan Ramanayake",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sajith Premadasa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Welikada",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ranjan Ramanayake",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Welikada",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Ranjan Ramanayake",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "රංජන්ට පූර්ණ නිදහස දෙන්න",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "සෑම දෙනාගේම අපේක්ෂාව වන රන්ජන් රාමනායක මහතාට පූර්ණ නිදහස ලැබේවි කියා තමන් අපේක්ෂා කරන බවත් ඒ දවස එනතුරු බලා සිටින බවත් විපක්ෂ නායක සජිත් ප්‍රේමදාස මහතා පැවසීය.",
        "මානව හිතවාදී දේශපාලනඥයෙකු මෙන්ම, ජනකාන්ත කලාකරුවෙකු ද ලෙස අඛණ්ඩ ජනප්‍රියත්වයක් හිමිකරගෙන ඇති රංජන් රාමනායක මහතා නිදහස් පුරවැසියකු ලෙස සමාජයට පැමිණ, නැවතත් ශක්ති සම්පන්නව සමාජ සාධාරණත්වය උදෙසා කටයුතු කරනවා දැකීම තම ඒකායන පරමාර්ථය බවද විපක්ෂ නායකවරයා  පැවසීය.",
        "වැලිකඩ බන්ධනාගාරයේ  සිරගතව සිටින රන්ජන් රාමනායක මහතාගේ සුවදුක් බැලීම සඳහා වැලිකඩ බන්ධනාගාරයට ගිය විපක්ෂ නායක සජිත් ප්‍රේමදාස මහතා ඉන් අනතුරුව මාධ්‍ය හමුවේ අදහස් දක්වමින් මේ බව කීවේය.",
        "රන්ජන් රාමනායක මහතා සමඟ එහිදී දීර්ඝ වේලාවක් අදහස් හුවමාරු කරගැනීමටද විපක්ෂ නායකවරයා කටයුතු කළේය."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "රන්ජන්",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "සජිත් ප්‍රේමදාස",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "රන්ජන් රාමනායක",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "එදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "රන්ජන් රාමනායක",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "සජිත් ප්‍රේමදාස",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "වැලිකඩ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "රන්ජන් රාමනායක",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "වැලිකඩ",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "රන්ජන් රාමනායක",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "ரஞ்சனுக்கு முழு சுதந்திரம் கொடுங்கள்",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "அனைவரின் எதிர்பார்ப்பாக இருக்கும் திரு.ரஞ்சன் ராமநாயக்கவுக்கு பூரண சுதந்திரம் கிடைக்கும் என எதிர்பார்ப்பதாகவும், அந்த நாளுக்காக காத்திருப்பதாகவும் எதிர்க்கட்சித் தலைவர் திரு.சஜித் பிரேமதாச தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "பரோபகார அரசியல்வாதியாகவும், நாட்டுப்புறக் கலைஞராகவும் தொடர்ந்து பிரபலமடைந்து வரும் திரு.ரஞ்சன் ராமநாயக்க சுதந்திரக் குடிமகனாக மீண்டும் சமூகத்திற்கு வந்து சமூக நீதிக்காக ஆற்றலுடன் செயற்படுவதே தமது ஒரே நோக்கமாகும் என எதிர்க்கட்சித் தலைவர் தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "வெலிக்கடை சிறைச்சாலையில் தடுத்து வைக்கப்பட்டுள்ள திரு.ரஞ்சன் ராமநாயக்கவின் நலம் விசாரிப்பதற்காக வெலிக்கடை சிறைச்சாலைக்குச் சென்ற எதிர்க்கட்சித் தலைவர் திரு.சஜித் பிரேமதாச, ஊடகங்களுக்கு கருத்து தெரிவிக்கும் போதே மேற்கண்டவாறு தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "எதிர்க்கட்சித் தலைவர் திரு.ரஞ்சன் ராமநாயக்க அவர்களுடன் நீண்ட நேரம் கருத்துக்களையும் பரிமாறிக் கொண்டார்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ரஞ்சன்",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "சஜித் பிரேமதாச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரஞ்சன் ராமநாயக்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "அந்த நாள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ரஞ்சன் ராமநாயக்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "சஜித் பிரேமதாச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "வெலிக்கடை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரஞ்சன் ராமநாயக்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "வெலிக்கடை",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ரஞ்சன் ராமநாயக்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}