{
  "newspaper_id": "ada-derana-lk",
  "url": "http://www.adaderana.lk/news/83960/president-invites-all-mps-to-join-talks-on-forming-all-party-govt",
  "time_ut": 1659110280,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "President invites all MPs to join talks on forming all-party govt",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "President invites all MPs to join talks on forming all-party govt",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "President Ranil Wickremesinghe has invited all Members of Parliament to join discussions on forming an all-party government to resolve the current situation in the country.",
        "According to the President’s Media Division (PMD), President Wickremesinghe has made the relevant request in writing this morning."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Media Division",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "PMD",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "this morning",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "සර්ව පාක්ෂික ආණ්ඩුවක් පිහිටුවීමේ සාකච්ඡාවට එක්වන්නැයි ජනපති සියලු මන්ත්‍රීවරුන්ට ආරාධනා කරයි",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "රට තුළ උද්ගතව ඇති තත්ත්වය විසඳීම සඳහා සර්ව පාක්ෂික ආණ්ඩුවක් පිහිටුවීම සම්බන්ධයෙන් සාකච්ඡා කිරීමට එක්වන ලෙස ජනාධිපති රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතා සියලුම මන්ත්‍රීවරුන්ට ආරාධනා කර තිබේ.",
        "ජනාධිපති මාධ්‍ය අංශයට (PMD) අනුව, ජනාධිපති වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතා විසින් අද පෙරවරුවේ ලිඛිතව මෙම ඉල්ලීම කර ඇත."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "මාධ්ය අංශය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "පීඑම්ඩී",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "මේ උදෑසන",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "அனைத்துக் கட்சி ஆட்சி அமைப்பதற்கான பேச்சுவார்த்தையில் பங்கேற்குமாறு அனைத்து நாடாளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர்களுக்கும் ஜனாதிபதி அழைப்பு விடுத்துள்ளார்",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "நாட்டில் தற்போது நிலவும் நிலமைக்கு தீர்வு காண அனைத்துக் கட்சிகளை உள்ளடக்கிய அரசாங்கத்தை அமைப்பது தொடர்பான கலந்துரையாடலில் கலந்துகொள்ளுமாறு ஜனாதிபதி ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க அனைத்து நாடாளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர்களுக்கும் அழைப்பு விடுத்துள்ளார்.",
        "ஜனாதிபதியின் ஊடகப் பிரிவு (PMD) படி, ஜனாதிபதி விக்ரமசிங்க இன்று காலை எழுத்து மூலம் இது தொடர்பான கோரிக்கையை முன்வைத்துள்ளார்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஊடகப் பிரிவு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "பிஎம்டி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று காலை",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}