{
  "newspaper_id": "daily-mirror-lk",
  "url": "https://www.dailymirror.lk/business-news/Oil-prices-drop-ahead-of-potential-large-United-States-rate-hike/273-241136",
  "time_ut": 1657859839,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Oil prices drop ahead of potential large United States rate hike",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Oil prices drop ahead of potential large United States rate hike",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "REUTERS: Oil prices fell yesterday as investors focused on the prospect of a large U.S. rate hike that could stem inflation but at the same time hit oil demand.",
        "Brent crude futures for September were down 18 cents to US$ 99.39 a barrel at 0727 GMT after settling below US$ 100 for the second straight session on Wednesday.",
        "U.S. West Texas Intermediate crude for August delivery was at US$ 95.84 a barrel, down 43 cents.",
        "Oil prices have tumbled in the past two weeks on recession concerns despite a drop in crude and refined products exports from Russia amid Western sanctions and supply disruption in Libya.",
        "“Clearly, focus is now on the demand side of the oil equation. Yesterday’s weekly EIA (U.S. Energy Information Administration) report showed sizeable builds in product inventories,” Tamas Varga, analyst at PVM Oil Associates, said.",
        "The Fed rate hike is expected to follow a similar surprise move by the Bank of Canada on Wednesday.",
        "Investors also flocked to the dollar, often seen as a safe haven asset. The dollar index hit a 20-year high on Wednesday, which makes oil purchases more expensive for non-U.S. buyers.",
        "Worries of COVID-19 curbs in multiple Chinese cities to rein in new cases of a highly infectious subvariant have also kept a lid on oil prices.",
        "China’s daily crude oil imports in June sank to their lowest since July 2018, as refiners anticipated lockdown measures to curb demand, customs data showed on Wednesday.",
        "Data from the U.S. Energy Information Administration also point to slackening demand, with product supplied slumping to 18.7 million barrels per day, the lowest since June 2021. Crude inventories rose, bolstered by another big release from strategic reserves.",
        "U.S. President Joe Biden will on Friday fly to Saudi Arabia, where he will attend a summit of Gulf allies and call for them to pump more oil.",
        "However, spare capacity at the Organization of the Petroleum Exporting Countries is running low, with most of the producers pumping at maximum capacity, and it is unclear how much extra Saudi Arabia can bring into the market quickly."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "United States",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "yesterday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "U.S.",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "September",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "18 cents",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "99.39",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "GMT",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "100",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "second",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Wednesday",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "U.S.",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "August",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "95.84",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "43 cents",
            "label": "MONEY"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the past two weeks",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Russia",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Libya",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Yesterday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "weekly",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "EIA",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "U.S. Energy Information Administration",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Tamas Varga",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "PVM Oil Associates",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Fed",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Bank of Canada",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Wednesday",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "20-year",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Wednesday",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Chinese",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "China",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "daily",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "June",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "July 2018",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Wednesday",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the U.S. Energy Information Administration",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "18.7 million barrels",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "June 2021",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "U.S.",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Joe Biden",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Friday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Saudi Arabia",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Gulf",
            "label": "LOC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the Organization of the Petroleum Exporting Countries",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Saudi Arabia",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "විභව විශාල එක්සත් ජනපද අනුපාත ඉහල දැමීමට පෙර තෙල් මිල පහත වැටේ",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "REUTERS: උද්ධමනය නැවැත්විය හැකි නමුත් ඒ සමඟම තෙල් ඉල්ලුමට පහර දෙන විශාල එක්සත් ජනපද අනුපාත ඉහල දැමීමේ අපේක්ෂාව කෙරෙහි ආයෝජකයින් අවධානය යොමු කිරීම නිසා ඊයේ තෙල් මිල පහත වැටුනි.",
        "සැප්තැම්බර් සඳහා බ්‍රෙන්ට් බොරතෙල් අනාගතය බදාදා දෙවන අඛණ්ඩ සැසිය සඳහා ඇමරිකානු ඩොලර් 100 ට වඩා අඩුවෙන් පසු 0727 GMT ට බැරලයක් ඩොලර් 99.39 ක් දක්වා ශත 18 කින් අඩු විය.",
        "අගෝස්තු මාසයේ බෙදාහැරීම සඳහා එක්සත් ජනපද බටහිර ටෙක්සාස් අතරමැදි බොරතෙල් බැරලයක් ඩොලර් 95.84 ක් වූ අතර එය ශත 43 කින් අඩු විය.",
        "බටහිර සම්බාධක සහ ලිබියාවේ සැපයුම් කඩාකප්පල් කිරීම් මධ්‍යයේ රුසියාවෙන් බොරතෙල් සහ පිරිපහදු කළ නිෂ්පාදන අපනයන පහත වැටීමක් තිබියදීත් පසුබෑමේ උත්සුකයන් මත පසුගිය සති දෙක තුළ තෙල් මිල පහත වැටී ඇත.",
        "“පැහැදිලිවම, දැන් අවධානය යොමු කර ඇත්තේ තෙල් සමීකරණයේ ඉල්ලුම පැත්තට ය. ඊයේ සතිපතා EIA (එක්සත් ජනපද බලශක්ති තොරතුරු පරිපාලනය) වාර්තාව නිෂ්පාදන ඉන්වෙන්ටරිවල සැලකිය යුතු වර්ධනයක් පෙන්නුම් කළේය, ”PVM Oil Associates හි විශ්ලේෂක Tamas Varga පැවසීය.",
        "ෆෙඩරල් මහ බැංකුවේ අනුපාත ඉහල දැමීම බදාදා කැනඩාවේ බැංකුව විසින් සිදු කරන ලද සමාන විස්මිත පියවරක් අනුගමනය කරනු ඇතැයි අපේක්ෂා කෙරේ.",
        "ආයෝජකයින් ද ඩොලරය වෙත ගලා ආ අතර, බොහෝ විට ආරක්ෂිත තෝතැන්නක් ලෙස සැලකේ. ඩොලරයේ දර්ශකය බදාදා වසර 20 ක ඉහළම මට්ටමට ළඟා වූ අතර එමඟින් එක්සත් ජනපද නොවන ගැනුම්කරුවන් සඳහා තෙල් මිලදී ගැනීම් මිල අධික වේ.",
        "අධික ලෙස බෝවන උප ප්‍රභේදයක නව අවස්ථා පාලනය කිරීම සඳහා බහු චීන නගරවල COVID-19 සීමා කිරීම් පිළිබඳ කනස්සල්ල ද තෙල් මිල මත පියනක් තබා ඇත.",
        "ඉල්ලුම මැඩපැවැත්වීම සඳහා පිරිපහදු කරන්නන් අගුලු දැමීමේ පියවරයන් අපේක්ෂා කරන බැවින්, ජුනි මාසයේදී චීනයේ දෛනික බොරතෙල් ආනයනය 2018 ජූලි මාසයේ සිට අවම මට්ටමට පහත වැටුණි, රේගු දත්ත බදාදා පෙන්වා දුන්නේය.",
        "එක්සත් ජනපද බලශක්ති තොරතුරු පරිපාලනයේ දත්ත ද, ඉල්ලුම අඩුවීම පෙන්නුම් කරයි, නිෂ්පාදිතය දිනකට බැරල් මිලියන 18.7 දක්වා පහත වැටීමත් සමඟ, 2021 ජූනි මාසයෙන් පසු අඩුම අගයයි. උපායමාර්ගික සංචිතවලින් තවත් විශාල නිකුතුවක් මගින් බොරතෙල් බඩු තොග ඉහළ ගියේය.",
        "එක්සත් ජනපද ජනාධිපති ජෝ බයිඩන් සිකුරාදා සෞදි අරාබියට පියාසර කරනු ඇති අතර එහිදී ඔහු ගල්ෆ් මිත්‍ර රටවල සමුළුවකට සහභාගී වී තවත් තෙල් පොම්ප කරන ලෙස ඉල්ලා සිටී.",
        "කෙසේ වෙතත්, ඛනිජ තෙල් අපනයනය කරන රටවල සංවිධානයේ අමතර ධාරිතාව අඩු වෙමින් පවතින අතර, බොහෝ නිෂ්පාදකයින් උපරිම ධාරිතාවයෙන් පොම්ප කරන අතර, සෞදි අරාබියට කොපමණ අමතර ප්‍රමාණයක් ඉක්මනින් වෙළඳපොළට ගෙන යා හැකිද යන්න පැහැදිලි නැත."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "එක්සත් ජනපදය",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ඊයේ",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "එක්සත් ජනපදය.",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "සැප්තැම්බර්",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශත 18 යි",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "99.39 කි",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "GMT",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "100",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "දෙවැනි",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "බදාදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "එක්සත් ජනපදය.",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "අගෝස්තු",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "95.84 කි",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශත 43 යි",
            "label": "MONEY"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "පසුගිය සති දෙක",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "රුසියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ලිබියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ඊයේ",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "සතිපතා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "EIA",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "එක්සත් ජනපද බලශක්ති තොරතුරු පරිපාලනය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "තමස් වර්ග",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "පීවීඑම් ඔයිල් ඇසෝසියේට්ස්",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ෆෙඩරල්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "කැනඩාවේ බැංකුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "බදාදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "අවුරුදු 20ක්",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "බදාදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "චීන",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "චීනය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "දිනපතා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජූනි",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "2018 ජූලි",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "බදාදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "එක්සත් ජනපද බලශක්ති තොරතුරු පරිපාලනය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "බැරල් මිලියන 18.7 කි",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "2021 ජූනි",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "එක්සත් ජනපදය.",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Joe Biden",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "සිකුරාදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "සවුදි අරාබිය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගල්ෆ්",
            "label": "LOC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ඛනිජ තෙල් අපනයනය කරන රටවල සංවිධානය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "සවුදි අරාබිය",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "அமெரிக்காவின் சாத்தியமான பெரிய விலை உயர்வுக்கு முன்னதாக எண்ணெய் விலைகள் குறைகின்றன",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "REUTERS: முதலீட்டாளர்கள் பணவீக்கத்தைத் தடுக்கக்கூடிய பெரிய அமெரிக்க விகித உயர்வின் வாய்ப்பில் கவனம் செலுத்தியதால் எண்ணெய் விலை நேற்று வீழ்ச்சியடைந்தது, ஆனால் அதே நேரத்தில் எண்ணெய் தேவையை பாதிக்கிறது.",
        "செப்டம்பர் மாதத்திற்கான ப்ரெண்ட் கச்சா எண்ணெய் 18 சென்ட்கள் குறைந்து 0727 GMT இல் ஒரு பீப்பாய் 99.39 அமெரிக்க டாலர்களாக இருந்தது",
        "ஆகஸ்ட் டெலிவரிக்கான யு.எஸ். வெஸ்ட் டெக்சாஸ் இன்டர்மீடியட் கச்சா எண்ணெய் ஒரு பீப்பாய்க்கு 43 காசுகள் குறைந்து 95.84 அமெரிக்க டாலராக இருந்தது.",
        "மேற்கத்திய பொருளாதாரத் தடைகள் மற்றும் லிபியாவில் விநியோக இடையூறுகளுக்கு மத்தியில் ரஷ்யாவிலிருந்து கச்சா மற்றும் சுத்திகரிக்கப்பட்ட பொருட்களின் ஏற்றுமதியில் சரிவு இருந்தபோதிலும், மந்தநிலை கவலைகளால் கடந்த இரண்டு வாரங்களாக எண்ணெய் விலைகள் சரிந்தன.",
        "\"தெளிவாக, இப்போது கவனம் எண்ணெய் சமன்பாட்டின் தேவை பக்கத்தில் உள்ளது. நேற்றைய வாராந்திர EIA (U.S. எனர்ஜி இன்ஃபர்மேஷன் அட்மினிஸ்ட்ரேஷன்) அறிக்கை, தயாரிப்பு சரக்குகளில் கணிசமான வளர்ச்சியைக் காட்டியது,” என்று PVM Oil Associates இன் ஆய்வாளர் Tamas Varga கூறினார்.",
        "பெடரல் வட்டி விகித உயர்வு புதன்கிழமை கனடா வங்கியின் இதேபோன்ற ஆச்சரியமான நடவடிக்கையைத் தொடர்ந்து வரும் என்று எதிர்பார்க்கப்படுகிறது.",
        "முதலீட்டாளர்களும் டாலரை நோக்கி குவிந்தனர், இது பெரும்பாலும் பாதுகாப்பான சொத்தாகக் கருதப்படுகிறது. டாலர் குறியீடு புதன்கிழமை 20 ஆண்டு உயர்வை எட்டியது, இது அமெரிக்க அல்லாத வாங்குபவர்களுக்கு எண்ணெய் வாங்குவதை அதிக விலைக்கு ஆக்குகிறது.",
        "பல சீன நகரங்களில் COVID-19 கட்டுப்பாடுகள் பற்றிய கவலைகள், அதிக தொற்றுள்ள துணை மாறுபாட்டின் புதிய நிகழ்வுகளைக் கட்டுப்படுத்தவும் எண்ணெய் விலையில் ஒரு மூடியை வைத்திருக்கிறது.",
        "ஜூன் மாதத்தில் சீனாவின் தினசரி கச்சா எண்ணெய் இறக்குமதி ஜூலை 2018 க்குப் பிறகு மிகக் குறைந்தது, சுத்திகரிப்பாளர்கள் தேவையைக் கட்டுப்படுத்த பூட்டுதல் நடவடிக்கைகளை எதிர்பார்த்ததால், சுங்கத் தரவு புதன்கிழமை காட்டியது.",
        "யு.எஸ். எனர்ஜி இன்ஃபர்மேஷன் அட்மினிஸ்ட்ரேஷன் தரவானது தேவை குறைந்து வருவதையும் சுட்டிக்காட்டுகிறது, தயாரிப்பு விநியோகம் நாளொன்றுக்கு 18.7 மில்லியன் பீப்பாய்கள், ஜூன் 2021 க்குப் பிறகு மிகக் குறைவு. மூலோபாய இருப்புக்களில் இருந்து மற்றொரு பெரிய வெளியீட்டால் கச்சா சரக்குகள் அதிகரித்தன.",
        "அமெரிக்க ஜனாதிபதி ஜோ பிடன் வெள்ளிக்கிழமை சவூதி அரேபியாவுக்குச் செல்வார், அங்கு அவர் வளைகுடா நட்பு நாடுகளின் உச்சிமாநாட்டில் கலந்துகொண்டு அதிக எண்ணெய் பம்ப் செய்ய அழைப்பு விடுப்பார்.",
        "எவ்வாறாயினும், பெட்ரோலியம் ஏற்றுமதி செய்யும் நாடுகளின் அமைப்பில் உதிரி திறன் குறைவாக உள்ளது, பெரும்பாலான உற்பத்தியாளர்கள் அதிகபட்ச திறனில் பம்ப் செய்கிறார்கள், மேலும் சவுதி அரேபியா எவ்வளவு கூடுதல் சந்தைக்கு விரைவாக கொண்டு வர முடியும் என்பது தெளிவாகத் தெரியவில்லை."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "அமெரிக்கா",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "நேற்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "எங்களுக்கு.",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "செப்டம்பர்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "18 சென்ட்",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "99.39",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "GMT",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "100",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "இரண்டாவது",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "புதன்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "எங்களுக்கு.",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆகஸ்ட்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "95.84",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "43 சென்ட்",
            "label": "MONEY"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "கடந்த இரண்டு வாரங்கள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரஷ்யா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "லிபியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "நேற்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "வாரந்தோறும்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "EIA",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "யு.எஸ். எரிசக்தி தகவல் நிர்வாகம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "தாமஸ் வர்கா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "பிவிஎம் ஆயில் அசோசியேட்ஸ்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஊட்டி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "கனடா வங்கி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "புதன்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "20-ஆண்டு",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "புதன்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "சீன",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "சீனா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "தினசரி",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜூன்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜூலை 2018",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "புதன்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "யு.எஸ். எரிசக்தி தகவல் நிர்வாகம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "18.7 மில்லியன் பீப்பாய்கள்",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜூன் 2021",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "எங்களுக்கு.",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Joe Biden",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "வெள்ளி",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சவூதி அரேபியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "வளைகுடா",
            "label": "LOC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பெட்ரோலியம் ஏற்றுமதி செய்யும் நாடுகளின் அமைப்பு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "சவூதி அரேபியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}