{
  "newspaper_id": "ada-derana-lk",
  "url": "http://www.adaderana.lk/news/83500/shipment-of-40000-mt-of-fertilizer-expected-tomorrow",
  "time_ut": 1657252980,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Shipment of 40,000 MT of fertilizer expected tomorrow",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Shipment of 40,000 MT of fertilizer expected tomorrow",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "A shipment of 40,000 MT of fertilizer is expected to reach the island in the late hours of tomorrow (July 09).",
        "Meanwhile, another consignment of 25,000 MT of fertilizer is lined up to arrive in Colombo within the next two days.",
        "Fertilizer distribution process will commence on July 10 (Sunday) following the arrival of these shipments, according to the Ministry of Agriculture.",
        "Meanwhile, Agriculture Minister Mahinda Amaraweera, speaking to the media, said necessary financial provisions have already been allocated to distribute fertilizer stocks required for the Maha Season."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "40,000",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "tomorrow",
          "label": "DATE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "40,000",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "MT",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the late hours of tomorrow",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "July 09",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "25,000",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "the next two days",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "July 10",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sunday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Ministry of Agriculture",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Agriculture",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Mahinda Amaraweera",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Maha Season",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "හෙට පොහොර මෙට්‍රික් ටොන් 40,000ක් නැව්ගත කිරීමට බලාපොරොත්තු වේ",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "පොහොර මෙට්‍රික් ටොන් 40,000ක තොගයක් හෙට (ජුලි 09) අගභාගයේදී දිවයිනට පැමිණීමට අපේක්ෂා කෙරේ.",
        "මේ අතර ඉදිරි දින දෙක තුළ තවත් මෙට්‍රික් ටොන් 25,000ක පොහොර තොගයක් කොළඹට පැමිණීමට නියමිතයි.",
        "මෙම පොහොර තොග පැමිණීමෙන් පසු පොහොර බෙදා හැරීමේ ක්‍රියාවලිය ජූලි 10 (ඉරිදා) ආරම්භ වන බව කෘෂිකර්ම අමාත්‍යාංශය පවසයි.",
        "මේ අතර, කෘෂිකර්ම අමාත්‍ය මහින්ද අමරවීර මාධ්‍ය වෙත අදහස් දක්වමින් කියා සිටියේ මහ කන්නයට අවශ්‍ය පොහොර තොග බෙදා හැරීමට අවශ්‍ය මුල්‍ය ප්‍රතිපාදන දැනටමත් වෙන් කර ඇති බවයි."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "40,000 කි",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "හෙට",
          "label": "DATE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "40,000 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "එම්.ටී",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "හෙට අග පැය",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජූලි 09",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "25,000 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉදිරි දින දෙක",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ජූලි 10",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉරිදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "කෘෂිකර්ම අමාත්‍යාංශය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "කෘෂිකර්ම",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "මහින්ද අමරවීර",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "මහ කන්නය",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "நாளை 40,000 மெட்ரிக் டன் உரம் ஏற்றுமதி செய்யப்படும் என எதிர்பார்க்கப்படுகிறது",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "40,000 மெட்ரிக் டன் உரம் நாளை (ஜூலை 09) பிற்பகுதியில் தீவை வந்தடையும் என்று எதிர்பார்க்கப்படுகிறது.",
        "இதேவேளை, 25,000 மெட்ரிக் தொன் உரம் அடுத்த இரண்டு நாட்களுக்குள் கொழும்புக்கு வருவதற்கு வரிசையாக உள்ளது.",
        "இந்த ஏற்றுமதிகள் வந்ததைத் தொடர்ந்து உர விநியோகம் ஜூலை 10 ஆம் தேதி (ஞாயிற்றுக்கிழமை) தொடங்கும் என்று விவசாய அமைச்சகம் தெரிவித்துள்ளது.",
        "இதேவேளை, விவசாய அமைச்சர் மஹிந்த அமரவீர ஊடகங்களுக்கு கருத்து தெரிவிக்கையில், மகா பருவத்திற்கு தேவையான உர இருப்புக்களை விநியோகிப்பதற்கு தேவையான நிதி ஒதுக்கீடுகள் ஏற்கனவே ஒதுக்கப்பட்டுள்ளதாக தெரிவித்தார்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "40,000",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "நாளை",
          "label": "DATE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "40,000",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "எம்டி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "நாளை பிற்பகுதியில்",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜூலை 09",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "25,000",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "அடுத்த இரண்டு நாட்கள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஜூலை 10",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஞாயிற்றுக்கிழமை",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "விவசாய அமைச்சகம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "வேளாண்மை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "மஹிந்த அமரவீர",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "மகா பருவம்",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}