{
  "newspaper_id": "daily-mirror-lk",
  "url": "https://www.dailymirror.lk/breaking_news/Slain-Japanese-PMs-funeral-tomorrow-SL-declares-day-of-mourning/108-240781",
  "time_ut": 1657509677,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Slain Japanese PM’s funeral tomorrow; SL declares day of mourning",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Slain Japanese PM’s funeral tomorrow; SL declares day of mourning",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "Tomorrow, the country will observe a state of mourning as a mark of respect to the longest served late Japanese Prime Minister Shinzo Abe.",
        "The day of mourning was declared by the Home Affairs Ministry as the slain leader will be laid to rest tomorrow.",
        "Tomorrow's mourning day will not affect the functions of the state sector and it will not be considered as a government holiday.",
        "The Home Affairs ministry informed all state institutions to fly the National flag at half mast.",
        "The former Japanese Premier had played a major role in strengthening ties between the two nations.",
        "The body of slain Shinzo Abe was brought to his home city Tokyo on Saturday (10), the day after he was shot and fatally wounded by a gunman and succumbed to his injuries during a campaign where he was delivering a speech in the western Japanese city of Nara. Japanese media reported that a night vigil is to be held on today, before the funeral tomorrow. (Chaturanga Samarawickrama)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Japanese PM’s",
          "label": "TIME"
        },
        {
          "text": "tomorrow",
          "label": "DATE"
        },
        {
          "text": "SL",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Tomorrow",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Japanese",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Shinzo Abe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the Home Affairs Ministry",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "tomorrow",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Tomorrow",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Home Affairs ministry",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "half",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Japanese",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "two",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Shinzo Abe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Tokyo",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Saturday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "10",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "the day",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Japanese",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Nara",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Japanese",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "tomorrow",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Chaturanga Samarawickrama",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "මියගිය ජපාන අගමැතිගේ අවසන් කටයුතු හෙට ශ්‍රී ලංකාව ශෝක දිනයක් ප්‍රකාශ කරයි",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "දීර්ඝතම කාලයක් සේවය කළ අභාවප්‍රාප්ත ජපාන අග්‍රාමාත්‍ය ෂින්සෝ අබේ මහතාට ගෞරව දැක්වීමක් ලෙස හෙට රට ශෝක ප්‍රකාශයක් පවත්වනු ඇත.",
        "ඝාතනයට ලක්වූ නායකයාගේ අවසන් කටයුතු හෙට සිදුකිරීමට නියමිත බැවින් ස්වදේශ කටයුතු අමාත්‍යාංශය විසින් ශෝක දිනයක් ප්‍රකාශයට පත් කර තිබේ.",
        "හෙට ශෝක දිනය රාජ්‍ය අංශයේ කටයුතුවලට බලපාන්නේ නැති අතර එය රජයේ නිවාඩු දිනයක් ලෙස නොසැලකේ.",
        "ජාතික ධජය අඩකුඹු කරන ලෙස ස්වදේශ කටයුතු අමාත්‍යාංශය සියලුම රාජ්‍ය ආයතනවලට දැනුම් දුන්නා.",
        "හිටපු ජපාන අග්‍රාමාත්‍යවරයා දෙරට අතර සබඳතා ශක්තිමත් කිරීමට විශාල කාර්යභාරයක් ඉටු කළේය.",
        "ඝාතනයට ලක් වූ ෂින්සෝ අබේගේ දේහය සෙනසුරාදා (10) ඔහුගේ උපන් නගරය වන ටෝකියෝ වෙත ගෙන එන ලද අතර, ඔහු බටහිර ජපාන නගරයේ දේශනයක් පවත්වමින් සිටි ප්‍රචාරක ව්‍යාපාරයක් අතරතුර තුවක්කුකරුවෙකු විසින් වෙඩි තබා මාරාන්තික තුවාල ලබා තුවාල ලබා මිය ගියේය. නාරාගේ. ජපාන මාධ්‍ය වාර්තා කළේ දේහය පිළිබඳ අවසන් කටයුතු හෙටට පෙර අද රාත්‍රී සෝදිසි කිරීමක් සිදුකිරීමට නියමිත බවයි. (චතුරංග සමරවික්‍රම)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ජපන් අගමැති",
          "label": "TIME"
        },
        {
          "text": "හෙට",
          "label": "DATE"
        },
        {
          "text": "එස්.එල්",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "හෙට",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජපන්",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Shinzo Abe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ස්වදේශ කටයුතු අමාත්‍යාංශය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "හෙට",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "හෙට",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ස්වදේශ කටයුතු අමාත්‍යාංශය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "අඩක්",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ජපන්",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "දෙක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Shinzo Abe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ටෝකියෝ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "සෙනසුරාදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "10",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "දවස",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජපන්",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "නාරා",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජපන්",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "හෙට",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "චතුරංග සමරවික්‍රම",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "கொல்லப்பட்ட ஜப்பான் பிரதமரின் இறுதி ஊர்வலம் நாளை; SL துக்க நாளை அறிவிக்கிறது",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "நீண்ட காலம் பணியாற்றிய மறைந்த ஜப்பானிய பிரதமர் ஷின்சோ அபேக்கு மரியாதை செலுத்தும் வகையில் நாளை நாடு முழுவதும் துக்கம் அனுசரிக்கப்படுகிறது.",
        "கொல்லப்பட்ட தலைவரின் உடல் நாளை அடக்கம் செய்யப்பட உள்ளதால், உள்துறை அமைச்சகம் துக்க தினமாக அறிவித்துள்ளது.",
        "நாளைய துக்க நாள் அரசுத் துறையின் செயல்பாடுகளை பாதிக்காது மற்றும் அரசு விடுமுறையாகக் கருதப்படாது.",
        "தேசியக் கொடியை அரைக்கம்பத்தில் பறக்கவிடுமாறு அனைத்து அரசு நிறுவனங்களுக்கும் உள்துறை அமைச்சகம் அறிவுறுத்தியுள்ளது.",
        "இரு நாடுகளுக்கும் இடையிலான உறவுகளை வலுப்படுத்துவதில் முன்னாள் ஜப்பானிய பிரதமர் முக்கிய பங்கு வகித்தார்.",
        "கொல்லப்பட்ட ஷின்சோ அபேயின் உடல் சனிக்கிழமை (10) அவரது சொந்த நகரமான டோக்கியோவிற்கு கொண்டு வரப்பட்டது, அவர் மேற்கு ஜப்பானிய நகரத்தில் ஒரு பிரச்சாரத்தின் போது துப்பாக்கிதாரி ஒருவரால் சுடப்பட்டு படுகாயமடைந்து காயங்களுக்கு ஆளானார். நாராவின். நாளை இறுதிச் சடங்கிற்கு முன்னதாக இன்று இரவு விழிப்பு உணர்வு நடத்தப்பட உள்ளதாக ஜப்பானிய ஊடகங்கள் செய்தி வெளியிட்டுள்ளன. (சதுரங்க சமரவிக்ரம)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ஜப்பானிய பிரதமர்கள்",
          "label": "TIME"
        },
        {
          "text": "நாளை",
          "label": "DATE"
        },
        {
          "text": "எஸ்.எல்",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "நாளை",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜப்பானியர்",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Shinzo Abe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "உள்துறை அமைச்சகம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "நாளை",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "நாளை",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "உள்துறை அமைச்சகம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாதி",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஜப்பானியர்",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "இரண்டு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Shinzo Abe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "டோக்கியோ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சனிக்கிழமை",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "10",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "தினம்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜப்பானியர்",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "நாரா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜப்பானியர்",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "நாளை",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சதுரங்க சமரவிக்ரம",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}