{
  "newspaper_id": "economy-next-com",
  "url": "https://economynext.com/sri-lankas-cpc-in-shocking-rs628bn-loss-on-soft-pegging-loans-96895/",
  "time_ut": 1656933960,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Sri Lanka’s CPC in shocking Rs628bn loss on soft-pegging loans",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Sri Lanka’s CPC in shocking Rs628bn loss on soft-pegging loans",
      "author": "",
      "body_lines": [
        "ECONOMYNEXT – Sri Lanka’s state-run Ceylon Petroleum Corporation has lost 628 billion rupees in the first four months of 2022, driven by un-hedged dollar loans it was forced to take whenever the central bank printed money to create forex shortages.",
        "The CPC had borrowed over 3 billion dollars from two state banks after importing oil on credit without buying dollars in the market whenever the central bank printed money to manipulate rates and created forex shortages and currency crises in the course of operating a flexible inflation targeting regime.",
        "The CPC had made an operating loss Rs64.95 billion rupees, up from Rs15.7 billion a year earlier, as oil prices went up but the entire balance came from forex loss.",
        "“The exchange rate loss during the first four months of 2022 was Rs. 549,955 million compared to Rs. 26,738 million recorded in the same period of 2021,” a Finance Ministry report said.",
        "“This has led to the CPC ending up with an overall loss of Rs. 628,381 million at the end of April 2022.”",
        "The CPC had been forced to import oil on dated letters of credit when the central bank blocked market interest rate with printed money, creating forex shortages. The loans had accumulated in the 2016, 2018 and 2020 soft-peg crises.",
        "The LCs were then repaid with dollars from the two state banks, officials had revealed earlier.",
        "Nick Leeson-style losses at Sri Lanka’s CPC raise big questions: Bellwether",
        "Sri Lanka trying to re-finance billion dollar CPC ‘Nick Leeson’ loan from state banks: report",
        "Shock revelation on how Sri Lanka’s CPC ended up with billions of dollar debt",
        "Analysts have labeled the blunder a Nick Leeson style blunder coming from operating a soft-pegged exchange rate and output gap targeting.",
        "“The total liability payable to the two state banks as at 30.04.2022 has reached Rs. 1,223,635 million,” the finance ministry report said.",
        "“The CPC’s accumulated losses and negative net worth amounted to Rs. 1,047,391 million and Rs. 985,886 million, respectively as at end April 2022.:",
        "A Treasury guarantee of Rs 596.77 billion had been issued to the People’s Bank to cover its loan.",
        "A Treasury guarantee of Rs 593.99 billion had been issued to the Bank of Ceylon to cover its dollar loan to the CPC.",
        "CPC was made to borrow dollars after money was printed in 2015/2016 to boost inflation in 2018 and 2020 target an output gap creating forex shortages and making it difficult for the CPC to exchagne rupees for dollar as the credibility of the peg was broken.",
        "Like the CPC the central government also borrowed dollars through sovereign bonds to repay dollar loans as the ability to exchange rupees for dollars was lost.",
        "Instead of sterilizing inflows to repay maturing bonds more bonds were borrowed through an active liability management (ALM) law, leading a steep rise in foreign central government debt.",
        "Analysts and economists have called for the monetary law to be tightened to take away the independence of the central to print money at will to manipulate interests rates, de-stabilize the currency and create forex shortages.",
        "Sri Lanka is now facing severe forex shortages and steep depreciation after failed attempt to switch to a floating regime. (Colombo/July04/2022)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Sri Lanka’s",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "CPC",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "Rs628bn",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka’s",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ceylon Petroleum Corporation",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "628 billion",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "the first four months of 2022",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "un",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "CPC",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "over 3 billion dollars",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "two",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "CPC",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "billion",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Rs15.7 billion",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "a year earlier",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the first four months of 2022",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "549,955 million",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "26,738 million",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "the same period of",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "2021",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Finance Ministry",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "CPC",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "628,381 million",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "the end of April 2022",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "CPC",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the 2016, 2018",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "2020",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "two",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Nick Leeson",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka’s",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "CPC",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Bellwether",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "billion dollar",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "CPC",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Nick Leeson",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka’s",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "CPC",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "billions of dollar",
            "label": "MONEY"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Nick Leeson",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "two",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "1,223,635 million",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "CPC",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "1,047,391 million",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "985,886 million",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "April 2022",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Treasury",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "596.77 billion",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "the People’s Bank",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Treasury",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "593.99 billion",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Bank of Ceylon",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "CPC",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "CPC",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "2015/2016",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "2018",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "2020",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "CPC",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "CPC",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ALM",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "ශ්‍රී ලංකා ඛනිජ තෙල් නීතිගත සංස්ථාවට සහනදායී ණය මත රුපියල් බිලියන 628 ක කම්පන සහගත පාඩුවක්",
      "author": "",
      "body_lines": [
        "ECONOMYNEXT - විදේශ විනිමය හිඟයක් ඇති කිරීම සඳහා මහ බැංකුව මුදල් මුද්‍රණය කළ සෑම අවස්ථාවකම ගැනීමට සිදු වූ රක්‍ෂණ රහිත ඩොලර් ණය හේතුවෙන් ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ රජය විසින් පවත්වාගෙන යනු ලබන ලංකා ඛනිජ තෙල් නීතිගත සංස්ථාවට 2022 පළමු මාස ​​හතර තුළ රුපියල් බිලියන 628 ක් අහිමි වී ඇත.",
        "නම්‍යශීලී උද්ධමනය ඉලක්ක කරගත් පාලන තන්ත්‍රයක් ක්‍රියාත්මක කිරීමේදී මහ බැංකුව මුදල් අනුපාත හසුරුවා ගැනීම සඳහා මුදල් මුද්‍රණය කර විදේශ විනිමය හිඟය සහ මුදල් අර්බුද ඇති කළ සෑම අවස්ථාවකදීම වෙළඳපොලේ ඩොලර් මිලදී නොගෙන ණයට තෙල් ආනයනය කිරීමෙන් පසු CPC විසින් රාජ්‍ය බැංකු දෙකකින් ඩොලර් බිලියන 3 කට අධික මුදලක් ණයට ගෙන තිබුණි.",
        "තෙල් මිල ඉහළ ගිය නමුත් සමස්ත ශේෂය විදේශ විනිමය අලාභය නිසා CPC විසින් රුපියල් බිලියන 64.95 ක මෙහෙයුම් අලාභයක් ලබා ඇති අතර එය පෙර වසරකට රුපියල් බිලියන 15.7 සිට ඉහළ ගොස් ඇත.",
        "“2022 පළමු මාස ​​හතර තුළ විනිමය අනුපාත අලාභය රු. මිලියන 549,955 ට සාපේක්ෂව රු. 2021 එම කාල සීමාව තුළ මිලියන 26,738 ක් වාර්තා වී ඇත, ”මුදල් අමාත්‍යාංශයේ වාර්තාවක සඳහන් වේ.",
        "\"මෙය CPC හි සමස්ත පාඩුව රු. 2022 අප්‍රේල් මස අවසානයේදී රුපියල් මිලියන 628,381ක්.",
        "විදේශ විනිමය හිඟයක් ඇති කරමින් මහ බැංකුව මුද්‍රිත මුදල් සමඟ වෙළඳපොළ පොලී අනුපාතිකය අවහිර කළ විට දිනැති ණයවර ලිපි මත තෙල් ආනයනය කිරීමට ඛනිජ තෙල් නීතිගත සංස්ථාවට සිදු විය. 2016, 2018 සහ 2020 සොෆ්ට්-පෙග් අර්බුද වලදී ණය එකතු වී ඇත.",
        "පසුව එම LC සඳහා රාජ්‍ය බැංකු දෙකෙන් ඩොලර් වලින් ආපසු ගෙවා ඇති බව නිලධාරීන් මීට පෙර අනාවරණය කර තිබුණි.",
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ CPC හි නික් ලීසන් ආකාරයේ පාඩු විශාල ප්‍රශ්න මතු කරයි: බෙල්වෙදර්",
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකාව රාජ්‍ය බැංකුවලින් ඩොලර් බිලියනයක CPC ‘නික් ලීසන්’ ණය ප්‍රති-මූල්‍ය කිරීමට උත්සාහ කරයි: වාර්තාව",
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ CPC ඩොලර් බිලියන ගණනක ණයවලින් අවසන් වූ ආකාරය පිළිබඳ කම්පන හෙළිදරව්ව",
        "විශ්ලේෂකයින් විසින් මෙම වරද නික් ලීසන් පන්නයේ වරදක් ලෙස නම් කර ඇත්තේ මෘදු විනිමය අනුපාතිකයක් සහ ප්‍රතිදාන පරතරය ඉලක්ක කර ගනිමින් ක්‍රියාත්මක වීමෙනි.",
        "“2022.04.30 දිනට රාජ්‍ය බැංකු දෙකට ගෙවිය යුතු සම්පූර්ණ වගකීම රු. මිලියන 1,223,635ක්” යැයි මුදල් අමාත්‍යාංශ වාර්තාව සඳහන් කරයි.",
        "\"CPC හි සමුච්චිත පාඩු සහ සෘණ ශුද්ධ වටිනාකම රු. මිලියන 1,047,391 ක් සහ රු. 2022 අප්‍රේල් අවසන් වන විට පිළිවෙලින් මිලියන 985,886.:",
        "මහජන බැංකුවේ ණය පියවීම සඳහා රුපියල් බිලියන 596.77ක භාණ්ඩාගාර ඇපකරයක් නිකුත් කර තිබුණි.",
        "තෙල් සංස්ථාවට ලබාදුන් ඩොලර් ණය පියවීම සඳහා රුපියල් බිලියන 593.99 ක භාණ්ඩාගාර ඇපයක් ලංකා බැංකුව වෙත නිකුත් කර තිබුණි.",
        "2018 සහ 2020 දී උද්ධමනය ඉහළ නැංවීම සඳහා 2015/2016 දී මුදල් මුද්‍රණය කිරීමෙන් පසු CPC ඩොලර් ණයට ගැනීමට සිදු කරන ලද්දේ විදේශ විනිමය හිඟයක් ඇති කරමින් නිමැවුම් පරතරයක් ඉලක්ක කර ගනිමින් CPC ට ඩොලරයේ විශ්වසනීයත්වය බිඳී යාම නිසා ඩොලරයට රුපියල් හුවමාරු කර ගැනීම දුෂ්කර කරමිනි.",
        "CPC වගේම මධ්‍යම රජයත් ඩොලර් ණය ගෙවීම සඳහා ස්වෛරී බැඳුම්කර හරහා ඩොලර් ණයට ගත්තේ රුපියල් ඩොලර්වලට හුවමාරු කර ගැනීමේ හැකියාව නැති වූ නිසයි.",
        "කල් පිරෙන බැඳුම්කර ආපසු ගෙවීම සඳහා ගලා එන ගලා ඒම විෂබීජහරණය කිරීම වෙනුවට ක්‍රියාකාරී වගකීම් කළමනාකරණ (ALM) නීතියක් හරහා තවත් බැඳුම්කර ණයට ගන්නා ලද අතර එය විදේශ මධ්‍යම රජයේ නය දැඩි ලෙස ඉහළ යාමට හේතු විය.",
        "පොලී අනුපාත හැසිරවීමට, මුදල් අස්ථාවර කිරීමට සහ විදේශ විනිමය හිඟයක් ඇති කිරීමට රිසි සේ මුදල් මුද්‍රණය කිරීමට මධ්‍යමයේ ස්වාධීනත්වය උදුරා ගැනීම සඳහා මුදල් නීතිය දැඩි කළ යුතු බව විශ්ලේෂකයින් සහ ආර්ථික විද්‍යාඥයින් ඉල්ලා ඇත.",
        "පාවෙන පාලන තන්ත්‍රයකට මාරුවීමේ අසාර්ථක උත්සාහයෙන් පසු ශ්‍රී ලංකාව දැන් දැඩි විදේශ විනිමය හිඟයකට හා දැඩි ක්ෂයවීම්වලට මුහුණ දී සිටී. (කොළඹ/ජූලි04/2022)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "CPC",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "රුපියල් බිලියන 628 කි",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ලංකා ඛනිජ තෙල් නීතිගත සංස්ථාව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "බිලියන 628 කි",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "2022 පළමු මාස ​​හතර",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "un",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "CPC",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඩොලර් බිලියන 3 කට වඩා",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "දෙක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "CPC",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "බිලියන",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "රුපියල් බිලියන 15.7 කි",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "වසරකට පෙර",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "2022 පළමු මාස ​​හතර",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මිලියන 549,955 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "මිලියන 26,738 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "එකම කාල පරිච්ඡේදය",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "2021",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මුදල් අමාත්යාංශය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "CPC",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "මිලියන 628,381 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "2022 අප්රේල් අවසානයේ",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "CPC",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "2016, 2018",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "2020",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "දෙක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "නික් ලීසන්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "CPC",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "බෙල්වෙදර්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඩොලර් බිලියන",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "CPC",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "නික් ලීසන්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "CPC",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඩොලර් බිලියන ගණනක්",
            "label": "MONEY"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "නික් ලීසන්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "දෙක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "මිලියන 1,223,635 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "CPC",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "මිලියන 1,047,391 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "මිලියන 985,886 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "අප්රේල් 2022",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "භාණ්ඩාගාර",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "බිලියන 596.77 කි",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "මහජන බැංකුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "භාණ්ඩාගාර",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "බිලියන 593.99 කි",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "ලංකා බැංකුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "CPC",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "CPC",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "2015/2016",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "2018",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "2020",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "CPC",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "CPC",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ALM",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "இலங்கையின் CPC க்கு அதிர்ச்சியளிக்கும் வகையில் 628 பில்லியன் ரூபாய் நஷ்டம்",
      "author": "",
      "body_lines": [
        "பொருளாதாரம் - இலங்கையின் அரச நிறுவனமான சிலோன் பெட்ரோலியம் கூட்டுத்தாபனம் 2022 ஆம் ஆண்டின் முதல் நான்கு மாதங்களில் 628 பில்லியன் ரூபாவை இழந்துள்ளது, இது அந்நியச் செலாவணி பற்றாக்குறையை உருவாக்க மத்திய வங்கி பணத்தை அச்சடிக்கும் போதெல்லாம் எடுக்க வேண்டிய கட்டாயம் ஏற்பட்டது.",
        "மத்திய வங்கி விகிதங்களைக் கையாள்வதற்காக பணத்தை அச்சடித்து, நெகிழ்வான பணவீக்கத்தை இலக்காகக் கொண்ட ஆட்சியின் போக்கில் அந்நிய செலாவணி பற்றாக்குறை மற்றும் நாணய நெருக்கடிகளை உருவாக்கும் போதெல்லாம் சந்தையில் டாலர்களை வாங்காமல் கடனில் எண்ணெய் இறக்குமதி செய்த பின்னர் CPC இரண்டு அரசு வங்கிகளிடமிருந்து 3 பில்லியன் டாலர்களுக்கு மேல் கடன் வாங்கியது.",
        "CPC ஆனது ரூ64.95 பில்லியனை இயக்க நஷ்டத்தை ஈட்டியது, இது முந்தைய ஆண்டு ரூ.15.7 பில்லியனில் இருந்து அதிகரித்து, எண்ணெய் விலை உயர்ந்தது, ஆனால் மொத்த நிலுவை அந்நிய செலாவணி இழப்பிலிருந்து வந்தது.",
        "“2022 முதல் நான்கு மாதங்களில் மாற்று விகித இழப்பு ரூ. 549,955 மில்லியன் ரூபாயுடன் ஒப்பிடுகையில். 2021 ஆம் ஆண்டின் அதே காலகட்டத்தில் 26,738 மில்லியன் பதிவு செய்யப்பட்டுள்ளது” என்று நிதி அமைச்சக அறிக்கை தெரிவித்துள்ளது.",
        "“இது CPC மொத்த இழப்பில் ரூ. ஏப்ரல் 2022 இறுதியில் 628,381 மில்லியன்.",
        "அந்நிய செலாவணி பற்றாக்குறையை உருவாக்கி, அச்சிடப்பட்ட பணத்துடன் சந்தை வட்டி விகிதத்தை மத்திய வங்கி தடுத்தபோது, ​​தேதியிட்ட கடன் கடிதங்களில் எண்ணெய் இறக்குமதி செய்ய CPC கட்டாயப்படுத்தப்பட்டது. 2016, 2018 மற்றும் 2020 சாஃப்ட்-பெக் நெருக்கடிகளில் கடன்கள் குவிந்தன.",
        "LC கள் இரண்டு மாநில வங்கிகளிடமிருந்து டாலர்களுடன் திருப்பிச் செலுத்தப்பட்டன, அதிகாரிகள் முன்பு வெளிப்படுத்தினர்.",
        "இலங்கையின் CPC இல் நிக் லீசன் பாணி இழப்புகள் பெரிய கேள்விகளை எழுப்புகின்றன: பெல்வெதர்",
        "இலங்கை அரச வங்கிகளில் இருந்து பில்லியன் டொலர் CPC ‘நிக் லீசன்’ கடனை மறு நிதியளிப்பதற்கு முயற்சிக்கிறது: அறிக்கை",
        "இலங்கையின் CPC பில்லியன் கணக்கான டாலர் கடனுடன் எப்படி முடிந்தது என்பது பற்றிய அதிர்ச்சி வெளிப்பாடு",
        "பகுப்பாய்வாளர்கள் இந்த தவறுக்கு நிக் லீசன் பாணியிலான தவறு என்று பெயரிட்டுள்ளனர், இது ஒரு சாஃப்ட்-பெக் செய்யப்பட்ட மாற்று விகிதம் மற்றும் வெளியீட்டு இடைவெளியை இலக்காகக் கொண்டு செயல்படுவதால் வருகிறது.",
        "“30.04.2022 இல் இரண்டு ஸ்டேட் வங்கிகளுக்கும் செலுத்த வேண்டிய மொத்தப் பொறுப்பு ரூ. 1,223,635 மில்லியன்” என்று நிதி அமைச்சக அறிக்கை கூறியது.",
        "“CPCயின் திரட்டப்பட்ட இழப்புகள் மற்றும் எதிர்மறை நிகர மதிப்பு ரூ. 1,047,391 மில்லியன் மற்றும் ரூ. ஏப்ரல் 2022 இன் இறுதியில் முறையே 985,886 மில்லியன்.:",
        "மக்கள் வங்கியின் கடனை ஈடுசெய்வதற்காக 596.77 பில்லியன் ரூபா திறைசேரி உத்தரவாதம் வழங்கப்பட்டது.",
        "இலங்கை வங்கிக்கு CPCக்கான டொலர் கடனை ஈடுசெய்வதற்காக 593.99 பில்லியன் ரூபா திறைசேரி உத்தரவாதம் வழங்கப்பட்டுள்ளது.",
        "2018 மற்றும் 2020 இல் பணவீக்கத்தை அதிகரிக்க 2015/2016 இல் பணம் அச்சிடப்பட்ட பின்னர் CPC டாலர்களை கடனாகப் பெற்றது, இது அந்நிய செலாவணி பற்றாக்குறையை உருவாக்குகிறது மற்றும் CPC க்கு நாணயத்தின் நம்பகத்தன்மை உடைந்ததால், டாலருக்கு மாற்றுவது கடினம்.",
        "சிபிசியைப் போலவே மத்திய அரசும் டாலர் கடனைத் திருப்பிச் செலுத்த இறையாண்மைப் பத்திரங்கள் மூலம் டாலர்களைக் கடனாகப் பெற்றது.",
        "முதிர்ச்சியடையும் பத்திரங்களைத் திருப்பிச் செலுத்துவதற்கான வரவுகளை கிருமி நீக்கம் செய்வதற்குப் பதிலாக, செயலில் உள்ள பொறுப்பு மேலாண்மை (ALM) சட்டத்தின் மூலம் அதிக பத்திரங்கள் கடன் வாங்கப்பட்டன, இது வெளிநாட்டு மத்திய அரசாங்கக் கடனில் செங்குத்தான உயர்வுக்கு வழிவகுத்தது.",
        "வட்டி விகிதங்களைக் கையாளவும், நாணயத்தை நிலைநிறுத்தவும், அந்நிய செலாவணி பற்றாக்குறையை உருவாக்கவும், விருப்பப்படி பணத்தை அச்சிடுவதற்கு மத்திய அரசின் சுதந்திரத்தை பறிக்க, பணவியல் சட்டத்தை கடுமையாக்க வேண்டும் என்று ஆய்வாளர்கள் மற்றும் பொருளாதார நிபுணர்கள் அழைப்பு விடுத்துள்ளனர்.",
        "மிதக்கும் ஆட்சிக்கு மாறுவதற்கான முயற்சி தோல்வியடைந்ததை அடுத்து இலங்கை இப்போது கடுமையான அந்நிய செலாவணி பற்றாக்குறை மற்றும் செங்குத்தான தேய்மானத்தை எதிர்கொள்கிறது. (கொழும்பு/ஜூலை04/2022)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "இலங்கையின்",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "CPC",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "ரூ628 பில்லியன்",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கையின்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை பெற்றோலியக் கூட்டுத்தாபனம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "628 பில்லியன்",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "2022 இன் முதல் நான்கு மாதங்கள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஐ.நா",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "CPC",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "3 பில்லியன் டாலர்களுக்கு மேல்",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "இரண்டு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "CPC",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "பில்லியன்",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரூ15.7 பில்லியன்",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஒரு வருடம் முன்பு",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "2022 இன் முதல் நான்கு மாதங்கள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "549,955 மில்லியன்",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "26,738 மில்லியன்",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "அதே காலம்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "2021",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "நிதி அமைச்சகம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "CPC",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "628,381 மில்லியன்",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஏப்ரல் 2022 இறுதியில்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "CPC",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "2016, 2018",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "2020",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இரண்டு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "நிக் லீசன்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கையின்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "CPC",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "பெல்வெதர்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "பில்லியன் டாலர்",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "CPC",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "நிக் லீசன்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கையின்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "CPC",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "பில்லியன் டாலர்கள்",
            "label": "MONEY"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "நிக் லீசன்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இரண்டு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "1,223,635 மில்லியன்",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "CPC",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "1,047,391 மில்லியன்",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "985,886 மில்லியன்",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஏப்ரல் 2022",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "கருவூலம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "596.77 பில்லியன்",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "மக்கள் வங்கி",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "கருவூலம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "593.99 பில்லியன்",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை வங்கி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "CPC",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "CPC",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "2015/2016",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "2018",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "2020",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "CPC",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "CPC",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஏ.எல்.எம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}