{
  "newspaper_id": "news-first-lk",
  "url": "https://www.newsfirst.lk/2022/07/12/basl-calls-for-a-peaceful-transition-of-power/",
  "time_ut": 1657638720,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "BASL calls for a peaceful transition of power",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "BASL calls for a peaceful transition of power",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); The Bar Association of Sri Lanka (BASL) has called for a smooth and peaceful transition of power while abiding by the rule of law and Constitutionalism.",
        "Issuing a statement, the BASL says that the contribution and sacrifices made by the people of Sri Lanka seeking real change, during the past few months, are immeasurable.",
        "However, the BASL notes that it is equally important to ensure an orderly transition, and continuous respect for rule of law and Constitutionalism in Sri Lanka, to protect the lives of Sri Lankans and their livelihoods.",
        "Pointing out that the BASL has become deeply concerned with regard to statements attributed to various parties including those who were part of the protest groups which undermine the rule of law in Sri Lanka, the Bar Association says that it is in the best interests of the country that the country’s functions are continued as it is with respect to Constitutionalism.",
        "Commenting on the reports concerning vandalism by occupied groups and protestors at the President’s House, Temple Trees, and the Presidential Secretariat, the BASL calls upon those occupying the premises to ensure that proper authorities are given custody of the buildings, and to ensure the protection of documents and other public properties, which are of archaeological significance.",
        "Moreover, the BASL urges all parties to continue to find solutions for the current economic and political instability in a democratic manner, through an existing Constitutional framework and legal process, in addition to advocating for changes in a manner that does not undermine the administration of justice."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "News 1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "The Bar Association of Sri Lanka",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Constitutionalism",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "BASL",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the past few months",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "BASL",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lankans",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "BASL",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Bar Association",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "House",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Temple Trees",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "BASL",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "BASL",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Constitutional",
            "label": "LAW"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "BASL සාමකාමී බල සංක්‍රාන්තියක් ඉල්ලා සිටී",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); නීතියේ ආධිපත්‍යයට සහ ව්‍යවස්ථානුකූලභාවයට අවනත වෙමින් සුමට හා සාමකාමී බල සංක්‍රමණයක් සිදු කළ යුතු බව ශ්‍රී ලංකා නීතිඥ සංගමය (BASL) පවසයි.",
        "නිවේදනයක් නිකුත් කරමින් ශ්‍රී ලංකා BASL ආයතනය පවසන්නේ පසුගිය මාස කිහිපය තුළ සැබෑ වෙනසක් අපේක්ෂා කරන ශ්‍රී ලාංකීය ජනතාව විසින් සිදු කරන ලද දායකත්වය සහ කැපකිරීම් අපමණ බවයි.",
        "කෙසේ වෙතත්, ශ්‍රී ලාංකිකයින්ගේ ජීවිත සහ ඔවුන්ගේ ජීවනෝපාය ආරක්ෂා කිරීම සඳහා ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ නීතියේ ආධිපත්‍යයට සහ ව්‍යවස්ථාවට අඛණ්ඩව ගරු කිරීම, විධිමත් සංක්‍රාන්තියක් සහතික කිරීමත් එකසේ වැදගත් බව BASL සඳහන් කරයි.",
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ නීතියේ ආධිපත්‍යය කඩාකප්පල් කරන විරෝධතා කණ්ඩායම්වල කොටස්කරුවන් ඇතුළු විවිධ පාර්ශ්වයන් විසින් කරන ලද ප්‍රකාශ සම්බන්ධයෙන් BASL දැඩි අවධානයට ලක්ව ඇති බව පෙන්වා දෙන නීතිඥ සංගමය, එය රටේ යහපතට හේතු වන බව පවසයි. ආණ්ඩුක්‍රම ව්‍යවස්ථාව සම්බන්ධයෙන් රටේ ක්‍රියාකාරකම් පවතින ආකාරයටම පවත්වාගෙන යන බව.",
        "ජනාධිපති මන්දිරයේ, අරලියගහ මන්දිරයේ සහ ජනාධිපති ලේකම් කාර්යාලයේ වාඩිලාගෙන සිටින කණ්ඩායම් සහ විරෝධතාකරුවන් විසින් කඩාකප්පල් කිරීම් පිළිබඳ වාර්තා පිළිබඳව අදහස් දක්වමින් BASL එම ගොඩනැගිලිවල භාරකාරත්වය නිසි බලධාරීන්ට ලබා දෙන බවට සහතික වන ලෙස එම පරිශ්‍රයේ පදිංචිකරුවන්ගෙන් ඉල්ලා සිටී. පුරාවිද්‍යාත්මක වැදගත්කමක් ඇති ලේඛන සහ අනෙකුත් පොදු දේපල.",
        "තවද, යුක්තිය පසිඳලීමට බාධාවක් නොවන අයුරින් වෙනස්කම් සඳහා පෙනී සිටීමට අමතරව පවතින ව්‍යවස්ථාමය රාමුවක් සහ නෛතික ක්‍රියාවලියක් හරහා ප්‍රජාතන්ත්‍රවාදී ආකාරයෙන් වත්මන් ආර්ථික හා දේශපාලන අස්ථාවරත්වයට විසඳුම් සෙවීමට අඛණ්ඩව කටයුතු කරන ලෙස BASL සියලු පාර්ශවයන්ගෙන් ඉල්ලා සිටී. ."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "News 1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකා නීතිඥ සංගමය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ව්යවස්ථානුකූලවාදය",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "BASL",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "පසුගිය මාස කිහිපය",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "BASL",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලාංකිකයන්",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "BASL",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "නීතිඥ සංගමය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "නිවස",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "අරලියගහ මන්දිරය",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "BASL",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "BASL",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ව්යවස්ථාපිත",
            "label": "LAW"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "BASL அமைதியான அதிகார மாற்றத்திற்கு அழைப்பு விடுக்கிறது",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); இலங்கை சட்டத்தரணிகள் சங்கம் (BASL) சட்டத்தின் ஆட்சி மற்றும் அரசியலமைப்பிற்கு உட்பட்டு சுமூகமான மற்றும் அமைதியான அதிகார மாற்றத்திற்கு அழைப்பு விடுத்துள்ளது.",
        "கடந்த சில மாதங்களாக உண்மையான மாற்றத்தை விரும்பும் இலங்கை மக்கள் ஆற்றிய பங்களிப்பும் தியாகங்களும் அளவிட முடியாதவை என BASL அறிக்கையொன்றை வெளியிட்டுள்ளது.",
        "எவ்வாறாயினும், இலங்கையர்களின் உயிர்கள் மற்றும் அவர்களின் வாழ்வாதாரங்களைப் பாதுகாப்பதற்காக, இலங்கையில் சட்டத்தின் ஆட்சி மற்றும் அரசியலமைப்பிற்கு தொடர்ச்சியான மரியாதை மற்றும் ஒழுங்கான மாற்றத்தை உறுதிப்படுத்துவது சமமாக முக்கியமானது என்று BASL குறிப்பிடுகிறது.",
        "இலங்கையில் சட்டத்தின் ஆட்சியை சீர்குலைக்கும் போராட்டக் குழுக்களில் அங்கம் வகித்தவர்கள் உட்பட பல்வேறு தரப்பினரின் அறிக்கைகள் தொடர்பில் BASL ஆழ்ந்த கவலையடைந்துள்ளதாக சுட்டிக்காட்டியுள்ள சட்டத்தரணிகள் சங்கம், இது நாட்டின் நலனுக்கானது என தெரிவித்துள்ளது. அரசியலமைப்புச் சட்டத்தைப் பொறுத்த வரை நாட்டின் செயல்பாடுகள் தொடரும்.",
        "ஜனாதிபதி மாளிகை, அலரிமாளிகை மற்றும் ஜனாதிபதி செயலகம் ஆகியவற்றில் ஆக்கிரமிக்கப்பட்ட குழுக்கள் மற்றும் ஆர்ப்பாட்டக்காரர்களின் நாசவேலை தொடர்பான அறிக்கைகள் குறித்து கருத்து தெரிவித்த BASL, கட்டிடங்களை உரிய அதிகாரிகளுக்கு வழங்குவதை உறுதிசெய்யவும், கட்டிடங்களின் பாதுகாப்பை உறுதிப்படுத்தவும் வளாகத்தை ஆக்கிரமித்துள்ளவர்களை அழைக்கிறது. தொல்பொருள் முக்கியத்துவம் வாய்ந்த ஆவணங்கள் மற்றும் பிற பொது சொத்துக்கள்.",
        "மேலும், தற்போதைய பொருளாதார மற்றும் அரசியல் ஸ்திரமின்மைக்கான தீர்வுகளை ஜனநாயக முறையில், தற்போதுள்ள அரசியலமைப்பு கட்டமைப்பு மற்றும் சட்ட செயல்முறைகள் மூலம், நீதி நிர்வாகத்தை குறைமதிப்பிற்கு உட்படுத்தாத வகையில் மாற்றங்களை வாதிடுவதுடன், அனைத்து தரப்பினரையும் BASL கேட்டுக்கொள்கிறது. ."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "News 1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை சட்டத்தரணிகள் சங்கம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "அரசியலமைப்புவாதம்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "BASL",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "கடந்த சில மாதங்களாக",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "BASL",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கையர்கள்",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "BASL",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "வழக்கறிஞர் சங்கம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "வீடு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "கோவில் மரங்கள்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "BASL",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "BASL",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "அரசியலமைப்பு",
            "label": "LAW"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}