{
  "newspaper_id": "lankadeepa-lk",
  "url": "https://www.lankadeepa.lk/features/නොවේ-මෙවන්-කුමාරයෙක්-ලොවේ/2-618134",
  "time_ut": 1660550816,
  "original_lang": "si",
  "original_title": "නොවේ මෙවන් කුමාරයෙක් ලොවේ",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "There is no such prince in the world",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "Mahagama Sekaryan's beautiful poetry, Pandit Amaradeva's vocal personality and Lionel Algamyan's vocal composition have led to the success of this song. This Kali is the first male version of the Sinhala song dynasty.",
        "We have heard this kind of masculine praise before only from Yashodhara. After Prince Sidhu attained enlightenment, she praised her father's highly decorated Buddha image to her son Prince Rahula with great devotion.",
        "After attaining enlightenment, the Buddha visited Kapila Vastu Pura with the aim of visiting Yashodhara and his sons. Pointing out the way to the Buddha, Goddess Yashodhara gave her son Rahula an amazing praise of the Father in nine Narasiha Gathas.",
        "The way Goddess Yashodhara constructs the male characteristics of the Buddha through similes and similes is wonderful. Then Goddess Yashodhara, who had not attained the path, this Purusha vaṇḍu, which is performed by the samsara habit, cultivates faith towards the devotees of Buddha.",
        "Before thinking about the meaning of this song, let's first ask what the story behind it is.",
        "We hear the story of this song written by Mahagama Sekaran for the ballet \"Nala Damayanti\" composed by Chitra Senayan from Mahabharata.",
        "Nala Kumaran, who lived in the kingdom of Nishad, was a handsome young man with a beautiful appearance and a handsome body. He mastered the art of sword and archery. Being a righteous ruler, the countrymen also respected him.",
        "One day a character brought a wonderful message to the princes who were on duty. Charapurushaya gave wonderful praise to the princes about Princess Damayanti, the two-step daughter of King Bhima, the ruler of Vidarbha.",
        "Prince Nala fell in love with Princess Damayanti, who fell in love with her. Prince Damayanti courted Princess Damayanti secretly. One day Prince Nala, who was walking by the lake thinking about Princess Damayanti, met a beautiful golden swan. Nala Prince Asura immediately caught the swan. The swan cried for refuge and said that if he is freed, he will befriend the beautiful princess Damayanti.",
        "Eager to see Princess Damayanti, the prince freed the swan on a promise. As promised, the swan, who went to find Princess Damayanti, praised the beauty of Prince Nala's images in front of her. This song sings that praise.",
        "His name floats in the wind that fills the shade of the cold sandalwood in the snow-covered Himalayan forest. He is the prince of pipes. Pipes are the wind. He was not unknown. Everyone in Nishad knows his name.",
        "He is the dream prince of young girls who enjoy the beauty of a bejeweled balcony on a starry night. Even at such a moment, the handsome beauty of Prince Nala appears. When you listen to the series of similes in this song, you will find wonderful words that are not even found in women's praises. Mahagama Sekaras paint the handsome beauty of Prince Nala in a fresh way.",
        "Nala Kumaru's chest area is like a golden deer. A man with such a large breast makes even the feet of a woman who sleeps in his arms blush.",
        "What a beautiful poem this is. Love and romance will be born in the heart of any woman who undergoes this healing. Doesn't this mean that the mild quality of the moon also meets it? Nura flavor overflows all over his lustful eyes.",
        "The comparison of breasts to swans is very conservative in literature. But Mahagama Sekara revolutionizes it with these verses. From the sexy blue Nuvan bowl - Nura is overflowing.",
        "His sexy eyes also look like Yuga Madhu. Don't you hear a rav asking for Kamasamiboga in these verses?",
        "Professor Sucharita Gamilath Surihu once said that this song is the best song written by Mahagama Sekaryan."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Mahagama Sekaryan's",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Pandit Amaradeva's",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Lionel Algamyan's",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kali",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "first",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sinhala",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Yashodhara",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Prince Sidhu",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Buddha",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Prince Rahula",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Buddha",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kapila Vastu Pura",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Yashodhara",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Buddha, Goddess Yashodhara",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Rahula",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "nine",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Narasiha Gathas",
            "label": "FAC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Goddess Yashodhara",
            "label": "PRODUCT"
          },
          {
            "text": "Buddha",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Goddess Yashodhara",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Purusha",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Buddha",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "Mahagama Sekaran",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Nala Damayanti",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Chitra Senayan",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Mahabharata",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Nala Kumaran",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Nishad",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "One day",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "two",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "King Bhima",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Vidarbha",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Prince Nala",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "One",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Prince Nala",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Nala Prince",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Asura",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Prince Nala's",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Himalayan",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Nishad",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "a starry night",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "Prince Nala",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Mahagama Sekaras",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Prince Nala",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Nala Kumaru's",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Nura",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Mahagama Sekara",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Yuga Madhu",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kamasamiboga",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sucharita Gamilath Surihu",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Mahagama Sekaryan",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "නොවේ මෙවන් කුමාරයෙක් ලොවේ",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "මහගම සේකරයන්ගේ සුදුර්ලභ කවි ශක්තිය ද පණ්ඩිත් අමරදේවයන්ගේ කර්ණරසායන හඬ පෞරුෂය ද ලයනල් අල්ගමයන්ගේ ස්වර සංරචනය ද මේ ගීතයේ සාර්ථකත්වයට තුඩුදී ඇත. මේ වූ කලී සිංහල ගීත වංශයේ ප්‍රථම  පුරුෂ වර්ණනයයි.",
        "මෙබඳු පුරුෂ වර්ණනාවක්  අප මීට පෙර අසා ඇත්තේ යශෝධරාවගෙන් පමණි. ඇය සිදුහත් කුමරු බුද්ධත්වයට පත්වීමෙන් අනතුරුව සිය පුත් රාහුල කුමරුන්ට පියාගේ අතිඅලංකෘත වු බුද්ධ රූපකාය   පිළිබඳ මහත් භක්ත්‍යාදරයෙන් වර්ණනා කළාය.",
        "බුදුන් වහන්සේ  බුද්ධත්වයට පත්වීමෙන් අනතුරුව යශෝධරාව සහ පුතණුවන් බැහැදැකීමේ අරමුණින්  කපිල වස්තු පුරයට වැඩම කළහ. මඟ වඩිනා බුදුන් වහන්සේ පෙන්වා යශෝධරා දේවිය තම පුතු රාහුල කුමාරයාට නරසීහ ගථා නවයකින් පියා පිළිබඳ විස්මිත වර්ණනයක් කළාය.",
        "යශෝධරා දේවිය බුදුන් වහන්සේගේ  පුරුෂ ලක්ෂණ උපමා උපමේය ඇසුරෙන් ගොඩනගන අයුරු විචිත්‍රය. එවිට මාර්ගඵල නොලබා සිටි යශෝධරා දේවිය සංසාර පුරුද්දෙන් කරන මේ පුරුෂ වැනුම බොදු බැතිමතුන් කෙරෙහි ශ්‍රද්ධාව වඩන්නකි.",
        "මේ ගීතයේ අරුත පිළිබඳ  සිතන්නට කලින් ඊට පාදක වූ කතා පුවත කුමක් දැයි අපි මුලින්ම විමසා බලමු.",
        "චිත්‍ර සේනයන් නිර්මාණය කළ \"නල දමයන්ති මුද්‍රා නාට්‍යයට මහගම සේකරයන් විසින් විරචිත මේ ගීතයේ කතා පුවත අපට අසන්නට ලැබෙන්නෙ මහභාරතයෙනි.",
        "නිෂධ රාජ්‍යයේ විසූ නල කුමරුන් රූපශ්‍රීයෙන් අනූන , ආරෝහ පරිනාහ දේහයෙන් යුතු කඩවසම් තරුණයෙක් වූයේය. කඩු දුනු ශිල්ප ප්‍රගුණ කළ  ඔහු අසරු ධාවනයෙන් ද කෙළ පැමිණියේය. ධර්මිෂ්ට පාලකයකු වූ ඔහුට රට වැසියෝ ද ගෞරවාදරය කළහ.",
        "දිනක් රාජකාරියේ නියැළී සිටි කුමරුන්  වෙත චරපුරුෂයෙක් අපූරු පණිවිඩයක් රැගෙන ආවෙිය. විදර්භ දේශයේ පාලක භීම රජුගේ දෙටු දියණිය වන දමයන්ති කුමරිය පිළිබඳ  චරපුරුෂයා කුමරුන්  ඉදිරියේ  අපූරු වර්ණනයක් කළේය.",
        "දමයන්ති කුමරියගේ රූප සොබාවට ලොබ බැඳි  නල කුමරුට ඇය ගැන ප්‍රේමනීය සිතක් පහළ විය. දමයන්ති කුමරියගේ රූ සපුව සිතින් ඇඳගත් කුමරු ඇයට රහසේම ආලය කළේය. දිනක් දමයන්ති කුමරිය ගැන සිතමින් විල් තෙරක ඇවිදිමින් සිටි නල කුමරුට ශෝභමාන ස්වර්ණහංසයකු මුණගැසිණි. නල කුමරු අසුරු සැණින් හංසයා අල්ලා ගත්තේය. අභයදානය ඉල්ලා හඬා වැටුණු හංසයා තමා නිදහස් කරන්නෙ නම් දමයන්ති නමැති සුන්දර කුමරිය මිතුරු කර දෙන බව කීය.",
        "දමයන්ති  කුමරිය දැක ගැනීමට ⁣ආසාවෙන් සිටි කුමරු පොරොන්දු පිට හංසයා නිදහස් කළේය. පොරොන්දු වු පරිදි දමයන්ති කුමරිය සොයා ගිය හංසයා නල කුමරුන්ගේ රූප සෞන්දර්ය පිළිබඳ ඇය ඉදිරියේ වර්ණනා කළේය. මෙම ගීතයෙන් කිය වෙන්නේ එකී වර්ණනාවයි.",
        "ඈත කඳු හිමෙන් වැසුණු හිමාල වනයේ සීතල සඳුන් තුරු සෙවණ පිරිමැද හමන සුළඟේ පාවී එන්නේ ඔහුගේ නාමයයි. ඔහු තමයි නල කුමරයා. නල යනු සුළඟයි. ඔහු පිළිබඳ නොදත් අයෙක් නොවූහ. ඔහුගේ නාමය නිෂධයේ සියල්ලෝම දනිති.",
        "අහස් කුසේ තරු බැබළෙන රාත්‍රියක මැණික් ඇතිරු සඳලුතලයක සුන්දරත්වය විඳින ළාබාල යුවතියන්ගේ සිහින කුමරා ඔහුයි. එබඳු මොහොතක පවා නල කුමරුන්ගේ කඩවසම් රූසපුව මැවී පෙනේ. මේ ගීතයේ උපමා රූපක මාලාව ඇසෙන කල්හි ස්ත්‍රි වර්ණනාවල පවා නොමැති අපූරු වදන් දක්නට ලැබේ. මහගම සේකරයෝ නල කුමරුන්ගේ කඩවසම් රූසපුව නැවුම් ආකාරයකට වර්ණනය කරති.",
        "නල කුමරුන්ගේ උරතලය හෙවත් පපු පෙදෙස රන්මුවකු බඳුය. ඒ තරමි සුවිසල් උරතලයක් හිමි පුරුෂයකුට තුරුලුවී නිදන කාන්තාවකගේ පයෝධර පවා මුසපත් වෙනවා.",
        "මෙය කෙතරම් රමණීය කාව්‍යෝක්තියක්ද? මේ සුවය විඳින ඕනෑම ගැහැනියකගේ හදවතේ ආදරය මෙන්ම ශෘංගාරයද උපදිනවා.චන්ද්‍රයාගේ සෞම්‍ය ගුණයත්  ඊට මුහුවන බව නොවෙද මේ කියන්නෙ? සරාගයෙන් පිරුණු ඔහුගේ ඇස් පුරා නුරා රසය ඉතිරෙනවා.",
        "පියවුරු හංසයන්ට උපමා කිරීම සාහිත්‍යයෙහි ඉතා ගතානුගතිකය. එහෙත් මහගම සේකරයෝ මේ පදවලින් එය විප්ලවීයකරණය කරති. සරාගී නිල් නුවන් බඳුනින් - නුරා ඉතිරෙන්නේ.",
        "ඔහුගේ සරාගික දෙනෙත් යුග මධු විතක් සේ දිසෙයි. මේ පදවලින් කාමසමිබෝගය ඉල්ලා නඟන රාවයක් නොඇසේද?",
        "මේ ගීතය මහගම සේකරයන් ලියු ගීත අතරින් විශිෂ්ටතම ගීතය බව වරක් මහාචාර්ය සුචරිත ගමිලත්  සූරීහු පැවසූහ."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "මහගම සේකරයන්ගේ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "පණ්ඩිත් අමරදේවයන්ගේ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ලයනල් අල්ගමියන්ගේ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "කාලි",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "පළමුවන",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "සිංහල",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "යශෝධරා",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "සිදුහත් කුමාරයා",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "බුද්ධ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "රාහුල කුමාරයා",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "බුද්ධ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "කපිල වස්තු පුර",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "යශෝධරා",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "බුදුන්, යශෝධරා දේවිය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "රාහුල",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "නවය",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "නරසිහ ගාථා",
            "label": "FAC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "යශෝධරා දේවිය",
            "label": "PRODUCT"
          },
          {
            "text": "බුද්ධ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "යශෝධරා දේවිය",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "පුරුෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "බුද්ධ",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "මහගම සේකරන්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "නල දමයන්ති",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "චිත්‍ර සේනායන්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "මහා භාරතය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "නල කුමාරන්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "නිශාද්",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "එක දවසක්",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "දෙක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "භීම රජු",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "විදර්භා",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "නාල කුමාරයා",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "එක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "නාල කුමාරයා",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "නල කුමාරයා",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "අසුර",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "නාල කුමරුගේ",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "හිමාලය",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "නිශාද්",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "තරු පිරුණු රාත්‍රියක්",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "නාල කුමාරයා",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මහගම සේකරයන්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "නාල කුමාරයා",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "නල කුමාරගේ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "නුරා",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "මහගම සේකර",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "යුග මධු",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "කාමසාමිබෝග",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "සුචරිත ගැමිලත් සූරිහු",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "මහගම සේකරයන්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "உலகில் இப்படி ஒரு இளவரசன் இல்லை",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "மகாகம செகரியானின் அழகிய கவிதையும், பண்டிட் அமரதேவாவின் குரல் ஆளுமையும், லயனல் அல்காம்யனின் குரல் வளமும் இந்தப் பாடலின் வெற்றிக்கு வழிவகுத்துள்ளன. இந்த காளி சிங்களப் பாடல் வம்சத்தின் முதல் ஆண் பதிப்பு.",
        "இந்த மாதிரியான புருஷார்த்தத்தை நாம் யசோதராவிடம் மட்டுமே கேட்டிருக்கிறோம். இளவரசர் சித்து ஞானம் பெற்ற பிறகு, தனது தந்தையின் மிகவும் அலங்கரிக்கப்பட்ட புத்தர் படத்தை தனது மகன் இளவரசர் ராகுலனிடம் மிகுந்த பக்தியுடன் பாராட்டினார்.",
        "ஞானம் பெற்ற பிறகு, புத்தர் யசோதரா மற்றும் அவரது மகன்களைப் பார்வையிடும் நோக்கத்துடன் கபில வாஸ்து புராவுக்குச் சென்றார். புத்தரின் வழியைச் சுட்டிக்காட்டி, யசோதரா தேவி தனது மகன் ராகுலனுக்கு ஒன்பது நரசிஹா கதாக்களில் தந்தையின் அற்புதமான புகழைக் கொடுத்தார்.",
        "யசோதரா தேவி புத்தரின் ஆண் பண்புகளை உருவகங்கள் மற்றும் உருவகங்கள் மூலம் கட்டமைக்கும் விதம் அற்புதம். அப்போது வழியை அடையாத யசோதரா தேவி, சம்சார பழக்கத்தால் செய்யப்படும் இந்த புருஷ வாண்டு, புத்தரின் பக்தர்களிடம் நம்பிக்கையை வளர்க்கிறார்.",
        "இந்தப் பாடலின் பொருளைப் பற்றி சிந்திக்கும் முன், இதன் பின்னணி என்ன என்று முதலில் கேட்போம்.",
        "மகாபாரதத்தில் இருந்து சித்ரா சேனயன் இயற்றிய \"நள தமயந்தி\" என்ற பாலேக்காக மகாகம சேகரன் எழுதிய இந்தப் பாடலின் கதையைக் கேட்கிறோம்.",
        "நிஷாத ராஜ்ஜியத்தில் வாழ்ந்த நள குமரன், அழகிய தோற்றமும், அழகிய உடலும் கொண்ட அழகிய இளைஞனாக இருந்தான். அவர் வாள் மற்றும் வில்வித்தை கலையில் தேர்ச்சி பெற்றார். நேர்மையான ஆட்சியாளனாக இருந்ததால், நாட்டு மக்களும் அவரை மதித்தனர்.",
        "ஒரு நாள் ஒரு பாத்திரம் பணியில் இருந்த இளவரசர்களுக்கு ஒரு அற்புதமான செய்தியைக் கொண்டு வந்தது. விதர்ப்ப மன்னன் பீமனின் இருபடி மகளான இளவரசி தமயந்தியைப் பற்றி சரபுருஷயா இளவரசர்களுக்கு அற்புதமான புகழாரம் சூட்டினார்.",
        "இளவரசி தமயந்தியை காதலித்த இளவரசன் நளன் மீது காதல் கொண்டான். இளவரசர் தமயந்தி இளவரசி தமயந்தியை ரகசியமாக சந்தித்தார். ஒரு நாள் இளவரசி தமயந்தியைப் பற்றி நினைத்துக் கொண்டு ஏரிக்கரையில் நடந்து கொண்டிருந்த இளவரசன் நளன் ஒரு அழகான தங்க அன்னத்தை சந்தித்தான். நள இளவரசன் அசுரன் உடனே அந்த அன்னத்தை பிடித்தான். அன்னம் தஞ்சம் அடைந்து தன்னை விடுவித்தால் அழகிய இளவரசி தமயந்தியுடன் நட்பாகப் பழகுவதாகக் கூறினாள்.",
        "இளவரசி தமயந்தியைப் பார்க்க ஆவலுடன், இளவரசர் வாக்குறுதியின் பேரில் அன்னத்தை விடுவித்தார். உறுதியளித்தபடி, இளவரசி தமயந்தியைக் கண்டுபிடிக்கச் சென்ற அன்னம், அவள் முன் இளவரசர் நளனின் உருவங்களின் அழகைப் பாராட்டியது. என்று புகழ்ந்து பாடுகிறது இந்தப் பாடல்.",
        "பனி படர்ந்த இமயமலைக் காட்டில் குளிர்ந்த சந்தனத்தின் நிழலை நிரப்பும் காற்றில் அவன் பெயர் மிதக்கிறது. அவர் குழாய்களின் இளவரசன். குழாய்கள் காற்று. அவர் அறியாதவர் அல்ல. நிஷாதில் எல்லோருக்கும் அவன் பெயர் தெரியும்.",
        "விண்மீன்கள் நிரம்பிய இரவில் பெட்சுகளால் ஆன பால்கனியின் அழகை ரசிக்கும் இளம் பெண்களின் கனவு இளவரசன். அத்தகைய தருணத்திலும், இளவரசர் நளனின் அழகான அழகு தோன்றுகிறது. இந்தப் பாடலில் வரும் தொடர் உவமைகளைக் கேட்கும் போது பெண்களின் புகழில் கூட இல்லாத அற்புதமான வார்த்தைகள் கிடைக்கும். மஹாகம சேகரஸ் இளவரசர் நளனின் அழகிய அழகை புதுவிதமாக வர்ணிக்கிறார்.",
        "நள குமாருவின் மார்புப் பகுதி தங்க மான் போன்றது. இவ்வளவு பெரிய மார்பகம் கொண்ட ஆண் தன் கைகளில் உறங்கும் பெண்ணின் பாதங்களைக் கூட சிவக்க வைக்கிறான்.",
        "என்ன அழகான கவிதை இது. இந்த குணமடையும் எந்த ஒரு பெண்ணின் இதயத்திலும் காதலும் காதலும் பிறக்கும்.இதன் அர்த்தம் சந்திரனின் லேசான குணமும் அதை சந்திக்கும் என்று அல்லவா? அவனது காமக் கண்கள் முழுவதும் நுரா சுவை பொங்கி வழிகிறது.",
        "மார்பகங்களை ஸ்வான்ஸுடன் ஒப்பிடுவது இலக்கியத்தில் மிகவும் பழமைவாதமானது. ஆனால் மகாகம சேகர இந்த வசனங்கள் மூலம் அதை புரட்டிப் போடுகிறார். கவர்ச்சியான நீல நுவன் பானையிலிருந்து - நுரா நிரம்பி வழிகிறது.",
        "அவனது கவர்ச்சியான கண்களும் யுக மதுவைப் போல் இருக்கும். இந்த வசனங்களில் காமசாமிபோகா என்று ஒரு ராவ் கேட்பது கேட்கவில்லையா?",
        "பேராசிரியை சுசரிதா கமிலத் சூரிஹு ஒருமுறை இந்தப் பாடல் மகாகம சேகர்யன் எழுதிய சிறந்த பாடல் என்று கூறினார்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "மகாகம செகர்யன் தான்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "பண்டிட் அமரதேவாவின்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "லியோனல் அல்காமியன் தான்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "காளி",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "முதலில்",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "சிங்களம்",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "யசோதரா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இளவரசர் சித்து",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "புத்தர்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இளவரசர் ராகுலா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "புத்தர்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "கபில வாஸ்து புரா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "யசோதரா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "புத்தர், யசோதரா தேவி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ராகுலா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஒன்பது",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "நரசிஹ கதாக்கள்",
            "label": "FAC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "யசோதரா தேவி",
            "label": "PRODUCT"
          },
          {
            "text": "புத்தர்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "யசோதரா தேவி",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "புருஷா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "புத்தர்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "மகாகம சேகரன்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "நள தமயந்தி",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "சித்ரா சேனயன்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "மகாபாரதம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "நல குமரன்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "நிஷாத்",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஒரு நாள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இரண்டு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "அரசன் பீமன்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "விதர்பா",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இளவரசர் நள",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஒன்று",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "இளவரசர் நள",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "நள இளவரசன்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "அசுரன்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இளவரசர் நளனின்",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இமயமலை",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "நிஷாத்",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஒரு நட்சத்திர இரவு",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "இளவரசர் நள",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "மகாகம சேகரஸ்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இளவரசர் நள",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "நல குமாரு தான்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "நுரா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "மகாகம சேகர",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "யுக மது",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "காமசாமிபோக",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "சுசரித கமிலத் சூரிஹு",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "மகாகம சேகர்யன்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}