{
  "newspaper_id": "daily-mirror-lk",
  "url": "https://www.dailymirror.lk/front_page/Those-who-could-not-work-in-Ypalana-Govt-with-Ranil-as-PM-now-trying-to-secure-positions-MP-Dayasiri/238-242946",
  "time_ut": 1660324674,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Those who  could not work in Y’palana Govt with Ranil as PM, now trying to secure positions - MP Dayasiri",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Those who  could not work in Y’palana Govt with Ranil as PM, now trying to secure positions - MP Dayasiri",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "Those who castigated Ranil Wickremesinghe and deserted the SLFP saying that they could not serve in the yahapalana government with Ranil as the Prime Minister now are in an intense battle to secure positions under President Wickremesinghe, General Secretary of the SLFP, former Minister Dayasiri Jayasekara said.",
        "Those who insulted former President Maithripala Sirisena, President Wickremesinghe, the SLFP and the Yahapalana Government even formed the Sri Lanka Podujana Peramuna (SLPP) and it was ironical that the SLPP has become the saviour of the Wickremesinghe regime today, he added.",
        "“With the emergence of the SLPP, many thought they buried the SLFP for ever. We were subjected to extremely cruel and unfair bashing at the last general election. Some SLPP politicians told voters not to vote for the SLFP. But the SLFP was able to secure 14 seats in Parliament even amidst these negative propaganda to maintain its position in domestic politics,” Mr. Jayasekara stressed.",
        "He said the media plays an extremely important role in politics and therefore, no political party or politician could survive by antagonizing the media.",
        "Former Minister Ranjith Siyambalalpitiya said the vernacular media in many instances use the Goebbel’s theory to attack politicians and political parties. Hitler’s top propaganda man in Nazi Germany mas Paul Joseph Goebbels who invented the Goebbels theory which means when you say a lie 100 times in the same way, it becomes a truth.",
        "The former President and SLFP leader is a victim of Goebbels’ theory during the last few years of the yahapalana regime because the media, the social media in particular spread a lot of lies against him,” Mr. Siyambalapitiya said.",
        "In today’s politics, the success of political parties and politicians depend on the handling of the media, he added."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Ranil",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ranil",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "SLFP",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Dayasiri Jayasekara",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Maithripala Sirisena",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "SLFP",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Yahapalana Government",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "Podujana Peramuna",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "14",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Jayasekara",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "Ranjith Siyambalalpitiya",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Goebbel",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Hitler",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Nazi",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Germany",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Paul Joseph Goebbels",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Goebbels",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "100",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "SLFP",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the last few years of the yahapalana",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Siyambalapitiya",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "රනිල් අගමැති කරලා වයිපලාන ආණ්ඩුවේ වැඩ කරන්න බැරි අය දැන් තනතුරු රැකගන්න හදනවා - පාර්ලිමේන්තු මන්ත්‍රී දයාසිරි",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "රනිල් අගමැති කරන යහපාලන ආණ්ඩුවේ කටයුතු කළ නොහැකි බව පවසමින් රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතාට බැණ වදිමින් ශ්‍රීලනිපය හැර ගිය පිරිස් දැන් ජනාධිපති වික්‍රමසිංහ යටතේ තනතුරු ලබා ගැනීමේ දැඩි සටනක යෙදී සිටින බව ශ්‍රීලනිප මහ ලේකම් හිටපු අමාත්‍ය දයාසිරි ජයසේකර මහතා පැවසීය.",
        "හිටපු ජනාධිපති මෛත්‍රීපාල සිරිසේන මහතාට, ජනාධිපති වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතාට, ශ්‍රීලනිපයට හා යහපාලන ආණ්ඩුවට අපහාස කළ අය ශ්‍රී ලංකා පොදුජන පෙරමුණ (SLPP) පවා පිහිටුවා ගත් අතර අද ශ්‍රී ලංකා පොදුජන පෙරමුණ වික්‍රමසිංහ පාලනයේ ගැලවුම්කාරයා බවට පත්ව තිබීම හාස්‍යජනක බව ඔහු වැඩිදුරටත් පැවසීය.",
        "“ශ්‍රී ලංකා පොදුජන පෙරමුණ බිහිවීමත් සමඟ බොහෝ දෙනා සිතුවේ ශ්‍රීලනිපය සදාකාලිකවම වළලා දැමූ බවයි. පසුගිය මහ මැතිවරණයේදී අපි අතිශය කෲර සහ අසාධාරණ බැන වැදීමකට ලක් වුණා. ශ්‍රීලනිපයට ඡන්දය නොදෙන ලෙස ශ්‍රී ලංකා පොදුජන පෙරමුණේ ඇතැම් දේශපාලනඥයන් ඡන්දදායකයින්ට කීවා. නමුත් මේ නිෂේධාත්මක ප්‍රචාර මධ්‍යයේත් ශ්‍රීලනිපයට පාර්ලිමේන්තුවේ ආසන 14ක් ලබාගන්න පුළුවන් වුණා දේශීය දේශපාලනයේ ස්ථාවරය පවත්වාගෙන යන්න.” ජයසේකර මහතා අවධාරණය කළේය.",
        "දේශපාලනයේ දී මාධ්‍ය අතිශයින් වැදගත් කාර්යභාරයක් ඉටු කරන බවත්, එබැවින් මාධ්‍ය සමඟ ගැටීමෙන් කිසිදු දේශපාලන පක්ෂයකට හෝ දේශපාලනඥයෙකුට පැවැත්මක් නොමැති බවත් ඔහු පැවසීය.",
        "හිටපු අමාත්‍ය රංජිත් සියඹලාල්පිටිය මහතා පැවසුවේ දේශීය මාධ්‍ය බොහෝ අවස්ථාවල දේශපාලනඥයන්ට සහ දේශපාලන පක්ෂවලට පහර දීම සඳහා ගොබෙල් න්‍යාය භාවිතා කරන බවයි. නාසි ජර්මනියේ හිට්ලර්ගේ ප්‍රධාන ප්‍රචාරක මිනිසා ගොබෙල්ස් න්‍යාය සොයාගත් පෝල් ජෝශප් ගොබෙල්ස් ය, එනම් ඔබ බොරුවක් 100 වතාවක් එකම ආකාරයකින් කී විට එය සත්‍යයක් බවට පත්වේ.",
        "යහපාලන ආණ්ඩුවේ පසුගිය වසර කිහිපය තුළ හිටපු ජනාධිපතිවරයා සහ ශ්‍රීලනිප නායකයා ගොබෙල්ස් න්‍යායේ ගොදුරක් වූයේ මාධ්‍ය, විශේෂයෙන්ම සමාජ මාධ්‍ය ඔහුට එරෙහිව බොහෝ බොරු ප්‍රචාරය කළ නිසා යැයි සියඹලාපිටිය මහතා පැවසීය.",
        "වර්තමාන දේශපාලනය තුළ දේශපාලන පක්ෂවල සහ දේශපාලනඥයන්ගේ සාර්ථකත්වය රඳා පවතින්නේ මාධ්‍ය හැසිරවීම මත බවද ඔහු වැඩිදුරටත් පැවසීය."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "රනිල්",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "රනිල්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රීලනිප",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "දයාසිරි ජයසේකර",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "මෛත්‍රීපාල සිරිසේන",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රීලනිප",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "යහපාලන රජය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "පොදුජන පෙරමුණ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "14",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජයසේකර",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "රංජිත් සියඹලාල්පිටිය",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගොබෙල්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "හිට්ලර්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "නාසි",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජර්මනිය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "පෝල් ජෝශප් ගොබෙල්ස්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගොබෙල්ස්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "100",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රීලනිප",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "යහපාලනයේ අවසන් වසර කිහිපය",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "සියඹලාපිටිය",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "ரணிலைப் பிரதமராகக் கொண்டு யபாலன அரசாங்கத்தில் செயற்பட முடியாதவர்கள் தற்போது பதவிகளைப் பெற முயற்சிக்கின்றனர் - பாராளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர் தயாசிறி",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "ரணில் பிரதமராக உள்ள யஹபாலன அரசாங்கத்தில் பணியாற்ற முடியாது என ரணில் விக்ரமசிங்கவை சாடியவர்கள், ஸ்ரீலங்கா சுதந்திரக் கட்சியை விட்டு விலகியவர்கள் தற்போது ஜனாதிபதி விக்ரமசிங்கவின் கீழ் பதவிகளைப் பெறுவதற்கு கடும் போரில் ஈடுபட்டுள்ளதாக ஸ்ரீலங்கா சுதந்திரக் கட்சியின் பொதுச் செயலாளர் தயாசிறி ஜயசேகர தெரிவித்துள்ளார்.",
        "முன்னாள் ஜனாதிபதி மைத்திரிபால சிறிசேன, ஜனாதிபதி விக்கிரமசிங்க, ஸ்ரீலங்கா சுதந்திரக் கட்சி மற்றும் யஹபாலன அரசாங்கத்தை அவமானப்படுத்தியவர்கள் ஸ்ரீலங்கா பொதுஜன பெரமுனவை (SLPP) கூட உருவாக்கினர், மேலும் SLPP இன்று விக்கிரமசிங்க ஆட்சியின் மீட்பராக மாறியுள்ளது நகைப்புக்குரியது என்றும் அவர் மேலும் கூறினார்.",
        "ஸ்ரீலங்கா பொதுஜன பெரமுனவின் தோற்றத்துடன், ஸ்ரீலங்கா சுதந்திரக் கட்சியை என்றென்றும் புதைத்துவிட்டதாக பலர் நினைத்தனர். கடந்த பொதுத் தேர்தலில் நாங்கள் மிகவும் கொடூரமான மற்றும் நியாயமற்ற தாக்குதலுக்கு உள்ளானோம். ஸ்ரீலங்கா சுதந்திரக் கட்சிக்கு வாக்களிக்க வேண்டாம் என சில SLPP அரசியல்வாதிகள் வாக்காளர்களிடம் கூறியுள்ளனர். ஆனால், உள்நாட்டு அரசியலில் தனது நிலைப்பாட்டை தக்கவைத்துக் கொள்வதற்காக ஸ்ரீலங்கா சுதந்திரக் கட்சி இந்த எதிர்மறையான பிரச்சாரங்களுக்கு மத்தியிலும் பாராளுமன்றத்தில் 14 ஆசனங்களைப் பெற முடிந்தது” என்று திரு. ஜெயசேகர வலியுறுத்தினார்.",
        "அரசியலில் ஊடகங்கள் மிக முக்கிய பங்கு வகிக்கின்றன, எனவே எந்த ஒரு அரசியல் கட்சியும் அல்லது அரசியல்வாதியும் ஊடகங்களை பகைத்துக்கொண்டு வாழ முடியாது என்றார்.",
        "அரசியல்வாதிகள் மற்றும் அரசியல் கட்சிகளை தாக்குவதற்கு கோயபல் கோட்பாட்டை பல சந்தர்ப்பங்களில் உள்ளூர் ஊடகங்கள் பயன்படுத்துகின்றன என முன்னாள் அமைச்சர் ரஞ்சித் சியம்பலால்பிட்டிய தெரிவித்துள்ளார். நாஜி ஜெர்மனியில் ஹிட்லரின் தலைசிறந்த பிரச்சாரகர் பால் ஜோசப் கோயபல்ஸ் கோயபல்ஸ் கோட்பாட்டைக் கண்டுபிடித்தவர், அதாவது நீங்கள் ஒரு பொய்யை 100 முறை சொன்னால் அது உண்மையாகிவிடும்.",
        "முன்னாள் ஜனாதிபதியும் ஸ்ரீ.ல.சு.க தலைவரும் கடந்த சில வருடங்களாக யஹபாலன ஆட்சியின் போது கோயபல்ஸின் கோட்பாட்டிற்கு பலியாகியுள்ளார், ஏனெனில் ஊடகங்கள், சமூக ஊடகங்கள் குறிப்பாக அவருக்கு எதிராக நிறைய பொய்களைப் பரப்பின, ”என்று திரு. சியம்பலாபிட்டிய கூறினார்.",
        "இன்றைய அரசியலில், அரசியல் கட்சிகள் மற்றும் அரசியல்வாதிகளின் வெற்றி ஊடகங்களைக் கையாள்வதில் தங்கியுள்ளது என்றும் அவர் மேலும் கூறினார்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ரணில்",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரணில்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஸ்ரீ.ல.சு.க",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "தயாசிறி ஜயசேகர",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "மைத்திரிபால சிறிசேன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஸ்ரீ.ல.சு.க",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "யஹபாலன அரசாங்கம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "பொதுஜன பெரமுன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "14",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜெயசேகர",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "ரஞ்சித் சியம்பலால்பிட்டிய",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "கோயபல்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஹிட்லர்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "நாஜி",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜெர்மனி",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "பால் ஜோசப் கோயபல்ஸ்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "கோயபல்ஸ்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "100",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஸ்ரீ.ல.சு.க",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "யஹபாலனாவின் கடைசி சில வருடங்கள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சியம்பலாபிட்டிய",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}