{
  "newspaper_id": "d-b-s-jeyaraj-com",
  "url": "https://dbsjeyaraj.com/dbsj/archives/78590",
  "time_ut": 1657878960,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Prime Minister Ranil Wickremesinghe Sworn in as Acting President Before Chief Justice Jayantha Jayasuriya;  new President  to be  elected on July 20 by Parliament",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Prime Minister Ranil Wickremesinghe Sworn in as Acting President Before Chief Justice Jayantha Jayasuriya;  new President  to be  elected on July 20 by Parliament",
      "author": "Administrator",
      "body_lines": [
        "Prime Minister Ranil Wickremesinghe was sworn in as the Acting President before Chief Justice Jayantha Jayasuriya yesterday shortly after the official announcement of the resignation of incumbent Gotabaya Rajapaksa.",
        "The six-times Premier Wickremesinghe will function in his interim post till 20 July when MPs will vote to elect a successor to Rajapaksa to serve remainder of the latter’s term.",
        "Parliament will meet today when the Secretary General of Parliament Dhammika Dassanayake will announce to the House that there is a vacancy in the office of President and nomination will be accepted on 19 July following which a vote by secret ballot will be taken on 20 July.  Speaker Mahinda Yapa Abeywardena last morning formally announced that he had received the letter of resignation from Rajapaksa and explained the process which will be followed to elect a new President.",
        "“I have received the letter of resignation sent by His Excellency the President Gotabaya Rajapaksa in terms of Article 38.1 (b) of the Constitution of the Democratic Socialist Republic of Sri Lanka. Accordingly, the President has officially resigned from his position on July 14th, 2022,” he said.",
        "He announced that this sets in motion the constitutional process of electing a new president and in the interim period the Prime Minister will act in accordance with the Constitution to exercise and perform the powers, functions and duties of the President until the completion of the said process.",
        "He said that the election of the new President will be carried out in accordance with the Presidential Elections (Special Provisions) Act No. 2 of 1981 in accordance with Article 40 of the Constitution.",
        "“It is my intention to successfully complete this process as soon as possible. As our nation is known for its pride of being the oldest democratic country in South Asia, the execution of this process within a maximum democratic framework and transparency will be an important historical event not only in our country but also in the political history of the world,” Abeywardena said.",
        "He requested all party leaders, Government officials and security personnel to extend their maximum support towards this process of democratic action and in particular, the respected and beloved public of our country to create a suitable and peaceful atmosphere for all the members representing the Parliament to freely act according to their conscience and participate in the meetings in order to implement the proper democratic parliamentary system."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Ranil Wickremesinghe Sworn",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "Jayantha Jayasuriya",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "July 20",
          "label": "DATE"
        },
        {
          "text": "Parliament",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Jayantha Jayasuriya",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "yesterday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Gotabaya Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "six",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "20 July",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Rajapaksa",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "House",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "19 July",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "20 July",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Mahinda Yapa Abeywardena",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "last morning",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "Rajapaksa",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Gotabaya Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Article 38.1",
            "label": "LAW"
          },
          {
            "text": "Democratic",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "July 14th, 2022",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Constitution",
            "label": "LAW"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the Presidential Elections (Special Provisions) Act No. 2 of 1981",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Article 40 of the Constitution",
            "label": "LAW"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "South Asia",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "Abeywardena",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "අග්‍රාමාත්‍ය රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතා වැඩබලන ජනාධිපතිවරයා ලෙස අගවිනිසුරු ජයන්ත ජයසූරිය මහතා ඉදිරියේ දිවුරුම් දෙයි. නව ජනාධිපතිවරයා ජූලි 20 වැනිදා පාර්ලිමේන්තුව විසින් තෝරා පත් කර ගැනීමට නියමිතය",
      "author": "පරිපාලක",
      "body_lines": [
        "අග්‍රාමාත්‍ය රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතා වැඩබලන ජනාධිපතිවරයා ලෙස අගවිනිසුරු ජයන්ත ජයසූරිය මහතා ඉදිරියේ ඊයේ දිවුරුම් දුන්නේ වත්මන් ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ මහතාගේ ඉල්ලා අස්වීම නිල වශයෙන් ප්‍රකාශ කිරීමත් සමඟය.",
        "හය වතාවක් අගමැති වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතා ජූලි 20 දක්වා ඔහුගේ අතුරු ධූරයේ කටයුතු කරනු ඇති අතර, ඉතිරි ධූර කාලය සඳහා රාජපක්ෂට අනුප්‍රාප්තිකයෙකු තෝරා ගැනීමට මන්ත්‍රීවරුන් ඡන්දය ප්‍රකාශ කරනු ඇත.",
        "ජනාධිපති ධූරයේ පුරප්පාඩුවක් පවතින බව පාර්ලිමේන්තු මහලේකම් ධම්මික දසනායක විසින් සභාවට ප්‍රකාශ කිරීමෙන් අනතුරුව ජුලි 19 වනදා නාමයෝජනා භාර ගැනීමෙන් අනතුරුව ජූලි 20 වනදා රහස් ඡන්දයෙන් ඡන්දය විමසීමට නියමිත බව පාර්ලිමේන්තු මන්ත්‍රී ධම්මික දසනායක මහතා විසින් සභාවට ප්‍රකාශ කිරීමෙන් අනතුරුව පාර්ලිමේන්තුව අද රැස්වේ. කථානායක මහින්ද යාපා අබේවර්ධන මහතා ඊයේ පෙරවරුවේ නිල වශයෙන් නිවේදනය කළේ රාජපක්ෂ මහතාගෙන් ඉල්ලා අස්වීමේ ලිපිය තමන් වෙත ලැබුණු බවත්, නව ජනාධිපතිවරයකු තෝරා පත් කර ගැනීම සඳහා අනුගමනය කරන ක්‍රියාදාමය පැහැදිලි කළ බවත්ය.",
        "“ශ්‍රී ලංකා ප්‍රජාතාන්ත්‍රික සමාජවාදී ජනරජයේ ආණ්ඩුක්‍රම ව්‍යවස්ථාවේ 38.1 (ආ) වගන්තිය ප්‍රකාරව අතිගරු ජනාධිපති ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ මහතා විසින් එවන ලද ඉල්ලා අස්වීමේ ලිපිය මා වෙත ලැබී ඇත. ඒ අනුව 2022 ජුලි 14 වැනි දින ජනාධිපතිවරයා නිල වශයෙන් සිය ධුරයෙන් ඉල්ලා අස්වී ඇත.",
        "නව ජනාධිපතිවරයෙකු තෝරා ගැනීමේ ව්‍යවස්ථාපිත ක්‍රියාවලිය මෙමගින් ක්‍රියාත්මක වන බවත්, එම ක්‍රියාවලිය අවසන් වන තුරු ජනාධිපතිවරයාගේ බලතල, කාර්ය භාර සහ යුතුකම් ක්‍රියාත්මක කිරීමට සහ ඉටු කිරීමට අග්‍රාමාත්‍යවරයා ආණ්ඩුක්‍රම ව්‍යවස්ථාවට අනුකූලව කටයුතු කරන බවත් ඔහු නිවේදනය කළේය. .",
        "ආණ්ඩුක්‍රම ව්‍යවස්ථාවේ 40 වැනි වගන්තිය ප්‍රකාරව 1981 අංක 2 දරන ජනාධිපතිවරණ (විශේෂ විධිවිධාන) පනතට අනුව නව ජනාධිපතිවරයා තෝරා පත් කර ගැනීම සිදු කරන බව ඔහු පැවසීය.",
        "“මෙම ක්‍රියාවලිය හැකි ඉක්මනින් සාර්ථකව නිම කිරීම මගේ අරමුණයි. දකුණු ආසියාවේ පැරණිතම ප්‍රජාතන්ත්‍රවාදී රට බවට අප ජාතිය ප්‍රකටව සිටින බැවින් උපරිම ප්‍රජාතන්ත්‍රවාදී රාමුවක් තුළ විනිවිදභාවයෙන් මෙම ක්‍රියාවලිය ක්‍රියාත්මක කිරීම අප රටේ පමණක් නොව ලෝක දේශපාලන ඉතිහාසයේ ද වැදගත් ඓතිහාසික සිදුවීමක් වනු ඇත. අබේවර්ධන කීවේය.",
        "මෙම ප්‍රජාතන්ත්‍රවාදී ක්‍රියාදාමය සඳහා උපරිම සහයෝගය ලබා දෙන ලෙසත්, විශේෂයෙන්ම, පාර්ලිමේන්තුව නියෝජනය කරන සියලුම මන්ත්‍රීවරුන්ට නිදහසේ සිටීමට සුදුසු සහ සාමකාමී වාතාවරණයක් නිර්මාණය කිරීමට අපේ රටේ ගෞරවනීය හා ආදරණීය මහජනතාවගෙන් උපරිම සහයෝගය ලබා දෙන ලෙසත් ඔහු සියලුම පක්ෂ නායකයින්, රාජ්‍ය නිලධාරීන් සහ ආරක්ෂක නිලධාරීන්ගෙන් ඉල්ලා සිටියේය. නිසි ප්‍රජාතන්ත්‍රවාදී පාර්ලිමේන්තු ක්‍රමය ක්‍රියාත්මක කිරීම සඳහා තම හෘද සාක්ෂියට එකඟව ක්‍රියා කිරීම සහ රැස්වීම්වලට සහභාගී වීම."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ දිවුරුම් දෙයි",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "ජයන්ත ජයසූරිය",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "ජූලි 20",
          "label": "DATE"
        },
        {
          "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජයන්ත ජයසූරිය",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඊයේ",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "හය",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "20 ජූලි",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "නිවස",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "19 ජූලි",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "20 ජූලි",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මහින්ද යාපා අබේවර්ධන",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "පසුගිය උදෑසන",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "38.1 වගන්තිය",
            "label": "LAW"
          },
          {
            "text": "ප්‍රජාතන්ත්‍රවාදී",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජූලි 14, 2022",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ව්යවස්ථාව",
            "label": "LAW"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "1981 අංක 2 දරන ජනාධිපතිවරණ (විශේෂ විධිවිධාන) පනත",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ආණ්ඩුක්රම ව්යවස්ථාවේ 40 වැනි වගන්තිය",
            "label": "LAW"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "දකුණු ආසියාව",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "අබේවර්ධන ය",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "பதில் ஜனாதிபதியாக பிரதம நீதியரசர் ஜயந்த ஜயசூரிய முன்னிலையில் பிரதமர் ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க பதவிப்பிரமாணம் செய்துகொண்டார். புதிய குடியரசுத் தலைவர் ஜூலை 20ஆம் தேதி நாடாளுமன்றத்தால் தேர்ந்தெடுக்கப்படுவார்",
      "author": "நிர்வாகி",
      "body_lines": [
        "தற்போதைய ஜனாதிபதி கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்சவின் பதவி விலகல் குறித்த உத்தியோகபூர்வ அறிவிப்பை அடுத்து, பிரதமர் ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க, பதில் ஜனாதிபதியாக நேற்று பிரதம நீதியரசர் ஜயந்த ஜயசூரிய முன்னிலையில் பதவிப்பிரமாணம் செய்துகொண்டார்.",
        "6 முறை பிரதமராக இருந்த விக்ரமசிங்கே தனது இடைக்கால பதவியில் ஜூலை 20 ஆம் தேதி வரை செயல்படுவார், அப்போது ராஜபக்சேவின் எஞ்சிய பதவிக்காலத்தில் பணியாற்ற எம்.பி.க்கள் வாக்களித்து ராஜபக்சேவின் வாரிசை தேர்வு செய்வார்கள்.",
        "பாராளுமன்றம் இன்று கூடும் போது ஜனாதிபதி பதவி வெற்றிடமாக இருப்பதாக பாராளுமன்ற செயலாளர் தம்மிக்க தசநாயக்க சபைக்கு அறிவித்து ஜூலை 19 ஆம் திகதி வேட்புமனு ஏற்றுக்கொள்ளப்பட்டு 20 ஆம் திகதி இரகசிய வாக்கெடுப்பு நடத்தப்படும். ராஜபக்சவிடம் இருந்து ராஜினாமா கடிதம் தனக்கு கிடைத்ததாக சபாநாயகர் மகிந்த யாப்பா அபேவர்தன நேற்று காலை உத்தியோகபூர்வமாக அறிவித்து புதிய அதிபரை தேர்ந்தெடுப்பதற்கான நடைமுறைகள் குறித்து விளக்கினார்.",
        "“இலங்கை ஜனநாயக சோசலிசக் குடியரசின் அரசியலமைப்பின் 38.1 (ஆ) பிரிவின்படி அதிமேதகு ஜனாதிபதி கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ஷ அவர்களால் அனுப்பப்பட்ட இராஜினாமா கடிதம் எனக்கு கிடைத்துள்ளது. அதன்படி, ஜூலை 14, 2022 அன்று ஜனாதிபதி தனது பதவியை உத்தியோகபூர்வமாக ராஜினாமா செய்தார், ”என்று அவர் கூறினார்.",
        "புதிய ஜனாதிபதியை தெரிவு செய்வதற்கான அரசியலமைப்புச் செயற்பாடுகளை இது முன்னெடுப்பதாக அவர் அறிவித்தார், இடைக்காலத்தின் போது ஜனாதிபதியின் அதிகாரங்கள், செயல்பாடுகள் மற்றும் கடமைகளை நிறைவேற்றுவதற்கு அரசியலமைப்பின் படி பிரதமர் செயல்படுவார். .",
        "அரசியலமைப்பின் 40 ஆவது சரத்திற்கு அமைய 1981 ஆம் ஆண்டின் 2 ஆம் இலக்க ஜனாதிபதி தேர்தல்கள் (விசேட ஏற்பாடுகள்) சட்டத்தின் பிரகாரம் புதிய ஜனாதிபதி தேர்தல் நடத்தப்படும் என அவர் தெரிவித்துள்ளார்.",
        "\"இந்த செயல்முறையை விரைவில் வெற்றிகரமாக முடிக்க வேண்டும் என்பதே எனது நோக்கம். தெற்காசியாவின் பழமையான ஜனநாயக நாடு என்ற பெருமைக்கு பெயர் பெற்ற நம் தேசம், அதிகபட்ச ஜனநாயக கட்டமைப்பிலும் வெளிப்படைத்தன்மையிலும் இந்த செயல்முறையை நிறைவேற்றுவது நம் நாட்டில் மட்டுமல்ல, உலக அரசியல் வரலாற்றிலும் ஒரு முக்கிய வரலாற்று நிகழ்வாக இருக்கும். அபேவர்தன கூறினார்.",
        "அனைத்துக் கட்சித் தலைவர்கள், அரசு அதிகாரிகள் மற்றும் பாதுகாப்புப் பணியாளர்கள் இந்த ஜனநாயக நடவடிக்கைக்கு அதிகபட்ச ஆதரவை வழங்குமாறும், குறிப்பாக, பாராளுமன்றத்தை பிரதிநிதித்துவப்படுத்தும் அனைத்து உறுப்பினர்களுக்கும் பொருத்தமான மற்றும் அமைதியான சூழ்நிலையை உருவாக்குவதற்கு நமது நாட்டின் மரியாதைக்குரிய மற்றும் அன்பான பொதுமக்களை அவர் கேட்டுக் கொண்டார். முறையான ஜனநாயக நாடாளுமன்ற முறையை நடைமுறைப்படுத்துவதற்காக அவர்களின் மனசாட்சிப்படி நடந்து, கூட்டங்களில் பங்கேற்க வேண்டும்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க பதவியேற்றார்",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "ஜயந்த ஜயசூரிய",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "ஜூலை 20",
          "label": "DATE"
        },
        {
          "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜயந்த ஜயசூரிய",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "நேற்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஆறு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "20 ஜூலை",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ராஜபக்சே",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "வீடு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "19 ஜூலை",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "20 ஜூலை",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "மஹிந்த யாப்பா அபேவர்தன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "கடைசி காலை",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "ராஜபக்சே",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "கட்டுரை 38.1",
            "label": "LAW"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜனநாயகம்",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜூலை 14, 2022",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "அரசியலமைப்பு",
            "label": "LAW"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "1981 ஆம் ஆண்டின் ஜனாதிபதித் தேர்தல்கள் (சிறப்பு ஏற்பாடுகள்) சட்டம் எண். 2",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "அரசியலமைப்பின் பிரிவு 40",
            "label": "LAW"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "தெற்காசியா",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "அபேவர்தன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}