{
  "newspaper_id": "news-first-lk",
  "url": "https://www.newsfirst.lk/2022/06/25/fuel-protests-continue-today-hatton-residents-allege-no-kerosene-since-9th/",
  "time_ut": 1656144960,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Fuel protests continue today; Hatton residents allege no kerosene since 9th",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Fuel protests continue today; Hatton residents allege no kerosene since 9th",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); Protests demanding fuel are being held at many areas today (25) as well.",
        "Residents of Hatton staged a protest demanding kerosene, blocking the Hatton-Colombo main road.",
        "They said that they have not received any kerosene stocks in the Hatton area since 9th June, and that they had to wait in line for hours every day to return home empty handed.",
        "Meanwhile, people were engaged in a protest blocking the Anuradhapura-Jayanthipura roundabout on the Puttalam-Anuradhapura main road.",
        "A group blocking the Galle Road in the Boossa area staged a protest this morning demanding fuel.",
        "People also blocked the Mahiyanganaya-Kandy road near the Mahaweli bridge demanding fuel, stating that they have been waiting for fuel for five days.",
        "Accordingly, the people engaged in a protest by crossing the Mahaweli Bridge due to the lack of fuel, however, the crowd dispersed after the OIC of the Mahiyanganaya Police promised fuel and handed tokens to those in queue.",
        "Fuel protests continue today; Hatton residents allege no kerosene since 9th",
        "Prof. Rangita De Silva De Alwis elected as SL representative for CEDAW"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "today",
          "label": "DATE"
        },
        {
          "text": "9th",
          "label": "ORDINAL"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "25",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Hatton-Colombo",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Hatton",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "9th June",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "hours every day",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Puttalam",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the Galle Road",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "Boossa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "this morning",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Mahaweli",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "five days",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the Mahaweli Bridge",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the OIC",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Mahiyanganaya Police",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "9th",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Rangita De Silva De Alwis",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "SL",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "CEDAW",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "අදත් ඉන්ධන විරෝධතා; හැටන් ප්‍රදේශවාසීන් චෝදනා කරන්නේ පසුගිය 9 වැනිදා සිට භූමිතෙල් නොමැති බවයි",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); ඉන්ධන ඉල්ලා අද (25) දිනයේත් ප්‍රදේශ රැසක විරෝධතා පැවැත්වෙනවා.",
        "භූමිතෙල් ඉල්ලා හැටන් ප්‍රදේශවාසීන් හැටන් කොළඹ ප්‍රධාන මාර්ගය අවහිර කරමින් විරෝධතාවක නිරත වුණා.",
        "ජූනි 9 වැනිදා සිට තමන්ට හැටන් ප්‍රදේශයේ භූමිතෙල් තොග ලැබී නොමැති බවත්, හිස් අතින් නිවෙස් බලා යාමට දිනපතා පැය ගණන් පෝලිමේ සිටීමට සිදුවූ බවත් ඔවුහු පැවසූහ.",
        "මේ අතර පුත්තලම - අනුරාධපුර ප්‍රධාන මාර්ගයේ අනුරාධපුර - ජයන්තිපුර වටරවුම අවහිර කරමින් ජනතාව විරෝධතාවක නිරත වුණා.",
        "ඉන්ධන ඉල්ලා අද පෙරවරුවේ බූස්ස ප්‍රදේශයෙන් ගාලු පාර අවහිර කරමින් පිරිසක් විරෝධතාවක නිරත වුණා.",
        "ඉන්ධන ඉල්ලා දින පහක් තිස්සේ ඉන්ධන ලබා ගැනීමට බලා සිටින බව පවසමින් ජනතාව මහියංගනය - නුවර මාර්ගය මහවැලි පාලම අසලින් ද අවහිර කළහ.",
        "ඒ අනුව, මහවේලි පාලම තරණය කිරීමෙන් ජනතාව විරෝධතාවයක නිරත වූ ජනතාව ඉන්ධන නොමැතිකම නිසා ජනතාව විසුරුවා හරින ලද මහිවන්ගායා පොලිසියේ ස්ථානාධිපතිවරයා පෝලිමේ සිටින අයට ද අත්හදා බැලීමෙන් පසුව මෙම පිරිස විසිර ගියහ.",
        "අදත් ඉන්ධන විරෝධතා; හැටන් ප්‍රදේශවාසීන් චෝදනා කරන්නේ පසුගිය 9 වැනිදා සිට භූමිතෙල් නොමැති බවයි",
        "CEDAW හි ශ්‍රී ලංකා නියෝජිතයා ලෙස මහාචාර්ය රංගිත ද සිල්වා ද අල්විස් තේරී පත් විය"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "අද",
          "label": "DATE"
        },
        {
          "text": "9 වැනි",
          "label": "ORDINAL"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "25",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "හැටන්-කොළඹ",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "හැටන්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජුනි 9",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "සෑම දිනකම පැය",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "පුත්තලම",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ගාලු පාර",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "බූස්ස",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "මේ උදෑසන",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "මහවැලි",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "දින පහක්",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "මහවැලි පාලම",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "OIC",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "මහියංගනය පොලිසිය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "9 වැනි",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "රංගිත ද සිල්වා ද අල්විස්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "එස්.එල්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "CEDAW",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "எரிபொருள் எதிர்ப்பு போராட்டம் இன்றும் தொடர்கிறது; கடந்த 9ஆம் திகதி முதல் மண்ணெண்ணெய் வழங்கப்படவில்லை என ஹட்டன் பிரதேச மக்கள் குற்றம் சுமத்துகின்றனர்",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); இன்றும் (25) பல பிரதேசங்களில் எரிபொருள் வழங்கக் கோரி ஆர்ப்பாட்டங்கள் நடத்தப்படுகின்றன.",
        "மண்ணெண்ணெய் கோரி ஹட்டன் - கொழும்பு பிரதான வீதியை மறித்து ஹட்டன் பிரதேச மக்கள் ஆர்ப்பாட்டத்தில் ஈடுபட்டனர்.",
        "கடந்த ஜூன் மாதம் 9ஆம் திகதி முதல் ஹட்டன் பகுதியில் மண்ணெண்ணெய் கையிருப்பு கிடைக்கவில்லை எனவும், தினமும் மணிக்கணக்கில் வரிசையில் காத்திருந்து வெறுங்கையுடன் வீடு திரும்ப வேண்டிய நிலை ஏற்பட்டுள்ளதாகவும் அவர்கள் தெரிவித்தனர்.",
        "இதேவேளை, புத்தளம் - அனுராதபுரம் பிரதான வீதியில் அனுராதபுரம் - ஜெயந்திபுர சுற்றுவட்டத்தை மறித்து மக்கள் ஆர்ப்பாட்டத்தில் ஈடுபட்டுள்ளனர்.",
        "பூஸ்ஸ பிரதேசத்தில் காலி வீதியை மறித்து ஒரு குழுவினர் எரிபொருளைக் கோரி இன்று காலை ஆர்ப்பாட்டத்தில் ஈடுபட்டனர்.",
        "மஹியங்கனை-கண்டி வீதியை மகாவலி பாலத்திற்கு அருகில் எரிபொருளைக் கோரி மக்கள் ஐந்து நாட்களாக எரிபொருளுக்காக காத்திருப்பதாகக் கூறி மறியல் செய்தனர்.",
        "இதன்படி, எரிபொருள் பற்றாக்குறையால் மக்கள் மகாவலி பாலத்தை கடந்து ஆர்ப்பாட்டத்தில் ஈடுபட்டனர், எனினும், மஹியங்கனை பொலிஸ் நிலைய பொறுப்பதிகாரி எரிபொருளை வழங்குவதாக உறுதியளித்ததையடுத்து வரிசையில் நின்றவர்களுக்கு டோக்கன்களை வழங்கியதை அடுத்து மக்கள் கலைந்து சென்றனர்.",
        "எரிபொருள் எதிர்ப்பு போராட்டம் இன்றும் தொடர்கிறது; கடந்த 9ஆம் திகதி முதல் மண்ணெண்ணெய் வழங்கப்படவில்லை என ஹட்டன் பிரதேச மக்கள் குற்றம் சுமத்துகின்றனர்",
        "CEDAW இன் இலங்கைப் பிரதிநிதியாக பேராசிரியர் ரங்கிதா டி சில்வா டி அல்விஸ் தேர்ந்தெடுக்கப்பட்டார்"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "இன்று",
          "label": "DATE"
        },
        {
          "text": "9வது",
          "label": "ORDINAL"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "25",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஹட்டன்-கொழும்பு",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஹட்டன்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜூன் 9",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஒவ்வொரு நாளும் மணிநேரம்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "புத்தளம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "காலி வீதி",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "பூஸ்ஸா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று காலை",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "மகாவலி",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஐந்து நாட்கள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "மகாவலி பாலம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "OIC",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "மஹியங்கனை பொலிஸ்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "9வது",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ரங்கிதா டி சில்வா டி அல்விஸ்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "எஸ்.எல்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "CEDAW",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}