{
  "newspaper_id": "daily-mirror-lk",
  "url": "https://www.dailymirror.lk/latest_news/Withdraw-from-services-if-sufficient-fuel-supplies-not-given-Gemunu/342-241522",
  "time_ut": 1658406114,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Withdraw from services, if sufficient fuel supplies not given: Gemunu",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Withdraw from services, if sufficient fuel supplies not given: Gemunu",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "The Lanka Private Bus Owners' Association (LPBOA) today said that they will withdraw from services in the next few days if they did not get sufficient fuel and if suitable arrangements were not made.",
        "Addressing the media, its Chairman, Gemunu Wijerathne, said that they have informed the Petroleum Minister and CEYPETCO Chairman in this regard.",
        "Therefore, Wijerathne requested the officials to grant facilities to get fuel through the CEYPETCO, Lanka IOC, and co-operative filling stations while suspending the fuel issuing service from the Sri Lanka Transport Board (SLTB) depots.",
        "“Due to internal issues at the SLTB depots, they do not provide us with sufficient fuel to run the service. Therefore, several bus strikes are being held in several areas in the country. Buses are not operating in most of the areas in the country, especially in the Southern Province and several areas in the Western Province, such as in Homagama,” he said.",
        "“According to the Transport Minister's instructions, a limited number of SLTB depots supply diesel. Other depots used to provide diesel with limited stocks. A maximum of 3,000 buses were operated during the past month, and it is not sufficient to provide a good service for the people,” Wijerathne said.",
        "\"It is sad to say that, even though fuel had been delivered to CEYPETCO filling stations, they refused to provide fuel for our buses.\" Several fuel stations issued fuel for only Rs.20,000 or Rs.7,000. A bus needs at least 150 litres (Rs.70,000) of diesel per day. \"With this situation, we cannot assure that we can provide a sufficient bus service for the people,\" Wijerathne said. (Chaturanga Samarawickrama)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Gemunu",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "The Lanka Private Bus Owners' Association",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the next few days",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Gemunu Wijerathne",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "CEYPETCO",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "CEYPETCO",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Lanka IOC",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Sri Lanka Transport Board",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "SLTB",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Southern Province",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Western Province",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "Homagama",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "SLTB",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "3,000",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "the past month",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "at least 150",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Chaturanga Samarawickrama",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "ප්‍රමාණවත් ඉන්ධන ලබා නොදේ නම් සේවාවලින් ඉවත් වන්න: ගැමුණු",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "ප්‍රමාණවත් ඉන්ධන නොලැබුණහොත් සහ සුදුසු වැඩපිළිවෙළක් සකස් නොකළහොත් ඉදිරි දින කිහිපය තුළ සේවයෙන් ඉවත් වන බව ලංකා පෞද්ගලික බස් හිමියන්ගේ සංගමය (LPBOA) අද ප්‍රකාශ කළේය.",
        "මාධ්‍ය වෙත අදහස් දක්වමින් එහි සභාපති ගැමුණු විජේරත්න කියා සිටියේ මේ සම්බන්ධයෙන් ඛනිජ තෙල් අමාත්‍යවරයා සහ CEYPETCO සභාපතිවරයා දැනුවත් කර ඇති බවයි.",
        "එබැවින් ශ්‍රී ලංකා ගමනාගමන මණ්ඩලයේ (ශ්‍රී ලංගම) ඩිපෝවලින් ඉන්ධන නිකුත් කිරීමේ සේවාව අත්හිටුවා CEYPETCO, Lanka IOC, සහ සමුපකාර පිරවුම්හල් හරහා ඉන්ධන ලබා ගැනීමට පහසුකම් සලසන ලෙස විජේරත්න නිලධාරීන්ගෙන් ඉල්ලා සිටියේය.",
        "“ශ්‍රී ලංගම ඩිපෝවල අභ්‍යන්තර ප්‍රශ්න නිසා අපට සේවාව පවත්වාගෙන යාමට ප්‍රමාණවත් ඉන්ධන ලබා දෙන්නේ නැහැ. එබැවින් දිවයිනේ ප්‍රදේශ කිහිපයක බස් වර්ජන කිහිපයක් ද ක්‍රියාත්මකයි. දිවයිනේ බොහෝ ප්‍රදේශවල, විශේෂයෙන්ම දකුණු පළාතේ සහ බස්නාහිර පළාතේ හෝමාගම වැනි ප්‍රදේශ කිහිපයක බස් රථ ධාවනය වන්නේ නැහැ,” ඔහු පැවසීය.",
        "“ප්‍රවාහන අමාත්‍යවරයාගේ උපදෙස් අනුව සීමිත ලංගම ඩිපෝවලින් ඩීසල් සපයනවා. අනෙකුත් ඩිපෝවල සීමිත තොග සහිත ඩීසල් සැපයීම සඳහා භාවිතා කරන ලදී. පසුගිය මාසය තුළ උපරිම වශයෙන් බස්රථ 3000ක් ධාවනය කර ඇති අතර එය ජනතාවට යහපත් සේවාවක් ලබාදීමට ප්‍රමාණවත් නොවන බවද විජේරත්න පැවසීය.",
        "“සිපෙට්කෝ ඉන්ධන පිරවුම්හල්වලට ඉන්ධන ලබාදී තිබුණත් ඔවුන් අපේ බස් රථවලට ඉන්ධන ලබාදීම ප්‍රතික්ෂේප කළ බව කියන්න කනගාටුයි.” ඉන්ධන පිරවුම්හල් කිහිපයකින් ඉන්ධන නිකුත් කළේ රුපියල් 20,000ක් හෝ 7000ක් පමණයි. බස් රථයකට දිනකට අවම වශයෙන් ඩීසල් ලීටර් 150ක් (රු. 70,000) අවශ්‍ය වේ. මේ තත්ත්වයත් සමඟ ජනතාවට ප්‍රමාණවත් බස්‌ සේවාවක්‌ ලබාදිය හැකි බවට අපට සහතික විය නොහැකි බවද විජේරත්න මහතා පැවසීය. (චතුරංග සමරවික්‍රම)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ගැමුණු",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ලංකා පෞද්ගලික බස් හිමියන්ගේ සංගමය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉදිරි දින කිහිපය",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ගැමුණු විජේරත්න",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "CEYPETCO",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "CEYPETCO",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ලංකා IOC",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකා ගමනාගමන මණ්ඩලය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ලංගම",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "දකුණු පළාත",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "බස්නාහිර පළාත",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "Homagama",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ලංගම",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "3,000 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "පසුගිය මාසය",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "අවම වශයෙන් 150",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "චතුරංග සමරවික්‍රම",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "போதிய எரிபொருள் விநியோகம் வழங்கப்படாவிட்டால், சேவைகளில் இருந்து விலகவும்: கெமுனு",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "தமக்கு போதிய எரிபொருள் கிடைக்காவிடின், உரிய ஏற்பாடுகள் மேற்கொள்ளப்படாவிட்டால், எதிர்வரும் சில தினங்களில் சேவையில் இருந்து விலகிக் கொள்வதாக இலங்கை தனியார் பஸ் உரிமையாளர்கள் சங்கம் (LPBOA) இன்று தெரிவித்துள்ளது.",
        "ஊடகங்களுக்கு கருத்து தெரிவித்த அதன் தலைவர் கெமுனு விஜேரத்ன, இது தொடர்பில் பெற்றோலிய அமைச்சர் மற்றும் CEYPETCO தலைவருக்கு அறிவித்துள்ளதாக தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "எனவே, இலங்கை போக்குவரத்து சபையின் (SLTB) டிப்போக்களில் இருந்து எரிபொருள் வழங்கும் சேவையை இடைநிறுத்தி, CEYPETCO, Lanka IOC மற்றும் கூட்டுறவு நிரப்பு நிலையங்கள் ஊடாக எரிபொருளைப் பெறுவதற்கான வசதிகளை வழங்குமாறு விஜேரத்ன அதிகாரிகளிடம் கோரிக்கை விடுத்தார்.",
        "350 நிரப்பு நிலையங்கள் வரை எரிபொருளை வழங்க முடியும்: பவுசர் உரிமையாளர்கள் உதவியாளர்.",
        "அமைச்சின் தீர்மானத்திற்கு அமைய அதிகபட்சமாக 350 எரிபொருள் நிரப்பு நிலையங்களுக்கு எரிபொருள் விநியோகிக்கப்படும் என இலங்கை பெற்றோலிய தனியார் பவுசர் உரிமையாளர்கள் சங்கம் (CPPBOA) இன்று தெரிவித்துள்ளது.",
        "CEYPETCO எரிபொருள் நிரப்பு நிலையங்களுக்கு எரிபொருள் விநியோகம் செய்யப்பட்ட போதிலும், அவர்கள் எமது பேருந்துகளுக்கு எரிபொருளை வழங்க மறுத்துவிட்டனர் என்பது வருத்தமளிக்கிறது. பல எரிபொருள் நிலையங்கள் ரூ.20,000 அல்லது ரூ.7,000க்கு மட்டுமே எரிபொருளை வழங்கின. ஒரு பஸ்சுக்கு ஒரு நாளைக்கு குறைந்தது 150 லிட்டர் (ரூ.70,000) டீசல் தேவைப்படுகிறது. இந்த நிலையில், மக்களுக்கு போதுமான பஸ் சேவையை வழங்க முடியும் என எங்களால் உறுதியளிக்க முடியாது என விஜேரத்ன தெரிவித்தார். (சதுரங்க சமரவிக்ரம)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "கெமுனு",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை தனியார் பஸ் உரிமையாளர்கள் சங்கம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "அடுத்த சில நாட்கள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "கெமுனு விஜேரத்ன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "சைபெட்கோ",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "சைபெட்கோ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "லங்கா ஐ.ஓ.சி",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை போக்குவரத்து சபை",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "SLTB",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "தென் மாகாணம்",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "மேல் மாகாணம்",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "Homagama",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "SLTB",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "3,000",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "கடந்த மாதம்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "குறைந்தது 150",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "சதுரங்க சமரவிக்ரம",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}