{
  "newspaper_id": "ada-derana-lk",
  "url": "http://www.adaderana.lk/news/84718/showery-condition-likely-to-enhance-from-today",
  "time_ut": 1662169800,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Showery condition likely to enhance from today",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Showery condition likely to enhance from today",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "Showery condition is expected to enhance some extent in the south-western part (Western and Sabaragamuwa provinces and in Kandy, Nuwara-Eliya, Galle and Matara districts) of the island from this afternoon (Sep 03) over the next few days, the Department of Meteorology says.",
        "Showers will occur at times in the Western, Sabaragamuwa and North-Western provinces and in Kandy, Nuwara-Eliya, Galle and Matara districts.",
        "Fairly heavy rainfalls above 50mm may occur at some places in Sabaragamuwa province and in Kandy, Nuwara-Eliya and Kalutara districts.",
        "Meanwhile, several spells of showers will occur in Jaffna district.",
        "Showers or thundershowers will occur at a few places in Uva province and in Batticaloa and Ampara districts during the evening or night.",
        "Strong winds of about 50 kmph can be expected at times over the western slopes of the Central hills.",
        "The general public is advised to take adequate precautions to minimize damages caused by temporary localized strong winds and lightning during thundershowers.",
        "On the apparent southward relative motion of the sun, it is going to be directly over the latitudes of Sri Lanka from August 28 to September 07 this year. The nearest towns of Sri Lanka over which the sun is overhead today (03) are Kakkapalliya (Puttalam District), Habarewewa (Kurunegala District), Kirimetiyawa (Matale District), Habarawa (Badulla District) and Divulana (Batticaloa District) about 12.10 noon.",
        "Showers or thundershowers will occur at several places in the sea areas around the Island.",
        "Winds will be south-westerly and wind speed will be 30-40 kmph. Wind speed may increase up to 45-50 kmph at times in the sea areas off the coast extending from Kankesanturai to Puttalam via Mannar and Galle to Pottuvil via Hambantota.",
        "The sea areas off the coast extending from Kankesanturai to Puttalam via Mannar and Galle to Pottuvil via Hambantota will be rough at times and sea areas off the coast extending from Puttalam to Galle via Colombo will be fairly rough at times. The other sea areas around the island may be moderate."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Western",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sabaragamuwa",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kandy",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Galle",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Matara",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "this afternoon",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "the next few days",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Department of Meteorology",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sabaragamuwa",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "North-Western",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kandy",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Galle",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Matara",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "50mm",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sabaragamuwa province",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kandy",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kalutara",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Jaffna",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Uva",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Batticaloa",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ampara",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "evening",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "night",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "about 50 kmph",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "August 28 to September 07 this year",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "03",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kakkapalliya",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Puttalam District",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Habarewewa",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kirimetiyawa",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Matale District",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Habarawa",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Badulla District",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Divulana",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Batticaloa District",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "about 12.10 noon",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "30-40 kmph",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "45-50 kmph",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kankesanturai",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Mannar",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Galle",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Kankesanturai",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Mannar",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Galle",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Puttalam",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Galle",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "වැසි තත්ත්වය අද සිට වැඩි වීමට ඉඩ ඇත",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "දිවයිනේ නිරිතදිග කොටසේ (බස්නාහිර සහ සබරගමුව පළාත්වල සහ මහනුවර, නුවරඑළිය, ගාල්ල සහ මාතර දිස්ත්‍රික්කවල) අද (සැප් 03) පස්වරුවේ සිට ඉදිරි දින කිහිපය තුළ වැසි තත්ත්වය තරමක් දුරට වර්ධනය වනු ඇතැයි අපේක්ෂා කරන බව එම දෙපාර්තමේන්තුව පවසයි. කාලගුණ විද්‍යාව පවසයි.",
        "බස්නාහිර, සබරගමුව සහ වයඹ පළාත්වලත් මහනුවර, නුවරඑළිය, ගාල්ල සහ මාතර දිස්ත්‍රික්කවලත් විටින් විට වැසි ඇති වේ.",
        "සබරගමුව පළාතේ සහ මහනුවර, නුවරඑළිය සහ කළුතර දිස්ත්‍රික්කවල ඇතැම් ස්ථානවලට මිලිමීටර් 50 ට වැඩි තරමක් තද වැසි ඇති විය හැක.",
        "මේ අතර යාපනය දිස්ත්‍රික්කයේ වැසි වාර කිහිපයක් ඇතිවේ.",
        "ඌව පළාතේ සහ මඩකලපුව සහ අම්පාර දිස්ත්‍රික්කවල ස්ථාන ස්වල්පයක සවස් කාලයේ හෝ රාත්‍රී කාලයේ වැසි හෝ ගිගුරුම් සහිත වැසි ඇති වේ.",
        "මධ්‍යම කඳුකරයේ බටහිර බෑවුම් ප්‍රදේශවල විටින් විට පැ.කි.මී.50 ක පමණ තද සුළං බලාපොරොත්තු විය හැක.",
        "ගිගුරුම් සහිත වැසි ඇති වන විට එම ප්‍රදේශවල තාවකාලික තද සුළං සහ අකුණු මඟින් සිදුවන අනතුරු අවම කර ගැනීමට අවශ්‍ය පියවර ගන්නා ලෙස සාමාන්‍ය ජනතාවට දැනුම් දෙනු ලැබේ.",
        "සූර්යයාගේ දෘශ්‍ය ලෙස දකුණට සාපේක්ෂ චලිතය මත, එය මේ වසරේ අගෝස්තු 28 සිට සැප්තැම්බර් 07 දක්වා ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ අක්ෂාංශ වලට සෘජුවම ඉහළින් පවතී. අද (03) දහවල් 12.10 ට පමණ හිරු මුදුන්ව පවතින ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ ආසන්නතම නගර වන්නේ කාක්කපල්ලිය (පුත්තලම දිස්ත්‍රික්කය), හබරවැව (කුරුණෑගල දිස්ත්‍රික්කය), කිරිමැටියාව (මාතලේ දිස්ත්‍රික්කය), හබරාව (බදුල්ල දිස්ත්‍රික්කය) සහ දිවුලන (මඩකලපුව දිස්ත්‍රික්කය) ය.",
        "දිවයින වටා වන මුහුදු ප්‍රදේශවල තැනින් තැන වැසි හෝ ගිගුරුම් සහිත වැසි ඇති වේ.",
        "සුළං නිරිත දෙසින් හමන අතර සුළගේ වේගය පැ.කි.මී.30-40 පමණ වේ. කන්කසන්තුරේ සිට මන්නාරම හරහා පුත්තලම දක්වා සහ ගාල්ල හරහා හම්බන්තොට හරහා පොතුවිල් දක්වා වෙරළට ඔබ්බෙන් වන මුහුදු ප්‍රදේශවල සුළගේ වේගය විටින් විට පැ.කි.මී.45-50 දක්වා වැඩි විය හැක.",
        "කන්කසන්තුරේ සිට මන්නාරම හරහා පුත්තලම දක්වා සහ ගාල්ල සිට හම්බන්තොට හරහා පොතුවිල් දක්වා වන මුහුදු ප්‍රදේශ විටින් විට රළු වන අතර පුත්තලම සිට කොළඹ හරහා ගාල්ල දක්වා වෙරළට ඔබ්බෙන් වන මුහුදු ප්‍රදේශ විටින් විට තරමක් රළු වේ. දිවයින වටා වන අනෙකුත් මුහුදු ප්‍රදේශ මධ්‍යස්ථ විය හැක."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "බටහිර",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "සබරගමුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "මහනුවර",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගාල්ල",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මාතර",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "අද පස්වරුවේ",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉදිරි දින කිහිපය",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "කාලගුණ විද්‍යා දෙපාර්තමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "සබරගමුව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "වයඹ",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "මහනුවර",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගාල්ල",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මාතර",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "50 මි.මී",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "සබරගමුව පළාත",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මහනුවර",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "කළුතර",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "යාපනය",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ඌව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මඩකලපුව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "අම්පාර",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "සවස",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "රෑ",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "50 kmph පමණ වේ",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මේ වසරේ අගෝස්තු 28 සිට සැප්තැම්බර් 07 දක්වා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "03",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "කාක්කපල්ලිය",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "පුත්තලම දිස්ත්‍රික්කය",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "හබරවැව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kirimetiyawa",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මාතලේ දිස්ත්‍රික්කය",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Habarawa",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "බදුල්ල දිස්ත්‍රික්කය",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "දිවුලන",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "මඩකලපුව දිස්ත්‍රික්කය",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "දහවල් 12.10ට පමණ",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "30-40 kmph",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "45-50 kmph",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "කන්කසන්තුරේ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "මන්නාරම",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගාල්ල",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "කන්කසන්තුරේ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "මන්නාරම",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගාල්ල",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "පුත්තලම",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගාල්ල",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "இன்று முதல் மழை பெய்ய வாய்ப்பு உள்ளது",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "இன்று (செப். 03) பிற்பகல் முதல் தீவின் தென்மேற்குப் பகுதியில் (மேற்கு மற்றும் சப்ரகமுவ மாகாணங்களிலும் கண்டி, நுவரெலியா, காலி மற்றும் மாத்தறை மாவட்டங்களிலும்) மழையுடனான வானிலை ஓரளவுக்கு அதிகரிக்கும் என எதிர்பார்க்கப்படுவதாக திணைக்களம் தெரிவித்துள்ளது. வானிலை ஆய்வு கூறுகிறது.",
        "மேல், சப்ரகமுவ மற்றும் வடமேல் மாகாணங்களிலும் கண்டி, நுவரெலியா, காலி மற்றும் மாத்தறை மாவட்டங்களிலும் அவ்வப்போது மழை பெய்யும்.",
        "சப்ரகமுவ மாகாணத்திலும் கண்டி, நுவரெலியா மற்றும் களுத்துறை மாவட்டங்களிலும் சில இடங்களில் 50 மில்லிமீற்றருக்கு மேல் ஓரளவு பலத்த மழை பெய்யக்கூடும்.",
        "இதேவேளை, யாழ்ப்பாண மாவட்டத்தில் பல தடவைகள் மழை பெய்யும்.",
        "ஊவா மாகாணத்திலும் மட்டக்களப்பு மற்றும் அம்பாறை மாவட்டங்களிலும் ஒரு சில இடங்களில் மாலை அல்லது இரவு வேளையில் மழை அல்லது இடியுடன் கூடிய மழை பெய்யும்.",
        "மத்திய மலைநாட்டின் மேற்கு சரிவுகளில் அவ்வப்போது மணிக்கு 50 கிலோமீட்டர் வேகத்தில் பலத்த காற்று வீசக்கூடும்.",
        "இடியுடன் கூடிய மழையின் போது தற்காலிகமாக பலத்த காற்று மற்றும் மின்னல் தாக்கங்களினால் ஏற்படக்கூடிய பாதிப்புகளை குறைத்துக்கொள்ள போதிய முன்னெச்சரிக்கை நடவடிக்கைகளை எடுக்குமாறு பொதுமக்கள் அறிவுறுத்தப்படுகிறார்கள்.",
        "சூரியனின் தெற்கு நோக்கிய ஒப்பீட்டு இயக்கத்தில், இது இந்த ஆண்டு ஆகஸ்ட் 28 முதல் செப்டம்பர் 07 வரை இலங்கையின் அட்சரேகைகளுக்கு நேராக இருக்கப் போகிறது. இன்று (03) கக்கப்பள்ளி (புத்தளம் மாவட்டம்), ஹபரவெவ (குருணாகல் மாவட்டம்), கிரிமெத்தியாவ (மாத்தளை மாவட்டம்), ஹபராவ (பதுளை மாவட்டம்) மற்றும் திவுலான (மட்டக்களப்பு மாவட்டம்) ஆகியவை நண்பகல் 12.10 மணிக்கு மேல் சூரியன் மேல்நோக்கி நிற்கும் இலங்கையின் அருகிலுள்ள நகரங்களாகும்.",
        "நாட்டைச் சூழவுள்ள கடற்பரப்புகளில் பல இடங்களில் மழை அல்லது இடியுடன் கூடிய மழை பெய்யும்.",
        "காற்று தென்மேற்கு திசையில் வீசும், காற்றின் வேகம் மணிக்கு 30-40 கி.மீ. காங்கேசன்துறையிலிருந்து மன்னார் ஊடாக புத்தளம் மற்றும் காலி ஊடாக ஹம்பாந்தோட்டை ஊடாக பொத்துவில் வரையான கடற்பரப்புகளில் காற்றின் வேகமானது அவ்வப்போது மணித்தியாலத்துக்கு 45-50 கிலோ மீற்றர் வரை அதிகரித்து வீசக்கூடும்.",
        "காங்கேசன்துறையிலிருந்து மன்னார் ஊடாக புத்தளம் வரையிலும், காலி முதல் ஹம்பாந்தோட்டை ஊடாக பொத்துவில் வரையான கடற்பரப்புகளும் அவ்வப்போது கொந்தளிப்பாகவும், புத்தளத்திலிருந்து கொழும்பு ஊடாக காலி வரையான கடற்பரப்புகளில் அவ்வப்போது ஓரளவு கொந்தளிப்பாகவும் காணப்படும். நாட்டைச் சூழவுள்ள ஏனைய கடற்பரப்புக்கள் மிதமானதாக இருக்கலாம்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "மேற்கு",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "சப்ரகமுவ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "கண்டி",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "காலி",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "மாத்தறை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று மதியம்",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "அடுத்த சில நாட்கள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "வளிமண்டலவியல் திணைக்களம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "சப்ரகமுவ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "வடமேற்கு",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "கண்டி",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "காலி",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "மாத்தறை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "50மிமீ",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "சப்ரகமுவ மாகாணம்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "கண்டி",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "களுத்துறை",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "யாழ்",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஊவா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "மட்டக்களப்பு",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "அம்பாறை",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "சாயங்காலம்",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "இரவு",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "சுமார் 50 கி.மீ",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்த ஆண்டு ஆகஸ்ட் 28 முதல் செப்டம்பர் 07 வரை",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "03",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "காக்கப்பள்ளியா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "புத்தளம் மாவட்டம்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஹபரேவெவ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kirimetiyawa",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "மாத்தளை மாவட்டம்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Habarawa",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "பதுளை மாவட்டம்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "திவுலான",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "மட்டக்களப்பு மாவட்டம்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "சுமார் 12.10 மதியம்",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "மணிக்கு 30-40 கி.மீ",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "மணிக்கு 45-50 கி.மீ",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "காங்கேசன்துறை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "மன்னார்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "காலி",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "காங்கேசன்துறை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "மன்னார்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "காலி",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "புத்தளம்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "காலி",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}