{
  "newspaper_id": "lankadeepa-lk",
  "url": "https://www.lankadeepa.lk/latest_news/කෝප්--කෝපා-පත්කිරීම්-ගැන-පොහොට්ටු-ලේකම්ගෙන්-විරෝධයක්/1-618675",
  "time_ut": 1661329668,
  "original_lang": "si",
  "original_title": "කෝප්, කෝපා පත්කිරීම් ගැන පොහොට්ටු ලේකම්ගෙන් විරෝධයක්",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Objection from the Secretary of Potthu about Cope, Kopa appointments",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "Mr. Sagara Kariyawasam, Secretary of the Sri Lanka Podujana Peramuna, has strongly objected to the proposals for the appointment of MPs to the positions of COP and COPA committee chairpersons outside the standing orders of the Parliament in the Parliamentary Affairs Committee meeting.",
        "He has pointed out here that the Samagi Jana Balawegaya party has proposed the names of two members of the party for the posts of chairman before the formation of those committees and it is not possible to do so according to the standing orders of the parliament.",
        "Mr. Kariyawasam has stated that it is clearly stated in the parliamentary standing orders that the committees should be formed first and then the chairman should be elected by the majority of the members.",
        "The chief organizer of the opposition, Mr. Lakshman Kiriella, who has presented the matter at this time, has stated that the speaker agreed to give the positions of the two committee chairpersons to the opposition in a previous parliamentary committee meeting.",
        "He further said that since there are notes of that meeting, he will ask the Speaker to act according to the decision taken that day.",
        "Before this, two members of the Sri Lanka Podujana Peramuna held the positions of COP and COPA committee chairpersons.",
        "Professor Charitha Herath acted as the chairman of the COPE Committee and Professor Tissa Witharana acted as the chairman of the COPE Committee.",
        "With the termination of the second session of the Ninth Parliament, nearly seventy parliamentary committees, including COP and COPA, were abolished."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Potthu",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "Cope",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Sagara Kariyawasam",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "Podujana Peramuna",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "COP",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "COPA",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Parliamentary Affairs Committee",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Samagi",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "two",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Kariyawasam",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "first",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Lakshman Kiriella",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "two",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "that day",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "two",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "Podujana Peramuna",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "COP",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "COPA",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Charitha Herath",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the COPE Committee",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Tissa Witharana",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the COPE Committee",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "second",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Ninth Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "COP",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "COPA",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "කෝප්, කෝපා පත්කිරීම් ගැන පොහොට්ටු ලේකම්ගෙන් විරෝධයක්",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "කෝප් සහ  කෝපා  කමිටු සභාපති තනතුරුවලට පාර්ලිමේන්තුවේ ස්ථාවර නියෝගවලට පිටින්  මන්ත්‍රීවරුන් පත් කිරීම සඳහා යෝජනා ඉදිරිපත් කිරීම සම්බන්ධයෙන් ශ්‍රී ලංකා පොදුජන පෙරමුණේ ලේකම් නීතිඥ සාගර කාරියවසම් මහතා පාර්ලිමේන්තු කටයුතු පිළිබඳ කාරක සභා රැස්වීමේදී  දැඩි විරෝධය පළ කර ඇත.",
        "එම කමිටු පිහිටුවීමටත් කලින් ඒවායේ සභාපති තනතුරු සඳහා සමගි ජන බලවේගය පක්ෂය එම පක්ෂයේ මන්ත්‍රීවරුන් දෙදෙනකුගේ නම් යෝජනා කර ඇතැයිද පාර්ලිමේන්තුවේ ස්ථාවර නියෝග අනුව එසේ කටයුතු කිරීමේ හැකියාවක් නැතැයිද  ඔහු මෙහිදී පෙන්වාදී  ඇත.",
        "මුලින්ම එම කමිටු පිහිටුවා ඉන් අනතුරුව එහි සාමාජික මන්ත්‍රීවරුන්ගේ බහුතර කැමැත්තෙන් සභාපතිවරයා තෝරා පත්කර ගතයුතු වන බව පාර්ලිමේන්තු ස්ථාවර නියෝගවල පැහැදිලිවම දැක්වෙන්නේ යැයි ප්‍රකාශ කර ඇති  කාරියවසම් මහතා එක් එක් අයට ඕන විදියට  සභාපති තනතුරුවලට  මන්ත්‍රීවරුන් පත් කළ නොහැකි බවද සඳහන් කර ඇත.",
        "මේ අවස්ථාවේදී කරුණු ඉදිරිපත් කර ඇති විපක්ෂයේ ප්‍රධාන සංවිධායක ලක්ෂ්මන් කිරිඇල්ල මහතා ප්‍රකාශ කර ඇත්තේ එම කමිටු දෙකේ සභාපති තනතුරු විපක්ෂයට ලබාදීමට කතානායක වරයා මෙයට පෙර පැවැති පාර්ලිමේන්තු කාරක සභා රැස්වීමකදී  එකඟ වූ බවයි.",
        "එම රැස්වීමේ සටහන් ඇති හෙයින් එදින ගත් තීරණය අනුව කටයුතු කරන ලෙස තමා කතානායකවරයාගෙන් ඉල්ලා සිටින බවද ඔහු මෙහිදී වැඩිදුරටත් පවසා ඇත.",
        "කෝප් සහ  කෝපා  කමිටු  සභාපති තනතුරුවල  මෙයට පෙර කටයුතු කළේ ශ්‍රී ලංකා පොදුජන පෙරමුණේ මන්ත්‍රීවරුන් දෙදෙනෙකි.",
        "කෝප් කමිටුවේ සභාපතිවරයා ලෙස මහාචාර්ය  චරිත හේරත් මහතාත් කෝපා කමිටුවේ  සභාපතිවරයා ලෙස මහාචාර්ය තිස්ස විතාරණ මහතාත් එලෙස  කටයුතු කළහ.",
        "නවවෙනි පාර්ලිමේන්තුවේ දෙවැනි සභාවාරය වාර අවසාන කිරීමත් සමඟ කෝප් සහ කෝපා  ඇතුළු පාර්ලිමේන්තු කාරක සභා හැත්තෑවකට ආසන්න සංඛ්‍යාවක් අහෝසිවී  ගියේය."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "පොතු",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "මුහුණ දෙන්න",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "සාගර කාරියවසම්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "පොදුජන පෙරමුණ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "COP",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "COPA",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තු කටයුතු කාරක සභාව",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "සමගි",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "දෙක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "කාරියවසම්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "පළමුවන",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ලක්ෂ්මන් කිරිඇල්ල",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "දෙක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "එදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "දෙක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "පොදුජන පෙරමුණ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "COP",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "COPA",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "චරිත හේරත්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "කෝප් කමිටුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "තිස්ස විතාරණ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "කෝප් කමිටුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "දෙවැනි",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "නවවැනි පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "COP",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "COPA",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "கோப், கோபா நியமனங்கள் குறித்து பொத்துவின் செயலாளரிடமிருந்து எதிர்ப்பு",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "பாராளுமன்ற அலுவல்கள் குழு கூட்டத்தில் பாராளுமன்றத்தின் நிலையியற் கட்டளைக்கு புறம்பாக கோப் மற்றும் கோபா குழு தலைவர் பதவிகளுக்கு எம்.பி.க்களை நியமிக்கும் முன்மொழிவுகளுக்கு ஸ்ரீலங்கா பொதுஜன பெரமுனவின் செயலாளர் திரு.சாகர காரியவசம் கடும் எதிர்ப்பு தெரிவித்துள்ளார்.",
        "அந்தக் குழுக்களை அமைப்பதற்கு முன்னர் சமகி ஜன பலவேகய கட்சி இரண்டு பேரின் பெயர்களை தலைவர் பதவிக்கு முன்மொழிந்துள்ளதாகவும், நாடாளுமன்ற நிலையியற் கட்டளையின் பிரகாரம் அவ்வாறு செய்ய முடியாது எனவும் அவர் இங்கு சுட்டிக்காட்டியுள்ளார்.",
        "முதலில் குழுக்கள் அமைக்கப்பட்டு அதன் பின்னர் பெரும்பான்மை உறுப்பினர்களால் தலைவர் தெரிவு செய்யப்பட வேண்டும் என பாராளுமன்ற நிலையியற் கட்டளைகளில் தெளிவாக கூறப்பட்டுள்ளதாக திரு காரியவசம் குறிப்பிட்டுள்ளார்.",
        "இதன்போது விடயத்தை முன்வைத்த எதிர்க்கட்சியின் பிரதம அமைப்பாளர் திரு.லக்ஷ்மன் கிரியெல்ல, முன்னைய பாராளுமன்றக் குழுக் கூட்டத்தில் இரண்டு குழுத் தலைவர்களின் பதவிகளை எதிர்க்கட்சிக்கு வழங்குவதற்கு சபாநாயகர் இணக்கம் தெரிவித்ததாகக் குறிப்பிட்டுள்ளார்.",
        "அந்தக் கூட்டத்தின் குறிப்புகள் இருப்பதால், அன்றைய தினம் எடுக்கப்பட்ட முடிவின்படி செயல்படுமாறு சபாநாயகரிடம் கேட்டுக் கொள்வதாக அவர் மேலும் தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "இதற்கு முன்னர், ஸ்ரீலங்கா பொதுஜன பெரமுனவின் இரு உறுப்பினர்கள் COP மற்றும் COPA குழுவின் தலைவர் பதவிகளை வகித்துள்ளனர்.",
        "பேராசிரியர் சரித ஹேரத் கோப் குழுவின் தலைவராகவும், பேராசிரியர் திஸ்ஸ விதாரண கோப் குழுவின் தலைவராகவும் செயற்பட்டனர்.",
        "ஒன்பதாவது பாராளுமன்றத்தின் இரண்டாவது அமர்வு முடிவடைந்தவுடன், COP மற்றும் COPA உட்பட கிட்டத்தட்ட எழுபது பாராளுமன்றக் குழுக்கள் ஒழிக்கப்பட்டன."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "பொத்து",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "சமாளிக்க",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "சாகர காரியவசம்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "பொதுஜன பெரமுன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "சிஓபி",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "COPA",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்ற விவகாரக் குழு",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "சமகி",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "இரண்டு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "காரியவசம்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "முதலில்",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "லக்ஷ்மன் கிரியெல்ல",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இரண்டு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "அந்த நாள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இரண்டு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "பொதுஜன பெரமுன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "சிஓபி",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "COPA",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "சரித ஹேரத்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "கோப் குழு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "திஸ்ஸ விதாரண",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "கோப் குழு",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இரண்டாவது",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஒன்பதாவது பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "சிஓபி",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "COPA",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}