{
  "newspaper_id": "ada-lk",
  "url": "https://www.ada.lk/breaking_news/ගංජා-කිලෝ-212-ක්-සමග-අයෙක්-කොටුවෙයි/11-395159",
  "time_ut": 1657086864,
  "original_lang": "si",
  "original_title": "ගංජා කිලෝ 212 ක් සමග අයෙක් කොටුවෙයි",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "A person is arrested with 212 kilos of ganja",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "In a special search operation carried out by the Sri Lanka Navy in Puttalam Norochchole area this morning (06th), a suspect was caught with a van that was transporting about 212 kg of Kerala Ganja.",
        "Accordingly, the Sri Lanka Naval Ship Thambapanni, which belongs to the North West Naval Command, together with the Norochchole Police, inspected a suspicious van near the Karamba roadblock in Norochchole this morning. There, a suspect and the van were arrested along with a stock of 212 kg of Kerala ganja, which was being transported in ninety-seven parcels of ten bags.",
        "The gross street value of the Kerala ganja seized in this operation is believed to be over Rs 63 million.",
        "Furthermore, the arrested suspect was identified as a 32-year-old resident of Colombo 14, and the suspect and a 6-year-old boy in the van were taken to Norochchole Police Station for further legal proceedings along with the seized Kerala ganja stock and the van. Delivery was made."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "212 kilos",
          "label": "QUANTITY"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "the Sri Lanka Navy",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Puttalam Norochchole",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "this morning",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "06th",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "212 kg",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kerala Ganja",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the Sri Lanka Naval Ship Thambapanni",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "the North West Naval Command",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Norochchole Police",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Norochchole",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "this morning",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "212 kg",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kerala",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ninety-seven",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ten",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Kerala",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "63 million",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "32-year-old",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "6-year-old",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Norochchole Police Station",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kerala",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "ගංජා කිලෝ 212 ක් සමග අයෙක් කොටුවෙයි",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකා නාවික හමුදාව පුත්තලම නොරොච්චෝලේ ප්‍රදේශයේ අද අළුයම (06දා) සිදුකල විශේෂ සෝදිසි මෙහෙයුමකදී, කේරළ ගංජා කිලෝ ග්‍රෑම් 212 ක පමණ තොගයක් ප්‍රවාහනය කරමින් තිබූ වෑන් රථයක් සමඟ සැකකරුවකු  නීතීයේ රැහැනට හසුකර දීමට කටයුතු කෙරිණි.",
        "ඒ අනුව, වයඹ නාවික විධානයට අයත් ශ්‍රී ලංකා නාවික නෞකා තම්බපණ්නි ආයතනය විසින් නොරොච්චෝලේ පොලීසිය හා එක්ව නොරොච්චෝලේ කරඹ මාර්ග බාධකය අසලදී අද අළුයම සැකකටයුතු වෑන් රථයක්  පරීක්‍ෂාවට ලක්කරන ලදී. එහිදී, එම වෑන් රථය තුල උර දහයක  පාර්සල් අනූ හතක්  වශයෙන් අසුරා ප්‍රවාහනය කරමින් තිබූ කේරල ගංජා කිලෝ ග්‍රෑම් 212 ක පමණ තොගයක් සමඟ  සැකකරුවෙකු සහ එම වෑන් රථය අත්අඩංගුවට ගන්නා ලදී.",
        "මෙම මෙහෙයුම මඟින් අත්අඩංගුවටගත් කේරළ ගංජා තොගයේ දළ වීථි වටිනාකම රුපියල් මිලියන 63 කට අධික වෙතැයි  විශ්වාස කෙරේ.",
        "තවද, අත්අඩංගුවට ගත් සැකකරු වයස අවුරුදු 32 ක් වන කොළඹ 14 ප්‍රදේශයේ පදිංචිකරුවකු බවට හඳුනාගන්නා ලද අතර, සැකකරු සහ වෑන් රථයේ සිටි වයස අවුරුදු 06 ක පමණ ගැහුණු ළමයෙකුද, මෙහිදී අත්අඩංගුවට ගත් කේරළ ගංජා තොගය හා වෑන් රථය සමඟ ඉදිරි නීතිමය කටයුතු සඳහා නොරොච්චෝලේ පොලිස් ස්ථානය වෙත භාරදීමට  කටයුතු කෙරිණි."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "කිලෝ 212",
          "label": "QUANTITY"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකා නාවික හමුදාව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "පුත්තලම නොරොච්චෝලේ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "මේ උදෑසන",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "06 වැනි",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "කිලෝ ග්රෑම් 212 කි",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "කේරළ ගංජා",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකා නාවික නෞකා තම්බපන්නි",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "වයඹ නාවික විධානය",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "නොරොච්චෝලේ පොලිසිය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "නොරොච්චෝලේ",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "මේ උදෑසන",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "කිලෝ ග්රෑම් 212 කි",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "කේරල",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "අනූ හත",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "දස",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "කේරල",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "මිලියන 63 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "32 හැවිරිදිය",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "6 හැවිරිදි",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "නොරොච්චෝලේ පොලිස් ස්ථානය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "කේරල",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "212 கிலோ கஞ்சாவுடன் ஒருவர் கைது செய்யப்பட்டுள்ளார்",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "இலங்கை கடற்படையினர் இன்று (06) காலை புத்தளம் நொரோச்சோலை பகுதியில் மேற்கொண்ட விசேட தேடுதல் நடவடிக்கையில் சுமார் 212 கிலோகிராம் கேரள கஞ்சாவை ஏற்றிச் சென்ற வேனுடன் சந்தேகநபர் ஒருவர் கைது செய்யப்பட்டுள்ளார்.",
        "இதன்படி, வடமேற்கு கடற்படை கட்டளைக்கு சொந்தமான இலங்கை கடற்படை கப்பல் தம்பபன்னி, நொரோச்சோலை பொலிஸாருடன் இணைந்து இன்று காலை நொரோச்சோலை கரம்ப வீதி தடைக்கு அருகில் சந்தேகத்திற்கிடமான வேன் ஒன்றை சோதனையிட்டனர். அங்கு, பத்து பைகள் கொண்ட தொண்ணூற்றேழு பார்சல்களில் கொண்டு செல்லப்பட்ட 212 கிலோ கேரள கஞ்சா கையிருப்புடன் சந்தேக நபர் மற்றும் வேனும் கைது செய்யப்பட்டனர்.",
        "இந்த நடவடிக்கையில் கைப்பற்றப்பட்ட கேரள கஞ்சாவின் மொத்த மதிப்பு 63 மில்லியன் ரூபாய் என நம்பப்படுகிறது.",
        "மேலும், கைது செய்யப்பட்ட சந்தேக நபர் 32 வயதுடைய கொழும்பு 14 பிரதேசத்தை சேர்ந்தவர் என அடையாளம் காணப்பட்டதுடன், கைப்பற்றப்பட்ட கேரள கஞ்சா கையிருப்புடன் மேலதிக சட்ட நடவடிக்கைகளுக்காக வேனில் இருந்த சந்தேக நபரும் 6 வயது சிறுவனும் நொரோச்சோலை பொலிஸ் நிலையத்திற்கு அழைத்துச் செல்லப்பட்டுள்ளனர். மற்றும் வேன் டெலிவரி செய்யப்பட்டது."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "212 கிலோ",
          "label": "QUANTITY"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை கடற்படை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "புத்தளம் நொரோச்சோலை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று காலை",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "06வது",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "212 கிலோ",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "கேரள கஞ்சா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை கடற்படை கப்பல் தம்பபன்னி",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "வட மேற்கு கடற்படை கட்டளை",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "நொரோச்சோலை பொலிஸ்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "நோரோச்சோல்",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று காலை",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "212 கிலோ",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "கேரளா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "தொண்ணூற்றி ஏழு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "பத்து",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "கேரளா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "63 மில்லியன்",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "32 வயது",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "6 வயது",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "நொரோச்சோலை பொலிஸ் நிலையம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "கேரளா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}