{
  "newspaper_id": "news-first-lk",
  "url": "https://www.newsfirst.lk/2022/08/18/inquiry-into-organic-fertilizer-imports/",
  "time_ut": 1660803300,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Inquiry into Organic Fertilizer Imports",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Inquiry into Organic Fertilizer Imports",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); The National Audit Office of Sri Lanka has launched a special investigation into the Organic Fertilizer import transactions that led to much controversy.",
        "Auditor General W.P. Wickramaratne said the investigations will be based on the Organic Fertilizer Imports from China, and Liquid Organic Fertilizer Imports from India.",
        "The Auditor General said that the investigation reports are expected to be submitted to Parliament as soon as possible.",
        "The Gotabaya Rajapaksa Government reached out to China and imported organic fertilizer from Qingdao Seawin Biotech. Initial tests on samples carried out by Sri Lanka's National Plant Quarantine Service confirmed that Qingdao’s fertilizer contained a microorganism identified as ‘Erwinia’ which could cause crop failure.",
        "Qingdao Seawin Biotech responded by demanding an US$8 million compensation from Sri Lanka’s National Plant Quarantine Services, asserting that failure to pay the sum would result in legal action.",
        "The People’s Bank of Sri Lanka was blacklisted by the Economic and Commercial Office of the Chinese Embassy in Sri Lanka for failing to make the payment according to the Letter of Credit and the contracts between the two parties.",
        "The People’s Bank of Sri Lanka paid a sum of USD 6.9 Million to Qingdao Seawin Biotech Group Co., Ltd, as per the Letter of Credit opened for the purchase of organic fertilizer, 48 hours after the Colombo Commercial High Court dissolved an order preventing the payment to a Chinese company for imported fertilizer.",
        "There were serious concerns as to who allowed the Letters of Credit to be opened, even before the samples were tested for a pathogen.",
        "In addition, concerns have been raised as to why Sri Lanka purchased Nano Nitrogen liquid fertilizer from India, above the market price in India."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "News 1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "The National Audit Office of Sri Lanka",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Organic Fertilizer",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "W.P. Wickramaratne",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Organic Fertilizer Imports",
            "label": "PRODUCT"
          },
          {
            "text": "China",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Liquid Organic Fertilizer Imports",
            "label": "PRODUCT"
          },
          {
            "text": "India",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "The Auditor General",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "The Gotabaya Rajapaksa Government",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "China",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Qingdao Seawin Biotech",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka's",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "National Plant Quarantine Service",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Qingdao",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "US$8 million",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka’s",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "National Plant Quarantine Services",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "The People’s Bank of Sri Lanka",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Economic and Commercial Office",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Chinese",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Letter of Credit",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "two",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "The People’s Bank of Sri Lanka",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Qingdao Seawin Biotech Group Co., Ltd",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "48 hours",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Colombo Commercial High Court",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "Chinese",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the Letters of Credit",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Nano Nitrogen",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "India",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "India",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "කාබනික පොහොර ආනයනය පිළිබඳ විමසීම",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); මහත් ආන්දෝලනයකට තුඩු දුන් කාබනික පොහොර ආනයනික ගනුදෙනු සම්බන්ධයෙන් ශ්‍රී ලංකා ජාතික විගණන කාර්යාලය විශේෂ පරීක්ෂණයක් ආරම්භ කර තිබේ.",
        "විගණකාධිපති ඩබ්ලිව්.පී. වික්‍රමරත්න මහතා පැවසුවේ, චීනයෙන් ආනයනය කරන කාබනික පොහොර සහ ඉන්දියාවෙන් ආනයනය කරන ද්‍රව කාබනික පොහොර මත පදනම්ව විමර්ශන සිදුකරන බවයි.",
        "විමර්ශන වාර්තා හැකි ඉක්මනින් පාර්ලිමේන්තුවට ඉදිරිපත් කිරීමට බලාපොරොත්තු වන බව විගණකාධිපතිවරයා පැවසීය.",
        "ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ ආන්ඩුව චීනයට අත ගසා Qingdao Seawin Biotech වෙතින් කාබනික පොහොර ආනයනය කළේය. ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ ජාතික ශාක නිරෝධායන සේවය විසින් සිදු කරන ලද සාම්පල මත සිදු කරන ලද මූලික පරීක්ෂණවලින් තහවුරු වූයේ Qingdao පොහොරවල බෝග අසාර්ථක වීමට හේතු විය හැකි ‘Erwinia’ ලෙස හඳුනාගෙන ඇති ක්ෂුද්‍ර ජීවියෙකු අඩංගු බවයි.",
        "Qingdao Seawin Biotech ප්‍රතිචාර දක්වමින් ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ ජාතික ශාක නිරෝධායන සේවා වෙතින් ඇමරිකානු ඩොලර් මිලියන 8 ක වන්දියක් ඉල්ලා සිටි අතර, එම මුදල ගෙවීමට අපොහොසත් වීම නීතිමය ක්‍රියාමාර්ගයකට එළඹෙන බව ප්‍රකාශ කළේය.",
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ චීන තානාපති කාර්යාලයේ ආර්ථික හා වාණිජ කාර්යාලය විසින් ශ්‍රී ලංකා මහජන බැංකුව අසාදු ලේඛනගත කරනු ලැබුවේ ණයවර ලිපියට සහ දෙපාර්ශවය අතර ඇති ගිවිසුම්වලට අනුව ගෙවීම සිදු කිරීමට අපොහොසත් වීම හේතුවෙනි.",
        "කාබනික පොහොර මිලදී ගැනීම සඳහා විවෘත කරන ලද ණයවර ලිපියට අනුව, ශ්‍රී ලංකා මහජන බැංකුව විසින් සීමාසහිත Qingdao Seawin Biotech Group Co., වෙත USD මිලියන 6.9 ක මුදලක් ගෙවා ඇත, කොළඹ වාණිජ මහාධිකරණය විසින් නිකුත් කළ නියෝගයක් අවලංගු කිරීමෙන් පැය 48 කට පසුව. ආනයනික පොහොර සඳහා චීන සමාගමකට ගෙවීම.",
        "රෝග කාරකයක් සඳහා සාම්පල පරීක්ෂා කිරීමට පෙර පවා ණයවර ලිපි විවෘත කිරීමට අවසර දුන්නේ කවුරුන්ද යන්න පිළිබඳව බරපතල ගැටළු ඇති විය.",
        "මීට අමතරව, ශ්‍රී ලංකාව නැනෝ නයිට්‍රජන් ද්‍රව පොහොර ඉන්දියාවේ වෙළෙඳපොළ මිලට වඩා වැඩි මිලට ඉන්දියාවෙන් මිලදී ගත්තේ ඇයිද යන්න පිළිබඳවද අවධානය යොමු වී තිබේ."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "News 1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ ජාතික විගණන කාර්යාලය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "කාබනික පොහොර",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ඩබ්ලිව්.පී. වික්‍රමරත්න",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "කාබනික පොහොර ආනයනය",
            "label": "PRODUCT"
          },
          {
            "text": "චීනය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "දියර කාබනික පොහොර ආනයනය",
            "label": "PRODUCT"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "විගණකාධිපති",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ ආණ්ඩුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "චීනය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Qingdao Seawin Biotech",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජාතික ශාක නිරෝධායන සේවය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "කිංඩාඕ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ඇමෙරිකානු ඩොලර් මිලියන 8ක්",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජාතික ශාක නිරෝධායන සේවා",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකා මහජන බැංකුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ආර්ථික හා වාණිජ කාර්යාලය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "චීන",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ණයවර ලිපිය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "දෙක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකා මහජන බැංකුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Qingdao Seawin Biotech Group Co., Ltd",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "පැය 48 යි",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "කොළඹ වාණිජ මහාධිකරණය",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "චීන",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ණයවර ලිපි",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "නැනෝ නයිට්‍රජන්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "கரிம உரம் இறக்குமதி பற்றிய விசாரணை",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); இலங்கையின் தேசிய கணக்காய்வு அலுவலகம் பல சர்ச்சைகளுக்கு வழிவகுத்த கரிம உர இறக்குமதி பரிவர்த்தனைகள் தொடர்பில் விசேட விசாரணையை ஆரம்பித்துள்ளது.",
        "ஆடிட்டர் ஜெனரல் டபிள்யூ.பி. சீனாவில் இருந்து கரிம உரம் இறக்குமதி மற்றும் இந்தியாவில் இருந்து திரவ கரிம உரம் இறக்குமதி ஆகியவற்றின் அடிப்படையில் விசாரணை நடத்தப்படும் என்று விக்கிரமரத்ன கூறினார்.",
        "விசாரணை அறிக்கைகள் கூடிய விரைவில் பாராளுமன்றத்தில் சமர்ப்பிக்கப்படும் என எதிர்பார்க்கப்படுவதாக கணக்காய்வாளர் நாயகம் தெரிவித்துள்ளார்.",
        "கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ச அரசாங்கம் சீனாவைச் சென்றடைந்தது மற்றும் Qingdao Seawin Biotech நிறுவனத்திடமிருந்து கரிம உரத்தை இறக்குமதி செய்தது. இலங்கையின் தேசிய தாவர தனிமைப்படுத்தல் சேவையால் மேற்கொள்ளப்பட்ட மாதிரிகள் மீதான ஆரம்ப சோதனைகள், கிங்டாவோவின் உரத்தில் ‘எர்வினியா’ என அடையாளம் காணப்பட்ட நுண்ணுயிர்கள் இருந்ததை உறுதிப்படுத்தியது, இது பயிர் செயலிழப்பை ஏற்படுத்தக்கூடும்.",
        "Qingdao Seawin Biotech, இலங்கையின் தேசிய தாவர தனிமைப்படுத்தப்பட்ட சேவைகளிடம் இருந்து 8 மில்லியன் அமெரிக்க டாலர் இழப்பீடு கோரியதன் மூலம், அந்தத் தொகையைச் செலுத்தத் தவறினால் சட்ட நடவடிக்கை எடுக்கப்படும் என்று வலியுறுத்தியது.",
        "கடன் கடிதம் மற்றும் இரு தரப்பினருக்கும் இடையிலான ஒப்பந்தங்களின்படி பணம் செலுத்தத் தவறியதற்காக, இலங்கையில் உள்ள சீனத் தூதரகத்தின் பொருளாதார மற்றும் வணிக அலுவலகத்தால், இலங்கை மக்கள் வங்கி தடுப்புப்பட்டியலில் சேர்க்கப்பட்டது.",
        "கரிம உரத்தை கொள்வனவு செய்வதற்காக திறக்கப்பட்ட கடன் கடிதத்தின்படி, இலங்கை மக்கள் வங்கி 6.9 மில்லியன் அமெரிக்க டொலர்களை Qingdao Seawin Biotech Group Co., Ltd க்கு வழங்கியது, கொழும்பு வர்த்தக உயர் நீதிமன்றம் தடை விதித்த உத்தரவை 48 மணித்தியாலங்களுக்குப் பின்னர் கலைத்தது. இறக்குமதி செய்யப்பட்ட உரத்திற்கான சீன நிறுவனத்திற்கு பணம் செலுத்துதல்.",
        "நோய்க்கிருமிக்கான மாதிரிகள் பரிசோதிக்கப்படுவதற்கு முன்பே, கடன் கடிதங்களை திறக்க அனுமதித்தது யார் என்பதில் தீவிர கவலைகள் இருந்தன.",
        "மேலும், இந்தியாவில் உள்ள சந்தை விலையை விட இலங்கை ஏன் நானோ நைட்ரஜன் திரவ உரத்தை இந்தியாவில் இருந்து கொள்வனவு செய்தது என்ற கவலையும் எழுந்துள்ளது."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "News 1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கையின் தேசிய கணக்காய்வு அலுவலகம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "கரிம உரம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "டபிள்யூ.பி. விக்கிரமரத்ன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "கரிம உரம் இறக்குமதி",
            "label": "PRODUCT"
          },
          {
            "text": "சீனா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "திரவ கரிம உரம் இறக்குமதி",
            "label": "PRODUCT"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்தியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஆடிட்டர் ஜெனரல்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ச அரசாங்கம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "சீனா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "கிங்டாவோ சீவின் பயோடெக்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கையின்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "தேசிய தாவர தனிமைப்படுத்தப்பட்ட சேவை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "கிங்டாவ்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "8 மில்லியன் அமெரிக்க டாலர்கள்",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கையின்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "தேசிய தாவர தனிமைப்படுத்தப்பட்ட சேவைகள்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை மக்கள் வங்கி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "பொருளாதார மற்றும் வணிக அலுவலகம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "சீன",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "கடன் கடிதம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இரண்டு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை மக்கள் வங்கி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Qingdao Seawin Biotech Group Co., Ltd",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "48 மணிநேரம்",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "கொழும்பு வர்த்தக உயர் நீதிமன்றம்",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "சீன",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "கடன் கடிதங்கள்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "நானோ நைட்ரஜன்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்தியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்தியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}