{
  "newspaper_id": "lankadeepa-lk",
  "url": "https://www.lankadeepa.lk/latest_news/පාරෙදි-අහුලාගත්-ලක්ෂ-පහ-හමාර-අයිතිකරුට-බාරදෙයි/1-619252",
  "time_ut": 1662257332,
  "original_lang": "si",
  "original_title": "පාරෙදි අහුලාගත් ලක්ෂ පහ හමාර අයිතිකරුට බාරදෙයි",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Five and a half lakhs collected on the road will be handed over to the owner",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "The Tissamaharama police stated that the conductor and driver of a Hakmana Tissamaharama bus found and handed over Rs.",
        "Thus the wallet was picked up by Mr. TG Bandulasena, a resident of Barawakumbuka, who works at the Tangalle depot, and Mr. H. M. Tissamaharama Police stated that the driver is a resident of Ambalantota area, Kulasiri.",
        "The manager of a hotel in Tissamaharama has complained to the Tissamaharama police that the wallet fell with the mobile phone when he was taking the money to deposit in a bank.",
        "Later, he contacted the mobile phone and said that the wallet was picked up near Tissamaharama bus stand and that the bus was going to Tangalle area and that he should come to Tangalle depot and collect the wallet.",
        "Accordingly, the Tissamaharama police went to the Tangalle depot with the owner and handed over the wallet to the owner in the presence of the police in a short period of three hours, said the Tissamaharama police."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Five and a half",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Hakmana Tissamaharama",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "TG Bandulasena",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Barawakumbuka",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Tangalle",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "H. M. Tissamaharama Police",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kulasiri",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Tissamaharama",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Tissamaharama",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Tangalle",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Tangalle",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Tangalle",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "three hours",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "පාරෙදි අහුලාගත් ලක්ෂ පහ හමාර අයිතිකරුට බාරදෙයි",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "හක්මන තිස්සමහාරාම බස් රථයක කොන්දොස්තර මහතා සහ රියැදුරු මහතා  තිස්ස මහා රහම බස් බස්නැවතුම්පල ආසන්නයේදී මඟ වැටී සිටියදී අහුලා  ගත්  රුපියල් ලක්ෂ පහමාරක් සහ ජංගම දුරකථනයක් එහි අයිතිකරු සොයා භාරදීමට කටයුතු කළ බව තිස්සමහාරාම පොලීසිය සඳහන් කළේය.",
        "මෙලෙස මුදල් පසුම්බිය අහුලාගෙන ඇත්තේ තංගල්ල ඩිපෝවේ සේවය කරන ටී ජී බන්දුලසේන නැමැති බරවකුඹුක ප්‍රදේශයේ පදිංචි කොන්දොස්තර මහතා සහ එච්. එම්. කුලසිරි යන අම්බලන්තොට ප්‍රදේශයේ පදිංචි රියදුරු මහතා බව තිස්සමහාරාම පොලීසිය සඳහන් කළේය.",
        "තිස්සමහාරාමේ හෝටලයක කළමනාකාරවරයා  බැංකුවක මෙම මුදල් තැන්පත් කිරීම සඳහා යතුරුපැදියෙන් රැගෙන යන අවස්ථාවේ මෙම මුදල් පසුම්බිය ජංගම දුරකතනය සමඟ වැටී ඇති බවට තිස්සමහාරාම පොලීසියට පැමිණිලි කර ඇත.",
        "පසුව එම ජංගම දුරකතනය සමඟ සම්බන්ධ වී එම මුදල් පසුම්බිය තිස්සමහාරාම බස් නැවතුම්පොළ ආසන්නයේ දී අහුලා ගත් බවත් බස් රථය මේ වනවිට තංගල්ල ප්‍රදේශයට ගමන් කරන බවත් තංගල්ල ඩීපොවට පැමිණ මුදල පසුම්බිය භාරගන්නා ලෙසත් පවසා ඇත.",
        "ඒ අනුව තිස්සමහාරාම පොලීසිය අයිතිකරු සමග තංගල්ලේ ඩිපෝවට ගොස් පැය තුනක පමණ කෙටි කාලයකින් මුදල් පසුම්බිය හිමිකරුට පොලිසිය ඉදිරියේ භාරදීමට කටයුතු කල බව තතිස්සමහාරාම පොලීසිය සඳහන් කළේය."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "පහහමාරක්",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "හක්මන තිස්සමහාරාමය",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ටීජී බන්දුලසේන",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "බරවකුඹුක",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "තංගල්ල",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "තිස්සමහාරාම පොලිසියේ එච්.එම්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "කුලසිරි ය",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "තිස්සමහාරාම",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "තිස්සමහාරාම",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "තංගල්ල",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "තංගල්ල",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "තංගල්ල",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "පැය තුනක්",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "சாலையில் வசூலான ஐந்தரை லட்சம் உரிமையாளரிடம் ஒப்படைக்கப்படும்",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "ஹக்மன திஸ்ஸமஹாராம பேரூந்து ஒன்றின் நடத்துனர் மற்றும் சாரதி ஆகியோர் கண்டுப்பிடித்து ரூ.1000 ரூபாயை ஒப்படைத்ததாக திஸ்ஸமஹாராம பொலிஸார் தெரிவித்தனர்.",
        "இவ்வாறு பணப்பையை தங்காலை டிப்போவில் பணிபுரியும் பரவகும்புக்காவில் வசிக்கும் திரு.டி.ஜி.பந்துலசேன மற்றும் திரு.எச். எம். குலசிறி அம்பலாந்தோட்டை பகுதியைச் சேர்ந்த சாரதி என திஸ்ஸமஹாராம பொலிஸார் தெரிவித்தனர்.",
        "திஸ்ஸமஹாராமவில் உள்ள ஹோட்டல் ஒன்றின் முகாமையாளர் வங்கியில் வைப்பிலிடுவதற்காக பணத்தை எடுத்துச் செல்லும் போது கைத்தொலைபேசியுடன் பணப்பை விழுந்ததாக திஸ்ஸமஹாராம பொலிஸில் முறைப்பாடு செய்துள்ளார்.",
        "பின்னர் கைத்தொலைபேசியில் தொடர்பு கொண்டு பணப்பையை திஸ்ஸமஹாராம பஸ் நிலையத்திற்கு அருகில் எடுத்ததாகவும் பஸ் தங்காலை பகுதிக்கு செல்வதாகவும் தங்காலை டிப்போவிற்கு வந்து பணப்பையை பெற்றுக்கொள்ளுமாறும் கூறியுள்ளார்.",
        "இதன்படி, திஸ்ஸமஹாராம பொலிஸார் உரிமையாளருடன் தங்காலை டிப்போவிற்குச் சென்று மூன்று மணித்தியாலங்களுக்குள் பொலிசார் முன்னிலையில் பணப்பையை உரிமையாளரிடம் ஒப்படைத்ததாக திஸ்ஸமஹாராம பொலிஸார் தெரிவித்தனர்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ஐந்தரை",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ஹக்மன திஸ்ஸமஹாராம",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "டி.ஜி பந்துலசேன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "பரவகும்புகா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "தங்கல்லை",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "எச்.எம்.திஸ்ஸமஹாராம பொலிஸ்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "குலசிறி",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "திஸ்ஸமஹாராம",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "திஸ்ஸமஹாராம",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "தங்கல்லை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "தங்கல்லை",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "தங்கல்லை",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "மூன்று மணி நேரங்கள்",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}