{
  "newspaper_id": "ada-derana-lk",
  "url": "http://www.adaderana.lk/news/83766/ranil-to-be-sworn-in-as-president-tomorrow",
  "time_ut": 1658307420,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Ranil to be sworn in as President tomorrow",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Ranil to be sworn in as President tomorrow",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "Ranil Wickremesinghe is to be sworn in as Sri Lanka’s 8th Executive President at the Parliamentary complex tomorrow morning (21 July).",
        "Sri Lankan Parliament today voted acting president Ranil Wickremesinghe as the next President of the country. He won 134 of the total 219 votes that were found valid.",
        "The other main candidate, ruling party lawmaker Dullas Alahapperuma received 82 votes while the third candidate, Anura Kumara Dissanayaka, got just three votes.",
        "Following his victory, Wickremesinghe said that Sri Lanka is in a very difficult situation and that there are big challenges ahead.",
        "While concluding his speech in the House, the President-elect also made a request to the Speaker to allow him take oaths as the President within the parliament premises.",
        "Wickremesinghe became acting president last week after former president Gotabaya Rajapaksa fled on a military plane to the Maldives and then took a commercial flight to Singapore."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "tomorrow",
          "label": "DATE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka’s",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "8th Executive",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliamentary",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "tomorrow morning",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "21 July",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "134",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "219",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Dullas Alahapperuma",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "82",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "third",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Anura",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kumara Dissanayaka",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "just three",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "House",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "last week",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Gotabaya Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Maldives",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Singapore",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "රනිල් හෙට ජනපති ලෙස දිවුරුම් දෙයි",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ 8 වැනි විධායක ජනාධිපතිවරයා ලෙස රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතා හෙට (ජුලි 21) පෙරවරුවේ පාර්ලිමේන්තු සංකීර්ණයේදී දිවුරුම් දීමට නියමිතය.",
        "වැඩබලන ජනාධිපති රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතා රටේ මීළඟ ජනාධිපතිවරයා ලෙස ශ්‍රී ලංකා පාර්ලිමේන්තුව අද ඡන්දය ප්‍රකාශ කළේය. වලංගු බව පෙනී ගිය මුළු ඡන්ද 219 න් 134 ක් ඔහු දිනා ගත්තේය.",
        "අනෙක් ප්‍රධාන අපේක්ෂකයා වූ ආණ්ඩු පක්ෂයේ පාර්ලිමේන්තු මන්ත්‍රී ඩලස් අලහප්පෙරුම මහතා ඡන්ද 82ක් ලබා ගත් අතර තෙවැනි අපේක්ෂක අනුර කුමාර දිසානායක මහතාට ලැබුණේ ඡන්ද තුනක් පමණි.",
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකාව ඉතා අසීරු තත්ත්වයක පසුවන බවත් ඉදිරියේදී විශාල අභියෝග තිබෙන බවත් වික්‍රමසිංහ සිය ජයග්‍රහණයෙන් අනතුරුව ප්‍රකාශ කළේය.",
        "පාර්ලිමේන්තුවේදී සිය කතාව අවසන් කරමින් තේරී පත් වූ ජනාධිපතිවරයා පාර්ලිමේන්තු පරිශ්‍රය තුළදී තමාට ජනාධිපතිවරයා ලෙස දිවුරුම් දීමට අවසර දෙන ලෙස කථානායකවරයාගෙන් ඉල්ලීමක් ද කළේය.",
        "හිටපු ජනාධිපති ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ හමුදා ගුවන් යානයකින් මාලදිවයිනට පලා ගොස් වාණිජ ගුවන් යානයකින් සිංගප්පූරුව බලා ගිය සතියේ වික්‍රමසිංහ වැඩබලන ජනාධිපති විය."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "හෙට",
          "label": "DATE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "8 වැනි විධායක",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තු",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "හෙට උදේ",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "21 ජූලි",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "134",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "219",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ඩලස් අලහප්පෙරුම",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "82",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "තෙවන",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "අනුර",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "කුමාර දිසානායක",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "තුනක් පමණි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "නිවස",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ගිය සතිය",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "මාලදිවයින",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "සිංගප්පූරුව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "ரணில் ஜனாதிபதியாக நாளை பதவியேற்கிறார்",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "இலங்கையின் 8வது நிறைவேற்று ஜனாதிபதியாக ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க நாளை (ஜூலை 21) காலை பாராளுமன்ற வளாகத்தில் பதவியேற்க உள்ளார்.",
        "இலங்கையின் அடுத்த ஜனாதிபதியாக தற்காலிக ஜனாதிபதி ரணில் விக்ரமசிங்கே இன்று பாராளுமன்றத்தில் வாக்களித்துள்ளார். மொத்தமுள்ள 219 வாக்குகளில் 134 வாக்குகளை அவர் வென்றார்.",
        "மற்றைய பிரதான வேட்பாளரான ஆளும் கட்சியின் நாடாளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர் டலஸ் அழகப்பெரும 82 வாக்குகளையும் மூன்றாவது வேட்பாளர் அனுரகுமார திஸாநாயக்க 3 வாக்குகளையே பெற்றுள்ளார்.",
        "தனது வெற்றியைத் தொடர்ந்து, இலங்கை மிகவும் கடினமான சூழ்நிலையில் இருப்பதாகவும், பாரிய சவால்கள் முன்னால் இருப்பதாகவும் விக்கிரமசிங்க தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "சபையில் தனது உரையை முடிக்கும் போது, ​​ஜனாதிபதியாக தெரிவு செய்யப்பட்ட ஜனாதிபதி, பாராளுமன்ற வளாகத்தினுள் ஜனாதிபதியாக சத்தியப்பிரமாணம் செய்ய அனுமதிக்குமாறு சபாநாயகரிடம் கோரிக்கை விடுத்தார்.",
        "முன்னாள் ஜனாதிபதி கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ச இராணுவ விமானத்தில் மாலைதீவுக்கு தப்பிச் சென்று பின்னர் வர்த்தக விமானத்தில் சிங்கப்பூர் சென்றதை அடுத்து கடந்த வாரம் விக்கிரமசிங்க தற்காலிக ஜனாதிபதியானார்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "நாளை",
          "label": "DATE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கையின்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "8வது நிர்வாகி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "நாளை காலை",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "21 ஜூலை",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "134",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "219",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "டலஸ் அழகப்பெரும",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "82",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "மூன்றாவது",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "அனுர",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "குமார திஸாநாயக்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "வெறும் மூன்று",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "வீடு",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "கடந்த வாரம்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "மாலத்தீவுகள்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "சிங்கப்பூர்",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}