{
  "newspaper_id": "island-lk",
  "url": "http://island.lk/despite-negative-travel-advisories-university-of-lincoln-student-delegation-arrives-on-a-study-tour-of-sl/",
  "time_ut": 1657284780,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Despite negative travel advisories, University of Lincoln student delegation arrives on a study tour of SL",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Despite negative travel advisories, University of Lincoln student delegation arrives on a study tour of SL",
      "author": "Thilina Walpola",
      "body_lines": [
        "A delegation consisting of seventeen students from the University of Lincoln, UK, arrived on a short visit to Sri Lanka in order to study the lifestyle of the people of Sri Lanka, culture, heritage and tourism experiences offered by the destination. They also visited the Sri Lanka Tourism Promotion Bureau on their visit, in order to gain more information for their studies on Sri Lanka as a tourism destination and get further insight for their queries regarding steps being taken in a post pandemic environment to restart/ revive the Tourism industry of Sri Lanka.",
        "The group arrived at a time when the UK government had issued several travel advisories against Sri Lanka, but despite that the group was able to continue with their visit to Sri Lanka under the guidance of their Tour leader, Prof.Martin Knight, who has been to Sri Lanka with student groups on many occasions. He is also the Programme Leader for MSc International Hospitality Management, and Programme Leader MSc Crisis and Disaster Management, of the Lincoln International Business School, University of Lincoln, plus being a Barrister at Law of both England and Wales, and an Attorney –At Law of the New York Bar.",
        "As a regular visitor to the country, Prof Knight has initiated the idea of bringing a student group to Sri Lanka to share his experience along with students and to give them knowledge and insight of Sri Lanka as one of the best Tourism destinations in the world.",
        "The group was warmly welcomed by the Tourism Bureau officials including chairman, Chalaka Gajabahu , Padma Siriwardene , Managing Director , and Dushan Wickramasuriya , Director Marketing , Sri Lanka Tourism Promotion Bureau. The chairman gave a brief but a very descriptive introduction about the Sri Lankan culture, lifestyle, delicious cuisine and its inhabitants, while giving them an idea of the experiences and what they might expect during their stay in Sri Lanka. He also urged the students to spread a positive message on Sri Lanka on their return home, and encourage more travelers to Sri Lanka which will definitely be a boost for Sri Lanka Tourism.Afterwards a very productive country presentation was done by Dushan Wickramasuriya , Director Marketing SLTPB which was followed by a Q&A session. All the logistical arrangement for the tour was provided by Airwing Tours.",
        "The University of Lincoln, UK, is rated among the UK’s top 20 universities for student satisfaction in the Guardian University Guide 2022 and the Complete University Guide 2022 and in the top 30 UK universities overall in the WhatUni Student Choice Awards 2020. They hold a top five-star rating in the QS Stars ratings system of global universities and are placed among the world’s top 150 young universities in The Times Higher Education Young University Rankings 2021.",
        "Encouraging student groups as these will bring more promotional success and a more positive message about Sri Lanka, and make it once again become the number one destination in the world for Tourism. (Sri Lanka Tourism Promotion Bureau)",
        "Leave a Reply Cancel replyYour email address will not be published. Required fields are marked *Comment Name *",
        "Save my name, email, and website in this browser for the next time I comment."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "University of Lincoln",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "SL",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "seventeen",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "the University of Lincoln",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "UK",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Sri Lanka Tourism Promotion Bureau",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "UK",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Tour",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Martin Knight",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "International Hospitality Management",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Lincoln International Business School, University of Lincoln",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Barrister",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "England",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Wales",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Prof Knight",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "one",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the Tourism Bureau",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Chalaka Gajabahu",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Dushan Wickramasuriya",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Marketing ,",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lankan",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka Tourism",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Dushan Wickramasuriya",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Marketing SLTPB",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Q&A",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Airwing Tours",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "The University of Lincoln",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "UK",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "UK",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "20",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Guardian University Guide",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "2022",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Complete University Guide 2022",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "30",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "UK",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the WhatUni Student Choice Awards",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "2020",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "five",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "150",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "The Times Higher Education Young University",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "2021",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "one",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [],
        []
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "සෘණ සංචාරක උපදේශන තිබියදීත්, ලින්කන් විශ්ව විද්‍යාලයේ ශිෂ්‍ය දූත පිරිසක් ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ අධ්‍යයන චාරිකාවක් සඳහා පැමිණේ",
      "author": "තිළිණ වල්පොල",
      "body_lines": [
        "එක්සත් රාජධානියේ ලින්කන් විශ්ව විද්‍යාලයේ සිසුන් 17 දෙනෙකුගෙන් සමන්විත දූත පිරිසක් කෙටි සංචාරයක් සඳහා ශ්‍රී ලංකාවට පැමිණියේ ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ ජනතාවගේ ජීවන රටාව, සංස්කෘතිය, උරුමය සහ ගමනාන්තයෙන් පිරිනමන සංචාරක අත්දැකීම් අධ්‍යයනය කිරීම සඳහා ය. සංචාරක ගමනාන්තයක් ලෙස ශ්‍රී ලංකාව පිළිබඳ ඔවුන්ගේ අධ්‍යයනයන් සඳහා වැඩිදුර තොරතුරු ලබා ගැනීම සඳහා සහ පශ්චාත් වසංගත පරිසරයක නැවත ආරම්භ කිරීමට / පුනර්ජීවනය කිරීමට ගෙන ඇති පියවර සම්බන්ධයෙන් ඔවුන්ගේ විමසීම් සඳහා වැඩිදුර අවබෝධයක් ලබා ගැනීම සඳහා ඔවුන් සිය සංචාරයේදී ශ්‍රී ලංකා සංචාරක ප්‍රවර්ධන කාර්යාංශයට ද පැමිණියහ. ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ සංචාරක කර්මාන්තය.",
        "බ්‍රිතාන්‍ය රජය ශ්‍රී ලංකාවට එරෙහිව සංචාරක උපදේශන කිහිපයක් නිකුත් කර තිබූ අවස්ථාවක මෙම කණ්ඩායම පැමිණියද, එසේ තිබියදීත්, ඔවුන්ගේ සංචාරක නායක මහාචාර්ය මාටින් නයිට්ගේ මඟපෙන්වීම යටතේ කණ්ඩායමට ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ සංචාරය දිගටම කරගෙන යාමට හැකි විය. බොහෝ අවස්ථාවල ශිෂ්‍ය කණ්ඩායම් සමඟ ශ්‍රී ලංකාවට. ඔහු ලින්කන් විශ්ව විද්‍යාලයේ ලින්කන් ජාත්‍යන්තර ව්‍යාපාරික පාසලේ MSc ජාත්‍යන්තර ආගන්තුක සත්කාර කළමනාකරණය සහ වැඩසටහන් නායක MSc අර්බුද සහ ආපදා කළමනාකරණය සඳහා වන වැඩසටහන් නායකයා වන අතර එංගලන්තයේ සහ වේල්සයේ නීතිවේදියෙකු වන අතර නීතිඥයෙකු ද වේ. නිව් යෝර්ක් බාර් එකේ.",
        "මෙරටට නිත්‍ය ආගන්තුකයෙකු ලෙස, මහාචාර්ය නයිට් විසින් ශිෂ්‍ය කණ්ඩායමක් ශ්‍රී ලංකාවට ගෙන්වා සිසුන් සමඟ ඔහුගේ අත්දැකීම් බෙදාහදා ගැනීමට සහ ඔවුන්ට ශ්‍රී ලංකාව ලෝකයේ හොඳම සංචාරක ගමනාන්තයක් ලෙස දැනුම හා අවබෝධය ලබා දීමේ අදහස ආරම්භ කර ඇත.",
        "සංචාරක කාර්යාංශයේ සභාපති චාලක ගජබාහු, කළමනාකාර අධ්‍යක්ෂ පද්මා සිරිවර්ධන සහ ශ්‍රී ලංකා සංචාරක ප්‍රවර්ධන කාර්යාංශයේ අලෙවි අධ්‍යක්ෂ දුෂාන් වික්‍රමසූරිය ඇතුළු නිලධාරීන් විසින් මෙම පිරිස උණුසුම් ලෙස පිළිගනු ලැබීය. සභාපතිවරයා ශ්‍රී ලාංකේය සංස්කෘතිය, ජීවන රටාව, රසවත් ආහාර සහ එහි වැසියන් පිළිබඳව කෙටි නමුත් ඉතා විස්තරාත්මක හැඳින්වීමක් කළ අතර, ඔවුන් ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ රැඳී සිටින කාලය තුළ ඔවුන් අපේක්ෂා කළ හැකි අත්දැකීම් සහ ඔවුන් අපේක්ෂා කළ හැකි දේ පිළිබඳ අදහසක් ලබා දුන්නේය. ශ්‍රී ලංකාවට පැමිණීමේදී ශ්‍රී ලංකාව පිළිබඳ ධනාත්මක පණිවිඩයක් ප්‍රචාරය කරන ලෙසත්, ශ්‍රී ලංකාවට පැමිණෙන සංචාරකයින් වැඩි ප්‍රමාණයක් දිරිමත් කරන ලෙසත් ඔහු සිසුන්ගෙන් ඉල්ලා සිටි අතර එය ශ්‍රී ලංකා සංචාරක ව්‍යාපාරයට නිසැකවම රුකුලක් වනු ඇත. ඉන් අනතුරුව ඉතා ඵලදායී රට ඉදිරිපත් කිරීමක් අලෙවි අධ්‍යක්ෂ දුෂාන් වික්‍රමසූරිය විසින් සිදු කරන ලදී. ප්‍රශ්නෝත්තර සැසියකින් අනතුරුව පැවති SLTPB. සංචාරය සඳහා සියලු සැපයුම් කටයුතු Airwing Tours විසින් සපයන ලදී.",
        "එක්සත් රාජධානියේ ලින්කන් විශ්ව විද්‍යාලය, Guardian University Guide 2022 සහ Complete University Guide 2022 හි ශිෂ්‍ය තෘප්තිය සඳහා එක්සත් රාජධානියේ හොඳම විශ්ව විද්‍යාල 20 අතරට ශ්‍රේණිගත කර ඇති අතර WhatUni Student Choice Awards 2020 හි සමස්ත UK විශ්ව විද්‍යාල 30 තුළ ඔවුන් ඉහළම තලයක් දරයි. ගෝලීය විශ්ව විද්‍යාලවල QS තරු ශ්‍රේණිගත කිරීමේ ක්‍රමයේ තරු පහේ ශ්‍රේණිගත කිරීම සහ ටයිම්ස් උසස් අධ්‍යාපන තරුණ විශ්ව විද්‍යාල ශ්‍රේණිගත කිරීම් 2021 හි ලොව හොඳම තරුණ විශ්ව විද්‍යාල 150 අතරට ඇතුළත් වේ.",
        "ශිෂ්‍ය කණ්ඩායම් දිරිමත් කිරීම ශ්‍රී ලංකාව පිළිබඳ වඩාත් ප්‍රවර්ධන සාර්ථකත්වයක් සහ වඩාත් ධනාත්මක පණිවිඩයක් ගෙන ඒම සහ එය නැවත වරක් සංචාරක කර්මාන්තය සඳහා ලෝකයේ අංක එකේ ගමනාන්තය බවට පත් කරනු ඇත. (ශ්‍රී ලංකා සංචාරක ප්‍රවර්ධන කාර්යාංශය)",
        "පිළිතුරක් දෙන්න පිළිතුර අවලංගු කරන්න ඔබගේ විද්‍යුත් තැපැල් ලිපිනය ප්‍රකාශයට පත් නොකෙරේ. අවශ්‍ය ක්ෂේත්‍ර සලකුණු කර ඇත *අදහස් නම *",
        "මම ඊළඟ වතාවේ අදහස් දැක්වීම සඳහා මගේ නම, විද්‍යුත් තැපෑල සහ වෙබ් අඩවිය මෙම බ්‍රවුසරයේ සුරකින්න."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ලින්කන් විශ්ව විද්යාලය",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "එස්.එල්",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "දාහත",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ලින්කන් විශ්ව විද්‍යාලය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "එක්සත් රාජධානිය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකා සංචාරක ප්‍රවර්ධන කාර්යාංශය",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "එක්සත් රාජධානිය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "සැරිය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "මාටින් නයිට්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජාත්‍යන්තර ආගන්තුක සත්කාර කළමනාකරණය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ලින්කන් ජාත්‍යන්තර ව්‍යාපාරික පාසල, ලින්කන් විශ්ව විද්‍යාලය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "බැරිස්ටර්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "එංගලන්තය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "වේල්ස්",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "මහාචාර්ය නයිට්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "එක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "සංචාරක කාර්යාංශය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "චාලක ගජබාහු",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "දුෂාන් වික්‍රමසූරිය",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "අලෙවි ,",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලාංකික",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකා සංචාරක ව්‍යාපාරය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "දුෂාන් වික්‍රමසූරිය",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "අලෙවි SLTPB",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ප්‍රශ්න සහ පිළිතුරු",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගුවන් ගමන් චාරිකා",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ලින්කන් විශ්ව විද්‍යාලය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "එක්සත් රාජධානිය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "එක්සත් රාජධානිය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "20",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගාඩියන් විශ්ව විද්‍යාල මාර්ගෝපදේශය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "2022",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "සම්පූර්ණ විශ්ව විද්‍යාල මාර්ගෝපදේශය 2022",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "30",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "එක්සත් රාජධානිය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "WhatUni Student Choice Awards",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "2020",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "පහ",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "150",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "The Times Higher Education Young University",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "2021",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "එක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [],
        []
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "எதிர்மறையான பயண ஆலோசனைகள் இருந்தபோதிலும், லிங்கன் பல்கலைக்கழக மாணவர் குழு SL இன் ஆய்வுச் சுற்றுப்பயணத்திற்கு வந்துள்ளது",
      "author": "திலின வல்பொல",
      "body_lines": [
        "ஐக்கிய இராச்சியத்தின் லிங்கன் பல்கலைக்கழகத்தைச் சேர்ந்த பதினேழு மாணவர்களைக் கொண்ட குழுவொன்று, இலங்கை மக்களின் வாழ்க்கை முறை, கலாசாரம், பாரம்பரியம் மற்றும் சுற்றுலா அனுபவங்களை ஆய்வு செய்வதற்காக இலங்கைக்கு ஒரு குறுகிய பயணமாக வந்துள்ளது. இலங்கையை ஒரு சுற்றுலாத் தலமாகப் பற்றிய அவர்களின் ஆய்வுகள் பற்றிய கூடுதல் தகவல்களைப் பெறுவதற்காகவும், தொற்றுநோய்க்குப் பிந்தைய சூழலில் மீண்டும் தொடங்குவதற்கு/ புத்துயிர் பெறுவதற்காக எடுக்கப்பட்ட நடவடிக்கைகள் தொடர்பான அவர்களின் கேள்விகளுக்கு மேலும் நுண்ணறிவைப் பெறுவதற்காகவும், அவர்கள் தங்கள் விஜயத்தின் போது இலங்கை சுற்றுலா மேம்பாட்டுப் பணியகத்தையும் பார்வையிட்டனர். இலங்கையின் சுற்றுலாத் துறை.",
        "பிரித்தானிய அரசாங்கம் இலங்கைக்கு எதிராக பல பயண ஆலோசனைகளை வழங்கியிருந்த நேரத்தில் இந்த குழு வந்தடைந்தது, ஆனால் அதையும் மீறி குழு அவர்களின் சுற்றுப்பயணத் தலைவர் பேராசிரியர் மார்ட்டின் நைட் அவர்களின் வழிகாட்டுதலின் கீழ் இலங்கைக்கான பயணத்தைத் தொடர முடிந்தது. பல சந்தர்ப்பங்களில் மாணவர் குழுக்களுடன் இலங்கைக்கு. லிங்கன் பல்கலைக்கழகத்தின் லிங்கன் இன்டர்நேஷனல் பிசினஸ் ஸ்கூலின் எம்எஸ்சி இன்டர்நேஷனல் ஹாஸ்பிடாலிட்டி மேனேஜ்மென்ட் மற்றும் புரோகிராம் லீடர் எம்எஸ்சி நெருக்கடி மற்றும் பேரிடர் மேலாண்மைக்கான திட்டத் தலைவராகவும் உள்ளார், மேலும் இங்கிலாந்து மற்றும் வேல்ஸ் ஆகிய இரு நாடுகளிலும் சட்டத்தில் பாரிஸ்டர் மற்றும் வழக்கறிஞர் -அட் லா. நியூயார்க் பட்டியின்.",
        "நாட்டிற்கு வழமையான வருகையாளர் என்ற வகையில், பேராசிரியர் நைட் தனது அனுபவத்தை மாணவர்களுடன் பகிர்ந்து கொள்வதற்காகவும், உலகின் சிறந்த சுற்றுலாத் தலங்களில் ஒன்றாக இலங்கையைப் பற்றிய அறிவையும் நுண்ணறிவையும் வழங்குவதற்காகவும் ஒரு மாணவர் குழுவை இலங்கைக்கு வரவழைக்கும் யோசனையை ஆரம்பித்துள்ளார்.",
        "சுற்றுலாப் பணியகத்தின் தலைவர் சாலக கஜபாஹு, முகாமைத்துவப் பணிப்பாளர் பத்மா சிறிவர்தன மற்றும் இலங்கை சுற்றுலா ஊக்குவிப்பு பணியகத்தின் சந்தைப்படுத்தல் பணிப்பாளர் துஷான் விக்ரமசூரிய உள்ளிட்ட அதிகாரிகள் குழுவை அன்புடன் வரவேற்றனர். இலங்கையின் கலாச்சாரம், வாழ்க்கை முறை, சுவையான உணவு வகைகள் மற்றும் அதன் குடிமக்கள் பற்றிய சுருக்கமான ஆனால் மிகவும் விளக்கமான அறிமுகத்தை தலைவர் வழங்கினார், அதே நேரத்தில் அவர்கள் இலங்கையில் தங்கியிருக்கும் போது அவர்கள் எதிர்பார்க்கும் அனுபவங்கள் மற்றும் அவர்கள் என்ன எதிர்பார்க்கலாம் என்பது பற்றிய யோசனையை அவர்களுக்கு வழங்கினார். மாணவர்கள் தாயகம் திரும்பும்போது இலங்கையைப் பற்றி ஒரு நேர்மறையான செய்தியைப் பரப்பவும், மேலும் இலங்கைக்கு அதிகமான பயணிகளை ஊக்குவிக்கவும் அவர் வலியுறுத்தினார், இது நிச்சயமாக இலங்கை சுற்றுலாவுக்கு ஊக்கமளிக்கும். SLTPB அதைத் தொடர்ந்து ஒரு கேள்வி பதில் அமர்வு. சுற்றுப்பயணத்திற்கான அனைத்து தளவாட ஏற்பாடுகளையும் ஏர்விங் டூர்ஸ் வழங்கியது.",
        "UK, லிங்கன் பல்கலைக்கழகம், கார்டியன் பல்கலைக்கழக வழிகாட்டி 2022 மற்றும் முழுமையான பல்கலைக்கழக வழிகாட்டி 2022 ஆகியவற்றில் மாணவர்களின் திருப்திக்காக UK இன் சிறந்த 20 பல்கலைக்கழகங்களில் தரப்படுத்தப்பட்டுள்ளது மற்றும் WhatUni மாணவர் தேர்வு விருதுகள் 2020 இல் ஒட்டுமொத்த முதல் 30 UK பல்கலைக்கழகங்களில் அவை சிறந்த இடத்தைப் பெற்றுள்ளன. உலகளாவிய பல்கலைக்கழகங்களின் QS நட்சத்திர மதிப்பீடு அமைப்பில் ஐந்து நட்சத்திர மதிப்பீடு மற்றும் டைம்ஸ் உயர் கல்வி இளம் பல்கலைக்கழக தரவரிசை 2021 இல் உலகின் சிறந்த 150 இளம் பல்கலைக்கழகங்களில் இடம்பிடித்துள்ளது.",
        "மாணவர் குழுக்களை ஊக்குவிப்பது அதிக ஊக்குவிப்பு வெற்றியையும் இலங்கையைப் பற்றிய நேர்மறையான செய்தியையும் கொண்டு வருவதோடு, சுற்றுலாவுக்கான உலகின் முதல் இடமாக அதை மீண்டும் மாற்றும். (இலங்கை சுற்றுலா ஊக்குவிப்பு பணியகம்)",
        "ஒரு பதிலை விடுங்கள் பதிலை ரத்துசெய் உங்கள் மின்னஞ்சல் முகவரி வெளியிடப்படாது. தேவையான புலங்கள் குறிக்கப்பட்டுள்ளன *கருத்து பெயர் *",
        "அடுத்த முறை நான் கருத்து தெரிவிக்க, எனது பெயர், மின்னஞ்சல் மற்றும் இணையதளத்தை இந்த உலாவியில் சேமிக்கவும்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "லிங்கன் பல்கலைக்கழகம்",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "எஸ்.எல்",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "பதினேழு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "லிங்கன் பல்கலைக்கழகம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "யுகே",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை சுற்றுலா ஊக்குவிப்பு பணியகம்",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "யுகே",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சுற்றுப்பயணம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "மார்ட்டின் நைட்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சர்வதேச விருந்தோம்பல் மேலாண்மை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "லிங்கன் சர்வதேச வணிகப் பள்ளி, லிங்கன் பல்கலைக்கழகம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாரிஸ்டர்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இங்கிலாந்து",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "வேல்ஸ்",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பேராசிரியர் நைட்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஒன்று",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "சுற்றுலா பணியகம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "சாலக கஜபாஹு",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "துஷான் விக்ரமசூரிய",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "சந்தைப்படுத்தல்,",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை சுற்றுலா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "துஷான் விக்ரமசூரிய",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "சந்தைப்படுத்தல் SLTPB",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "கேள்வி பதில்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஏர்விங் டூர்ஸ்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "லிங்கன் பல்கலைக்கழகம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "யுகே",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "யுகே",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "20",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "கார்டியன் பல்கலைக்கழக வழிகாட்டி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "2022",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "முழுமையான பல்கலைக்கழக வழிகாட்டி 2022",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "30",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "யுகே",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "WhatUni மாணவர் தேர்வு விருதுகள்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "2020",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஐந்து",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "150",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "டைம்ஸ் உயர் கல்வி இளம் பல்கலைக்கழகம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "2021",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஒன்று",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [],
        []
      ]
    }
  }
}