{
  "newspaper_id": "lankadeepa-lk",
  "url": "https://www.lankadeepa.lk/latest_news/දේශබන්දු-ඇතුළු-තිදෙනකුට-පහරදුන්-තිදෙනෙක්-මාට්ටු/1-618990",
  "time_ut": 1661837955,
  "original_lang": "si",
  "original_title": "දේශබන්දු ඇතුළු තිදෙනකුට පහරදුන් තිදෙනෙක් මාට්ටු",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Three people who attacked three people, including Deshbandu, were caught",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "The police say that three suspects were arrested for assaulting and injuring three police officers, including the Senior DIG in charge of the Western Province, Mr. Deshbandu Tennakoon, on May 10 in the Kollupitiya police domain.",
        "Police say they are residents of Colombo 15 and Pitabaddara.",
        "They are going to be presented to the court under the facts of assaulting the police officers, illegal population and violation of the law."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Three",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "three",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "Deshbandu",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "three",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "three",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Western Province",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "Deshbandu Tennakoon",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "May 10",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kollupitiya",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Pitabaddara",
            "label": "LOC"
          }
        ],
        []
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "දේශබන්දු ඇතුළු තිදෙනකුට පහරදුන් තිදෙනෙක් මාට්ටු",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "බස්නාහිර පළාත භාර ජ්‍යෙෂ්ඨ නියෝජ්‍ය පොලිස්පති දේශබන්දු තෙන්නකෝන් මහතා ඇතුළු පොලිස් නිලධාරීන් තිදෙනකුට මැයි මස 10 දින කොල්ලුපිටිය පොලිස් වසමේ දී පහර දී තුවාල සිදුකිරීම සම්බන්ධයෙන් සැකකරුවන් තිදෙනකු අත්අඩංගුවට ගත් බව පොලිසිය කියයි.",
        "කොළඹ 15 සහ පිටබැද්දර යන ප්‍රදේශවල පදිංචිකරුවන් බව පොලීසිය කියයි.",
        "පොලිස් නිලධාරීන්ට පහර දීම, අයුතු ජනරාශිය, නීතිය උල්ලංඝනය කිරීම යන කරුණු යටතේ ඔවුන් අධිකරණයට ඉදිරිපත් කිරීමට නියමිතව ඇත."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "තුන්",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "තුන්",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "දේශබන්දු",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "තුන්",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "තුන්",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "බස්නාහිර පළාත",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "දේශබන්දු තෙන්නකෝන්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "මැයි 10",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "කොල්ලුපිටිය",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "පිටබද්දර",
            "label": "LOC"
          }
        ],
        []
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "தேஷ்பந்து உட்பட 3 பேரை தாக்கிய 3 பேர் பிடிபட்டனர்",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "மேல்மாகாண சிரேஷ்ட பிரதி பொலிஸ் மா அதிபர் தேஷ்பந்து தென்னகோன் உட்பட மூன்று பொலிஸ் உத்தியோகத்தர்களை கடந்த மே மாதம் 10 ஆம் திகதி கொள்ளுப்பிட்டி பொலிஸ் பிரிவில் தாக்கி காயப்படுத்திய சந்தேகநபர்கள் மூவர் கைது செய்யப்பட்டதாக பொலிஸார் தெரிவிக்கின்றனர்.",
        "இவர்கள் கொழும்பு 15 மற்றும் பிடபத்தர பிரதேசங்களில் வசிப்பவர்கள் என பொலிஸார் தெரிவித்துள்ளனர்.",
        "காவல்துறை அதிகாரிகளைத் தாக்கியது, சட்டவிரோத மக்கள் தொகை மற்றும் சட்டத்தை மீறியமை ஆகிய உண்மைகளின் கீழ் அவர்கள் நீதிமன்றத்தில் ஆஜர்படுத்தப்பட உள்ளனர்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "மூன்று",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "மூன்று",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "தேஷ்பந்து",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "மூன்று",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "மூன்று",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "மேல் மாகாணம்",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "தேஷ்பந்து தென்னகோன்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "மே 10",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "கொள்ளுப்பிட்டி",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பிடபத்தாரா",
            "label": "LOC"
          }
        ],
        []
      ]
    }
  }
}