{
  "newspaper_id": "news-first-lk",
  "url": "https://www.newsfirst.lk/2022/07/20/sri-lanka-gets-a-new-president-ranil-wickremesinghe-wins-with-134-votes/",
  "time_ut": 1658301000,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Sri Lanka gets a new President: Ranil Wickremesinghe wins with 134 votes",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Sri Lanka gets a new President: Ranil Wickremesinghe wins with 134 votes",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); Ranil Wickremesinghe was elected as the new President of the Democratic Socialist Republic of Sri Lanka following a vote in Parliament.",
        "Ranil Wickremesinghe entered Parliament from the United National Party National List following the Parliamentary Elections in August 2020.",
        "223 Members of Parliament cast their votes. 2 MPs abstained from voting. Four votes were considered as invalid and the number of valid votes were 219.",
        "This was the first time in the history of Sri Lanka that a vote took place in Parliament to elect a succeeding President, following the post being left vacant by Gotabaya Rajapaksa who resigned on the 14th of July 2022.",
        "Although there was one previous experience of electing a president by parliament in Sri Lanka, this time is special.",
        "In 1993, given the demise of the former President Ranasinghe Premadasa, D.B. Wijetunga was elected for the remainder of the term of President unanimously, without a poll as the succeeding President.",
        "But this time, as several candidates had come forward a poll was held. Accordingly, it will be marked as a new experience in the parliamentary history of this country.",
        "The names of three Members of Parliament were proposed and seconded in the Parliament yesterday (19) for the vacancy of the Presidency, with the resignation of former President Gotabaya Rajapaksa.",
        "Accordingly, the names of Acting President Ranil Wickremesinghe, Member of Parliament Dullas Alahapperuma and Member of Parliament Anura Kumara Dissanayake were proposed.",
        "Sri Lanka gets a new President: Ranil Wickremesinghe wins with 134 votes"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Sri Lanka",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "Ranil Wickremesinghe",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "134",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "News 1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Democratic Socialist Republic of Sri Lanka",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the United National Party National List",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Parliamentary Elections",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "August 2020",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "223",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "2",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Four",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "219",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "first",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Gotabaya Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the 14th of July 2022",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "one",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "1993",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ranasinghe Premadasa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "D.B. Wijetunga",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "three",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "yesterday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "19",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Gotabaya Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament Dullas Alahapperuma",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kumara Dissanayake",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "134",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවට නව ජනාධිපතිවරයෙක් ලැබේ: රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ ඡන්ද 134 කින් ජයග්‍රහණය කරයි",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); ශ්‍රී ලංකා ප්‍රජාතාන්ත්‍රික සමාජවාදී ජනරජයේ නව ජනාධිපතිවරයා ලෙස රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතා පාර්ලිමේන්තුවේ පැවති ඡන්ද විමසීමකින් අනතුරුව තේරී පත් විය.",
        "2020 අගෝස්තු මාසයේ පැවති පාර්ලිමේන්තු මැතිවරණයෙන් පසු රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ එක්සත් ජාතික පක්ෂ ජාතික ලැයිස්තුවෙන් පාර්ලිමේන්තුවට පිවිසියේය.",
        "මන්ත්‍රීවරු 223 දෙනෙක් ඡන්දය ප්‍රකාශ කළහ. මන්ත්‍රීවරු දෙදෙනෙක් ඡන්දය දීමෙන් වැළකී සිටියහ. ඡන්ද හතරක් වලංගු නොවන ලෙස සලකනු ලැබූ අතර වලංගු ඡන්ද සංඛ්‍යාව 219 කි.",
        "2022 ජුලි 14 වැනි දින ඉල්ලා අස් වූ ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ මහතා විසින් එම ධුරය පුරප්පාඩු වීමෙන් පසු, ශ්‍රී ලංකා ඉතිහාසයේ අනුප්‍රාප්තික ජනාධිපතිවරයකු තෝරා පත් කර ගැනීම සඳහා පාර්ලිමේන්තුවේ ඡන්ද විමසීමක් පැවැත්වූ පළමු අවස්ථාව මෙය විය.",
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ පාර්ලිමේන්තුවෙන් ජනාධිපතිවරයකු තෝරා ගැනීමේ එක් අත්දැකීමක් මීට පෙර තිබුණත් මෙවර විශේෂයි.",
        "1993 දී හිටපු ජනාධිපති රණසිංහ ප්‍රේමදාස මහතාගේ අභාවයත් සමඟ ඩී.බී. විජේතුංග ජනාධිපතිවරයාගේ ඉතිරි ධුර කාලය සඳහා ඒකමතිකව තේරී පත් වූයේ, අනුප්‍රාප්තික ජනාධිපතිවරයා ලෙස ඡන්ද විමසීමකින් තොරවය.",
        "නමුත් මෙවර අපේක්ෂකයන් කිහිප දෙනෙකු ඉදිරිපත් වී සිටි නිසා ඡන්ද විමසීමක් පැවැත්වුණා. ඒ අනුව එය මෙරට පාර්ලිමේන්තු ඉතිහාසයේ නවමු අත්දැකීමක් ලෙස සනිටුහන් වනු ඇත.",
        "හිටපු ජනාධිපති ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ මහතා ඉල්ලා අස්වීමත් සමඟ පුරප්පාඩු වූ ජනාධිපති ධූරය සඳහා පාර්ලිමේන්තු මන්ත්‍රීවරුන් තිදෙනෙකුගේ නම් ඊයේ (19) පාර්ලිමේන්තුවේදී යෝජනා වී ස්ථිර කෙරිණි.",
        "ඒ අනුව වැඩබලන ජනාධිපති රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ, පාර්ලිමේන්තු මන්ත්‍රී ඩලස් අලහප්පෙරුම සහ පාර්ලිමේන්තු මන්ත්‍රී අනුර කුමාර දිසානායක යන මහත්වරුන්ගේ නම් යෝජනා විය.",
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවට නව ජනාධිපතිවරයෙක් ලැබේ: රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ ඡන්ද 134 කින් ජයග්‍රහණය කරයි"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "134",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "News 1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකා ප්‍රජාතාන්ත්‍රික සමාජවාදී ජනරජය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "එක්සත් ජාතික පක්ෂ ජාතික ලැයිස්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තු මැතිවරණය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "2020 අගෝස්තු",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "223",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "2",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "හතර",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "219",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "පළමුවන",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "2022 ජූලි 14 වෙනිදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "එක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "1993",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "රණසිංහ ප්‍රේමදාස",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඩී.බී. විජේතුංග",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "තුන්",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඊයේ",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "19",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව ඩලස් අලහප්පෙරුම",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "කුමාර දිසානායක",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "134",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "இலங்கைக்கு புதிய ஜனாதிபதி: ரணில் விக்ரமசிங்கே 134 வாக்குகள் பெற்று வெற்றி பெற்றார்",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); இலங்கை ஜனநாயக சோசலிசக் குடியரசின் புதிய அதிபராக ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க நாடாளுமன்றத்தில் வாக்கெடுப்பின் மூலம் தெரிவு செய்யப்பட்டார்.",
        "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க 2020 ஆகஸ்ட் மாதம் நடைபெற்ற நாடாளுமன்றத் தேர்தலைத் தொடர்ந்து ஐக்கிய தேசியக் கட்சியின் தேசியப் பட்டியலில் இருந்து நாடாளுமன்றம் நுழைந்தார்.",
        "223 நாடாளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர்கள் வாக்களித்தனர். 2 எம்.பி.க்கள் வாக்களிக்காமல் புறக்கணித்தனர். நான்கு வாக்குகள் செல்லாதவையாகக் கருதப்பட்டு, செல்லுபடியாகும் வாக்குகளின் எண்ணிக்கை 219 ஆகும்.",
        "2022 ஆம் ஆண்டு ஜூலை 14 ஆம் திகதி இராஜினாமா செய்த கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ஷவினால் ஜனாதிபதி பதவி வெற்றிடமாக இருந்ததைத் தொடர்ந்து, இலங்கையின் வரலாற்றில் ஜனாதிபதியை தெரிவு செய்வதற்கான வாக்கெடுப்பு பாராளுமன்றத்தில் இடம்பெற்றது இதுவே முதல் தடவையாகும்.",
        "இலங்கையில் இதற்கு முன்னர் ஒரு ஜனாதிபதியை பாராளுமன்றம் மூலம் தெரிவு செய்த அனுபவம் இருந்த போதிலும், இம்முறை விசேடமானது.",
        "1993 இல், முன்னாள் ஜனாதிபதி ரணசிங்க பிரேமதாசவின் மறைவைக் கருத்தில் கொண்டு, டி.பி. விஜேதுங்க ஜனாதிபதியின் எஞ்சிய காலப்பகுதிக்கு ஒரு வாக்கெடுப்பு இல்லாமல் ஏகமனதாக தேர்ந்தெடுக்கப்பட்டார்.",
        "ஆனால் இம்முறை பல வேட்பாளர்கள் முன் வந்ததால் கருத்துக்கணிப்பு நடத்தப்பட்டது. அதன்படி, இந்நாட்டு நாடாளுமன்ற வரலாற்றில் புதிய அனுபவமாக இது குறிப்பிடப்படும்.",
        "முன்னாள் ஜனாதிபதி கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்சவின் இராஜினாமாவை அடுத்து வெற்றிடமான ஜனாதிபதி பதவிக்கு மூன்று பாராளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர்களின் பெயர்கள் நேற்று (19) பாராளுமன்றத்தில் முன்மொழியப்பட்டு உறுதிப்படுத்தப்பட்டன.",
        "இதன்படி, பதில் ஜனாதிபதி ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க, நாடாளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர் டலஸ் அழகப்பெரும மற்றும் நாடாளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர் அனுரகுமார திஸாநாயக்க ஆகியோரின் பெயர்கள் முன்மொழியப்பட்டன.",
        "இலங்கைக்கு புதிய ஜனாதிபதி: ரணில் விக்ரமசிங்கே 134 வாக்குகள் பெற்று வெற்றி பெற்றார்"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "இலங்கை",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "134",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "News 1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை ஜனநாயக சோசலிச குடியரசு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஐக்கிய தேசியக் கட்சியின் தேசியப் பட்டியல்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்ற தேர்தல்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆகஸ்ட் 2020",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "223",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "2",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "நான்கு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "219",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "முதலில்",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜூலை 14, 2022",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஒன்று",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "1993",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரணசிங்க பிரேமதாச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "டி.பி. விஜேதுங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "மூன்று",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "நேற்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "19",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம் டலஸ் அழகப்பெரும",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "குமார திஸாநாயக்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "134",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}