{
  "newspaper_id": "ada-lk",
  "url": "https://www.ada.lk/breaking_news/කැබ්---යතුරු-පැදි-ගැටී-අයෙක්-මරුට/11-396401",
  "time_ut": 1660802993,
  "original_lang": "si",
  "original_title": "කැබ් - යතුරු පැදි ගැටී අයෙක් මරුට",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "One killed in cab-motorcycle collision",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "A 74-year-old man has died in a car accident yesterday (17th) on the 2nd post of Pelawatta Neluwa main road in the Meghathanna police domain, according to the Meghathanna police.",
        "A 74-year-old man named Pathiranage Somapala, a resident of Galboraluwa, Post 2, died as follows.",
        "The motorcyclist died as a result of the collision between a cab and a motorcycle. Another person traveling on the motorcycle was seriously injured and admitted to the Nagoda hospital.",
        "The driver of the cab, a 24-year-old resident of Wellapanatha, Tanabima, has been arrested by the Meeghathanna police. The Meghathanna police are conducting further investigations."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "74-year-old",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "yesterday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "17th",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "the 2nd",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Pelawatta",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Meghathanna",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Meghathanna",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "74-year-old",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Pathiranage Somapala",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Galboraluwa",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Post 2",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "24-year-old",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Wellapanatha",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Tanabima",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Meeghathanna",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Meghathanna",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "කැබ් - යතුරු පැදි ගැටී අයෙක් මරුට",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "මීගහතැන්න පොලිස් වසමේ පැලවත්ත නෙළුව ප්‍රධාන මාර්ගයේ 2 කණුව ප්‍රදේශයේදී ඊ‍යේ (17දා)  සිදුවූ රිය අනතුරකින් 74 හැවිරිදි පුද්ගලයෙකු මියගොස් ඇති බව මීගහතැන්න පොලිසිය පවසයි.",
        "පහලහෙවෙස්ස,ගල්බොරලුව,2 කණුව පදිංචි පතිරණගේ සෝමපාල නමැති 74 හැවිරිදි අයෙකු මෙසේ මියගොස් ඇත.",
        "කැබ් රථයක් සහ යතුරු පැදියක් ගැටීමෙන් සිදුවූ මෙම අනතුරින් යතුරුපැදිකරු මෙසේ මියගොස් ඇත.එම යතුරුපැදියේ ගමන්ගත් තවත් පුද්ගලයෙක් බරපතල තුවාල ලබා නාගොඩ රෝහලට ඇතුලත්කර ඇත.",
        "කැබ් රථයේ රියදුරු වන වැල්ලපනාත ,තණබිම පදිංචි 24 හැවිරිදි පුද්ගලයෙකු මීගහතැන්න පොලිසිය අත්අඩංගුවට ගෙන ඇත.මීගහතැන්න පොලිසිය වැඩිදුර පරීක්ෂණ පවත්වයි."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "74 හැවිරිදිය",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඊයේ",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "17 වැනි",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "2 වන",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "පැලවත්ත",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "මේඝතැන්න",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මේඝතැන්න",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "74 හැවිරිදිය",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "පතිරණගේ සෝමපාල",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගල්බොරලුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "පෝස්ට් 2",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "24 හැවිරිදිය",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "වැල්ලපනත",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "තනබිම",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මීගහතැන්න",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "මේඝතැන්න",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "வண்டியும் மோட்டார் சைக்கிளும் மோதியதில் ஒருவர் பலி",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "மேகத்தன்ன பொலிஸ் பிரிவிற்குட்பட்ட பெலவத்த நெலுவ பிரதான வீதியின் 2 ஆம் கந்தையில் நேற்று (17) இடம்பெற்ற வாகன விபத்தில் 74 வயதுடைய முதியவர் ஒருவர் உயிரிழந்துள்ளதாக மேகத்தன்ன பொலிஸார் தெரிவித்துள்ளனர்.",
        "கல்பொரலுவ, போஸ்ட் 2 இல் வசித்து வந்த 74 வயதுடைய பத்திரனகே சோமபால என்ற நபரே இவ்வாறு உயிரிழந்துள்ளார்.",
        "கெப் வண்டியும் மோட்டார் சைக்கிளும் மோதியதில் மோட்டார் சைக்கிளில் பயணித்தவர் உயிரிழந்துள்ளார்.மோட்டார் சைக்கிளில் பயணித்த மற்றுமொருவர் படுகாயமடைந்து நாகொட வைத்தியசாலையில் அனுமதிக்கப்பட்டுள்ளார்.",
        "கெப் வண்டியின் சாரதியான தனபிம, வெல்லப்பநத்த பகுதியைச் சேர்ந்த 24 வயதுடைய இளைஞரே மீகத்தன்ன பொலிஸாரால் கைது செய்யப்பட்டுள்ளார்.மேகத்தன்ன பொலிஸார் மேலதிக விசாரணைகளை மேற்கொண்டு வருகின்றனர்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "74 வயதானவர்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "நேற்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "17வது",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "2வது",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "பெலவத்த",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "மேகதன்னா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "மேகதன்னா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "74 வயதானவர்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "பத்திரனகே சோமபால",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "கல்பொரலுவ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இடுகை 2",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "24 வயது",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "வெல்லபநாத",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "தனபிமா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "மீகதண்ணா",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "மேகதன்னா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}