{
  "newspaper_id": "daily-mirror-lk",
  "url": "https://www.dailymirror.lk/breaking_news/India-must-give-military-help-to-Sri-Lanka-if-requested-Swamy/108-240769",
  "time_ut": 1657473551,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "India must give military help to Sri Lanka if requested - Swamy",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "India must give military help to Sri Lanka if requested - Swamy",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "Rajya Sabha MP and Bharatiya Janata Party (BJP) stalwart Dr Subramanian Swamy said India must give military help to Sri Lanka .",
        "Dr . Swamy who is well versed in Sri Lankan politics and a close friend of the Rajapaksa family, asked in a Twitter message how India could allow a mob to overturn a legitimate election.",
        "“Both  Gotabaya and Mahinda Rajapaksha were elected in a free election with thumping majority. How can India allow a mob to overturn such a  legitimate election? Then no democratic country in our neighbourhood will be safe. If Rajapaksa wants India’s military help we must give, “ he tweeted . (Kelum Bandara)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "India",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "Sri Lanka",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Rajya Sabha MP",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Bharatiya Janata Party",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "BJP",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Dr Subramanian Swamy",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "India",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lankan",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "India",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "India",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "democratic",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "India",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kelum Bandara",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "ඉන්දියාව ඉල්ලන්නේ නම් ශ්‍රී ලංකාවට හමුදා ආධාර දිය යුතුයි - ස්වාමි",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "රාජ්‍ය සභා මන්ත්‍රී සහ භාරතීය ජනතා පක්ෂයේ (බීජේපී) ප්‍රබල ආචාර්ය සුබ්‍රමනියන් ස්වාමි පැවසුවේ ඉන්දියාව ශ්‍රී ලංකාවට හමුදා ආධාර දිය යුතු බවයි.",
        "ආචාර්ය . ශ්‍රී ලංකා දේශපාලනය පිළිබඳව මනා දැනුමක් ඇති රාජපක්ෂ පවුලේ සමීපතම මිතුරෙකු වන ස්වාමි ට්විටර් පණිවුඩයක් නිකුත් කරමින් ප්‍රශ්න කළේ නීත්‍යානුකූල මැතිවරණයක් පෙරළීමට ඉන්දියාව මැර පිරිසකට ඉඩ දෙන්නේ කෙසේ ද යන්නයි.",
        "“ගෝඨාභය සහ මහින්ද රාජපක්ෂ යන දෙදෙනාම නිදහස් මැතිවරණයකින් වැඩි බහුතරයකින් තේරී පත් විය. එවැනි නීත්‍යානුකූල මැතිවරණයක් පෙරලා දැමීමට ඉන්දියාව මැර පිරිසකට ඉඩ දෙන්නේ කෙසේද? එවිට අපේ අසල්වැසි කිසිදු ප්‍රජාතන්ත්‍රවාදී රටක් ආරක්ෂිත නොවනු ඇත. රාජපක්ෂට ඉන්දියාවේ හමුදා ආධාර අවශ්‍ය නම් අපි දිය යුතුයි, ”ඔහු ට්වීට් කළේය. (කැළුම් බණ්ඩාර)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ඉන්දියාව",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "රාජ්‍ය සභා මන්ත්‍රී",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "භාරතීය ජනතා පක්ෂය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "බී.ජේ.පී",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ආචාර්ය සුබ්‍රමනියන් ස්වාමි",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලාංකික",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ප්රජාතන්ත්රවාදී",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "කැළුම් බණ්ඩාර",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "இந்தியா இலங்கைக்கு ராணுவ உதவி கோரினால் வழங்க வேண்டும் - சுவாமி",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "ராஜ்யசபா எம்பியும் பாரதீய ஜனதா கட்சியின் தலைவருமான டாக்டர் சுப்பிரமணியன் சுவாமி, இலங்கைக்கு இந்தியா ராணுவ உதவி வழங்க வேண்டும் என்றார்.",
        "டாக்டர். இலங்கை அரசியலை நன்கு அறிந்தவரும், ராஜபக்சே குடும்பத்தின் நெருங்கிய நண்பருமான சுவாமி, சட்டப்பூர்வமான தேர்தலை ஒரு கும்பல் கவிழ்க்க இந்தியா எப்படி அனுமதிக்கும் என்று ட்விட்டர் செய்தியில் கேள்வி எழுப்பியுள்ளார்.",
        "“கோட்டாபய மற்றும் மஹிந்த ராஜபக்ஷ ஆகிய இருவருமே சுதந்திரமான தேர்தலில் அறுதிப் பெரும்பான்மையுடன் தேர்ந்தெடுக்கப்பட்டனர். அத்தகைய ஒரு  சட்டபூர்வமான தேர்தலை ஒரு கும்பல் கவிழ்க்க இந்தியா எப்படி அனுமதிக்கும்? அப்போது நமது சுற்றுப்புறத்தில் உள்ள எந்த ஒரு ஜனநாயக நாடும் பாதுகாப்பாக இருக்காது. இந்தியாவின் ராணுவ உதவியை ராஜபக்சே விரும்பினால் நாங்கள் வழங்க வேண்டும்” என்று அவர் ட்வீட் செய்துள்ளார். (கெலும் பண்டார)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "இந்தியா",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "இலங்கை",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ராஜ்யசபா எம்.பி",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாரதிய ஜனதா கட்சி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "பா.ஜ.க",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "டாக்டர் சுப்பிரமணியன் சுவாமி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்தியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ராஜபக்சே",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்தியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இந்தியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜனநாயக",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ராஜபக்சே",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்தியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "கெலும் பண்டார",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}