{
  "newspaper_id": "ada-derana-lk",
  "url": "http://www.adaderana.lk/news/84659/early-landslide-warning-issued-to-four-districts",
  "time_ut": 1661927280,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Early landslide warning issued to four districts",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Early landslide warning issued to four districts",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "As heavy rainfall prevails in many parts of the island, the National Building Research Organization (NBRO) issued an early landslide warning (Level 1) to four districts – Kalutara, Kandy, Matale and Ratnapura.",
        "People living in these areas have been advised to be watchful for the possibility of landslides, slope failures, rock falls and ground subsidence.",
        "Meanwhile, the Department of Meteorology, in an advisory issued this morning, cautioned of low-level atmospheric disturbance in the vicinity of Sri Lanka.",
        "The department said downpours above 150mm can be expected at some places in Western, Southern, Sabaragamuwa, Central and Uva provinces today.",
        "People living in hilly areas (particularly landslide-prone areas) and low-lying areas in river basins are requested to be vigilant in this regard."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "four",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "the National Building Research Organization",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "NBRO",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "1",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "four",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Matale",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ratnapura",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "the Department of Meteorology",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "this morning",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "150mm",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "Western",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Southern, Sabaragamuwa, Central",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Uva",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        []
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "දිස්ත්‍රික්ක හතරකට පූර්ව නායයෑම් අනතුරු ඇඟවීම්",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "දිවයිනේ බොහෝ ප්‍රදේශවල අධික වර්ෂාපතනයක් පවතින බැවින්, ජාතික ගොඩනැගිලි පර්යේෂණ සංවිධානය (NBRO) කළුතර, මහනුවර, මාතලේ සහ රත්නපුර දිස්ත්‍රික්ක හතරකට පූර්ව නායයාමේ අනතුරු ඇඟවීමක් (1 මට්ටමේ) නිකුත් කළේය.",
        "මෙම ප්‍රදේශවල වෙසෙන ජනතාවට නායයෑම්, බෑවුම් කඩා වැටීම්, ගල් පෙරළීම් සහ පොළව ගිලා බැසීමේ අවදානම පිළිබඳව අවධානයෙන් පසුවන ලෙස දන්වා ඇත.",
        "මේ අතර, කාලගුණ විද්‍යා දෙපාර්තමේන්තුව අද උදෑසන නිකුත් කළ උපදේශනයෙන් ශ්‍රී ලංකාව ආසන්න පහළ වායුගෝලයේ කැළඹිලි ස්වභාවයක් ගැන අනතුරු අඟවා ඇත.",
        "බස්නාහිර, දකුණ, සබරගමුව, මධ්‍යම සහ ඌව පළාත්වල ඇතැම් ස්ථානවලට අද දිනයේ මිලිමීටර් 150 ට වැඩි වර්ෂාපතනයක් අපේක්ෂා කළ හැකි බව එම දෙපාර්තමේන්තුව පවසයි.",
        "කඳුකර ප්‍රදේශවල (විශේෂයෙන් නාය යාම් අවදානම් සහිත ප්‍රදේශවල) සහ ගංගා ද්‍රෝණි ආශ්‍රිත පහත් බිම්වල වෙසෙන ජනතාව මේ සම්බන්ධයෙන් විමසිලිමත් වන ලෙස ඉල්ලා සිටියි."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "හතර",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ජාතික ගොඩනැගිලි පර්යේෂණ සංවිධානය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "NBRO",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "1",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "හතර",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "මාතලේ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "රත්නපුරය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "කාලගුණ විද්‍යා දෙපාර්තමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "මේ උදෑසන",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "150 මි.මී",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "බටහිර",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "දකුණ, සබරගමුව, මධ්‍යම",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඌව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        []
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "நான்கு மாவட்டங்களுக்கு மண்சரிவு அபாய எச்சரிக்கை விடுக்கப்பட்டுள்ளது",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "தீவின் பல பகுதிகளில் கடும் மழை பெய்து வருவதால், களுத்துறை, கண்டி, மாத்தளை மற்றும் இரத்தினபுரி ஆகிய நான்கு மாவட்டங்களுக்கு தேசிய கட்டிட ஆராய்ச்சி நிறுவனம் (NBRO) ஆரம்ப மண்சரிவு எச்சரிக்கையை (நிலை 1) விடுத்துள்ளது.",
        "நிலச்சரிவுகள், சரிவுகள் சரிவுகள், பாறை சரிவுகள் மற்றும் நிலம் சரிவு ஏற்படுவதற்கான சாத்தியக்கூறுகள் குறித்து இந்த பகுதிகளில் வசிக்கும் மக்கள் அவதானமாக இருக்குமாறு அறிவுறுத்தப்பட்டுள்ளனர்.",
        "இதற்கிடையில், வளிமண்டலவியல் திணைக்களம், இன்று காலை வெளியிட்ட ஆலோசனையில், இலங்கையை அண்மித்த பகுதிகளில் குறைந்த வளிமண்டல குழப்பம் குறித்து எச்சரித்துள்ளது.",
        "மேல், தெற்கு, சப்ரகமுவ, மத்திய மற்றும் ஊவா மாகாணங்களில் சில இடங்களில் இன்று 150 மில்லிமீற்றருக்கும் அதிகமான மழைவீழ்ச்சியை எதிர்பார்க்கலாம் என திணைக்களம் தெரிவித்துள்ளது.",
        "மலைப்பாங்கான பகுதிகளில் (குறிப்பாக மண்சரிவு அபாயம் உள்ள பகுதிகள்) மற்றும் ஆற்றுப்படுகைகளில் தாழ்வான பகுதிகளில் வசிக்கும் மக்கள் இது தொடர்பில் அவதானமாக இருக்குமாறு கேட்டுக்கொள்ளப்பட்டுள்ளனர்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "நான்கு",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "தேசிய கட்டிட ஆராய்ச்சி நிறுவனம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "NBRO",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "1",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "நான்கு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "மாத்தளை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இரத்தினபுரி",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "வளிமண்டலவியல் திணைக்களம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று காலை",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "150மிமீ",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "மேற்கு",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "தெற்கு, சப்ரகமுவ, மத்திய",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஊவா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        []
      ]
    }
  }
}