{
  "newspaper_id": "news-first-lk",
  "url": "https://www.newsfirst.lk/2022/07/12/distressed-fishermen-in-high-seas-rescued/",
  "time_ut": 1657602360,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Distressed fishermen in high seas rescued",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Distressed fishermen in high seas rescued",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); The Maritime Rescue Coordination Centre (MRCC) Colombo on 11th July 2022 coordinated the rescue of 03 fishermen whose lives were at risk aboard a distressed local fishing trawler at sea. The fishing trawler was in high seas southeast of Sri Lanka, about 174 nautical miles (about 322 km) from the Great Basses Reef Lighthouse.",
        "The local fishing trawler (Reg No. IMUL – A-0301 MTR) is reported to have left the Valaichchenai Fisheries Harbour with 03 fishermen on 02nd July 2022 for a fishing voyage. Meanwhile, the Department of Fisheries and Aquatic Resources alerted MRCC Colombo established in the Navy Headquarters that the vessel was in distress in high seas.",
        "Responding promptly to the distress call, MRCC Colombo located that the distressed fishing trawler was in high seas, southeast of Sri Lanka, about 174 nautical miles from the Great Basses Reef Lighthouse. Subsequently, MRCC Colombo has directed the MT-SHOGUN, an oil tanker which was sailing nearby to assist the distressed fishing trawler.",
        "Through the mediation of MRCC Colombo, the tanker managed to rescue 03 fishermen whose lives were at risk from the distressed local fishing vessel this evening, having reached the distressed fishing vessel that was adrift hazardously in rough sea condition. Necessary arrangements to bring the 03 fishermen to the Galle harbour are being made by MRCC Colombo as of now.",
        "Remaining true to its duty, the MRCC Colombo established in the Navy Headquarters works in full swing to assist naval and fishing communities in distress in Sri Lanka’s search and rescue region."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "News 1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "The Maritime Rescue Coordination Centre",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "11th July 2022",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "03",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "about 174",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "322 km",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Great Basses Reef Lighthouse",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "MTR",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "03",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "02nd July 2022",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Department of Fisheries and Aquatic Resources",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Navy Headquarters",
            "label": "EVENT"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Colombo",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "about 174",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Great Basses Reef Lighthouse",
            "label": "EVENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "Colombo",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "MRCC Colombo",
            "label": "WORK_OF_ART"
          },
          {
            "text": "03",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "this evening",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "03",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Galle",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Colombo",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Navy",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka’s",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "මහ මුහුදේ විපතට පත් ධීවරයින් බේරා ගැනේ",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); 2022 ජූලි 11 වන දින කොළඹ සමුද්‍රීය ගලවා ගැනීමේ සම්බන්ධීකරණ මධ්‍යස්ථානය (MRCC) විසින් මුහුදේ විපතට පත් දේශීය ධීවර යාත්‍රාවක ජීවිත අවදානමට ලක්ව සිටි ධීවරයින් 03 දෙනෙකු බේරා ගැනීම සම්බන්ධීකරණය කරන ලදී. ධීවර යාත්‍රාව ශ්‍රී ලංකාවට ගිනිකොන දෙසින් මහ මුහුදේ, ග්‍රේට් බාස් රීෆ් ප්‍රදීපාගාරයේ සිට නාවික සැතපුම් 174ක් (කිලෝමීටර් 322ක් පමණ) දුරින් විය.",
        "දේශීය ධීවර යාත්‍රාව (Reg No. IMUL – A-0301 MTR) 2022 ජූලි 02 වන දින ධීවරයින් 03 දෙනෙකු සමඟ වාලච්චේන ධීවර වරායෙන් ධීවර ගමනක් සඳහා පිටත්ව ගිය බව වාර්තා වේ. මේ අතර, ධීවර හා ජලජ සම්පත් දෙපාර්තමේන්තුව නාවික හමුදා මූලස්ථානයේ ස්ථාපිත MRCC Colombo වෙත දැනුම් දුන්නේ මෙම යාත්‍රාව මහ මුහුදේදී අනතුරට ලක්ව ඇති බවයි.",
        "ආපදා ඇමතුමට වහා ප්‍රතිචාර දැක්වූ MRCC Colombo විසින් විපතට පත් ධීවර යාත්‍රාව ශ්‍රී ලංකාවට ගිනිකොන දෙසින් මහා මුහුදේ, Great Basses Reef Lighthouse සිට නාවික සැතපුම් 174 ක් පමණ දුරින් ඇති බව සොයා ගන්නා ලදී. පසුව, MRCC Colombo විසින් විපතට පත් ධීවර යාත්‍රාවට සහය වීමට ඒ අසල යාත්‍රා කරමින් තිබූ MT-SHOGUN නම් තෙල් නැව යොමු කර ඇත.",
        "කොළඹ එම්ආර්සීසී එම්ආර්සීසී ආයතනයේ මැදිහත්වීම මත අද සවස අනතුරට පත් දේශීය ධීවර යාත්‍රාවෙන් ජීවිත අවදානමට ලක්ව සිටි ධීවරයින් 03 දෙනෙකු බේරා ගැනීමට තෙල් ටැංකිය සමත් වී ඇත. මෙම ධීවරයින් 03 දෙනා ගාලු වරායට රැගෙන ඒම සඳහා අවශ්‍ය කටයුතු මේ වන විට කොළඹ MRCC ආයතනය විසින් සිදු කරමින් පවතී.",
        "නාවික හමුදා මූලස්ථානයේ ස්ථාපිත MRCC Colombo ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ සෙවීම් සහ ගලවා ගැනීමේ කලාපයේ විපතට පත් නාවික සහ ධීවර ප්‍රජාවන්ට සහය වීම සඳහා පූර්ණ වශයෙන් ක්‍රියා කරයි."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "News 1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "සමුද්‍ර ගලවා ගැනීමේ සම්බන්ධීකරණ මධ්‍යස්ථානය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "2022 ජූලි 11",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "03",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "174 පමණ",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "කිලෝමීටර 322 කි",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "මහා බාස් රීෆ් ප්‍රදීපාගාරය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "MTR",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "03",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "2022 ජූලි 02",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ධීවර හා ජලජ සම්පත් දෙපාර්තමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "නාවික හමුදා මූලස්ථානය",
            "label": "EVENT"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "කොළඹ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "174 පමණ",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "මහා බාස් රීෆ් ප්‍රදීපාගාරය",
            "label": "EVENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "කොළඹ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "MRCC කොළඹ",
            "label": "WORK_OF_ART"
          },
          {
            "text": "03",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "අද සවස",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "03",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගාල්ල",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "කොළඹ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "නාවික",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "கடலில் தத்தளித்த மீனவர்கள் மீட்கப்பட்டனர்",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); கடல்சார் மீட்பு ஒருங்கிணைப்பு மையம் (MRCC) கொழும்பு 11 ஜூலை 2022 அன்று கடலில் உள்ளூர் மீன்பிடி இழுவை படகில் உயிருக்கு ஆபத்தில் இருந்த 03 மீனவர்களை ஒருங்கிணைத்தது. இந்த மீன்பிடி இழுவை படகு இலங்கைக்கு தென்கிழக்கே உயர் கடலில், கிரேட் பாஸ்ஸ் ரீஃப் லைட்ஹவுஸிலிருந்து சுமார் 174 கடல் மைல் (சுமார் 322 கிமீ) தொலைவில் இருந்தது.",
        "உள்ளூர் மீன்பிடி இழுவைப்படகு (பதிவு எண். IMUL – A-0301 MTR) 02 ஜூலை 2022 அன்று வாழைச்சேனை மீன்பிடித் துறைமுகத்திலிருந்து 02 ஜூலை 2022 அன்று மீன்பிடிப் பயணத்திற்காகப் புறப்பட்டதாகத் தெரிவிக்கப்படுகிறது. இதற்கிடையில், கடற்றொழில் மற்றும் நீரியல் வளத் திணைக்களம், கடற்படைத் தலைமையகத்தில் நிறுவப்பட்ட எம்.ஆர்.சி.சி கொழும்பை எச்சரித்துள்ளது.",
        "பேரிடர் அழைப்பிற்கு உடனடியாகப் பதிலளித்த MRCC கொழும்பு, இலங்கையின் தென்கிழக்கே, கிரேட் பாஸ்ஸ் ரீஃப் லைட்ஹவுஸிலிருந்து சுமார் 174 கடல் மைல் தொலைவில், இலங்கையின் தென்கிழக்கில், உயர் கடலில், பாதிக்கப்பட்ட மீன்பிடி இழுவைப்படகு இருந்ததைக் கண்டறிந்தது. அதனைத் தொடர்ந்து, MRCC Colombo, MT-SHOGUN என்ற எண்ணெய்க் கப்பலை, அருகில் சென்று கொண்டிருந்த மீன்பிடி இழுவை படகிற்கு உதவியாக அனுப்பியுள்ளது.",
        "கொழும்பில் MRCC இன் மத்தியஸ்தத்தின் ஊடாக, இன்று மாலை, கடற்பரப்பில் ஆபத்தான நிலையில் தத்தளித்துக் கொண்டிருந்த மீன்பிடி கப்பலை அடைந்து, இன்று மாலை, உள்ளூர் மீன்பிடி கப்பலில் இருந்து உயிருக்கு ஆபத்தில் இருந்த 03 மீனவர்களை டேங்கர் மூலம் காப்பாற்ற முடிந்தது. 03 மீனவர்களையும் காலி துறைமுகத்திற்கு அழைத்து வருவதற்கு தேவையான ஏற்பாடுகள் தற்போது MRCC கொழும்பு நிறுவனத்தினால் மேற்கொள்ளப்பட்டு வருகின்றது.",
        "கடற்படைத் தலைமையகத்தில் நிறுவப்பட்ட MRCC கொழும்பு தனது கடமைக்கு உண்மையாகவே உள்ளது, இலங்கையின் தேடுதல் மற்றும் மீட்புப் பிராந்தியத்தில் துன்பத்தில் உள்ள கடற்படை மற்றும் மீனவ சமூகங்களுக்கு உதவ முழு வீச்சில் செயல்படுகிறது."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "News 1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "கடல்சார் மீட்பு ஒருங்கிணைப்பு மையம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "11 ஜூலை 2022",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "03",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சுமார் 174",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "322 கி.மீ",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "கிரேட் பாஸ்ஸ் ரீஃப் லைட்ஹவுஸ்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "எம்டிஆர்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "03",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "02 ஜூலை 2022",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "மீன்பிடி மற்றும் நீரியல் வளங்கள் திணைக்களம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "கடற்படை தலைமையகம்",
            "label": "EVENT"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "கொழும்பு",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சுமார் 174",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "கிரேட் பாஸ்ஸ் ரீஃப் லைட்ஹவுஸ்",
            "label": "EVENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "கொழும்பு",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "MRCC கொழும்பு",
            "label": "WORK_OF_ART"
          },
          {
            "text": "03",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று மாலை",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "03",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "காலி",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "கொழும்பு",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "கடற்படை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கையின்",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}