{
  "newspaper_id": "news-first-lk",
  "url": "https://www.newsfirst.lk/2022/08/15/india-marks-independence-modi-sets-goals-for-2047/",
  "time_ut": 1660539060,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "India marks Independence: Modi sets Goals for 2047",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "India marks Independence: Modi sets Goals for 2047",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "New Delhi: India Prime Minister Narendra Modi, leading the celebrations for 75 years of Independence today (15) , set the people a series of goals for the next 25 years.",
        "India, he said, must become a developed nation before it marks the Centenary of Independence.",
        "\"We are thankful to Bapu, Netaji Subhash Chandra Bose, Babasaheb Ambedkar, Veer Savarkar who gave their lives for country's independence,\" PM Modi said.",
        "In his address, PM Modi called upon the people to move forward with five pledges to fulfill the dreams of freedom fighters by 2047 — a theme President Droupadi Murmu had also underscored it in her speech on the eve of Independence Day.",
        "The five pledges for 2047 are — having developed India, removing any sign of servility, pride in heritage, unity and fulfilling our duties, PM Modi said.",
        "The celebrations had started with PM Modi's visit to Raj Ghat where he paid homage to Mahatma Gandhi. After arriving at the Red Fort, he examined the inter-services and police Guard of Honour and hoisted the national flag.",
        "The celebrations for 75 years of Independence are being marked by a mega programme, the Azadi ka Amrit Mahotsav, which started in March 2021. The day will be observed by flag hoisting and other events. Across the nation, national monuments and iconic buildings have been lit up.",
        "The Indo-Tibetan Border Police personnel has scaled 75 peaks simultaneously today as Mission 'Amritarohan' and hoisted National Flag atop those 75 peaks as a distinguished record.",
        "In a first, the government has also allowed people to display the flag at their homes for three days. The flag laws had to be tweaked for the \"Har Ghar Tiranga\" campaign.",
        "For the first time, indigenously made howitzer guns were used in the ceremonial 21-gun salute. The Advanced Towed Artillery Gun System (ATAGS) developed by the defence research organisation DRDO is the flagship product of PM Modi's Make in India campaign.",
        "Extensive security arrangements have been made across the national capital. More than 10,000 personnel have been deployed to guard the Red Fort in a multi-layered security cover. Facial recognition system cameras have been installed at the entry point. Around 7,000 invitees are expected to attend the event.",
        "This year, wall hangings of prominent freedom fighters and decorative ones depicting cultural, natural and religious heritage from different states and Union Territories are adorning the walls of the Red Fort."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "2047",
          "label": "DATE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "New Delhi",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "India",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Narendra Modi",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "75 years",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "15",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "the next 25 years",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "India",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Centenary of Independence",
            "label": "WORK_OF_ART"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Bapu",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Veer Savarkar",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "PM Modi",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "five",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "2047",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Droupadi Murmu",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Independence Day",
            "label": "EVENT"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "five",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "2047",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "India",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "PM Modi",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "PM Modi's",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Mahatma Gandhi",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Red Fort",
            "label": "LOC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "75 years",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "March 2021",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "The day",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "75",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Mission 'Amritarohan'",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "National Flag",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "75",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "first",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "three days",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Har Ghar",
            "label": "WORK_OF_ART"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "first",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "21",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "the defence research organisation",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "PM Modi's",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "India",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "More than 10,000",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Red Fort",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "7,000",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "This year",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Union Territories",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Red Fort",
            "label": "LOC"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "ඉන්දියාව නිදහස සනිටුහන් කරයි: මෝඩි 2047 සඳහා ඉලක්ක තබයි",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "නවදිල්ලිය: ඉන්දීය අගමැති නරේන්ද්‍ර මෝදි අද (15) නිදහසේ 75 වසර සැමරීමේ ප්‍රධානත්වයෙන් ඉදිරි වසර 25 සඳහා ජනතාවට ඉලක්ක මාලාවක් තැබීය.",
        "නිදහසේ ශත සංවත්සරය සනිටුහන් කිරීමට පෙර ඉන්දියාව සංවර්ධිත ජාතියක් බවට පත්විය යුතු බව ඔහු පැවසීය.",
        "“රටේ නිදහස වෙනුවෙන් දිවි දුන් බාපු, නේතාජි සුභාෂ් චන්ද්‍රබෝස්, බාබාසාහේබ් අම්බෙඩ්කාර්, වීර් සවර්කාර් යන අයට අපි ස්තූතිවන්ත වෙනවා,” අගමැති මෝදි පැවසීය.",
        "අගමැති මෝදි සිය දේශනයේදී 2047 වන විට නිදහස් සටන්කාමීන්ගේ සිහින සැබෑ කිරීමට පොරොන්දු පහක් සමඟ ඉදිරියට යන ලෙස ජනතාවගෙන් ඉල්ලා සිටියේය - ජනාධිපති ද්‍රෞපදි මුර්මු ද නිදහස් දිනය ආසන්නයේ සිය කතාවේදී එය අවධාරණය කර තිබුණි.",
        "2047 සඳහා වන ප්‍රතිඥාවන් පහ නම් - ඉන්දියාව දියුණු කර තිබීම, වහල්භාවයේ කිසිදු සලකුණක් ඉවත් කිරීම, උරුමයේ අභිමානය, එකමුතුකම සහ අපගේ යුතුකම් ඉටු කිරීම, අගමැති මෝදි පැවසීය.",
        "සැමරුම් උත්සවය ආරම්භ වූයේ අගමැති මෝදි මහතා මහත්මා ගාන්ධිට උපහාර දැක්වීමත් සමඟ රාජ් ගාට් වෙත පැමිණීමත් සමඟය. රතු බලකොටුවට පැමිණීමෙන් පසු ඔහු අන්තර් සේවා සහ පොලිස් ගෞරව ආරක්‍ෂාව පරීක්‍ෂා කර ජාතික ධජය එසවීය.",
        "2021 මාර්තු මස ආරම්භ වූ Azadi ka Amrit Mahotsav නම් දැවැන්ත වැඩසටහනක් මගින් වසර 75 ක නිදහස සඳහා වූ සැමරුම් සනිටුහන් කෙරේ. මෙම දිනය ධජය එසවීම සහ අනෙකුත් සිදුවීම් මගින් නිරීක්ෂණය කෙරේ. රට පුරා ජාතික ස්මාරක සහ සංකේතාත්මක ගොඩනැගිලි ආලෝකමත් කර ඇත.",
        "ඉන්දු-ටිබෙට් දේශසීමා පොලිස් භටයින් අද දින ‘අම්රිතාරෝහන්’ මෙහෙයුම ලෙස එකවර කඳු මුදුන් 75ක් තරණය කර එම කඳු මුදුන් 75 මත ජාතික කොඩිය එසවූයේ විශිෂ්ට වාර්තාවක් ලෙසිනි.",
        "ප්‍රථමයෙන් දින තුනක් තම නිවෙස්වල කොඩිය ප්‍රදර්ශනය කිරීමට රජය අවසර දී ඇත. \"හර් ඝර් ටිරංග\" ව්‍යාපාරය සඳහා කොඩි නීති වෙනස් කිරීමට සිදු විය.",
        "ප්‍රථම වතාවට, ස්වදේශීයව සාදන ලද හොවිට්සර් තුවක්කු 21 තුවක්කු ආචාරය සඳහා භාවිතා කරන ලදී. ආරක්ෂක පර්යේෂණ සංවිධානයක් වන DRDO විසින් වැඩි දියුණු කරන ලද ඇදගෙන යන කාලතුවක්කු පද්ධතිය (ATAGS) යනු අගමැති මෝදිගේ Make in India ව්‍යාපාරයේ ප්‍රමුඛතම නිෂ්පාදනයයි.",
        "ජාතික අගනුවර පුරා පුළුල් ආරක්ෂක විධිවිධාන යොදා ඇත. රතු කොටුවේ ආරක්ෂාව සඳහා 10,000කට අධික පිරිසක් යොදවා ඇත්තේ බහු ස්ථර ආරක්‍ෂක ආවරණයකිනි. පිවිසුම් ස්ථානයේ මුහුණු හඳුනාගැනීමේ පද්ධති කැමරා සවි කර ඇත. මෙම අවස්ථාවට ආරාධිතයින් 7,000ක් පමණ සහභාගි වනු ඇතැයි අපේක්ෂා කෙරේ.",
        "මෙම වසරේ, ප්‍රමුඛ නිදහස් සටන්කාමීන්ගේ බිත්ති සැරසිලි සහ විවිධ ප්‍රාන්ත සහ යූනියන් ප්‍රදේශවලින් සංස්කෘතික, ස්වාභාවික හා ආගමික උරුමයන් නිරූපණය කරන අලංකාර ඒවා රතු කොටුවේ බිත්ති අලංකාර කරයි."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "2047",
          "label": "DATE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "නව දිල්ලි",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "නරේන්ද්‍ර මෝදි",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "අවුරුදු 75 යි",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "15",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉදිරි වසර 25",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "නිදහසේ ශත සංවත්සරය",
            "label": "WORK_OF_ART"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "බාපු",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "වීර් සාවර්කාර්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "අගමැති මෝදි",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "පහ",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "2047",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ද්‍රෞපදී මුර්මු",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "නිදහස් දිනය",
            "label": "EVENT"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "පහ",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "2047",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "අගමැති මෝදි",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "අගමැති මෝදිගේ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "මහත්මා ගාන්ධි",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "රතු බලකොටුව",
            "label": "LOC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "අවුරුදු 75 යි",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "2021 මාර්තු",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "දවස",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "75",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මෙහෙයුම 'අම්රිතාරෝහන්'",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජාතික කොඩිය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "75",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "පළමුවන",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "දවස් තුනක්",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "හර් ගාර්",
            "label": "WORK_OF_ART"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "පළමුවන",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "21",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ආරක්ෂක පර්යේෂණ සංවිධානය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "අගමැති මෝදිගේ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "10,000 කට වඩා වැඩිය",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "රතු බලකොටුව",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "7,000 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "මේ වසරේ",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "යුනියන් ප්‍රදේශ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "රතු බලකොටුව",
            "label": "LOC"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "இந்தியா சுதந்திரத்தைக் குறிக்கிறது: மோடி 2047க்கான இலக்குகளை நிர்ணயித்தார்",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "புதுடெல்லி: இந்தியப் பிரதமர் நரேந்திர மோடி, இன்று (15) 75வது சுதந்திர தின கொண்டாட்டங்களைத் தலைமை தாங்கி, அடுத்த 25 ஆண்டுகளுக்கான இலக்குகளை மக்களுக்கு நிர்ணயித்தார்.",
        "சுதந்திரத்தின் நூற்றாண்டைக் கொண்டாடும் முன் இந்தியா வளர்ந்த நாடாக மாற வேண்டும் என்றார்.",
        "நாட்டின் சுதந்திரத்திற்காக உயிர் தியாகம் செய்த பாபு, நேதாஜி சுபாஷ் சந்திரபோஸ், பாபாசாகேப் அம்பேத்கர், வீர் சாவர்க்கர் ஆகியோருக்கு நன்றி தெரிவித்துக் கொள்கிறோம் என்று பிரதமர் மோடி கூறினார்.",
        "பிரதமர் மோடி தனது உரையில், 2047 ஆம் ஆண்டிற்குள் சுதந்திரப் போராட்ட வீரர்களின் கனவுகளை நிறைவேற்ற ஐந்து உறுதிமொழிகளுடன் மக்கள் முன்னேற வேண்டும் என்று அழைப்பு விடுத்தார் - ஜனாதிபதி திரௌபதி முர்முவும் சுதந்திர தினத்தை முன்னிட்டு தனது உரையில் அதை அடிக்கோடிட்டுக் காட்டினார்.",
        "2047 ஆம் ஆண்டிற்கான ஐந்து உறுதிமொழிகள் - இந்தியாவை வளர்ச்சியடையச் செய்தல், அடிமைத்தனத்தின் எந்த அடையாளத்தையும் அகற்றுவது, பாரம்பரியத்தின் பெருமை, ஒற்றுமை மற்றும் நமது கடமைகளை நிறைவேற்றுவது என்று பிரதமர் மோடி கூறினார்.",
        "பிரதமர் மோடி ராஜ்காட் சென்று அங்கு மகாத்மா காந்திக்கு அஞ்சலி செலுத்திய உடன் கொண்டாட்டங்கள் தொடங்கின. செங்கோட்டையை வந்தடைந்த அவர், ராணுவத்தினருக்கும், காவல் துறையினருக்கும் மரியாதை செலுத்தி, தேசியக் கொடியை ஏற்றி வைத்தார்.",
        "75 ஆண்டுகால சுதந்திரத்திற்கான கொண்டாட்டங்கள் மார்ச் 2021 இல் தொடங்கிய ஆசாதி கா அம்ரித் மஹோத்சவ் என்ற மெகா நிகழ்ச்சியால் குறிக்கப்படுகின்றன. கொடியேற்றம் மற்றும் பிற நிகழ்வுகள் மூலம் நாள் அனுசரிக்கப்படும். நாடு முழுவதும், தேசிய நினைவுச்சின்னங்கள் மற்றும் சின்னமான கட்டிடங்கள் ஒளிர்கின்றன.",
        "இந்தோ-திபெத்திய எல்லைக் காவல் படையினர் இன்று ஒரே நேரத்தில் 75 சிகரங்களை மிஷன் 'அமிர்தரோஹன்' என்ற பெயரில் ஏறி, அந்த 75 சிகரங்களில் தேசியக் கொடியை ஏற்றி சாதனை படைத்துள்ளனர்.",
        "முதன்முதலாக, மக்கள் தங்கள் வீடுகளில் மூன்று நாட்களுக்கு கொடியைக் காட்ட அரசாங்கம் அனுமதித்துள்ளது. \"ஹர் கர் திரங்கா\" பிரச்சாரத்திற்காக கொடி சட்டங்கள் மாற்றியமைக்கப்பட வேண்டும்.",
        "முதன்முறையாக, சம்பிரதாயமான 21-துப்பாக்கி வணக்கத்தில் உள்நாட்டிலேயே தயாரிக்கப்பட்ட ஹோவிட்சர் துப்பாக்கிகள் பயன்படுத்தப்பட்டன. பாதுகாப்பு ஆராய்ச்சி அமைப்பான டிஆர்டிஓவால் உருவாக்கப்பட்ட மேம்பட்ட தோண்டப்பட்ட பீரங்கி துப்பாக்கி அமைப்பு (ஏடிஏஜிஎஸ்) பிரதமர் மோடியின் மேக் இன் இந்தியா பிரச்சாரத்தின் முதன்மை தயாரிப்பு ஆகும்.",
        "தலைநகர் முழுவதும் விரிவான பாதுகாப்பு ஏற்பாடுகள் செய்யப்பட்டுள்ளன. செங்கோட்டையில் 10,000க்கும் மேற்பட்ட வீரர்கள் பல அடுக்கு பாதுகாப்பு பணியில் ஈடுபடுத்தப்பட்டுள்ளனர். நுழைவாயிலில் முக அடையாளம் காணும் கேமராக்கள் பொருத்தப்பட்டுள்ளன. இந்நிகழ்ச்சியில் சுமார் 7,000 அழைப்பாளர்கள் கலந்து கொள்வார்கள் என்று எதிர்பார்க்கப்படுகிறது.",
        "இந்த ஆண்டு, பல்வேறு மாநிலங்கள் மற்றும் யூனியன் பிரதேசங்களின் கலாச்சார, இயற்கை மற்றும் மத பாரம்பரியத்தை சித்தரிக்கும் முக்கிய சுதந்திர போராட்ட வீரர்களின் சுவர் தொங்கல்கள் மற்றும் அலங்கார சுவர்கள் செங்கோட்டையின் சுவர்களை அலங்கரிக்கின்றன."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "2047",
          "label": "DATE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "புது தில்லி",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்தியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "நரேந்திர மோடி",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "75 ஆண்டுகள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "15",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "அடுத்த 25 ஆண்டுகள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இந்தியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சுதந்திரத்தின் நூற்றாண்டு",
            "label": "WORK_OF_ART"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பாபு",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "வீர் சாவர்க்கர்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "பிரதமர் மோடி",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஐந்து",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "2047",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "திரௌபதி முர்மு",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "சுதந்திர தினம்",
            "label": "EVENT"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஐந்து",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "2047",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்தியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "பிரதமர் மோடி",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பிரதமர் மோடியின்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "மகாத்மா காந்தி",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "செங்கோட்டை",
            "label": "LOC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "75 ஆண்டுகள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "மார்ச் 2021",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "தினம்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "75",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "மிஷன் 'அமிர்தரோஹன்'",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "தேசிய கொடி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "75",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "முதலில்",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "மூன்று நாட்கள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஹர் கர்",
            "label": "WORK_OF_ART"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "முதலில்",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "21",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாதுகாப்பு ஆராய்ச்சி அமைப்பு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "பிரதமர் மோடியின்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்தியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "10,000க்கு மேல்",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "செங்கோட்டை",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "7,000",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இந்த வருடம்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "யூனியன் பிரதேசங்கள்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "செங்கோட்டை",
            "label": "LOC"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}