{
  "newspaper_id": "daily-mirror-lk",
  "url": "https://www.dailymirror.lk/breaking_news/CA-rejects-British-instagrammers-writ-petition-against-deportation/108-243161",
  "time_ut": 1660635477,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "CA rejects British instagrammer’s writ petition against deportation",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "CA rejects British instagrammer’s writ petition against deportation",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "A writ petition filed by British woman instagrammer Kayleigh Fraser challenging the authorities' decision to deport her from Sri Lanka was today dismissed by Court of Appeal.",
        "Kayleigh Fraser who had been documenting the Sri Lanka’s anti-government protests on social media filed this petition seeking an order to quash the decision of Department of Immigration and Emigration to deport her in an arbitrary manner. (Lakmal Sooriyagoda)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "British",
          "label": "NORP"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "British",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kayleigh Fraser",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Court",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Kayleigh Fraser",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Sri Lanka’s",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "Department of Immigration and Emigration",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Lakmal Sooriyagoda",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "පිටුවහල් කිරීමට එරෙහිව බ්‍රිතාන්‍ය instagrammer ගේ රිට් පෙත්සම CA ප්‍රතික්ෂේප කරයි",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "තමන්ව ශ්‍රී ලංකාවෙන් පිටුවහල් කිරීමට බලධාරීන් ගත් තීරණය අභියෝගයට ලක් කරමින් බ්‍රිතාන්‍ය කාන්තා ඉන්ස්ටග්‍රෑම් ගායිකා කේලී ෆ්‍රේසර් ගොනු කළ රිට් පෙත්සමක් අභියාචනාධිකරණය විසින් අද නිෂ්ප්‍රභ කළේය.",
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ රාජ්‍ය විරෝධී විරෝධතා සමාජ මාධ්‍ය ඔස්සේ ලේඛනගත කරමින් සිටි කේලී ෆ්‍රේසර් මෙම පෙත්සම ගොනු කළේ තමන් අත්තනෝමතික ලෙස පිටුවහල් කිරීමට ආගමන හා විගමන දෙපාර්තමේන්තුව ගත් තීරණය අවලංගු කරන ලෙසට නියෝගයක් නිකුත් කරන ලෙසයි. (ලක්මාල් සූරියගොඩ)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "බ්රිතාන්ය",
          "label": "NORP"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "බ්රිතාන්ය",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kayleigh Fraser",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "අධිකරණය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Kayleigh Fraser",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "ආගමන විගමන දෙපාර්තමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ලක්මාල් සූරියගොඩ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "நாடுகடத்தலுக்கு எதிரான பிரிட்டிஷ் இன்ஸ்டாகிராமரின் ரிட் மனுவை CA நிராகரித்தது",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "பிரித்தானிய பெண் இன்ஸ்டாகிராமர் கெய்லி பிரேசர், தன்னை இலங்கையில் இருந்து நாடு கடத்தும் அதிகாரிகளின் முடிவை எதிர்த்து தாக்கல் செய்த ரிட் மனு இன்று மேன்முறையீட்டு நீதிமன்றத்தால் தள்ளுபடி செய்யப்பட்டது.",
        "இலங்கையின் அரசாங்கத்திற்கு எதிரான போராட்டங்களை சமூக ஊடகங்களில் பதிவு செய்து வந்த கெய்லி பிரேசர், குடிவரவு மற்றும் குடியகல்வு திணைக்களத்தின் தன்னிச்சையான முறையில் நாடு கடத்தும் முடிவை ரத்து செய்யுமாறு கோரி இந்த மனுவை தாக்கல் செய்துள்ளார். (லக்மால் சூரியகொட)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "பிரிட்டிஷ்",
          "label": "NORP"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "பிரிட்டிஷ்",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "கெய்லீ ஃப்ரேசர்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "நீதிமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "கெய்லீ ஃப்ரேசர்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கையின்",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "குடிவரவு மற்றும் குடியகல்வு திணைக்களம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "லக்மால் சூரியகொட",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}