{
  "newspaper_id": "d-b-s-jeyaraj-com",
  "url": "https://dbsjeyaraj.com/dbsj/archives/79334",
  "time_ut": 1662145020,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Gotabaya Rajapaksa will be given a security detail from the Police and the Army in accordance with the privileges of an Executive President says Public Security Minister Tiran Alles",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Gotabaya Rajapaksa will be given a security detail from the Police and the Army in accordance with the privileges of an Executive President says Public Security Minister Tiran Alles",
      "author": "Administrator",
      "body_lines": [
        "Former President Gotabaya Rajapaksa (GR) will be given a security detail in accordance with the Constitution following a threat assessment, Minister of Public Security Tiran Alles said yesterday (3).",
        "“He will be offered a security detail from the Police and the Army in accordance with the privileges of an Executive President. Sri Lanka has done so with several former presidents and their families,” Minister Alles told The Sunday Morning.",
        "He pointed out that former First Lady Hema Premadasa and former Presidents Chandrika Bandaranaike Kumaratunga and Mahinda Rajapaksa remained under the protection of the State in accordance with the Constitution.",
        "According to Alles, a protection group for the seventh Executive President will be formed, similar to the units formed for the previous presidents. This will be made up of Police and Army personnel, depending on the threat assessment that will be carried out.",
        "When contacted, the Sri Lanka Army and the Ministry of Defence did not comment on the security arrangements except to say that a security detail would be provided following a threat assessment.",
        "However, a senior defence official told The Sunday Morning that former President Rajapaksa was likely to be guarded by a team of Army Commandos, along with personnel from the President’s Security Division (PSD) and the Special Task Force (STF).",
        "The ousted President, the first elected president to resign from his post, returned to Sri Lanka on Friday (2) night from Thailand and was escorted in a motorcade to a State residence in Colombo 7."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Gotabaya Rajapaksa",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "Army",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "Executive",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "Tiran Alles",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Gotabaya Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Constitution",
            "label": "LAW"
          },
          {
            "text": "Tiran Alles",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "yesterday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "3",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Army",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Executive",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Alles",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "The Sunday Morning",
            "label": "WORK_OF_ART"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "First",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Chandrika Bandaranaike",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kumaratunga",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Mahinda Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "State",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Constitution",
            "label": "LAW"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Alles",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "seventh",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Army",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the Sri Lanka Army",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Ministry of Defence",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "The Sunday Morning",
            "label": "WORK_OF_ART"
          },
          {
            "text": "Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Army Commandos",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Security Division",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "PSD",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Special Task Force",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "first",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Friday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Thailand",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "State",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "විධායක ජනාධිපතිවරයෙකුගේ වරප්‍රසාද අනුව ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ මහතාට පොලිසියෙන් සහ යුද හමුදාවෙන් ආරක්ෂාව ලබාදෙන බව මහජන ආරක්ෂක අමාත්‍ය ටිරාන් අලස් මහතා පවසයි.",
      "author": "පරිපාලක",
      "body_lines": [
        "තර්ජන තක්සේරුවකින් පසු ආණ්ඩුක්‍රම ව්‍යවස්ථාවට අනුව හිටපු ජනාධිපති ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ මහතාට (GR) ආරක්ෂාව ලබා දෙන බව මහජන ආරක්ෂාව පිළිබඳ අමාත්‍ය ටිරාන් අලස් මහතා ඊයේ (3) පැවසීය.",
        "“විධායක ජනාධිපතිවරයෙකුගේ වරප්‍රසාද අනුව ඔහුට පොලිසියෙන් සහ යුද හමුදාවෙන් ආරක්‍ෂක විස්තරයක් පිරිනමනු ඇත. හිටපු ජනාධිපතිවරුන් කිහිප දෙනෙකු සහ ඔවුන්ගේ පවුල් සමඟ ශ්‍රී ලංකාව එසේ කර ඇත,” අමාත්‍ය අලස් The Sunday Morning වෙත පැවසීය.",
        "හිටපු ජනාධිපති ආර්යා හේමා ප්‍රේමදාස මහත්මිය සහ හිටපු ජනාධිපතිවරුන් වන චන්ද්‍රිකා බණ්ඩාරනායක කුමාරතුංග මහත්මිය සහ මහින්ද රාජපක්ෂ මහතා ආණ්ඩුක්‍රම ව්‍යවස්ථාවට අනුව රාජ්‍ය ආරක්ෂාව යටතේ රැඳී සිටි බව ඔහු පෙන්වා දුන්නේය.",
        "අලස් පවසන පරිදි හත්වැනි විධායක ජනාධිපතිවරයා වෙනුවෙන්ද ආරක්‍ෂක කණ්ඩායමක් පිහිටුවනු ලබන්නේ මීට පෙර සිටි ජනාධිපතිවරුන් වෙනුවෙන් පිහිටුවා තිබූ ඒකකවලට සමානවය. සිදු කෙරෙන තර්ජන තක්සේරුව අනුව මෙය පොලිස් සහ යුද හමුදා නිලධාරීන්ගෙන් සමන්විත වේ.",
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකා යුධ හමුදාව සහ ආරක්ෂක අමාත්‍යාංශය සම්බන්ධ කර ගත් විට, තර්ජන තක්සේරුවකින් පසු ආරක්ෂක විස්තරයක් ලබා දෙන බව කීවා හැර ආරක්ෂක විධිවිධාන පිළිබඳව අදහස් පළ කළේ නැත.",
        "කෙසේ වෙතත්, ජ්‍යෙෂ්ඨ ආරක්ෂක නිලධාරියෙකු ඉරිදා උදෑසනට පැවසුවේ, හිටපු ජනාධිපති රාජපක්ෂට ජනාධිපති ආරක්ෂක අංශයේ (PSD) සහ විශේෂ කාර්ය බලකායේ (STF) නිලධාරීන් සමඟ හමුදා කමාන්ඩෝ කණ්ඩායමක් විසින් ආරක්ෂාව ලබා දීමට ඉඩ ඇති බවයි.",
        "සිය ධූරයෙන් ඉල්ලා අස්වූ පළමු තේරී පත් වූ ජනාධිපතිවරයා වන නෙරපා හරින ලද ජනාධිපතිවරයා සිකුරාදා (2) රාත්‍රියේ තායිලන්තයේ සිට ශ්‍රී ලංකාවට පැමිණි අතර රථ පෙළපාලියකින් කොළඹ 7 පිහිටි රජයේ නිවසකට කැඳවාගෙන යනු ලැබීය."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "හමුදා",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "විධායක",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "ටිරාන් අලස්",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ව්යවස්ථාව",
            "label": "LAW"
          },
          {
            "text": "ටිරාන් අලස්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඊයේ",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "3",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "හමුදා",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "විධායක",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "අලස්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉරිදා උදෑසන",
            "label": "WORK_OF_ART"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "පළමුවන",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "චන්ද්‍රිකා බණ්ඩාරනායක",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "කුමාරතුංග ය",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "මහින්ද රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "රජයේ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ව්යවස්ථාව",
            "label": "LAW"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "අලස්",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "හත්වන",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "හමුදා",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකා යුද හමුදාව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ආරක්ෂක අමාත්යාංශය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ඉරිදා උදෑසන",
            "label": "WORK_OF_ART"
          },
          {
            "text": "රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "යුධ හමුදා කමාන්ඩෝ භටයින්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ආරක්ෂක අංශය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "PSD",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "විශේෂ කාර්ය බලකාය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "පළමුවන",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "සිකුරාදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "තායිලන්තය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "රජයේ",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "நிறைவேற்று அதிகாரம் கொண்ட ஜனாதிபதியின் சிறப்புரிமைகளுக்கு ஏற்ப கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்சவுக்கு பொலிஸ் மற்றும் இராணுவத்தின் பாதுகாப்பு விவரங்கள் வழங்கப்படும் என பொது பாதுகாப்பு அமைச்சர் திரன் அலஸ் தெரிவித்துள்ளார்.",
      "author": "நிர்வாகி",
      "body_lines": [
        "முன்னாள் ஜனாதிபதி கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ஷவுக்கு (ஜி.ஆர்) அச்சுறுத்தல் ஏற்பட்டதைத் தொடர்ந்து அரசியலமைப்பின் படி அவருக்கு பாதுகாப்பு விவரம் வழங்கப்படும் என பொது பாதுகாப்பு அமைச்சர் திரன் அலஸ் நேற்று (3) தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "“ஒரு நிறைவேற்று ஜனாதிபதியின் சிறப்புரிமைகளுக்கு ஏற்ப அவருக்கு பொலிஸ் மற்றும் இராணுவத்தின் பாதுகாப்பு விவரம் வழங்கப்படும். பல முன்னாள் ஜனாதிபதிகள் மற்றும் அவர்களது குடும்பத்தினருடன் இலங்கை அவ்வாறு செய்துள்ளது” என அமைச்சர் அலஸ் தி சண்டே மோர்னிங்கிற்கு தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "முன்னாள் முதல் பெண்மணி ஹேமா பிரேமதாச மற்றும் முன்னாள் ஜனாதிபதிகளான சந்திரிக்கா பண்டாரநாயக்க குமாரதுங்க மற்றும் மஹிந்த ராஜபக்ஷ ஆகியோர் அரசியலமைப்பின் பிரகாரம் அரசின் பாதுகாப்பில் இருப்பதாக அவர் சுட்டிக்காட்டினார்.",
        "அலஸின் கூற்றுப்படி, ஏழாவது நிறைவேற்று ஜனாதிபதிக்கான பாதுகாப்புக் குழு ஒன்று உருவாக்கப்படும், இது முந்தைய ஜனாதிபதிகளுக்காக உருவாக்கப்பட்ட அலகுகளைப் போன்றது. இது நடத்தப்படும் அச்சுறுத்தல் மதிப்பீட்டைப் பொறுத்து, காவல்துறை மற்றும் ராணுவ வீரர்களால் உருவாக்கப்படும்.",
        "சிறிலங்கா இராணுவமும் பாதுகாப்பு அமைச்சும் தொடர்பு கொண்டபோது, ​​அச்சுறுத்தல் மதிப்பீட்டைத் தொடர்ந்து பாதுகாப்பு விவரம் வழங்கப்படும் என்று கூறியதே தவிர பாதுகாப்பு ஏற்பாடுகள் குறித்து எந்த கருத்தும் தெரிவிக்கவில்லை.",
        "எவ்வாறாயினும், முன்னாள் ஜனாதிபதி ராஜபக்ஷவை இராணுவ கமாண்டோக்கள் குழுவும், ஜனாதிபதியின் பாதுகாப்பு பிரிவு (PSD) மற்றும் சிறப்பு அதிரடிப்படை (STF) ஆகியவற்றின் பணியாளர்களும் பாதுகாப்பார்கள் என்று மூத்த பாதுகாப்பு அதிகாரி ஒருவர் தி சண்டே மார்னிங்கிற்கு தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "பதவியில் இருந்து ராஜினாமா செய்த முதல் தேர்ந்தெடுக்கப்பட்ட ஜனாதிபதியான பதவி நீக்கப்பட்ட ஜனாதிபதி, வெள்ளிக்கிழமை (2) இரவு தாய்லாந்தில் இருந்து இலங்கை திரும்பியதுடன், கொழும்பு 7 இல் உள்ள அரச இல்லத்திற்கு வாகன பேரணியில் அழைத்துச் செல்லப்பட்டார்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ச",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "இராணுவம்",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "நிர்வாகி",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "டிரன் அலஸ்",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "அரசியலமைப்பு",
            "label": "LAW"
          },
          {
            "text": "டிரன் அலஸ்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "நேற்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "3",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இராணுவம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "நிர்வாகி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "அல்லேஸ்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஞாயிறு காலை",
            "label": "WORK_OF_ART"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "முதலில்",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "சந்திரிகா பண்டாரநாயக்கா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "குமாரதுங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "மஹிந்த ராஜபக்ஷ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "நிலை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "அரசியலமைப்பு",
            "label": "LAW"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "அல்லேஸ்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஏழாவது",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "இராணுவம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை இராணுவம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாதுகாப்பு அமைச்சகம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஞாயிறு காலை",
            "label": "WORK_OF_ART"
          },
          {
            "text": "ராஜபக்சே",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இராணுவ கமாண்டோக்கள்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாதுகாப்பு பிரிவு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "PSD",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "சிறப்பு அதிரடிப்படை",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "முதலில்",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "வெள்ளி",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "தாய்லாந்து",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "நிலை",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}