{
  "newspaper_id": "daily-mirror-lk",
  "url": "https://www.dailymirror.lk/breaking_news/Army-responds-to-shooting-at-entrance-of-Presidents-House/108-240770",
  "time_ut": 1657476632,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Army responds to shooting at entrance of President’s House",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Army responds to shooting at entrance of President’s House",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "The Sri Lanka Army said today that Army troops fired a few rounds to the air and the sidewalls of the main gate entrance to the President's House on Saturday preventing the entry of the protesters into the compound, and did not intend on causing deliberate harm to the protesters.",
        "The Army said in a statement that the attention has been drawn to a few video clips going viral claiming that the Army troops opened fire at protesters in order to cause intentional harm to them when they were attempting to forcibly enter the President's House compound in Colombo, Fort on Saturday (9) afternoon.",
        "The Army categorically denies having opened fire towards the protesters, but fired a few rounds to the air and the sidewalls of the main gate entrance to the President's House compound as a deterrent, aimed at preventing the entry of the protesters into the compound, they said.",
        "Firing into the air and sidewalls do not therefore necessarily mean that those Army personnel on duty were intent on causing deliberate harm to the protesters, the Army said.(DSB)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Army",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "House",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "The Sri Lanka Army",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Army",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "House",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Saturday",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Army",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Army",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "House",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Colombo",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Fort",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Saturday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "9) afternoon",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Army",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "House",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Army",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Army",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "ජනාධිපති මන්දිරයට වෙඩි තැබීමට හමුදාවෙන් ප්‍රතිචාර",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "සෙනසුරාදා ජනාධිපති මන්දිරයේ ප්‍රධාන ගේට්ටුවේ ප්‍රධාන ගේට්ටුවේ පාර්ශ්වයට හමුදා භට පිරිස් විසින් ගුවනට සහ පැති බැම්ම දෙසට වෙඩි තබා විරෝධතාකරුවන්ට විරෝධතාකරුවන්ට ඇතුළුවීම වළක්වාලමින් සිතාමතා හානියක් සිදුකිරීමට අදහස් නොකළ බව ශ්‍රී ලංකා යුද හමුදාව පවසයි. විරෝධතාකරුවන්.",
        "විරෝධතාකරුවන් කොළඹ ජනාධිපති මන්දිර පරිශ්‍රයට බලහත්කාරයෙන් ඇතුළු වීමට උත්සාහ කිරීමේදී ඔවුන්ට හිතාමතා හානි කිරීම සඳහා යුද හමුදා භට පිරිස් වෙඩි තැබූ බවට පැතිර යන වීඩියෝ දර්ශන කිහිපයක් සම්බන්ධයෙන් අවධානය යොමුව ඇති බව යුද හමුදාව නිවේදනයක් නිකුත් කරමින් කියා සිටියා. කොටුව සෙනසුරාදා (9) පස්වරුවේ.",
        "විරෝධතාකරුවන් දෙසට වෙඩි තැබීමක් සිදු කිරීම යුද හමුදාව තරයේ ප්‍රතික්ෂේප කරන නමුත් විරෝධතාකරුවන් පරිශ්‍රයට ඇතුළුවීම වැළැක්වීමේ අරමුණින් වළක්වන පියවරක් ලෙස ජනාධිපති මන්දිරයේ ප්‍රධාන ගේට්ටුවේ ප්‍රධාන දොරටුවේ පැති බැම්මට ගුවනට සහ පැති බැමිවලට වෙඩි තැබූ බව ඔවුහු පැවසූහ. .",
        "එබැවින් අහසට වෙඩි තැබීමෙන් සහ පැති බැම්මකට වෙඩි තැබීමෙන් අදහස් වන්නේ රාජකාරියේ යෙදී සිටි එම හමුදා නිලධාරීන් විරෝධතාකරුවන්ට හිතාමතාම හානි කිරීමට අදහස් කළ බව නොවේ. (DSB)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "හමුදා",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "නිවස",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකා යුද හමුදාව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "හමුදා",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "නිවස",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "සෙනසුරාදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "හමුදා",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "හමුදා",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "නිවස",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "කොළඹ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "බලකොටුව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "සෙනසුරාදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "9) දහවල්",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "හමුදා",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "නිවස",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "හමුදා",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "හමුදා",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "ஜனாதிபதி மாளிகை நுழைவாயிலில் துப்பாக்கிச் சூடு நடத்தியதற்கு ராணுவம் பதிலடி கொடுத்துள்ளது",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "சனிக்கிழமையன்று ஜனாதிபதி மாளிகையின் பிரதான வாயில் நுழைவாயிலின் பக்கவாட்டுச் சுவர்களை நோக்கி இராணுவத் துருப்புக்கள் சில ரவுண்டுகள் துப்பாக்கிச் சூடு நடத்தியதாகவும், எதிர்ப்பாளர்கள் வளாகத்திற்குள் நுழைவதைத் தடுத்ததாகவும், வேண்டுமென்றே தீங்கு விளைவிப்பதை நோக்கமாகக் கொண்டிருக்கவில்லை என்றும் இலங்கை இராணுவம் தெரிவித்துள்ளது. எதிர்ப்பாளர்கள்.",
        "ஆர்ப்பாட்டக்காரர்கள் கொழும்பில் உள்ள ஜனாதிபதி மாளிகைக்குள் பலவந்தமாக நுழைய முற்பட்ட போது, ​​அவர்களுக்கு வேண்டுமென்றே தீங்கு விளைவிக்கும் வகையில் இராணுவப் படையினர் துப்பாக்கிச் சூடு நடத்தியதாகக் கூறும் சில காணொளிகள் வைரலாக பரவி வருவது கவனத்தை ஈர்த்துள்ளதாக இராணுவம் அறிக்கையொன்றில் தெரிவித்துள்ளது. சனிக்கிழமை (9) பிற்பகல் கோட்டை.",
        "போராட்டக்காரர்களை நோக்கி துப்பாக்கிச் சூடு நடத்தப்பட்டதை இராணுவம் திட்டவட்டமாக மறுத்துள்ளது, ஆனால் எதிர்ப்பாளர்கள் வளாகத்திற்குள் நுழைவதைத் தடுக்கும் நோக்கில், ஜனாதிபதி மாளிகை வளாகத்தின் பிரதான வாயிலின் நுழைவாயிலின் பக்கவாட்டுச் சுவர்கள் மற்றும் வான் மீது சில ரவுண்டுகள் சுட்டதாக அவர்கள் தெரிவித்தனர். .",
        "வான் மற்றும் பக்கவாட்டுச் சுவர்களில் துப்பாக்கிச் சூடு நடத்துவதால், பணியில் இருந்த ராணுவ வீரர்கள், எதிர்ப்பாளர்களுக்கு வேண்டுமென்றே தீங்கு விளைவிப்பதை நோக்கமாகக் கொண்டிருந்தனர் என்று அர்த்தமில்லை என்று ராணுவம் தெரிவித்துள்ளது.(டிஎஸ்பி)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "இராணுவம்",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "வீடு",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை இராணுவம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இராணுவம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "வீடு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "சனிக்கிழமை",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இராணுவம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இராணுவம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "வீடு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "கொழும்பு",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "கோட்டை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சனிக்கிழமை",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "9) பிற்பகல்",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இராணுவம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "வீடு",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இராணுவம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இராணுவம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}