{
  "newspaper_id": "lankadeepa-lk",
  "url": "https://www.lankadeepa.lk/news/මූල්‍ය-අරමුදලේ--සාකච්ඡා-ගැන-අගමැතිගෙන්-ප්‍රකාශයක්/101-615841",
  "time_ut": 1656918575,
  "original_lang": "si",
  "original_title": "මූල්‍ය අරමුදලේ  සාකච්ඡා ගැන අගමැතිගෙන් ප්‍රකාශයක්",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "A statement from the Prime Minister on the discussions of the financial fund",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "Minister of Mass Media Bandula Gunawardena said in Parliament today (4) that Prime Minister Ranil Wickremesinghe is scheduled to make a statement in Parliament tomorrow (5) regarding the progress of negotiations with the International Monetary Fund.",
        "The Minister said that several rounds of negotiations with the International Monetary Fund have been held so far and the Prime Minister will make a comment in this regard.",
        "Mr. Bandula Gunawardena mentioned this during the questions that require oral answers in the Parliament."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Bandula Gunawardena",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "4",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "tomorrow",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "5",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "the International Monetary Fund",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the International Monetary Fund",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Bandula Gunawardena",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "මූල්‍ය අරමුදලේ  සාකච්ඡා ගැන අගමැතිගෙන් ප්‍රකාශයක්",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "ජාත්‍යන්තර  මූල්‍ය අරමුදල සමඟ කෙරෙන  සාකච්ඡා වල ප්‍රගතිය සම්බන්ධයෙන් අග්‍රාමාත්‍ය රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතා පාර්ලිමේන්තුවේ දී හෙට (5) ප්‍රකාශයක් කිරීමට නියමිත බව ජනමාධ්‍ය අමාත්‍ය බන්දුල ගුණවර්ධන මහතා පාර්ලිමේන්තුවේ දී අද (4) පැවසීය.",
        "ජාත්‍යන්තර මූල්‍ය අරමුදල සමඟ සාකච්ඡා වට ගණනාවක් මෙි වන විට පවත්වා තිබෙන බව කී අමාත්‍යවරයා ඒ සම්බන්ධයෙන් අග්‍රාමාත්‍යවරයා විවරණයක් කරනු ඇති බවද සඳහන් කළේය.",
        "පාර්ලිමේන්තුවේ වාචික  පිළිතුරු අපේක්ෂා කරන ප්‍රශ්න අවස්ථාවේදී බන්දුල ගුණවර්ධන මහතා මේ බව සඳහන් කළේය."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "බන්දුල ගුණවර්ධන",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "4",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "හෙට",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "5",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජාත්‍යන්තර මුල්‍ය අරමුදල",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ජාත්‍යන්තර මුල්‍ය අරමුදල",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "බන්දුල ගුණවර්ධන",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "நிதி நிதி பற்றிய விவாதங்கள் குறித்து பிரதமரின் அறிக்கை",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "சர்வதேச நாணய நிதியத்துடனான பேச்சுவார்த்தையின் முன்னேற்றம் குறித்து பிரதமர் ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க நாளை (5) பாராளுமன்றத்தில் அறிக்கையொன்றை வெளியிட உள்ளதாக வெகுஜன ஊடக அமைச்சர் பந்துல குணவர்தன இன்று (4) பாராளுமன்றத்தில் தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "சர்வதேச நாணய நிதியத்துடன் இதுவரை பல சுற்றுப் பேச்சுவார்த்தைகள் நடத்தப்பட்டுள்ளதாகவும், இது தொடர்பில் பிரதமர் கருத்து வெளியிடுவார் எனவும் அமைச்சர் தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "பாராளுமன்றத்தில் வாய்மூல பதில் தேவைப்படும் கேள்விகளின் போதே பந்துல குணவர்தன இதனைக் குறிப்பிட்டார்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "பந்துல குணவர்தன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "4",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "நாளை",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "5",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "சர்வதேச நாணய நிதியம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "சர்வதேச நாணய நிதியம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பந்துல குணவர்தன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}