{
  "newspaper_id": "economy-next-com",
  "url": "https://economynext.com/sri-lanka-opposition-npp-will-support-short-term-programme-if-govt-doesnt-resign-96960/",
  "time_ut": 1657017300,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Sri Lanka opposition NPP will support short term programme if govt doesn’t resign",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Sri Lanka opposition NPP will support short term programme if govt doesn’t resign",
      "author": "Chanka Jayasinghe",
      "body_lines": [
        "ECONOMYNEXT – Sri Lanka opposition National People’s Power (NPP) MP Anura Kumara Dissanayake said his party will support a short term economic recovery plan by the government before going for an election, if the government refuses to resign and give power to the NPP.",
        "Responding to Prime Minister Ranil Wickremesinghe’s speech in parliament on Tuesday July 05 morning, Dissanayake said the NPP never intended to solve the economic crisis in the country within six months as claimed by Wickremasinghe.",
        "“What I said was, we will provide immediate solutions to the current fuel, gas and medicine issues in the country within the next six months. After that we can go for an election. The reason we should go for an election is, to overcome this issue, it is not only a stable government that we need, but also a stable and trusted government,” said Dissanayake.",
        "“If you won’t let us form our own government, we said, we will support a short term plan within a specific time period.”",
        "Replying to Dissanayaka’s remarks on the speech, Prime Minister Wickremesinghe said the government is ready to take any suggestions from the NPP or any capable parry to overcome what has become Sri Lanka’s worst economic crisis since independence.",
        "Both parties came to an agreement to discuss a short term plan, forming an all party committee as per a proposal made by Minister of Justice Wijedasa Rajapakshe.",
        "“Now with the speeches of the PM, ministers and all other MPs, one thing is clear and that is the need to find an immediate solution ti the current situation,” said Rajapakshe.",
        "“The government has already taken some measures to provide immediate solutions. I would like to propose that, with the government’s steps to achieve this short term and long term goals to provide relief to the public, to form a committee with the representation of all these parties and to discuss the government’s plans with that committee.",
        "“So we can get their ideas to initiate the best solution. We can come to an agreement that within a specific time period we will follow this decision and after that we will go for an election,” he said.",
        "Responding to Rajapakshe’s proposal, the NPP leader said they will support a programme with a specific time period.",
        "“There should be a programme with a specific time period. As I said, it should be either us or you. If you are forming the government, there should be a short term programme with a specific time period. If that is being done, we are ready to respond to that,” he said. (Colombo/Jul05/2022)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Sri Lanka",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "NPP",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "National People’s Power",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Anura Kumara Dissanayake",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "NPP",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Tuesday July 05",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Dissanayake",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "NPP",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "six months",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Wickremasinghe",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the next six months",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Dissanayake",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "Dissanayaka",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "NPP",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka’s",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Wijedasa Rajapakshe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "one",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Rajapakshe",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "Rajapakshe",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "NPP",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Colombo/Jul05/2022",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "රජය ඉල්ලා අස් නොවන්නේ නම් ශ්‍රී ලංකා විපක්ෂයේ එන්පීපී කෙටි කාලීන වැඩසටහනට සහාය වනු ඇත",
      "author": "චංක ජයසිංහ",
      "body_lines": [
        "ආර්ථිකය - ශ්‍රී ලංකා විපක්ෂයේ ජාතික ජන බලවේගයේ (NPP) පාර්ලිමේන්තු මන්ත්‍රී අනුර කුමාර දිසානායක පැවසුවේ, ආණ්ඩුව ඉල්ලා අස්වී NPP වෙත බලය ලබාදීම ප්‍රතික්ෂේප කරන්නේ නම්, මැතිවරණයකට යාමට පෙර ආණ්ඩුවේ කෙටිකාලීන ආර්ථික ප්‍රකෘති සැලැස්මකට තම පක්ෂය සහාය දෙන බව ය.",
        "ජුලි 05 අඟහරුවාදා උදෑසන අගමැති රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතා පාර්ලිමේන්තුවේදී කළ කතාවට ප්‍රතිචාර දක්වමින් දිසානායක කියා සිටියේ වික්‍රමසිංහ ප්‍රකාශ කළ පරිදි මාස හයක් ඇතුළත රටේ ආර්ථික අර්බුදය විසඳීමට NPP කිසිවිටෙකත් අදහස් නොකළ බවයි.",
        "“මම කිව්වේ රටේ දැනට පවතින ඉන්ධන, ගෑස් සහ ඖෂධ ප්‍රශ්නවලට ඉදිරි මාස හය ඇතුළත අපි කඩිනම් විසඳුම් ලබා දෙනවා. ඊට පස්සේ මැතිවරණයකට යන්න පුළුවන්. අපි මැතිවරණයකට යා යුතු හේතුව තමයි මේ ප්‍රශ්නයෙන් ගොඩ එන්න නම් අපට අවශ්‍ය ස්ථාවර ආණ්ඩුවක් පමණක් නොවෙයි, ස්ථාවර විශ්වාසවන්ත ආණ්ඩුවක් අවශ්‍යයි.” දිසානායක පැවසීය.",
        "\"ඔබ අපට අපේම රජයක් පිහිටුවීමට ඉඩ නොදෙන්නේ නම්, අපි නිශ්චිත කාල සීමාවක් තුළ කෙටි කාලීන සැලැස්මකට සහාය දෙන බව අපි කීවෙමු.\"",
        "දිසානායකගේ කතාවට පිළිතුරු දෙමින් අග්‍රාමාත්‍ය වික්‍රමසිංහ පැවසුවේ නිදහසින් පසු ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ දරුණුතම ආර්ථික අර්බුදය බවට පත්ව ඇති දෙය ජය ගැනීම සඳහා NPP හෝ ඕනෑම දක්ෂ පාර්ශ්වයකින් ඕනෑම යෝජනාවක් ගැනීමට රජය සූදානම් බවයි.",
        "අධිකරණ අමාත්‍ය විජේදාස රාජපක්ෂ මහතා විසින් කරන ලද යෝජනාවකට අනුව සර්ව පාක්ෂික කමිටුවක් පිහිටුවා කෙටි කාලීන සැලැස්මක් සාකච්ඡා කිරීමට දෙපාර්ශවය එකඟතාවයකට පැමිණියා.",
        "“දැන් අගමැතිතුමා, මැති ඇමතිවරු සහ අනෙකුත් සියලුම මන්ත්‍රීවරුන්ගේ කතාවලින් එක දෙයක් පැහැදිලියි, වත්මන් තත්ත්වයට කඩිනම් විසඳුමක් සෙවීමේ අවශ්‍යතාව එයයි,” රාජපක්ෂ පැවසීය.",
        "“කඩිනම් විසඳුම් ලබාදීමට රජය දැනටමත් යම් යම් ක්‍රියාමාර්ග ගෙන තිබෙනවා. මහජනතාවට සහන සැලසීමේ කෙටි කාලීන සහ දිගු කාලීන අරමුණු ඉටුකර ගැනීමට රජය ගන්නා පියවරත් සමඟම මේ සියලු පාර්ශ්ව නියෝජනය කරමින් කමිටුවක් පිහිටුවා එම කමිටුව සමඟ රජයේ සැලසුම් සාකච්ඡා කරන ලෙස මම යෝජනා කිරීමට කැමැත්තෙමි.",
        "“එබැවින් හොඳම විසඳුම ආරම්භ කිරීම සඳහා අපට ඔවුන්ගේ අදහස් ලබා ගත හැකිය. නිශ්චිත කාලසීමාවක් ඇතුළත අපි මේ තීන්දුව අනුව කටයුතු කරන බවටත් ඉන් පසුව මැතිවරණයකට යන බවටත් අපට එකඟතාවකට පැමිණිය හැකියි.",
        "රාජපක්ෂගේ යෝජනාවට ප්‍රතිචාර දක්වමින් NPP නායකයා කියා සිටියේ නිශ්චිත කාල සීමාවක් සහිත වැඩපිළිවෙලකට සහය දෙන බවයි.",
        "“නිශ්චිත කාල සීමාවක් සහිත වැඩපිළිවෙළක් තිබිය යුතුයි. මම කී පරිදි, එය අප හෝ ඔබ විය යුතුය. ඔබ ආණ්ඩුව පිහිටුවන්නේ නම් නිශ්චිත කාල සීමාවක් සහිත කෙටි කාලීන වැඩපිළිවෙළක් තිබිය යුතුයි. එහෙම කරනවා නම් අපි ඒකට උත්තර දෙන්න ලෑස්තියි.” (කොළඹ/ජූලි 05/2022)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "එන්පීපී",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ජාතික ජනතා බලය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "අනුර කුමාර දිසානායක",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "එන්පීපී",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජූලි 05 අඟහරුවාදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "දිසානායක",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "එන්පීපී",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "මාස හයක්",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ඉදිරි මාස හය",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "දිසානායක",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "දිසානායක",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "එන්පීපී",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "විජේදාස රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "එක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "එන්පීපී",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "කොළඹ/ජූලි 05/2022",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "அரசாங்கம் ராஜினாமா செய்யாவிட்டால், இலங்கை எதிர்க்கட்சியான NPP குறுகிய கால வேலைத்திட்டத்தை ஆதரிக்கும்",
      "author": "சங்க ஜெயசிங்க",
      "body_lines": [
        "அரசாங்கம் ராஜினாமா செய்து NPPக்கு அதிகாரத்தை வழங்க மறுத்தால், தேர்தலுக்குச் செல்வதற்கு முன்னர் அரசாங்கத்தின் குறுகிய கால பொருளாதார மீட்சித் திட்டத்திற்கு தமது கட்சி ஆதரவளிக்கும் என இலங்கை எதிர்க்கட்சியான தேசிய மக்கள் சக்தி (NPP) பாராளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர் அனுரகுமார திஸாநாயக்க தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "ஜூலை 05 செவ்வாய்கிழமை காலை பாராளுமன்றத்தில் பிரதமர் ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்கவின் உரைக்கு பதிலளித்த திஸாநாயக்க, விக்கிரமசிங்க கூறியது போல் நாட்டில் ஏற்பட்டுள்ள பொருளாதார நெருக்கடியை ஆறு மாதங்களுக்குள் தீர்க்கும் நோக்கத்தை NPP ஒருபோதும் கொண்டிருக்கவில்லை என்றார்.",
        "“நான் சொன்னது என்னவென்றால், நாட்டில் தற்போது நிலவும் எரிபொருள், எரிவாயு மற்றும் மருந்துப் பிரச்சினைகளுக்கு அடுத்த ஆறு மாதங்களுக்குள் உடனடித் தீர்வுகளை வழங்குவோம். அதன் பிறகு தேர்தலுக்கு செல்லலாம். நாம் தேர்தலுக்குச் செல்ல வேண்டியதன் காரணம், இந்தப் பிரச்சினையை முறியடிக்க, எங்களுக்கு நிலையான அரசாங்கம் மட்டுமல்ல, நிலையான மற்றும் நம்பகமான அரசாங்கமும் தேவை” என்று திஸாநாயக்க கூறினார்.",
        "\"எங்கள் சொந்த அரசாங்கத்தை அமைக்க நீங்கள் எங்களை அனுமதிக்கவில்லை என்றால், நாங்கள் குறிப்பிட்ட காலத்திற்குள் ஒரு குறுகிய கால திட்டத்தை ஆதரிப்போம்.\"",
        "திசாநாயக்கவின் உரைக்கு பதிலளித்த பிரதமர் விக்கிரமசிங்க, சுதந்திரத்திற்குப் பின்னர் இலங்கையின் மிக மோசமான பொருளாதார நெருக்கடியை சமாளிக்க NPP அல்லது திறமையான எந்தவொரு பாரியிடமிருந்தும் எந்தவொரு ஆலோசனையையும் பெற அரசாங்கம் தயாராக உள்ளது என்றார்.",
        "நீதியமைச்சர் விஜேதாச ராஜபக்ஷவினால் முன்வைக்கப்பட்ட பிரேரணையின் பிரகாரம் அனைத்துக் கட்சிக் குழுவொன்றை உருவாக்கி குறுகிய காலத் திட்டம் குறித்து கலந்துரையாடுவதற்கு இரு தரப்பினரும் இணக்கப்பாட்டுக்கு வந்தனர்.",
        "\"இப்போது பிரதமர், அமைச்சர்கள் மற்றும் ஏனைய அனைத்து பாராளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர்களின் உரைகளின் மூலம், ஒன்று தெளிவாக உள்ளது, தற்போதைய சூழ்நிலைக்கு உடனடித் தீர்வைக் காண வேண்டியது அவசியமாகும்\" என்று ராஜபக்ஷ கூறினார்.",
        "“உடனடி தீர்வுகளை வழங்க அரசாங்கம் ஏற்கனவே சில நடவடிக்கைகளை எடுத்துள்ளது. பொதுமக்களுக்கு நிவாரணம் வழங்குவதற்கான குறுகிய கால மற்றும் நீண்ட கால இலக்குகளை அடைவதற்கான அரசாங்கத்தின் நடவடிக்கைகளுடன், இந்த அனைத்து தரப்பினரின் பிரதிநிதிகளையும் கொண்ட ஒரு குழுவை உருவாக்கி, அந்த குழுவுடன் அரசாங்கத்தின் திட்டங்களை விவாதிக்க வேண்டும் என்று நான் முன்மொழிய விரும்புகிறேன்.",
        "\"எனவே சிறந்த தீர்வைத் தொடங்க அவர்களின் யோசனைகளைப் பெறலாம். குறிப்பிட்ட காலக்கெடுவுக்குள் இந்த முடிவைப் பின்பற்றி தேர்தலுக்குச் செல்வது என்று ஒரு உடன்பாட்டுக்கு வரலாம்,'' என்றார்.",
        "இராஜபக்ஷவின் பிரேரணைக்கு பதிலளித்த NPP தலைவர் குறிப்பிட்ட காலப்பகுதியுடன் கூடிய வேலைத்திட்டத்திற்கு ஆதரவளிப்பதாக தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "“ஒரு குறிப்பிட்ட காலக்கெடுவுடன் ஒரு திட்டம் இருக்க வேண்டும். நான் சொன்னது போல், அது நாமாகவோ அல்லது நீங்களாகவோ இருக்க வேண்டும். நீங்கள் அரசாங்கத்தை அமைப்பதாக இருந்தால், குறிப்பிட்ட காலக்கெடுவுடன் கூடிய குறுகிய கால வேலைத்திட்டம் இருக்க வேண்டும். அவ்வாறு செய்தால், அதற்கு பதிலளிக்க தயாராக உள்ளோம்,'' என்றார். (கொழும்பு/ஜூலை05/2022)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "இலங்கை",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "NPP",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "தேசிய மக்கள் சக்தி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "அனுரகுமார திஸாநாயக்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "NPP",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜூலை 05 செவ்வாய்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "திசாநாயக்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "NPP",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆறு மாதங்கள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "அடுத்த ஆறு மாதங்கள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "திசாநாயக்க",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "திஸாநாயக்க",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "NPP",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கையின்",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "விஜேதாச ராஜபக்ஷ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஒன்று",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ராஜபக்சே",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "ராஜபக்சே",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "NPP",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "கொழும்பு/ஜூலை05/2022",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}