{
  "newspaper_id": "daily-ft-lk",
  "url": "https://www.ft.lk/news/Right-of-Reply-Qualification-of-MPs/56-738999",
  "time_ut": 1661201880,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Right of Reply: Qualification of MPs",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Right of Reply: Qualification of MPs",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "With reference to the Rohantha Athukorala column published on Friday 19 August 2022 titled “Sri Lanka going the Turkey way?”  https://www.ft.lk/columns/Sri-Lanka-going-the-Turkey-way/4-738867, wherein it was stated “Sri Lanka Parliament has over 80% with only the ordinary level qualification being severely challenged”.",
        "Parliament of Sri Lanka Director Legislative Services/Director Communication (Acting) Janakantha Silva clarified that according to the information provided by the Members of Parliament, the percentage of PhD holders, Degree holders and Diploma and G.C.E. Advance Level qualified members is 87%."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Friday 19 August 2022",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "Turkey",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka Parliament",
            "label": "WORK_OF_ART"
          },
          {
            "text": "over 80%",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Parliament of Sri Lanka",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Legislative Services",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Janakantha Silva",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "PhD",
            "label": "WORK_OF_ART"
          },
          {
            "text": "Degree",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Diploma",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "G.C.E. Advance Level",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "87%",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "පිළිතුරු දීමේ අයිතිය: මන්ත්‍රීවරුන්ගේ සුදුසුකම්",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "2022 අගෝස්තු 19 වැනි සිකුරාදා “ශ්‍රී ලංකාව තුර්කියේ ගමන් කරනවාද?” යන මැයෙන් පළ වූ රොහන්ත අතුකෝරල තීරු ලිපියට අදාළව. https://www.ft.lk/columns/Sri-Lanka-going-the-Turkey-way/4-738867, එහි සඳහන් වූයේ “ශ්‍රී ලංකා පාර්ලිමේන්තුවට 80% ඉක්මවන අතර සාමාන්‍ය පෙළ සුදුසුකම පමණක් දැඩි ලෙස අභියෝගයට ලක්ව ඇත” .",
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකා පාර්ලිමේන්තුවේ අධ්‍යක්ෂ ව්‍යවස්ථාදායක සේවා/අධ්‍යක්ෂ සන්නිවේදන (වැඩබලන) ජනකාන්ත සිල්වා මහතා පැහැදිලි කළේ පාර්ලිමේන්තු මන්ත්‍රීවරුන් විසින් සපයනු ලබන තොරතුරු අනුව ආචාර්ය උපාධිධාරීන්, උපාධිධාරීන් සහ ඩිප්ලෝමාධාරීන්ගේ ප්‍රතිශතය සහ G.C.E. උසස් පෙළ සුදුසුකම් ලත් සාමාජිකයින් 87% කි."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "2022 අගෝස්තු 19 සිකුරාදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "කළුකුමා",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකා පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "WORK_OF_ART"
          },
          {
            "text": "80% ට වැඩි",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකා පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ව්යවස්ථාදායක සේවා",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජනකාන්ත සිල්වා",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ආචාර්ය උපාධිය",
            "label": "WORK_OF_ART"
          },
          {
            "text": "උපාධිය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඩිප්ලෝමාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "G.C.E. උසස් පෙළ",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "87%",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "பதில் உரிமை: எம்.பி.க்களின் தகுதி",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "19 ஆகஸ்ட் 2022 வெள்ளியன்று “துருக்கி வழியில் இலங்கை செல்கிறதா?” என்ற தலைப்பில் வெளியிடப்பட்ட ரோஹந்த அத்துகோரல பத்தியின் குறிப்புடன். https://www.ft.lk/columns/Sri-Lanka-going-the-Turkey-way/4-738867, அதில் \"இலங்கை பாராளுமன்றம் 80% க்கும் அதிகமான சாதாரண தர தகுதிகளை மட்டுமே கடுமையாக சவாலுக்கு உட்படுத்தியுள்ளது\" .",
        "பாராளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர்களால் வழங்கப்பட்ட தகவல்களின்படி, PhD பெற்றவர்கள், பட்டதாரிகள் மற்றும் டிப்ளோமா மற்றும் G.C.E சதவிகிதம் என இலங்கை பாராளுமன்றத்தின் பணிப்பாளர் சட்டவாக்க சேவைகள்/பணியாளர் தொடர்பாடல் (செயல்திறன்) ஜனகாந்த சில்வா தெளிவுபடுத்தினார். அட்வான்ஸ் லெவல் தகுதியான உறுப்பினர்கள் 87%."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "19 ஆகஸ்ட் 2022 வெள்ளிக்கிழமை",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "துருக்கி",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "WORK_OF_ART"
          },
          {
            "text": "80%க்கு மேல்",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "சட்டமன்ற சேவைகள்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜனகாந்த சில்வா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "முனைவர் பட்டம்",
            "label": "WORK_OF_ART"
          },
          {
            "text": "பட்டம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "டிப்ளமோ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜி.சி.இ. அட்வான்ஸ் லெவல்",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "87%",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}