{
  "newspaper_id": "d-b-s-jeyaraj-com",
  "url": "https://dbsjeyaraj.com/dbsj/archives/78937",
  "time_ut": 1660071960,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Ranil Wickremesinghe Makes First Official Visit as Elected President to Army Headquarters and thanks Military for Protecting Parliament and Preventing its seizure by a group without Opening Fire on People",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Ranil Wickremesinghe Makes First Official Visit as Elected President to Army Headquarters and thanks Military for Protecting Parliament and Preventing its seizure by a group without Opening Fire on People",
      "author": "Administrator",
      "body_lines": [
        "On Tuesday August 9,  Sri Lankan President Ranil Wickremesinghe paid his first official visit to the Army HQ in the outskirts of Colombo and addressed the troops even as protesters were planning to renew the agitation to oust him from the Presidency.",
        "As it turned out, the function at the Army HQ went off without a hitch and calm prevailed in the island with no sign of the planned stir.",
        "But it did appear as if Wickremesinghe had deliberately chosen August 9 to make a ceremonial first visit to the Army HQ. It symbolically challenged the protestors’ bid to launch another wave of their agitation to bring down his government and force fresh elections.",
        "In his address at the Army HQ, the President praised the troops for the sagacious way in which they protected parliament from a group determined to storm and seize it. By preventing the seizure, the troops had saved the constitution of Sri Lanka, he said. If the violent crowd had barged into parliament, government would have fallen and the course of Sri Lanka’s history would have been different, he noted. But the troops on duty managed to prevent the catastrophe, and he was grateful to them for that.",
        "“Many people do not know the significance of this. Therefore, I wish to dwell in it. There are three pillars on which the constitution of the country rests – the Executive, the Judiciary and Parliament. If these are disabled, the country will go out of control, the constitution will be in tatters and democracy will be destroyed,” Wickremesinghe said.",
        "He recalled that on July 9, the President’s’ official residence and the Presidential Secretariat were occupied. Therefore, the Executive could not function. In the evening, the Prime Minister’s office was occupied. “Then, fearing that I could take over the Presidency, violent elements set fire to my residence. Only the Prime Minister’s office at Earnest de Silva Mawatha was left. But on July 13 that too was stormed and taken over. There was no place for me to function from. In the evening, they tried to surround parliament. If parliament had been disabled, there could be no government.”",
        "“A party leaders’ meeting was on in parliament at the time. Sensing the gravity of the situation, the Speaker suspended the meeting and there was a realization that if parliament was disabled, the constitution too would go. I called a meeting of the Security Council and spoke to Gen. Shavendra Silva and Army Commander Lt. Gen.Liyanage. Aware of the consequences of a disabled parliament, they acted. Without opening fire, the troops quelled those who were attempting to seize parliament. For that I express my gratitude. Just as you saved the country from terrorism, you saved the constitution of the country,” Wickremesinghe told the men.",
        "“It is now up to the 225 members of parliament to unite and find solutions to the problems facing the country,” the President added."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Ranil Wickremesinghe",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "Army Headquarters",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "Protecting Parliament and Preventing",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "Opening Fire",
          "label": "WORK_OF_ART"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Tuesday August 9",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lankan",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "first",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Army",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Colombo",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Army",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "August 9",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "first",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Army",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Army",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka’s",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "three",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Executive",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "July 9",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Executive",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the evening",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "Earnest de Silva Mawatha",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "July 13",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the evening",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the Security Council",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Shavendra Silva",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Army",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Liyanage",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "225",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "ජනාධිපති ලෙස තේරී පත් වූ රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතා ප්‍රථම වරට යුද හමුදා මූලස්ථානයට නිල සංචාරයක නිරත වන අතර ජනතාවට වෙඩි තැබීමකින් තොරව පාර්ලිමේන්තුව ආරක්ෂා කිරීම සහ කණ්ඩායමක් විසින් අල්ලා ගැනීම වැලැක්වීම පිළිබඳව හමුදාවට ස්තුතිය",
      "author": "පරිපාලක",
      "body_lines": [
        "අගෝස්තු 9 වෙනි අඟහරුවාදා, ශ්‍රී ලංකා ජනාධිපති රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතා සිය ප්‍රථම නිල සංචාරය කොළඹින් පිටත පිහිටි යුධ හමුදා මූලස්ථානයට පැමිණ, ඔහුව ජනාධිපති ධුරයෙන් නෙරපා හැරීමේ උද්ඝෝෂණ නැවත ආරම්භ කිරීමට විරෝධතාකරුවන් සැලසුම් කර තිබියදීත්, හමුදා අමතමින්.",
        "එයින් පෙනී ගිය පරිදි, යුධ හමුදා මූලස්ථානයේ උත්සවය කිසිදු බාධාවකින් තොරව අවසන් වූ අතර, සැලසුම් කළ කලබලයක සලකුණක් නොමැතිව දිවයින පුරා සන්සුන් විය.",
        "එහෙත් එය පෙනෙන්නට තිබුණේ වික්‍රමසිංහ හමුදා මූලස්ථානයට චාරිත්‍රානුකූල පළමු සංචාරයක් සඳහා හිතාමතාම අගෝස්තු 9 වැනිදා තෝරාගෙන ඇති බවයි. එය සංකේතාත්මකව ඔහුගේ ආන්ඩුව බලයෙන් පහ කිරීමට සහ නව මැතිවරනයකට බලකිරීම සඳහා තවත් උද්ඝෝෂණ රැල්ලක් දියත් කිරීමට විරෝධතාකරුවන්ගේ උත්සාහයට අභියෝග කළේය.",
        "යුධ හමුදා මූලස්ථානයේ පැවති දේශනයේදී ජනාධිපතිවරයා විසින් පාර්ලිමේන්තුව කඩාකප්පල් කර එය අත්පත් කර ගැනීමට අධිෂ්ඨාන කර ගත් කණ්ඩායමකින් හමුදාව ආරක්ෂා කළ විචක්ෂණ ආකාරය පිළිබඳව ප්‍රශංසා කළේය. අල්ලා ගැනීම වැලැක්වීමෙන් හමුදාව ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ ආණ්ඩුක්‍රම ව්‍යවස්ථාව බේරා ගත් බව ඔහු පැවසීය. ප්‍රචණ්ඩකාරී ජනකාය පාර්ලිමේන්තුවට කඩා වැදුනේ නම්, රජය වැටීමට ඉඩ තිබූ අතර, ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ ඉතිහාසය මීට වඩා වෙනස් වනු ඇති බව ඔහු සඳහන් කළේය. එහෙත් එම ව්‍යසනය වළක්වා ගැනීමට රාජකාරියේ යෙදී සිටි භට පිරිස් සමත් වූ අතර, ඒ පිළිබඳව ඔහු ඔවුන්ට කෘතඥ විය.",
        "“බොහෝ අය මේකේ වැදගත්කම දන්නේ නැහැ. එබැවින් මම එහි වාසය කිරීමට කැමැත්තෙමි. රටේ ආණ්ඩුක්‍රම ව්‍යවස්ථාව රදා පවතින කුළුණු තුනකි - විධායකය, අධිකරණය සහ පාර්ලිමේන්තුව. මේවා ආබාධිත වුණොත් රට පාලනයෙන් මිදී, ව්‍යවස්ථාව කුඩු පට්ටම් වෙලා, ප්‍රජාතන්ත්‍රවාදය විනාශ වෙනවා,” වික්‍රමසිංහ පැවසීය.",
        "ජූලි 9 වැනිදා ජනාධිපතිවරයාගේ නිල නිවස සහ ජනාධිපති ලේකම් කාර්යාලය අල්ලාගෙන සිටි බව ඔහු සිහිපත් කළේය. ඒ නිසා විධායකයට වැඩ කරන්න බැරි වුණා. සවස් වන විට අගමැති කාර්යාලය වාඩිලාගෙන සිටියේය. “ඉන්පසු, මම ජනාධිපතිකම භාරගත හැකි යැයි බියෙන්, ප්‍රචණ්ඩකාරී පිරිස් මගේ නිවසට ගිනි තැබුවා. ඉතිරිව තිබුණේ අර්නස්ට් ද සිල්වා මාවතේ පිහිටි අගමැති කාර්යාලය පමණි. නමුත් ජුලි 13 වැනිදා ඒකත් කඩා වැදී පවරා ගත්තා. මට වැඩ කරන්න තැනක් තිබුණේ නැහැ. හවස පාර්ලිමේන්තුව වට කරන්න හැදුවා. පාර්ලිමේන්තුව අබල කළා නම් ආණ්ඩුවක් තියෙන්න බැහැ.”",
        "“ඒ වෙලාවේ පාර්ලිමේන්තුවේ පක්ෂ නායක රැස්වීමක් තිබුණා. තත්ත්වය බරපතළ බව දැනගත් කථානායකවරයා රැස්වීම අත්හිටුවා පාර්ලිමේන්තුව අක්‍රිය කළහොත් ව්‍යවස්ථාව ද යන බව අවබෝධ විය. මම ආරක්ෂක කවුන්සිලයේ රැස්වීමක් කැඳවා ජෙනරාල් ශවේන්ද්‍ර සිල්වා සහ යුද හමුදාපති ලුතිනන් ජෙනරාල් ලියනගේ සමඟ කතා කළා. ආබාධිත පාර්ලිමේන්තුවක ප්‍රතිවිපාක දැනගෙන ඔවුන් ක්‍රියා කළා. වෙඩි තැබීමකින් තොරව, හමුදාව විසින් පාර්ලිමේන්තුව අල්ලා ගැනීමට උත්සාහ කළ පිරිස් මැඩපැවැත්වීය. ඒ සඳහා මම මගේ කෘතඥතාව පළ කරනවා. ඔබ ත්‍රස්තවාදයෙන් රට බේරා ගත්තා සේම රටේ ව්‍යවස්ථාව බේරා ගත්තා” යැයි වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතා ජනතාවට කීවේය.",
        "පාර්ලිමේන්තුවේ සිටින මන්ත්‍රීවරුන් 225 දෙනාම එකතු වී රට මුහුණ දී සිටින ප්‍රශ්නවලට විසඳුම් සෙවීම දැන් පැවරී ඇති බව ජනාධිපතිවරයා වැඩිදුරටත් පැවසීය."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "යුධ හමුදා මූලස්ථානය",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව ආරක්ෂා කිරීම සහ වැළැක්වීම",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "විවෘත කිරීමේ ගින්න",
          "label": "WORK_OF_ART"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "අගෝස්තු 9 අඟහරුවාදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලාංකික",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "පළමුවන",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "හමුදා",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "කොළඹ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "හමුදා",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "අගෝස්තු 9",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "පළමුවන",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "හමුදා",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "හමුදා",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "තුන්",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "විධායක",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ජූලි 9",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "විධායක",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "සවස",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "අර්නස්ට් ද සිල්වා මාවත",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජූලි 13",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "සවස",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ආරක්ෂක මණ්ඩලය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශවේන්ද්‍ර සිල්වා",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "හමුදා",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ලියනගේ ය",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "225",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க தெரிவுசெய்யப்பட்ட ஜனாதிபதியாக இராணுவத் தலைமையகத்திற்கு முதலாவது உத்தியோகபூர்வ விஜயத்தை மேற்கொண்டதுடன், மக்கள் மீது துப்பாக்கிச் சூடு நடத்தாமல் ஒரு குழுவினரால் பாராளுமன்றத்தைக் கைப்பற்றியதற்கும் அதனைக் கைப்பற்றியதற்கும் இராணுவத்தினருக்கு நன்றி தெரிவித்தார்.",
      "author": "நிர்வாகி",
      "body_lines": [
        "ஆகஸ்ட் 9 செவ்வாய்க்கிழமை, இலங்கை ஜனாதிபதி ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க தனது முதல் உத்தியோகபூர்வ விஜயத்தை கொழும்பு புறநகரில் உள்ள இராணுவத் தலைமையகத்திற்குச் சென்று ஜனாதிபதி பதவியில் இருந்து அகற்றுவதற்கான போராட்டத்தை எதிர்ப்பாளர்கள் புதுப்பிக்க திட்டமிட்டிருந்தபோதும் துருப்புக்களிடம் உரையாற்றினார்.",
        "இராணுவத் தலைமையகத்தில் நடந்த நிகழ்ச்சி எந்தத் தடையுமின்றி நடந்து முடிந்ததால், திட்டமிட்ட பரபரப்புக்கான எந்த அறிகுறியும் இல்லாமல் தீவில் அமைதி நிலவியது.",
        "ஆனால், இராணுவத் தலைமையகத்திற்கு சம்பிரதாய ரீதியிலான முதல் விஜயத்தை மேற்கொள்வதற்கு விக்கிரமசிங்க வேண்டுமென்றே ஆகஸ்ட் 9 ஆம் திகதியை தெரிவுசெய்தது போல் தோன்றியது. அவரது அரசாங்கத்தை வீழ்த்துவதற்கும் புதிய தேர்தல்களை கட்டாயப்படுத்துவதற்கும் எதிர்ப்பாளர்களின் மற்றொரு போராட்ட அலையைத் தொடங்குவதற்கான முயற்சியை இது அடையாளமாக சவால் செய்தது.",
        "இராணுவத் தலைமையகத்தில் அவர் ஆற்றிய உரையில், ஜனாதிபதி அவர்கள் பாராளுமன்றத்தை புயல்காற்று மற்றும் கைப்பற்றுவதற்கு தீர்மானித்த ஒரு குழுவிலிருந்து துருப்புக்கள் சாதுரியமான முறையில் பாதுகாப்பதற்காக பாராட்டினார். கைப்பற்றுதலை தடுத்ததன் மூலம் இலங்கையின் அரசியலமைப்பை படையினர் காப்பாற்றியுள்ளதாக அவர் குறிப்பிட்டுள்ளார். வன்முறைக் கூட்டம் பாராளுமன்றத்திற்குள் நுழைந்திருந்தால், அரசாங்கம் வீழ்ந்திருக்கும் மற்றும் இலங்கையின் வரலாற்றின் போக்கு வேறுவிதமாக இருந்திருக்கும் என்று அவர் குறிப்பிட்டார். ஆனால் பணியில் இருந்த துருப்புக்கள் பேரழிவைத் தடுக்க முடிந்தது, அதற்காக அவர் அவர்களுக்கு நன்றி தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "“இதன் முக்கியத்துவம் பலருக்குத் தெரியாது. எனவே, நான் அதில் வசிக்க விரும்புகிறேன். நாட்டின் அரசியலமைப்பு மூன்று தூண்களில் உள்ளது - நிறைவேற்று, நீதித்துறை மற்றும் பாராளுமன்றம். இவை முடக்கப்பட்டால், நாடு கட்டுப்பாட்டை மீறும், அரசியலமைப்பு சிதைந்து, ஜனநாயகம் அழிந்துவிடும்” என்று விக்கிரமசிங்க கூறினார்.",
        "ஜூலை 9 ஆம் திகதி ஜனாதிபதியின் உத்தியோகபூர்வ இல்லமும் ஜனாதிபதி செயலகமும் ஆக்கிரமிக்கப்பட்டிருந்ததை அவர் நினைவு கூர்ந்தார். அதனால், நிர்வாகிகள் செயல்பட முடியவில்லை. மாலையில் பிரதமர் அலுவலகம் முற்றுகையிடப்பட்டது. “பின்னர், நான் ஜனாதிபதியாக பதவியேற்கலாம் என்ற அச்சத்தில், வன்முறையாளர்கள் எனது இல்லத்திற்கு தீ வைத்தனர். எர்னஸ்ட் டி சில்வா மாவத்தையில் உள்ள பிரதமர் அலுவலகம் மட்டுமே எஞ்சியிருந்தது. ஆனால் ஜூலை 13-ம் தேதி அதுவும் புயல் அடித்து கையகப்படுத்தப்பட்டது. நான் இருந்து செயல்பட இடமில்லை. மாலையில் நாடாளுமன்றத்தை முற்றுகையிட முயன்றனர். பாராளுமன்றம் முடக்கப்பட்டிருந்தால், அரசாங்கம் இருக்க முடியாது.",
        "“அப்போது நாடாளுமன்றத்தில் கட்சித் தலைவர்கள் கூட்டம் நடந்து கொண்டிருந்தது. நிலைமையின் தீவிரத்தை உணர்ந்த சபாநாயகர் கூட்டத்தை இடைநிறுத்தியதோடு, நாடாளுமன்றம் முடக்கப்பட்டால் அரசியலமைப்புச் சட்டமும் செல்லும் என்பதை உணர்ந்தார். பாதுகாப்புச் சபையின் கூட்டத்தை நான் கூட்டி ஜெனரல் சவேந்திர சில்வா மற்றும் இராணுவத் தளபதி லெப்டினன்ட் ஜெனரல் லியனகே ஆகியோரிடம் பேசினேன். முடக்கப்பட்ட நாடாளுமன்றத்தின் விளைவுகளை உணர்ந்து செயல்பட்டனர். பாராளுமன்றத்தைக் கைப்பற்ற முயன்றவர்களை துப்பாக்கிச் சூடு நடத்தாமல் படையினர் அடக்கினர். அதற்கு என் நன்றியை தெரிவித்துக் கொள்கிறேன். நீங்கள் நாட்டை பயங்கரவாதத்திலிருந்து காப்பாற்றியது போல், நாட்டின் அரசியலமைப்பையும் காப்பாற்றினீர்கள்” என்று விக்கிரமசிங்க அந்த நபர்களிடம் கூறினார்.",
        "\"நாடு எதிர்நோக்கும் பிரச்சினைகளுக்கு 225 நாடாளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர்களும் ஒன்றிணைந்து தீர்வு காண வேண்டியது தற்போது உள்ளது\" என ஜனாதிபதி மேலும் தெரிவித்தார்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "இராணுவ தலைமையகம்",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "பாராளுமன்றத்தைப் பாதுகாத்தல் மற்றும் தடுப்பது",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "திறப்பு நெருப்பு",
          "label": "WORK_OF_ART"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ஆகஸ்ட் 9 செவ்வாய்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "முதலில்",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "இராணுவம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "கொழும்பு",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இராணுவம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆகஸ்ட் 9",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "முதலில்",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "இராணுவம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இராணுவம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கையின்",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "மூன்று",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "நிர்வாகி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஜூலை 9",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "நிர்வாகி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "மாலை",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "எர்னஸ்ட் டி சில்வா மாவத்தை",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜூலை 13",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "மாலை",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பாதுகாப்பு கவுன்சில்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "சவேந்திர சில்வா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இராணுவம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "லியனகே",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "225",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}