{
  "newspaper_id": "ada-derana-lk",
  "url": "http://www.adaderana.lk/news/83859/firearm-reported-missing-during-protest-recovered-from-diyawanna-lake",
  "time_ut": 1658734380,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Firearm reported missing during protest recovered from Diyawanna Lake",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Firearm reported missing during protest recovered from Diyawanna Lake",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "Sri Lanka Police says that a T-56 firearm that was reported missing during the protest near the Polduwa Junction on July 13, has been recovered from under a bridge in the Diyawanna Lake along with an empty magazine.",
        "During the protest held on July 13 near the Parliament entry road at Polduwa Junction, protesters had snatched two T-56 assault rifles with two magazines containing 60 live rounds of ammunition, from two army soldiers on duty.",
        "Police said that one of the two firearms was recovered along with an empty magazine by navy divers in Rajagiriya near the Butterfly Bridge of the Diyawanna Lake under the bridge towards the Parliament.",
        "Sri Lanka Navy has handed over the firearm and empty magazine to Welikada Police who are conducting further investigations."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Firearm",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "Diyawanna",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka Police",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "T-56",
            "label": "PRODUCT"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Polduwa Junction",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "July 13",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Diyawanna Lake",
            "label": "LOC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "July 13",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Polduwa Junction",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "two",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "T-56",
            "label": "PRODUCT"
          },
          {
            "text": "two",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "60",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "two",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "one",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "two",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "navy",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Rajagiriya",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Butterfly Bridge",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka Navy",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Welikada Police",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "විරෝධතාවයක් අතරතුර අතුරුදන් වූ ගිනි අවියක් දියවන්නා වැවෙන් සොයා ගැනේ",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "ජුලි 13 වනදා පොල්දූව හන්දිය අසල පැවති විරෝධතාවයේදී අතුරුදන් වූ බව කියන ටී 56 ගිනි අවියක් දියවන්නා වැවේ පාලමක් යට තිබී හිස් මැගසිනයක් සමඟ සොයා ගත් බව ශ්‍රී ලංකා පොලිසිය පවසයි.",
        "ජුලි 13 වැනිදා පොල්දූව හන්දියේ පාර්ලිමේන්තු පිවිසුම් මාර්ගය අසළ පැවති විරෝධතාවයේදී රාජකාරියේ නියුතු හමුදා සෙබළුන් දෙදෙනෙකුගෙන් සජීවී පතොරම් 60ක් සහිත මැගසින් දෙකක් සහිත ටී 56 ගිනි අවි දෙකක් උදුරා ගෙන තිබේ.",
        "රාජගිරිය ප්‍රදේශයේ දියවන්නා වැවේ සමනල පාලම අසලින් පාර්ලිමේන්තුව දෙසට පාලම අසලදී නාවික හමුදා කිමිදුම්කරුවන් විසින් හිස් මැගසින් එකක් සමඟ ගිනි අවි දෙකෙන් එකක් සොයා ගත් බව පොලිසිය පවසයි.",
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකා නාවික හමුදාව විසින් එම ගිනි අවිය සහ හිස් මැගසිනය වැලිකඩ පොලිසිය වෙත භාරදී ඇති අතර ඔවුන් වැඩිදුර පරීක්ෂණ පවත්වයි."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ගිනි අවිය",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "දියවන්නාවේ",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකා පොලිසිය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ටී-56",
            "label": "PRODUCT"
          },
          {
            "text": "පොල්දූව හන්දිය",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජූලි 13",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "දියවන්නා වැව",
            "label": "LOC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ජූලි 13",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "පොල්දූව හන්දිය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "දෙක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ටී-56",
            "label": "PRODUCT"
          },
          {
            "text": "දෙක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "60",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "දෙක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "එක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "දෙක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "නාවික",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "රාජගිරිය",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "සමනල පාලම",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකා නාවික හමුදාව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "වැලිකඩ පොලිසිය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "தியவன்னா ஏரியில் இருந்து கண்டெடுக்கப்பட்ட போராட்டத்தின் போது காணமல் போன துப்பாக்கி",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "ஜூலை 13ஆம் திகதி பொல்துவ சந்திக்கு அருகில் இடம்பெற்ற ஆர்ப்பாட்டத்தின் போது காணாமல் போனதாக கூறப்படும் T-56 துப்பாக்கி ஒன்று தியவன்னா ஏரியின் பாலத்தின் அடியில் இருந்து வெற்று சஞ்சிகையுடன் மீட்கப்பட்டுள்ளதாக இலங்கை பொலிஸார் தெரிவித்துள்ளனர்.",
        "பொல்துவ சந்தியில் பாராளுமன்ற நுழைவு வீதிக்கு அருகில் ஜூலை 13 அன்று நடைபெற்ற ஆர்ப்பாட்டத்தின் போது, ​​கடமையில் ஈடுபட்டிருந்த இரண்டு இராணுவ சிப்பாய்களிடம் இருந்து 60 ரவைகள் அடங்கிய இரண்டு மகசீன்களுடன் இரண்டு T-56 ரக துப்பாக்கிகளையும் போராட்டக்காரர்கள் பறித்துச் சென்றனர்.",
        "ராஜகிரியவில் தியவன்னா ஏரியின் பட்டாம்பூச்சி பாலத்திற்கு அருகில் பாராளுமன்றம் நோக்கிய பாலத்திற்கு அருகில் இரண்டு துப்பாக்கிகளில் ஒன்று வெற்று பத்திரிகையுடன் கடற்படையினரால் மீட்கப்பட்டுள்ளதாக பொலிஸார் தெரிவித்தனர்.",
        "வெலிக்கடை பொலிஸாரிடம் சிறிலங்கா கடற்படையினர் துப்பாக்கி மற்றும் வெற்றுப் பத்திரிகையை ஒப்படைத்துள்ளனர், அவர்கள் மேலதிக விசாரணைகளை மேற்கொண்டு வருகின்றனர்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "துப்பாக்கி",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "தியவன்னா",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை காவல்துறை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "டி-56",
            "label": "PRODUCT"
          },
          {
            "text": "பொல்துவ சந்தி",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜூலை 13",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "தியவன்னா ஏரி",
            "label": "LOC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஜூலை 13",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "பொல்துவ சந்தி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இரண்டு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "டி-56",
            "label": "PRODUCT"
          },
          {
            "text": "இரண்டு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "60",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "இரண்டு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஒன்று",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "இரண்டு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "கடற்படை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ராஜகிரிய",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "பட்டாம்பூச்சி பாலம்",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை கடற்படை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "வெலிக்கடை பொலிஸ்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}