{
  "newspaper_id": "news-first-lk",
  "url": "https://www.newsfirst.lk/2022/07/10/president-sirisena-writes-10-point-letter-to-build-sri-lanka/",
  "time_ut": 1657435740,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "President & PM have no moral right to remain in power; Sirisena writes 10-point letter to build Sri Lanka",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "President & PM have no moral right to remain in power; Sirisena writes 10-point letter to build Sri Lanka",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); Former Sri Lankan President and Chairman of the Sri Lanka Freedom Party Maithripala Sirisena said that the current president, the prime minister or the government have no political or moral right to remain in power.",
        "“It is clear that a very dangerous situation is likely to arise in the country if they continue to act without understanding the opposition coming from the people.,” the Former President said in a statement.",
        "Therefore, Sri Lanka Freedom Party strongly emphasizes the following proposals to all responsible parties.",
        "1. The President and the Prime Minister must resign immediately.",
        "2. The Speaker shall be appointed Acting President until a President is appointed.",
        "3. In order to install the proposed all-party interim government, a National Executive Council or Leadership Council should be established consisting of the leaders of all the political parties represented in the Parliament.",
        "4. The President and Prime Minister should be appointed with the agreement of the National Executive Council or Leadership Council and civil activists, academics and professionals.",
        "5. A crisis management cabinet should be appointed with a limited number of scopes to achieve essential and targeted objectives to bring the country back to its pre-crisis status.",
        "6. A national advisory council composed of academics, professionals, civil activists and opinion leaders should be established under the respective ministries in the crisis management cabinet.",
        "7. To manage the crisis, an integrated management program aimed at economy, food security, essential services, social welfare and social security program, and socio-political reform/decentralization approaches should be implemented as soon as possible.",
        "8. The 19th Constitutional Amendment should be re-enacted with the necessary optimal amendment without delay.",
        "9. As soon as the country is restored to its pre-crisis status, a parliamentary election should be held and the people should be given the democratic right to appoint a new government.",
        "10. In order to build the Sri Lankan nation, and to build the legal and constitutional base necessary to make Sri Lanka a developed country, to implement socio-political reforms, and to make the necessary structural transformations, the drafting of a new constitution should be the leading task of the new government.",
        "President & PM have no moral right to remain in power; Sirisena writes 10-point letter to build Sri Lanka"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "President & PM",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "Sirisena",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "10",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "Sri Lanka",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lankan",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Sri Lanka Freedom Party",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Maithripala Sirisena",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka Freedom Party",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "1",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "2",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "3",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "National Executive Council",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Leadership Council",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "4",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "the National Executive Council or Leadership Council",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "5",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "6",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "7",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "8",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "19th",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Constitutional Amendment",
            "label": "LAW"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "9",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "10",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lankan",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "President & PM",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sirisena",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "10",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "ජනාධිපතිට සහ අගමැතිට බලයේ සිටීමට සදාචාරාත්මක අයිතියක් නැත; සිරිසේන ලංකාව හදන්න කරුණු 10ක ලිපියක් ලියයි",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); වත්මන් ජනාධිපතිවරයාට, අගමැතිවරයාට හෝ රජයට තවදුරටත් බලයේ සිටීමට දේශපාලන හෝ සදාචාරාත්මක අයිතියක් නොමැති බව ශ්‍රී ලංකා හිටපු ජනාධිපති, ශ්‍රී ලංකා නිදහස් පක්ෂයේ සභාපති මෛත්‍රීපාල සිරිසේන මහතා පැවසීය.",
        "ජනතාවගෙන් එල්ල වන විරෝධය තේරුම් නොගෙන තවදුරටත් කටයුතු කළහොත් රට තුළ ඉතා භයානක තත්ත්වයක් උද්ගත වීමට ඉඩ ඇති බව පැහැදිලියි” හිටපු ජනාධිපතිවරයා නිවේදනයක් නිකුත් කරමින් කියා සිටියේය.",
        "එබැවින් පහත සඳහන් යෝජනා ශ්‍රී ලංකා නිදහස් පක්ෂය සියලු වගකිව යුතු පාර්ශව වෙත දැඩිව අවධාරණය කරයි.",
        "1. ජනාධිපතිවරයා සහ අගමැතිවරයා වහාම ඉල්ලා අස්විය යුතුය.",
        "2. ජනාධිපතිවරයෙකු පත් කරන තුරු කථානායකවරයා වැඩ බලන ජනාධිපති ලෙස පත් කළ යුතුය.",
        "3. යෝජිත සර්ව පාක්ෂික අන්තර්වාර ආණ්ඩුව පිහිටුවීම සඳහා පාර්ලිමේන්තුව නියෝජනය කරන සියලුම දේශපාලන පක්ෂවල නායකයන්ගෙන් සමන්විත ජාතික විධායක සභාවක් හෝ නායකත්ව මණ්ඩලයක් ස්ථාපිත කළ යුතුය.",
        "4. ජාතික විධායක සභාව හෝ නායකත්ව මණ්ඩලය සහ සිවිල් ක්‍රියාකාරීන්, විද්වතුන් සහ වෘත්තිකයන්ගේ එකඟතාවය මත ජනාධිපතිවරයා සහ අගමැතිවරයා පත් කළ යුතුය.",
        "5. රට යළි අර්බුදකාරී තත්ත්වයට ගෙන ඒම සඳහා අත්‍යවශ්‍ය සහ ඉලක්කගත අරමුණු සාක්ෂාත් කර ගැනීම සඳහා සීමිත විෂය පථ සංඛ්‍යාවක් සහිත අර්බුද කළමනාකරණ කැබිනට් මණ්ඩලයක් පත් කළ යුතුය.",
        "6. අර්බුද කළමනාකරණ කැබිනට් මණ්ඩලයේ අදාළ අමාත්‍යාංශ යටතේ විද්වතුන්, වෘත්තිකයන්, සිවිල් ක්‍රියාකාරීන් සහ මතධාරීන්ගෙන් සැදුම්ලත් ජාතික උපදේශක සභාවක් ස්ථාපිත කළ යුතුය.",
        "7. අර්බුදය කළමනාකරණය කිරීම සඳහා, ආර්ථිකය, ආහාර සුරක්ෂිතතාව, අත්‍යවශ්‍ය සේවා, සමාජ සුබසාධන සහ සමාජ ආරක්ෂණ වැඩසටහන ඉලක්ක කරගත් ඒකාබද්ධ කළමනාකරණ වැඩසටහනක් සහ සමාජ-දේශපාලන ප්‍රතිසංස්කරණ/විමධ්‍යගත කිරීමේ ප්‍රවේශයන් හැකි ඉක්මනින් ක්‍රියාත්මක කළ යුතුය.",
        "8. 19 වැනි ආණ්ඩුක්‍රම ව්‍යවස්ථා සංශෝධනය ප්‍රමාදයකින් තොරව අවශ්‍ය ප්‍රශස්ත සංශෝධනයක් සමඟ නැවත බලාත්මක කළ යුතුය.",
        "9. රට පෙර තිබූ අර්බුදකාරී තත්ත්වයට පත් වූ වහාම පාර්ලිමේන්තු මැතිවරණයක් පවත්වා නව රජයක් පත් කර ගැනීමේ ප්‍රජාතන්ත්‍රවාදී අයිතිය ජනතාවට ලබා දිය යුතුය.",
        "10. ශ්‍රී ලාංකේය ජාතිය ගොඩනැගීමටත්, ශ්‍රී ලංකාව සංවර්ධිත රටක් බවට පත් කිරීමට අවශ්‍ය නෛතික හා ව්‍යවස්ථාමය පදනම ගොඩනඟා ගැනීමටත්, සමාජ දේශපාලන ප්‍රතිසංස්කරණ ක්‍රියාත්මක කිරීමටත්, අවශ්‍ය ව්‍යුහාත්මක පරිවර්තනයන් සිදු කිරීමටත්, නව ආණ්ඩුක්‍රම ව්‍යවස්ථාවක් සම්පාදනය කළ යුතුය. නව රජයේ ප්‍රමුඛ කාර්යය විය.",
        "ජනාධිපතිට සහ අගමැතිට බලයේ සිටීමට සදාචාරාත්මක අයිතියක් නැත; සිරිසේන ලංකාව හදන්න කරුණු 10ක ලිපියක් ලියයි"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ජනාධිපති සහ අගමැති",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "සිරිසේන",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "10",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලාංකික",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකා නිදහස් පක්ෂය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "මෛත්‍රීපාල සිරිසේන",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකා නිදහස් පක්ෂය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "1",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "2",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "3",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජාතික විධායක සභාව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "නායකත්ව මණ්ඩලය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "4",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජාතික විධායක සභාව හෝ නායකත්ව මණ්ඩලය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "5",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "6",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "7",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "8",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "19 වැනි",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ව්යවස්ථා සංශෝධනය",
            "label": "LAW"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "9",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "10",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලාංකික",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ජනාධිපති සහ අගමැති",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "සිරිසේන",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "10",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "ஜனாதிபதிக்கும் பிரதமருக்கும் அதிகாரத்தில் இருக்க தார்மீக உரிமை இல்லை; இலங்கையை கட்டியெழுப்ப 10 அம்ச கடிதம் எழுதுகிறார் சிறிசேனா",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); தற்போதைய ஜனாதிபதி, பிரதமருக்கோ அல்லது அரசாங்கத்திற்கோ ஆட்சியில் நீடிப்பதற்கு அரசியல் அல்லது தார்மீக உரிமை கிடையாது என சிறிலங்காவின் முன்னாள் ஜனாதிபதியும் ஸ்ரீலங்கா சுதந்திரக் கட்சியின் தலைவருமான மைத்திரிபால சிறிசேன தெரிவித்துள்ளார்.",
        "மக்களிடம் இருந்து வரும் எதிர்ப்பை புரிந்து கொள்ளாமல் அவர்கள் தொடர்ந்தும் செயற்பட்டால் நாட்டில் மிகவும் ஆபத்தான சூழ்நிலை உருவாகும் என்பது தெளிவாகும் என முன்னாள் ஜனாதிபதி தனது அறிக்கையில் தெரிவித்துள்ளார்.",
        "எனவே, பொறுப்புவாய்ந்த அனைத்து தரப்பினருக்கும் ஸ்ரீலங்கா சுதந்திரக் கட்சி பின்வரும் முன்மொழிவுகளை வலுவாக வலியுறுத்துகிறது.",
        "1. ஜனாதிபதியும் பிரதமரும் உடனடியாக பதவி விலக வேண்டும்.",
        "2. ஜனாதிபதி நியமிக்கப்படும் வரை சபாநாயகர் செயல் தலைவராக நியமிக்கப்படுவார்.",
        "3. உத்தேச அனைத்துக் கட்சி இடைக்கால அரசாங்கத்தை நிறுவுவதற்கு, பாராளுமன்றத்தில் பிரதிநிதித்துவப்படுத்தப்படும் அனைத்து அரசியல் கட்சிகளின் தலைவர்களைக் கொண்ட தேசிய நிறைவேற்று சபை அல்லது தலைமைத்துவ சபை நிறுவப்பட வேண்டும்.",
        "4. தேசிய செயற்குழு அல்லது தலைமைத்துவ கவுன்சில் மற்றும் சிவில் ஆர்வலர்கள், கல்வியாளர்கள் மற்றும் தொழில் வல்லுநர்களின் உடன்படிக்கையுடன் ஜனாதிபதி மற்றும் பிரதமர் நியமிக்கப்பட வேண்டும்.",
        "5. நெருக்கடிக்கு முந்தைய நிலைக்கு நாட்டை மீண்டும் கொண்டு வருவதற்கான அத்தியாவசிய மற்றும் இலக்கு நோக்கங்களை அடைவதற்கு வரையறுக்கப்பட்ட எண்ணிக்கையிலான நோக்கங்களுடன் நெருக்கடி மேலாண்மை அமைச்சரவை நியமிக்கப்பட வேண்டும்.",
        "6. நெருக்கடி மேலாண்மை அமைச்சரவையில் அந்தந்த அமைச்சகங்களின் கீழ் கல்வியாளர்கள், தொழில் வல்லுநர்கள், சிவில் ஆர்வலர்கள் மற்றும் கருத்துத் தலைவர்களைக் கொண்ட தேசிய ஆலோசனைக் குழு நிறுவப்பட வேண்டும்.",
        "7. நெருக்கடியை நிர்வகிப்பதற்கு, பொருளாதாரம், உணவுப் பாதுகாப்பு, அத்தியாவசிய சேவைகள், சமூக நலன் மற்றும் சமூகப் பாதுகாப்புத் திட்டம் மற்றும் சமூக-அரசியல் சீர்திருத்தம்/பகிர்வமயமாக்கல் அணுகுமுறைகளை இலக்காகக் கொண்ட ஒருங்கிணைந்த மேலாண்மைத் திட்டம் விரைவில் செயல்படுத்தப்பட வேண்டும்.",
        "8. 19வது அரசியலமைப்புத் திருத்தம் தாமதமின்றி தேவையான உகந்த திருத்தத்துடன் மீண்டும் அமுல்படுத்தப்பட வேண்டும்.",
        "9. நெருக்கடிக்கு முந்தைய நிலைக்கு நாடு திரும்பியவுடன், நாடாளுமன்றத் தேர்தல் நடத்தி, புதிய அரசாங்கத்தை நியமிக்கும் ஜனநாயக உரிமை மக்களுக்கு வழங்கப்பட வேண்டும்.",
        "10. இலங்கை தேசத்தை கட்டியெழுப்புவதற்கும், இலங்கையை வளர்ந்த நாடாக மாற்றுவதற்கு தேவையான சட்ட மற்றும் அரசியலமைப்பு அடிப்படையை கட்டியெழுப்புவதற்கும், சமூக அரசியல் சீர்திருத்தங்களை நடைமுறைப்படுத்துவதற்கும், தேவையான கட்டமைப்பு மாற்றங்களை செய்வதற்கும், புதிய அரசியலமைப்பை உருவாக்க வேண்டும். புதிய அரசாங்கத்தின் முக்கிய பணியாக இருக்கும்.",
        "ஜனாதிபதிக்கும் பிரதமருக்கும் அதிகாரத்தில் இருக்க தார்மீக உரிமை இல்லை; இலங்கையை கட்டியெழுப்ப 10 அம்ச கடிதம் எழுதுகிறார் சிறிசேனா"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ஜனாதிபதி & பிரதமர்",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "சிறிசேன",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "10",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "இலங்கை",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஸ்ரீலங்கா சுதந்திரக் கட்சி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "மைத்திரிபால சிறிசேன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஸ்ரீலங்கா சுதந்திரக் கட்சி",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "1",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "2",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "3",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "தேசிய நிர்வாக சபை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "தலைமைத்துவ கவுன்சில்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "4",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "தேசிய நிர்வாக சபை அல்லது தலைமைத்துவ கவுன்சில்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "5",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "6",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "7",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "8",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "19வது",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "அரசியலமைப்பு திருத்தம்",
            "label": "LAW"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "9",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "10",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஜனாதிபதி & பிரதமர்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "சிறிசேன",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "10",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}