{
  "newspaper_id": "daily-ft-lk",
  "url": "https://www.ft.lk/business/Hat-trick-for-Kalubowitiyana-Tea-Factory/34-737499",
  "time_ut": 1657816125,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Hat-trick for Kalubowitiyana Tea Factory",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Hat-trick for Kalubowitiyana Tea Factory",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "Kalubowitiyana Tea Factory re-established an all-time record for the third consecutive week, by achieving a price of Rs. 2,950 per kg on a PF1 grade in the CTC Low Grown category, at the tea auction held on 11 July, surpassing their own record price of Rs. 2,750 per kg for the same grade, obtained at last week’s tea auction. This line of tea was purchased by Uniworld Teas Ltd.",
        "Kalubowitiyana Tea Factory is situated in Morawaka and managed by Kalubowitiyana Tea Factory Ltd. The selling broker was John Keells PLC",
        "Uva Highlands Estate located in Bandarawela, achieved an all-time record price at the weekly tea auction held on 11 July by securing a price of Rs. 2,250 per kg on a BOPF.Sp grade in the Uva High Grown elevation category. This invoice of tea was purchased by Heritage Teas Ltd.",
        "Uva Highlands Estate comes under the purview of Malwatte Valley Plantations PLC and John Keells PLC were the brokers associated with the sale of this",
        "Aislaby Estate located in Bandarawela and managed by Malwattte Valley Plantations PLC, established an attractive all-time record price of Rs. 3,500 per kg on a FBOP grade, in the Uva High Category at the weekly tea auction held on 11 July.",
        "This line of tea was purchased by Inter Tea Ltd, and the sale was conducted by tea broker John Keells PLC.",
        "Delta Estate located in Pupuressa, achieved an all-time record price at this week’s tea auction held on 12 July, by securing a price of Rs. 1,000 per kg on a BP1 grade in the CTC Medium Grown Category. This line of tea was purchased by Heritage Teas Ltd.",
        "Delta Estate comes under the purview of Pussellawa Plantations Ltd. and the selling broker was John",
        "Ceciliyan Tea Factory, managed by Ceciliyan Associates Ltd. and situated in Kalawana, Ratnapura, established an all-time record price of Rs. 2,800 per kg on a BOP.Sp grade in the Low Grown Category at this week’s tea auction held on 12 July.",
        "This invoice of tea was purchased by Expoteas Ceylon Ltd., and the sale was conducted by tea broker John",
        "Broadlands Small Holders Tea Factory, situated in Pitawela, Ginigathhena and managed by Tea Smallholder Factories PLC, achieved an all-time record price at the tea auction held on 11 July, by securing an attractive price of Rs. 2,850 per kg on a BOPF.Sp grade in the Low Grown Category.",
        "This invoice of tea was purchased by Mabroc Teas Ltd., and the selling broker was John Keells PLC."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Kalubowitiyana Tea Factory",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Kalubowitiyana Tea Factory",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the third consecutive week",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "2,950 per kg",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "CTC Low Grown",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "11 July",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "2,750 per kg",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "last week’s",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Uniworld Teas Ltd.",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Kalubowitiyana Tea Factory",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Morawaka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kalubowitiyana Tea Factory Ltd.",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "John Keells PLC",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Bandarawela",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "weekly",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "11 July",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "2,250 per kg",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "Uva High Grown",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Heritage Teas Ltd.",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Malwatte Valley Plantations PLC",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "John Keells PLC",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Aislaby Estate",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Bandarawela",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Malwattte Valley Plantations PLC",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "FBOP",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "weekly",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "11 July",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Inter Tea Ltd",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "John Keells PLC",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Delta Estate",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Pupuressa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "week",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "12 July",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "1,000 per kg",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "the CTC Medium Grown Category",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Heritage Teas Ltd.",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Delta Estate",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Pussellawa Plantations Ltd.",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Ceciliyan Tea Factory",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ceciliyan Associates Ltd.",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kalawana",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ratnapura",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "2,800",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Low Grown Category",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "week",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "12 July",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Expoteas Ceylon Ltd.",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Broadlands Small Holders Tea Factory",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Pitawela",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ginigathhena",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Tea Smallholder Factories PLC",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "11 July",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "2,850",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Low Grown Category",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Mabroc Teas Ltd.",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "John Keells PLC",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "කළුබෝවිටියන තේ කර්මාන්ත ශාලාවට හැට්‍රික්",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "කළුබෝවිටියන තේ කර්මාන්ත ශාලාව අඛණ්ඩව තෙවැනි සතියටත් සර්වකාලීන වාර්තාවක් පිහිටුවමින් රු. ජුලි 11 වැනි දින පැවති තේ වෙන්දේසියේදී CTC අඩු වැඩුණු කාණ්ඩයේ PF1 ශ්‍රේණියේ කිලෝග්‍රෑමයකට රු. පසුගිය සතියේ තේ වෙන්දේසියේදී ලබාගත් එම ශ්‍රේණිය සඳහා කිලෝග්‍රෑමයකට රුපියල් 2,750 කි. Uniworld Teas Ltd විසින් මෙම තේ පෙළ මිලදී ගෙන ඇත.",
        "කළුබෝවිටියන තේ කර්මාන්ත ශාලාව මොරවක ප්‍රදේශයේ පිහිටා ඇති අතර එය කළමනාකරණය කරනු ලබන්නේ සීමාසහිත කළුබෝවිටියාන තේ කර්මාන්ත ශාලාව විසිනි. විකුණුම් තැරැව්කරු වූයේ ජෝන් කීල්ස් පීඑල්සී ය.",
        "බණ්ඩාරවෙල පිහිටි ඌව හයිලන්ඩ්ස් වතුයාය ජූලි 11 වැනි දින සතිපතා පැවති තේ වෙන්දේසියේදී රු. Uva High Grown උන්නතාංශ කාණ්ඩයේ BOPF.Sp ශ්‍රේණියේ කිලෝග්‍රෑමයකට රුපියල් 2,250 කි. මෙම තේ ඉන්වොයිසිය Heritage Teas Ltd විසින් මිලදී ගෙන ඇත.",
        "ඌව හයිලන්ඩ්ස් වතුයාය මල්වත්ත වැලි ප්ලාන්ටේෂන් පීඑල්සී යටතට පත්වන අතර ජෝන් කීල්ස් පීඑල්සී මෙය විකිණීමට සම්බන්ධ තැරැව්කරුවන් විය.",
        "මල්වත්ත වැලි ප්ලාන්ටේෂන්ස් පීඑල්සී විසින් කළමනාකරණය කරනු ලබන බණ්ඩාරවෙල පිහිටි අයිස්ලබි වත්ත ආකර්ශනීය සර්වකාලීන වාර්තාගත මිල රු. ජුලි 11 දින පැවති සතිපතා තේ වෙන්දේසියේදී ඌව ඉහළ කාණ්ඩයේ FBOP ශ්‍රේණිය මත කිලෝග්‍රෑමයකට රුපියල් 3,500ක්.",
        "මෙම තේ පෙළ සීමාසහිත Inter Tea සමාගම විසින් මිලදී ගෙන ඇති අතර, අලෙවිය තේ තැරැව්කරු John Keells PLC විසින් සිදු කරන ලදී.",
        "පුපුරැස්ස ප්‍රදේශයේ පිහිටි ඩෙල්ටා වතුයාය ජුලි 12 වැනි දින පැවති මෙම සතියේ තේ වෙන්දේසියේ දී රු. CTC මධ්‍යම වර්ධනය වන කාණ්ඩයේ BP1 ශ්‍රේණියේ කිලෝග්‍රෑමයකට රුපියල් 1,000 කි. මෙම තේ පේළිය හෙරිටේජ් ටීස් ලිමිටඩ් විසින් මිලදී ගෙන ඇත.",
        "ඩෙල්ටා වතුයාය පුස්සැල්ලාව වැවිලි සමාගමට අයත් වන අතර එහි විකුණුම් තැරැව්කරු ජෝන් ය.",
        "සීමාසහිත සිසිලියන් ඇසෝසියේට්ස් විසින් කළමනාකරණය කරනු ලබන රත්නපුර කලවාන ප්‍රදේශයේ පිහිටි සිසිලියන් තේ කම්හල සර්වකාලීන වාර්තාගත මිල රු. ජුලි 12 වන දින පැවති මෙම සතියේ තේ වෙන්දේසියේදී අඩු වර්ධනය වූ කාණ්ඩයේ BOP.Sp ශ්‍රේණියක් මත කිලෝග්‍රෑමයකට රුපියල් 2,800 කි.",
        "මෙම තේ ඉන්වොයිසිය Expoteas Ceylon Ltd විසින් මිලදී ගෙන ඇති අතර, අලෙවිය තේ තැරැව්කරු ජෝන් විසින් සිදු කරන ලදී.",
        "ගිනිගත්හේන පිටවෙල පිහිටි Broadlands Small Tea Factory, Tea Smallholder Factories PLC විසින් කළමනාකරණය කරනු ලබන අතර, ජුලි 11 වන දින පැවති තේ වෙන්දේසියේදී රු. අඩු වර්ධනය වූ කාණ්ඩයේ BOPF.Sp ශ්‍රේණියේ කිලෝග්‍රෑමයකට රුපියල් 2,850.",
        "මෙම තේ ඉන්වොයිසිය මාබ්‍රොක් ටීස් ලිමිටඩ් විසින් මිලදී ගෙන ඇති අතර, අලෙවි තැරැව්කරු වූයේ ජෝන් කීල්ස් පීඑල්සී ය."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "කළුබෝවිටියන තේ කම්හල",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "කළුබෝවිටියන තේ කම්හල",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "අඛණ්ඩව තුන්වන සතිය",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "2,950 කි",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "CTC අඩු වර්ධනය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජූලි 11",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "2,750 කි",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "පසුගිය සතියේ",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Uniworld Teas Ltd.",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "කළුබෝවිටියන තේ කම්හල",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Morawaka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "සීමාසහිත කළුබෝවිටියාන තේ කර්මාන්ත ශාලාව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජෝන් කීල්ස් පීඑල්සී",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "බණ්ඩාරවෙල",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "සතිපතා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජූලි 11",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "2,250 කි",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඌව හයි වර්‍ඩ්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "හෙරිටේජ් ටීස් ලිමිටඩ්.",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "මල්වත්ත වැලි වැවිලි පීඑල්සී",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජෝන් කීල්ස් පීඑල්සී",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "අයිස්ලබි වත්ත",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "බණ්ඩාරවෙල",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Malwatt Valley Plantations PLC",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "FBOP",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "සතිපතා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජූලි 11",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ඉන්ටර් ටී ලිමිටඩ්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජෝන් කීල්ස් පීඑල්සී",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ඩෙල්ටා වතුයාය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "පුපුරැස්ස",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "සතිය",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජූලි 12",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "1,000 කි",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "CTC Medium Grown Category",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "හෙරිටේජ් ටීස් ලිමිටඩ්.",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ඩෙල්ටා වතුයාය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "පුස්සැල්ලාව වැවිලි සමාගම",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "සිසිලියන් තේ කම්හල",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "සිසිලියන් ඇසෝසියේට්ස් ලිමිටඩ්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "කලවාන",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "රත්නපුරය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "2,800 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "අඩු වර්ධනය වූ කාණ්ඩය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "සතිය",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජූලි 12",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Expoteas Ceylon Ltd.",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "බ්‍රෝඩ්ලන්ඩ්ස් කුඩා තේ වතු හිමියන්ගේ තේ කර්මාන්ත ශාලාව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "පිටවෙල",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගිනිගත්හේන",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "කුඩා තේ වතු කර්මාන්තශාලා පීඑල්සී",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජූලි 11",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "2,850 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "අඩු වර්ධනය වූ කාණ්ඩය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Mabroc Teas Ltd.",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජෝන් කීල්ස් පීඑල්සී",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "களுபோவிட்டியன தேயிலை தொழிற்சாலைக்கு ஹாட்ரிக்",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "களுபோவிட்டியன தேயிலை தொழிற்சாலையானது தொடர்ந்து மூன்றாவது வாரமாக 100 ரூபா விலையை எட்டியதன் மூலம் அனைத்து கால சாதனையையும் மீண்டும் நிறுவியுள்ளது. ஜூலை 11 அன்று நடைபெற்ற தேயிலை ஏலத்தில், CTC குறைந்த அளவு வளர்ந்த பிரிவில், PF1 கிரேடில் கிலோ ஒன்றுக்கு ரூ. 2,950, அவர்களின் சொந்த சாதனை விலையான ரூ. கடந்த வார தேயிலை ஏலத்தில் கிடைத்த அதே தரத்திற்கு ஒரு கிலோ ரூ.2,750. யூனிவேர்ல்ட் டீஸ் லிமிடெட் மூலம் இந்த தேயிலை வரிசை வாங்கப்பட்டது.",
        "களுபோவிட்டியன தேயிலை தொழிற்சாலை மொரவகாவில் அமைந்துள்ளது மற்றும் களுபோவிட்டியன தேயிலை தொழிற்சாலை லிமிடெட் மூலம் நிர்வகிக்கப்படுகிறது. விற்பனை தரகர் ஜோன் கீல்ஸ் பிஎல்சி ஆவார்.",
        "பண்டாரவளையில் அமைந்துள்ள ஊவா ஹைலண்ட்ஸ் தோட்டம், ஜூலை 11ஆம் திகதி நடைபெற்ற வாராந்த தேயிலை ஏலத்தில் அனைத்து கால சாதனை விலையையும் பெற்று ரூ. Uva High Grown elevation பிரிவில் BOPF.Sp தரத்தில் கிலோ ஒன்றுக்கு 2,250. இந்த டீ இன்வாய்ஸ் ஹெரிடேஜ் டீஸ் லிமிடெட் மூலம் வாங்கப்பட்டது.",
        "ஊவா ஹைலண்ட்ஸ் தோட்டம் மல்வத்தை வேலி பிளான்டேஷன்ஸ் பிஎல்சியின் கீழ் வருகிறது மற்றும் ஜோன் கீல்ஸ் பிஎல்சி இதன் விற்பனையுடன் தொடர்புடைய தரகர்கள்.",
        "பண்டாரவளையில் அமைந்துள்ள Aislaby தோட்டம் மற்றும் Malwatt Valley Plantations PLC ஆல் நிர்வகிக்கப்பட்டு, கவர்ச்சிகரமான அனைத்து கால சாதனை விலையான ரூ. ஜூலை 11 ஆம் தேதி நடைபெற்ற வாராந்திர தேயிலை ஏலத்தில் ஊவா உயர் பிரிவில் FBOP தரத்தில் கிலோ ஒன்றுக்கு 3,500 ரூபாய்.",
        "இந்த வரிசை தேயிலை இன்டர் டீ லிமிடெட் நிறுவனத்தால் வாங்கப்பட்டது, மேலும் விற்பனையை தேயிலை தரகர் ஜோன் கீல்ஸ் பிஎல்சி நடத்தினார்.",
        "புபுரெஸ்ஸாவில் அமைந்துள்ள டெல்டா எஸ்டேட், ஜூலை 12 அன்று நடைபெற்ற இந்த வார தேயிலை ஏலத்தில், ரூ. ரூ. CTC நடுத்தர வளர்ந்த பிரிவில் பிபி1 தரத்தில் கிலோவுக்கு 1,000. இந்த தேயிலையை ஹெரிடேஜ் டீஸ் லிமிடெட் வாங்கியது.",
        "டெல்டா தோட்டம் புஸ்ஸல்லாவ பிளான்டேஷன்ஸ் லிமிட்டெட்டின் கீழ் வருகிறது மற்றும் விற்பனை தரகர் ஜோன் ஆவார்.",
        "சிசிலியன் அசோசியேட்ஸ் லிமிடெட் மூலம் நிர்வகிக்கப்படும் சிசிலியன் தேயிலை தொழிற்சாலை, கலவான, இரத்தினபுரியில் அமைந்துள்ள, அனைத்து கால சாதனை விலையாக ரூ. ஜூலை 12 அன்று நடைபெற்ற இந்த வார தேயிலை ஏலத்தில் குறைந்த வளர்ச்சி பிரிவில் BOP.Sp கிரேடில் கிலோ ஒன்றுக்கு 2,800 ரூபாய்.",
        "இந்த தேயிலை விலைப்பட்டியல் எக்ஸ்போடீஸ் சிலோன் லிமிடெட் நிறுவனத்தால் வாங்கப்பட்டது, மேலும் விற்பனையை தேயிலை தரகர் ஜான் நடத்தினார்.",
        "டீ ஸ்மால்ஹோல்டர் ஃபேக்டரீஸ் பிஎல்சியால் நிர்வகிக்கப்படும், கினிகத்தேன, பிடவெலவில் அமைந்துள்ள Broadlands சிறு தேயிலை தொழிற்சாலை, ஜூலை 11 அன்று நடைபெற்ற தேயிலை ஏலத்தில், ரூ. ரூ. கவர்ச்சிகரமான விலையைப் பெற்று, அனைத்து கால சாதனை விலையையும் பெற்றது. குறைந்த வளர்ந்த பிரிவில் BOPF.Sp தரத்தில் ஒரு கிலோவுக்கு 2,850.",
        "இந்த தேயிலை விலைப்பட்டியல் மேப்ரோக் டீஸ் லிமிடெட் நிறுவனத்தால் வாங்கப்பட்டது, மேலும் விற்பனை செய்யும் தரகர் ஜான் கீல்ஸ் பிஎல்சி."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "களுபோவிட்டியன தேயிலை தொழிற்சாலை",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "களுபோவிட்டியன தேயிலை தொழிற்சாலை",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "தொடர்ந்து மூன்றாவது வாரம்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஒரு கிலோ 2,950",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "CTC குறைந்த வளர்ச்சி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "11 ஜூலை",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஒரு கிலோ 2,750",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "கடந்த வாரம்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "யுனிவேர்ல்ட் டீஸ் லிமிடெட்.",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "களுபோவிட்டியன தேயிலை தொழிற்சாலை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Morawaka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "களுபோவிட்டியன தேயிலை தொழிற்சாலை லிமிடெட்.",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜான் கீல்ஸ் பிஎல்சி",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பண்டாரவளை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "வாரந்தோறும்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "11 ஜூலை",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஒரு கிலோ 2,250 ரூபாய்",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஊவா உயர் வளர்ந்தது",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஹெரிடேஜ் டீஸ் லிமிடெட்.",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Malwatte Valley Plantations PLC",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜான் கீல்ஸ் பிஎல்சி",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஐஸ்லாபி எஸ்டேட்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "பண்டாரவளை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Malwatt Valley Plantations PLC",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "FBOP",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "வாரந்தோறும்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "11 ஜூலை",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இண்டர் டீ லிமிடெட்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜான் கீல்ஸ் பிஎல்சி",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "டெல்டா எஸ்டேட்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "புபுரெஸ்ஸா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "வாரம்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "12 ஜூலை",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஒரு கிலோ 1,000",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "CTC நடுத்தர வளர்ந்த வகை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஹெரிடேஜ் டீஸ் லிமிடெட்.",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "டெல்டா எஸ்டேட்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "புஸ்ஸல்லாவ பிளான்டேஷன்ஸ் லிமிடெட்.",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "சிசிலியன் தேயிலை தொழிற்சாலை",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "சிசிலியன் அசோசியேட்ஸ் லிமிடெட்.",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "கலவானா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இரத்தினபுரி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "2,800",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "குறைந்த வளர்ந்த வகை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "வாரம்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "12 ஜூலை",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Expoteas Ceylon Ltd.",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பிராட்லேண்ட்ஸ் சிறு உரிமையாளர்கள் தேயிலை தொழிற்சாலை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "பிடவெல",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "கினிகத்தேன",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "டீ ஸ்மால்ஹோல்டர் ஃபேக்டரீஸ் பிஎல்சி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "11 ஜூலை",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "2,850",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "குறைந்த வளர்ந்த வகை",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "மாப்ரோக் டீஸ் லிமிடெட்.",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜான் கீல்ஸ் பிஎல்சி",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}