{
  "newspaper_id": "daily-mirror-lk",
  "url": "https://www.dailymirror.lk/breaking_news/Rs-17-85-Million-cash-recovered-inside-Presidents-House-Police-yet-to-keep-recovered-money-in-judicial-custody/108-241970",
  "time_ut": 1659013737,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Rs. 17.85 Million cash recovered inside President’s House: Police yet to keep recovered money in judicial custody",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Rs. 17.85 Million cash recovered inside President’s House: Police yet to keep recovered money in judicial custody",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "It was transpired before Colombo Fort Magistrate's Court that even after the lapse of three weeks, the Fort Police is yet to keep Rs. 17.85 Million in cash recovered from the President's House, under judicial custody.",
        "Taking into consideration the facts, Colombo Fort Magistrate Thilina Gamage today issued an order directing the OIC of Fort police to immediately produce in court, a sum of Rs. 17.8 Million recovered by protesters inside President's House on 9th July.",
        "Colombo Fort Magistrate Thilina Gamage made this order when the four suspects arrested for forcibly entering the President's House on the 9th of July were produced before Court by Slave Island Police.",
        "Defence Counsel appeared on behalf of the suspects and alleged that police have arrested four individuals out of thousands of people who entered the President's House following the 9th of July incident. They submitted to the court that individuals who acted to hand over the recovered money to the Fort Police have been arrested unreasonably.",
        "Refusing a request made by Slave Island police to remand the suspect, the Magistrate ordered to release of each suspect on a surety bail of Rs.500,000.",
        "President's Counsel Rienzie Arsekularatne with counsel Sunil Watagala, Chamindri Arsekularatne, Udara Muhandiramge and Nuwan Bopage appeared for the suspects.(Lakmal Sooriyagoda)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "17.85 Million",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "House",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Colombo Fort Magistrate's",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the lapse of three weeks",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Fort Police",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Rs",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "17.85 Million",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "House",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Colombo Fort Magistrate",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Thilina Gamage",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "OIC",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Fort",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "17.8 Million",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "House",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "9th July",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "four",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "House",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "9th",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "July",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Court",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Slave Island Police",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Defence Counsel",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "four",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "thousands",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "House",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "9th of July",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Fort Police",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Slave Island",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Magistrate",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Counsel Rienzie Arsekularatne",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sunil Watagala",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Chamindri Arsekularatne",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Udara Muhandiramge",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Nuwan Bopage",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sooriyagoda",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "රුපියල්. ජනාධිපති මන්දිරයේ තිබී මිලියන 17.85ක මුදල් සොයා ගැනේ: පොලිසිය තවමත් අධිකරණය භාරයේ තබා නැත",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "සති තුනක් ගතවී ඇතත් කොටුව පොලිසියේ රුපියල් කෝටි 100ක මුදලක් තවමත් තබාගෙන නොමැති බව කොළඹ කොටුව මහේස්ත්‍රාත් අධිකරණය හමුවේ ප්‍රකාශ විය. අධිකරණ භාරයට පත් ජනාධිපති මන්දිරයේ තිබී රුපියල් මිලියන 17.85 ක මුදල් සොයා ගැනේ.",
        "කරුණු සැලකිල්ලට ගත් කොළඹ කොටුව මහේස්ත්‍රාත් තිළිණ ගමගේ අද නියෝගයක් නිකුත් කරමින් කොටුව පොලිසියේ ස්ථානාධිපතිවරයාට රුපියල් ලක්ෂයක මුදලක් කඩිනමින් අධිකරණයට ඉදිරිපත් කරන ලෙසට නියෝග කළේය. ජුලි 9 වැනි දින ජනාධිපති මන්දිරය තුළ විරෝධතාකරුවන් විසින් මිලියන 17.8 ක් අයකර ගන්නා ලදී.",
        "කොළඹ කොටුව මහේස්ත්‍රාත් තිළිණ ගමගේ මහතා මෙම නියෝගය කළේ පසුගිය ජූලි 9 වැනිදා ජනාධිපති මන්දිරයට බලහත්කාරයෙන් ඇතුළුවීම සම්බන්ධයෙන් අත්අඩංගුවට ගත් සැකකරුවන් සිව්දෙනා කොම්පඤ්ඤවීදිය පොලිසිය විසින් අධිකරණයට ඉදිරිපත් කළ අවස්ථාවේදීය.",
        "සැකකරුවන් වෙනුවෙන් පෙනී සිටි විත්තියේ නීතිඥවරයා චෝදනා කළේ ජුලි මස 9 වැනිදා සිදුවීමෙන් පසු ජනාධිපති මන්දිරයට ඇතුළු වූ දහස් සංඛ්‍යාත ජනතාවගෙන් 4 දෙනෙකු පොලිසිය විසින් අත්අඩංගුවට ගෙන ඇති බවයි. ඔවුන් අධිකරණයට ඉදිරිපත් කළේ අයකර ගත් මුදල් කොටුව පොලිසියට ලබාදීමට කටයුතු කළ පුද්ගලයන් අසාධාරණ ලෙස අත්අඩංගුවට ගෙන ඇති බවයි.",
        "සැකකරු රිමාන්ඩ් භාරයට පත් කරන ලෙස කොම්පඤ්ඤවීදිය පොලිසිය කළ ඉල්ලීම ප්‍රතික්ෂේප කළ මහේස්ත්‍රාත්වරයා එක් සැකකරුවෙකු රුපියල් ලක්ෂ පහක ශරීර ඇප මත මුදා හැරීමට නියෝග කළේය.",
        "සැකකරුවන් වෙනුවෙන් ජනාධිපති නීතිඥ රියන්සි අර්සකුලරත්න, නීතිඥ සුනිල් වටගල, චමින්ද්‍රි අර්සකුලරත්න, උදාර මුහන්දිරම්ගේ සහ නුවන් බෝපගේ යන මහත්වරු පෙනී සිටියහ.(ලක්මාල් සූරියගොඩ)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "මිලියන 17.85 කි",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "නිවස",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "කොළඹ කොටුව මහේස්ත්‍රාත්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "සති තුනක කාලය",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "කොටුව පොලිසිය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "රුපියල්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "මිලියන 17.85 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "නිවස",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "කොළඹ කොටුව මහේස්ත්‍රාත්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "තිළිණ ගමගේ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ස්ථානාධිපති",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "බලකොටුව",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "මිලියන 17.8 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "නිවස",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජූලි 9",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "හතර",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "නිවස",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "9 වැනි",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජුලි",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "අධිකරණය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "කොම්පඤ්ඤවීදි පොලිසිය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ආරක්ෂක උපදේශක",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "හතර",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "දහස්",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "නිවස",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජූලි 9 වෙනිදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "කොටුව පොලිසිය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "කොම්පඤ්ඤවීදිය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මහේස්ත්රාත්වරයා",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "නීතිඥ රියන්සි අර්සකුලරත්න",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "සුනිල් වටගල",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "චමින්ද්‍රි අර්සකුලරත්න",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "උදාර මුහන්දිරම්ගේ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Nuwan Bopage",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "සූරියගොඩ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "ரூ. ஜனாதிபதி மாளிகைக்குள் 17.85 மில்லியன் பணம் மீட்பு: மீட்கப்பட்ட பணத்தை இன்னும் நீதிமன்ற காவலில் வைக்கவில்லை",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "மூன்று வாரங்கள் கடந்துள்ள நிலையிலும், கோட்டை பொலிஸாரினால் இதுவரை ரூ.5000000000000000000000000000000000000000000000000000000000000000000000000000000000000000000000000000000000000000000000000000000000000000000000000000000000000000000000000000ஐ 3வாரங்கள் கைவசமிருக்கவில்லை என கொழும்பு கோட்டை நீதவான் நீதிமன்றில் தெரிவிக்கப்பட்டது. ஜனாதிபதி மாளிகையில் இருந்து 17.85 மில்லியன் ரொக்கம், நீதிமன்ற காவலில் மீட்கப்பட்டது.",
        "இந்த விடயங்களை கருத்திற்கொண்ட கொழும்பு கோட்டை நீதவான் திலின கமகே, கோட்டை பொலிஸ் நிலைய பொறுப்பதிகாரியை உடனடியாக நீதிமன்றில் ஆஜர்படுத்துமாறு உத்தரவு பிறப்பித்துள்ளார். ஜூலை 9 ஆம் தேதி ஜனாதிபதி மாளிகைக்குள் போராட்டக்காரர்களால் 17.8 மில்லியன் மீட்கப்பட்டது.",
        "கடந்த ஜூலை மாதம் 9 ஆம் திகதி ஜனாதிபதி மாளிகைக்குள் பலவந்தமாக பிரவேசித்த குற்றச்சாட்டின் பேரில் கைது செய்யப்பட்ட நான்கு சந்தேகநபர்களையும் கொம்பைத்தீவு பொலிஸார் நீதிமன்றில் முன்னிலைப்படுத்திய போதே கொழும்பு கோட்டை நீதவான் திலின கமகே இந்த உத்தரவை பிறப்பித்தார்.",
        "சந்தேகநபர்கள் சார்பில் ஆஜரான சட்டத்தரணி, ஜூலை 9ஆம் திகதி இடம்பெற்ற சம்பவத்தைத் தொடர்ந்து ஜனாதிபதி மாளிகைக்குள் பிரவேசித்த ஆயிரக்கணக்கான மக்களில் நால்வரை பொலிஸார் கைது செய்துள்ளதாக குற்றம் சுமத்தினார். மீட்கப்பட்ட பணத்தை கோட்டை பொலிஸாரிடம் ஒப்படைக்க செயற்பட்ட நபர்கள் நியாயமற்ற முறையில் கைது செய்யப்பட்டுள்ளதாக அவர்கள் நீதிமன்றத்தில் தெரிவித்துள்ளனர்.",
        "சந்தேக நபரை விளக்கமறியலில் வைக்குமாறு கொம்பைத்தீவு பொலிஸார் விடுத்த கோரிக்கையை நிராகரித்த நீதவான் ஒவ்வொரு சந்தேக நபரையும் 500,000 ரூபா சரீரப் பிணையில் விடுவிக்க உத்தரவிட்டார்.",
        "சந்தேகநபர்கள் சார்பில் ஜனாதிபதி சட்டத்தரணி றியன்சி அர்செகுலரத்ன, சட்டத்தரணி சுனில் வதகல, சமிந்திரி அர்செகுலரத்ன, உதார முஹந்திரம்கே மற்றும் நுவான் போபகே ஆகியோர் முன்னிலையாகினர்.(லக்மால் சூரியகொட)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "17.85 மில்லியன்",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "வீடு",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "கொழும்பு கோட்டை நீதவான்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "மூன்று வாரங்கள் கழிந்தது",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "கோட்டை போலீஸ்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரூ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "17.85 மில்லியன்",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "வீடு",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "கொழும்பு கோட்டை நீதவான்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "திலின கமகே",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "OIC",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "கோட்டை",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "17.8 மில்லியன்",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "வீடு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜூலை 9",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "நான்கு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "வீடு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "9வது",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜூலை",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "நீதிமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "அடிமை தீவு போலீஸ்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பாதுகாப்பு ஆலோசகர்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "நான்கு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆயிரக்கணக்கான",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "வீடு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜூலை 9 ஆம் தேதி",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "கோட்டை போலீஸ்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "அடிமை தீவு",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "மாஜிஸ்திரேட்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "சட்டத்தரணி றியன்சி அர்செகுலரத்ன",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "சுனில் வதகல",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "சமிந்திரி அர்செகுலரத்ன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "உதாரா முஹந்திரம்கே",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Nuwan Bopage",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "சூரியகொட",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}