{
  "newspaper_id": "lankadeepa-lk",
  "url": "https://www.lankadeepa.lk/news/කන්දකාඩු-කඳවුරේ-ගැටුමක්/101-615592",
  "time_ut": 1656486349,
  "original_lang": "si",
  "original_title": "කන්දකාඩු කඳවුරේ ගැටුමක්",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "A clash at Kandakadu camp",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "A tense situation has arisen between the inmates of the Welikanda Kandakadu Drug Rehabilitation Center and the Army following the mysterious death of an inmate this morning.",
        "Nearly 440 detainees are reported to have escaped during the clashes.",
        "The Army and the Police have been called in to control the situation, Welikanda Police said.",
        "The canopy of the body of the detainee who died under suspicious circumstances could not be obtained by the police or the army."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Kandakadu",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "the Welikanda Kandakadu Drug Rehabilitation Center",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Army",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "this morning",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Nearly 440",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Army",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Welikanda Police",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        []
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "කන්දකාඩු කඳවුරේ ගැටුමක්",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "වැලිකන්ද කන්දකාඩු මත්ද්‍රව්‍ය පුනුරුත්ථාපන කඳවුරේ රැඳවියකු අද උදෑසන අභිරහස් ලෙස මරණයට පත් වීමත් සමග එම කඳවුරේ සිටින රැඳිවියන් සහ හමුදාව අතර උණුසුම් තත්ත්වයක් හටගෙන ඇතැයි වාර්තා වෙයි .",
        "එම ගැටුම අතර තුර රැඳිවියන් 440ක  ආසන්න සංඛ්‍යාවක් පැනගොස් ඇති බව ද වාර්තා වෙයි.",
        "උණුසුම්කාරී තත්වය පාලනය කිරීමට යුද හමුදාව සහ පොලිසිය කැඳවා ඇති බව වැලිකන්ද පොලීසිය සඳහන් කරයි.",
        "සැකකටයුතු ලෙස මියගිය රැඳිවියාගේ මළ සිරුර පොලිසියට හෝ හමුදාවට ලබා ගැනීමට නොහැකිව එම ස්ථානයේම තබාගෙන සිටීමට රැද වියන් කටයුතු කර තිබෙනවා."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "කන්දකාඩු",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "වැලිකන්ද කන්දකාඩු මත්ද්‍රව්‍ය පුනරුත්ථාපන මධ්‍යස්ථානය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "හමුදා",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "මේ උදෑසන",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "440ට ආසන්නයි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "හමුදා",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "වැලිකන්ද පොලිසිය",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        []
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "கந்தகாடு முகாமில் மோதல்",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "வெலிகந்த கந்தகாடு போதைப்பொருள் மறுவாழ்வு நிலையத்தில் இன்று காலை கைதி ஒருவர் மர்மமான முறையில் உயிரிழந்ததையடுத்து அங்குள்ள சிறைக்கைதிகளுக்கும் இராணுவத்தினருக்கும் இடையில் முறுகல் நிலை ஏற்பட்டுள்ளது.",
        "மோதலின் போது கிட்டத்தட்ட 440 கைதிகள் தப்பியோடியதாகத் தெரிவிக்கப்படுகிறது.",
        "நிலைமையை கட்டுப்படுத்த இராணுவம் மற்றும் பொலிசார் வரவழைக்கப்பட்டுள்ளதாக வெலிகந்த பொலிஸார் தெரிவித்தனர்.",
        "சந்தேகத்திற்கிடமான முறையில் மரணமடைந்த கைதியின் சடலத்தை பொலிஸாரோ அல்லது இராணுவத்தினரோ பெற்றுக்கொள்ள முடியவில்லை."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "கண்டகாடு",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "வெலிகந்த கந்தகாடு போதைப்பொருள் மறுவாழ்வு மையம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இராணுவம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று காலை",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "கிட்டத்தட்ட 440",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இராணுவம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "வெலிகந்த பொலிஸ்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        []
      ]
    }
  }
}