{
  "newspaper_id": "lankadeepa-lk",
  "url": "https://www.lankadeepa.lk/news/චීන-පොහොර-නැවට-ගෙවූ-මුදල-නැවත-ගැනීමේ-උත්සාහයන්-අසාර්ථකයි/101-619099",
  "time_ut": 1662008961,
  "original_lang": "si",
  "original_title": "චීන පොහොර නැවට ගෙවූ මුදල නැවත ගැනීමේ උත්සාහයන් අසාර්ථකයි",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Efforts to recover the payment for the Chinese fertilizer ship have been unsuccessful",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "The Minister of Agriculture, Wildlife and Forestry, Mr. Mahinda Amaraweera said in the Parliament today (1) that the 6.9 million dollars paid to the Chinese fertilizer ship or the attempts made to get chemical fertilizers instead have failed.",
        "The Minister of Agriculture said that the Attorney General has been consulted on the steps to be taken in this regard and action will be taken soon.",
        "The Minister said that an expert committee headed by the Secretary of the Ministry of Agriculture has been appointed to look into this issue further and come up with solutions.",
        "The Minister of Agriculture said this while replying to a question raised by Athuraliye Ratana Thero, a member of our People's Power Party."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Chinese",
          "label": "NORP"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Mahinda",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Amaraweera",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "1",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "the 6.9 million dollars",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "Chinese",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "the Ministry of Agriculture",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Athuraliye Ratana Thero",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "People's Power Party",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "චීන පොහොර නැවට ගෙවූ මුදල නැවත ගැනීමේ උත්සාහයන් අසාර්ථකයි",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "චීන පොහොර නැවට ගෙවූ ඩොලර් මිලියන 6.9ක මුදල හෝ ඒ වෙනුවට රසායනික පොහොර ලබා ගැනීමට කළ උත්සාහයන් අසාර්ථක වී ඇතැයි කෘෂිකර්ම වනජීවී හා වන සංරක්ෂණ අමාත්‍ය මහින්ද අමරවීර මහතා පාර්ලිමේන්තුවේ දී අද (1)පැවසීය.",
        "මේ සම්බන්ධව ගත ගත යුතු පියවර පිළිබඳ නීතිපති උපදෙස් ලබාගෙන තිබෙන අතර නුදුරේදීම ඒ ගැන ක්‍රියාමාර්ග ගන්නා බවද කෘෂිකර්ම අමාත්‍යවරයා කීය.",
        "මේ ප්‍රශ්නය පිළිබඳ වැඩිදුර සොයා බලා විසඳුම් ඉදිරිපත් කිරීමට කෘෂිකර්ම අමාත්‍යංශ ලේකම්ගේ ප්‍රධානත්වයෙන් විශේෂඥ කමිටුවක් පත්කර තිබෙන බවද අමාත්‍යවරයා කීය.",
        "අපේ ජන බල පක්ෂයේ  මන්ත්‍රී අතුරලියේ රතන හිමියන් මතු කළ ප්‍රශ්නයකට පිළිතුරු දෙමින් කෘෂිකර්ම අමාත්‍යවරයා මේ බව කීය."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "චීන",
          "label": "NORP"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "මහින්ද",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "අමරවීර",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "1",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඩොලර් මිලියන 6.9 කි",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "චීන",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "කෘෂිකර්ම අමාත්‍යාංශය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "අතුරලියේ රතන හිමි",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජනතා බලය පක්ෂය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "சீன உரக் கப்பலுக்கான கட்டணத்தை மீட்பதற்கான முயற்சிகள் வெற்றியளிக்கவில்லை",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "சீன உரக் கப்பலுக்கு செலுத்தப்பட்ட 6.9 மில்லியன் டொலர்கள் அல்லது அதற்குப் பதிலாக இரசாயன உரங்களைப் பெற்றுக்கொள்ள மேற்கொள்ளப்பட்ட முயற்சிகள் தோல்வியடைந்துள்ளதாக விவசாய, வனஜீவராசிகள் மற்றும் வனவள அமைச்சர் மஹிந்த அமரவீர இன்று (1) பாராளுமன்றத்தில் தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "இது தொடர்பாக எடுக்க வேண்டிய நடவடிக்கைகள் குறித்து சட்டமா அதிபரிடம் ஆலோசிக்கப்பட்டு விரைவில் நடவடிக்கை எடுக்கப்படும் என விவசாய அமைச்சர் தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "இது தொடர்பில் மேலும் ஆராய்ந்து தீர்வுகளை முன்வைப்பதற்காக விவசாய அமைச்சின் செயலாளர் தலைமையில் நிபுணர் குழுவொன்று நியமிக்கப்பட்டுள்ளதாக அமைச்சர் தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "எமது மக்கள் சக்தி கட்சியின் உறுப்பினர் அத்துரலியே ரதன தேரர் எழுப்பிய கேள்விக்கு பதிலளிக்கும் போதே விவசாய அமைச்சர் மேற்கண்டவாறு தெரிவித்தார்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "சீன",
          "label": "NORP"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "மஹிந்த",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "அமரவீர",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "1",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "6.9 மில்லியன் டாலர்கள்",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "சீன",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "விவசாய அமைச்சகம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "அத்துரலியே ரதன தேரர்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "மக்கள் சக்தி கட்சி",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}