{
  "newspaper_id": "ada-lk",
  "url": "https://www.ada.lk/breaking_news/අනේ-දෙයියනේ-මටනම්-අගමැතිකම-ඕන-නෑ/11-396684",
  "time_ut": 1661741981,
  "original_lang": "si",
  "original_title": "අනේ දෙයියනේ මටනම් අගමැතිකම ඕන නෑ",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Oh God, I don't want the prime ministership",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "Former President Maithripala Sirisena, the leader of the Sri Lanka Freedom Party, said that although the Sri Lanka Freedom Party proposed to the government from the beginning that it would be possible to solve the problems in the country through the formation of an all-party government, the current president is ignoring the request and is trying to form a traditional government instead of an all-party government. .",
        "The former president said that his party proposed that an all-party government should be formed by limiting the cabinet minister positions to twenty and further said that the 30 government cabinet minister positions and the 40 state minister positions that will be created in the future will be given.",
        "Former President Maithripala Sirisena said this while addressing the first Constituency Board meeting organized at a function hall in Thalavathugoda last (28) after the new constituency organizer of the Sri Lanka Freedom Party, Mr. Saman Pushpakumara Lankeswara, assumed his position in the Maharagama Constituency.",
        "I remember Minister Nimal Siripala de Silva said that an all-party government should be formed in the truest sense of the word. Having said that, my friend Mr. Nimal Siripala de Silva joined the government and took a ministership the next day. After that they said in the media that they joined the government with the approval of the party Central Committee and on the advice of the President Maithripala Sirisena. It's a flat out lie. They were never given my or the party's approval.",
        "In that way, an all-party government has not been established. A traditional government. We have heard that in the future, 30 cabinet ministers, 40 state ministers and 40 ministers are going to be formed. This is not an all-party government. It is a traditional government. We have no agreement for that. We proposed to form a new government with twenty ministers. But that didn't happen. In the meantime, others are suggesting me to take over the prime ministership of the new government. Oh God, I don't want to be the prime minister.",
        "Even though a new president has been appointed, the leaders of the Pohottu party are still ruling this country. That is the true story. Because the largest number of MPs in the Parliament are in Pohotta, so if any bill is passed, it should be done with their help. So I am not going to take any position in such a government. The party does not approve it. If someone leaves the party and joins the government, it is not to build the country but to get positions. That is our policy. These rulers have no plan to solve the existing problems. Only the Sri Lanka Freedom Party has the solutions for that.\""
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Maithripala Sirisena",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Sri Lanka Freedom Party",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Sri Lanka Freedom Party",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "twenty",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "30",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "40",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Maithripala Sirisena",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "first",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Constituency Board",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Thalavathugoda",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "28",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Sri Lanka Freedom Party",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Saman Pushpakumara Lankeswara",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Maharagama Constituency",
            "label": "LOC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Nimal Siripala de Silva",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Nimal Siripala de Silva",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the next day",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Central Committee",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Maithripala Sirisena",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "30",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "40",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "40",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "twenty",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the Pohottu party",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Pohotta",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Freedom Party",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "අනේ දෙයියනේ මටනම් අගමැතිකම ඕන නෑ",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "සර්ව පාක්ෂික රජයක් බිහිකිරීම තුළින් රටේ පවතින ප්‍රශ්න විසඳීමට හැකිවනු ඇති බව ශ්‍රී ලංකා නිදහස් පක්ෂය මුල සිටම රජයට යෝජනා කළත් වත්මන් ජනාධිපතිවරයා එම ඉල්ලීම පසෙකලා  සර්ව පාක්ෂික රජයක් බිහි නොකොට සාම්ප්‍රදායික රජයක් බිහි කිරීමට උත්සාහ දරමින් සිටින බව ශ්‍රී ලංකා නිදහස් පක්ෂයේ නායක  හිටපු ජනාධිපති මෛත්‍රීපාල සිරිසේන මහතා පැවසීය .",
        "කැබිනට් ඇමතිධුර විස්සකට සීමාකොට සර්ව පාක්ෂික රජයක් බිහි කළ යුතු බවට එහිදී තම පක්ෂය යෝජනා කළ බව පැවසූ හිටපු ජනාධිපතිවරයා ඉදිරියේදී බිහි කිරීමට නියමිත රජයේ කැබිනට් ඇමැති ධූර 30 සහ රාජ්‍ය ඇමති ධුර 40 ලබා දීමට නියමිත බවද වැඩිදුරටත් කියා සිටියේය.",
        "හිටපු ජනාධිපති මෛත්‍රීපාල සිරිසේන මහතා මේ බව කියා සිටියේ මහරගම ආසනයේ ශ්‍රී ලංකා නිදහස් පක්ෂයේ  නව ආසන  සංවිධායක සමන් පුෂ්පකුමාර ලංකේශ්වර මහතා සිය තනතුරට පත්වීමෙන් අනතුරුව ඉකුත් (28) දා තලවතුගොඩ ප්‍රදේශයේ උත්සව ශාලාවක සංවිධානය කර  තිබූ පළමු ආසන බල මණ්ඩල රැස්වීම  අමතමිනි.",
        "මට මතකයි නිමල් සිරිපාල ද සිල්වා ඇමතිතුමා කියා සිටියේ  වචනයේ පරිසමාප්ත අර්ථයෙන්ම සර්ව පාක්ෂික රජයක් බිහි කළ යුතු බවයි. එහෙම කියපු මා මිත්‍ර නිමල් සිරිපාල ද සිල්වා මහත්මයා පහුවෙනිදා රජයට එකතුවෙලා ඇමතිකමක් ගත්තා. ඊට පස්සෙ මාධ්‍ය හමුවේ ඔවුන් කියා සිටිනවා පක්ෂය අනුමැතියෙන් පක්ෂ මධ්‍යම කාරක සභාවේ අනුමැතියෙන් මෛත්‍රීපාල සිරිසේන ජනාධිපතිවරයාගේ උපදෙස් මත රජයට එකතු වූ බව. ඒක  පට්ටපල් බොරුවක් . කිසිම වෙලාවක මගේ හෝ පක්ෂයේ අනුමැතියක්  ඔවුන්ට ලබල දුන්නේ නැහැ.",
        "ඒ විදියට දැන් හදා ගෙන තියෙන්නේ සර්ව පාක්ෂික රජයක් නෙමෙයි. සාම්ප්‍රදායික ආණ්ඩුවක්.  අපිට ආරංචියි ඉදිරියේදී කැබිනට් ඇමතිධුර 30 රාජ්‍ය අමාත්‍යධුර අමාත්‍ය ධුර 40  දීලා අලුතෙන් ආණ්ඩුවක් හදන්න යනවා කියලා. මේ හැදෙන්නෙ සර්ව පාක්ෂික ආණ්ඩුවක් නෙමෙයි. ඒක සම්ප්‍රදායික ආණ්ඩුවක . ඒ  සදහා  අපේ කිසිම එකඟතාවයක් නෑ. අපි යෝජනා කළේ ඇමතිධූර විස්සකින් අලුත් ආණ්ඩුවක් හදමු කියලා. ඒත් එහෙම වුණේ නෑ. මේ අතරෙ තවත් අය මට යෝජනා කරනවා අලුත් ආණ්ඩුවේ අගමැතිකම භාර ගන්න කියලා. අනේ දෙයියනේ මටනම් අගමැති වෙන්න ඕනේ නැහැ.",
        "අලුත් ජනාධිපතිවරයෙක් පත්වුණාට අදටත් මේ රට පාලනය කරන්නෙ පොහොට්ටු පක්ෂයේ නායකයො.ඒක තමයි ඇත්ත කතාව. මොකද පාර්ලිමේන්තුවේ වැඩිම මන්ත්‍රීවරුන් පිරිසක් ඉන්නේ පොහොට්ටවේ .ඉතින් යම් පනතක් සම්මත කරනවා  නම් ඔවුන්ගේ උදව් ඇතිව තමයි කෙරෙන්න ඕනෙ. ඉතින්  එවන් රජයක කිසිම තනතුරක් ගන්න මම යන්නෙත් නැහැ. පක්ෂය ඒකට අනුමැතිය දෙන්නෙත් නෑ. යම් කෙනෙක් පක්ෂ අත හැරල යම් කෙනෙක් රජයට එකතු වෙනවා නම් ඒ යන්නෙ රට හදන්න නෙමෙයි තනතුරු ලබා ගන්නයි.  එයයි අපේ ප්‍රතිපත්තිය. මේ පාලකයින්ට පවතින ප්‍රශ්න විසදීමට  කිසිම සැලැස්මක් නෑ. ඒ සඳහා විසඳුම් ඇත්තෙ ශ්‍රී ලංකා නිදහස් පක්ෂය සතුව පමණයි.”"
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "මෛත්‍රීපාල සිරිසේන",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකා නිදහස් පක්ෂය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකා නිදහස් පක්ෂය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "විස්සක්",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "30",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "40",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "මෛත්‍රීපාල සිරිසේන",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "පළමුවන",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ආසන මණ්ඩලය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "තලවතුගොඩ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "28",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකා නිදහස් පක්ෂය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "සමන් පුෂ්පකුමාර ලංකේශ්වර",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "මහරගම මැතිවරණ කොට්ඨාසය",
            "label": "LOC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "නිමල් සිරිපාල ද සිල්වා",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "නිමල් සිරිපාල ද සිල්වා",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඊළඟ දිනය",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මධ්‍යම කාරක සභාව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "මෛත්‍රීපාල සිරිසේන",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "30",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "40",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "40",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "විස්සක්",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "පොහොට්ටු පක්ෂය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "පොහොට්ටා",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "නිදහස් පක්ෂය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "கடவுளே, எனக்கு பிரதமர் பதவி வேண்டாம்",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "ஶ்ரீலங்கா சுதந்திரக் கட்சி ஆரம்பத்திலிருந்தே அரசாங்கத்திடம் பிரேரணைகளை முன்வைத்த போதிலும் நாட்டில் நிலவும் பிரச்சினைகளுக்கு சர்வகட்சி அரசாங்கம் அமைப்பதன் மூலம் தீர்வு காண முடியும் என ஸ்ரீலங்கா சுதந்திரக் கட்சியின் தலைவரும், முன்னாள் ஜனாதிபதி மைத்திரிபால சிறிசேனா தெரிவித்தார். , தற்போதைய ஜனாதிபதி கோரிக்கையை புறக்கணித்து அனைத்து கட்சி அரசாங்கத்திற்கு பதிலாக பாரம்பரிய அரசாங்கத்தை அமைக்க முயற்சிக்கிறார்.",
        "அமைச்சரவை அமைச்சுப் பதவிகளை இருபதுக்கு மட்டுப்படுத்தி சர்வகட்சி அரசாங்கமொன்றை அமைக்க வேண்டும் என தமது கட்சி முன்மொழிந்ததாகத் தெரிவித்த முன்னாள் ஜனாதிபதி, அரசாங்கத்தின் 30 அமைச்சரவை அமைச்சுப் பதவிகளும், 40 இராஜாங்க அமைச்சர் பதவிகளும் எதிர்காலத்தில் உருவாக்கப்படும் என்றும் தெரிவித்தார். கொடுக்கப்பட்டது.",
        "ஸ்ரீலங்கா சுதந்திரக் கட்சியின் புதிய தொகுதி அமைப்பாளர் திரு.சமன் புஸ்பகுமார லங்கேஸ்வரா மஹரகம தொகுதியில் தனது பதவியை பொறுப்பேற்றதன் பின்னர் கடந்த (28) தலவத்துகொடையில் அமைந்துள்ள விழா மண்டபத்தில் ஏற்பாடு செய்யப்பட்ட முதலாவது தொகுதி சபை கூட்டத்தில் கலந்து கொண்டு உரையாற்றும் போதே முன்னாள் ஜனாதிபதி மைத்திரிபால சிறிசேன மேற்கண்டவாறு தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "வார்த்தையின் உண்மையான அர்த்தத்தில் சர்வகட்சி அரசாங்கம் அமைக்கப்பட வேண்டும் என்று அமைச்சர் நிமல் சிறிபால டி சில்வா கூறியது எனக்கு நினைவிருக்கிறது. என்று கூறிவிட்டு எனது நண்பர் திரு.நிமல் சிறிபால டி சில்வா அரசாங்கத்தில் இணைந்து அடுத்த நாளே அமைச்சுப் பதவியைப் பெற்றுக்கொண்டார். அதன் பின்னர் கட்சியின் மத்திய குழுவின் அங்கீகாரத்துடன் ஜனாதிபதி மைத்திரிபால சிறிசேனவின் ஆலோசனைக்கு அமைய அரசாங்கத்தில் இணைந்து கொண்டதாக அவர்கள் ஊடகங்களில் தெரிவித்துள்ளனர். இது அப்பட்டமான பொய். அவர்களுக்கு எனது அல்லது கட்சியின் அங்கீகாரம் வழங்கப்படவில்லை.",
        "அந்த வகையில் அனைத்துக் கட்சி ஆட்சி அமைக்கப்படவில்லை. ஒரு பாரம்பரிய அரசாங்கம். எதிர்காலத்தில் 30 கேபினட் அமைச்சர்கள், 40 இராஜாங்க அமைச்சர்கள், 40 அமைச்சர்கள் பதவியேற்கப் போகிறார்கள் என்று கேள்விப்பட்டிருக்கிறோம். இது அனைத்துக் கட்சி அரசு அல்ல. இது ஒரு பாரம்பரிய அரசு. அதில் எங்களுக்கு உடன்பாடு இல்லை. இருபது அமைச்சர்களைக் கொண்ட புதிய அரசாங்கத்தை அமைக்க நாங்கள் முன்மொழிந்தோம். ஆனால் அது நடக்கவில்லை. இதற்கிடையில், புதிய அரசாங்கத்தின் பிரதமர் பதவியை ஏற்க மற்றவர்கள் எனக்கு ஆலோசனை வழங்குகின்றனர். கடவுளே, எனக்கு பிரதமராக விருப்பம் இல்லை.",
        "புதிய ஜனாதிபதி நியமிக்கப்பட்டாலும் பொஹொட்டு கட்சியின் தலைவர்களே இந்த நாட்டை ஆட்சி செய்கின்றார்கள் அதுதான் உண்மை கதை. நாடாளுமன்றத்தில் அதிக எண்ணிக்கையிலான எம்.பி.க்கள் பொஹோட்டாவில் இருப்பதால், எந்த சட்டமூலம் நிறைவேற்றப்பட்டாலும் அவர்களின் உதவியுடன்தான் நிறைவேற்றப்பட வேண்டும். எனவே அவ்வாறான அரசாங்கத்தில் நான் எந்த பதவியையும் எடுக்கப் போவதில்லை. அதை கட்சி ஏற்கவில்லை. ஒருவர் கட்சியை விட்டு வெளியேறி அரசாங்கத்தில் இணைந்தால் அது பதவிகளைப் பெறுவதற்காகவே தவிர நாட்டைக் கட்டியெழுப்புவதற்காக அல்ல. அதுதான் எங்களின் கொள்கை. தற்போதுள்ள பிரச்சினைகளை தீர்க்க இந்த ஆட்சியாளர்களிடம் எந்த திட்டமும் இல்லை. அதற்கான தீர்வுகள் ஸ்ரீலங்கா சுதந்திரக் கட்சியிடம் மாத்திரமே உள்ளது."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "மைத்திரிபால சிறிசேன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஸ்ரீலங்கா சுதந்திரக் கட்சி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஸ்ரீலங்கா சுதந்திரக் கட்சி",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இருபது",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "30",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "40",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "மைத்திரிபால சிறிசேன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "முதலில்",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "தொகுதி வாரியம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "தலவத்துகொட",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "28",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஸ்ரீலங்கா சுதந்திரக் கட்சி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "சமன் புஷ்பகுமார லங்கேஸ்வரா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "மஹரகம தொகுதி",
            "label": "LOC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "நிமல் சிறிபால டி சில்வா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "நிமல் சிறிபால டி சில்வா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "அடுத்த நாள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "மத்திய குழு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "மைத்திரிபால சிறிசேன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "30",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "40",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "40",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "இருபது",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பொஹொட்டு கட்சி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "பொஹோட்டா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "சுதந்திரக் கட்சி",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}