{
  "newspaper_id": "daily-mirror-lk",
  "url": "https://www.dailymirror.lk/latest_news/22nd-Amendment-bill-does-not-meet-peoples-aspirations-BASL/342-240611",
  "time_ut": 1657263511,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "22nd Amendment bill does not meet people’s aspirations -BASL",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "22nd Amendment bill does not meet people’s aspirations -BASL",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "The Bar Association of Sri Lanka (BASL) today announced that the 22nd Amendment to the Constitution Bill in the present form does not meet the aspirations of the people who are agitating for a change in the system.",
        "BASL President Saliya Pieris PC said at a press conference that the Executive Committee of the BASL is of the view that the said Bill would not create a climate of confidence both within the country and outside",
        "the country of an intention to engage in proper political reform.",
        "The BASL President also raised issues relating to the process of appointment to Constitutional Council and its composition. Mr. Pieris said the BASL is of the view that the proposed 22nd Amendment as presently constituted does",
        "not sufficiently guarantee the independence of the process of appointment of non-Parliamentary members of the Constitutional Council.",
        "The Constitutional Council will have seven parliamentarians and three non parliamentarians. Among the three non parliamentarians, the 22nd amendment has proposed that they should be appointed with the approval of the majority of the members of the Parliament.",
        "Pieris said that the majority in parliament will be able to control the composition of the constitutional council adversely affecting the ability of the",
        "Constitutional Council to act as a check and balance on the exercise of Presidential powers.",
        "If the Constitutional Council is not independent then the question would arise regarding the independence of the appointment which the constitutional council approves, the BASL President added.",
        "The BASL President further observed that the independence of the Constitutional Council is very important because it is the Constitutional Council which approves the key officers of the state including the judges of the apex courts, the Attorney General and Inspector General of Police.",
        "The BASL further observed that the Monetary Board of the Central Bank has not been brought within the purview",
        "of the Constitutional Council, although the Governor of the Central Bank is included.",
        "The Executive Committee of the BASL also observed that the 22nd Amendment does not create sufficient checks and balances on the exercise of powers by the incumbent President under the current Parliament, since most of the provisions in the amendment which seek to limit the powers of the President will",
        "become operative only after the dissolution of the present Parliament.",
        "The BASL is also concerned that the 22nd Amendment has included several provisos as transitional provisions, which will result in the provisions of the 22nd Amendment relating to the removal of the Prime Minister and the appointment of Minister and designation of subjects to them will not apply to the present President during the tenure of the present Parliament, thus failing to introduce adequate checks and balances on the present President. (Lakmal Sooriyagoda)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "22nd Amendment",
          "label": "LAW"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "The Bar Association of Sri Lanka",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the 22nd Amendment",
            "label": "LAW"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Constitution Bill",
            "label": "LAW"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "BASL",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Saliya Pieris",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Executive Committee",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "BASL",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Bill",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "BASL",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Constitutional Council",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Pieris",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "BASL",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "22nd Amendment",
            "label": "LAW"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the Constitutional Council",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "The Constitutional Council",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "seven",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "three",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "three",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "22nd",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Pieris",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Constitutional Council",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the Constitutional Council",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "BASL",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "BASL",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Constitutional Council",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Constitutional Council",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "BASL",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Monetary Board of the Central Bank",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the Constitutional Council",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Central Bank",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "The Executive Committee",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "BASL",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the 22nd Amendment",
            "label": "LAW"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "BASL",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the 22nd Amendment",
            "label": "LAW"
          },
          {
            "text": "22nd Amendment",
            "label": "LAW"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Lakmal Sooriyagoda",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "22 වැනි සංශෝධන පනත් කෙටුම්පත ජනතා අභිලාෂයන් සපුරාලන්නේ නැහැ -BASL",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "ආණ්ඩුක්‍රම ව්‍යවස්ථාවේ 22 වැනි සංශෝධන පනත් කෙටුම්පත වත්මන් ආකෘතියෙන් ක්‍රමයේ වෙනසක් ඉල්ලා උද්ඝෝෂණ කරන ජනතාවගේ අපේක්ෂාවන් ඉටු නොවන බව ශ්‍රී ලංකා නීතිඥ සංගමය (BASL) අද නිවේදනය කළේය.",
        "BASL සභාපති ජනාධිපති නීතිඥ සාලිය පීරිස් මහතා මාධ්‍ය හමුවකදී ප්‍රකාශ කළේ එම පනත් කෙටුම්පත රට තුළ සහ පිටත විශ්වාසය තැබිය හැකි වාතාවරණයක් ඇති නොකරන බව BASL විධායක කමිටුවේ අදහස බවයි.",
        "නිසි දේශපාලන ප්‍රතිසංස්කරණයක නියැලීමේ අභිප්‍රාය ඇති රට.",
        "ආණ්ඩුක්‍රම ව්‍යවස්ථා සභාවට පත්කිරීමේ ක්‍රියාවලිය සහ එහි සංයුතිය සම්බන්ධ ගැටළු ද BASL සභාපතිවරයා විසින් මතු කරන ලදී. පීරිස් මහතා ප්‍රකාශ කළේ යෝජිත 22 වැනි ව්‍යවස්ථා සංශෝධනය මගින් දැනට පිහිටුවා ඇති පරිදි BASL අදහස වන බවයි.",
        "ආණ්ඩුක්‍රම ව්‍යවස්ථා සභාවේ පාර්ලිමේන්තු නොවන සාමාජිකයින් පත් කිරීමේ ක්‍රියාවලියේ ස්වාධීනත්වය ප්‍රමාණවත් ලෙස සහතික කර නොමැත.",
        "ආණ්ඩුක්‍රම ව්‍යවස්ථා සභාවට පාර්ලිමේන්තු මන්ත්‍රීවරුන් හත් දෙනෙකු සහ පාර්ලිමේන්තු නොවන මන්ත්‍රීවරුන් තිදෙනෙකු ඇතුළත් වේ. පාර්ලිමේන්තු නොවන මන්ත්‍රීවරුන් තිදෙනා අතරින් පාර්ලිමේන්තුවේ බහුතර මන්ත්‍රීවරුන්ගේ අනුමැතියෙන් ඔවුන් පත් කළ යුතු බවට 22 වැනි සංශෝධනයෙන් යෝජනා කර ඇත.",
        "පීරිස් ප්‍රකාශ කළේ ව්‍යවස්ථාදායක සභාවේ සංයුතිය පාලනය කිරීමට පාර්ලිමේන්තුවේ බහුතර බලයට හැකි වනු ඇති බවයි.",
        "ආණ්ඩුක්‍රම ව්‍යවස්ථා සභාව ජනාධිපති බලතල ක්‍රියාත්මක කිරීමේදී සමබරව ක්‍රියා කිරීම.",
        "ආණ්ඩුක්‍රම ව්‍යවස්ථා සභාව ස්වාධීන නොවන්නේ නම් ආණ්ඩුක්‍රම ව්‍යවස්ථා සභාව අනුමත කරන පත්කිරීමේ ස්වාධීනත්වය පිළිබඳ ප්‍රශ්නය මතුවන බවද ශ්‍රී ලංකා නිදහස් පක්ෂයේ සභාපතිවරයා වැඩිදුරටත් පැවසීය.",
        "ආණ්ඩුක්‍රම ව්‍යවස්ථා සභාවේ ස්වාධීනත්වය ඉතා වැදගත් වන්නේ ශ්‍රේෂ්ඨාධිකරණ විනිසුරුවරුන්, නීතිපතිවරයා සහ පොලිස්පතිවරයා ඇතුළු රාජ්‍යයේ ප්‍රධාන නිලධාරීන් අනුමත කරන්නේ ආණ්ඩුක්‍රම ව්‍යවස්ථා සභාව බැවින් බව BASL සභාපතිවරයා වැඩිදුරටත් නිරීක්ෂණය කළේය.",
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකා මහ බැංකුවේ මුදල් මණ්ඩලය විෂය පථයට ඇතුළත් කර නොමැති බව ශ්‍රී ලංකා BASL වැඩිදුරටත් නිරීක්ෂණය කළේය",
        "ආණ්ඩුක්‍රම ව්‍යවස්ථා සභාවේ, මහ බැංකු අධිපතිවරයා ඇතුළත් වුවද.",
        "22 වැනි සංශෝධනය මගින් වත්මන් පාර්ලිමේන්තුව යටතේ වත්මන් ජනාධිපතිවරයාගේ බලතල ක්‍රියාත්මක කිරීම සම්බන්ධයෙන් ප්‍රමාණවත් සංවරණ සහ තුලනයක් ඇති නොවන බව ද BASL හි විධායක කමිටුව නිරීක්ෂණය කළේ සංශෝධනයේ බොහෝ ප්‍රතිපාදන ජනාධිපතිවරයාගේ බලතල සීමා කිරීමට අපේක්ෂා කරන බැවිනි. කැමැත්ත",
        "ක්‍රියාත්මක වන්නේ වත්මන් පාර්ලිමේන්තුව විසුරුවා හැරීමෙන් පසුවය.",
        "22 වැනි ව්‍යවස්ථා සංශෝධනයට සංක්‍රාන්ති විධිවිධාන ලෙස ප්‍රතිපාදන කිහිපයක් ඇතුළත් කර ඇති අතර, එහි ප්‍රතිඵලයක් ලෙස 22 වැනි සංශෝධනයේ අග්‍රාමාත්‍යවරයා ඉවත් කිරීම සහ අමාත්‍යවරයා පත් කිරීම සහ ඔවුන්ට විෂයයන් නම් කිරීම සම්බන්ධ විධිවිධාන අදාළ නොවන බව BASL ද අවධානය යොමු කරයි. වත්මන් ජනාධිපතිවරයා වත්මන් පාර්ලිමේන්තුවේ පාලන කාලය තුළ වත්මන් ජනාධිපතිවරයා සම්බන්ධයෙන් ප්‍රමාණවත් චෙක්පත් සහ ශේෂයන් හඳුන්වා දීමට අපොහොසත් විය. (ලක්මාල් සූරියගොඩ)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "22 වැනි සංශෝධනය",
          "label": "LAW"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකා නීතිඥ සංගමය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "22 වැනි සංශෝධනය",
            "label": "LAW"
          },
          {
            "text": "ආණ්ඩුක්‍රම ව්‍යවස්ථා කෙටුම්පත",
            "label": "LAW"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "BASL",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "සාලිය පීරිස්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "විධායක කමිටුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "BASL",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "බිල්පත්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "BASL",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ව්යවස්ථා සභාව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "පීරිස්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "BASL",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "22 වැනි සංශෝධනය",
            "label": "LAW"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ආණ්ඩුක්රම ව්යවස්ථා සභාව",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ආණ්ඩුක්‍රම ව්‍යවස්ථා සභාව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "හත",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "තුන්",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "තුන්",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "22 වැනි",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "පීරිස්",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ව්යවස්ථා සභාව",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ආණ්ඩුක්රම ව්යවස්ථා සභාව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "BASL",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "BASL",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ආණ්ඩුක්රම ව්යවස්ථා සභාව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ආණ්ඩුක්රම ව්යවස්ථා සභාව",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "BASL",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "මහ බැංකුවේ මුදල් මණ්ඩලය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ආණ්ඩුක්රම ව්යවස්ථා සභාව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "මහ බැංකුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "විධායක කමිටුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "BASL",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "22 වැනි සංශෝධනය",
            "label": "LAW"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "BASL",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "22 වැනි සංශෝධනය",
            "label": "LAW"
          },
          {
            "text": "22 වැනි සංශෝධනය",
            "label": "LAW"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ලක්මාල් සූරියගොඩ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "22வது திருத்தச் சட்டமூலம் மக்களின் அபிலாஷைகளை பூர்த்தி செய்யவில்லை -BASL",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "அரசியலமைப்பின் 22 ஆவது திருத்தச் சட்டமூலமானது தற்போதைய வடிவத்தில் மாற்றத்தை ஏற்படுத்துமாறு போராடும் மக்களின் அபிலாஷைகளை பூர்த்தி செய்யவில்லை என இலங்கை சட்டத்தரணிகள் சங்கம் (BASL) இன்று அறிவித்துள்ளது.",
        "BASL தலைவர் சாலிய பீரிஸ் பிசி ஒரு செய்தியாளர் சந்திப்பில், BASL இன் நிறைவேற்றுக் குழு, நாட்டிற்குள்ளும் வெளியேயும் நம்பிக்கைக்குரிய சூழலை உருவாக்காது என்று கூறினார்.",
        "சரியான அரசியல் சீர்திருத்தத்தில் ஈடுபடும் எண்ணம் கொண்ட நாடு.",
        "அரசியலமைப்பு சபைக்கான நியமனம் மற்றும் அதன் அமைப்பு தொடர்பான பிரச்சினைகளையும் BASL தலைவர் எழுப்பினார். தற்போது உருவாக்கப்பட்டுள்ள உத்தேச 22வது திருத்தம் BASL இன் கருத்தைக் கொண்டுள்ளது என்று திரு. பீரிஸ் கூறினார்.",
        "அரசியலமைப்பு சபையின் பாராளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர் அல்லாதவர்களை நியமிக்கும் செயல்முறையின் சுதந்திரத்திற்கு போதுமான உத்தரவாதம் இல்லை.",
        "அரசியலமைப்பு பேரவையில் ஏழு பாராளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர்களும் மூன்று பாராளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர்கள் அல்லாதவர்களும் இருப்பார்கள். பாராளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர்கள் மூவரில், 22ஆவது திருத்தச் சட்டத்தில், பெரும்பான்மையான நாடாளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர்களின் அங்கீகாரத்துடன் அவர்கள் நியமிக்கப்பட வேண்டும் என முன்மொழியப்பட்டுள்ளது.",
        "பாராளுமன்றத்தில் பெரும்பான்மையினரால் அரசியலமைப்பு பேரவையின் கட்டமைப்பை கட்டுப்படுத்த முடியும் என பீரிஸ் தெரிவித்துள்ளார்.",
        "அரசியலமைப்பு சபை ஜனாதிபதியின் அதிகாரங்களைப் பயன்படுத்துவதில் ஒரு சரிபார்ப்பு மற்றும் சமநிலையாக செயல்படும்.",
        "அரசியலமைப்புச் சபை சுயாதீனமாக இல்லாவிட்டால், அரசியலமைப்புச் சபை அங்கீகரிக்கும் நியமனத்தின் சுதந்திரம் பற்றிய கேள்வி எழும் என BASL தலைவர் மேலும் தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "உச்ச நீதிமன்ற நீதிபதிகள், அட்டர்னி ஜெனரல் மற்றும் பொலிஸ் மா அதிபர் உட்பட அரசின் முக்கிய அதிகாரிகளை அரசியலமைப்பு சபையே அங்கீகரிப்பதால் அரசியலமைப்பு சபையின் சுதந்திரம் மிகவும் முக்கியமானது என BASL தலைவர் மேலும் குறிப்பிட்டார்.",
        "மத்திய வங்கியின் நாணயச் சபை எல்லைக்குள் கொண்டுவரப்படவில்லை என BASL மேலும் அவதானித்துள்ளது",
        "அரசியலமைப்புச் சபையின், மத்திய வங்கியின் ஆளுனர் உள்ளடக்கப்பட்டிருந்தாலும்.",
        "BASL இன் நிறைவேற்றுக் குழு, தற்போதைய பாராளுமன்றத்தின் கீழ் தற்போதைய ஜனாதிபதியின் அதிகாரங்களைப் பயன்படுத்துவதில் 22 வது திருத்தம் போதுமான காசோலைகள் மற்றும் சமநிலைகளை உருவாக்கவில்லை, ஏனெனில் திருத்தத்தில் உள்ள பெரும்பாலான விதிகள் ஜனாதிபதியின் அதிகாரங்களை மட்டுப்படுத்த முயல்கின்றன. விருப்பம்",
        "தற்போதைய பாராளுமன்றம் கலைக்கப்பட்ட பின்னரே செயல்படும்.",
        "22 வது திருத்தம் இடைக்கால விதிகளாக பல விதிகளை உள்ளடக்கியுள்ளது என்றும் BASL கவலை கொண்டுள்ளது, இதன் விளைவாக 22 வது திருத்தத்தின் பிரதம மந்திரியை நீக்குவது மற்றும் அமைச்சரை நியமிப்பது மற்றும் அவர்களுக்கான பாடங்களை நியமிப்பது தொடர்பான விதிகள் பொருந்தாது. தற்போதைய ஜனாதிபதி தற்போதைய பாராளுமன்றத்தின் ஆட்சிக் காலத்தில், தற்போதைய ஜனாதிபதிக்கு போதுமான காசோலைகள் மற்றும் நிலுவைகளை அறிமுகப்படுத்தத் தவறிவிட்டார். (லக்மால் சூரியகொட)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "22வது திருத்தம்",
          "label": "LAW"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை சட்டத்தரணிகள் சங்கம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "22 வது திருத்தம்",
            "label": "LAW"
          },
          {
            "text": "அரசியலமைப்பு மசோதா",
            "label": "LAW"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "BASL",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "சாலியா பீரிஸ்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "செயற்குழு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "BASL",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ர சி து",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "BASL",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "அரசியலமைப்பு சபை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "பீரிஸ்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "BASL",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "22வது திருத்தம்",
            "label": "LAW"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "அரசியலமைப்பு சபை",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "அரசியலமைப்பு சபை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஏழு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "மூன்று",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "மூன்று",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "22வது",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பீரிஸ்",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "அரசியலமைப்பு சபை",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "அரசியலமைப்பு சபை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "BASL",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "BASL",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "அரசியலமைப்பு சபை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "அரசியலமைப்பு சபை",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "BASL",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "மத்திய வங்கியின் நாணய வாரியம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "அரசியலமைப்பு சபை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "மத்திய வங்கி",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "செயற்குழு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "BASL",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "22 வது திருத்தம்",
            "label": "LAW"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "BASL",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "22 வது திருத்தம்",
            "label": "LAW"
          },
          {
            "text": "22வது திருத்தம்",
            "label": "LAW"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "லக்மால் சூரியகொட",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}