{
  "newspaper_id": "virakesari-lk",
  "url": "http://www.virakesari.lk/article/131977",
  "time_ut": 1658413013,
  "original_lang": "ta",
  "original_title": "ஜனாதிபதி ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க பாதுகாப்பு அமைச்சிற்கு விஜயம்",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "President Ranil Wickremesinghe visits the Ministry of Defence",
      "author": "Vishnu",
      "body_lines": [
        "President Ranil Wickremesinghe visited the Ministry of Defense located at the Sri Jayawardenepura Fort after taking the oath of office at the Parliament Complex on the 21st of Thursday morning.",
        "The President, who visited the Ministry, was received by Defense Secretary Retired General Kamal Gunaratna.",
        "This was President Ranil Wickremesinghe's first visit to a government institution after taking oath of office.",
        "During the President's visit, Minister Dron Alas, Attorney General, Secretary to the President, Acting Chief of Defense General General Shavendra Silva, Tri-Army Commanders, Inspector General of Police, Chief of State Intelligence and Director of National Intelligence were also present."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Ranil Wickremesinghe",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "the Ministry of Defence",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Ministry of Defense",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Sri Jayawardenepura Fort",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Parliament Complex",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the 21st of",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Thursday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "morning",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Defense",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kamal Gunaratna",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "first",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Dron Alas",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Shavendra Silva",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Tri-Army Commanders",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "National Intelligence",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "ජනාධිපති රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතා ආරක්ෂක අමාත්‍යාංශයට පැමිණෙයි",
      "author": "විෂ්ණු",
      "body_lines": [
        "ජනාධිපති රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතා 21 බ්‍රහස්පතින්දා පෙරවරුවේ පාර්ලිමේන්තු සංකීර්ණයේදී දිවුරුම් දීමෙන් අනතුරුව ශ්‍රී ජයවර්ධනපුර කොටුවේ පිහිටි ආරක්ෂක අමාත්‍යාංශය වෙත ගියේය.",
        "අමාත්‍යාංශය වෙත ගිය ජනාධිපතිතුමා පිළිගනු ලැබුවේ ආරක්ෂක ලේකම් විශ්‍රාමික ජෙනරාල් කමල් ගුණරත්න මහතා විසිනි.",
        "ජනාධිපති රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතා දිවුරුම් දීමෙන් පසු රජයේ ආයතනයකට ගිය පළමු අවස්ථාව මෙයයි.",
        "ජනාධිපතිවරයාගේ මෙම සංචාරයට අමාත්‍ය ඩ්‍රොන් අලස්, නීතිපති, ජනාධිපති ලේකම්, වැඩබලන ආරක්ෂක ප්‍රධානී ජෙනරාල් ශවේන්ද්‍ර සිල්වා, ත්‍රිවිධ හමුදාපතිවරුන්, පොලිස්පති, රාජ්‍ය බුද්ධි ප්‍රධානී සහ ජාතික බුද්ධි අධ්‍යක්ෂ ඇතුළු පිරිසක් එක්ව සිටියහ."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "ආරක්ෂක අමාත්යාංශය",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ආරක්ෂක අමාත්යාංශය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ජයවර්ධනපුර බලකොටුව",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තු සංකීර්ණය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "21 වෙනිදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "බ්රහස්පතින්දා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "උදෑසන",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ආරක්ෂක",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "කමල් ගුණරත්න",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "පළමුවන",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ඩ්‍රොන් අහෝ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශවේන්ද්‍ර සිල්වා",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ත්‍රිවිධ හමුදාපතිවරු",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජාතික බුද්ධි",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "ஜனாதிபதி ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க பாதுகாப்பு அமைச்சிற்கு விஜயம்",
      "author": "Vishnu",
      "body_lines": [
        "ஜனாதிபதி ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க இன்று 21 ஆம் திகதி வியாழக்கிழமை முற்பகல் பாராளுமன்ற வளாகத்தில் பதவிப்பிரமாணம் செய்த பின்னர் , ஸ்ரீ ஜயவர்தனபுற கோட்டையில் அமைந்துள்ள பாதுகாப்பு அமைச்சிற்கு விஜயம் செய்துள்ளார்.",
        "அமைச்சிற்கு விஜயம் செய்த ஜனாதிபதி , பாதுகாப்பு செயலாளர் ஓய்வு பெற்ற ஜெனரல் கமல் குணரத்னவினால் வரவேற்கப்பட்டார்.",
        "ஜனாதிபதி ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க பதவிப் பிரமாணம் செய்த பின்னர் அரச நிறுவனமொன்றுக்கு மேற்கொண்ட முதலாவது விஜயம் இதுவாகும்.",
        "ஜனாதிபதியின் இந்த விஜயத்தின் போது அமைச்சர் டிரான் அலஸ், சட்டமா அதிபர், ஜனாதிபதி செயலாளர், பாதுகாப்பு பதவிநிலை தலைமை அதிகாரி ஜெனரல் ஜெனரல் சவேந்திர சில்வா , முப்படை தளபதிகள் , பொலிஸ்மா அதிபர், அரச புலனாய்வு பிரதானி, தேசிய புலனாய்வு பிரிவின் பணிப்பாளர் உள்ளிட்ட முக்கியஸ்தர்களும் கலந்து கொண்டனர்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "பாதுகாப்பு அமைச்சகம்",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாதுகாப்பு அமைச்சகம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஸ்ரீ ஜெயவர்தனபுர கோட்டை",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்ற வளாகம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "21 ஆம் தேதி",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "வியாழன்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "காலை",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பாதுகாப்பு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "கமல் குணரத்னா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "முதலில்",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "துரோன் ஐயோ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "சவேந்திர சில்வா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "முப்படைத் தளபதிகள்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "தேசிய புலனாய்வு",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}