{
  "newspaper_id": "economy-next-com",
  "url": "https://economynext.com/sri-lanka-given-us4-0bn-dollars-of-support-from-india-envoy-98886/",
  "time_ut": 1661220300,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Sri Lanka given US$4.0bn dollars of support from India: envoy",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Sri Lanka given US$4.0bn dollars of support from India: envoy",
      "author": "",
      "body_lines": [
        "ECONOMYNEXT – India has so far given Sri Lanka about 4.0 billion US dollars in financing in 2022, High Commissioner Gopal Bagley told reporters as a second consignment of fertilizer landed in Colombo financed by a credit line from his country.",
        "A shipment of 21,000 metric tonnes of fertilizer landed in Colombo on August 22, financed by the Indian credit line. India has already supplied 44,000 metric tonnes of fertilizer.",
        "“This is for the people of Sri Lanka. This is fo the farmers of Sri Lanka,” High Commissioner Gopal Bagley told reporters.",
        "“India has so far given Sri Lanka about 4.0 billion dollars of support.”",
        "India has given 500 million US dollar credit line for fuel and 1,000 billion dollars in credit line for other imports including fertilizer.",
        "The import credit lines when fully re-imbursed by the private sector also allows budget support.",
        "In addition India has delayed about 200 to 300 million US dollars in import payments due under the Asian clearing union allowing the central bank to use it.",
        "Sri Lanka ran into the worst currency crisis in the history of the country’s intermediate regime central bank after two year of money printing and a failed float with a surrender requirement (forced dollar sales to the central bank).",
        "Sri Lanka’s economists got the power to create forex shortages, high inflation and severe economic crisis with the setting up of an intermediate regime central bank (soft-peg) in August 1950.",
        "Forex shortages and currency crises are a problem associated with soft-pegs (central banks which operate a policy rate and collects reserves by targeting an exchange rate) which is not found in hard pegs or clean floats.",
        "Once the credibility of the peg has been lost due to money printing (mainly open market operations), economic activity has to be smashed with extra high interest rates to reduce outflows and end money printing.",
        "Sri Lanka has been intervening in fore markets with Indian money but economic activity is rapidly falling after rates went up and private credit slowed. (Colombo/Aug23/2022)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Sri Lanka",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "US$4.0bn dollars",
          "label": "MONEY"
        },
        {
          "text": "India",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "India",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "about 4.0 billion US dollars",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "2022",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Gopal Bagley",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "second",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Colombo",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "21,000 metric tonnes",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "Colombo",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "August 22",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Indian",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "India",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "44,000 metric tonnes",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Gopal Bagley",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "India",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "about 4.0 billion dollars",
            "label": "MONEY"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "India",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "500 million US dollar",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "1,000 billion dollars",
            "label": "MONEY"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "India",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "about 200 to 300 million US dollars",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "Asian",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "two year",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka’s",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "August 1950",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Indian",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවට ඉන්දියාවෙන් ඩොලර් බිලියන 4.0 ක ආධාරයක් ලබා දී ඇත: තානාපති",
      "author": "",
      "body_lines": [
        "ECONOMYNEXT - ඉන්දියාව මේ වන විට 2022 දී ශ්‍රී ලංකාවට ඇමරිකානු ඩොලර් බිලියන 4.0 ක පමණ මූල්‍ය ආධාරයක් ලබා දී ඇති බව මහ කොමසාරිස් ගෝපාල් බග්ලි වාර්තාකරුවන්ට පැවසුවේ තම රටෙන් ණය මාර්ගයකින් මුදල් ලබා ගත් දෙවන පොහොර තොගයක් කොළඹට ගොඩ බැස්ස බවයි.",
        "ඉන්දීය ණය මාර්ගයෙන් මූල්‍ය ආධාර මත පොහොර මෙට්‍රික් ටොන් 21,000ක තොගයක් අගෝස්තු 22දා කොළඹට ගොඩබස්වන ලදී. ඉන්දියාව දැනටමත් පොහොර මෙට්‍රික් ටොන් 44,000ක් සපයා ඇත.",
        "“මේක ලංකාවේ මිනිස්සුන්ට. මෙය ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ ගොවීන් සඳහායි, ”මහ කොමසාරිස් ගෝපාල් බග්ලි වාර්තාකරුවන්ට පැවසීය.",
        "\"ඉන්දියාව මේ වන විට ශ්‍රී ලංකාවට ඩොලර් බිලියන 4.0 ක පමණ ආධාරයක් ලබා දී ඇත.\"",
        "ඉන්දියාව ඉන්ධන සඳහා ඩොලර් මිලියන 500 ක ණය මාර්ගයක් සහ පොහොර ඇතුළු අනෙකුත් ආනයන සඳහා ඩොලර් බිලියන 1,000 ක ණය මාර්ගයක් ලබා දී ඇත.",
        "ආනයන ණය මාර්ග පුද්ගලික අංශය විසින් සම්පූර්ණයෙන්ම ප්‍රතිපූරණය කරන විට අයවැය සහය ද ලබා දේ.",
        "මීට අමතරව, ආසියානු නිෂ්කාශන සංගමය යටතේ ඉන්දියාව විසින් ගෙවිය යුතු ආනයනික ගෙවීම් ඩොලර් මිලියන 200 සිට 300 දක්වා ප්‍රමාද කර ඇති අතර එය මහ බැංකුවට භාවිතා කිරීමට ඉඩ සලසයි.",
        "වසර දෙකක මුදල් මුද්‍රණයකින් සහ යටත් වීමේ අවශ්‍යතාවයක් (මහ බැංකුවට බලහත්කාරයෙන් ඩොලර් විකිණීම) සමඟ අසාර්ථක පාවීමකින් පසු රටේ අතරමැදි පාලන තන්ත්‍රයේ මහ බැංකු ඉතිහාසයේ දරුණුතම මුදල් අර්බුදයට ශ්‍රී ලංකාව මුහුණ දුන්නේය.",
        "1950 අගෝස්තු මාසයේදී අතරමැදි පාලන තන්ත්‍ර මධ්‍යම බැංකුවක් (සොෆ්ට්-පෙග්) පිහිටුවීමත් සමඟ විදේශ විනිමය හිඟය, ඉහළ උද්ධමනය සහ දරුණු ආර්ථික අර්බුදයක් ඇති කිරීමට ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ ආර්ථික විද්‍යාඥයින්ට බලය ලැබුණි.",
        "විදේශ විනිමය හිඟය සහ මුදල් අර්බුද යනු දෘඩ පෙග් හෝ පිරිසිදු පාවෙන වල දක්නට නොලැබෙන මෘදු-පෙග් (ප්‍රතිපත්තිමය අනුපාතයක් ක්‍රියාත්මක කරන සහ විනිමය අනුපාතයක් ඉලක්ක කර සංචිත එකතු කරන මහ බැංකු) හා සම්බන්ධ ගැටලුවකි.",
        "මුදල් මුද්‍රණය (ප්‍රධාන වශයෙන් විවෘත වෙළඳපල මෙහෙයුම්) හේතුවෙන් ඇණෙහි විශ්වසනීයත්වය නැති වූ පසු, පිටතට ගලායාම අඩු කිරීමට සහ මුදල් මුද්‍රණය අවසන් කිරීමට අමතර ඉහළ පොලී අනුපාත සමඟ ආර්ථික ක්‍රියාකාරකම් කඩා දැමීමට සිදුවේ.",
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකාව ඉන්දියානු මුදලින් පෙර වෙලඳපොලවල් වලට මැදිහත් වී ඇති නමුත් පොලී අනුපාත ඉහල යාමෙන් සහ පුද්ගලික ණය මන්දගාමී වීමෙන් පසු ආර්ථික ක්‍රියාකාරකම් ශීඝ්‍රයෙන් පහත වැටේ. (කොළඹ/අගෝස්තු 23/2022)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "ඩොලර් බිලියන 4.0 ක්",
          "label": "MONEY"
        },
        {
          "text": "ඉන්දියාව",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඇමරිකානු ඩොලර් බිලියන 4.0 ක් පමණ වේ",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "2022",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගෝපාල් බග්ලි",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "දෙවැනි",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "කොළඹ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "මෙට්‍රික් ටොන් 21,000 කි",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "කොළඹ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "අගෝස්තු 22",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දීය",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මෙට්‍රික් ටොන් 44,000 කි",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගෝපාල් බග්ලි",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඩොලර් බිලියන 4.0 ක් පමණ වේ",
            "label": "MONEY"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඩොලර් මිලියන 500 කි",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඩොලර් බිලියන 1,000 කි",
            "label": "MONEY"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඩොලර් මිලියන 200 සිට 300 දක්වා",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "ආසියානු",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "වසර දෙකක්",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "1950 අගෝස්තු",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දීය",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "இந்தியாவிடம் இருந்து இலங்கைக்கு 4.0 பில்லியன் அமெரிக்க டாலர்கள் ஆதரவு: தூதுவர்",
      "author": "",
      "body_lines": [
        "பொருளாதாரம் - இந்தியா இதுவரை 2022 ஆம் ஆண்டில் இலங்கைக்கு சுமார் 4.0 பில்லியன் அமெரிக்க டாலர்களை நிதியுதவியாக வழங்கியுள்ளது என்று உயர் ஸ்தானிகர் கோபால் பாக்லே செய்தியாளர்களிடம் தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "21,000 மெட்ரிக் டன் உரங்களின் ஏற்றுமதி ஆகஸ்ட் 22 அன்று கொழும்பில் தரையிறங்கியது, இந்திய கடன் வரியால் நிதியளிக்கப்பட்டது. இந்தியா ஏற்கனவே 44,000 மெட்ரிக் டன் உரங்களை வழங்கியுள்ளது.",
        "“இது இலங்கை மக்களுக்கானது. இது இலங்கை விவசாயிகளுக்கானது” என உயர்ஸ்தானிகர் கோபால் பாக்லே செய்தியாளர்களிடம் தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "\"இந்தியா இதுவரை இலங்கைக்கு சுமார் 4.0 பில்லியன் டாலர் ஆதரவை வழங்கியுள்ளது.\"",
        "இந்தியா 500 மில்லியன் அமெரிக்க டாலர்களை எரிபொருளுக்காகவும், 1,000 பில்லியன் டாலர்களை உரம் உள்ளிட்ட பிற இறக்குமதிகளுக்காகவும் கடன் வழங்கியுள்ளது.",
        "இறக்குமதி கடன் வரிகள் தனியார் துறையால் முழுமையாக திரும்ப செலுத்தப்படும் போது பட்ஜெட் ஆதரவையும் அனுமதிக்கிறது.",
        "கூடுதலாக, இந்தியா மத்திய வங்கியைப் பயன்படுத்த அனுமதிக்கும் ஆசிய தீர்வு ஒன்றியத்தின் கீழ் செலுத்த வேண்டிய இறக்குமதிக் கொடுப்பனவுகளில் சுமார் 200 முதல் 300 மில்லியன் அமெரிக்க டாலர்களை தாமதப்படுத்தியுள்ளது.",
        "இரண்டு வருட பண அச்சடிப்பு மற்றும் சரணடைதல் தேவையுடன் (மத்திய வங்கிக்கு கட்டாயப்படுத்தப்பட்ட டாலர் விற்பனை) தோல்வியடைந்த மிதப்பின் பின்னர் நாட்டின் இடைநிலை ஆட்சி மத்திய வங்கியின் வரலாற்றில் இலங்கை மிக மோசமான நாணய நெருக்கடியில் சிக்கியது.",
        "1950 ஆம் ஆண்டு ஆகஸ்ட் மாதம் ஒரு இடைநிலை ஆட்சி மத்திய வங்கி (soft-peg) ஸ்தாபிக்கப்பட்டதன் மூலம் இலங்கையின் பொருளாதார வல்லுநர்கள் அந்நிய செலாவணி பற்றாக்குறை, அதிக பணவீக்கம் மற்றும் கடுமையான பொருளாதார நெருக்கடியை உருவாக்கும் சக்தியைப் பெற்றனர்.",
        "அந்நிய செலாவணி பற்றாக்குறை மற்றும் நாணய நெருக்கடிகள் மென்மையான ஆப்புகளுடன் தொடர்புடைய ஒரு பிரச்சனையாகும் (கொள்கை விகிதத்தை இயக்கும் மற்றும் மாற்று விகிதத்தை குறிவைத்து இருப்புக்களை சேகரிக்கும் மத்திய வங்கிகள்) கடினமான ஆப்புகளில் அல்லது சுத்தமான மிதவைகளில் காணப்படவில்லை.",
        "பணம் அச்சிடுதல் (முக்கியமாக திறந்த சந்தை செயல்பாடுகள்) காரணமாக ஆப்புகளின் நம்பகத்தன்மை இழந்தவுடன், வெளியேறுவதைக் குறைக்கவும் பணத்தை அச்சிடுவதை முடிவுக்குக் கொண்டுவரவும் கூடுதல் அதிக வட்டி விகிதங்களுடன் பொருளாதார நடவடிக்கைகளை நொறுக்க வேண்டும்.",
        "இந்தியப் பணத்துடன் இலங்கை முன் சந்தைகளில் தலையிடுகிறது ஆனால் விகிதங்கள் அதிகரித்து தனியார் கடன் மந்தமடைந்ததை அடுத்து பொருளாதார நடவடிக்கைகள் வேகமாக வீழ்ச்சியடைந்து வருகின்றன. (கொழும்பு/ஆகஸ்ட்23/2022)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "இலங்கை",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "US$4.0bn டாலர்கள்",
          "label": "MONEY"
        },
        {
          "text": "இந்தியா",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "இந்தியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சுமார் 4.0 பில்லியன் அமெரிக்க டாலர்கள்",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "2022",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "கோபால் பாக்லே",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இரண்டாவது",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "கொழும்பு",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "21,000 மெட்ரிக் டன்",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "கொழும்பு",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆகஸ்ட் 22",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்தியன்",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்தியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "44,000 மெட்ரிக் டன்",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "கோபால் பாக்லே",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இந்தியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சுமார் 4.0 பில்லியன் டாலர்கள்",
            "label": "MONEY"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இந்தியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "500 மில்லியன் அமெரிக்க டாலர்",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "1,000 பில்லியன் டாலர்கள்",
            "label": "MONEY"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "இந்தியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சுமார் 200 முதல் 300 மில்லியன் அமெரிக்க டாலர்கள்",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆசிய",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இரண்டு வருடம்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கையின்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆகஸ்ட் 1950",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்தியன்",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}