{
  "newspaper_id": "ada-derana-lk",
  "url": "http://www.adaderana.lk/news/83637/protesters-decide-to-hand-over-occupied-govt-buildings",
  "time_ut": 1657779540,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Protesters decide to hand over occupied govt buildings",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Protesters decide to hand over occupied govt buildings",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "The Galle Face protesters have decided to hand over the government buildings they occupied, including the President’s House, Presidential Secretariat and Prime Minister’s Office, aiming to restore peace in the country."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Galle Face",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "House",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Presidential Secretariat",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Prime Minister’s Office",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "වාඩිලාගෙන සිටින රජයේ ගොඩනැගිලි පවරා දීමට විරෝධතාකරුවන් තීරණය කරයි",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "රට තුළ සාමය ඇති කිරීමේ අරමුණින් ජනාධිපති මන්දිරය, ජනාධිපති ලේකම් කාර්යාලය, අග්‍රාමාත්‍ය කාර්යාලය ඇතුළු තමන් විසින් අල්ලාගෙන සිටි රජයේ ගොඩනැගිලි යළි භාරදීමට ගාලුමුවදොර විරෝධතාකරුවන් තීරණය කර තිබේ."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ගාලු මුවදොර",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "නිවස",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජනාධිපති ලේකම් කාර්යාලය",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "අගමැති කාර්යාලය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "ஆக்கிரமிக்கப்பட்ட அரசு கட்டிடங்களை ஒப்படைக்க போராட்டக்காரர்கள் முடிவு",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "நாட்டில் அமைதியை நிலைநாட்டும் நோக்கில், ஜனாதிபதி மாளிகை, ஜனாதிபதி செயலகம், பிரதமர் அலுவலகம் உள்ளிட்ட தாம் ஆக்கிரமித்துள்ள அரச கட்டிடங்களை கையளிக்க காலி முகத்திடல் ஆர்ப்பாட்டக்காரர்கள் தீர்மானித்துள்ளனர்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "காலி முகம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "வீடு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜனாதிபதி செயலகம்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "பிரதமர் அலுவலகம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}