{
  "newspaper_id": "daily-ft-lk",
  "url": "https://www.ft.lk/news/Sri-Lanka-celebrates-26th-anniversary-of-diplomatic-relations-with-Lithuania/56-738716",
  "time_ut": 1660593639,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Sri Lanka celebrates 26th anniversary of diplomatic relations with Lithuania",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Sri Lanka celebrates 26th anniversary of diplomatic relations with Lithuania",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "The year 2022 marks the 26th anniversary of the official establishment of bilateral relations between the Socialist Republic of Sri Lanka and the Republic of Lithuania.",
        "Lithuania is a former Soviet republic (also known as Soviet Lithuania or Lithuanian Soviet Socialist Republic, was one of the constituent republics of the USSR between 1940-1941 and 1944-1990) seceded from the Russian Federation on 11 March 1990, and became an independent democratic State.",
        "Since then, Lithuania has sought to build friendly and independent foreign relations with many countries around the world. Lithuania established official foreign relations with Sri Lanka on 20 August 1996, while establishing itself as an independent State, having served as a friendly member Government of the European Union.",
        "Since the commencement of diplomatic relations between Sri Lanka and Lithuania, the Ministry of External Affairs of Sri Lanka appointed excellent Diplomat Alfred Kulendran of Sri Lanka to establish diplomatic relations with Lithuania as the Ambassador to represent Sri Lanka. He was the Ambassador of Sri Lanka to Sweden from 1996 to 1999 whilst he served as the Associate Ambassador of Sri Lanka to Lithuania.",
        "Mohhamad Anzar Jabir was appointed by the Lithuanian Government as the first Lithuanian Consul in Sri Lanka from 1996 to 2014. Following his untimely demise, the Lithuanian Embassy in Sri Lank temporarily closed its office in Sri Lanka.",
        "With the prior recommendation and approval of the Government of Lithuania, in a short time period, the Lithuanian Ministry of Foreign Affairs, re-established the Lithuanian Consulate by appointing R.M. Mannivannan in the year 2015. He is the Chairman of Supreme Global Group, a reputed and leading commercial company in Sri Lanka.",
        "Limonas Talat Kelpsa was the first Lithuanian Ambassador to Sri Lanka, appointed by the Government of Lithuania. Julius Pranevičius is currently the concurrent Ambassador of the Lithuanian Ministry of Foreign Affairs to Sri Lanka.",
        "Over the past 26 years, foreign relations between Sri Lanka and Lithuania have been developing in a strong manner. The two countries have made significant strides in the fields of tourism, commerce, higher education, and technology. They have been contributing very positively with a friendly approach to the decisions taken by the association, for the betterment and the prosperity of Sri Lanka.",
        "The Republic of Lithuania, which is closely monitoring the economic crisis that Sri Lanka is currently facing, is working together with the European Union to provide relief to the people of Sri Lanka. Also, in the coming period, the Lithuanian consulates and the Lithuanian embassy in Sri Lanka are making arrangements with the Ministry of Foreign Affairs of Sri Lanka to attract more Lithuanian tourists by introducing Sri Lanka as their long-term holiday destination among Lithuanian tourists.",
        "Also, Lithuania has already become a popular destination for Sri Lankan entrepreneurs, Sri Lankan students seeking higher education and Sri Lankans seeking employment abroad.",
        "Through 26 years of successful diplomatic relations, space will be created to further strengthen the diplomatic relations between the two countries through building stronger relations in economic, entrepreneurial, science and technology, innovation as well as cultural, political and economic sectors."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Sri Lanka",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "26th",
          "label": "ORDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "Lithuania",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "The year 2022",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "26th",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Socialist Republic of Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Republic of Lithuania",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Lithuania",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Soviet",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Soviet",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Lithuanian",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "USSR",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "1940-1941",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "1944-1990",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Russian Federation",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "11 March 1990",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "State",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Lithuania",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Lithuania",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "20 August 1996",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "State",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the European Union",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Lithuania",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Ministry of External Affairs of Sri Lanka",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Alfred Kulendran",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Lithuania",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sweden",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "1996 to 1999",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Lithuania",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Mohhamad Anzar Jabir",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Lithuanian Government",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "first",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Lithuanian Consul",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "2014",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Lithuanian Embassy in",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lank",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Lithuania",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Lithuanian Ministry of Foreign Affairs",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Lithuanian Consulate",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "R.M. Mannivannan",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the year 2015",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Supreme Global Group",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Talat Kelpsa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "first",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Lithuanian",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Government of Lithuania",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Julius Pranevičius",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Lithuanian Ministry of Foreign Affairs to Sri Lanka",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the past 26 years",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Lithuania",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "two",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "The Republic of Lithuania",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the European Union",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Ministry of Foreign Affairs of Sri Lanka",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Lithuanian",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Lithuanian",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Lithuania",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lankan",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lankan",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lankans",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "26 years",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "two",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "ශ්‍රී ලංකාව ලිතුවේනියාව සමඟ රාජ්‍ය තාන්ත්‍රික සබඳතාවල 26 වැනි සංවත්සරය සමරයි",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "2022 වසර ශ්‍රී ලංකා සමාජවාදී ජනරජය සහ ලිතුවේනියා ජනරජය අතර ද්විපාර්ශ්වික සබඳතා නිල වශයෙන් ස්ථාපිත කිරීමේ 26 වැනි සංවත්සරය සනිටුහන් කරයි.",
        "ලිතුවේනියාව යනු පැරණි සෝවියට් ජනරජයකි (සෝවියට් ලිතුවේනියාව හෝ ලිතුවේනියානු සෝවියට් සමාජවාදී ජනරජය ලෙසද හැඳින්වේ, 1940-1941 සහ 1944-1990 අතර සෝවියට් සංගමයේ සංඝටක ජනරජ වලින් එකකි) 1990 මාර්තු 11 දින රුසියානු සමූහාණ්ඩුවෙන් වෙන්වී ස්වාධීන විය. ප්රජාතන්ත්රවාදී රාජ්යය.",
        "එතැන් සිට ලිතුවේනියාව ලොව පුරා බොහෝ රටවල් සමඟ මිත්රශීලී සහ ස්වාධීන විදේශ සබඳතා ගොඩනඟා ගැනීමට උත්සාහ කරයි. යුරෝපා සංගමයේ මිත්‍රශීලී සාමාජික රජයක් ලෙස කටයුතු කරමින් ස්වාධීන රාජ්‍යයක් ලෙස ස්ථාපිත වෙමින් ලිතුවේනියාව 1996 අගෝස්තු 20 වැනි දින ශ්‍රී ලංකාව සමඟ නිල විදේශ සබඳතා ආරම්භ කළේය.",
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකාව සහ ලිතුවේනියාව අතර රාජ්‍ය තාන්ත්‍රික සබඳතා ආරම්භ වූ දා සිට ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ විදේශ කටයුතු අමාත්‍යාංශය විසින් ශ්‍රී ලංකාව නියෝජනය කිරීම සඳහා ලිතුවේනියාව සමඟ රාජ්‍ය තාන්ත්‍රික සබඳතා ඇති කර ගැනීම සඳහා ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ විශිෂ්ට රාජ්‍ය තාන්ත්‍රිකයෙකු වන ඇල්ෆ්‍රඩ් කුලේන්ද්‍රන් පත් කරන ලදී. ඔහු 1996 සිට 1999 දක්වා ස්වීඩනයේ ශ්‍රී ලංකා තානාපතිවරයා වූ අතර ලිතුවේනියාවේ ශ්‍රී ලංකා සහකාර තානාපතිවරයා ලෙස සේවය කළේය.",
        "1996 සිට 2014 දක්වා ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ පළමු ලිතුවේනියානු කොන්සල්වරයා ලෙස මොහොමඩ් අන්සාර් ජබීර් මහතා ලිතුවේනියානු රජය විසින් පත් කරන ලදී.",
        "ලිතුවේනියා රජයේ පූර්ව නිර්දේශය සහ අනුමැතිය ඇතිව, කෙටි කාලයක් තුළ, ලිතුවේනියානු විදේශ කටයුතු අමාත්‍යාංශය, ලිතුවේනියානු කොන්සල් කාර්යාලය නැවත ස්ථාපිත කළේ ආර්.එම්. Mannivannan වසර 2015. ඔහු ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ කීර්තිමත් සහ ප්‍රමුඛතම වාණිජ සමාගමක් වන සුප්‍රීම් ග්ලෝබල් සමූහයේ සභාපතිවරයා වේ.",
        "Limonas Talat Kelpsa ලිතුවේනියා රජය විසින් පත් කරන ලද ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ පළමු ලිතුවේනියානු තානාපතිවරයා විය. Julius Pranevičius දැනට ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ ලිතුවේනියානු විදේශ කටයුතු අමාත්‍යාංශයේ සමගාමී තානාපතිවරයා වේ.",
        "පසුගිය වසර 26 තුළ ශ්‍රී ලංකාව සහ ලිතුවේනියාව අතර විදේශ සබඳතා ශක්තිමත් ලෙස වර්ධනය වෙමින් පවතී. සංචාරක, වාණිජ, උසස් අධ්‍යාපන සහ තාක්ෂණ යන ක්ෂේත්‍රවල දෙරට සැලකිය යුතු ප්‍රගතියක් ලබා ඇත. ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ අභිවෘද්ධිය සහ සෞභාග්‍යය වෙනුවෙන් සංගමය විසින් ගනු ලබන තීරණ සඳහා සුහදශීලී ප්‍රවේශයකින් ඔවුන් ඉතා ධනාත්මක ලෙස දායක වී ඇත.",
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකාව මේ වන විට මුහුණ දී සිටින ආර්ථික අර්බුදය පිළිබඳව දැඩි අවධානයෙන් සිටින ලිතුවේනියා ජනරජය යුරෝපා සංගමය සමඟ එක්ව ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ ජනතාවට සහන සැලසීමට කටයුතු කරමින් සිටී. එසේම ඉදිරි කාලසීමාව තුළ ලිතුවේනියානු සංචාරකයින් අතර ඔවුන්ගේ දිගුකාලීන නිවාඩු ගමනාන්තය ලෙස ශ්‍රී ලංකාව හඳුන්වා දීමෙන් ලිතුවේනියානු සංචාරකයින් වැඩි වශයෙන් ආකර්ෂණය කර ගැනීමට ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ ලිතුවේනියානු කොන්සල් කාර්යාල සහ ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ ලිතුවේනියානු තානාපති කාර්යාලය ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ විදේශ කටයුතු අමාත්‍යාංශය සමඟ කටයුතු කරමින් සිටී.",
        "එසේම, ලිතුවේනියාව දැනටමත් ශ්‍රී ලාංකික ව්‍යවසායකයින්, උසස් අධ්‍යාපනය අපේක්ෂා කරන ශ්‍රී ලාංකික සිසුන් සහ විදේශ රැකියා අපේක්ෂා කරන ශ්‍රී ලාංකිකයින් සඳහා ජනප්‍රිය ගමනාන්තයක් බවට පත්ව ඇත.",
        "වසර 26ක සාර්ථක රාජ්‍ය තාන්ත්‍රික සබඳතා තුළින් ආර්ථික, ව්‍යවසායක, විද්‍යා හා තාක්ෂණ, නවෝත්පාදන මෙන්ම සංස්කෘතික, දේශපාලන හා ආර්ථික ක්ෂේත්‍රවල ශක්තිමත් සබඳතා ගොඩනගා ගනිමින් දෙරට අතර රාජ්‍ය තාන්ත්‍රික සබඳතා තවදුරටත් ශක්තිමත් කර ගැනීමට අවකාශය නිර්මාණය වනු ඇත."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "26 වැනි",
          "label": "ORDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "ලිතුවේනියාව",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "වසර 2022",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "26 වැනි",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකා සමාජවාදී ජනරජය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ලිතුවේනියා ජනරජය",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ලිතුවේනියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "සෝවියට්",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "සෝවියට්",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ලිතුවේනියානු",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "සෝවියට් සංගමය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "1940-1941",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "1944-1990",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "රුසියානු සමූහාණ්ඩුව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "1990 මාර්තු 11",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "රජයේ",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ලිතුවේනියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ලිතුවේනියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "1996 අගෝස්තු 20",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "රජයේ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "යුරෝපා සංගමය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ලිතුවේනියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ විදේශ කටයුතු අමාත්‍යාංශය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඇල්ෆ්‍රඩ් කුලේන්ද්‍රන්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ලිතුවේනියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ස්වීඩනය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "1996 සිට 1999 දක්වා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ලිතුවේනියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "මොහොමඩ් අන්සාර් ජබීර්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ලිතුවේනියානු රජය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "පළමුවන",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ලිතුවේනියානු කොන්සල්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "2014",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ලිතුවේනියානු තානාපති කාර්යාලය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ලිතුවේනියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ලිතුවේනියානු විදේශ කටයුතු අමාත්යාංශය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ලිතුවේනියානු කොන්සල් කාර්යාලය",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "ආර්.එම්. මන්නිවන්නන්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "2015 වර්ෂය",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "සුප්‍රීම් ග්ලෝබල් සමූහය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "තලත් කෙල්ප්සා",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "පළමුවන",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ලිතුවේනියානු",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ලිතුවේනියා රජය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජුලියස් ප්‍රනෙවිකියස්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ලිතුවේනියානු විදේශ කටයුතු අමාත්‍යාංශය ශ්‍රී ලංකාවට",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "පසුගිය වසර 26 තුළ",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ලිතුවේනියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "දෙක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ලිතුවේනියා ජනරජය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "යුරෝපා සංගමය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ විදේශ කටයුතු අමාත්‍යාංශය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ලිතුවේනියානු",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ලිතුවේනියානු",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ලිතුවේනියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලාංකික",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලාංකික",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලාංකිකයන්",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "අවුරුදු 26 යි",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "දෙක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "லிதுவேனியாவுடனான இராஜதந்திர உறவுகளின் 26வது ஆண்டு நிறைவை இலங்கை கொண்டாடுகிறது",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "2022 ஆம் ஆண்டு இலங்கை சோசலிசக் குடியரசுக்கும் லிதுவேனியா குடியரசுக்கும் இடையே இருதரப்பு உறவுகளை உத்தியோகபூர்வமாக நிறுவியதன் 26வது ஆண்டு நிறைவைக் குறிக்கிறது.",
        "லிதுவேனியா ஒரு முன்னாள் சோவியத் குடியரசு (சோவியத் லிதுவேனியா அல்லது லிதுவேனியன் சோவியத் சோசலிஸ்ட் குடியரசு என்றும் அழைக்கப்படுகிறது, இது 1940-1941 மற்றும் 1944-1990 க்கு இடையில் சோவியத் ஒன்றியத்தின் தொகுதி குடியரசுகளில் ஒன்றாகும்) 11 மார்ச் 1990 இல் ரஷ்ய கூட்டமைப்பிலிருந்து பிரிந்து சுதந்திரமானது. ஜனநாயக அரசு.",
        "அப்போதிருந்து, லிதுவேனியா உலகெங்கிலும் உள்ள பல நாடுகளுடன் நட்பு மற்றும் சுதந்திரமான வெளிநாட்டு உறவுகளை உருவாக்க முயன்றது. லிதுவேனியா 20 ஆகஸ்ட் 1996 இல் இலங்கையுடன் உத்தியோகபூர்வ வெளிநாட்டு உறவுகளை ஏற்படுத்தியது, அதே நேரத்தில் தன்னை ஒரு சுதந்திர நாடாக நிறுவியது, ஐரோப்பிய ஒன்றியத்தின் நட்பு உறுப்பு அரசாங்கமாக பணியாற்றியது.",
        "இலங்கைக்கும் லிதுவேனியாவுக்கும் இடையில் இராஜதந்திர உறவுகள் ஆரம்பிக்கப்பட்டதிலிருந்து, இலங்கையின் வெளிவிவகார அமைச்சு இலங்கையின் சிறந்த இராஜதந்திரி அல்பிரட் குலேந்திரனை இலங்கையின் தூதுவராக லிதுவேனியாவுடன் தூதுவராக நியமித்தது. அவர் 1996 முதல் 1999 வரை ஸ்வீடனுக்கான இலங்கையின் தூதுவராக இருந்தார், அதே நேரத்தில் அவர் லிதுவேனியாவுக்கான இலங்கையின் துணைத் தூதராக பணியாற்றினார்.",
        "மொஹமட் அன்சார் ஜாபிர் 1996 முதல் 2014 வரை இலங்கையின் முதல் லிதுவேனியன் தூதராக லிதுவேனிய அரசாங்கத்தால் நியமிக்கப்பட்டார். அவரது அகால மரணத்தைத் தொடர்ந்து, இலங்கையில் உள்ள லிதுவேனியன் தூதரகம் இலங்கையில் உள்ள தனது அலுவலகத்தை தற்காலிகமாக மூடியது.",
        "லிதுவேனியா அரசாங்கத்தின் முன் பரிந்துரை மற்றும் ஒப்புதலுடன், குறுகிய காலத்தில், லிதுவேனிய வெளியுறவு அமைச்சகம், ஆர்.எம். மன்னிவண்ணன் 2015 ஆம் ஆண்டு. இலங்கையின் புகழ்பெற்ற மற்றும் முன்னணி வர்த்தக நிறுவனமான சுப்ரீம் குளோபல் குழுமத்தின் தலைவராக உள்ளார்.",
        "Limonas Talat Kelpsa இலங்கைக்கான முதல் லிதுவேனியா தூதுவர், லிதுவேனியா அரசாங்கத்தால் நியமிக்கப்பட்டார். Julius Pranevičius தற்போது இலங்கைக்கான லிதுவேனிய வெளிவிவகார அமைச்சின் தூதுவராக உள்ளார்.",
        "கடந்த 26 வருடங்களாக இலங்கைக்கும் லிதுவேனியாவுக்கும் இடையிலான வெளிநாட்டு உறவுகள் வலுவாக வளர்ச்சியடைந்து வருகின்றன. சுற்றுலா, வர்த்தகம், உயர்கல்வி, தொழில்நுட்பம் ஆகிய துறைகளில் இரு நாடுகளும் குறிப்பிடத்தக்க முன்னேற்றம் கண்டுள்ளன. இலங்கையின் முன்னேற்றம் மற்றும் செழுமைக்காக சங்கம் எடுக்கும் முடிவுகளுக்கு அவர்கள் மிகவும் சாதகமான அணுகுமுறையுடன் மிகவும் சாதகமான பங்களிப்பை அளித்து வருகின்றனர்.",
        "இலங்கை தற்போது எதிர்நோக்கி வரும் பொருளாதார நெருக்கடியை உன்னிப்பாக அவதானித்து வரும் லிதுவேனியா குடியரசு, ஐரோப்பிய ஒன்றியத்துடன் இணைந்து இலங்கை மக்களுக்கு நிவாரணம் வழங்க நடவடிக்கை எடுத்து வருகிறது. மேலும், எதிர்வரும் காலங்களில், இலங்கையில் உள்ள லிதுவேனிய தூதரகங்கள் மற்றும் லிதுவேனிய தூதரகம், லிதுவேனிய சுற்றுலாப் பயணிகள் மத்தியில் நீண்ட கால விடுமுறை இடமாக இலங்கையை அறிமுகப்படுத்துவதன் மூலம் அதிக லிதுவேனிய சுற்றுலாப் பயணிகளை ஈர்க்கும் வகையில் இலங்கையின் வெளியுறவு அமைச்சகத்துடன் ஏற்பாடுகளைச் செய்து வருகின்றன.",
        "மேலும், லிதுவேனியா ஏற்கனவே இலங்கை தொழில்முனைவோர், உயர்கல்வி பெற விரும்பும் இலங்கை மாணவர்கள் மற்றும் வெளிநாட்டில் வேலை தேடும் இலங்கையர்களின் பிரபலமான இடமாக மாறியுள்ளது.",
        "26 ஆண்டுகால வெற்றிகரமான இராஜதந்திர உறவுகளின் மூலம், பொருளாதாரம், தொழில்முனைவு, அறிவியல் மற்றும் தொழில்நுட்பம், புத்தாக்கம் மற்றும் கலாச்சாரம், அரசியல் மற்றும் பொருளாதாரத் துறைகளில் வலுவான உறவுகளை உருவாக்குவதன் மூலம் இரு நாடுகளுக்கும் இடையிலான இராஜதந்திர உறவுகளை மேலும் வலுப்படுத்துவதற்கான இடம் உருவாக்கப்படும்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "இலங்கை",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "26 ஆம் தேதி",
          "label": "ORDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "லிதுவேனியா",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "2022 ஆம் ஆண்டு",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "26 ஆம் தேதி",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை சோசலிச குடியரசு",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "லிதுவேனியா குடியரசு",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "லிதுவேனியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சோவியத்",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "சோவியத்",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "லிதுவேனியன்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சோவியத் ஒன்றியம்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "1940-1941",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "1944-1990",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரஷ்ய கூட்டமைப்பு",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "11 மார்ச் 1990",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "நிலை",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "லிதுவேனியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "லிதுவேனியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "20 ஆகஸ்ட் 1996",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "நிலை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஐரோப்பிய ஒன்றியம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "லிதுவேனியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கையின் வெளிவிவகார அமைச்சு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆல்பிரட் குலேந்திரன்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "லிதுவேனியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஸ்வீடன்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "1996 முதல் 1999 வரை",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "லிதுவேனியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "முகமது அன்சார் ஜாபிர்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "லிதுவேனியன் அரசாங்கம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "முதலில்",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "லிதுவேனியன் தூதர்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "2014",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "லிதுவேனியன் தூதரகம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "லிதுவேனியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "லிதுவேனிய வெளியுறவு அமைச்சகம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "லிதுவேனியன் தூதரகம்",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆர்.எம். மன்னிவண்ணன்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "2015 ஆம் ஆண்டு",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "உச்ச குளோபல் குழு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "தலத் கெல்ப்சா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "முதலில்",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "லிதுவேனியன்",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "லிதுவேனியா அரசு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜூலியஸ் பிரனேவிசியஸ்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கைக்கான லிதுவேனிய வெளியுறவு அமைச்சகம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "கடந்த 26 ஆண்டுகளாக",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "லிதுவேனியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இரண்டு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "லிதுவேனியா குடியரசு",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஐரோப்பிய ஒன்றியம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கையின் வெளிவிவகார அமைச்சு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "லிதுவேனியன்",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "லிதுவேனியன்",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "லிதுவேனியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கையர்கள்",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "26 ஆண்டுகள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இரண்டு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}