{
  "newspaper_id": "ada-lk",
  "url": "https://www.ada.lk/sports/පොදුරාජ්‍ය-මණ්ඩලයීය-තරගාවලියට-ගිය-ලංකාවේ-5කට-කොවිඩ්/9-395831",
  "time_ut": 1659002433,
  "original_lang": "si",
  "original_title": "පොදුරාජ්‍ය මණ්ඩලයීය තරගාවලියට ගිය ලංකාවේ 5කට කොවිඩ්",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "5 Sri Lankans who went to the Commonwealth tournament have Covid",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "Four players and a coach of the Sri Lankan team who left for the United Kingdom to join the Commonwealth tournament have tested positive for Covid. Two gymnasts, a gymnastics coach and a men's and women's basketball player are among those who have tested positive for Covid.",
        "These players and coaches have been given the opportunity to stay in an isolated hotel arranged by the Commonwealth Games organisers. They are recovering under medical supervision."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "5",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "Sri Lankans",
          "label": "NORP"
        },
        {
          "text": "Commonwealth",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "Covid",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Four",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lankan",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "the United Kingdom",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Commonwealth",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Covid",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Two",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Covid",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Commonwealth Games",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "පොදුරාජ්‍ය මණ්ඩලයීය තරගාවලියට ගිය ලංකාවේ 5කට කොවිඩ්",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "පොදුරාජ්‍ය මණ්ඩලීය තරගාවලියට එක්වීමට එක්සත් රාජධානිය බලා පිටත්ව ගිය ශ්‍රී ලංකා කණ්ඩායමේ ක්‍රීඩකයන් 4ක් හා පුහුණුකරුවෙක් කොවිඩ් ධනාත්මක වී තිබේ. මෙසේ කොවිඩ් ධනාත්මක වූවන් අතර ජිම්නාස්ටික් ක්‍රීඩකයින් දෙදෙනෙකු, ජිම්නාස්ටික් පුහුණුකරුවෙකු සහ පිරිමි සහ කාන්තා පැසිපන්දු ක්‍රීඩක ක්‍රීඩිකාවක්ද වෙයි.",
        "මෙම ක්‍රීඩකයන් හා පුහුණුකරුරට පොදුරාජ්‍ය මණ්ඩලීය ක්‍රීඩා සංවිධායකයින් විසින් සංවිධානය කරන ලද හුදකලා හෝටලයක නවාතැන්ප්‍ ගැනීමට අවස්ථාව ලබා දී තිබේ. ඔවුන් වෛද්‍ය අධීක්ෂණය යටතේ සුව වෙමින් පසුවෙයි."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "5",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "ශ්‍රී ලාංකිකයන්",
          "label": "NORP"
        },
        {
          "text": "පොදු රාජ්ය මණ්ඩලය",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "කොවිඩ්",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "හතර",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලාංකික",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "එක්සත් රාජධානිය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "පොදු රාජ්ය මණ්ඩලය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "කොවිඩ්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "දෙක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "කොවිඩ්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "පොදුරාජ්‍ය මණ්ඩලීය ක්‍රීඩා උළෙල",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "காமன்வெல்த் போட்டிக்கு சென்ற 5 இலங்கையர்களுக்கு கோவிட் தொற்று உள்ளது",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "பொதுநலவாய போட்டியில் இணைந்து கொள்வதற்காக ஐக்கிய இராச்சியம் சென்ற இலங்கை அணியின் நான்கு வீரர்கள் மற்றும் பயிற்சியாளர் ஒருவருக்கு கொவிட் தொற்று உறுதி செய்யப்பட்டுள்ளது. இரண்டு ஜிம்னாஸ்ட்கள், ஒரு ஜிம்னாஸ்டிக்ஸ் பயிற்சியாளர் மற்றும் ஒரு ஆண்கள் மற்றும் பெண்கள் கூடைப்பந்து வீரர் ஆகியோர் கோவிட் க்கு நேர்மறை சோதனை செய்தவர்களில் அடங்குவர்.",
        "இந்த வீரர்கள் மற்றும் பயிற்சியாளர்கள் காமன்வெல்த் விளையாட்டு போட்டி அமைப்பாளர்களால் ஏற்பாடு செய்யப்பட்ட தனிமைப்படுத்தப்பட்ட ஹோட்டலில் தங்குவதற்கு வாய்ப்பு வழங்கப்பட்டுள்ளது. மருத்துவக் கண்காணிப்பில் அவர்கள் குணமடைந்து வருகின்றனர்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "5",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "இலங்கையர்கள்",
          "label": "NORP"
        },
        {
          "text": "காமன்வெல்த்",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "கோவிட்",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "நான்கு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஐக்கிய இராச்சியம்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "காமன்வெல்த்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "கோவிட்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இரண்டு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "கோவிட்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "காமன்வெல்த் விளையாட்டு",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}