{
  "newspaper_id": "economy-next-com",
  "url": "https://economynext.com/sri-lanka-to-make-income-tax-files-compulsory-99180/",
  "time_ut": 1661847000,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Sri Lanka to make income tax files compulsory",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Sri Lanka to make income tax files compulsory",
      "author": "",
      "body_lines": [
        "ECONOMYNEXT – Sri Lanka will make income tax registration compulsory for everyone above 18 years, President Ranil Wickremesinghe is presenting a revised a budget.",
        "Sri Lanka is trying to raise taxes and reduce the deficit, expanding the state sector steeply since 2005 under the Rata Perata framework and seeing higher monetary instability under flexible inflation targeting.",
        "Sri Lanka will also cut the retirement age of state workers back to 60 years from 65."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Sri Lanka",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "above 18 years",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "2005",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "60 years",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "ශ්‍රී ලංකාව ආදායම් බදු ලිපිගොනු අනිවාර්ය කරයි",
      "author": "",
      "body_lines": [
        "ECONOMYNEXT – ශ්‍රී ලංකාව අවුරුදු 18ට වැඩි සියලු දෙනාටම ආදායම් බදු ලියාපදිංචි කිරීම අනිවාර්ය කරන බව ජනාධිපති රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතා විසින් සංශෝධිත අයවැයක් ඉදිරිපත් කරයි.",
        "රට පෙරට රාමුව යටතේ 2005 සිට රාජ්‍ය අංශය දැඩි ලෙස ව්‍යාප්ත කරමින් සහ නම්‍යශීලී උද්ධමන ඉලක්ක යටතේ ඉහළ මූල්‍ය අස්ථාවරත්වයක් දකිමින් ශ්‍රී ලංකාව බදු ඉහළ නැංවීමට සහ හිඟය අඩු කිරීමට උත්සාහ කරයි.",
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකාව ද රාජ්‍ය සේවකයන්ගේ විශ්‍රාම වයස අවුරුදු 65 සිට අවුරුදු 60 දක්වා අඩු කරනු ඇත."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "අවුරුදු 18 ට වැඩි",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "2005",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "අවුරුදු 60 යි",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "வருமான வரிக் கோப்புகளை இலங்கை கட்டாயமாக்க வேண்டும்",
      "author": "",
      "body_lines": [
        "ECONOMYNEXT – இலங்கையில் 18 வயதுக்கு மேற்பட்ட அனைவருக்கும் வருமான வரி பதிவு கட்டாயமாக்கப்படும், ஜனாதிபதி ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க திருத்தப்பட்ட வரவு செலவுத் திட்டத்தை சமர்ப்பிக்கிறார்.",
        "இலங்கை வரிகளை உயர்த்தி பற்றாக்குறையை குறைக்க முயற்சிக்கிறது, 2005 ஆம் ஆண்டு முதல் ரத பெரட்டா கட்டமைப்பின் கீழ் அரச துறையை செங்குத்தாக விரிவுபடுத்துகிறது மற்றும் நெகிழ்வான பணவீக்க இலக்கின் கீழ் அதிக பண உறுதியற்ற தன்மையைக் காண்கிறது.",
        "இலங்கை அரசு ஊழியர்களின் ஓய்வூதிய வயதை 65ல் இருந்து 60 ஆக குறைக்கும்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "இலங்கை",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "18 வயதுக்கு மேல்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "2005",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "60 ஆண்டுகள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}