{
  "newspaper_id": "lankadeepa-lk",
  "url": "https://www.lankadeepa.lk/latest_news/උසස්-පෙළ-ප්‍රතිඵල-නිකුත්-වෙයි/1-618879",
  "time_ut": 1661684309,
  "original_lang": "si",
  "original_title": "උසස් පෙළ ප්‍රතිඵල නිකුත් වෙයි",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "A-level results are released",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "The Commissioner General of Examinations Mr. L. M. D. Dharmasena said that the results of the General Certificate of Education A Level 2021 examination were released this afternoon.",
        "The Commissioner General of Examinations also says that the examination results can be obtained through the websites www.doenets.lk and www.results.exams.gov.lk of the examination department.",
        "The Commissioner General of Examinations also stated that 236035 school applicants and 36647 private applicants appeared for this year's advanced level examination, totaling 272682 applicants."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "L. M. D. Dharmasena",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the General Certificate of Education A Level",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "2021",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "this afternoon",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "www.doenets.lk",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "www.results.exams.gov.lk",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "236035",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "36647",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "year",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "272682",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "උසස් පෙළ ප්‍රතිඵල නිකුත් වෙයි",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "අධ්‍යාපන පොදු සහතික පත්‍ර උසස් පෙළ 2021 විභාගයේ ප්‍රතිඵල අද පස්වරුවේ නිකුත් කළ බව විභාග කොමසාරිස් ජනරාල් එල්.එම්.ඩී.ධර්මසේන මහතා පවසයි.",
        "එම විභාග ප්‍රතිඵල විභාග දෙපාර්තමේන්තුවේ www.doenets.lk සහ  www.results.exams.gov.lk යන වෙබ් අඩවි මගින් ලබාගත හැකි බව ද විභාග කොමසාරිස් ජනරාල්වරයා කියයි.",
        "මෙවර උසස් පෙළ විභාගයට පාසල් අයදුම්කරුවන් 236035 දෙනකු සහ පෞද්ගලික අයදුම්කරුවන් 36647 වශයෙන් මුළු අයදුම්කරුවන් 272682 පෙනී සිටි බව ද විභාග කොමසාරිස් ජනරාල්වරයා සඳහන් කරයි."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "L. M. D. ධර්මසේන",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "උසස් අධ්‍යාපන පොදු සහතිකය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "2021",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "අද පස්වරුවේ",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "www.doenets.lk",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "www.results.exams.gov.lk",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "236035",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "36647",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "වර්ෂය",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "272682",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "ஏ-நிலை முடிவுகள் வெளியாகியுள்ளன",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "கல்விப் பொதுத்தராதர உயர்தர 2021 பரீட்சையின் பெறுபேறுகள் இன்று பிற்பகல் வெளியிடப்பட்டதாக பரீட்சைகள் ஆணையாளர் நாயகம் திரு.எல்.எம்.டி.தர்மசேன தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "பரீட்சை பெறுபேறுகளை பரீட்சை திணைக்களத்தின் www.doenets.lk மற்றும் www.results.exams.gov.lk ஆகிய இணையத்தளங்களில் பெற்றுக்கொள்ள முடியும் எனவும் பரீட்சைகள் ஆணையாளர் நாயகம் மேலும் தெரிவித்துள்ளார்.",
        "இவ்வருட உயர்தரப் பரீட்சைக்கு 236035 பாடசாலை விண்ணப்பதாரர்களும் 36647 தனியார் விண்ணப்பதாரர்களும் தோற்றியதாகவும் மொத்தமாக 272682 விண்ணப்பதாரர்கள் விண்ணப்பித்துள்ளதாகவும் பரீட்சைகள் ஆணையாளர் நாயகம் தெரிவித்தார்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "எல்.எம்.டி.தர்மசேன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "கல்வி பொதுச் சான்றிதழ் A நிலை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "2021",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று மதியம்",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "www.doenets.lk",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "www.results.exams.gov.lk",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "236035",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "36647",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆண்டு",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "272682",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}