{
  "newspaper_id": "economy-next-com",
  "url": "https://economynext.com/japan-seeks-to-organise-sri-lanka-creditors-meeting-on-debt-crisis-reuters-99050/",
  "time_ut": 1661493480,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Japan seeks to organise Sri Lanka creditors’ meeting on debt crisis: Reuters",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Japan seeks to organise Sri Lanka creditors’ meeting on debt crisis: Reuters",
      "author": "",
      "body_lines": [
        "ECONOMYNEXT – Japan is seeking to organise a Sri Lanka creditors’ conference in a bid to solve the South Asian nation’s debt crisis, Reuters reported, noting however that uncertainties cloud the outlook for any talks.",
        "Citing sources with knowledge of the planning, Reuters reported on Friday August 27 that Tokyo is open to hosting talks among all the creditor nations aimed at lifting Colombo from its worst debt crisis since independence.",
        "However, it is not clear whether top creditor China would join and a lack of clarity remains about Sri Lanka’s finances, the news agency quoted one source as saying.",
        "Japan would be willing to chair such a meeting with China if that would speed up the process for addressing Sri Lanka’s debt, estimated at 6.2 billion US dollars on a bilateral basis at the end of 2020, the source had said.",
        "President Ranil Wickremesinghe had told the Tokyo-based Nikkei Asia on Thursday August 24 that Sri Lanka would like China to dramatically change its stance on debt relief. The financial news website said Wickremesinghe had conceded that reaching a deal with China will be no simple task.",
        "Sri Lanka president wants China to dramatically change stance on debt relief",
        "In an earlier interview given to Reuters, Wickremesinghe had said that Sri Lanka would ask Japan to invite the main creditor nations to talks on restructuring bilateral debts. The agency quoted him as saying he would discuss the issue with Prime Minister Fumio Kishida in Tokyo next month, when he is expected to attend the funeral of the assassinated former premier Shinzo Abe.",
        "Tokyo, Sri Lanka’s number two bilateral creditor, has a stake in rescuing the island nation, not just to recoup its three billion dollars in loans but also its diplomatic interest in checking China’s growing presence in the region, Reuters reported.",
        "Meanwhile, an International Monetary Fund (IMF) team met Wickremesinghe on Wednesday to discuss a bailout, including restructuring 29 billion dollars in debt, as Colombo seeks a three billion dollar IMF aid programme.",
        "The president met the same day with Japan’s ambassador and, according to the source cited by Reuters, Tokyo believes a new “platform” is needed to pull creditors together.",
        "“Sri Lanka is running out of time since it defaulted on its debt. The priority is for creditor nations to agree on an effective scheme,” one source said.",
        "“Japan is keen to move this forward. But it’s not something Japan alone can raise its hand and push through,” said the source, adding that the cooperation of other nations was crucial.",
        "The source had told Reuters that getting Beijing’s cooperation on a debt restructuring was complicated by factors such as a large number of lenders and that China was baulking at taking a “haircut” on its loans and at reducing Colombo’s debt burden.",
        "A Chinese foreign ministry spokesman told Reuters that Beijing was “willing to stand with relevant countries and international financial institutions and continue to play a positive role in helping Sri Lanka respond to its present difficulties, relieve its debt burden and realise sustainable development.”",
        "Japan hopes to see a new debt restructuring framework resembling one set up by the Group of 20 big economies targeting low-income countries, reported Reuters. Sri Lanka does not fall under this “common framework” because it is classified as a middle-income emerging country.",
        "“It must be a platform where all creditor nations participate” to ensure they all shoulder a fair share in waiving debt, another source said. The third said, “Until these conditions are met, it would be difficult for any talks to succeed.”",
        "The common framework, launched by the G20 and the Paris Club of rich creditor nations in 2020, provides debt relief mainly through extension in debt-payment deadlines and reduction in interest payments.",
        "Some people involved think an initial creditors’ meeting could be held in September, but one source said it would “take a little while, possibly several months”.",
        "Restructuring talks are only possible after the IMF scrutinises Sri Lanka’s debt, the sources told the agency. (Colombo/Aug26/2022)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Japan",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "Sri Lanka",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "Reuters",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Japan",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "South Asian",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Reuters",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Reuters",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Friday August 27",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Tokyo",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Colombo",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "China",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "one",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Japan",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "China",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "6.2 billion US dollars",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "the end of 2020",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Tokyo",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Nikkei Asia",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Thursday August 24",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "China",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "China",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "China",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Reuters",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Japan",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Fumio Kishida",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Tokyo",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "next month",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Shinzo Abe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Tokyo",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka’s",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "number two",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "three billion dollars",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "China",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Reuters",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "International Monetary Fund",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Wednesday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "29 billion dollars",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "Colombo",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "three billion dollar",
            "label": "MONEY"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the same day",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Japan",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Reuters",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Tokyo",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "one",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Japan",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Japan",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Reuters",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Beijing",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "China",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Colombo",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Chinese",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Reuters",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Beijing",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Japan",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Group",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "20",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Reuters",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "third",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "G20",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Paris Club",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "2020",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "September",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "one",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "several months",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "ණය අර්බුදය පිළිබඳ ශ්‍රී ලංකා ණය හිමියන්ගේ රැස්වීම සංවිධානය කිරීමට ජපානය උත්සාහ කරයි: රොයිටර්",
      "author": "",
      "body_lines": [
        "ECONOMYNEXT - දකුණු ආසියානු ජාතියේ ණය අර්බුදය විසඳීම සඳහා ජපානය ශ්‍රී ලංකා ණය හිමියන්ගේ සමුළුවක් සංවිධානය කිරීමට උත්සාහ කරන බව රොයිටර් වාර්තා කරයි, කෙසේ වෙතත් අවිනිශ්චිතතාවයන් ඕනෑම සාකච්ඡාවක් සඳහා අපේක්ෂාවන් වළක්වයි.",
        "සැලසුම් කිරීම පිළිබඳ දැනුමක් ඇති මූලාශ්‍ර උපුටා දක්වමින්, අගෝස්තු 27 සිකුරාදා රොයිටර් වාර්තා කළේ, නිදහසින් පසු කොළඹ එහි දරුණුතම නය අර්බුදයෙන් මුදා ගැනීම ඉලක්ක කරගත් සියලුම ණය දෙන ජාතීන් අතර සාකච්ඡා පැවැත්වීමට ටෝකියෝ විවෘතව සිටින බවයි.",
        "කෙසේ වෙතත්, ප්‍රමුඛ පෙළේ ණයහිමියා වන චීනය ඊට සම්බන්ධ වන්නේද යන්න පැහැදිලි නැති අතර ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ මූල්‍ය කටයුතු පිළිබඳ පැහැදිලිකමක් නොමැති බව එක් මූලාශ්‍රයක් උපුටා දක්වමින් ප්‍රවෘත්ති ඒජන්සිය පවසයි.",
        "2020 අවසානයේ දී ද්විපාර්ශ්වික පදනමින් ඩොලර් බිලියන 6.2 ක් ලෙස ඇස්තමේන්තු කර ඇති ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ ණය පියවීමේ ක්‍රියාවලිය වේගවත් කරන්නේ නම්, චීනය සමඟ එවැනි රැස්වීමක මුලසුන දැරීමට ජපානය කැමැත්තෙන් සිටින බව මූලාශ්‍රය පවසයි.",
        "නය සහන සම්බන්ධයෙන් චීනය සිය ස්ථාවරය නාටකාකාර ලෙස වෙනස් කරනවාට ශ්‍රී ලංකාව කැමති බව ජනාධිපති රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතා අගෝස්තු 24 බ්‍රහස්පතින්දා ටෝකියෝ හි නිකේ ඒෂියා වෙත පවසා තිබුණි. චීනය සමඟ ගිවිසුමකට එළැඹීම සරල කාර්යයක් නොවන බව වික්‍රමසිංහ පිළිගෙන ඇති බව මූල්‍ය පුවත් වෙබ් අඩවිය පවසයි.",
        "ණය සහන පිළිබඳ ස්ථාවරය නාටකාකාර ලෙස වෙනස් කිරීමට චීනයට ශ්‍රී ලංකා ජනාධිපතිවරයාට අවශ්‍යයි",
        "මීට පෙර රොයිටර් පුවත් සේවයට ලබා දුන් සම්මුඛ සාකච්ඡාවකදී වික්‍රමසිංහ පවසා තිබුණේ ද්විපාර්ශ්වික ණය ප්‍රතිව්‍යුහගත කිරීම පිළිබඳ සාකච්ඡා සඳහා ප්‍රධාන ණය දෙන ජාතීන්ට ආරාධනා කරන ලෙස ශ්‍රී ලංකාව ජපානයෙන් ඉල්ලා සිටින බවයි. ඝාතනයට ලක් වූ හිටපු අගමැති ෂින්සෝ අබේගේ අවමංගල්‍ය උත්සවයට සහභාගී වීමට අපේක්ෂා කරන විට ලබන මාසයේ ටෝකියෝහිදී අගමැති ෆුමියෝ කිෂිඩා සමඟ ගැටලුව සාකච්ඡා කරන බව ඔහු පැවසූ බව ඒජන්සිය උපුටා දක්වයි.",
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ අංක දෙක ද්විපාර්ශ්වික ණයහිමියා වන ටෝකියෝ, දූපත් ජාතිය ගලවා ගැනීමේ වගකීමක් ඇති අතර, එහි ඩොලර් බිලියන තුනක ණය ආපසු ලබා ගැනීමට පමණක් නොව, කලාපය තුළ චීනයේ වර්ධනය වන පැවැත්ම පරීක්ෂා කිරීමට එහි රාජ්‍යතාන්ත්‍රික උනන්දුව ද ඇති බව රොයිටර් වාර්තා කරයි.",
        "මේ අතර, කොළඹ ඩොලර් බිලියන තුනක ජාත්‍යන්තර මූල්‍ය අරමුදලේ ආධාර වැඩසටහනක් අපේක්ෂා කරන බැවින්, ඩොලර් බිලියන 29 ක නය ප්‍රතිව්‍යුහගත කිරීම ඇතුළු ඇපදීමක් ගැන සාකච්ඡා කිරීමට ජාත්‍යන්තර මූල්‍ය අරමුදල (IMF) කණ්ඩායමක් බදාදා වික්‍රමසිංහ හමුවිය.",
        "ජනාධිපතිවරයා එදිනම ජපාන තානාපතිවරයා හමුවූ අතර, රොයිටර් විසින් උපුටා දක්වන ලද මූලාශ්‍රයට අනුව, ණයහිමියන් එකතු කර ගැනීමට නව “වේදිකාවක්” අවශ්‍ය බව ටෝකියෝ විශ්වාස කරයි.",
        "“ශ්‍රී ලංකාව සිය ණය ගෙවීම පැහැර හැරීම නිසා කාලය අවසන් වෙමින් පවතී. ප්‍රමුඛතාවය වන්නේ ණය දෙන ජාතීන් ඵලදායී යෝජනා ක්‍රමයක් සඳහා එකඟ වීමයි,” එක් මූලාශ්‍රයක් පැවසීය.",
        "“ජපානය මෙය ඉදිරියට ගෙන යාමට උනන්දු වෙයි. නමුත් එය ජපානයට පමණක් අත ඔසවා තල්ලු කළ හැකි දෙයක් නොවේ, ”මූලාශ්‍රය පැවසුවේ අනෙකුත් ජාතීන්ගේ සහයෝගීතාවය තීරණාත්මක බවයි.",
        "නය ප්‍රතිව්‍යුහගත කිරීම සඳහා බීජිනයේ සහයෝගීතාවය ලබා ගැනීම ණය දෙන්නන් විශාල සංඛ්‍යාවක් වැනි සාධක මගින් සංකීර්ණ වී ඇති බවත් චීනය සිය නය මත “කොණ්ඩා කැපීමක්” කිරීමට සහ කොලඹ ණය බර අඩු කර ගැනීමට පොලඹවන බවත් මූලාශ්‍රය රොයිටර් පුවත් සේවයට පවසා තිබුණි.",
        "චීන විදේශ අමාත්‍යාංශයේ ප්‍රකාශකයෙකු රොයිටර් පුවත් සේවයට පැවසුවේ, “අදාළ රටවල් සහ ජාත්‍යන්තර මූල්‍ය ආයතන සමඟ නැගී සිටීමටත්, ශ්‍රී ලංකාවට එහි වර්තමාන දුෂ්කරතාවලට ප්‍රතිචාර දැක්වීමටත්, එහි ණය බරින් මිදීමට සහ තිරසාර සංවර්ධනයක් සාක්ෂාත් කර ගැනීමටත් උපකාර කිරීමේදී ධනාත්මක කාර්යභාරයක් ඉටු කිරීමට බීජිනය කැමැත්තෙන් සිටින” බවයි.",
        "අඩු ආදායම්ලාභී රටවල් ඉලක්ක කර ගනිමින් විශාල ආර්ථිකයන් 20 ක කණ්ඩායම විසින් පිහිටුවන ලද නව ණය ප්‍රතිව්‍යුහගත කිරීමේ රාමුවක් දැකීමට ජපානය බලාපොරොත්තු වන බව රොයිටර් පුවත් සේවය වාර්තා කරයි. ශ්‍රී ලංකාව මෙම “පොදු රාමුවට” නොවැටෙන්නේ එය මැදි ආදායම් ලබන රටක් ලෙස වර්ගීකරණය කර ඇති බැවිනි.",
        "“එය සියලුම ණය දෙන ජාතීන් සහභාගී වන වේදිකාවක් විය යුතුය” ඔවුන් සියල්ලන්ම ණය අත්හැරීමේ සාධාරණ කොටසකට උර දෙන බව සහතික කිරීම සඳහා, තවත් මූලාශ්‍රයක් පැවසීය. තුන්වැන්නා පැවසුවේ, \"මෙම කොන්දේසි සපුරාලන තුරු, ඕනෑම සාකච්ඡාවක් සාර්ථක වීමට අපහසු වනු ඇත.\"",
        "2020 දී G20 සහ පොහොසත් ණය හිමියන්ගේ පැරිස් සමාජය විසින් දියත් කරන ලද පොදු රාමුව, ප්‍රධාන වශයෙන් ණය-ගෙවීමේ කාලසීමාවන් දීර්ඝ කිරීම සහ පොලී ගෙවීම් අඩු කිරීම හරහා ණය සහන සපයයි.",
        "ආරම්භක ණය හිමියන්ගේ රැස්වීමක් සැප්තැම්බර් මාසයේදී පැවැත්විය හැකි යැයි සම්බන්ධ වූ සමහර අය සිතන්නේ, නමුත් එක් මූලාශ්‍රයක් පැවසුවේ එයට “ටික කාලයක්, සමහරවිට මාස කිහිපයක් ගතවනු ඇති” බවයි.",
        "ප්‍රතිව්‍යුහගත කිරීමේ සාකච්ඡා කළ හැක්කේ ජාත්‍යන්තර මූල්‍ය අරමුදල ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ ණය පිරික්සීමෙන් පසුව පමණක් බව මූලාශ්‍ර ඒජන්සියට පැවසීය. (කොළඹ/අගෝස්තු26/2022)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ජපානය",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "රොයිටර්",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ජපානය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "දකුණු ආසියානු",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "රොයිටර්",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "රොයිටර්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "අගෝස්තු 27 සිකුරාදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ටෝකියෝ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "කොළඹ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "චීනය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "එක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ජපානය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "චීනය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඩොලර් බිලියන 6.2 කි",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "2020 අවසානයේ",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ටෝකියෝ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Nikkei Asia",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "අගෝස්තු 24 බ්‍රහස්පතින්දා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "චීනය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "චීනය",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "චීනය",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "රොයිටර්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජපානය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Fumio Kishida",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ටෝකියෝ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ලබන මාසයේ",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Shinzo Abe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ටෝකියෝ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "අංක දෙක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඩොලර් බිලියන තුනක්",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "චීනය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "රොයිටර්",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ජාත්යන්තර මූල්ය අරමුදල",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "බදාදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඩොලර් බිලියන 29 කි",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "කොළඹ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඩොලර් බිලියන තුනක්",
            "label": "MONEY"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "එදිනම",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජපානය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "රොයිටර්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ටෝකියෝ",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "එක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ජපානය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජපානය",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "රොයිටර්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "බීජිං",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "චීනය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "කොළඹ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "චීන",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "රොයිටර්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "බීජිං",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ජපානය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "සමූහය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "20",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "රොයිටර්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "තෙවන",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "G20",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "පැරිස් සමාජය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "2020",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "සැප්තැම්බර්",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "එක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "මාස කිහිපයක්",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "கடன் நெருக்கடி தொடர்பாக இலங்கை கடனாளர்களின் கூட்டத்தை ஏற்பாடு செய்ய ஜப்பான் முயல்கிறது: ராய்ட்டர்ஸ்",
      "author": "",
      "body_lines": [
        "ECONOMYNEXT - தெற்காசிய நாட்டின் கடன் நெருக்கடியைத் தீர்க்கும் முயற்சியில் ஜப்பான் இலங்கை கடன் வழங்குநர்கள் மாநாட்டை ஏற்பாடு செய்ய முயல்கிறது, இருப்பினும் நிச்சயமற்ற தன்மைகள் எந்தவொரு பேச்சுக்களுக்கான கண்ணோட்டத்தையும் மறைக்கின்றன என்று ராய்ட்டர்ஸ் தெரிவித்துள்ளது.",
        "திட்டமிடல் பற்றிய அறிவுள்ள ஆதாரங்களை மேற்கோள் காட்டி, ராய்ட்டர்ஸ் ஆகஸ்ட் 27 வெள்ளியன்று, சுதந்திரத்திற்குப் பிறகு கொழும்பை அதன் மோசமான கடன் நெருக்கடியிலிருந்து மீட்டெடுக்கும் நோக்கில் அனைத்து கடன் வழங்கும் நாடுகளுக்கும் இடையே பேச்சுக்களை நடத்துவதற்கு டோக்கியோ திறந்திருப்பதாக அறிவித்தது.",
        "எவ்வாறாயினும், உயர்மட்டக் கடன் வழங்குநரான சீனாவும் இணையுமா என்பது தெளிவாகத் தெரியவில்லை, மேலும் இலங்கையின் நிதி தொடர்பான தெளிவின்மை இன்னும் உள்ளது என்று ஒரு வட்டாரத்தை மேற்கோள்காட்டி செய்தி நிறுவனம் தெரிவித்துள்ளது.",
        "2020 ஆம் ஆண்டின் இறுதியில் இருதரப்பு அடிப்படையில் 6.2 பில்லியன் அமெரிக்க டொலர்கள் என மதிப்பிடப்பட்டுள்ள இலங்கையின் கடனை நிவர்த்தி செய்வதற்கான செயல்முறையை விரைவுபடுத்தினால், சீனாவுடனான அத்தகைய சந்திப்பிற்கு ஜப்பான் தலைமை தாங்கும் என்று அந்த வட்டாரம் தெரிவித்தது.",
        "ஜனாதிபதி ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க, ஆகஸ்ட் 24 வியாழன் அன்று டோக்கியோவை தளமாகக் கொண்ட நிக்கேய் ஏசியாவிடம், கடன் நிவாரணம் தொடர்பான தனது நிலைப்பாட்டை சீனா வியத்தகு முறையில் மாற்றிக்கொள்ள இலங்கை விரும்புவதாக தெரிவித்திருந்தார். சீனாவுடன் உடன்படிக்கையை எட்டுவது இலகுவான காரியம் அல்ல என விக்கிரமசிங்க ஒப்புக்கொண்டதாக நிதிச் செய்தி இணையத்தளம் தெரிவித்துள்ளது.",
        "கடன் நிவாரணம் தொடர்பான நிலைப்பாட்டை சீனா வியத்தகு முறையில் மாற்றிக்கொள்ள வேண்டுமென இலங்கை ஜனாதிபதி விரும்புகிறார்",
        "ராய்ட்டர்ஸுக்கு வழங்கிய முந்தைய நேர்காணலில், இருதரப்பு கடன்களை மறுசீரமைப்பது தொடர்பான பேச்சுவார்த்தைக்கு முக்கிய கடன் வழங்கும் நாடுகளை அழைக்குமாறு ஜப்பானை இலங்கை கேட்கும் என்று விக்கிரமசிங்க கூறியிருந்தார். படுகொலை செய்யப்பட்ட முன்னாள் பிரதமர் ஷின்சோ அபேயின் இறுதிச் சடங்கில் அவர் கலந்துகொள்வார் என்று எதிர்பார்க்கப்படும் போது, ​​அடுத்த மாதம் டோக்கியோவில் பிரதமர் ஃபுமியோ கிஷிடாவுடன் இந்த விவகாரம் குறித்து விவாதிப்பதாக அவர் கூறியதாக நிறுவனம் மேற்கோளிட்டுள்ளது.",
        "இலங்கையின் இரண்டாவது இருதரப்புக் கடன் வழங்குநரான டோக்கியோ, தீவு நாட்டை மீட்பதில் பங்கு கொண்டுள்ளது, அதன் மூன்று பில்லியன் டாலர் கடனைத் திரும்பப் பெறுவது மட்டுமல்லாமல், பிராந்தியத்தில் சீனாவின் வளர்ந்து வரும் இருப்பை சரிபார்க்கும் ராஜதந்திர ஆர்வமும் உள்ளது, ராய்ட்டர்ஸ் தெரிவித்துள்ளது.",
        "இதற்கிடையில், சர்வதேச நாணய நிதியத்தின் (IMF) குழு ஒன்று புதன்கிழமை விக்கிரமசிங்கவை சந்தித்து 29 பில்லியன் டாலர் கடனை மறுசீரமைப்பது உட்பட பிணை எடுப்பு பற்றி விவாதிக்க, கொழும்பு மூன்று பில்லியன் டாலர் IMF உதவித் திட்டத்தை நாடுகிறது.",
        "ஜனாதிபதி அதே நாளில் ஜப்பானின் தூதரை சந்தித்தார், மேலும் ராய்ட்டர்ஸ் மேற்கோள் காட்டிய ஆதாரத்தின்படி, கடன் வழங்குபவர்களை ஒன்றிணைக்க ஒரு புதிய \"தளம்\" தேவை என்று டோக்கியோ நம்புகிறது.",
        "“இலங்கை தனது கடனைத் திருப்பிச் செலுத்தாததால், நேரம் முடிவடைகிறது. கடன் வழங்கும் நாடுகள் ஒரு பயனுள்ள திட்டத்தை ஒப்புக்கொள்வதே முன்னுரிமை,” என்று ஒரு ஆதாரம் கூறியது.",
        "\"ஜப்பான் இதை முன்னோக்கி நகர்த்த ஆர்வமாக உள்ளது. ஆனால் இது ஜப்பானால் மட்டும் கையை உயர்த்தித் தள்ளக்கூடிய ஒன்றல்ல, ”என்று ஆதாரம் கூறியது, மற்ற நாடுகளின் ஒத்துழைப்பு முக்கியமானது.",
        "கடன் மறுசீரமைப்பிற்கு பெய்ஜிங்கின் ஒத்துழைப்பைப் பெறுவது அதிக எண்ணிக்கையிலான கடன் வழங்குபவர்கள் போன்ற காரணிகளால் சிக்கலானது என்றும், சீனா தனது கடன்களில் \"முடி வெட்டும்\" மற்றும் கொழும்பின் கடன் சுமையைக் குறைப்பதில் திணறுகிறது என்றும் ஆதாரம் ராய்ட்டர்ஸிடம் கூறியது.",
        "சீன வெளிவிவகார அமைச்சின் பேச்சாளர் ராய்ட்டர்ஸிடம், பெய்ஜிங், \"சம்பந்தப்பட்ட நாடுகள் மற்றும் சர்வதேச நிதி நிறுவனங்களுடன் நிற்கவும், இலங்கையின் தற்போதைய சிரமங்களுக்கு பதிலளிக்கவும், அதன் கடன் சுமையைக் குறைக்கவும் மற்றும் நிலையான வளர்ச்சியை உணரவும் உதவுவதில் தொடர்ந்து நேர்மறையான பங்கை வகிக்க தயாராக உள்ளது\" என்று கூறினார்.",
        "குறைந்த வருமானம் கொண்ட நாடுகளை இலக்காகக் கொண்டு 20 பெரிய பொருளாதாரங்களின் குழுவால் அமைக்கப்பட்ட ஒரு புதிய கடன் மறுசீரமைப்பு கட்டமைப்பை ஜப்பான் எதிர்பார்க்கிறது என்று ராய்ட்டர்ஸ் தெரிவித்துள்ளது. இலங்கை இந்த \"பொது கட்டமைப்பின்\" கீழ் வரவில்லை, ஏனெனில் அது நடுத்தர வருமானம் பெறும் நாடு என்று வகைப்படுத்தப்பட்டுள்ளது.",
        "\"அனைத்து கடன் வழங்கும் நாடுகளும் பங்கேற்கும் ஒரு தளமாக இது இருக்க வேண்டும்\" அவர்கள் அனைவரும் கடனைத் தள்ளுபடி செய்வதில் நியாயமான பங்கை ஏற்றுக்கொள்வதை உறுதிசெய்ய வேண்டும், மற்றொரு ஆதாரம் கூறியது. மூன்றாமவர், \"இந்த நிபந்தனைகள் நிறைவேற்றப்படும் வரை, எந்தப் பேச்சுவார்த்தையும் வெற்றி பெறுவது கடினம்\" என்றார்.",
        "G20 மற்றும் பணக்கார கடன் வழங்கும் நாடுகளின் பாரிஸ் கிளப் 2020 இல் தொடங்கப்பட்ட பொதுவான கட்டமைப்பானது, முக்கியமாக கடன்-கட்டண காலக்கெடுவை நீட்டித்தல் மற்றும் வட்டி செலுத்துதல்களைக் குறைப்பதன் மூலம் கடன் நிவாரணத்தை வழங்குகிறது.",
        "சம்பந்தப்பட்ட சிலர், செப்டம்பரில் ஒரு ஆரம்ப கடனாளிகளின் கூட்டம் நடத்தப்படலாம் என்று நினைக்கிறார்கள், ஆனால் ஒரு ஆதாரம் \"சிறிது நேரம், ஒருவேளை பல மாதங்கள் ஆகும்\" என்று கூறியது.",
        "இலங்கையின் கடனை சர்வதேச நாணய நிதியம் ஆராய்ந்த பின்னரே மறுசீரமைப்பு பேச்சுவார்த்தைகள் சாத்தியமாகும் என அந்த வட்டாரங்கள் தெரிவித்துள்ளன. (கொழும்பு/ஆகஸ்ட்26/2022)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ஜப்பான்",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "இலங்கை",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "ராய்ட்டர்ஸ்",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ஜப்பான்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "தெற்காசிய",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ராய்ட்டர்ஸ்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ராய்ட்டர்ஸ்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆகஸ்ட் 27 வெள்ளிக்கிழமை",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "டோக்கியோ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "கொழும்பு",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "சீனா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஒன்று",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஜப்பான்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சீனா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "6.2 பில்லியன் அமெரிக்க டாலர்கள்",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "2020 இறுதியில்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "டோக்கியோ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "நிக்கி ஆசியா",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆகஸ்ட் 24 வியாழன்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சீனா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "சீனா",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சீனா",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ராய்ட்டர்ஸ்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜப்பான்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Fumio Kishida",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "டோக்கியோ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "அடுத்த மாதம்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Shinzo Abe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "டோக்கியோ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கையின்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "எண் இரண்டு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "மூன்று பில்லியன் டாலர்கள்",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "சீனா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ராய்ட்டர்ஸ்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "சர்வதேச நாணய நிதியம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "புதன்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "29 பில்லியன் டாலர்கள்",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "கொழும்பு",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "மூன்று பில்லியன் டாலர்",
            "label": "MONEY"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "அதே நாள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜப்பான்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ராய்ட்டர்ஸ்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "டோக்கியோ",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஒன்று",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஜப்பான்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜப்பான்",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ராய்ட்டர்ஸ்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "பெய்ஜிங்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சீனா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "கொழும்பு",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "சீன",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ராய்ட்டர்ஸ்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "பெய்ஜிங்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஜப்பான்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "குழு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "20",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ராய்ட்டர்ஸ்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "மூன்றாவது",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "G20",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாரிஸ் கிளப்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "2020",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "செப்டம்பர்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஒன்று",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "பல மாதங்கள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}