{
  "newspaper_id": "ada-derana-lk",
  "url": "http://www.adaderana.lk/news/84496/sri-lanka-aims-to-cut-fiscal-deficit-in-budget-2023",
  "time_ut": 1661282760,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Sri Lanka aims to cut fiscal deficit in budget 2023",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Sri Lanka aims to cut fiscal deficit in budget 2023",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "Sri Lanka’s 2023 budget would aim to reduce the fiscal deficit to 6.8 per cent in 2023 from the projected 9.9 per cent in 2022, a senior Cabinet Minister said on Tuesday, ahead of the visit by the IMF delegation for a bailout package to the crisis-hit island nation.",
        "Sri Lanka is in the midst of an unprecedented economic crisis that has led to severe shortages of fuel and other essentials, leading to long serpentine queues in front of filling stations.",
        "“Sri Lanka is planning to cut the budget deficit to 6.8 per cent of gross domestic product in 2023 from an expected 9.9 per cent in 2022,” Bandula Gunawardena, the Cabinet spokesman and Minister of Mass Media said on Tuesday.",
        "“The Cabinet of ministers has approved a fiscal framework for 2023-2025. Sri Lanka is facing the worst fiscal crisis in its history,” he said.",
        "“We have to eventually bring down the deficit to 5 per cent of the GDP to manage debt, reduce money printing and have low inflation,” Gunawardena said.",
        "The deficit target was announced ahead of the visit by the IMF delegation which will arrive here tonight. They are to resume talks on reaching the staff level agreement between August 24 and 31.",
        "The government’s statistics office said on Monday that the overall rate of inflation as measured by the National Consumer Price Index on a year-on-year basis had gone up to 66.7 per cent in July over the 58.9 recorded in June.",
        "“This was mainly due to the higher price levels prevailing in both food and non-food groups. The food group increased to 82.5 in July 2022 from 75.8 in June 2022,” the release said.",
        "In its latest assessment, the World Bank has said that Sri Lanka has been ranked 5th with the highest food price inflation in the world. Sri Lanka is ranked behind Zimbabwe, Venezuela, and Turkey, while Lebanon leads the list.",
        "The World Bank said record high food prices have triggered a global crisis that will drive millions more into extreme poverty, magnifying hunger and malnutrition while threatening to erase hard-won gains in development.",
        "The war in Ukraine, supply chain disruptions, and the continued economic fallout of the covid-19 pandemic are reversing years of development gains and pushing food prices to all-time highs.",
        "Rising food prices have a greater impact on people in low- and middle-income countries since they spend a larger share of their income on food than people in high-income countries. This brief looks at rising food insecurity and World Bank responses to date."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Sri Lanka",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "2023",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka’s",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "2023",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "6.8 per cent",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "2023",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "9.9 per cent",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "2022",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Cabinet",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Tuesday",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "6.8 per cent",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "2023",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "9.9 per cent",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "2022",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Bandula Gunawardena",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Cabinet",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Tuesday",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "2023-2025",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "5 per cent",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "Gunawardena",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "tonight",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "between August 24 and 31",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Monday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the National Consumer Price",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "a year-on-year",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "66.7 per cent",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "July",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "58.9",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "June",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "82.5",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "July 2022",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "75.8",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "June 2022",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the World Bank",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "5th",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Zimbabwe",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Venezuela",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Turkey",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Lebanon",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "The World Bank",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "millions",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Ukraine",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "covid-19",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "years",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "World Bank",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "2023 අයවැයෙන් මූල්‍ය හිඟය කපා හැරීම ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ අරමුණයි",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ 2023 අයවැය මගින් මූල්‍ය හිඟය 2022 දී ප්‍රක්ෂේපිත සියයට 9.9 සිට 2023 දී සියයට 6.8 දක්වා අඩු කිරීමට ඉලක්ක කෙරෙනු ඇතැයි ජ්‍යෙෂ්ඨ කැබිනට් අමාත්‍යවරයෙක් අඟහරුවාදා ප්‍රකාශ කළේ, අර්බුදයට ඇපදීමේ පැකේජයක් සඳහා IMF නියෝජිත පිරිසගේ සංචාරයට පෙරය. පහර දූපත් ජාතිය.",
        "ඉන්ධන සහ අනෙකුත් අත්‍යාවශ්‍ය ද්‍රව්‍යවල උග්‍ර හිඟයකට තුඩු දී ඇති, ඉන්ධන පිරවුම්හල් ඉදිරිපිට දිගු සර්ප පෝලිම්වලට තුඩු දී ඇති පෙර නොවූ විරූ ආර්ථික අර්බුදයකට ශ්‍රී ලංකාව මුහුණ දී සිටී.",
        "\"2022 දී අපේක්ෂිත සියයට 9.9 සිට 2023 දී දළ දේශීය නිෂ්පාදිතයෙන් සියයට 6.8 දක්වා අයවැය හිඟය අඩු කිරීමට ශ්‍රී ලංකාව සැලසුම් කරයි\" යනුවෙන් කැබිනට් ප්‍රකාශක සහ ජනමාධ්‍ය අමාත්‍ය බන්දුල ගුණවර්ධන අඟහරුවාදා පැවසීය.",
        "“2023-2025 සඳහා වන මූල්‍ය රාමුවක් අමාත්‍ය මණ්ඩලය විසින් අනුමත කර ඇත. ශ්‍රී ලංකාව එහි ඉතිහාසයේ දරුණුතම මූල්‍ය අර්බුදයට මුහුණ දී සිටී,” ඔහු පැවසීය.",
        "“ණය කළමනාකරණය කිරීමට, මුදල් මුද්‍රණය අඩු කිරීමට සහ උද්ධමනය අඩු කිරීමට අපට අවසානයේ දී හිඟය දළ දේශීය නිෂ්පාදිතයෙන් සියයට 5 දක්වා අඩු කළ යුතුයි,” ගුණවර්ධන පැවසීය.",
        "අද රාත්‍රියේ මෙහි පැමිණෙන IMF නියෝජිත පිරිස සංචාරයට පෙර හිඟ ඉලක්කය ප්‍රකාශයට පත් කරන ලදී. අගෝස්තු 24 සහ 31 අතර කාලය තුළ මාණ්ඩලික මට්ටමේ එකඟතාවයකට පැමිණීම පිළිබඳව ඔවුන් නැවත සාකච්ඡා ආරම්භ කිරීමට නියමිතයි.",
        "රජයේ සංඛ්‍යාලේඛන කාර්යාලය සඳුදා ප්‍රකාශ කළේ ජාතික පාරිභෝගික මිල දර්ශකය මගින් වසරින් වසර පදනම මත මනිනු ලබන සමස්ත උද්ධමනය ජුනි මාසයේදී වාර්තා වූ 58.9 ට වඩා ජූලි මාසයේදී සියයට 66.7 දක්වා ඉහළ ගොස් ඇති බවයි.",
        "“මෙයට ප්‍රධාන වශයෙන් හේතු වූයේ ආහාර සහ ආහාර නොවන කණ්ඩායම් දෙකෙහිම පවතින ඉහළ මිල මට්ටමයි. ආහාර කාණ්ඩය 2022 ජුනි මාසයේ 75.8 සිට 2022 ජූලි මාසයේදී 82.5 දක්වා වැඩි විය.",
        "ලෝක බැංකුව සිය නවතම තක්සේරුවේදී පවසා ඇත්තේ ලෝකයේ ඉහළම ආහාර මිල උද්ධමනය සහිත ශ්‍රී ලංකාව 5 වැනි ස්ථානයට පත්ව ඇති බවයි. ශ්‍රී ලංකාව සිම්බාබ්වේ, වෙනිසියුලාව සහ තුර්කියට පිටුපසින් සිටින අතර ලෙබනනය එම ලැයිස්තුවේ පෙරමුණ ගෙන සිටී.",
        "ලෝක බැංකුව පැවසුවේ වාර්තාගත ඉහළ ආහාර මිල ගෝලීය අර්බුදයක් අවුලුවා ඇති අතර එය තවත් මිලියන ගනනක් අන්ත දරිද්‍රතාවයට තල්ලු කර ඇති අතර, සාගින්න සහ මන්දපෝෂණය විශාලනය කරන අතරම සංවර්ධනයේ දුෂ්කර ජයග්‍රහණ මකා දැමීමට තර්ජනය කරයි.",
        "යුක්රේනයේ යුද්ධය, සැපයුම් දාම කඩාකප්පල් කිරීම් සහ covid-19 වසංගතයේ අඛණ්ඩ ආර්ථික බිඳවැටීම වසර ගණනාවක සංවර්ධන ජයග්‍රහණ ආපසු හැරවීම සහ ආහාර මිල ගණන් සර්වකාලීන ඉහළම මට්ටමට තල්ලු කරයි.",
        "ඉහළ ආදායම් ලබන රටවල මිනිසුන්ට වඩා අඩු සහ මධ්‍යම ආදායම් ලබන රටවල ජනතාව තම ආදායමෙන් වැඩි කොටසක් ආහාර සඳහා වැය කරන බැවින් ආහාර මිල ඉහළ යාම ඔවුන්ට වැඩි බලපෑමක් ඇති කරයි. මෙම කෙටියෙන් ආහාර අනාරක්ෂිතභාවය සහ අද දක්වා ලෝක බැංකු ප්‍රතිචාර දෙස බලයි."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "2023",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "2023",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "සියයට 6.8 කි",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "2023",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "සියයට 9.9 කි",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "2022",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මණ්ඩල",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "අඟහරුවාදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "සියයට 6.8 කි",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "2023",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "සියයට 9.9 කි",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "2022",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "බන්දුල ගුණවර්ධන",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "මණ්ඩල",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "අඟහරුවාදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "2023-2025",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "සියයට 5 කි",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගුණවර්ධන ය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "අද රෑ",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "අගෝස්තු 24 සහ 31 අතර",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "සඳුදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජාතික පාරිභෝගික මිල",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "වසරින් වසර",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "සියයට 66.7 කි",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජුලි",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "58.9",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජූනි",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "82.5",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "2022 ජූලි",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "75.8",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "2022 ජූනි",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ලෝක බැංකුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "5 වැනි",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "සිම්බාබ්වේ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "වෙනිසියුලාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "කළුකුමා",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ලෙබනනය",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ලෝක බැංකුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "මිලියන",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "යුක්රේනය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "කොවිඩ්-19",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "වසර",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ලෝක බැංකුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "2023ஆம் ஆண்டு வரவு செலவுத் திட்டத்தில் நிதிப் பற்றாக்குறையை குறைக்க இலங்கை இலக்கு கொண்டுள்ளது",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "இலங்கையின் 2023 வரவுசெலவுத் திட்டம், 2022 இல் திட்டமிடப்பட்ட 9.9 சதவீதத்திலிருந்து 2023 இல் 6.8 சதவீதமாக நிதிப் பற்றாக்குறையைக் குறைப்பதை இலக்காகக் கொண்டிருக்கும் என்று, நெருக்கடிக்கான பிணை எடுப்புப் பொதிக்கான சர்வதேச நாணய நிதியக் குழுவின் வருகைக்கு முன்னதாக, மூத்த அமைச்சரவை அமைச்சர் ஒருவர் செவ்வாய்கிழமை தெரிவித்தார். தீவு தேசத்தை தாக்கியது.",
        "இலங்கை முன்னெப்போதும் இல்லாத பொருளாதார நெருக்கடியின் மத்தியில் உள்ளது, இது எரிபொருள் மற்றும் பிற அத்தியாவசியப் பொருட்களின் கடுமையான பற்றாக்குறைக்கு வழிவகுத்தது, இது நிரப்பு நிலையங்களுக்கு முன்னால் நீண்ட பாம்பு வரிசையில் நிற்க வழிவகுத்தது.",
        "2022ல் எதிர்பார்க்கப்படும் 9.9 சதவீதத்திலிருந்து 2023ல் மொத்த உள்நாட்டு உற்பத்தியில் 6.8 சதவீதமாக வரவு செலவுத் திட்ட பற்றாக்குறையை குறைக்க இலங்கை திட்டமிட்டுள்ளது என அமைச்சரவைப் பேச்சாளரும் ஊடகத்துறை அமைச்சருமான பந்துல குணவர்தன செவ்வாய்க்கிழமை தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "“2023-2025 ஆம் ஆண்டிற்கான நிதிக் கட்டமைப்பிற்கு அமைச்சர்கள் அமைச்சரவை ஒப்புதல் அளித்துள்ளது. இலங்கை அதன் வரலாற்றில் மிக மோசமான நிதி நெருக்கடியை எதிர்கொண்டுள்ளது” என்று அவர் கூறினார்.",
        "\"கடனை நிர்வகிக்கவும், பணம் அச்சிடுவதைக் குறைக்கவும் மற்றும் குறைந்த பணவீக்கத்தைக் கொண்டிருப்பதற்கும் நாம் இறுதியில் மொத்த உள்நாட்டு உற்பத்தியில் 5 சதவீதமாக பற்றாக்குறையைக் குறைக்க வேண்டும்\" என்று குணவர்தன கூறினார்.",
        "இன்றிரவு இங்கு வரும் IMF குழுவின் வருகைக்கு முன்னதாக பற்றாக்குறை இலக்கு அறிவிக்கப்பட்டது. ஆகஸ்ட் 24 மற்றும் 31 க்கு இடையில் ஊழியர்கள் நிலை ஒப்பந்தத்தை எட்டுவது குறித்த பேச்சுவார்த்தையை மீண்டும் தொடங்க உள்ளனர்.",
        "தேசிய நுகர்வோர் விலைக் குறியீட்டின்படி ஆண்டு அடிப்படையில் கணக்கிடப்படும் ஒட்டுமொத்த பணவீக்க விகிதம் ஜூன் மாதத்தில் பதிவான 58.9ஐ விட ஜூலையில் 66.7 சதவீதமாக உயர்ந்துள்ளதாக திங்களன்று அரசாங்கத்தின் புள்ளியியல் அலுவலகம் தெரிவித்துள்ளது.",
        "\"இது முக்கியமாக உணவு மற்றும் உணவு அல்லாத குழுக்களில் நிலவும் அதிக விலை நிலைகள் காரணமாகும். ஜூன் 2022 இல் 75.8 ஆக இருந்த உணவுக் குழு ஜூலை 2022 இல் 82.5 ஆக அதிகரித்தது, ”என்று வெளியீடு கூறியது.",
        "உலக வங்கி தனது சமீபத்திய மதிப்பீட்டில், உலகிலேயே அதிக உணவு விலை பணவீக்கத்துடன் இலங்கை 5வது இடத்தைப் பிடித்துள்ளதாகத் தெரிவித்துள்ளது. சிம்பாப்வே, வெனிசுலா, துருக்கி ஆகிய நாடுகளுக்குப் பின்னால் இலங்கையும், லெபனான் முதலிடத்திலும் உள்ளது.",
        "உலக வங்கி, உணவுப் பொருட்களின் விலை உயர்வானது உலகளாவிய நெருக்கடியைத் தூண்டிவிட்டதாகக் கூறியுள்ளது.",
        "உக்ரைனில் போர், விநியோகச் சங்கிலி சீர்குலைவுகள் மற்றும் கோவிட்-19 தொற்றுநோயின் தொடர்ச்சியான பொருளாதார வீழ்ச்சி ஆகியவை பல ஆண்டுகால வளர்ச்சி ஆதாயங்களை மாற்றியமைத்து உணவு விலைகளை எல்லா நேரத்திலும் உச்சத்திற்கு தள்ளுகின்றன.",
        "உயர்ந்துவரும் உணவுப் பொருட்களின் விலை குறைந்த மற்றும் நடுத்தர வருமான நாடுகளில் உள்ள மக்கள் மீது அதிக தாக்கத்தை ஏற்படுத்துகிறது, ஏனெனில் அவர்கள் அதிக வருமானம் உள்ள நாடுகளில் உள்ள மக்களை விட உணவுக்காக தங்கள் வருமானத்தில் பெரும் பங்கை செலவிடுகிறார்கள். இந்த சுருக்கம் இன்றுவரை அதிகரித்து வரும் உணவுப் பாதுகாப்பின்மை மற்றும் உலக வங்கியின் பதில்களைப் பார்க்கிறது."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "இலங்கை",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "2023",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கையின்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "2023",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "6.8 சதவீதம்",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "2023",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "9.9 சதவீதம்",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "2022",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "மந்திரி சபை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "செவ்வாய்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "6.8 சதவீதம்",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "2023",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "9.9 சதவீதம்",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "2022",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "பந்துல குணவர்தன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "மந்திரி சபை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "செவ்வாய்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "2023-2025",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "5 சதவீதம்",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "குணவர்தன",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இன்றிரவு",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆகஸ்ட் 24 மற்றும் 31 க்கு இடையில்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "திங்கட்கிழமை",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "தேசிய நுகர்வோர் விலை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆண்டுக்கு ஆண்டு",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "66.7 சதவீதம்",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜூலை",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "58.9",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜூன்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "82.5",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜூலை 2022",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "75.8",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜூன் 2022",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "உலக வங்கி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "5வது",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜிம்பாப்வே",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "வெனிசுலா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "துருக்கி",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "லெபனான்",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "உலக வங்கி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "மில்லியன்கள்",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "உக்ரைன்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "கோவிட்-19",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆண்டுகள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "உலக வங்கி",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}