{
  "newspaper_id": "ada-derana-lk",
  "url": "http://www.adaderana.lk/news/84633/retirement-age-of-govt-semi-govt-employees-to-be-reduced",
  "time_ut": 1661848080,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Retirement age of govt & semi-govt employees to be reduced",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Retirement age of govt & semi-govt employees to be reduced",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "The retirement age of government and semi-government employees will be reduced to 60 years, President Ranil Wickremesinghe says.",
        "Presenting the Interim Budget 2022 for the remainder of the fiscal year 2022, the Head of State noted that all employees who have served up to the age of 60 years should retire from the service.",
        "As a result of increasing the retirement age of government and semi-government employees to 65 years and 62 years, respectively, it is observed that the number of unemployed youths in the country is on the rise, President Wickremesinghe explained."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "govt & semi",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "60 years",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "2022",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the fiscal year 2022",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "State",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the age of 60 years",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "65 years",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "62 years",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "රජයේ සහ අර්ධ රාජ්‍ය සේවකයන්ගේ විශ්‍රාම වයස අඩු කෙරේ",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "රජයේ සහ අර්ධ රාජ්‍ය සේවකයින්ගේ විශ්‍රාම යන වයස අවුරුදු 60 දක්වා අඩු කරන බව ජනාධිපති රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතා පවසයි.",
        "2022 මුදල් වර්ෂයේ ඉතිරි කාලය සඳහා 2022 අතුරු අයවැය ඉදිරිපත් කරමින් රාජ්‍ය නායකයා සඳහන් කළේ වයස අවුරුදු 60 දක්වා සේවය කර ඇති සියලුම සේවකයින් සේවයෙන් විශ්‍රාම ගත යුතු බවයි.",
        "රාජ්‍ය හා අර්ධ රාජ්‍ය සේවකයන්ගේ විශ්‍රාම යන වයස පිළිවෙලින් අවුරුදු 65 සහ අවුරුදු 62 දක්වා ඉහළ දැමීමේ ප්‍රතිඵලයක් ලෙස රටේ රැකියා විරහිත තරුණ තරුණියන්ගේ සංඛ්‍යාව ඉහළ යමින් පවතින බව නිරීක්ෂණය වන බව ජනාධිපති වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතා පැහැදිලි කළේය."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "රජය සහ අර්ධ",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "අවුරුදු 60 යි",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "2022",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "2022 මුදල් වර්ෂය",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "රජයේ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "වයස අවුරුදු 60 යි",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "අවුරුදු 65 යි",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "අවුරුදු 62 යි",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "அரசு மற்றும் அரை அரசு ஊழியர்களின் ஓய்வு வயது குறைக்கப்படும்",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "அரச மற்றும் அரை அரச ஊழியர்களின் ஓய்வு பெறும் வயது 60 ஆக குறைக்கப்படும் என ஜனாதிபதி ரணில் விக்ரமசிங்க தெரிவித்துள்ளார்.",
        "2022 ஆம் ஆண்டின் எஞ்சிய நிதியாண்டுக்கான இடைக்கால வரவு செலவுத் திட்டத்தை முன்வைத்த அரச தலைவர், 60 வயது வரை சேவையாற்றிய அனைத்து ஊழியர்களும் சேவையில் இருந்து ஓய்வு பெற வேண்டும் என்று குறிப்பிட்டார்.",
        "அரச மற்றும் அரை அரச ஊழியர்களின் ஓய்வூதிய வயதை முறையே 65 மற்றும் 62 ஆக அதிகரிப்பதன் விளைவாக நாட்டில் வேலையற்ற இளைஞர்களின் எண்ணிக்கை அதிகரித்து வருவதை அவதானிக்க முடிகின்றது என ஜனாதிபதி விக்ரமசிங்க விளக்கமளித்துள்ளார்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "அரசு மற்றும் அரை",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "60 ஆண்டுகள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "2022",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "2022 நிதியாண்டு",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "நிலை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "60 வயது",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "65 ஆண்டுகள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "62 ஆண்டுகள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}