{
  "newspaper_id": "ada-derana-lk",
  "url": "http://www.adaderana.lk/news/84704/japan-calls-for-creditor-nations-talks-on-sri-lanka-debt-restructuring",
  "time_ut": 1662097800,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Japan calls for creditor nations’ talks on Sri Lanka debt restructuring",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Japan calls for creditor nations’ talks on Sri Lanka debt restructuring",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "Japanese Finance Minister Shunichi Suzuki on Friday urged all creditor nations to discuss Sri Lanka’s debt restructuring, after the crisis-hit South Asian nation reached a loan agreement with the International Monetary Fund.",
        "“It’s important for all creditor nations, including China and India, to gather to discuss Sri Lanka’s debt restructuring,” Suzuki told a news conference.",
        "Sri Lanka has reached a preliminary agreement with the IMF for a loan of about $2.9 billion, the global lender said on Thursday, as the country seeks a way out of its worst economic crisis since independence from Britain in 1948."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Japan",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "Sri Lanka",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Japanese",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Shunichi Suzuki",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Friday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "South Asian",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "the International Monetary Fund",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "China",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "India",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Suzuki",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "IMF",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "about $2.9 billion",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "Thursday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Britain",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "1948",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "ජපානය ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ ණය ප්‍රතිව්‍යුහගත කිරීම පිළිබඳ ණයහිමි ජාතීන්ගේ සාකච්ඡා ඉල්ලා සිටී",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "අර්බුදකාරී දකුණු ආසියානු ජාතිය ජාත්‍යන්තර මූල්‍ය අරමුදල සමඟ ණය ගිවිසුමකට එළඹීමෙන් පසු ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ ණය ප්‍රතිව්‍යුහගත කිරීම පිළිබඳව සාකච්ඡා කරන ලෙස ජපාන මුදල් අමාත්‍ය Shunichi Suzuki සිකුරාදා සියලුම ණය දෙන ජාතීන්ගෙන් ඉල්ලා සිටියේය.",
        "“ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ ණය ප්‍රතිව්‍යුහගත කිරීම ගැන සාකච්ඡා කිරීමට චීනය සහ ඉන්දියාව ඇතුළු සියලුම ණය දෙන ජාතීන්ට එක්රැස් වීම වැදගත්,” සුසුකි ප්‍රවෘත්ති සාකච්ඡාවකදී පැවසීය.",
        "1948 දී බ්‍රිතාන්‍යයෙන් නිදහස ලැබීමෙන් පසු රට මුහුණ දුන් දරුණුතම ආර්ථික අර්බුදයෙන් මිදීමට මගක් සොයමින් සිටින විට ශ්‍රී ලංකාව ඩොලර් බිලියන 2.9 ක පමණ ණයක් සඳහා IMF සමඟ මූලික එකඟතාවයකට පැමිණ ඇති බව ගෝලීය ණය දෙන්නා බ්‍රහස්පතින්දා ප්‍රකාශ කළේය."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ජපානය",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ජපන්",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Shunichi Suzuki",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "සිකුරාදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "දකුණු ආසියානු",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජාත්‍යන්තර මුල්‍ය අරමුදල",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "චීනය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Suzuki",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "IMF",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඩොලර් බිලියන 2.9 ක් පමණ",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "බ්රහස්පතින්දා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "බ්රිතාන්යය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "1948",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "இலங்கை கடன் மறுசீரமைப்பு தொடர்பாக கடன் வழங்கும் நாடுகளின் பேச்சுவார்த்தைக்கு ஜப்பான் அழைப்பு விடுத்துள்ளது",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "நெருக்கடியால் பாதிக்கப்பட்ட தெற்காசிய நாடு சர்வதேச நாணய நிதியத்துடன் கடன் ஒப்பந்தத்தை எட்டிய பின்னர், இலங்கையின் கடன் மறுசீரமைப்பு குறித்து விவாதிக்குமாறு அனைத்து கடன் வழங்கும் நாடுகளையும் ஜப்பானிய நிதி அமைச்சர் ஷுனிச்சி சுசுகி வெள்ளிக்கிழமை வலியுறுத்தினார்.",
        "\"சீனா மற்றும் இந்தியா உட்பட அனைத்து கடன் வழங்கும் நாடுகளும் இலங்கையின் கடன் மறுசீரமைப்பு பற்றி விவாதிக்க ஒன்று கூடுவது முக்கியம்\" என்று Suzuki செய்தி மாநாட்டில் தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "1948 ஆம் ஆண்டு பிரித்தானியாவிடமிருந்து சுதந்திரம் பெற்ற பின்னர் ஏற்பட்ட மோசமான பொருளாதார நெருக்கடியிலிருந்து வெளியேறுவதற்கான வழியை நாடு தேடும் நிலையில், சுமார் 2.9 பில்லியன் டாலர் கடனுக்காக IMF உடன் இலங்கை ஆரம்ப ஒப்பந்தத்தை எட்டியுள்ளது என்று உலக கடன் வழங்குநர் வியாழக்கிழமை தெரிவித்தார்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ஜப்பான்",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "இலங்கை",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ஜப்பானியர்",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Shunichi Suzuki",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "வெள்ளி",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "தெற்காசிய",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "சர்வதேச நாணய நிதியம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "சீனா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்தியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Suzuki",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "IMF",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "சுமார் $2.9 பில்லியன்",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "வியாழன்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "பிரிட்டன்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "1948",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}