{
  "newspaper_id": "news-first-lk",
  "url": "https://www.newsfirst.lk/2022/07/02/red-alert-issued-for-rough-seas-amber-alert-for-strong-winds/",
  "time_ut": 1656754380,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Red alert issued for rough seas, amber alert for strong winds",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Red alert issued for rough seas, amber alert for strong winds",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); The Meteorology Department had issued a Red alert for strong winds and rough seas, with wind speeds at the risk of increasing up to (60-70) kmph in the sea areas off the coast extending from Puttalam to Pottuvil via Colombo, Galle and Hambantota due to the active south-west monsoon condition.",
        "The swell waves (about 2.5 m – 3.0 m) height (This is not for land area) may increase in the above-mentioned sea areas and these sea areas will be rough to very rough.",
        "There is a possibility that near shore sea areas off the coast extending from Puttalam to Matara via Colombo and Galle, may experience surges due to swell waves.",
        "Therefore, it is advised not to venture in fishing and naval activities in the sea areas off the coast extending from Colombo to Hambantota via Galle until 05:30 PM today (02).",
        "Meanwhile, an amber alert has been issued for strong winds today (02), with strong winds about (50-60) kmph being expected at times over the western slopes of the Central hills, Western and Southern provinces due to the active southwest monsoon condition.",
        "Red alert issued for rough seas, amber alert for strong winds"
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "The Meteorology Department",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "60-70",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Puttalam",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Galle",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Hambantota",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "3.0",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Matara",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Hambantota",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Galle",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "05:30 PM",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "02",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "02",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "50-60",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Central ",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "Western",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Southern",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "southwest monsoon",
            "label": "LOC"
          }
        ],
        []
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "රළු මුහුදු ප්‍රදේශ සඳහා රතු නිවේදන, තද සුළං සඳහා ඇම්බර් නිවේදන නිකුත් කර ඇත",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); පුත්තලම සිට කොළඹ, ගාල්ල සහ හම්බන්තොට හරහා පොතුවිල් දක්වා වෙරළට ඔබ්බෙන් වන මුහුදු ප්‍රදේශවල සුළගේ වේගය පැයට කිලෝමීටර් (60-70) දක්වා වැඩි වීමේ අවදානමක් සහිත තද සුළං සහ රළු මුහුදු ප්‍රදේශ සඳහා රතු නිවේදනයක් නිකුත් කර තිබුණි. සක්‍රීය නිරිතදිග මෝසම් තත්ත්වයට.",
        "ඉහත සඳහන් කර ඇති මුහුදු ප්‍රදේශ වල රළ (මීටර් 2.5 - 3.0 පමණ) උස (මෙය ගොඩබිම් ප්‍රදේශය සඳහා නොවේ) වැඩි විය හැකි අතර මෙම මුහුදු ප්‍රදේශ රළු සිට ඉතා රළු වේ.",
        "පුත්තලම සිට කොළඹ සහ ගාල්ල හරහා මාතර දක්වා විහිදෙන වෙරළට ඔබ්බෙන් වන වෙරළාසන්න මුහුදු ප්‍රදේශවල රළ සැඩ පහර හේතුවෙන් රළ නැගීමේ හැකියාවක් පවතී.",
        "එබැවින් අද (02) පස්වරු 05.30 දක්වා කොළඹ සිට ගාල්ල හරහා හම්බන්තොට දක්වා වෙරළට ඔබ්බෙන් වන මුහුදු ප්‍රදේශවල ධීවර හා නාවික කටයුතුවල නොයෙදෙන ලෙස උපදෙස් දෙනු ලැබේ.",
        "මේ අතර, සක්‍රීය නිරිතදිග මෝසම් තත්ත්වය හේතුවෙන් මධ්‍යම කඳුකරයේ බටහිර බෑවුම් ප්‍රදේශවල, බස්නාහිර සහ දකුණු පළාත්වල විටින් විට පැයට කිලෝමීටර් (50-60) පමණ තද සුළං බලාපොරොත්තු විය හැකි බැවින්, අද (02) තද සුළං සඳහා ඇම්බර් අනතුරු ඇඟවීමක් නිකුත් කර ඇත. .",
        "රළු මුහුදු ප්‍රදේශ සඳහා රතු නිවේදන, තද සුළං සඳහා ඇම්බර් නිවේදන නිකුත් කර ඇත"
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "කාලගුණ විද්‍යා දෙපාර්තමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "60-70",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "පුත්තලම",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගාල්ල",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "හම්බන්තොට",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "3.0",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "මාතර",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "හම්බන්තොට",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගාල්ල",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "05:30 ප.ව",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "02",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "02",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "50-60",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "මධ්යම",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "බටහිර",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "දකුණු",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "නිරිතදිග මෝසම්",
            "label": "LOC"
          }
        ],
        []
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "கடல் சீற்றத்திற்கு சிவப்பு எச்சரிக்கையும், பலத்த காற்றுக்கு அம்பர் அலர்ட் விடுக்கப்பட்டுள்ளது",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); புத்தளத்திலிருந்து கொழும்பு, காலி மற்றும் அம்பாந்தோட்டை ஊடாக பொத்துவில் வரையான கடற்பரப்புகளில் காற்றின் வேகம் மணிக்கு (60-70) கிலோ மீற்றர் வரை அதிகரித்து வீசும் அபாயத்துடன் கூடிய பலத்த காற்று மற்றும் கொந்தளிப்பான கடல்களுக்கான சிவப்பு எச்சரிக்கையை வளிமண்டலவியல் திணைக்களம் விடுத்துள்ளது. செயலில் உள்ள தென்மேற்கு பருவமழை நிலைக்கு.",
        "மேற்கூறிய கடல் பகுதிகளில் அலைகள் (சுமார் 2.5 மீ - 3.0 மீ) உயரம் (இது நிலப்பரப்புக்கானது அல்ல) அதிகரிக்கக்கூடும், மேலும் இந்த கடல் பகுதிகள் மிகவும் கொந்தளிப்பாக இருக்கும்.",
        "புத்தளத்தில் இருந்து கொழும்பு மற்றும்  காலி ஊடாக மாத்தறை வரையான கரையோரப் பகுதிகளுக்கு அண்மித்த கரையோரப் பகுதிகள்  அலைகளின் அலைகள் காரணமாக எழுச்சியை அனுபவிக்கும் சாத்தியக்கூறுகள் உள்ளன.",
        "எனவே, இன்று (02) மாலை 05:30 மணி வரை கொழும்பிலிருந்து காலி ஊடாக ஹம்பாந்தோட்டை வரையான கடற்பரப்புகளுக்கு அப்பால் உள்ள கடற்பரப்புகளில் மீன்பிடி மற்றும் கடற்படை நடவடிக்கைகளில் ஈடுபட வேண்டாம் என அறிவுறுத்தப்படுகிறது.",
        "இதற்கிடையில், இன்று (02) பலத்த காற்று வீசுவதற்கான அம்பர் எச்சரிக்கை விடுக்கப்பட்டுள்ளது, தென்மேற்கு பருவமழை செயலில் உள்ளதால் மத்திய மலைகள், மேற்கு மற்றும் தெற்கு மாகாணங்களின் மேற்கு சரிவுகளில் அவ்வப்போது மணிக்கு (50-60) கிமீ வேகத்தில் பலத்த காற்று வீசக்கூடும். .",
        "கடல் சீற்றத்திற்கு சிவப்பு எச்சரிக்கையும், பலத்த காற்றுக்கு அம்பர் அலர்ட் விடுக்கப்பட்டுள்ளது"
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "வளிமண்டலவியல் திணைக்களம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "60-70",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "புத்தளம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "காலி",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஹம்பாந்தோட்டை",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "3.0",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "மாத்தறை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஹம்பாந்தோட்டை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "காலி",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "மாலை 05:30",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "02",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "02",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "50-60",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "மத்திய",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "மேற்கு",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "தெற்கு",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "தென்மேற்கு பருவமழை",
            "label": "LOC"
          }
        ],
        []
      ]
    }
  }
}