{
  "newspaper_id": "news-first-lk",
  "url": "https://www.newsfirst.lk/2022/07/26/gotabaya-to-return-to-sri-lanka-soon-bandula/",
  "time_ut": 1658820120,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Gotabaya to return to Sri Lanka, soon – Bandula",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Gotabaya to return to Sri Lanka, soon – Bandula",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st): Cabinet Spokesperson Dr. Bandula Gunawardena said that Former President Gotabaya Rajapaksa will return to Sri Lanka soon.",
        "Speaking at the weekly Cabinet Media Briefing Dr. Gunawardena said he does not believe the Former President fled the country, and is in hiding, but Gotabaya Rajapaksa in fact went over seas following the necessary official channels.",
        "Commenting on the request made to the Singapore Attorney General to detain the Former Sri Lankan President, the Cabinet Spokesperson said that if there is a situation, the responsible officials in the country will take steps to ensure no harm is done to the Former President."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Gotabaya",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "Sri Lanka",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "News 1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Spokesperson",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Bandula Gunawardena",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Gotabaya Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "weekly",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Cabinet Media Briefing",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Gunawardena",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Gotabaya Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Singapore",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Cabinet Spokesperson",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "ගෝඨාභය ළඟදීම ලංකාවට එනවා - බන්දුල",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st) : හිටපු ජනාධිපති ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ මහතා ළඟදීම ශ්‍රී ලංකාවට පැමිණෙන බව කැබිනට් ප්‍රකාශක ආචාර්ය බන්දුල ගුණවර්ධන මහතා පැවසීය.",
        "සතිපතා පැවැත්වෙන කැබිනට් මාධ්‍ය හමුවට එක්වෙමින් වෛද්‍ය ගුණවර්ධන කියා සිටියේ හිටපු ජනාධිපතිවරයා රටින් පැන ගොස් සැඟවී සිටින බව තමා විශ්වාස නොකරන නමුත් ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ ඇත්ත වශයෙන්ම අවශ්‍ය නිල මාර්ග අනුගමනය කරමින් මුහුද හරහා ගිය බවයි.",
        "හිටපු ශ්‍රී ලංකා ජනාධිපතිවරයා රඳවා ගන්නා ලෙස සිංගප්පූරු නීතිපතිවරයාගෙන් කළ ඉල්ලීම සම්බන්ධයෙන් අදහස් දක්වමින් කැබිනට් ප්‍රකාශකවරයා කියා සිටියේ යම් තත්ත්වයක් ඇති වුවහොත් හිටපු ජනාධිපතිවරයාට කිසිදු හානියක් සිදුනොවීමට රටේ වගකිවයුතු නිලධාරීන් කටයුතු කරන බවයි."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ගෝඨාභය",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "News 1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ප්‍රකාශක",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "බන්දුල ගුණවර්ධන",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "සතිපතා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "කැබිනට් මාධ්‍ය සාකච්ඡාව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගුණවර්ධන ය",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "සිංගප්පූරුව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "කැබිනට් ප්‍රකාශක",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "கோட்டாபய விரைவில் இலங்கை திரும்புவார் – பந்துல",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st): முன்னாள் ஜனாதிபதி கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ஷ விரைவில் இலங்கை திரும்புவார் என அமைச்சரவைப் பேச்சாளர் கலாநிதி பந்துல குணவர்தன தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "வாராந்த அமைச்சரவை ஊடகவியலாளர் சந்திப்பில் கலந்துகொண்டு உரையாற்றிய கலாநிதி குணவர்தன, முன்னாள் ஜனாதிபதி நாட்டை விட்டு தப்பியோடி, தலைமறைவாக இருப்பதாக தாம் நம்பவில்லை, ஆனால் கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ஷ உண்மையில் தேவையான உத்தியோகபூர்வ வழிகளை பின்பற்றி கடல் வழியாக சென்றுள்ளார்.",
        "சிறிலங்காவின் முன்னாள் ஜனாதிபதியை தடுத்து வைக்குமாறு சிங்கப்பூர் சட்டமா அதிபரிடம் விடுக்கப்பட்ட கோரிக்கை தொடர்பில் கருத்து தெரிவித்த அமைச்சரவைப் பேச்சாளர், நிலைமை ஏற்பட்டால், முன்னாள் ஜனாதிபதிக்கு எவ்வித பாதிப்பும் ஏற்படாதவாறு நாட்டில் உள்ள பொறுப்புள்ள அதிகாரிகள் நடவடிக்கை எடுப்பார்கள்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "கோட்டாபய",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "இலங்கை",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "News 1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "செய்தி தொடர்பாளர்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "பந்துல குணவர்தன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "வாரந்தோறும்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "அமைச்சரவை ஊடகவியலாளர் சந்திப்பு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "குணவர்தன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "சிங்கப்பூர்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "அமைச்சரவை செய்தி தொடர்பாளர்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}