{
  "newspaper_id": "ada-derana-lk",
  "url": "http://www.adaderana.lk/news/83907/sc-orders-to-discharge-president-from-petition-filed-over-economic-crisis",
  "time_ut": 1658920620,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "SC orders to discharge President from petition filed over economic crisis",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "SC orders to discharge President from petition filed over economic crisis",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "The Supreme Court today (July 27) ordered to discharge President Ranil Wickremesinghe from the proceedings of the petition filed over the economic crisis, in which he is named as a respondent.",
        "The petition was lodged by the former Chairman of the Ceylon Chamber of Commerce (CCC) Chandra Jayaratne and several others, demanding that an investigation be ordered against the individuals responsible for the current economic crisis.",
        "The order was issued by a five-member Supreme Court bench presided over by Chief Justice Jayantha Jayasuriya.",
        "President’s Counsel Chandaka Jayasundara, who appeared for the petitioners, requested the court to release President Wickremesinghe from the court proceedings, stating that the petitioners do not seek relief against him although he is named as a respondent in the petition.",
        "Accordingly, the Supreme Court ordered to discharge President Wickremesinghe from the petition after taking the request into consideration.",
        "The petition will continue to be taken up for consideration."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "SC",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "The Supreme Court",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "July 27",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the Ceylon Chamber of Commerce",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "CCC",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Chandra Jayaratne",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "five",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Supreme Court",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Jayantha Jayasuriya",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Chandaka Jayasundara",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the Supreme Court",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        []
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "ආර්ථික අර්බුදය සම්බන්ධයෙන් ගොනු කළ පෙත්සමෙන් ජනපති නිදහස් කරන ලෙස ශ්‍රේෂ්ඨාධිකරණය නියෝග කරයි",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "ජනාධිපති රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතා වගඋත්තරකරුවෙකු ලෙස නම් කර ඇති ආර්ථික අර්බුදය සම්බන්ධයෙන් ගොනු කර ඇති පෙත්සම් විභාගයෙන් ඔහු නිදහස් කිරීමට ශ්‍රේෂ්ඨාධිකරණය අද (ජුලි 27) නියෝග කළේය.",
        "ලංකා වාණිජ මණ්ඩලයේ හිටපු සභාපති චන්ද්‍රා ජයරත්න මහතා ඇතුළු පිරිසක් විසින් මෙම පෙත්සම ගොනු කර තිබුණේ වත්මන් ආර්ථික අර්බුදයට වගකිව යුතු පුද්ගලයන් සම්බන්ධයෙන් පරීක්ෂණයක් පවත්වන ලෙසට ඉල්ලා සිටින ලෙසයි.",
        "අගවිනිසුරු ජයන්ත ජයසූරිය මහතා ප්‍රමුඛ පංච පුද්ගල ශ්‍රේෂ්ඨාධිකරණ විනිසුරු මඩුල්ලක් විසින් මෙම නියෝගය නිකුත් කර ඇත.",
        "පෙත්සම්කරුවන් වෙනුවෙන් පෙනී සිටි ජනාධිපති නීතීඥ චන්දක ජයසුන්දර මහතා අධිකරණයෙන් ඉල්ලා සිටියේ ජනාධිපති වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතා මෙම පෙත්සමේ වගඋත්තරකරුවෙකු ලෙස නම් කර ඇතත් ඔහුට එරෙහිව පෙත්සම්කරුවන් සහනයක් අපේක්ෂා නොකරන බව පවසමින් ඔහුව අධිකරණ කටයුතුවලින් නිදහස් කරන ලෙසයි.",
        "ඒ අනුව එම ඉල්ලීම සැලකිල්ලට ගෙන ජනාධිපති වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතා පෙත්සමෙන් නිදහස් කිරීමට ශ්‍රේෂ්ඨාධිකරණය නියෝග කළේය.",
        "මෙම පෙත්සම තවදුරටත් සලකා බැලීමට නියමිතය."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "SC",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රේෂ්ඨාධිකරණය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජූලි 27",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ලංකා වාණිජ මණ්ඩලය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "CCC",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "චන්ද්‍රා ජයරත්න",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "පහ",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රේෂ්ඨාධිකරණය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජයන්ත ජයසූරිය",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "චන්දක ජයසුන්දර",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රේෂ්ඨාධිකරණය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        []
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "பொருளாதார நெருக்கடி தொடர்பாக தாக்கல் செய்யப்பட்ட மனுவில் இருந்து ஜனாதிபதியை விடுவிக்க உச்சநீதிமன்றம் உத்தரவு",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "ஜனாதிபதி ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்கவின் பொருளாதார நெருக்கடி தொடர்பாக தாக்கல் செய்யப்பட்ட மனு மீதான விசாரணைகளில் இருந்து அவரை விடுவிக்குமாறு உயர் நீதிமன்றம் இன்று (ஜூலை 27) உத்தரவிட்டுள்ளது.",
        "தற்போதைய பொருளாதார நெருக்கடிக்கு காரணமான நபர்களுக்கு எதிராக விசாரணைக்கு உத்தரவிடுமாறு கோரி இலங்கை வர்த்தக சம்மேளனத்தின் (சி.சி.சி) முன்னாள் தலைவர் சந்திரா ஜயரத்ன மற்றும் பலர் இந்த மனுவை தாக்கல் செய்துள்ளனர்.",
        "பிரதம நீதியரசர் ஜயந்த ஜயசூரிய தலைமையிலான ஐவரடங்கிய உச்ச நீதிமன்ற அமர்வு இந்த உத்தரவை பிறப்பித்துள்ளது.",
        "மனுதாரர்கள் சார்பில் ஆஜரான ஜனாதிபதி சட்டத்தரணி சாந்தக ஜயசுந்தர, மனுவில் பிரதிவாதியாக குறிப்பிடப்பட்டுள்ள போதிலும் மனுதாரர்கள் ஜனாதிபதி விக்ரமசிங்கவிற்கு எதிராக நிவாரணம் கோரவில்லை என தெரிவித்து, நீதிமன்ற நடவடிக்கைகளில் இருந்து அவரை விடுவிக்குமாறு நீதிமன்றில் கோரினார்.",
        "இதனடிப்படையில், இந்த கோரிக்கையை கவனத்தில் கொண்டு ஜனாதிபதி விக்ரமசிங்கவை மனுவில் இருந்து விடுவிக்குமாறு உயர் நீதிமன்றம் உத்தரவிட்டுள்ளது.",
        "இந்த மனு தொடர்ந்து பரிசீலனைக்கு எடுத்துக்கொள்ளப்படும்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "எஸ்சி",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "உச்ச நீதிமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜூலை 27",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை வர்த்தக சபை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "CCC",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "சந்திரா ஜயரத்ன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஐந்து",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "உச்ச நீதிமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜயந்த ஜயசூரிய",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "சந்தக ஜயசுந்தர",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "உச்ச நீதிமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        []
      ]
    }
  }
}