{
  "newspaper_id": "ada-lk",
  "url": "https://www.ada.lk/international/මෙරට-තත්ත්වය-ගැන-චීනය-සමීප-නිරීක්ෂණයක-යෙදේ/3-395326",
  "time_ut": 1657535604,
  "original_lang": "si",
  "original_title": "මෙරට තත්ත්වය ගැන චීනය සමීප නිරීක්ෂණයක යෙදේ",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "China is closely monitoring the situation in this country",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "Chinese Foreign Ministry spokesperson Wang Wengbin says that China is closely monitoring the development of the situation in Sri Lanka.",
        "He stated that China, as a friendly neighbor of Sri Lanka, sincerely hopes that all sectors of Sri Lanka will work for the basic needs of the country and its people and work together to quickly achieve social stability, economic recovery and livelihood improvements.",
        "Wang said this while commenting on the current situation in Sri Lanka at the regular press conference.",
        "After months of frustration with an unprecedented economic crisis, protesters stormed the Sri Lankan presidential palace in the capital Colombo on Saturday, Chinese media said, adding that the president announced his resignation on July 13, hours after leaving his home."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "China",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Chinese Foreign Ministry",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Wang Wengbin",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "China",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "China",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Wang",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "months",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lankan",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "Saturday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Chinese",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "July 13, hours",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "මෙරට තත්ත්වය ගැන චීනය සමීප නිරීක්ෂණයක යෙදේ",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ තත්ත්වය වර්ධනය වීම පිළිබඳව චීනය සමීපව නිරීක්‍ෂණය කරමින් සිටින බව චීන විදේශ අමාත්‍යාංශයේ ප්‍රකාශක වැන්ග් වෙන්ග්බින් පවසයි.",
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ සියලුම අංශ, රටේ සහ එහි ජනතාවගේ මූලික අවශ්‍යතා වෙනුවෙන් ක්‍රියා කරනු ඇති බවත්, සමාජ ස්ථාවරත්වය, ආර්ථික ප්‍රකෘතිය සහ ජීවනෝපාය වැඩිදියුණු කිරීම් ඉක්මනින් සාක්ෂාත් කර ගැනීම සඳහා එක්ව කටයුතු කරනු ඇතැයි කියා ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ මිත්‍ර අසල්වැසියෙකු ලෙස චීනය අවංකවම බලාපොරොත්තු වන බවත්  හෙතෙම සඳහන් කළේය.",
        "නිත්‍ය මාධ්‍ය හමුවේදී ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ වත්මන් තත්ත්වය පිළිබඳව අදහස් දැක්වමින් වැන්ග් මේ බව ප්‍රකාශ කළේය.",
        "පෙර නොවූ විරූ ආර්ථික අර්බුදයකින් මාස ගණනාවක කලකිරීමෙන් පසුව, කොළඹ අගනුවර පිහිටි ශ්‍රී ලංකා ජනාධිපති මන්දිරයට සෙනසුරාදා උද්ඝෝෂකයන් කඩා වැදුණු බව පවසන චීන මාධ්‍ය, ජනාධිපතිවරයා සිය නිවසින් බැහැර වී පැය කිහිපයකට පසු එලැඹෙන ජූලි 13දා ඉල්ලා අස්වන බව ප්‍රකාශ කළ බවත් සඳහන් කළේය."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "චීනය",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "චීන විදේශ අමාත්‍යාංශය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Wang Wengbin",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "චීනය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "චීනය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "වැන්ග්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "මාස",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලාංකික",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "සෙනසුරාදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "චීන",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජූලි 13, පැය",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "இந்த நாட்டின் நிலைமையை சீனா உன்னிப்பாக கவனித்து வருகிறது",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "இலங்கையில் ஏற்பட்டுள்ள நிலைமையை சீனா உன்னிப்பாக அவதானித்து வருவதாக சீன வெளிவிவகார அமைச்சின் பேச்சாளர் வாங் வெங்பின் தெரிவித்துள்ளார்.",
        "இலங்கையின் நட்பு அண்டை நாடான சீனா, இலங்கையின் அனைத்துத் துறைகளும் நாட்டின் மற்றும் அதன் மக்களின் அடிப்படைத் தேவைகளுக்காக பாடுபடுவதோடு, சமூக ஸ்திரத்தன்மை, பொருளாதார மீட்சி மற்றும் வாழ்வாதார மேம்பாடுகளை விரைவாக அடைய ஒன்றிணைந்து செயல்படும் என்று உண்மையாக நம்புவதாக அவர் கூறினார்.",
        "வழமையான ஊடகவியலாளர் சந்திப்பில் இலங்கையின் தற்போதைய நிலைமை குறித்து கருத்து தெரிவிக்கும் போதே வாங் இவ்வாறு தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "முன்னோடியில்லாத பொருளாதார நெருக்கடியால் பல மாதங்களாக விரக்தியடைந்த பின்னர், சனிக்கிழமையன்று தலைநகர் கொழும்பில் உள்ள இலங்கை ஜனாதிபதி மாளிகையை எதிர்ப்பாளர்கள் முற்றுகையிட்டனர், சீன ஊடகங்கள், ஜனாதிபதி தனது வீட்டை விட்டு வெளியேறிய சில மணிநேரங்களுக்குப் பிறகு ஜூலை 13 அன்று ராஜினாமா செய்வதாக அறிவித்தார்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "சீனா",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "சீன வெளியுறவு அமைச்சகம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Wang Wengbin",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "சீனா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "சீனா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "வாங்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "மாதங்கள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "சனிக்கிழமை",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சீன",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜூலை 13, மணி",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}