{
  "newspaper_id": "tamil-mirror-lk",
  "url": "https://www.tamilmirror.lk/செய்திகள்/இலங்கை-சட்டத்தரணிகள்-சங்கம்-வெளியிட்டுள்ள-அறிக்கை/175-300508",
  "time_ut": 1657914896,
  "original_lang": "ta",
  "original_title": "இலங்கை சட்டத்தரணிகள் சங்கம் வெளியிட்டுள்ள அறிக்கை",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "A report issued by the Sri Lankan Bar Association",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "The Bar Association of Sri Lanka has requested all party leaders to act swiftly to rebuild public confidence in Sri Lanka's legal and constitutional mechanisms.",
        "It is titled Statement of the Sri Lankan Bar Association on the Resignation of President Gotabaya Rajapaksa.",
        "The President of the Sri Lanka Bar Association, President Advocate Saliya Peiris, and Secretary Advocate Isuru Balapattabendi have signed it.",
        "In a situation where the country is suffering from social, political and economic instability, it has been mentioned in the statement issued by the Bar Association that members of parliament should act quickly to avoid further deterioration of the situation. (a)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "the Sri Lankan Bar Association",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "The Bar Association of Sri Lanka",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka's",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the Sri Lankan Bar Association",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Gotabaya Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the Sri Lanka Bar Association",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Advocate Saliya Peiris",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Advocate Isuru",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the Bar Association",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "ශ්‍රී ලංකා නීතිඥ සංගමය නිකුත් කළ වාර්තාවකි",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ නීතිමය සහ ව්‍යවස්ථාපිත යාන්ත්‍රණයන් පිළිබඳව මහජන විශ්වාසය යළි ගොඩනැගීම සඳහා කඩිනමින් ක්‍රියා කරන ලෙස ශ්‍රී ලංකා නීතීඥ සංගමය සියලුම පක්ෂ නායකයින්ගෙන් ඉල්ලීමක් කර තිබේ.",
        "එය නම් කර ඇත්තේ ජනාධිපති ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂගේ ඉල්ලා අස්වීම පිළිබඳ ශ්‍රී ලංකා නීතිඥ සංගමයේ ප්‍රකාශය ලෙසයි.",
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකා නීතීඥ සංගමයේ සභාපති, සභාපති අධිනීතිඥ සාලිය පීරිස් සහ ලේකම් අධිනීතිඥ ඉසුරු බාලපට්ටබැඳි යන මහත්වරුන් ඊට අත්සන් තබා ඇත.",
        "රට සමාජ, දේශපාලන සහ ආර්ථික අස්ථාවරත්වයකින් පෙළෙන තත්ත්වයක් තුළ එම තත්ත්වය තවදුරටත් පිරිහීම වැළැක්වීමට මන්ත්‍රීවරුන් කඩිනමින් ක්‍රියා කළ යුතු බව නීතිඥ සංගමය නිකුත් කළ නිවේදනයේ සඳහන් වේ. (ඒ)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකා නීතිඥ සංගමය",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකා නීතිඥ සංගමය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකා නීතිඥ සංගමය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකා නීතිඥ සංගමය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "නීතිඥ සාලිය පීරිස්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "අධිනීතිඥ ඉසුරු",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "නීතිඥ සංගමය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "இலங்கை சட்டத்தரணிகள் சங்கம் வெளியிட்டுள்ள அறிக்கை",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "இலங்கையின் சட்டம் மற்றும் அரசியலமைப்பு பொறிமுறைகளில் பொதுமக்களின் நம்பிக்கையை மீள கட்டியெழுப்பும் நோக்கில், விரைவாக செயற்படுமாறு அனைத்து கட்சித் தலைவர்களிடமும் இலங்கை சட்டத்தரணிகள் சங்கம் கோரிக்கை விடுத்துள்ளது.",
        "ஜனாதிபதி கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ஸவின் பதவி விலகல் குறித்தான இலங்கை சட்டத்தரணிகள் சங்கத்தின் அறிக்கை என அதற்கு தலைப்பிடப்பட்டுள்ளது.",
        "இலங்கை சட்டத்தரணிகள் சங்கத்தின் தலைவர், ஜனாதிபதி சட்டத்தரணி சாலிய பீரிஸ், செயலாளர் சட்டத்தரணி இசுறு பாலபட்டபெந்தி ஆகியோர் அதில் கையொப்பம் இட்டிருக்கின்றார்கள்.",
        "நாடு சமூக, அரசியல், பொருளாதார ஸ்திரமின்மை போன்றவற்றால் பாதிக்கப்பட்டுள்ள சூழ்நிலையில், நிலைமை மேலும் மோசமடைவதை தவிர்ப்பதற்காக பாராளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர்கள் விரைந்து செயற்பட வேண்டும் என சட்டத்தரணிகள் சங்கம் விடுத்துள்ள அறிக்கையில் குறிப்பிடப்பட்டுள்ளது. (a)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "இலங்கை சட்டத்தரணிகள் சங்கம்",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை சட்டத்தரணிகள் சங்கம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கையின்",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை சட்டத்தரணிகள் சங்கம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை சட்டத்தரணிகள் சங்கம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "சட்டத்தரணி சாலிய பீரிஸ்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "வழக்கறிஞர் இசுரு",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "வழக்கறிஞர் சங்கம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}