{
  "newspaper_id": "ada-lk",
  "url": "https://www.ada.lk/international/තායිවානය-මුල්කර-චීනයෙන්-ඇමෙරිකාවට-අනතුරු-ඇඟවීම්/3-396303",
  "time_ut": 1660540039,
  "original_lang": "si",
  "original_title": "තායිවානය මුල්කර චීනයෙන් ඇමෙරිකාවට අනතුරු ඇඟවීම්",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Warnings from China to America based on Taiwan",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "China opposes any form of official relations between the US and the Taiwan region, and should expect resolute countermeasures in response to US provocations, said Liu Pengyu, a spokesman for the Chinese Embassy in the US.",
        "A fresh visit by a bipartisan US congressional delegation to Taiwan on Sunday shows the US does not want to see stability across the Taiwan Strait, described by the US as meddling in the internal affairs of both sides and China.",
        "\"The responsibility for the current tension across the Taiwan Strait rests entirely with the US side. They should bear all the consequences of the relevant lawmakers coming to Taiwan,\" he said."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "China",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "America",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "Taiwan",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "China",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "US",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Taiwan",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "US",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Liu Pengyu",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Chinese Embassy",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "US",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "US",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Taiwan",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sunday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "US",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Taiwan Strait",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "US",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "China",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the Taiwan Strait",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "US",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Taiwan",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "තායිවානය මුල්කර චීනයෙන් ඇමෙරිකාවට අනතුරු ඇඟවීම්",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "එක්සත් ජනපදය සහ තායිවාන කලාපය අතර ඕනෑම ආකාරයක නිල සබඳතාවලට චීනය විරුද්ධ වන බවත්, එක්සත් ජනපදයේ ප්‍රකෝප කිරීම්වලට ප්‍රතිචාර වශයෙන් අධිෂ්ඨානශීලී ප්‍රතිප්‍රහාර බලාපොරොත්තු විය යුතු බවත් එක්සත් ජනපදයේ චීන තානාපති කාර්යාලයේ ප්‍රකාශක ලියු පෙන්ග්යු පවසයි.",
        "ඉරිදා තායිවානයට පියාසර කළ එක්සත් ජනපද ද්විපාර්ශ්වික කොංග්‍රස් දූත පිරිසකගේ නැවුම් සංචාරය, තායිවාන සමුද්‍ර සන්ධිය හරහා ස්ථාවරත්වයක් දැකීමට එක්සත් ජනපදයට අවශ්‍ය නොවන බව පෙන්නුම් කරන අතරම, මෙය ඇමෙරිකාව විසින් දෙපාර්ශ්වය සහ චීනයේ අභ්‍යන්තර කටයුතුවලට මැදිහත් වීමක් ලෙස විස්තර කෙරෙයි.",
        "\"තායිවාන් සමුද්‍ර සන්ධිය හරහා පවතින වත්මන් ආතතියේ වගකීම සම්පූර්ණයෙන්ම එක්සත් ජනපද පාර්ශ්වය වෙත පැවරී තිබෙනවා. අදාළ නීති සම්පාදකයින් තායිවානයට පැමිණීම නිසා ඇතිවන සියලු ප්‍රතිවිපාක ඔවුන් විඳදරාගත යුතුයි\" ඔහු පැවසීය."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "චීනය",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "ඇමරිකාව",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "තායිවානය",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "චීනය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "එක්සත් ජනපදය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "තායිවානය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "එක්සත් ජනපදය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Liu Pengyu",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "චීන තානාපති කාර්යාලය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "එක්සත් ජනපදය",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "එක්සත් ජනපදය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "තායිවානය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉරිදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "එක්සත් ජනපදය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "තායිවාන් සමුද්‍ර සන්ධිය",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "එක්සත් ජනපදය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "චීනය",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "තායිවාන් සමුද්‍ර සන්ධිය",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "එක්සත් ජනපදය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "තායිවානය",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "தைவானின் அடிப்படையில் சீனாவிலிருந்து அமெரிக்காவிற்கு எச்சரிக்கைகள்",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "அமெரிக்காவிற்கும் தைவான் பிராந்தியத்திற்கும் இடையிலான உத்தியோகபூர்வ உறவுகளை சீனா எதிர்க்கிறது, மேலும் அமெரிக்க ஆத்திரமூட்டல்களுக்கு பதிலளிக்கும் வகையில் உறுதியான எதிர் நடவடிக்கைகளை எதிர்பார்க்க வேண்டும் என்று அமெரிக்காவில் உள்ள சீன தூதரகத்தின் செய்தித் தொடர்பாளர் லியு பெங்யு கூறினார்.",
        "ஞாயிறு அன்று தைவானுக்கு ஒரு இரு கட்சி அமெரிக்க காங்கிரஸ் தூதுக்குழுவின் புதிய விஜயம், தைவான் ஜலசந்தி முழுவதும் அமெரிக்கா ஸ்திரத்தன்மையைக் காண விரும்பவில்லை என்பதைக் காட்டுகிறது, இது இரு தரப்பு மற்றும் சீனாவின் உள் விவகாரங்களில் அமெரிக்கா தலையிடுவதாக விவரிக்கிறது.",
        "\"தைவான் ஜலசந்தியின் தற்போதைய பதற்றத்திற்கான பொறுப்பு முழுவதுமாக அமெரிக்க தரப்பைச் சார்ந்தது. சம்பந்தப்பட்ட சட்டமியற்றுபவர்கள் தைவானுக்கு வருவதால் ஏற்படும் அனைத்து விளைவுகளையும் அவர்கள் ஏற்க வேண்டும்,\" என்று அவர் கூறினார்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "சீனா",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "அமெரிக்கா",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "தைவான்",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "சீனா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "எங்களுக்கு",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "தைவான்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "எங்களுக்கு",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Liu Pengyu",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "சீன தூதரகம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "எங்களுக்கு",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "எங்களுக்கு",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "தைவான்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஞாயிற்றுக்கிழமை",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "எங்களுக்கு",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "தைவான் ஜலசந்தி",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "எங்களுக்கு",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சீனா",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "தைவான் ஜலசந்தி",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "எங்களுக்கு",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "தைவான்",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}