{
  "newspaper_id": "lankadeepa-lk",
  "url": "https://www.lankadeepa.lk/politics/මූල්‍ය-ආධාර---සහන-ගැනීමට-ජනපති-කැබිනට්-කමිටු-3ක්/13-609523",
  "time_ut": 1646842283,
  "original_lang": "si",
  "original_title": "මූල්‍ය ආධාර - සහන ගැනීමට ජනපති කැබිනට් කමිටු 3ක්",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Financial assistance - 3 Presidential Cabinet Committees to take relief",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "Foreign Minister Professor G. said that President Gotabhaya Rajapaksa has appointed three cabinet committees to negotiate with the countries and obtain financial assistance and relief. L. Mr. Peiris said.",
        "The minister said that the three committees are working in discussions with China, Japan and the Middle East countries and also mentioned that the committee is working with the aim of getting some relief by negotiating with those countries very quickly regarding things like import goods needed by the country.",
        "The minister also said that 31 of the 45 countries that participated in the discussion on Sri Lanka in the 49th session of the Human Rights Council directly supported and approved the position of Sri Lanka, which is a big victory for our country.",
        "Minister Prof. G. said that those countries expressed a clear conclusion that Sri Lanka's position is normal and that position should be accepted by the international community. L. Mr. Peiris also mentioned that it was possible to get this successful result because of unity and working as a collective effort.",
        "Out of the 81 Sri Lankan citizens who were in the middle of the war in Ukraine, 15 are students and 39 of the remaining 66 have already left Ukraine and gone to Poland, Romania, Germany and the 27 people who are currently there do not want to leave Ukraine. said",
        "Foreign Minister Professor G. L. Mr. Peiris said so.",
        "\"The discussion regarding Sri Lanka in the 49th session of the Human Rights Council in Geneva ended yesterday. We presented Sri Lanka's position very clearly. I had two opportunities to address the Geneva Human Rights Council. On both occasions, I presented certain facts regarding the practical progress that Sri Lanka has made on all these issues.",
        "A great victory for our country, a great satisfaction for us, 31 of the 45 countries that participated in the discussion about Sri Lanka directly approved our position and supported it.",
        "I presented both lectures with five main points. First, the international community was asked if this was fair. There has been a great war in Europe. Then, in the midst of all this, is the attention given to Sri Lanka internal? Is there any meaning about the time and effort that Midangu spends on that? All those people were earnestly asked to know what is the reason for pursuing our country.",
        "Secondly, 80 percent of the contents of Mrs. Michelle Bachelet's report are about the internal issues of this country. Not issues that affect the international in any way. It is a question whether this comes under the scope of the Human Rights Council at all. As a third point, if investigations are being conducted on the internal issues of our country in this way, why is it that only Sri Lanka is being pursued without investigating other countries? And the fourth point is that the huge amount of money spent in this regard is spent in the bad situation of today's world. Regarding Sri Lanka, which is living in a loss that does no harm to anyone, the question was raised that the millions of dollars spent on a massive offensive program are at all reasonable. As the fifth point, I stated that there is no benefit from the money being spent or a huge loss. It divides the world into two. No one benefited from this. I presented these five points and 31 out of 45 countries accepted those arguments. It is a great victory for our country."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "3",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "G.",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Gotabhaya Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "three",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "L.",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Peiris",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "three",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "China",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Japan",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Middle East",
            "label": "LOC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "31",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "45",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Human Rights Council",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "G.",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka's",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "L.",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Peiris",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "81",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lankan",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ukraine",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "15",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "39",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "66",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ukraine",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Poland",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Romania",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Germany",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "27",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ukraine",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "G. L.",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Peiris",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Human Rights Council",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Geneva",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "yesterday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka's",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "two",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Geneva Human Rights Council",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "31",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "45",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "five",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "First",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Europe",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Midangu",
            "label": "LOC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Secondly",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Michelle Bachelet's",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Human Rights Council",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "third",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "fourth",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the millions of dollars",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "fifth",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "two",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "five",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "31",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "45",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "මූල්‍ය ආධාර - සහන ගැනීමට ජනපති කැබිනට් කමිටු 3ක්",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "රටවල් සමඟ සාකච්ඡා කර මූල්‍ය ආධාර සහ සහන ලබාගැනීමට ජනාධිපති ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ මහතා කැබිනට් කමිටු තුනක් පත්කර ඇති බවත් එම කමිටුවල ප‍්‍රධානියා ලෙස තමන් කටයුතු කරන බවත් විදේශ අමාත්‍ය මහාචාර්ය ජී. එල්. පීරිස් මහතා පැවැසීය.",
        "චීනය, ජපානය සහ මැදපෙරදිග රටවල් සමඟ එම කමිටු තුන සාකච්ඡා කර කටයුතු කරන බව කී අමාත්‍යවරයා රටට අවශ්‍ය ආනයන භාණ්ඩ වැනි දේවල් සම්බන්ධයෙන් එම රටවල් සමග ඉතා ඉක්මනින් සාකච්ඡා කර යම්කිසි සහනයක් ලබා ගැනීමේ අරමුණ ඇතිව එම කමිටුව කටයුතු කරන බව ද සඳහන් කළේය.",
        "මානව හිමිකම් කවුන්සිලයේ 49 සැසිවාරයේදී ශ‍්‍රී ලංකාව පිළිබඳව සාකච්ඡාවට සහාභාගී වූ රටවල් 45 න් 31 ක් සෘජුව ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ ස්ථාවරය අනුමත කරමින් සහයෝගය දීම අපේ රට ලැබූ විශාල ජයග‍්‍රහණයක් බව ද අමාත්‍යවරයා කීය.",
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ ස්ථාවරය සාධරණ සහ එම ස්ථාවරය ජාත්‍යන්තරය පිළිගත යුතු යැයි පැහැදිලි නිගමනය එම රටවල් ප‍්‍රකාශ කළ බව කී අමාත්‍ය මහාචාර්ය ජී. එල්. පීරිස් මහතා එකමුතුව සහ සාමුහික ප‍්‍රයත්නයක් ලෙස කටයුතු කිරීම නිසා මෙම සාර්ථක ප‍්‍රතිඵලය ලබාගැනීමට හැකි වූ බව ද සඳහන් කළේය.",
        "යුක්රේනයේ යුද්ධයට මැදිව සිටි ශ‍්‍රී ලංකා පුරවැසියන් 81 දෙනාගෙන් 15 ශිෂ්‍යයන් බවත් ඉතිරි 66 දෙනාගෙන් 39 ක් මේ වන විටත් යුක්රේනය අතහැර පෝලන්තය, රුමේනියාව, ජර්මනියට යන රටවල්වල ගොස් ඇති අතර මේ වන විට එහි සිටින පුද්ගලයන් 27 දෙනා යුක්රේනය අතහැර යෑමට අවශ්‍ය නොමැති බව දැනුම්දී ඇති බවත් අමාත්‍යවරයා කීය.",
        "බෙත්තරමුල්ල, නෙළුම් මාවත පොදුජන පෙරමුණ පක්‍ෂ කාර්යාලයේදී අද පැවැති මාධ්‍ය හමුවේදී විදේශ අමාත්‍ය මහාචාර්ය ජී. එල්. පීරිස් මහතා එසේ පැවසීය.",
        "”ජිනිවා නගරයේ මානව හිමිකම් කවුන්සිලයේ 49 සැසිවාරයේ ශ්‍රී ලංකාව සම්බන්ධයෙන් සාකච්ඡාව ඊයේ අවසන් වුණා. අපි ඉතාමත් පැහැදිලිව ඉදිරිපත් කළා ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ ස්ථාවරය. ජිනිවා මානව හිමිකම් කවුන්සිලයේ ඇමතීමට මට අවස්ථා දෙකක් ලැබුණා. ඒ අවස්ථා දෙකේදීම මම යම් යම් කරුණු ඉදිරිපත්කරමින් කියා සිටියේ මේ සියලූම ප‍්‍රශ්න සම්බන්ධයෙන් ශ‍්‍රී ලංකාව ප‍්‍රායෝගික වශයෙන් ලබාගෙන තිබෙන ප‍්‍රගතිය පිළීබඳව.",
        "අපේ රටට විශාල ජයග‍්‍රහණයක්, අපිට ඉමහත් තෘප්තියක් ශ‍්‍රී ලංකාව පිළිබඳව සාකච්ඡාවට සහාභාගී වූ රටවල් 45 න් 31 ක් සෘජුව අපේ ස්ථාවරය අනුමත කළ සේම ඒ සඳහා සහයෝගය දුන්නා.",
        "මම දේශන දෙකම ඉදිරිපත් කළේ ප‍්‍රධාන මූලික කරුණු පහකින්. පළමුව ජාත්‍යන්තර ප‍්‍රජාවගෙන් විමසුවා මෙය සාධාරණ ද කියලා. යුරෝපයේ මහ සංග‍්‍රාමයක් ඇති වෙලා තිබෙනවා. එවිට මේ සියල්ලක් මධ්‍යයේ ශ‍්‍රී ලංකාව පිළිබඳව දක්වන අවධානය තුළනාත්මක ද. ඒ සම්බන්ධයෙන් මිඩංගු කරන කාලය, උත්සහය පිළිබඳව අර්ථයක් තිබෙනවාද? අපේ රට ලූහුබැඳ ගෙන යෑමට ඇති හේතුව කුමක්ද කියලා ඒ සියලූ දෙනාගෙන්ම ඕනෑකමින් ඉල්ලා සිටියා.",
        "දෙවැනි කරුණ ලෙස මිෂෙල් බැචලේ මැතිණියගේ වාර්තාවේ අන්තර්ගත කරුණුවලින් සියයට 80 ක් තිබෙන්නේ මේ රටේ අභ්‍යන්තර ප‍්‍රශ්න පිළිබඳවයි. ජාත්‍යන්තරයට කිසිම විදිහට බලපාන ප‍්‍රශ්න නොවේ. මේ පිළිබඳව මානව හිමිකම් කවුන්සිලයේ විෂය පථයට කිසිසේත් ඇතුලූ වෙනවාද කියලා ප‍්‍රශ්නයක්. තුන්වන කරුණ ලෙස මේ විදිහට අපේ රටේ අභ්‍යන්තර ප‍්‍රශ්න පිළිබඳව විමර්ශන පවත්වනවා නම් වෙන රටවල් සම්බන්ධයෙන් විමර්ශන නොකර විශේෂයෙන් ලංකාව පමණක් ලූහුබැඳ ගෙන යන්නේ ඇයි කියලා මම ප‍්‍රකාශ කළා. ඒ වගේම හතරවෙනි කරුණ තමයි මේ සම්බන්ධයෙන් වියදම් කරන අති විශාල මුදල් ප‍්‍රමාණයන් වියදම් කරන්නේ අද ලෝකයේ තිබෙන අයහපත් තත්වයක් තුළ තමයි. කාටවත් කිසිම හානියක් නොකරන පාඩුවේ ජිවත්වන ශ‍්‍රී ලංකාව සම්බන්ධයෙන් මහා දැවැන්ත ප‍්‍රහාරාත්මක වැඩපිළිවෙළක් සඳහා වියදම් කරන ඩොලර් මිලියන ගාන කිසිසේත් සාධරණ ද කියන ප‍්‍රශ්නය යොමු කළා. පස්වෙනි කාරණය ලෙස මම ප‍්‍රකාශ කළේ මේ වියදම් කරන මුදල් වලින් කිසිම ප‍්‍රයෝජනයක් වෙනවාද නැතිනම් දැවැන්ත හානියක් ද කියලා. එයින් ජාත්‍යන්තරය දෙකට බෙදෙනවා. මෙයින් කිසිම ප‍්‍රයෝජනයක් කාටවත් වුණේ නෑ. මා මෙම කරුණු පහ ඉදිරිපත් කළ අතර රටවල් 45 න් රටවල් 31 ඒ තර්ක පිළිගත්තා. එය අපේ රටට ලොකු ජයග‍්‍රහණයක්."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "3",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ජී.",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "තුන්",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "එල්.",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "පීරිස්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "තුන්",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "චීනය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජපානය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මැද පෙරදිග",
            "label": "LOC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "31",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "45",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මානව හිමිකම් කවුන්සිලය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ජී.",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "එල්.",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "පීරිස්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "81",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලාංකික",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "යුක්රේනය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "15",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "39",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "66",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "යුක්රේනය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "පෝලන්තය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "රුමේනියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජර්මනිය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "27",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "යුක්රේනය",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ජී.එල්.",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "පීරිස්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මානව හිමිකම් කවුන්සිලය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජිනීවා",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඊයේ",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "දෙක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජිනීවා මානව හිමිකම් කවුන්සිලය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "31",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "45",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "පහ",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "පළමුවන",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "යුරෝපය",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Midangu",
            "label": "LOC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "දෙවනුව",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "මිෂෙල් බැචලට්ගේ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "මානව හිමිකම් කවුන්සිලය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "තෙවන",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "හතරවන",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඩොලර් මිලියන ගණනක්",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "පස්වන",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "දෙක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "පහ",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "31",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "45",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "நிதி உதவி - நிவாரணம் எடுக்க 3 ஜனாதிபதி அமைச்சரவை குழுக்கள்",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "நாடுகளுடன் பேச்சுவார்த்தை நடத்தி நிதியுதவி மற்றும் நிவாரணங்களைப் பெற்றுக் கொள்வதற்காக மூன்று அமைச்சரவைக் குழுக்களை ஜனாதிபதி கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ஷ நியமித்துள்ளதாக வெளிவிவகார அமைச்சர் பேராசிரியர் ஜீ. எல். பீரிஸ் தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "இந்த மூன்று குழுக்களும் சீனா, ஜப்பான் மற்றும் மத்திய கிழக்கு நாடுகளுடன் பேச்சுவார்த்தை நடத்தி வருவதாக கூறிய அமைச்சர், அந்த நாடுகளுக்கு தேவையான பொருட்களை இறக்குமதி செய்வது போன்ற விஷயங்களில் மிக விரைவாக பேச்சுவார்த்தை நடத்தி ஓரளவு நிவாரணம் பெறும் நோக்கில் குழு செயல்பட்டு வருவதாகவும் குறிப்பிட்டார். நாடு.",
        "மனித உரிமைகள் பேரவையின் 49வது அமர்வில் இலங்கை தொடர்பான விவாதத்தில் கலந்து கொண்ட 45 நாடுகளில் 31 நாடுகள் இலங்கையின் நிலைப்பாட்டை நேரடியாக ஆதரித்து அங்கீகரித்துள்ளது எமது நாட்டுக்கு கிடைத்த பாரிய வெற்றி எனவும் அமைச்சர் தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "இலங்கையின் நிலைப்பாடு இயல்பானது என்றும் அந்த நிலைப்பாட்டை சர்வதேசம் ஏற்றுக்கொள்ள வேண்டும் என்றும் அந்த நாடுகள் தெளிவான முடிவை தெரிவித்ததாக அமைச்சர் பேராசிரியர் ஜி. எல். ஒற்றுமை மற்றும் கூட்டு முயற்சியாக செயற்பட்டதன் காரணமாகவே இந்த வெற்றிகரமான பெறுபேற்றை பெற முடிந்ததாகவும் திரு.பீரிஸ் குறிப்பிட்டுள்ளார்.",
        "உக்ரேனில் போரின் நடுவில் இருந்த 81 இலங்கை பிரஜைகளில் 15 பேர் மாணவர்கள், மீதமுள்ள 66 பேரில் 39 பேர் ஏற்கனவே உக்ரைனை விட்டு வெளியேறி போலந்து, ருமேனியா, ஜேர்மனி ஆகிய நாடுகளுக்குச் சென்றுள்ளனர், தற்போது அங்குள்ள 27 பேர் விரும்பவில்லை. உக்ரைனை விட்டு வெளியேற வேண்டும் என்றார்",
        "வெளியுறவு அமைச்சர் பேராசிரியர் ஜி. எல். பீரிஸ் இவ்வாறு தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "“ஜெனீவாவில் மனித உரிமைகள் பேரவையின் 49வது அமர்வில் இலங்கை தொடர்பான விவாதம் நேற்றுடன் நிறைவடைந்தது. இலங்கையின் நிலைப்பாட்டை மிகத் தெளிவாக முன்வைத்தோம். ஜெனிவா மனித உரிமைகள் பேரவையில் உரையாற்றுவதற்கு எனக்கு இரண்டு சந்தர்ப்பங்கள் கிடைத்தன. இரண்டு சந்தர்ப்பங்களிலும், இந்த அனைத்து விடயங்களிலும் இலங்கை அடைந்துள்ள நடைமுறை முன்னேற்றம் தொடர்பான சில உண்மைகளை நான் முன்வைத்தேன்.",
        "எமது நாட்டுக்கு கிடைத்த மாபெரும் வெற்றி, எமக்கு பெரும் திருப்தி, இலங்கை தொடர்பான கலந்துரையாடலில் கலந்து கொண்ட 45 நாடுகளில் 31 நாடுகள் எமது நிலைப்பாட்டை நேரடியாக அங்கீகரித்து ஆதரவளித்தன.",
        "நான் இரண்டு விரிவுரைகளையும் ஐந்து முக்கிய புள்ளிகளுடன் முன்வைத்தேன். முதலில், இது நியாயமா என்று சர்வதேச சமூகத்திடம் கேட்கப்பட்டது. ஐரோப்பாவில் பெரும் போர் நடந்துள்ளது. அப்படியானால், இத்தனைக்கும் மத்தியில் இலங்கைக்கு உள்நாட்டில் கவனம் செலுத்தப்படுகிறதா? மிடாங்கு அதற்காகச் செலவிடும் நேரமும் உழைப்பும் ஏதேனும் பொருள் உள்ளதா? அந்த மக்கள் அனைவரும் நம் நாட்டை பின்தொடர்வதற்கான காரணம் என்ன என்பதை அறிய ஆர்வமாக கேட்கப்பட்டனர்.",
        "இரண்டாவதாக, திருமதி மிஷேல் பச்லெட்டின் அறிக்கையின் உள்ளடக்கங்களில் 80 வீதமானவை இந்நாட்டின் உள்நாட்டுப் பிரச்சினைகள் பற்றியவை. சர்வதேசத்தை எந்த வகையிலும் பாதிக்கும் பிரச்சினைகள் அல்ல. இது மனித உரிமைகள் பேரவையின் எல்லைக்குள் வருமா என்பது கேள்விக்குறியே. மூன்றாவது விடயமாக, இவ்வாறு எமது நாட்டின் உள்நாட்டுப் பிரச்சினைகள் தொடர்பில் விசாரணைகள் நடத்தப்படுமானால், ஏனைய நாடுகளை விசாரிக்காமல் இலங்கையை மட்டும் பின்தொடர்வது ஏன்? மேலும் நான்காவது விடயம், இதற்காக செலவிடப்படும் பெரும் தொகை இன்றைய உலகின் மோசமான சூழ்நிலையில் செலவிடப்படுகிறது. எவருக்கும் தீங்கு விளைவிக்காத நஷ்டத்தில் வாழும் இலங்கை தொடர்பில், பாரிய தாக்குதல் வேலைத்திட்டத்திற்கு செலவிடப்பட்ட மில்லியன் கணக்கான டொலர்கள் நியாயமானதே என கேள்வி எழுப்பப்பட்டது. ஐந்தாவது புள்ளியாக, செலவழித்த பணத்தால் எந்தப் பயனும் இல்லை அல்லது பெரும் நஷ்டமும் இல்லை என்று தெரிவித்தேன். இது உலகை இரண்டாகப் பிரிக்கிறது. இதனால் யாருக்கும் பலன் இல்லை. நான் இந்த ஐந்து கருத்துக்களை முன்வைத்தேன், 45 நாடுகளில் 31 நாடுகள் அந்த வாதங்களை ஏற்றுக்கொண்டன. இது நம் நாட்டுக்கு கிடைத்த மாபெரும் வெற்றி."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "3",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ஜி.",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "கோத்தபாய ராஜபக்ச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "மூன்று",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "எல்.",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "பீரிஸ்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "மூன்று",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "சீனா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜப்பான்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "மத்திய கிழக்கு",
            "label": "LOC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "31",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "45",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "மனித உரிமைகள் பேரவை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஜி.",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கையின்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "எல்.",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "பீரிஸ்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "81",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "உக்ரைன்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "15",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "39",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "66",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "உக்ரைன்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "போலந்து",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ருமேனியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜெர்மனி",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "27",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "உக்ரைன்",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஜி.எல்.",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "பீரிஸ்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "மனித உரிமைகள் பேரவை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜெனீவா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "நேற்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கையின்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இரண்டு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜெனிவா மனித உரிமைகள் பேரவை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "31",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "45",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஐந்து",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "முதலில்",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஐரோப்பா",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Midangu",
            "label": "LOC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இரண்டாவதாக",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "மைக்கேல் பேச்லெட்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "மனித உரிமைகள் பேரவை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "மூன்றாவது",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "நான்காவது",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "மில்லியன் டாலர்கள்",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஐந்தாவது",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "இரண்டு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஐந்து",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "31",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "45",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}