{
  "newspaper_id": "virakesari-lk",
  "url": "http://www.virakesari.lk/article/130577",
  "time_ut": 1656671675,
  "original_lang": "ta",
  "original_title": "இலங்கையில் சீனத்திட்டங்களை விரிவுபடுத்துவது குறித்து சீனத்தூதுவர் அமைச்சர் தம்மிக பெரேராவுடன் பேச்சுவார்த்தை",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Talks with Chinese Ambassador to Sri Lanka Dammika Perera on Expansion of Chinese Projects in Sri Lanka",
      "author": "T. Saranya",
      "body_lines": [
        "Chinese Ambassador to Sri Lanka Chi Chenhong has held discussions with Minister for Technology and Investment Promotion Tammika Perera regarding the expansion of Chinese projects in Sri Lanka.",
        "Encouraging Chinese investment was discussed during a recent meeting between Chinese Ambassador to Sri Lanka Xi Senhong and Minister of Technology and Investment Promotion Tammika Perera at the Chinese Embassy in Colombo.",
        "A gazette notification was issued last week to bring significant structures under Dammika Perera's Ministry of Technology and Investment Promotion, including some projects being carried out in Sri Lanka with Chinese funding.",
        "Accordingly, Minister Thammika Perera has been entrusted with the challenging responsibility of promoting foreign investment and private investment in Sri Lanka, which is facing a massive economic crisis.",
        "It is in this context that the meeting with the Chinese Ambassador to Sri Lanka discussed the promotion of Chinese investment in Sri Lanka and the expansion of existing projects."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Chinese",
          "label": "NORP"
        },
        {
          "text": "Sri Lanka Dammika Perera on Expansion of Chinese Projects",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "Sri Lanka",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Chinese",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka Chi Chenhong",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Chinese",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Chinese",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Chinese",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Xi Senhong",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Chinese",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Colombo",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "last week",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Dammika Perera's",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ministry of Technology and Investment Promotion",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Chinese",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Thammika Perera",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Chinese",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Chinese",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ චීන ව්‍යාපෘති ව්‍යාප්ත කිරීම සම්බන්ධයෙන් චීන තානාපති අමාත්‍ය ටම්මික පෙරේරා සමඟ සාකච්ඡා",
      "author": "T. Saranya",
      "body_lines": [
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ චීන තානාපති ෂී ෂෙන්හොං මහතා ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ චීන ව්‍යාපෘති පුළුල් කිරීම පිළිබඳව තාක්ෂණ හා ආයෝජන ප්‍රවර්ධන අමාත්‍ය දම්මික පෙරේරා මහතා සමඟ සාකච්ඡා කළේය.",
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ චීන තානාපති ෂී හොංකොං මහතා සහ තාක්ෂණ හා ආයෝජන ප්‍රවර්ධන අමාත්‍ය දම්මික පෙරේරා මහතා අතර පසුගියදා කොළඹ චීන තානාපති කාර්යාලයේ පැවැති සාකච්ඡාවේදී චීන ආයෝජන දිරිගැන්වීම පිළිබඳව සාකච්ඡා කෙරිණි.",
        "දම්මික පෙරේරා මහතාගේ තාක්ෂණ හා ආයෝජන ප්‍රවර්ධන අමාත්‍යාංශය යටතට ගෙන ඒම සඳහා වූ ගැසට් නිවේදනයක් පසුගිය සතියේ නිකුත් කෙරුණු අතර, චීන ආධාර මත ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ සිදු කෙරෙන ඇතැම් ව්‍යාපෘති ද ඇතුළත් ය.",
        "ඒ අනුව විශාල ආර්ථික අර්බුදයකට මුහුණ පා සිටින ශ්‍රී ලංකාව තුළ විදේශ ආයෝජන සහ පෞද්ගලික ආයෝජන දිරිගැන්වීමේ අභියෝගාත්මක වගකීම පැවරී ඇත්තේ ධම්මික පෙරේරා ඇමැතිවරයාටය.",
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ චීන තානාපතිවරයා සමඟ පැවති සාකච්ඡාවේදී ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ චීන ආයෝජන ප්‍රවර්ධනය කිරීම සහ දැනට ක්‍රියාත්මක ව්‍යාපෘති පුළුල් කිරීම පිළිබඳව සාකච්ඡා කර ඇත්තේ මේ තත්ත්වය යටතේය."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "චීන",
          "label": "NORP"
        },
        {
          "text": "චීන ව්‍යාපෘති පුළුල් කිරීම පිළිබඳව ශ්‍රී ලංකා දම්මික පෙරේරා",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "චීන",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka Chi Chenhong",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "චීන",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "චීන",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "චීන",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Xi Senhong",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "චීන",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "කොළඹ",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ගිය සතිය",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "දම්මික පෙරේරාගේ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "තාක්ෂණ හා ආයෝජන ප්‍රවර්ධන අමාත්‍යාංශය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "චීන",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "තම්මික පෙරේරා",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "චීන",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "චීන",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "இலங்கையில் சீனத்திட்டங்களை விரிவுபடுத்துவது குறித்து சீனத்தூதுவர் அமைச்சர் தம்மிக பெரேராவுடன் பேச்சுவார்த்தை",
      "author": "T. Saranya",
      "body_lines": [
        "இலங்கையில் சீனத்திட்டங்களை விரிவுபடுத்துவது குறித்து இலங்கைக்கான சீனத்தூதுவர் சி சென்ஹொங் தொழில்நுட்ப, முதலீட்டு ஊக்குவிப்பு அமைச்சர் தம்மிக பெரேராவுடன் கலந்துரையாடல்களை முன்னெடுத்துள்ளார்.",
        "அண்மையில் இலங்கைக்கான சீனத்தூதுவர் சி சென்ஹொங் மற்றும் தொழில்நுட்ப, முதலீட்டு ஊக்குவிப்பு அமைச்சர் தம்மிக பெரேரா ஆகியோருக்கு இடையில் கொழும்பிலுள்ள சீனத்தூதரகத்தில் இடம்பெற்ற சந்திப்பின்போதே சீன முதலீடுகளை ஊக்குவிப்பது குறித்துக் கலந்துரையாடப்பட்டுள்ளது.",
        "சீனாவின் நிதியுதவியுடன் இலங்கையில் முன்னெடுக்கப்படும் சில திட்டங்கள் உள்ளடங்கலாகக் குறிப்பிடத்தக்களவிலான கட்டமைப்புக்களை தம்மிக பெரேராவின் தொழில்நுட்பம் மற்றும் முதலீட்டு ஊக்குவிப்பு அமைச்சின்கீழ் கொண்டுவருவதற்கான வர்த்தமானி அறிவித்தல் கடந்த வாரம் வெளியிடப்பட்டது.",
        "அதன்படி பாரிய பொருளாதார நெருக்கடிக்கு முகங்கொடுத்திருக்கும் இலங்கைக்குள் வெளிநாட்டு முதலீடுகள் மற்றும் தனியார் முதலீடுகளை ஊக்குவிக்கவேண்டிய சவால்மிக்க பொறுப்பு அமைச்சர் தம்மிக பெரேரா வசம் ஒப்படைக்கப்பட்டுள்ளது.",
        "இவ்வாறானதொரு பின்னணியிலேயே இலங்கைக்கான சீனத்தூதுவருடனான சந்திப்பின்போது இலங்கையில் சீன முதலீடுகளை ஊக்குவித்தல் மற்றும் ஏற்கனவே நடைமுறையிலிருக்கும் திட்டங்களை விரிவுபடுத்தல் ஆகியன தொடர்பில் கலந்துரையாடப்பட்டுள்ளது."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "சீன",
          "label": "NORP"
        },
        {
          "text": "சீன திட்டங்களின் விரிவாக்கம் குறித்து இலங்கை தம்மிக்க பெரேரா",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "இலங்கை",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "சீன",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka Chi Chenhong",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சீன",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "சீன",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "சீன",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Xi Senhong",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "சீன",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "கொழும்பு",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "கடந்த வாரம்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "தம்மிக்க பெரேராவின்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "தொழில்நுட்பம் மற்றும் முதலீட்டு ஊக்குவிப்பு அமைச்சகம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சீன",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "தம்மிக்க பெரேரா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "சீன",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சீன",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}