{
  "newspaper_id": "lankadeepa-lk",
  "url": "https://www.lankadeepa.lk/news/’’නිල්-පාට-ඇමති’’-කොළ-කොඩියක්-වනයි/101-619284",
  "time_ut": 1662308877,
  "original_lang": "si",
  "original_title": "’’නිල් පාට ඇමති’’ කොළ කොඩියක් වනයි",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "\"Blue Minister\" is a green flag",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "Tangalle Nakulogamuwa Railway Station was opened today under the chairmanship of the Minister of Agriculture, Wildlife and Forest Conservation Mr. Mahinda Amaraweera.",
        "The foundation stone for this station was laid by Mr. Mahinda Amaraweera during his tenure as the Minister of Transport.",
        "Mr. Mahinda Amaraweera is also the Senior Vice President of the Sri Lanka Freedom Party and had expressed critical comments in front of the media about the recent amendment of the Constitution of the Sri Lanka Freedom Party.",
        "In the meantime, media reports also appeared that several ministers of the Sri Lanka Freedom Party are going to become members of the United National Party."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Mahinda Amaraweera",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Mahinda",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Amaraweera",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Mahinda Amaraweera",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Sri Lanka Freedom Party",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Constitution of the Sri Lanka Freedom Party",
            "label": "LAW"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the Sri Lanka Freedom Party",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the United National Party",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "’’නිල් පාට ඇමති’’ කොළ කොඩියක් වනයි",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "තංගල්ල නාකුළුගමුව දුම්රිය නැවතුම්පොළ කෘෂිකර්ම,වනජීවී හා වන සංරක්ෂණ අමාත්‍ය මහින්ද අමරවීර මහතාගේ ප්‍රධානත්වයෙන් අද විවෘත කෙරිණි.",
        "මහින්ද අමරවීර මහතා ප්‍රවාහන අමාත්‍ය ධුරය දරන සමයේ මෙම නැවතුම්පොළ සඳහා මුල්ගල තබා තිබේ.",
        "මහින්ද අමරවීර මහතා ශ්‍රී ලංකා නිදහස් පක්ෂයේ ජ්‍යෙෂ්ඨ උප සභාපතිවරයාද වන අතර පසුගිය දා සිදු කෙරෙනු ශ්‍රී ලංකා නිදහස් පක්ෂයේ ව්‍යවස්ථා සංශෝධනය පිළිබඳව මාධ්‍ය හමුවේ විවේචනාත්මකව අදහස් පළකර තිබිණි.",
        "මේ අතර ශ්‍රී ලංකා නිදහස් පක්ෂයේ අමාත්‍යවරුන් කිහිප දෙනකු එක්සත් ජාතික පක්ෂයේ සාමාජිකත්වය ලබා ගැනීමට නියමිත බවටද මාධ්‍ය වාර්තා පළවිය."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මහින්ද අමරවීර",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "මහින්ද",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "අමරවීර",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "මහින්ද අමරවීර",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකා නිදහස් පක්ෂය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකා නිදහස් පක්ෂයේ ව්‍යවස්ථාව",
            "label": "LAW"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකා නිදහස් පක්ෂය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "එක්සත් ජාතික පක්ෂය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "\"நீல அமைச்சர்\" பச்சைக் கொடி",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "தங்காலை நகுலோகமுவ புகையிரத நிலையம் இன்று விவசாய, வனஜீவராசிகள் மற்றும் வன பாதுகாப்பு அமைச்சர் திரு.மகிந்த அமரவீர தலைமையில் திறந்து வைக்கப்பட்டது.",
        "மகிந்த அமரவீர போக்குவரத்து அமைச்சராக இருந்த காலத்தில் இந்த நிலையத்திற்கான அடிக்கல் நாட்டப்பட்டது.",
        "ஸ்ரீலங்கா சுதந்திரக் கட்சியின் சிரேஷ்ட உபதலைவரும் திரு.மகிந்த அமரவீர என்பதுடன், ஸ்ரீலங்கா சுதந்திரக் கட்சியின் அண்மைய அரசியலமைப்புத் திருத்தம் தொடர்பில் ஊடகங்களுக்கு முன் விமர்சனக் கருத்துக்களை வெளியிட்டிருந்தார்.",
        "இதேவேளை, ஸ்ரீலங்கா சுதந்திரக் கட்சியின் அமைச்சர்கள் பலர் ஐக்கிய தேசியக் கட்சியில் அங்கம் வகிக்கப் போவதாகவும் ஊடகங்களில் செய்திகள் வெளியாகின."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "மஹிந்த அமரவீர",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "மஹிந்த",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "அமரவீர",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "மஹிந்த அமரவீர",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஸ்ரீலங்கா சுதந்திரக் கட்சி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஸ்ரீலங்கா சுதந்திரக் கட்சியின் அரசியலமைப்பு",
            "label": "LAW"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஸ்ரீலங்கா சுதந்திரக் கட்சி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஐக்கிய தேசிய கட்சி",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}