{
  "newspaper_id": "ada-lk",
  "url": "https://www.ada.lk/breaking_news/කමල්-ගුණරත්න-මානව-හිමිකම්-කොමිසමට/11-395166",
  "time_ut": 1657097431,
  "original_lang": "si",
  "original_title": "කමල් ගුණරත්න මානව හිමිකම් කොමිසමට",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Kamal Gunaratne to Human Rights Commission",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "The Sri Lanka Human Rights Commission has inquired from the Defense Secretary General (retired) Kamal Gunaratne regarding the recent incident of an army officer kicking a person at the Yakgahapitiya petrol station in Kurunegala.",
        "The Secretary of Defense appeared there yesterday (5th) according to a notice given by the Chairperson of the Human Rights Commission.",
        "The Defense Secretary has informed the Commission that he condemns this incident as the Defense Secretary and that the Army has started an investigation in this regard."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Kamal Gunaratne to Human Rights Commission",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "The Sri Lanka Human Rights Commission",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kamal Gunaratne",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Yakgahapitiya",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kurunegala",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Defense",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "yesterday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "5th",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Defense",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Defense",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Army",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "කමල් ගුණරත්න මානව හිමිකම් කොමිසමට",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "කුරුණෑගල යක්ගහපිටිය ඉන්ධන පිරවුම්හලේ දී පසුගිය දා යුද හමුදා නිලධාරියකු විසින්  පුද්ගලයකුට පා පහර එල්ල කිරීමේ සිදුවීම සම්බන්ධයෙන් ආරක්ෂක ලේකම් ජෙනරාල් (විශ්‍රාමික) කමල් ගුණරත්න මහතාගෙන් ශ්‍රි ලංකා මානව හිමිකම් කොමිසම කරුණු විමසා තිබේ.",
        "ආරක්ෂක ලේකම්වරයා මානව හිමිකම් කොමිසමේ සභාපතිවරිය කර තිබු දැනුම් දීමකට අනුව ඊයේ (5දා) එහි පෙනී සිටියේය.",
        "මෙම සිදුවීම ආරක්ෂක ලේකම්වරයා වශයෙන් තමන් හෙළා දකින බවත් , මේ සම්බන්ධයෙන් යුද හමුදාව විමර්ශනයක් ආරම්භ කර ඇති බවද ආරක්ෂක ලේකම්වරයා කොමිසමට දැනුම් දී තිබේ."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "කමල් ගුණරත්න මානව හිමිකම් කොමිසමට",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකා මානව හිමිකම් කොමිෂන් සභාව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "කමල් ගුණරත්න",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "යක්ගහපිටිය",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "කුරුණෑගල",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ආරක්ෂක",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඊයේ",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "5 වැනි",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ආරක්ෂක",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ආරක්ෂක",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "හමුදා",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "மனித உரிமைகள் ஆணைக்குழுவிடம் கமல் குணரத்ன",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "அண்மையில் குருநாகல் யக்கஹபிட்டிய எரிபொருள் நிரப்பு நிலையத்தில் இராணுவ அதிகாரி ஒருவர் உதைத்த சம்பவம் தொடர்பில் பாதுகாப்பு செயலாளர் நாயகம் (ஓய்வு பெற்ற) கமல் குணரத்னவிடம் இலங்கை மனித உரிமைகள் ஆணைக்குழு வினவியுள்ளது.",
        "மனித உரிமைகள் ஆணைக்குழுவின் தலைவர் வழங்கிய அறிவித்தலின் பிரகாரம் பாதுகாப்புச் செயலாளர் நேற்று (5ஆம் திகதி) அங்கு ஆஜராகியுள்ளார்.",
        "இந்த சம்பவத்தை பாதுகாப்பு செயலாளர் என்ற ரீதியில் தாம் கண்டிப்பதாகவும், இது தொடர்பில் இராணுவம் விசாரணைகளை ஆரம்பித்துள்ளதாகவும் பாதுகாப்பு செயலாளர் ஆணைக்குழுவிடம் தெரிவித்துள்ளார்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "மனித உரிமைகள் ஆணைக்குழுவிடம் கமல் குணரத்ன",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை மனித உரிமைகள் ஆணைக்குழு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "கமல் குணரத்ன",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "யக்கஹாபிட்டிய",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "குருநாகல்",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பாதுகாப்பு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "நேற்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "5வது",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பாதுகாப்பு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாதுகாப்பு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இராணுவம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}