{
  "newspaper_id": "lankadeepa-lk",
  "url": "https://www.lankadeepa.lk/news/කොහාගෙ-බිත්තර-කන්න-එන-නයි-පොළොඟුන්ට-කොටනවා/101-619186",
  "time_ut": 1662107551,
  "original_lang": "si",
  "original_title": "කොහාගෙ බිත්තර කන්න එන නයි පොළොඟුන්ට කොටනවා",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Koha's eggs are eaten by caterpillars",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "We are the ones who keep Koha's eggs. The chief organizer of the ruling party, Mr. Prasanna Ranatunga, Minister of Urban Development and Housing, said in Parliament today (2) that the eggs that come to eat those eggs will be cut off.",
        "Mr. Prasanna Ranatunga said this while commenting on the interim budget debate.",
        "Mr. Prasanna Ranatunga said this in reply to the statement made by Samagi Jana Balavega Colombo District Councilor Dr. Harsha De Silva on the last 31st when starting the budget debate, \"Ranil's economic policy is like a chick in a nest\".",
        "\"The President invited them to forget all that and think about the country and get the country out of the crisis. The opposition compares him to someone who has laid eggs in the crow's nest. Remember that he is the first to tell us that the flowers will bloom and the years will come. Yes, we should lay our eggs there. Our nest was given. We gave it willingly. We were told where it was. Therefore, we are not going to cut it anywhere.",
        "He first tried to make drugs with you. Mr. Prasanna Ranatunga said that it was you who chased him away."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Koha",
          "label": "DATE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Koha",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Prasanna Ranatunga",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Urban Development and Housing",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "2",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Prasanna Ranatunga",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Prasanna Ranatunga",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Samagi",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Harsha De Silva",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the last 31st",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ranil",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "first",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "the years",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Prasanna Ranatunga",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "කොහාගෙ බිත්තර කන්න එන නයි පොළොඟුන්ට කොටනවා",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "කොහාගේ බිත්තර රකින්නේ පොහොට්ටුවේ අපි. ඒ බිත්තර කන්න එන නයි පොළොන්ගුන්ට කොටනවා යැයි ආණ්ඩු පක්ෂයේ ප්‍රධාන සංවිධායක නාගරික සංවර්ධන සහ නිවාස අමාත්‍ය ප්‍රසන්න රණතුංග මහතා පාර්ලිමේන්තුවේ දී අද (2) පැවසීය.",
        "ප්‍රසන්න රණතුංග මහතා මේ බව පැවසූයේ අතුරු අයවැය පිළිබඳ විවාදයේ අදහස් දක්වමිනි.",
        "රනිල්ගේ ආර්ථික ප්‍රතිපත්තිය කාක් කූඩුවේ හදපු කොහා පැටවකු වගේ\"යැයි අයවැය විවාදය අරඹමින් සමගි ජන බලවේගයේ කොළඹ දිස්ත්‍රික් මන්ත්‍රී ආචාර්ය හර්ෂ ද සිල්වා මහතා ඉකුත් 31වෙනිදා කළ ප්‍රකාශයට පිළිතුරු දෙමින් ප්‍රසන්න රණතුංග මහතා මේ බව කීය.",
        "\"ජනාධිපතිතුමා ඒ සියල්ල අමතක කරලා රට ගැන හිතලා රට අර්බුදයෙන් ගොඩ ගන්න ඒ අයට ආරාධනා කළා. විපක්ෂය එතුමා කපුටු කූඩුවේ බිත්තර දැමූ කොහෙකුට සමාන කරනවා. එරබදු මල් පිපිලා අවුරුදු එන බව අපිට මුලින්ම කියන්නෙත් කොහා කියලා මතක තියාගන්න.ඔව් ,අපි ඒ කොහාට බිත්තර දාන්න අපි අපේ කූඩුව දුන්නා.අපි කැමැත්තෙන් දුන්නේ. කොහා කියලා දැනගෙන දුන්නේ. ඒ නිසා අපි කොහාට කොටන්න යන්නේ නෑ.",
        "එතුමා මුලින්ම කුඩු හදන්න උත්සහා කළේ ඔබතුමාලා එක්ක. ඔබතුමාලා තමයි එතුමාට කොටලා එලෙව්වේ ,යනුවෙන් ද ප්‍රසන්න රණතුංග මහතා පැවසීය."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "කොහා",
          "label": "DATE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "කොහා",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ප්‍රසන්න රණතුංග",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "නාගරික සංවර්ධන හා නිවාස",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "2",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ප්‍රසන්න රණතුංග",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ප්‍රසන්න රණතුංග",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "සමගි",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "හර්ෂ ද සිල්වා",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "පසුගිය 31 වැනිදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "රනිල්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "පළමුවන",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "වසර",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ප්‍රසන්න රණතුංග",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "கோஹாவின் முட்டைகளை கம்பளிப்பூச்சிகள் உண்ணும்",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "கோஹாவின் முட்டைகளை நாம்தான் வைத்திருப்போம். அந்த முட்டைகளை சாப்பிட வரும் முட்டைகள் வெட்டப்படும் என ஆளும் கட்சியின் பிரதம அமைப்பாளரும், நகர அபிவிருத்தி மற்றும் வீடமைப்பு அமைச்சருமான திரு.பிரசன்ன ரணதுங்க இன்று (2) பாராளுமன்றத்தில் தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "இடைக்கால வரவு செலவுத்திட்ட விவாதத்தில் கருத்து தெரிவிக்கும் போதே பிரசன்ன ரணதுங்க மேற்கண்டவாறு தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "கடந்த 31ஆம் திகதி சமகி ஜன பலவேக கொழும்பு மாவட்ட சபை உறுப்பினர் கலாநிதி ஹர்ஷ டி சில்வா வரவு செலவுத் திட்ட விவாதத்தின் ஆரம்பத்தில் தெரிவித்த கருத்துக்கு பதிலளிக்கும் போதே பிரசன்ன ரணதுங்க மேற்கண்டவாறு தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "“அதையெல்லாம் மறந்து நாட்டைப் பற்றி சிந்தித்து நாட்டை நெருக்கடியில் இருந்து விடுங்கள் என ஜனாதிபதி அவர்களை அழைத்தார்.எதிர்க்கட்சிகள் அவரை காக்கை கூட்டில் முட்டையிட்டவருக்கு ஒப்பிடுகிறார்கள்.பூக்கள் என்று முதலில் சொன்னவர் அவர் என்பதை நினைவில் கொள்ளுங்கள். பூத்து வருஷங்கள் வரும்.ஆமாம் அங்கேதான் முட்டையிட வேண்டும்.எங்கள் கூடு கொடுக்கப்பட்டது.விரும்பினால் கொடுத்தோம்.எங்கே என்று சொல்லிவிட்டோம்.எனவே அதை எங்கும் வெட்டப்போவதில்லை.",
        "அவர் முதலில் உன்னுடன் போதைப்பொருள் தயாரிக்க முயன்றார். நீங்கள்தான் அவரை விரட்டியடித்தீர்கள் என்று திரு.பிரசன்ன ரணதுங்க கூறினார்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "கோஹா",
          "label": "DATE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "கோஹா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "பிரசன்ன ரணதுங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "நகர்ப்புற வளர்ச்சி மற்றும் வீட்டுவசதி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "2",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பிரசன்ன ரணதுங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பிரசன்ன ரணதுங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "சமகி",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஹர்ஷ டி சில்வா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "கடந்த 31ம் தேதி",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரணில்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "முதலில்",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆண்டுகள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பிரசன்ன ரணதுங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}