{
  "newspaper_id": "island-lk",
  "url": "http://island.lk/reds-at-sea/",
  "time_ut": 1660072440,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Reds at sea",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Reds at sea",
      "author": "Sahan Weerasooriya",
      "body_lines": [
        "The JVP has refused to join the proposed all-party government, calling it a ruse to perpetuate the Rajapaksa rule, in all but name, with President Ranil Wickremesinghe being at the beck and call of the SLPP leadership. What the country needs is an interim government pending an early general election because the SLPP’s popular mandates have expired, the JVP says. This is an interesting argument.",
        "Mid-term elections are the best way to ascertain public opinion about a government in power, and this is why the SLPP has postponed the local government polls indefinitely, but it has been losing the co-operative society elections, which are considered a political windsock in that they help gauge popular support for a government. Popularly elected President, Gotabaya Rajapaksa, has resigned, and Prime Minister Mahinda Rajapaksa, who led the SLPP’s general election campaign in 2020 and obtained a mandate for the party, has stepped down; Ranil Wickremesinghe, who did not run for President and failed to secure his parliamentary seat, has become the President with the help of the SLPP. Thus, the current dispensation has lost legitimacy, as the JVP claims. It is like a third-rate mega teledrama dragging on without the title character.",
        "It is being argued in some quarters that the SLPP administration is constitutionally empowered to complete its full term because it has a working majority in Parliament; President Gotabaya Rajapaksa’s successor has been elected by the legislature in the constitutionally prescribed manner, and therefore the government has a legitimate right to remain in power, and there is no need for a snap general election. But what is constitutionally permitted and approved by Parliament does not necessarily become legitimate or morally right or acceptable to the public. The 18th and 20th Amendments introduced by the Rajapaksas to enhance the executive powers of the President may serve as examples. They passed muster with the Supreme Court, in the bill form, and were ratified by Parliament with two-thirds majorities, but the very MPs who voted for the 18th Amendment, overwhelmingly supported the 19th Amendment, which curtailed the presidential powers, in 2015; President Gotabaya Rajapaksa, who had the 20th Amendment ratified for self-aggrandisement, finally agreed to deep-six it. In 2018, the UNP government succeeded in securing a majority in the House and defeating a bid to dislodge it, but it suffered massive electoral setbacks in 2019 and 2020. So much for the public acceptability of parliamentary majorities!",
        "The JVP, however, has a history of propping up crumbling regimes and supporting governments while being in the Opposition; in 2018, it defended the UNP-led UNF government vis-à-vis a bid by the then President Maithripala Sirisena, and Mahinda Rajapaksa to wrest control of Parliament. It voted with the UNP, enabling the latter to retain a working majority in the House. The JVP was also a member of the National Executive Council (NEC) set up by the Yahapalana government in 2015 purportedly to strengthen democracy; the NEC consisted of political parties with parliamentary representation, and some civil society outfits. Subsequently, the JVP pulled out of the NEC, which became defunct. In 2001, the JVP offered to shore up the Chandrika Kumaratunga government, which was teetering on the brink of collapse, owing to a spate of crossovers, and undertook to introduce the 17th Amendment, curtailing the powers of the Executive President. So, President Wickremesinghe may be able to enlist the JVP’s support if he can assure the outfit that the all-party government on the anvil will be an interim one. Such an arrangement will go a long way towards restoring political and social order.",
        "What the JVP ought to bear in mind is that the time is opportune for making some progressive laws that the country is badly in need of. The Executive Presidency is like an attenuated virus in a vaccine; the incumbent President is without popular support, and the SLPP fears the public. It is hoped that the JVP and other political parties that claim to be pro-people will not squander this opportunity. As the late Ven. Maduluwawe Sobitha Thera famously said, rotis must be baked while the griddle is hot.",
        "Leave a Reply Cancel replyYour email address will not be published. Required fields are marked *Comment Name *",
        "Save my name, email, and website in this browser for the next time I comment."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "JVP",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Rajapaksa",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "JVP",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "SLPP",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Gotabaya Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Mahinda Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "2020",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "JVP",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "third",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "some quarters",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "SLPP",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Gotabaya Rajapaksa’s",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "18th",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Rajapaksas",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Supreme Court",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "two-thirds",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "18th",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "2015",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Gotabaya Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "20th",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "six",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "2018",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "UNP",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "House",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "2019",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "2020",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "JVP",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Opposition",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "2018",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "UNP",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "UNF",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Maithripala Sirisena",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Mahinda Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "UNP",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "House",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "JVP",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the National Executive Council",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "NEC",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Yahapalana",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "2015",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "NEC",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "JVP",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "NEC",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "2001",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "JVP",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Chandrika Kumaratunga",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the 17th Amendment",
            "label": "LAW"
          },
          {
            "text": "Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "JVP",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "JVP",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "JVP",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Maduluwawe Sobitha Thera",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [],
        []
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "මුහුදේ රතු",
      "author": "සහන් වීරසූරිය",
      "body_lines": [
        "යෝජිත සර්ව පාක්ෂික ආන්ඩුවට එක්වීම ජනතා විමුක්ති පෙරමුණ ප්‍රතික්ෂේප කර ඇති අතර, එය නමින් හැර අන් සියල්ලෙන් ම, ශ්‍රී ලංකා පොදුජන පෙරමුණේ නායකත්වයේ අභිමතය පරිදි ජනාධිපති රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ සිටීමත් සමග රාජපක්ෂ පාලනය පවත්වාගෙන යාමේ කූට උපායක් ලෙස හඳුන්වයි. රටට අවශ්‍ය වන්නේ ශ්‍රී ලංකා පොදුජන පෙරමුණේ ජනවරම අවසන් වී ඇති බැවින් ඉක්මන් මහ මැතිවරණයක් පැවැත්වීමට නියමිත අන්තර්කාලීන ආණ්ඩුවක් බව ජනතා විමුක්ති පෙරමුණ පවසයි. මෙය සිත්ගන්නා තර්කයකි.",
        "මධ්‍ය කාලීන මැතිවරණය යනු බලයේ සිටින රජයක් පිළිබඳ මහජන මතය දැන ගැනීමට ඇති හොඳම ක්‍රමය වන අතර, ශ්‍රී ලංකා පොදුජන පෙරමුණ පළාත් පාලන මැතිවරණය දින නියමයක් නොමැතිව කල් දැමූ නමුත් දේශපාලන සුළඟක් ලෙස සැලකෙන සමුපකාර සමිති මැතිවරණ පරාජයට පත්වෙමින් තිබේ. ඒ තුළ ඔවුන් රජයක් සඳහා මහජන සහයෝගය මැන බැලීමට උපකාර කරයි. ජනප්‍රියව තේරී පත් වූ ජනාධිපති ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ මහතා ඉල්ලා අස්වී ඇති අතර, 2020 දී ශ්‍රී ලංකා පොදුජන පෙරමුණේ මහ මැතිවරණ ව්‍යාපාරයට නායකත්වය දී පක්ෂයට ජනවරමක් ලබාගත් අගමැති මහින්ද රාජපක්ෂ මහතා ඉල්ලා අස්වී තිබේ. ජනාධිපතිවරණයට ඉදිරිපත් නොවී තම පාර්ලිමේන්තු මන්ත්‍රී ධුරය තහවුරු කර ගැනීමට නොහැකි වූ රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතා ශ්‍රී ලංකා පොදුජන පෙරමුණේ සහයෝගයෙන් ජනාධිපති වී ඇත. මේ අනුව, ජනතා විමුක්ති පෙරමුණ පවසන පරිදි වත්මන් පාලනයට නීත්‍යානුකූලභාවය අහිමි වී ඇත. ඒක හරියට තුන්වෙනි පෙළ මෙගා ටෙලිනාට්‍යයක් මාතෘකාවෙන් තොරව ඇදගෙන යනවා වගේ.",
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකා පොදුජන පෙරමුණේ පරිපාලනයට පාර්ලිමේන්තුවේ ක්‍රියාකාරී බහුතරයක් ඇති නිසා එහි සම්පූර්ණ ධූර කාලය සම්පූර්ණ කිරීමට ව්‍යවස්ථානුකූලව බලය ලබා දී ඇති බව ඇතැම් පාර්ශ්වවල තර්ක කෙරෙමින් පවතී. ජනාධිපති ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂගේ අනුප්‍රාප්තිකයා ව්‍යවස්ථාදායකය විසින් තෝරා පත් කර ගෙන ඇත්තේ ව්‍යවස්ථාපිතව නියම කර ඇති ආකාරයට බැවින් රජයට බලයේ රැඳී සිටීමට නීත්‍යානුකූල අයිතියක් ඇති අතර හදිසි මහ මැතිවරණයක් අවශ්‍ය නොවේ. එහෙත් ව්‍යවස්ථානුකූලව අවසර දී ඇති සහ පාර්ලිමේන්තුව විසින් අනුමත කරන ලද දෙය මහජනතාවට නීත්‍යානුකූල හෝ සදාචාරාත්මක වශයෙන් හරි හෝ පිළිගත හැකි දෙයක් බවට පත්වීම අවශ්‍ය නොවේ. ජනාධිපතිවරයාගේ විධායක බලතල ඉහළ නැංවීම සඳහා රාජපක්ෂවරුන් විසින් ගෙන ආ 18 වැනි සහ 20 වැනි සංශෝධන ඊට උදාහරණ ලෙස දැක්විය හැකිය. ඔවුන් පනත් කෙටුම්පත් ආකාරයෙන් ශ්‍රේෂ්ඨාධිකරණය සමඟ එකතු වී, පාර්ලිමේන්තුවෙන් තුනෙන් දෙකක බහුතරයකින් අනුමත කරන ලද නමුත්, 18 වැනි සංශෝධනයට ඡන්දය දුන් මන්ත්‍රීවරුම, 2015 දී ජනාධිපති බලතල කප්පාදු කළ 19 වැනි සංශෝධනයට අතිමහත් ලෙස සහාය දුන්හ. 20 වැනි ආණ්ඩුක්‍රම ව්‍යවස්ථා සංශෝධනය ස්වයං-උත්තමාචාරය සඳහා අනුමත කළ ජනාධිපති ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ අවසානයේ එය ගැඹුරට හයකට එකඟ විය. 2018 දී UNP ආණ්ඩුව සභාවේ බහුතර බලය තහවුරු කර ගැනීමටත්, එය විසුරුවා හැරීමේ උත්සාහයක් පරාජය කිරීමටත් සමත් වූ නමුත්, 2019 සහ 2020 දී එය දැවැන්ත මැතිවරණ පසුබෑමකට ලක් විය. පාර්ලිමේන්තු බහුතරයේ මහජන පිළිගැනීමට බොහෝ දේ!",
        "කෙසේ වෙතත්, ජවිපෙට ඇත්තේ ගරාවැටෙන පාලන තන්ත‍්‍රවලට මුක්කු ගසා විපක්‍ෂයේ සිටිමින් ආණ්ඩුවලට සහාය දීමේ ඉතිහාසයකි. 2018 දී, එය එවක ජනාධිපති මෛත්‍රීපාල සිරිසේන සහ මහින්ද රාජපක්ෂ විසින් පාර්ලිමේන්තුවේ පාලනය උදුරා ගැනීමේ උත්සාහයට එරෙහිව එජාපය ප්‍රමුඛ එජාප රජය ආරක්ෂා කළේය. එය එජාපය සමඟ ඡන්දය දුන් අතර, දෙවැන්නාට සභාවේ වැඩ කරන බහුතරයක් රඳවා ගැනීමට හැකි විය. ප්‍රජාතන්ත්‍රවාදය ශක්තිමත් කිරීම සඳහා යැයි කියනු ලබන යහපාලන රජය 2015 දී පිහිටුවන ලද ජාතික විධායක සභාවේ (NEC) ජනතා විමුක්ති පෙරමුණ ද සාමාජිකයෙකි. NEC සමන්විත වූයේ පාර්ලිමේන්තු නියෝජනයක් සහිත දේශපාලන පක්ෂ සහ සමහර සිවිල් සමාජ සංවිධාන වලිනි. පසුව, ජවිපෙ NEC එකෙන් ඉවත් වූ අතර එය අභාවයට ගියේය. 2001 දී ජ.වි.පෙ, හරස් මාරුවීම් නිසා බිඳවැටීමේ අද්දර වැටී සිටි චන්ද්‍රිකා කුමාරතුංග ආණ්ඩුව ගොඩ ගැනීමට ඉදිරිපත් වූ අතර, විධායක ජනාධිපතිගේ බලතල කප්පාදු කරමින් 17 වැනි සංශෝධනය ගෙන ඒමට භාර විය. එබැවින්, සර්ව පාක්ෂික ආණ්ඩුව අන්තර්කාලීන එකක් බවට සහතික කළ හැකි නම්, ජනාධිපති වික්‍රමසිංහට ජවිපෙ සහාය ලබා ගැනීමට හැකි වනු ඇත. එවැනි විධිවිධානයක් දේශපාලන හා සමාජ පර්යාය යථා තත්ත්වයට පත් කිරීම සඳහා දිගු ගමනක් වනු ඇත.",
        "ජනතා විමුක්ති පෙරමුණ මතක තබා ගත යුතු කරුණ නම් රටට අත්‍යාවශ්‍ය ප්‍රගතිශීලී නීති කිහිපයක් සකස් කිරීමට කාලය එළඹ ඇති බවයි. විධායක ජනාධිපති ක්‍රමය එන්නතක ඇති දුර්වල වූ වෛරසයක් වැනිය. වත්මන් ජනාධිපතිවරයාට මහජන සහයෝගයක් නොමැති අතර ශ්‍රී ලංකා පොදුජන පෙරමුණ මහජනතාවට බිය වේ. ජනතා විමුක්ති පෙරමුණ ඇතුළු ජනතා හිතවාදී යැයි කියා ගන්නා දේශපාලන පක්ෂ මේ අවස්ථාව අපතේ නොයනු ඇතැයි අපේක්ෂා කෙරේ. අපවත් වී වදාළ හාමුදුරුවෝ විදියට. මාදුළුවාවේ සෝභිත හිමියන් ප්‍රකටව කියා සිටියේ රොටි බැද ගත යුත්තේ දැල රත් වන විට බවයි.",
        "පිළිතුරක් දෙන්න පිළිතුර අවලංගු කරන්න ඔබගේ විද්‍යුත් තැපැල් ලිපිනය ප්‍රකාශයට පත් නොකෙරේ. අවශ්‍ය ක්ෂේත්‍ර සලකුණු කර ඇත *අදහස් නම *",
        "මම ඊළඟ වතාවේ අදහස් දැක්වීම සඳහා මගේ නම, විද්‍යුත් තැපෑල සහ වෙබ් අඩවිය මෙම බ්‍රවුසරයේ සුරකින්න."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ජ.වි.පෙ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජ.වි.පෙ",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "SLPP",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "මහින්ද රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "2020",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජ.වි.පෙ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "තෙවන",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "සමහර කාර්තු",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "SLPP",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂගේ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "18 වැනි",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "රාජපක්ෂලා",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රේෂ්ඨාධිකරණය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "තුනෙන් දෙකක්",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "18 වැනි",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "2015",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "20 වැනි",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "හය",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "2018",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "එජාප",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "නිවස",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "2019",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "2020",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ජ.වි.පෙ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "විපක්ෂ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "2018",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "එජාප",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "යූඑන්එෆ්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "මෛත්‍රීපාල සිරිසේන",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "මහින්ද රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "එජාප",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "නිවස",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජ.වි.පෙ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජාතික විධායක සභාව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "NEC",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "යහපාලන",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "2015",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "NEC",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජ.වි.පෙ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "NEC",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "2001",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජ.වි.පෙ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "චන්ද්‍රිකා කුමාරතුංග",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "17 වැනි සංශෝධනය",
            "label": "LAW"
          },
          {
            "text": "වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජ.වි.පෙ",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ජ.වි.පෙ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජ.වි.පෙ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "මාදුළුවාවේ සෝභිත හිමි",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [],
        []
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "கடலில் சிவப்பு",
      "author": "சஹான் வீரசூரிய",
      "body_lines": [
        "ஜே.வி.பி முன்மொழியப்பட்ட சர்வகட்சி அரசாங்கத்தில் இணைய மறுத்துவிட்டது, இது ராஜபக்ச ஆட்சியை நிலைநிறுத்துவதற்கான சூழ்ச்சி என்று கூறியது, பெயரைத் தவிர, ஜனாதிபதி ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க SLPP தலைமையின் அழைப்பு மற்றும் அழைப்பில் இருக்கிறார். ஸ்ரீலங்கா பொதுஜன பெரமுனவின் மக்கள் ஆணைகள் காலாவதியாகிவிட்டதால், நாட்டிற்கு தேவையானது ஒரு இடைக்கால அரசாங்கம் முன்கூட்டியே பொதுத் தேர்தல் நிலுவையில் உள்ளது என்று ஜே.வி.பி. இது ஒரு சுவாரஸ்யமான வாதம்.",
        "ஆட்சியில் இருக்கும் அரசாங்கம் பற்றிய பொதுக் கருத்தை அறிய இடைக்காலத் தேர்தல்கள் சிறந்த வழியாகும், இதனால்தான் உள்ளூராட்சித் தேர்தலை காலவரையறையின்றி SLPP ஒத்திவைத்துள்ளது, ஆனால் அது ஒரு அரசியல் சூறாவளியாகக் கருதப்படும் கூட்டுறவு சங்கத் தேர்தலில் தோல்வியடைந்து வருகிறது. ஒரு அரசாங்கத்திற்கான மக்கள் ஆதரவை அளவிடுவதற்கு அவை உதவுகின்றன. மக்களால் தேர்ந்தெடுக்கப்பட்ட ஜனாதிபதி கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ச ராஜினாமா செய்தார், மேலும் 2020 இல் SLPP இன் பொதுத் தேர்தல் பிரச்சாரத்திற்கு தலைமை தாங்கி கட்சிக்கான ஆணையைப் பெற்ற பிரதமர் மஹிந்த ராஜபக்ஷ பதவி விலகினார்; ஜனாதிபதி தேர்தலில் போட்டியிடாத ரணில் விக்ரமசிங்க, தனது பாராளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர் பதவியை பெற்றுக்கொள்ள முடியாத நிலையில், ஸ்ரீலங்கா பொதுஜன பெரமுனவின் உதவியுடன் ஜனாதிபதியானார். இதனால், ஜே.வி.பி கூறுவது போல் தற்போதைய ஆட்சிமுறை சட்டபூர்வமான தன்மையை இழந்துள்ளது. மூன்றாம் தர மெகா டெலிட்ராமா டைட்டில் கேரக்டர் இல்லாமல் இழுத்தடிப்பது போல் உள்ளது.",
        "SLPP நிர்வாகம் பாராளுமன்றத்தில் பெரும்பான்மையைப் பெற்றிருப்பதால், அதன் முழு பதவிக் காலத்தையும் முடிக்க அரசியலமைப்பு ரீதியாக அதிகாரம் பெற்றுள்ளது என்று சில இடங்களில் வாதிடப்படுகிறது; ஜனாதிபதி கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ஷவின் வாரிசு, அரசியலமைப்பு ரீதியாக பரிந்துரைக்கப்பட்ட முறையில் சட்டமன்றத்தால் தேர்ந்தெடுக்கப்பட்டுள்ளார், எனவே அரசாங்கத்திற்கு அதிகாரத்தில் இருக்க நியாயமான உரிமை உள்ளது, மேலும் அவசர பொதுத் தேர்தல் தேவையில்லை. ஆனால் அரசியலமைப்பு ரீதியாக அனுமதிக்கப்பட்ட மற்றும் பாராளுமன்றத்தால் அங்கீகரிக்கப்பட்டவை சட்டபூர்வமானதாகவோ அல்லது தார்மீக ரீதியாகவோ அல்லது பொதுமக்களுக்கு ஏற்றுக்கொள்ளக்கூடியதாகவோ ஆகாது. ஜனாதிபதியின் நிறைவேற்று அதிகாரங்களை அதிகரிப்பதற்காக ராஜபக்சக்களால் கொண்டுவரப்பட்ட 18வது மற்றும் 20வது திருத்தங்கள் இதற்கு உதாரணமாக அமையலாம். அவர்கள் உச்ச நீதிமன்றத்தில் சட்டமூல வடிவில் சமர்ப்பித்து, மூன்றில் இரண்டு பங்கு பெரும்பான்மையுடன் பாராளுமன்றத்தால் அங்கீகரிக்கப்பட்டனர், ஆனால் 18வது திருத்தத்திற்கு வாக்களித்த பாராளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர்களே, 2015ல் ஜனாதிபதியின் அதிகாரங்களைக் குறைக்கும் 19வது திருத்தத்தை பெருமளவில் ஆதரித்தனர்; சுயமரியாதைக்காக 20வது திருத்தச் சட்டத்தை அங்கீகரித்த ஜனாதிபதி கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ஷ இறுதியாக அதை ஆழமாக ஆற ஒப்புக்கொண்டார். 2018 இல், UNP அரசாங்கம் சபையில் பெரும்பான்மையைப் பெறுவதில் வெற்றி பெற்றது மற்றும் அதை அகற்றுவதற்கான முயற்சியை தோற்கடித்தது, ஆனால் அது 2019 மற்றும் 2020 இல் பாரிய தேர்தல் பின்னடைவைச் சந்தித்தது. பாராளுமன்ற பெரும்பான்மையை மக்கள் ஏற்றுக்கொள்வதற்கு இவ்வளவு!",
        "எவ்வாறாயினும், ஜே.வி.பி., எதிர்க் கட்சியில் இருந்தபோது, ​​சிதைந்து வரும் ஆட்சிகளுக்கு முட்டுக் கொடுத்து, அரசாங்கங்களுக்கு ஆதரவளித்த வரலாற்றைக் கொண்டுள்ளது; 2018 இல், அது அப்போதைய ஜனாதிபதி மைத்திரிபால சிறிசேன மற்றும் மகிந்த ராஜபக்ச பாராளுமன்றத்தின் கட்டுப்பாட்டை கைப்பற்றுவதற்கான முயற்சிக்கு எதிராக UNP தலைமையிலான UNF அரசாங்கத்தை பாதுகாத்தது. அது யூ.என்.பி.யுடன் சேர்ந்து வாக்களித்தது, பிந்தையவர்கள் சபையில் வேலை செய்யும் பெரும்பான்மையை தக்க வைத்துக் கொள்ள முடிந்தது. ஜனநாயகத்தை வலுப்படுத்துவதற்காக 2015 இல் யஹபாலன அரசாங்கத்தால் அமைக்கப்பட்ட தேசிய நிறைவேற்று சபையில் (NEC) ஜே.வி.பி.யும் அங்கம் வகித்தது; NEC என்பது பாராளுமன்ற பிரதிநிதித்துவம் கொண்ட அரசியல் கட்சிகள் மற்றும் சில சிவில் சமூக அமைப்புகளை உள்ளடக்கியது. பின்னர், ஜே.வி.பி NEC யிலிருந்து வெளியேறியது, அது செயலிழந்தது. 2001 இல், ஜே.வி.பி., பல குறுக்குவெட்டுகளின் காரணமாக, சரிவின் விளிம்பில் தத்தளித்துக் கொண்டிருந்த சந்திரிகா குமாரதுங்க அரசாங்கத்தை தூக்கி நிறுத்த முன்வந்தது மற்றும் நிறைவேற்று ஜனாதிபதியின் அதிகாரங்களைக் குறைத்து 17வது திருத்தத்தை அறிமுகப்படுத்தியது. எனவே, ஜனாதிபதி விக்கிரமசிங்க ஜே.வி.பி.யின் ஆதரவைப் பெற முடியும் என்றால், சர்வகட்சி அரசாங்கம் ஒரு இடைக்கால அரசாங்கமாக இருக்கும் என்று அவர் உறுதியளிக்கிறார். இத்தகைய ஏற்பாடு அரசியல் மற்றும் சமூக ஒழுங்கை மீட்டெடுப்பதற்கு நீண்ட தூரம் செல்லும்.",
        "ஜே.வி.பி மனதில் கொள்ள வேண்டியது என்னவென்றால், நாட்டிற்கு மிகவும் மோசமாகத் தேவைப்படும் சில முற்போக்கான சட்டங்களை உருவாக்குவதற்கான நேரம் இதுவாகும். எக்ஸிகியூட்டிவ் பிரசிடென்சி என்பது தடுப்பூசியில் உள்ள அட்டன்யூடேட்டட் வைரஸ் போன்றது; தற்போதைய ஜனாதிபதிக்கு மக்கள் ஆதரவு இல்லை, மேலும் SLPP பொதுமக்களுக்கு அஞ்சுகிறது. இந்த சந்தர்ப்பத்தை ஜே.வி.பி மற்றும் மக்கள் சார்பானவர்கள் எனக் கூறும் ஏனைய அரசியல் கட்சிகள் வீணடிக்காது என நம்பப்படுகிறது. மறைந்த வண. மாதுலுவாவே சோபித தேரர், ரொட்டியை சூடாக இருக்கும்போதே சுட வேண்டும் என்று கூறியுள்ளார்.",
        "ஒரு பதிலை விடுங்கள் பதிலை ரத்துசெய் உங்கள் மின்னஞ்சல் முகவரி வெளியிடப்படாது. தேவையான புலங்கள் குறிக்கப்பட்டுள்ளன *கருத்து பெயர் *",
        "அடுத்த முறை நான் கருத்து தெரிவிக்க, எனது பெயர், மின்னஞ்சல் மற்றும் இணையதளத்தை இந்த உலாவியில் சேமிக்கவும்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ஜே.வி.பி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ராஜபக்சே",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜே.வி.பி",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "எஸ்.எல்.பி.பி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "மஹிந்த ராஜபக்ஷ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "2020",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜே.வி.பி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "மூன்றாவது",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "சில காலாண்டுகள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "எஸ்.எல்.பி.பி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்சவின்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "18வது",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ராஜபக்சேக்கள்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "உச்ச நீதிமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "மூன்றில் இரண்டு பங்கு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "18வது",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "2015",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "20வது",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆறு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "2018",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஐ.தே.க",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "வீடு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "2019",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "2020",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஜே.வி.பி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "எதிர்ப்பு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "2018",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஐ.தே.க",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஐ.தே.மு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "மைத்திரிபால சிறிசேன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "மஹிந்த ராஜபக்ஷ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஐ.தே.க",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "வீடு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜே.வி.பி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "தேசிய நிர்வாக சபை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "NEC",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "யஹபாலன",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "2015",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "NEC",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜே.வி.பி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "NEC",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "2001",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜே.வி.பி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "சந்திரிகா குமாரதுங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "17வது திருத்தம்",
            "label": "LAW"
          },
          {
            "text": "விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜே.வி.பி",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஜே.வி.பி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜே.வி.பி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "மாதுலுவாவே சோபித தேரர்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [],
        []
      ]
    }
  }
}