{
  "newspaper_id": "ada-derana-lk",
  "url": "http://www.adaderana.lk/news/83930/advisory-issued-for-thundershowers-and-severe-lightning-",
  "time_ut": 1659005220,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Advisory issued for thundershowers and severe lightning",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Advisory issued for thundershowers and severe lightning",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "Thundershowers accompanied by severe lightning are likely to occur at several places in Sabaragamuwa, Central, North-central, North-western, Uva, Eastern and Southern provinces.",
        "Heavy showers of about 100 mm may occur at some places in these areas.",
        "The general public is kindly requested to take adequate precautions to minimize damages caused by lightning activity."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Sabaragamuwa, Central,",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "North-western",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Uva",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Eastern",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Southern",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [],
        []
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "ගිගුරුම් සහිත වැසි සහ ප්‍රබල අකුණු සඳහා උපදෙස් නිකුත් කෙරේ",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "සබරගමුව, මධ්‍යම, උතුරු-මැද, වයඹ, ඌව, නැගෙනහිර සහ දකුණු පළාත්වල ස්ථාන කිහිපයක ප්‍රබල අකුණු සමඟ ගිගුරුම් සහිත වැසි ඇති විය හැක.",
        "එම ප්‍රදේශවල ඇතැම් ස්ථානවලට මිලිමීටර් 100ක පමණ තද වැසි ඇති විය හැක.",
        "අකුණු මඟින් සිදුවන අනතුරු අවම කර ගැනීමට අවශ්‍ය පියවර ගන්නා ලෙස මහජනතාවගෙන් කාරුණිකව ඉල්ලා සිටිනු ලැබේ."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "සබරගමුව, මධ්‍යම,",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "වයඹ",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඌව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "නැගෙනහිර",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "දකුණු",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [],
        []
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "இடியுடன் கூடிய மழை மற்றும் கடுமையான மின்னலுக்கான ஆலோசனை வழங்கப்பட்டுள்ளது",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "சப்ரகமுவ, மத்திய, வடமத்திய, வடமேல், ஊவா, கிழக்கு மற்றும் தென் மாகாணங்களில் பல இடங்களில் கடுமையான மின்னலுடன் கூடிய இடியுடன் கூடிய மழை பெய்யக்கூடும்.",
        "இந்தப் பிரதேசங்களில் சில இடங்களில் சுமார் 100 மில்லிமீற்றர் அளவில் பலத்த மழை பெய்யக்கூடும்.",
        "மின்னல் தாக்கங்களினால் ஏற்படக்கூடிய பாதிப்புகளை குறைத்துக்கொள்ள தேவையான முன்னெச்சரிக்கை நடவடிக்கைகளை எடுத்துக் கொள்ளுமாறு பொதுமக்கள் கேட்டுக் கொள்ளப்படுகிறார்கள்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "சப்ரகமுவ, மத்திய,",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "வடமேற்கு",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஊவா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "கிழக்கு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "தெற்கு",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [],
        []
      ]
    }
  }
}