{
  "newspaper_id": "news-first-lk",
  "url": "https://www.newsfirst.lk/2022/08/31/us-organization-donates-medical-supplies/",
  "time_ut": 1661918460,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "US organization donates medical supplies",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "US organization donates medical supplies",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); Heart to Heart International, a renowned global humanitarian organization in the United States, donated its first consignment of medical supplies worth $908,547 last month.",
        "This was safely collected by officials from the Ministry of Health in Colombo on 13 July 2022 for further distribution.",
        "Progressing from this, under the guidance of Ambassador Mahinda Samarasinghe, Heart to Heart International has now obtained all necessary government approvals for the second in-kind donation of urgent medical aid, worth approximate $8,222,898.78 (i.e., LKR 3,042,061,403.66) to the people of Sri Lanka.",
        "This donation includes an extensive amount of crucial pain medication and antibiotics such as amoxicillin, potassium chloride, penicillin, and venlafaxine, which are in short supply and urgently required in Sri Lanka. Thus far, Heart to Heart International has made a total contribution of $9,131,445.78 (i.e., LKR 3,378,178,366.311) worth of urgent medical aid to Sri Lanka.",
        "The Ambassador, during his meeting on 20 July 2022 with the CEO of Heart to Heart International, Kim Carroll, thanked and expressed his sincere gratitude to Heart to Heart International for the generous donations to be extended to the people of Sri Lanka at this critical juncture.",
        "In coordination with the Sri Lankan Ministry of Health and the Embassy of Sri Lanka in Washington D.C., the second donation is due to be sent via air in five separate air shipments to Colombo, Sri Lanka.",
        "Similar to the first donation, all expenses will be borne by Heart to Heart International, and the Ministry of Health will receive the donation for immediate distribution at no cost to the people of Sri Lanka in due course.",
        "Headquartered in Lenexa, Kansas, Heart to Heart International (HHI) is a global humanitarian organization focused on improving access to health. Since its inception in 1992, HHI has delivered medical aid and supplies worth $2.5 billion to more than 130 countries, including the United States.",
        "HHI responds to natural disasters both domestically and internationally by supplying medical relief and mobilizing volunteers. The organization is a 4-star Charity Navigator charity, a BBB Accredited charity, and is on the \"Philanthropy 400.\"",
        "Distribution & Sales: CAA imposes strict conditions on series of goods"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "US",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "News 1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the United States",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "first",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "908,547",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "last month",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the Ministry of Health in Colombo",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "13 July 2022",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Mahinda Samarasinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "second",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "8,222,898.78",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "LKR",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "9,131,445.78",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "20 July 2022",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kim Carroll",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the Sri Lankan Ministry of Health",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Embassy of Sri Lanka",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Washington D.C.",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "second",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "five",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Colombo",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "first",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Ministry of Health",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Lenexa",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kansas",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "HHI",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "1992",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "HHI",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "$2.5 billion",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "more than 130",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "the United States",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "4",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "BBB Accredited",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        []
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "එක්සත් ජනපද සංවිධානය වෛද්‍ය සැපයුම් පරිත්‍යාග කරයි",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); එක්සත් ජනපදයේ සුප්‍රසිද්ධ ගෝලීය මානුෂීය සංවිධානයක් වන හාර්ට් ටු හාට් ඉන්ටර්නැෂනල් විසින් පසුගිය මාසයේ ඩොලර් 908,547ක් වටිනා සිය පළමු වෛද්‍ය සැපයුම් තොගය පරිත්‍යාග කළේය.",
        "මෙය 2022 ජූලි 13 වන දින කොළඹ සෞඛ්‍ය අමාත්‍යාංශයේ නිලධාරීන් විසින් තවදුරටත් බෙදා හැරීම සඳහා ආරක්ෂිතව එකතු කරන ලදී.",
        "මෙයින් ප්‍රගතියක් ලබමින්, තානාපති මහින්ද සමරසිංහගේ මගපෙන්වීම යටතේ, හාට් ටු හාට් ඉන්ටර්නැෂනල් ආයතනය විසින්, ආසන්න වශයෙන් ඩොලර් 8,222,898.78 (එනම්, ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ ජනතාවට රුපියල් 3,042,061,403) වටිනා හදිසි වෛද්‍ය ආධාර දෙවන පරිත්‍යාගය සඳහා අවශ්‍ය සියලුම රජයේ අනුමැතිය ලබාගෙන ඇත. .",
        "මෙම පරිත්‍යාගයට ශ්‍රී ලංකාව තුළ හිඟ සහ කඩිනමින් අවශ්‍ය වන ඇමොක්සිසිලින්, පොටෑසියම් ක්ලෝරයිඩ්, පෙනිසිලින් සහ වන්ලාෆැක්සින් වැනි තීරණාත්මක වේදනා නාශක ඖෂධ සහ ප්‍රතිජීවක විශාල ප්‍රමාණයක් ඇතුළත් වේ. මේ වන විට, Heart to Heart International විසින් ශ්‍රී ලංකාවට හදිසි වෛද්‍ය ආධාර සඳහා ඩොලර් 9,131,445.78 (එනම්, රුපියල් 3,378,178,366.311) සම්පූර්ණ දායකත්වයක් ලබා දී ඇත.",
        "2022 ජුලි 20 වැනි දින හාර්ට් ටු හාට් ඉන්ටර්නැෂනල් හි ප්‍රධාන විධායක නිලධාරී කිම් කැරොල් සමඟ පැවති සාකච්ඡාවේදී තානාපතිවරයා, මෙම තීරණාත්මක අවස්ථාවේදී ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ ජනතාව වෙත නොමසුරුව පරිත්‍යාග කිරීමට හාර්ට් ටු හාට් ඉන්ටර්නැෂනල් වෙත සිය අවංක කෘතඥතාව පළ කළේය. .",
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකා සෞඛ්‍ය අමාත්‍යාංශය සහ Washington D.C. හි ශ්‍රී ලංකා තානාපති කාර්යාලය සමඟ සම්බන්ධීකරණයෙන්, දෙවන පරිත්‍යාගය ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ කොළඹට වෙනම ගුවන් නැව්ගත කිරීම් පහකින් ගුවනින් යැවීමට නියමිතය.",
        "පළමු පරිත්‍යාගයට සමානව සියලුම වියදම් හාට් ටු හාට් ඉන්ටර්නැෂනල් ආයතනය විසින් දරනු ලබන අතර, සෞඛ්‍ය අමාත්‍යාංශයට එම පරිත්‍යාගය ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ ජනතාවට කිසිදු වියදමකින් තොරව කඩිනමින් බෙදා හැරීම සඳහා නියමිත වේලාවට ලැබෙනු ඇත.",
        "Heart to Heart International (HHI) යනු කන්සාස් හි ලෙනෙක්සා හි මූලස්ථානය, සෞඛ්‍යයට ප්‍රවේශය වැඩිදියුණු කිරීම කෙරෙහි අවධානය යොමු කරන ගෝලීය මානුෂීය සංවිධානයකි. 1992 හි ආරම්භයේ සිට, HHI විසින් එක්සත් ජනපදය ඇතුළු රටවල් 130 කට වැඩි ගණනකට ඩොලර් බිලියන 2.5 ක් වටිනා වෛද්‍ය ආධාර සහ සැපයුම් ලබා දී ඇත.",
        "දේශීය හා ජාත්‍යන්තර වශයෙන් ස්වභාවික විපත්වලට HHI ප්‍රතිචාර දක්වන්නේ වෛද්‍ය සහන සැපයීමෙන් සහ ස්වේච්ඡා සේවකයන් බලමුලු ගැන්වීමෙනි. සංවිධානය තරු 4 පුණ්‍යායතන Navigator පුණ්‍යායතනයක් වන අතර, BBB ප්‍රතීතනය ලත් පුණ්‍යායතනයක් වන අතර එය \"Philanthropy 400\" හි ඇත.",
        "බෙදා හැරීම සහ විකුණුම්: CAA විසින් භාණ්ඩ මාලාවක් සඳහා දැඩි කොන්දේසි පනවයි"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "එක්සත් ජනපදය",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "News 1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "එක්සත් ජනපදය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "පළමුවන",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "908,547 කි",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "පසුගිය මාසයේ",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "කොළඹ සෞඛ්‍ය අමාත්‍යාංශය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "2022 ජූලි 13",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "මහින්ද සමරසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "දෙවැනි",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "8,222,898.78 කි",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "LKR",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "9,131,445.78 කි",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "2022 ජූලි 20",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "කිම් කැරොල්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකා සෞඛ්‍ය අමාත්‍යාංශය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකා තානාපති කාර්යාලය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "වොෂින්ටන් ඩී.සී.",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "දෙවැනි",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "පහ",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "කොළඹ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "පළමුවන",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "සෞඛ්ය අමාත්යාංශය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ලෙනෙක්සා",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "කැන්සාස්",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "HHI",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "1992",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "HHI",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඩොලර් බිලියන 2.5 කි",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "130 ට වැඩි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "එක්සත් ජනපදය",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "4",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "BBB ප්‍රතීතනය කර ඇත",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        []
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "அமெரிக்க அமைப்பு மருத்துவப் பொருட்களை நன்கொடையாக வழங்குகிறது",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); அமெரிக்காவில் உள்ள புகழ்பெற்ற உலகளாவிய மனிதாபிமான அமைப்பான ஹார்ட் டு ஹார்ட் இன்டர்நேஷனல், கடந்த மாதம் $908,547 மதிப்புள்ள மருத்துவப் பொருட்களை வழங்கியது.",
        "இது 13 ஜூலை 2022 அன்று கொழும்பில் உள்ள சுகாதார அமைச்சின் அதிகாரிகளால் மேலதிக விநியோகத்திற்காக பாதுகாப்பாக சேகரிக்கப்பட்டது.",
        "இதிலிருந்து முன்னேறி, தூதுவர் மகிந்த சமரசிங்கவின் வழிகாட்டுதலின் கீழ், ஹார்ட் டு ஹார்ட் இன்டர்நேஷனல் அவசர மருத்துவ உதவிக்கான இரண்டாவது வகையான நன்கொடைக்கு தேவையான அனைத்து அரசாங்க அனுமதிகளையும் பெற்றுள்ளது, இதன் மதிப்பு தோராயமாக $8,222,898.78 (அதாவது, இலங்கை மக்களுக்கு 3,042,0661,403 ரூபாய்). .",
        "இந்த நன்கொடையில் இலங்கையில் பற்றாக்குறை மற்றும் அவசரமாக தேவைப்படும் அமோக்ஸிசிலின், பொட்டாசியம் குளோரைடு, பென்சிலின் மற்றும் வென்லாஃபாக்சின் போன்ற முக்கியமான வலி மருந்துகள் மற்றும் நுண்ணுயிர் எதிர்ப்பிகளின் விரிவான அளவு அடங்கும். இதுவரை, ஹார்ட் டு ஹார்ட் இன்டர்நேஷனல், இலங்கைக்கு அவசர மருத்துவ உதவியாக $9,131,445.78 (அதாவது, LKR 3,378,178,366.311) மொத்த பங்களிப்பைச் செய்துள்ளது.",
        "தூதுவர், 2022 ஜூலை 20 அன்று ஹார்ட் டு ஹார்ட் இன்டர்நேஷனல் நிறுவனத்தின் தலைமை நிர்வாக அதிகாரி கிம் கரோல் உடனான சந்திப்பின் போது, ​​இந்த இக்கட்டான தருணத்தில் இலங்கை மக்களுக்கு தாராளமாக வழங்கிய நன்கொடைகளுக்கு ஹார்ட் டு ஹார்ட் இன்டர்நேஷனலுக்கு தனது மனமார்ந்த நன்றியைத் தெரிவித்தார். .",
        "இலங்கையின் சுகாதார அமைச்சு மற்றும் வாஷிங்டன் டி.சி.யில் உள்ள இலங்கை தூதரகம் ஆகியவற்றின் ஒருங்கிணைப்பில், இரண்டாவது நன்கொடையானது இலங்கையின் கொழும்புக்கு ஐந்து தனித்தனி விமான ஏற்றுமதிகளில் விமானம் மூலம் அனுப்பப்பட உள்ளது.",
        "முதல் நன்கொடையைப் போலவே, அனைத்து செலவுகளும் ஹார்ட் டு ஹார்ட் இன்டர்நேஷனல் நிறுவனத்தால் ஏற்கப்படும், மேலும் சுகாதார அமைச்சகம் நன்கொடையை இலங்கை மக்களுக்கு எந்த கட்டணமும் இன்றி உடனடியாக விநியோகிக்கும்.",
        "ஹார்ட் டு ஹார்ட் இன்டர்நேஷனல் (HHI) என்பது லெனெக்சா, கன்சாஸில் தலைமையிடமாக உள்ளது, இது ஆரோக்கியத்திற்கான அணுகலை மேம்படுத்துவதில் கவனம் செலுத்தும் ஒரு உலகளாவிய மனிதாபிமான அமைப்பாகும். 1992 இல் தொடங்கப்பட்டதிலிருந்து, HHI, அமெரிக்கா உட்பட 130க்கும் மேற்பட்ட நாடுகளுக்கு $2.5 பில்லியன் மதிப்புள்ள மருத்துவ உதவி மற்றும் பொருட்களை வழங்கியுள்ளது.",
        "HHI மருத்துவ நிவாரணம் மற்றும் தன்னார்வலர்களை அணிதிரட்டுவதன் மூலம் உள்நாட்டிலும் சர்வதேச அளவிலும் இயற்கை பேரழிவுகளுக்கு பதிலளிக்கிறது. இந்த அமைப்பு 4-நட்சத்திர தொண்டு நேவிகேட்டர் தொண்டு நிறுவனம், BBB அங்கீகாரம் பெற்ற தொண்டு, மேலும் இது \"பரோபகாரம் 400\" இல் உள்ளது.",
        "விநியோகம் மற்றும் விற்பனை: தொடர் சரக்குகளுக்கு CAA கடுமையான நிபந்தனைகளை விதிக்கிறது"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "எங்களுக்கு",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "News 1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஐக்கிய நாடுகள்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "முதலில்",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "908,547",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "கடந்த மாதம்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "கொழும்பில் சுகாதார அமைச்சு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "13 ஜூலை 2022",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "மஹிந்த சமரசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இரண்டாவது",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "8,222,898.78",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "எல்.கே.ஆர்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "9,131,445.78",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "20 ஜூலை 2022",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "கிம் கரோல்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை சுகாதார அமைச்சு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை தூதரகம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "வாஷிங்டன் டிசி.",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இரண்டாவது",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஐந்து",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "கொழும்பு",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "முதலில்",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "சுகாதார அமைச்சகம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "லெனெக்சா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "கன்சாஸ்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "HHI",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "1992",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "HHI",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "$2.5 பில்லியன்",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "130க்கு மேல்",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஐக்கிய நாடுகள்",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "4",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "BBB அங்கீகாரம் பெற்றது",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        []
      ]
    }
  }
}