{
  "newspaper_id": "daily-ft-lk",
  "url": "https://www.ft.lk/news/Freedom-People-s-Congress-formed-to-free-country-of-corruption-nepotism-and-political-ignorance/56-739431",
  "time_ut": 1662143505,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Freedom People’s Congress formed to free country of corruption, nepotism and political ignorance",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Freedom People’s Congress formed to free country of corruption, nepotism and political ignorance",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "Member Dr. Charitha Herath says country needs broad independent political movement",
        "Claims program would ensure political reforms and politics based on futuristic vision",
        "Sri Lankan Podujana Peramuna (SLPP) MP Dr. Charitha Herath now part of the independent group led by MP Dullas Alahapperuma said Sri Lanka at this juncture needs a broad independent political movement.",
        "According to him, therefore the group’s main objective relating to reforms is to free the country from corruption, nepotism and the making of ignorant political decisions.",
        "The MP made these comments at the opening of a new office by the SLPP independent group titled the ‘Freedom People’s Congress’ yesterday. The head office of the organisation was declared open by the MPs in Nawala following a simple ceremony consisting of religious and cultural observances.   “We are commencing this program to ensure independent reforms and to push the country towards a culture of politics based on talents and a futuristic vision,” he said.",
        "SLPP MPs Dullas Alahapperuma, Dilan Perera, Dr. Nalaka Godahewa, Prof. Charitha Herath, Prof. Channa Jayasumana, K.P.S. Kumarasiri, Dr. Gunapala Rathnasekara, Udayana Kirindigoda, Dr. Upul Galappatti, Dr. Thilak Rajapaksa, Wasantha Yapa, and Lalith Ellawala announced in Parliament this week that they would function as an independent group within the Parliament.",
        "The group also refrained from voting at the interim budget vote held yesterday citing several reasons."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Charitha Herath",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lankan",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Podujana Peramuna",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Charitha Herath",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Dullas Alahapperuma",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "the ‘Freedom People’s Congress’",
            "label": "EVENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "yesterday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Nawala",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Dullas Alahapperuma",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Dilan Perera",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Nalaka Godahewa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Charitha Herath",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Channa Jayasumana",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "K.P.S. Kumarasiri",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Gunapala Rathnasekara",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Udayana Kirindigoda",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Upul Galappatti",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Thilak Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Wasantha Yapa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Lalith Ellawala",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "this week",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "yesterday",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "දූෂණයෙන්, ඥාති සංග්‍රහයෙන් සහ දේශපාලන නූගත්කමෙන් රට නිදහස් කිරීමට නිදහස් මහජන කොංග්‍රසය පිහිටුවන ලදී",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "සාමාජික ආචාර්ය චරිත හේරත් මහතා පවසන්නේ රටට පුළුල් ස්වාධීන දේශපාලන ව්‍යාපාරයක් අවශ්‍ය බවයි",
        "හිමිකම් වැඩසටහන අනාගත දැක්ම මත පදනම් වූ දේශපාලන ප්‍රතිසංස්කරණ සහ දේශපාලනය සහතික කරනු ඇත",
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකා පොදුජන පෙරමුණේ (SLPP) පාර්ලිමේන්තු මන්ත්‍රී ආචාර්ය චරිත හේරත් දැන් පාර්ලිමේන්තු මන්ත්‍රී ඩලස් අලහප්පෙරුමගේ නායකත්වයෙන් යුත් ස්වාධීන කණ්ඩායමේ කොටසක් වන බව ප්‍රකාශ කළේ ශ්‍රී ලංකාවට මේ මොහොතේ පුළුල් ස්වාධීන දේශපාලන ව්‍යාපාරයක් අවශ්‍ය බවයි.",
        "ඔහුට අනුව, එබැවින් ප්‍රතිසංස්කරණ සම්බන්ධ කණ්ඩායමේ ප්‍රධාන අරමුණ වන්නේ දූෂණයෙන්, ඥාති සංග්‍රහයෙන් සහ නූගත් දේශපාලන තීරණ ගැනීමෙන් රට මුදා ගැනීමයි.",
        "මන්ත්‍රීවරයා මේ අදහස් පළ කළේ ශ්‍රී ලංකා පොදුජන පෙරමුණේ ස්වාධීන කණ්ඩායමේ ‘නිදහස් ජනතා කොංග්‍රසය’ නමින් නව කාර්යාලයක් විවෘත කිරීමේ අවස්ථාවට ඊයේ එක්වෙමිනි. ආගමික හා සංස්කෘතික චාරිත්‍රවලින් සමන්විත චාම් උත්සවයකින් අනතුරුව එම සංවිධානයේ ප්‍රධාන කාර්යාලය පාර්ලිමේන්තු මන්ත්‍රීවරුන් විසින් නාවල ප්‍රදේශයේ දී විවෘත කෙරිණි. \"අපි මෙම වැඩසටහන ආරම්භ කරන්නේ ස්වාධීන ප්‍රතිසංස්කරණ සහතික කිරීමට සහ දක්ෂතා සහ අනාගත දැක්මක් මත පදනම් වූ දේශපාලන සංස්කෘතියක් කරා රට තල්ලු කිරීමට\" ඔහු පැවසීය.",
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකා පොදුජන පෙරමුණේ පාර්ලිමේන්තු මන්ත්‍රීවරුන් වන ඩලස් අලහප්පෙරුම, ඩිලාන් පෙරේරා, ආචාර්ය නාලක ගොඩහේවා, මහාචාර්ය චරිත හේරත්, මහාචාර්ය චන්න ජයසුමන, කේ.පී.එස්. කුමාරසිරි, ආචාර්ය ගුණපාල රත්නසේකර, උදයන කිරිඳිගොඩ, වෛද්‍ය උපුල් ගලප්පත්ති, වෛද්‍ය තිලක් රාජපක්ෂ, වසන්ත යාපා සහ ලලිත් එල්ලාවල මේ සතියේ පාර්ලිමේන්තුවේදී ප්‍රකාශ කළේ තමන් පාර්ලිමේන්තුව තුළ ස්වාධීන කණ්ඩායමක් ලෙස කටයුතු කරන බවයි.",
        "ඊයේ පැවති අතුරු අයවැය ඡන්ද විමසීමේදීද කරුණු කිහිපයක් සඳහන් කරමින් එම කණ්ඩායම ඡන්දය ප්‍රකාශ කිරීමෙන් වැළකී සිටියා."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "චරිත හේරත්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලාංකික",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "පොදුජන පෙරමුණ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "චරිත හේරත්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඩලස් අලහප්පෙරුම",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "'නිදහස් ජනතා කොංග්‍රසය'",
            "label": "EVENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඊයේ",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "නාවල",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ඩලස් අලහප්පෙරුම",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඩිලාන් පෙරේරා",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "නාලක ගොඩහේවා",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "චරිත හේරත්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "චන්න ජයසුමන",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "කේ.පී.එස්. කුමාරසිරි ය",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගුණපාල රත්නසේකර",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "උදයන කිරිඳිගොඩ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "උපුල් ගලප්පත්ති",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "තිලක් රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "වසන්ත යාපා",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ලලිත් එල්ලාවල",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "මෙම සතිය",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ඊයේ",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "சுதந்திர மக்கள் காங்கிரசு, ஊழல், சொந்த பந்தம் மற்றும் அரசியல் அறியாமை ஆகியவற்றிலிருந்து நாட்டை விடுவிக்க உருவாக்கப்பட்டது",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "நாட்டிற்கு பரந்த சுதந்திரமான அரசியல் இயக்கம் தேவை என உறுப்பினர் கலாநிதி சரித ஹேரத் தெரிவித்துள்ளார்",
        "உரிமைகோரல் திட்டம் அரசியல் சீர்திருத்தங்கள் மற்றும் எதிர்கால நோக்கத்தின் அடிப்படையில் அரசியலை உறுதி செய்யும்",
        "ஸ்ரீலங்கா பொதுஜன பெரமுன (SLPP) பாராளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர் டொக்டர் சரித ஹேரத் தற்போது பாராளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர் டலஸ் அழகப்பெரும தலைமையிலான சுயேச்சைக் குழுவில் அங்கம் வகிக்கின்றார் என இலங்கைக்கு இந்த தருணத்தில் பரந்த சுதந்திரமான அரசியல் இயக்கம் தேவை என்றார்.",
        "அவரைப் பொறுத்தவரை, சீர்திருத்தங்கள் தொடர்பான குழுவின் முக்கிய நோக்கம், ஊழல், உறவினர் மற்றும் அறியாமை அரசியல் முடிவுகளை எடுப்பதில் இருந்து நாட்டை விடுவிப்பதாகும்.",
        "ஸ்ரீலங்கா பொதுஜன பெரமுனவின் சுயேட்சைக்குழுவின் ‘சுதந்திர மக்கள் காங்கிரஸ்’ என்ற புதிய அலுவலகத்தை நேற்று திறந்து வைத்து உரையாற்றும் போதே பாராளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர் மேற்கண்டவாறு தெரிவித்தார். சமய மற்றும் கலாசார அனுஷ்டானங்களை உள்ளடக்கிய எளிய வைபவத்தைத் தொடர்ந்து அமைப்பின் தலைமை அலுவலகம் நாவலில் பாராளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர்களால் திறந்து வைக்கப்பட்டது. \"சுதந்திரமான சீர்திருத்தங்களை உறுதிப்படுத்தவும், திறமைகள் மற்றும் எதிர்கால பார்வையை அடிப்படையாகக் கொண்ட அரசியல் கலாச்சாரத்தை நோக்கி நாட்டைத் தள்ளவும் இந்த திட்டத்தை நாங்கள் தொடங்குகிறோம்,\" என்று அவர் கூறினார்.",
        "ஸ்ரீலங்கா பொதுஜன பெரமுனவின் பாராளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர்களான டலஸ் அழகப்பெரும, டிலான் பெரேரா, கலாநிதி நாலக கொடஹேவா, பேராசிரியர் சரித ஹேரத், பேராசிரியர் சன்ன ஜயசுமன, கே.பி.எஸ். குமாரசிறி, கலாநிதி குணபால ரத்னசேகர, உதயன கிரிந்திகொட, கலாநிதி உபுல் கலப்பட்டி, கலாநிதி திலக் ராஜபக்ஷ, வசந்த யாப்பா மற்றும் லலித் எல்லாவல ஆகியோர் இந்த வாரம் பாராளுமன்றத்தில் சுயேச்சைக் குழுவாக செயற்படவுள்ளதாக அறிவித்துள்ளனர்.",
        "நேற்று நடைபெற்ற இடைக்கால வரவு செலவுத் திட்ட வாக்கெடுப்பில் பல காரணங்களை முன்வைத்து குழு வாக்களிப்பதில் இருந்து விலகியிருந்தது."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "சரித ஹேரத்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "பொதுஜன பெரமுன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "சரித ஹேரத்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "டலஸ் அழகப்பெரும",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "‘சுதந்திர மக்கள் காங்கிரஸ்’",
            "label": "EVENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "நேற்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "நாவல",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "டலஸ் அழகப்பெரும",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "திலான் பெரேரா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "நாலக கொடஹேவா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "சரித ஹேரத்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "சன்ன ஜெயசுமண",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "கே.பி.எஸ். குமாரசிறி",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "குணபால ரத்னசேகர",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "உதயன கிரிந்திகொட",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "உப்புல் கலப்பட்டி",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "திலக் ராஜபக்ஷ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "வசந்த யாப்பா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "லலித் எல்லாவல",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்த வாரம்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "நேற்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}