{
  "newspaper_id": "daily-ft-lk",
  "url": "https://www.ft.lk/news/Celebration-of-75th-anniversary-of-Independence-Day-of-Pakistan-in-Sri-Lanka/56-738677",
  "time_ut": 1660506272,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Celebration of 75th anniversary of Independence Day of Pakistan in Sri Lanka",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Celebration of 75th anniversary of Independence Day of Pakistan in Sri Lanka",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "The High Commission of Pakistan and the Pakistani community in Sri Lanka on Saturday celebrated “The Diamond Jubilee” of independence of Pakistan with traditional fervour and resolve to make Pakistan a strong, dynamic, progressive, tolerant and democratic Islamic welfare State.",
        "The High Commissioner of the Islamic Republic of Pakistan in Sri Lanka, Maj. Gen. (Retd.) Umar Farooq Burki HI hoisted the national flag of Pakistan to the tune of the national anthem in a vibrant and colourful ceremony at the Pakistan High Commission in Colombo.",
        "Trade and Investment Attaché Asmma Kamal read out the message of Pakistan President Dr. Arif Alvi quoting: “On the joyous occasion of the 75th anniversary of Pakistan’s Independence, I extend my heartiest felicitations to the entire nation. This day reminds us of the innumerable sacrifices rendered by our founding fathers under the dynamic leadership of Quaid-e-Azam Muhammad Ali Jinnah for carving this homeland “Pakistan” for us. Today, we also reaffirm our resolve to uphold Pakistan’s ideology and make Pakistan an ideal modern Islamic welfare nation-State.”",
        "The message of Pakistan Prime Minister Mian Muhammad Shehbaz Sharif was read out for the audience by Attaché Kalsoom Qaiser. The message included: “The 75th Independence Day is a watershed moment in our nation’s history. Today we pay rich tributes to Muslims of the sub-continent and express our collective gratitude to them for their heroic struggle, and epic sacrifices for the creation of a new State. The coming of Pakistan into existence was not less than a miracle that stunned friends and foes alike, beating all predictions and assessments.”",
        "In his remarks, the High Commissioner Burki said 14 August is the day of happiness; a day of bowing our heads before Almighty Allah in thankfulness and a day of renewing our pledge that we will continue to work with unity, faith and discipline for the objectives, for which Pakistan was created. Today we remember our forefathers and martyrs and pay our gratitude to them for making extraordinary sacrifices to give us an independent homeland.",
        "“We believe in having cordial relations with all countries and especially so with countries in our neighbourhood.  That is the reason that Pakistan was and is a strong advocate of regional connectivity in South Asia through the specialised forum of SAARC.  Both Pakistan and Sri Lanka are key members of SAARC and both countries have shared strong bonds of friendship and brotherhood since they came into being,” the High Commissioner added.",
        "The event was well-attended by a good number of participants including diplomats, members of the Pakistani community, officials and families of the High Commission, local dignitaries, journalists and friends of Pakistan. The event was also attended by officers of PNS Taimur which called Colombo on Friday."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "75th",
          "label": "ORDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "Independence Day",
          "label": "EVENT"
        },
        {
          "text": "Pakistan",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "Sri Lanka",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Pakistan",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Pakistani",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Saturday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "The Diamond Jubilee",
            "label": "WORK_OF_ART"
          },
          {
            "text": "Pakistan",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Pakistan",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Islamic",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "State",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Pakistan",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Umar Farooq Burki HI",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Pakistan",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Pakistan High Commission",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Colombo",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Asmma Kamal",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Pakistan",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Arif Alvi",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "75th",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Pakistan",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "This day",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Quaid-e-Azam",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Muhammad Ali Jinnah",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Pakistan",
            "label": "WORK_OF_ART"
          },
          {
            "text": "Today",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Pakistan",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Pakistan",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Islamic",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Pakistan",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Mian Muhammad",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Shehbaz Sharif",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Attaché Kalsoom Qaiser",
            "label": "PRODUCT"
          },
          {
            "text": "75th",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Independence Day",
            "label": "EVENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "Today",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Muslims",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "State",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Pakistan",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Burki",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "14 August",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the day",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Pakistan",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Today",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Pakistan",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "South Asia",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "SAARC",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Pakistan",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Pakistani",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "the High Commission",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Pakistan",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "PNS Taimur",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Colombo",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Friday",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "පාකිස්ථානයේ 75 වන නිදහස් දින සැමරුම ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේදී",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "පාකිස්තානයේ මහ කොමසාරිස් කාර්යාලය සහ ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ පාකිස්තාන ප්‍රජාව සෙනසුරාදා පාකිස්තානයේ නිදහසේ “වජ්‍ර ජුබිලිය” සාම්ප්‍රදායික උද්යෝගයෙන් සහ පාකිස්තානය ශක්තිමත්, ගතික, ප්‍රගතිශීලී, ඉවසිලිවන්ත සහ ප්‍රජාතන්ත්‍රවාදී ඉස්ලාමීය සුබසාධන රාජ්‍යයක් බවට පත් කිරීමට අධිෂ්ඨානයෙන් සමරනු ලැබීය.",
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ පකිස්ථාන ඉස්ලාමීය ජනරජයේ මහ කොමසාරිස්, මේජර් ජෙනරාල් (විශ්‍රාමික) උමාර් ෆාරුක් බුර්කි එච්අයි විසින් පකිස්ථාන මහ කොමසාරිස් කාර්යාලයේදී විචිත්‍රවත් හා වර්ණවත් උත්සවයකදී ජාතික ගීය තාලයට පාකිස්ථානයේ ජාතික ධජය එසවීය. කොළඹ.",
        "වෙළඳ හා ආයෝජන අනුයුක්ති අස්මා කමල් විසින් පකිස්තාන ජනාධිපති ආචාර්ය අරිෆ් අල්විගේ පණිවිඩය කියවන ලදී: “පකිස්තානයේ නිදහසේ 75 වන සංවත්සරයේ ප්‍රීතිමත් අවස්ථාවෙහිදී, මම මුළු ජාතියටම මගේ හෘදයාංගම සුබ පැතුම් පිරිනමමි. ක්වායිඩ්-ඊ-අසාම් මුහම්මද් අලි ජින්නාගේ ගතික නායකත්වය යටතේ අපගේ ආරම්භක පියවරුන් විසින් මෙම නිජබිම \"පකිස්ථානය\" අප වෙනුවෙන් කැටයම් කිරීම සඳහා කළ අප්‍රමාණ කැපකිරීම් මෙම දිනය අපට සිහිපත් කරයි. අද අපි පකිස්තානයේ දෘෂ්ටිවාදය ආරක්ෂා කිරීමට සහ පකිස්ථානය පරමාදර්ශී නූතන ඉස්ලාමීය සුභසාධන රාජ්‍යයක් බවට පත් කිරීමට අපගේ අධිෂ්ඨානය යළිත් තහවුරු කරමු.",
        "පාකිස්ථාන අග්‍රාමාත්‍ය මියන් මුහම්මද් ෂෙබාස් ෂරීෆ්ගේ පණිවිඩය අනුයුක්ත Kalsoom Qaiser විසින් ප්‍රේක්ෂකයින් සඳහා කියවන ලදී. පණිවිඩයේ ඇතුළත් වූයේ: “75 වැනි නිදහස් දිනය අපේ ජාතියේ ඉතිහාසයේ දිය කඩන මොහොතකි. අද අපි උප මහාද්වීපයේ මුස්ලිම්වරුන්ට පොහොසත් උපහාර පුද කරන අතර නව රාජ්‍යයක් නිර්මාණය කිරීම සඳහා ඔවුන්ගේ වීරෝදාර අරගලය සහ වීර කාව්‍ය පරිත්‍යාග සඳහා අපගේ සාමූහික කෘතඥතාව පළ කරමු. පකිස්තානය පැවැත්මට පැමිණීම සියලු අනාවැකි සහ තක්සේරු කිරීම් අභිබවා මිතුරන් හා සතුරන් මවිතයට පත් කළ ආශ්චර්යයකට වඩා අඩු නොවේ.",
        "ඔහුගේ ප්‍රකාශයේ මහ කොමසාරිස් බුර්කි පැවසුවේ අගෝස්තු 14 සතුටේ දිනයයි; සර්වබලධාරී අල්ලාහ් ඉදිරියේ අපගේ හිස නමා ස්තුතිවන්ත වන දිනයක් සහ පකිස්ථානය නිර්මාණය කරන ලද අරමුණු සඳහා අපි එකමුතුකම, විශ්වාසය සහ විනය ඇතිව අඛණ්ඩව කටයුතු කරන බවට අපගේ ප්‍රතිඥාව අලුත් කරන දිනයක්. අද අපි අපේ මුතුන් මිත්තන් සහ දිවි පිදූවන් සිහිපත් කරන අතර අපට ස්වාධීන නිජබිමක් ලබා දීමට අසාමාන්‍ය කැපකිරීම් කළ ඔවුන්ට අපගේ ප්‍රණාමය පුද කරමු.",
        "“සියලු රටවල් සමඟ සහ විශේෂයෙන්ම අපගේ අසල්වැසි රටවල් සමඟ සුහද සබඳතා පැවැත්වීම ගැන අපි විශ්වාස කරනවා. සාර්ක් විශේෂ සංසදය හරහා දකුණු ආසියාවේ කලාපීය සම්බන්ධතාව සඳහා පකිස්තානය ප්‍රබලව පෙනී සිටින්නේත් එයත් එයට හේතුවයි. පකිස්තානය සහ ශ්‍රී ලංකාව යන රටවල් දෙකම සාර්ක් සංවිධානයේ ප්‍රධාන සාමාජිකයන් වන අතර එම රටවල් දෙක බිහි වූ දා සිට මිත්‍රත්වයේ සහ සහෝදරත්වයේ ශක්තිමත් බැඳීම් ඇති කර ගෙන ඇත,” මහ කොමසාරිස්වරයා වැඩිදුරටත් පැවසීය.",
        "මෙම අවස්ථාවට රාජ්‍ය තාන්ත්‍රිකයින්, පකිස්ථාන ප්‍රජාවේ සාමාජිකයින්, මහ කොමසාරිස් කාර්යාලයේ නිලධාරීන් සහ පවුල්වල සාමාජිකයින්, ප්‍රාදේශීය සම්භාවනීයයින්, මාධ්‍යවේදීන් සහ පකිස්ථානයේ හිතවතුන් ඇතුළු විශාල පිරිසක් සහභාගී වූහ. මෙම අවස්ථාවට සිකුරාදා කොළඹ ඇමතූ PNS Taimur හි නිලධාරීන් ද සහභාගී විය."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "75 වැනි",
          "label": "ORDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "නිදහස් දිනය",
          "label": "EVENT"
        },
        {
          "text": "පකිස්ථානය",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "පකිස්ථානය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "පකිස්ථානු",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "සෙනසුරාදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "දියමන්ති ජුබිලිය",
            "label": "WORK_OF_ART"
          },
          {
            "text": "පකිස්ථානය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "පකිස්ථානය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉස්ලාමීය",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "රජයේ",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "පකිස්ථානය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "උමාර් ෆාරුක් බුර්කි එච්.අයි",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "පකිස්ථානය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "පකිස්ථාන මහ කොමසාරිස් කාර්යාලය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "කොළඹ",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "අස්මා කමල්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "පකිස්ථානය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "අරිෆ් අල්වි",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "75 වැනි",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "පකිස්ථානය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "අද දවස",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ක්වායිඩ්-ඊ-අසාම්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "මුහම්මද් අලි ජින්නා",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "පකිස්ථානය",
            "label": "WORK_OF_ART"
          },
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "පකිස්ථානය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "පකිස්ථානය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉස්ලාමීය",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "පකිස්ථානය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මියන් මුහම්මද්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Shehbaz Sharif",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "අනුයුක්ත Kalsoom Qaiser",
            "label": "PRODUCT"
          },
          {
            "text": "75 වැනි",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "නිදහස් දිනය",
            "label": "EVENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මුස්ලිම්",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "රජයේ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "පකිස්ථානය",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "බුර්කි",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "අගෝස්තු 14",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "දවස",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "පකිස්ථානය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "පකිස්ථානය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "දකුණු ආසියාව",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "සාක්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "පකිස්ථානය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "පකිස්ථානු",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "මහ කොමසාරිස්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "පකිස්ථානය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "පීඑන්එස් තයිමූර්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "කොළඹ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "සිකුරාදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "பாகிஸ்தானின் 75வது சுதந்திர தின விழா இலங்கையில் கொண்டாடப்பட்டது",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "பாகிஸ்தானின் உயர் ஸ்தானிகராலயம் மற்றும் இலங்கையில் உள்ள பாக்கிஸ்தான் சமூகம் சனிக்கிழமையன்று பாகிஸ்தானின் சுதந்திரத்தின் \"வைர விழாவை\" பாரம்பரிய ஆர்வத்துடன் கொண்டாடியது மற்றும் பாகிஸ்தானை வலுவான, ஆற்றல்மிக்க, முற்போக்கான, சகிப்புத்தன்மை மற்றும் ஜனநாயக இஸ்லாமிய நலன்புரி நாடாக மாற்றும் தீர்மானம் கொண்டது.",
        "இலங்கையில் உள்ள பாகிஸ்தான் இஸ்லாமியக் குடியரசின் உயர் ஸ்தானிகர் மேஜர் ஜெனரல் (ஓய்வு) உமர் ஃபாரூக் புர்கி எச்ஐ பாகிஸ்தான் உயர் ஸ்தானிகராலயத்தில் ஒரு துடிப்பான மற்றும் வண்ணமயமான விழாவில் தேசிய கீதம் இசைக்கப்படும் வகையில் பாகிஸ்தானின் தேசியக் கொடியை ஏற்றினார். கொழும்பு.",
        "வர்த்தகம் மற்றும் முதலீட்டு இணைப்பாளர் அஸ்மா கமால், பாகிஸ்தான் அதிபர் டாக்டர் ஆரிஃப் அல்வியின் செய்தியை மேற்கோள் காட்டினார்: “பாகிஸ்தானின் 75 வது சுதந்திர தினத்தின் மகிழ்ச்சியான சந்தர்ப்பத்தில், முழு தேசத்திற்கும் எனது மனமார்ந்த வாழ்த்துகளைத் தெரிவித்துக் கொள்கிறேன். இந்த தாயகமான \"பாகிஸ்தானை\" நமக்காக செதுக்குவதற்காக குவைத்-இ-ஆசம் முஹம்மது அலி ஜின்னாவின் ஆற்றல்மிக்க தலைமையின் கீழ் நமது ஸ்தாபக தந்தைகள் ஆற்றிய எண்ணற்ற தியாகங்களை இந்த நாள் நினைவூட்டுகிறது. இன்று, பாகிஸ்தானின் சித்தாந்தத்தை நிலைநிறுத்துவதற்கும், பாகிஸ்தானை ஒரு சிறந்த நவீன இஸ்லாமிய நலன்புரி நாடாக மாற்றுவதற்கும் எங்களின் தீர்மானத்தை மீண்டும் உறுதிப்படுத்துகிறோம்.",
        "பாகிஸ்தான் பிரதமர் மியான் முஹம்மது ஷெஹ்பாஸ் ஷெரீப்பின் செய்தியை அட்டாச் கல்சூம் கைசர் பார்வையாளர்களுக்காக வாசித்தார். அந்த செய்தியில் கூறப்பட்டுள்ளதாவது: “75வது சுதந்திர தினம் நமது நாட்டின் வரலாற்றில் ஒரு முக்கியமான தருணம். இன்று நாம் துணைக் கண்டத்தின் முஸ்லிம்களுக்கு செழுமையான அஞ்சலி செலுத்துகிறோம், மேலும் அவர்களின் வீரம் செறிந்த போராட்டத்திற்காகவும், ஒரு புதிய மாநிலத்தை உருவாக்குவதற்கான காவிய தியாகத்திற்காகவும் அவர்களுக்கு எங்கள் கூட்டு நன்றியைத் தெரிவித்துக் கொள்கிறோம். அனைத்து கணிப்புகளையும் மதிப்பீடுகளையும் முறியடித்து, நண்பர்களையும் எதிரிகளையும் ஒரே மாதிரியாக திகைக்கச் செய்த ஒரு அதிசயத்திற்குக் குறைவானது அல்ல, பாகிஸ்தான் உருவானது.",
        "உயர் ஸ்தானிகர் புர்கி தனது கருத்துக்களில், ஆகஸ்ட் 14 மகிழ்ச்சியின் நாள்; எல்லாம் வல்ல அல்லாஹ்வுக்கு நன்றியுடன் தலை வணங்கும் நாள் மற்றும் பாகிஸ்தான் உருவாக்கப்பட்ட நோக்கங்களுக்காக ஒற்றுமை, நம்பிக்கை மற்றும் ஒழுக்கத்துடன் தொடர்ந்து பணியாற்றுவோம் என்ற உறுதிமொழியை புதுப்பிக்கும் நாள். இன்று நாம் எமது முன்னோர்களையும், தியாகிகளையும் நினைவு கூர்வதுடன், சுதந்திரமான தாயகத்தை எமக்கு வழங்குவதற்கு அசாதாரன தியாகங்களைச் செய்தமைக்காக அவர்களுக்கு எமது நன்றியை செலுத்துகின்றோம்.",
        "“அனைத்து நாடுகளுடனும், குறிப்பாக நமது அண்டை நாடுகளில் உள்ள நாடுகளுடனும் நல்லுறவைக் கொண்டிருப்பதை நாங்கள் நம்புகிறோம். அதனால்தான், SAARC இன் சிறப்பு மன்றத்தின் மூலம் தெற்காசியாவில் பிராந்திய இணைப்புக்கு பாகிஸ்தான் வலுவான ஆதரவாளராக இருந்தது. பாக்கிஸ்தான் மற்றும் இலங்கை ஆகிய இரண்டும் சார்க் அமைப்பின் முக்கிய அங்கத்தினர்கள் மற்றும் இரு நாடுகளும் அவை உருவானதில் இருந்து வலுவான நட்பு மற்றும் சகோதரத்துவப் பிணைப்பைப் பகிர்ந்து கொள்கின்றன, ”என்று உயர்ஸ்தானிகர் மேலும் கூறினார்.",
        "தூதர்கள், பாகிஸ்தான் சமூகத்தைச் சேர்ந்தவர்கள், அதிகாரிகள் மற்றும் உயர் ஸ்தானிகராலயத்தின் குடும்பத்தினர், உள்ளூர் பிரமுகர்கள், ஊடகவியலாளர்கள் மற்றும் பாகிஸ்தானின் நண்பர்கள் உட்பட ஏராளமான பங்கேற்பாளர்கள் இந்த நிகழ்வில் கலந்து கொண்டனர். இந்த நிகழ்வில் வெள்ளிக்கிழமை கொழும்பை அழைத்த PNS தைமூர் அதிகாரிகளும் கலந்து கொண்டனர்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "75வது",
          "label": "ORDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "சுதந்திர தினம்",
          "label": "EVENT"
        },
        {
          "text": "பாகிஸ்தான்",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "இலங்கை",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "பாகிஸ்தான்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாகிஸ்தானியர்",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சனிக்கிழமை",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "வைர விழா",
            "label": "WORK_OF_ART"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாகிஸ்தான்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாகிஸ்தான்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இஸ்லாமிய",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "நிலை",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பாகிஸ்தான்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "உமர் பாரூக் புர்கி எச்.ஐ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாகிஸ்தான்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாகிஸ்தான் உயர் ஸ்தானிகராலயம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "கொழும்பு",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "அஸ்மா கமல்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாகிஸ்தான்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆரிஃப் ஆல்வி",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "75வது",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாகிஸ்தான்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்த நாள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "குவைட்-இ-ஆசம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "முகமது அலி ஜின்னா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாகிஸ்தான்",
            "label": "WORK_OF_ART"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாகிஸ்தான்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாகிஸ்தான்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இஸ்லாமிய",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பாகிஸ்தான்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "மியான் முஹம்மது",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஷெபாஸ் ஷெரீப்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "கல்சூம் கைசர் இணைக்கவும்",
            "label": "PRODUCT"
          },
          {
            "text": "75வது",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "சுதந்திர தினம்",
            "label": "EVENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "முஸ்லிம்கள்",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "நிலை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாகிஸ்தான்",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "புர்கி",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "14 ஆகஸ்ட்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "தினம்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாகிஸ்தான்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பாகிஸ்தான்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "தெற்காசியா",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "சார்க்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாகிஸ்தான்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பாகிஸ்தானியர்",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "உயர் ஆணையம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாகிஸ்தான்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "பிஎன்எஸ் தைமூர்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "கொழும்பு",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "வெள்ளி",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}