{
  "newspaper_id": "ada-derana-lk",
  "url": "http://www.adaderana.lk/news/84582/youth-missing-after-jumping-into-river-from-peradeniya-bridge",
  "time_ut": 1661659440,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Youth missing after jumping into river from Peradeniya Bridge",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Youth missing after jumping into river from Peradeniya Bridge",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "A person has reportedly gone missing after jumping into the Mahaweli River from the bridge near the Peradeniya town in Kandy.",
        "Police said that a traveling bag was found at the place where the person had jumped into the river and that a national identity card, an university ID card, a laptop, two bank cards, an exam admission card, a wallet and a pair of shoes were found in it.",
        "Accordingly, it has been revealed that the missing person is a 22-year-old resident of Bulagahapitiya, Eheliyagoda.",
        "Police lifeguards, navy lifeguards and local residents are engaged in a search operation for the missing person."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Peradeniya Bridge",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "the Mahaweli River",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Peradeniya",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kandy",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "two",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "22-year-old",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "navy",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "පේරාදෙණිය පාලමෙන් ගඟට පැන තරුණයෙක් අතුරුදන්",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "මහනුවර පේරාදෙණිය නගරයට නුදුරින් පිහිටි පාලමෙන් මහවැලි ගඟට පැන පුද්ගලයෙකු අතුරුදන්ව ඇතැයි වාර්තා වේ.",
        "පුද්ගලයා ගඟට පැන ඇති ස්ථානයේ තිබී ගමන් බෑගයක් ද ජාතික හැඳුනුම්පතක්, විශ්වවිද්‍යාල හැඳුනුම්පතක්, ලැප්ටොප් පරිගණකයක්, බැංකු කාඩ්පත් දෙකක්, විභාග ප්‍රවේශ පත්‍රයක්, මුදල් පසුම්බියක් සහ පාවහන් යුගලයක් ද තිබී සොයාගත් බව පොලිසිය පවසයි. එහි තිබී හමු විය.",
        "ඒ අනුව අතුරුදන්ව ඇත්තේ ඇහැලියගොඩ බුලගහපිටිය ප්‍රදේශයේ පදිංචි 22 හැවිරිදි තරුණයෙකු බවයි අනාවරණ වී ඇත්තේ.",
        "පොලිස් ජීවිතාරක්ෂක නිලධාරීන්, නාවික හමුදා ජීවිතාරක්ෂක නිලධාරීන් සහ ප්‍රදේශවාසීන් එක්ව අතුරුදන් වූ පුද්ගලයා සෙවීමේ මෙහෙයුම්වල නිරතව සිටිනවා."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "පේරාදෙණිය පාලම",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "මහවැලි ගඟ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "පේරාදෙණිය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මහනුවර",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "දෙක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "22 හැවිරිදිය",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "නාවික",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "பேராதனை பாலத்தில் இருந்து ஆற்றில் குதித்த இளைஞர் காணாமல் போயுள்ளார்",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "கண்டி பேராதனை நகருக்கு அருகில் உள்ள பாலத்தில் இருந்து மகாவலி ஆற்றில் குதித்த நபர் ஒருவர் காணாமல் போயுள்ளதாக தெரிவிக்கப்படுகின்றது.",
        "குறித்த நபர் ஆற்றில் குதித்த இடத்திலிருந்து பயணப் பை ஒன்றும், தேசிய அடையாள அட்டை, பல்கலைக்கழக அடையாள அட்டை, மடிக்கணினி, இரண்டு வங்கி அட்டைகள், பரீட்சை அனுமதி அட்டை, பணப்பை மற்றும் ஒரு ஜோடி காலணிகள் என்பன காணப்பட்டதாக பொலிஸார் தெரிவித்தனர். அதில் காணப்பட்டன.",
        "இதன்படி, காணாமல் போனவர் எஹலியகொட, புலகஹாபிட்டிய பகுதியைச் சேர்ந்த 22 வயதுடையவர் எனத் தெரியவந்துள்ளது.",
        "காணாமல் போன நபரை தேடும் நடவடிக்கையில் பொலிஸார், கடற்படையின் உயிர்காக்கும் படையினர் மற்றும் பிரதேசவாசிகள் ஈடுபட்டுள்ளனர்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "பேராதனை பாலம்",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "மகாவலி ஆறு",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "பேராதனை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "கண்டி",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இரண்டு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "22 வயது",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "கடற்படை",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}