{
  "newspaper_id": "economy-next-com",
  "url": "https://economynext.com/sri-lanka-ex-mp-ranjan-ramayanake-leaves-prison-job-offered-99056/",
  "time_ut": 1661506140,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Sri Lanka ex-MP Ranjan Ramayanake leaves prison, job offered",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Sri Lanka ex-MP Ranjan Ramayanake leaves prison, job offered",
      "author": "",
      "body_lines": [
        "ECONOMYNEXT – Sri Lanka former MP Ranjan Ramanayake, who received a conditional presidential pardon, has left the Welikada prison in Colombo and has also been offered a position as goodwill ambassador for migrant workers.",
        "A large crowd had gathered outside the Welikada prison complex to welcome the popular actor-turned-politician who had been imprisoned over charges of contempt of court.",
        "Shouts of “Ranja! Ranja!” (his nickname) were heard as he came out of the prison gates Friday August 26 afternoon.",
        "Meanwhile, Minister of Labour and Foreign Employment Manusha Nanayakkara, one of Ramanayake’s former colleagues in the main opposition Samagi Jana Balawegaya (SJB) who lobbied for his release, has offered him a job.",
        "“I just offered [Ramanayake] a position as goodwill ambassador to promote Sri Lankan migrant worker welfare globally and he gladly accepted,” Nanayakkara tweeted Friday afternoon.",
        "I just offered @RamanayakeR a position as a goodwill ambassador to promote Sri Lankan migrant worker welfare globally upon his release and he gladly accepted. This is a voluntary position to make use of his tacit knowledges in the area of foreign employment pic.twitter.com/Zqz7BqcNMz",
        "Ramanayake has been vocal about migrant worker rights and was actively, albeit unsuccessfully, involved in efforts to save the life of a Sri Lankan domestic worker who was executed in Saudi Arabia.",
        "Sri Lanka president signs conditional pardon for ex MP Ranjan Ramanayake",
        "Ramanayake left prison on Friday having served over one and a half years of a four-year sentence.",
        "The Supreme Court sentenced the former main opposition Samagi Jana Balavegaya (SJB) parliamentarian to four years’ rigorous imprisonment on January 12, 2021, over contempt of court charges, in connection with disparaging remarks he had allegedly made about the judiciary in August 2017.",
        "Opposition and SJB leader Sajith Premadasa had previously written to former President Gotabaya Rajapaksa appealing for a presidential pardon for Ramanayake. The pardon never came, though Rajapaksa controversially pardoned murder-convict and former MP Duminda Silva, drawing criticism from the the Office of the United Nations High Commissioner for Human Rights (OHCHR) and others. (Colombo/Aug26/2022)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Sri Lanka",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "Ranjan Ramayanake",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ranjan Ramanayake",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Welikada",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Colombo",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Welikada",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Ranja",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Friday August 26",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "afternoon",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "one",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ramanayake",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Samagi",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Jana Balawegaya",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "SJB",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lankan",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "Friday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "afternoon",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lankan",
            "label": "LOC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lankan",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "Saudi Arabia",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ranjan Ramanayake",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Friday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "one and a half years",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "four-year",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "The Supreme Court",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Samagi",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Jana Balavegaya",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "SJB",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "four years",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "January 12, 2021",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "August 2017",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "SJB",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sajith Premadasa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Gotabaya Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ramanayake",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Rajapaksa",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Duminda Silva",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the the Office of the United Nations",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Colombo/Aug26/2022",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "ශ්‍රී ලංකා හිටපු පාර්ලිමේන්තු මන්ත්‍රී රන්ජන් රාමායණක හිරෙන් පිටව යයි, රැකියාවක් පිරිනැමේ",
      "author": "",
      "body_lines": [
        "ECONOMYNEXT – කොන්දේසි සහිත ජනාධිපති සමාවක් ලැබූ ශ්‍රී ලංකා හිටපු පාර්ලිමේන්තු මන්ත්‍රී රන්ජන් රාමනායක මහතා කොළඹ වැලිකඩ බන්ධනාගාරයෙන් පිටව ගොස් ඇති අතර ඔහුට සංක්‍රමණික ශ්‍රමිකයින් සඳහා සුහද තානාපති තනතුරක් ද පිරිනමා තිබේ.",
        "අධිකරණයට අපහාස කිරීමේ චෝදනාව මත සිරගත කර සිටින ජනප්‍රිය නළුවෙකු හා දේශපාලනඥයෙකු පිළිගැනීමට වැලිකඩ බන්ධනාගාර සංකීර්ණය ඉදිරිපිට විශාල පිරිසක් රැස්ව සිටියහ.",
        "“රංජා! රන්ජා!” (ඔහුගේ අන්වර්ථ නාමය) ඔහු අගෝස්තු 26 සිකුරාදා සවස බන්ධනාගාර ගේට්ටුවෙන් පිටතට එන විට ඇසිණි.",
        "මේ අතර, ඔහු නිදහස් කර ගැනීම සඳහා බලපෑම් කළ ප්‍රධාන විපක්ෂයේ සමගි ජන බලවේගයේ (SJB) රාමනායකගේ හිටපු සගයෙකු වන කම්කරු හා විදේශ රැකියා අමාත්‍ය මනූෂ නානායක්කාර ඔහුට රැකියාවක් ලබා දී ඇත.",
        "“ශ්‍රී ලාංකික සංක්‍රමණික සේවක සුභසාධනය ගෝලීය වශයෙන් ප්‍රවර්ධනය කිරීම සඳහා මම [රාමනායක]ට හොඳ හිත තානාපති තනතුරක් පිරිනැමූ අතර ඔහු සතුටින් පිළිගත්තා,” නානායක්කාර සිකුරාදා සවස ට්විටර් කළේය.",
        "ඔහු නිදහස් වූ පසු ගෝලීය වශයෙන් ශ්‍රී ලාංකික සංක්‍රමණික සේවක සුභසාධනය ප්‍රවර්ධනය කිරීම සඳහා මම @RamanayakeR හට හොඳ හිත තානාපති තනතුරක් පිරිනැමූ අතර ඔහු සතුටින් පිළිගත්තේය. මෙය විදේශ රැකියා ක්ෂේත්‍රයේ ඔහුගේ නිහඬ දැනුම භාවිතා කිරීමට ස්වේච්ඡා තනතුරකි pic.twitter.com/Zqz7BqcNMz",
        "රාමනායක මහතා සංක්‍රමණික සේවක අයිතීන් පිළිබඳව හඬ නඟා ඇති අතර සෞදි අරාබියේදී මරණ දඬුවමට ලක් වූ ශ්‍රී ලාංකික ගෘහ සේවිකාවකගේ ජීවිතය බේරා ගැනීමේ ප්‍රයත්නවල අසාර්ථක වූවත් ක්‍රියාකාරීව සම්බන්ධ විය.",
        "හිටපු පාර්ලිමේන්තු මන්ත්‍රී රන්ජන් රාමනායකට ශ්‍රී ලංකා ජනාධිපතිවරයා කොන්දේසි සහිත සමාවක් අත්සන් කරයි",
        "වසර හතරක සිර දඬුවමකින් වසර එකහමාරකට වැඩි කාලයක් ගෙවා සිකුරාදා රාමනායක බන්ධනාගාරයෙන් පිටව ගියේය.",
        "2017 අගෝස්තු මාසයේදී අධිකරණයට අපහාස කළ බව කියන ප්‍රකාශ සම්බන්ධයෙන් අධිකරණයට අපහාස කිරීමේ චෝදනාව මත ශ්‍රේෂ්ඨාධිකරණය විසින් 2021 ජනවාරි 12 වැනි දින හිටපු ප්‍රධාන විපක්ෂයේ සමගි ජන බලවේගයේ (SJB) පාර්ලිමේන්තු මන්ත්‍රීවරයාට වසර 4ක බරපතළ වැඩ සහිත සිර දඬුවමක් නියම කළේය.",
        "විපක්ෂයේ සහ SJB නායක සජිත් ප්‍රේමදාස මහතා මීට පෙර හිටපු ජනාධිපති ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ මහතාට ලිඛිතව ලිඛිතව ඉල්ලා සිටියේ රාමනායක මහතාට ජනාධිපති සමාවක් ලබාදෙන ලෙසයි. එක්සත් ජාතීන්ගේ මානව හිමිකම් පිළිබඳ මහ කොමසාරිස් කාර්යාලයේ (OHCHR) සහ අනෙකුත් අයගේ විවේචනයට ලක්ව රාජපක්ෂ විසින් මිනීමැරුම් වරදකරු සහ හිටපු පාර්ලිමේන්තු මන්ත්‍රී දුමින්ද සිල්වාට මතභේදාත්මක ලෙස සමාව ලබා දුන්නද සමාව කිසිදා නොලැබුණි. (කොළඹ/අගෝස්තු26/2022)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "රන්ජන් රාමායනක",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "රන්ජන් රාමනායක",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "වැලිකඩ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "කොළඹ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "වැලිකඩ",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "රන්ජා",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "අගෝස්තු 26 සිකුරාදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "දහවල්",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "එක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "රාමනායක",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "සමගි",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජන බලවේගය",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "එස්.ජේ.බී",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලාංකික",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "සිකුරාදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "දහවල්",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලාංකික",
            "label": "LOC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලාංකික",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "සවුදි අරාබිය",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "රන්ජන් රාමනායක",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "සිකුරාදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "අවුරුදු එකහමාරක්",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "අවුරුදු හතරක්",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රේෂ්ඨාධිකරණය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "සමගි",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජන බලවේගය",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "එස්.ජේ.බී",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "අවුරුදු හතරක්",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "2021 ජනවාරි 12",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "2017 අගෝස්තු",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "එස්.ජේ.බී",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "සජිත් ප්‍රේමදාස",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "රාමනායක",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "දුමින්ද සිල්වා",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "එක්සත් ජාතීන්ගේ කාර්යාලය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "කොළඹ/අගෝස්තු 26/2022",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "இலங்கை முன்னாள் எம்.பி., ரஞ்சன் ராமாயணகே சிறையில் இருந்து வெளியேறினார், வேலை வாய்ப்பு!",
      "author": "",
      "body_lines": [
        "பொருளாதாரம் - நிபந்தனையுடன் கூடிய ஜனாதிபதி மன்னிப்பைப் பெற்ற இலங்கையின் முன்னாள் பாராளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர் ரஞ்சன் ராமநாயக்க, கொழும்பு வெலிக்கடை சிறையிலிருந்து வெளியேறியதுடன், புலம்பெயர்ந்த தொழிலாளர்களுக்கான நல்லெண்ணத் தூதுவராக பதவியும் வழங்கப்பட்டுள்ளது.",
        "நீதிமன்றத்தை அவமதித்த குற்றச்சாட்டின் பேரில் சிறையில் அடைக்கப்பட்டுள்ள பிரபல நடிகரும் அரசியல்வாதியுமான அவரை வரவேற்க வெலிக்கடை சிறைச்சாலை வளாகத்திற்கு வெளியே பெருந்திரளான மக்கள் திரண்டிருந்தனர்.",
        "“ரஞ்சா! ரஞ்சா!” (அவரது புனைப்பெயர்) அவர் வெள்ளிக்கிழமை ஆகஸ்ட் 26 மதியம் சிறை வாயிலிலிருந்து வெளியே வந்தபோது கேட்டது.",
        "இதற்கிடையில், தொழிலாளர் மற்றும் வெளிநாட்டு வேலைவாய்ப்பு அமைச்சர் மனுஷ நாணயக்கார, ராமநாயக்கவின் முன்னாள் சகாக்களில் ஒருவரான பிரதான எதிர்க்கட்சியான சமகி ஜன பலவேகய (SJB) அவரது விடுதலைக்காக அழுத்தம் கொடுத்தவர், அவருக்கு வேலை வாய்ப்பை வழங்கியுள்ளார்.",
        "\"உலகளவில் இலங்கை புலம்பெயர்ந்த தொழிலாளர் நலனை மேம்படுத்துவதற்காக நான் [ராமநாயக்க] நல்லெண்ண தூதராக ஒரு பதவியை வழங்கினேன், அவர் மகிழ்ச்சியுடன் ஏற்றுக்கொண்டார்\" என்று வெள்ளிக்கிழமை பிற்பகல் நாணயக்கார ட்வீட் செய்தார்.",
        "நான் @RamanayakeR விடுதலையானதும் இலங்கையின் புலம்பெயர்ந்த தொழிலாளர் நலனை உலகளவில் மேம்படுத்துவதற்கு ஒரு நல்லெண்ண தூதுவராக பதவியை வழங்கினேன், அதை அவர் மகிழ்ச்சியுடன் ஏற்றுக்கொண்டார். இது வெளிநாட்டு வேலைவாய்ப்பு துறையில் அவரது மறைமுக அறிவைப் பயன்படுத்துவதற்கான ஒரு தன்னார்வ நிலைப்பாடு pic.twitter.com/Zqz7BqcNMz",
        "சவூதி அரேபியாவில் தூக்கிலிடப்பட்ட இலங்கை வீட்டுப் பணிப்பெண்ணின் உயிரைக் காப்பாற்றும் முயற்சிகளில் தோல்வியுற்றாலும், புலம்பெயர்ந்த தொழிலாளர் உரிமைகள் குறித்து ராமநாயக்க குரல் கொடுத்து வருகிறார்.",
        "முன்னாள் பாராளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர் ரஞ்சன் ராமநாயக்கவுக்கு நிபந்தனையுடன் கூடிய மன்னிப்பில் இலங்கை ஜனாதிபதி கையெழுத்திட்டுள்ளார்",
        "நான்கு வருட சிறைத்தண்டனையின் ஒன்றரை வருடங்களுக்கும் மேலாக சிறைவாசம் அனுபவித்த ராமநாயக்க வெள்ளிக்கிழமை சிறையிலிருந்து வெளியேறினார்.",
        "முன்னாள் பிரதான எதிர்க்கட்சியான சமகி ஜன பலவேகய (SJB) நாடாளுமன்ற உறுப்பினருக்கு, ஆகஸ்ட் 2017 இல் நீதித்துறையை அவமதித்ததாகக் கூறப்பட்டதாகக் கூறப்படும் நீதிமன்ற அவமதிப்புக் குற்றச்சாட்டின் பேரில், உச்ச நீதிமன்றம் 2021 ஜனவரி 12 அன்று நான்கு ஆண்டுகள் கடுங்காவல் சிறைத்தண்டனை விதித்தது.",
        "ராமநாயக்கவுக்கு ஜனாதிபதி மன்னிப்பு வழங்குமாறு எதிர்க்கட்சி மற்றும் SJB தலைவரான சஜித் பிரேமதாச முன்னர் முன்னாள் ஜனாதிபதி கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ஷவுக்கு கடிதம் எழுதியிருந்தார். கொலைக் குற்றவாளியும் முன்னாள் எம்.பி.யுமான துமிந்த சில்வாவை ராஜபக்ச சர்ச்சைக்குரிய வகையில் மன்னித்தாலும், ஐக்கிய நாடுகள் மனித உரிமைகளுக்கான உயர்ஸ்தானிகர் அலுவலகம் (OHCHR) மற்றும் பிறரிடமிருந்து விமர்சனங்களுக்கு ஆளான போதிலும், மன்னிப்பு ஒருபோதும் வரவில்லை. (கொழும்பு/ஆகஸ்ட்26/2022)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "இலங்கை",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "ரஞ்சன் ராமாயணகே",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரஞ்சன் ராமநாயக்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "வெலிக்கடை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "கொழும்பு",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "வெலிக்கடை",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ரஞ்சா",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆகஸ்ட் 26 வெள்ளிக்கிழமை",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "பிற்பகல்",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஒன்று",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ராமநாயக்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "சமகி",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜன பலவேகயா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "எஸ்.ஜே.பி",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "வெள்ளி",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "பிற்பகல்",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "LOC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "சவூதி அரேபியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரஞ்சன் ராமநாயக்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "வெள்ளி",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஒன்றரை ஆண்டுகள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "நான்கு ஆண்டுகள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "உச்ச நீதிமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "சமகி",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜன பலவேகயா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "எஸ்.ஜே.பி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "நான்கு வருடங்கள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜனவரி 12, 2021",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆகஸ்ட் 2017",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "எஸ்.ஜே.பி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "சஜித் பிரேமதாச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ராமநாயக்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ராஜபக்சே",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "துமிந்த சில்வா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஐக்கிய நாடுகளின் அலுவலகம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "கொழும்பு/ஆகஸ்ட்26/2022",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}