{
  "newspaper_id": "tamil-mirror-lk",
  "url": "https://www.tamilmirror.lk/யாழ்ப்பாணம்/தமிழ்-மக்களின்-பிரச்சினைக்கும்-தீர்வு-வேண்டும்/71-300390",
  "time_ut": 1657733887,
  "original_lang": "ta",
  "original_title": "’தமிழ் மக்களின் பிரச்சினைக்கும் தீர்வு வேண்டும்’",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "'The problem of Tamil people also needs to be solved'",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "The religious leaders have jointly emphasized that all the parliamentary representatives should come together and take a decisive decision to propose a solution to the problem of the Tamil people in the current crisis.",
        "The religious leaders have jointly emphasized in a special media meeting held today at Nallai Thirunnasambandar Atheenam.",
        "In this regard, in their further statement, the religious leaders said that all the Tamil parties and especially the Tamil parliamentarians should come together soon and decide what the decision should be taken in today's Sri Lankan political environment. In this regard, they further stated,",
        "This is the moment when Tamil parliamentarians and party leaders, regardless of whether they are from the north-east, the hills or the south, overcome their differences and come together for the people. So get together and investigate with a wise vision. It is the imperative of time. At this time you will refuse to come together and investigate but it will be a great historical mistake.",
        "In this media meeting, Nallai Atheena Guru Principal Somasundara Paramacharya Swami, Jaffa Diocese Bishop Justin Paynat Gnanaprakasam, Thellippa Durgadevi Devasthanam President Kalanithi Aru. Thirumurugan and Rishi Thondunatha Swamy were present. (a)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Tamil",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Tamil",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Nallai Thirunnasambandar Atheenam",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Tamil",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Tamil",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lankan",
            "label": "LOC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Tamil",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Nallai Atheena",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Somasundara Paramacharya Swami",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Jaffa Diocese Bishop Justin Paynat",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kalanithi Aru",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Thirumurugan",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "දෙමළ ජනතාවගේ ප්‍රශ්නයත් විසඳිය යුතුයි",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "පවතින අර්බුදකාරී තත්ත්වය තුළ දෙමළ ජනතාවගේ ප්‍රශ්නයට විසඳුම් යෝජනා කිරීමට පාර්ලිමේන්තු නියෝජිතයන් සියලු දෙනා එක් වී තීරණාත්මක තීරණයක් ගත යුතු බව ආගමික නායකයින් ඒකාබද්ධව අවධාරණය කර තිබේ.",
        "නල්ලෙයි තිරුනසම්බන්ධර් ඇතීනම් හි අද පැවති විශේෂ මාධ්‍ය හමුවකදී ආගමික නායකයින් එක්ව අවධාරණය කර ඇත.",
        "මේ සම්බන්ධයෙන් වැඩිදුරටත් ප්‍රකාශයක් කරමින් ආගමික නායකයින් කියා සිටියේ සියලුම දෙමළ පක්ෂ සහ විශේෂයෙන්ම දෙමළ පාර්ලිමේන්තු මන්ත්‍රීවරුන් ඉක්මනින් එකතු වී අද පවතින ශ්‍රී ලාංකීය දේශපාලන වාතාවරණය තුළ ගත යුතු තීරණය කුමක්ද යන්න තීරණය කළ යුතු බවයි. මේ සම්බන්ධයෙන් ඔවුන් වැඩිදුරටත් මෙසේද කියා සිටියා.",
        "උතුරු නැඟෙනහිර, කඳුකරය, දකුණ යන භේදයකින් තොරව දෙමළ පාර්ලිමේන්තු මන්ත්‍රීවරුන් සහ පක්ෂ නායකයන් තම මතභේද දුරලා ජනතාව වෙනුවෙන් එක්වන මොහොතයි මේ. ඒ නිසා ඥානවන්ත දැක්මකින් එකතු වෙලා විමර්ශනය කරන්න. එය කාලයේ අවශ්‍යතාවයකි. මේ වෙලාවේ ඔබලා එකතුවෙලා විමර්ශනය කිරීම ප්‍රතික්‍ෂේප කරනවා නමුත් ඒක මහා ඓතිහාසික වරදක් වෙනවා.",
        "මෙම මාධ්‍ය හමුවේදී නල්ලෙයි ඇතීන ගුරු විදුහල්පති සෝමසුන්දර පරමාචාර්ය ස්වාමි, යාපනය රදගුරු හිමිපාණන් වන ජස්ටින් පයිනාට් ඥානප්‍රකාශම්, තෙල්ලිප්පා දුර්ගාදේවි දේවස්ථානයේ සභාපති කලනිති ආරු. තිරුමුරුගන් සහ රිෂි තොණ්ඩුනාථ ස්වාමි යන මහත්වරු පැමිණ සිටියහ. (ඒ)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "දෙමළ",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "දෙමළ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "නල්ලෙයි තිරුනසම්බන්ධර් ඇතීනම්",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "දෙමළ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "දෙමළ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලාංකික",
            "label": "LOC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "දෙමළ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "නල්ලයි ඇතීනා",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "සෝමසුන්දර පරමාචාර්ය ස්වාමි",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "යාපන රදගුරු පදවියේ රදගුරු ජස්ටින් පේනාට්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "කලනිති අරූ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "තිරුමුරුගන්",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "’தமிழ் மக்களின் பிரச்சினைக்கும் தீர்வு வேண்டும்’",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "தற்போதைய நெருக்கடிநிலையில் தமிழ்மக்களின் பிரச்சினைக்கான தீர்வினை முன்வைப்பதற்கு அனைத்து நாடாளுமன்றப் பிரதிநிதிகளும் ஒன்று கூடி தீர்க்கமான முடிவெடுக்கவேண்டுமென  மதத்தலைவர்கள் கூட்டாக வலியுறுத்தியுள்ளனர்.",
        "நல்லை திருஞானசம்பந்தர் ஆதீனத்தில் இன்று இடம்பெற்ற விசேட ஊடக சந்திப்பிலேயே சமயத்தலைவர்கள் கூட்டாக வலியுறுத்தியுள்ளனர்.",
        "இதுதொடர்பில் அவர்கள் மேலும் அறிக்கையில், சகல தமிழ்க் கட்சிகளும் குறிப்பாக தமிழ் நாடாளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர்களும் விரைவில் ஒன்று கூடி இன்றைய இலங்கை அரசியல் சூழலில் எடுக்கவேண்டிய தீர்மானம் என்ன என்பதை சீராகத் தீர்மானிப்பதற்கு முன் வரவேண்டுமெனவும் மதத்தலைவர்கள்  தெரிவித்துள்ளனர்.  இதுதொடர்பில் அவர்கள் மேலும் தெரிவிக்கையில்,",
        "வடக்கு-கிழக்கு, மலையகம், தெற்கு என்ற பேதமின்றி தமிழ் நாடாளுமன்ற அங்கத்தவர்கள், கட்சித் தலைவர்கள்  வேறுபாடுகளைக் கடந்து மக்களுக்காக ஒன்று கூடவேண்டிய தருணம் இது. எனவே அறிவு பூர்வமாக தீர்க்க தரிசனத்தோடு ஒன்றுகூடி ஆராயுங்கள். இது காலத்தின் கட்டாயம். இவ்வேளை நீங்கள் ஒன்றுகூடி ஆராய மறுப்பீர்கள் ஆனால் அது மாபெரும் வரலாற்றுத் தவறாகும் என்று தெரிவித்தனர்.",
        "இந்த ஊடக சந்திப்பில் நல்லை ஆதீன குரு முதல்வர் சோமசுந்தர பரமாச்சார்ய சுவாமிகள், யாழ் மறைமாவட்ட ஆயர் ஜஸ்டின் பேனாட் ஞானப்பிரகாசம், தெல்லிப்பழை துர்க்காதேவி தேவஸ்தானத்தின் தலைவர் கலாநிதி ஆறு. திருமுருகன், ரிஷி தொண்டுநாத சுவாமிகள் ஆகியோர் கலந்து கொண்டனர். (a)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "தமிழ்",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "தமிழ்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "நல்லை திருஞானசம்பந்தர் ஆதீனம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "தமிழ்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "தமிழ்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "LOC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "தமிழ்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "நல்லை ஆதீன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "சோமசுந்தர பரமாச்சார்ய சுவாமிகள்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "யாழ் மறைமாவட்ட ஆயர் ஜஸ்டின் பைனாட்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "கலாநிதி அரு",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "திருமுருகன்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}