{
  "newspaper_id": "ada-lk",
  "url": "https://www.ada.lk/breaking_news/රටින්-පැනීමට-තැත්-කළ-07ක්-කොටුවෙයි/11-395186",
  "time_ut": 1657172124,
  "original_lang": "si",
  "original_title": "රටින් පැනීමට තැත් කළ 07ක් කොටුවෙයි",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "07 people who tried to escape from the country are locked up",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "During a patrol carried out by the Sri Lanka Navy in the sea area off Thalaimannar yesterday (06th) night, 07 people suspected of illegally trying to migrate from Sri Lanka to a foreign country by sea were arrested along with 02 smugglers.",
        "A coastal patrol vessel belonging to the Sri Lanka Naval Vessels Tammanna of the North Central Naval Command inspected a suspicious dinghy sailing in the sea area off Thalaimannaram last night (06th). There, a man who was suspected of illegally trying to migrate to a foreign country by sea in the dinghy along with 07 people including 03 women and 03 small children and 02 smugglers involved in that smuggling were taken into the custody of the Navy along with the dinghy.",
        "The people taken into custody by the Navy were identified as residents of Kilinochchi and Pesale, aged between 09 and 43 months, and they were handed over to the Thalaimannar Police for further legal proceedings."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "07",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "the Sri Lanka Navy",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Thalaimannar",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "yesterday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "06th) night",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "07",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "02",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the Sri Lanka Naval Vessels Tammanna",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "the North Central Naval Command",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Thalaimannaram",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "last night",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "06th",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "07",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "03",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "03",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "02",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Navy",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Navy",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kilinochchi",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Pesale",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "between 09 and 43 months",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Thalaimannar Police",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "රටින් පැනීමට තැත් කළ 07ක් කොටුවෙයි",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකා නාවික හමුදාව තලෙයිමන්නාරමට ඔබ්බෙන් වූ මුහුදු  ප්‍රදේශයේ ඊයේ (06දා) රාත්‍රියේ සිදුකළ මුර සංචාරයකදී, නීති විරෝධී ලෙස මුහුදු මාර්ග ඔස්සේ මෙරටින් විදෙස් රටකට සංක්‍රමණය වීමට උත්සහ කළ බවට සැකකෙරෙන පුද්ගලයන් 07 ක් සමග ජාවාරම්කරුවන් 02 ක්  නාවික හමුදා භාරයට ගැනීමට කටයුතු කෙරිණි.",
        "උතුරු මැද නාවික විධානයේ ශ්‍රී ලංකා නාවික නෞකා තම්මැන්නා ආයතනයට අයත් වෙරළබඩ  මුර යාත්‍රාවක්, තලෙයිමන්නාරමට ඔබ්බෙන් වූ මුහුදු ප්‍රදේශයේ ඊයේ (06දා) රාත්‍රීයේ සිදුකළ මුර සංචාරයකදී එම මුහුදු ප්‍රදේශයේ යාත්‍රා කරමින් තිබූ සැකකටයුතු ඩිංගි යාත්‍රාවක් පරීක්ෂාවට ලක්කරන ලදී. එහිදී එම ඩිංගි යාත්‍රාව තුල සිටි නීති වි‍රෝධීව මුහුද මඟින් විදෙස් රටකට සංක්‍රමණය වීමට උත්සාහ කළ බවට සැකකෙරෙන පිරිමි පුද්ගලයෙකු කාන්තාවන් 03 දෙනෙකු සහ කුඩා ළමුන් 03 ක් ඇතුළු 07 දෙනෙකු සමඟ එම ජාවාරමට සම්බන්ධ ජාවාරම් කරුවන් 02 දෙනෙකු එම ඩිංගි යාත්‍රාව සමඟ නාවික හමුදා භාරයට ගන්නා ලදී.",
        "මෙලෙස නාවික හමුදාව භාරයට ගත් පිරිස වයස මාස 09 ත් 43 ත් අතර පසුවන  කිලිනොච්චිය හා පේසාලේ යන ප්‍රදේශයන්හී පදිංචිකරුවන් බවට හඳුනා ගන්නා ලද අතර, එම පිරිස ඉදිරි නීතිමය කටයුතු සඳහා තලෙයිමන්නාරම පොලිසිය වෙත භාරදීමට කටයුතු කරන ලදි."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "07",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකා නාවික හමුදාව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "තලෙයිමන්නාරම",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඊයේ",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "06) රාත්‍රිය",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "07",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "02",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකා නාවික නෞකා තම්න්නා",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "උතුරු මැද නාවික විධානය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "තලෙයිමන්නාරම්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "අවසන් රාත්රිය",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "06 වැනි",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "07",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "03",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "03",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "02",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "නාවික",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "නාවික",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "කිලිනොච්චි",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "පේසාලේ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මාස 09 සහ 43 අතර",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "තලෙයිමන්නාරම පොලිසිය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "நாட்டை விட்டு தப்பிச் செல்ல முயன்ற 07 பேர் கைது செய்யப்பட்டுள்ளனர்",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "தலைமன்னார் கடற்பரப்பில் நேற்று (06) இரவு இலங்கை கடற்படையினர் மேற்கொண்ட ரோந்து நடவடிக்கையின் போது சட்டவிரோதமான முறையில் இலங்கையிலிருந்து கடல் மார்க்கமாக வெளிநாட்டுக்கு செல்ல முயன்றதாக சந்தேகிக்கப்படும் 07 பேர் 02 ஆட்கடத்தல்காரர்களுடன் கைது செய்யப்பட்டுள்ளனர்.",
        "வடமத்திய கடற்படை கட்டளையின் இலங்கை கடற்படை கப்பல்கள் தம்மன்னாவிற்கு சொந்தமான கரையோர ரோந்துக் கப்பல் நேற்று (06) இரவு தலைமன்னாரம் கடற்பகுதியில் சந்தேகத்திற்கிடமான வகையில் பயணித்த டிங்கி படகு ஒன்றை ஆய்வு செய்தது. அங்கு டிங்கி படகில் சட்டவிரோதமாக கடல் வழியாக வெளிநாடு செல்ல முயன்றதாக சந்தேகிக்கப்படும் ஆண் ஒருவர், 03 பெண்கள், 03 சிறு குழந்தைகள் உட்பட 07 பேரும், அந்த கடத்தலில் ஈடுபட்ட 02 கடத்தல்காரர்களும் கடற்படையினரால் கைது செய்யப்பட்டனர். டிங்கி",
        "கடற்படையினரால் கைது செய்யப்பட்டவர்கள் கிளிநொச்சி மற்றும் பேசாலை பிரதேசங்களில் வசிப்பவர்கள் என 09 முதல் 43 மாதங்களுக்கு இடைப்பட்டவர்கள் என அடையாளம் காணப்பட்டு மேலதிக சட்ட நடவடிக்கைகளுக்காக தலைமன்னார் பொலிஸாரிடம் ஒப்படைக்கப்பட்டனர்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "07",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை கடற்படை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "தலைமன்னார்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "நேற்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "06) இரவு",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "07",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "02",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை கடற்படை கப்பல்கள் தம்மன்னா",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "வட மத்திய கடற்படை கட்டளை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "தலைமன்னாரம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "நேற்று இரவு",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "06வது",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "07",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "03",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "03",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "02",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "கடற்படை",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "கடற்படை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "கிளிநொச்சி",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "பேசலே",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "09 மற்றும் 43 மாதங்களுக்கு இடையில்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "தலைமன்னார் காவல்துறை",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}