{
  "newspaper_id": "daily-mirror-lk",
  "url": "https://www.dailymirror.lk/breaking_news/CID-record-statements-from-Dulanjalee-Premadasa-and-Hirunika/108-243428",
  "time_ut": 1661002854,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "CID record statements from Dulanjalee Premadasa and Hirunika",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "CID record statements from Dulanjalee Premadasa and Hirunika",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "Dulanjalee Premadasa, the sister of Opposition Leader Sajith Premadasa and SJB Member Hirunika Premachandra today gave statements to the Criminal Investigations Department (CID) over ongoing investigations.",
        "The CID summoned Dulanjalee Premadasa to record a statement over the investigation into the setting of fire to President Ranil Wickremesinghe's private residence in Colombo.",
        "Meanwhile, the CID also recorded over six hours long a statement from Hirunika Premachandra this morning as well."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "CID",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "Premadasa",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "Hirunika",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Dulanjalee Premadasa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sajith Premadasa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "SJB",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Hirunika Premachandra",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Criminal Investigations Department",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "CID",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "CID",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Premadasa",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Colombo",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "CID",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Hirunika Premachandra",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "දුලාංජලී ප්‍රේමදාසගෙන් සහ හිරුණිකාගෙන් CID ප්‍රකාශ සටහන් කර ගනී",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "විපක්ෂ නායක සජිත් ප්‍රේමදාසගේ සොහොයුරිය වන දුලාංජලී ප්‍රේමදාස සහ SJB මන්ත්‍රී හිරුණිකා ප්‍රේමචන්ද්‍ර යන මහත්ම මහත්මීන් අද අපරාධ පරීක්ෂණ දෙපාර්තමේන්තුවට (CID) ප්‍රකාශ ලබා දුන්නේ මේ සම්බන්ධයෙන් සිදුකෙරෙන පරීක්ෂණ සම්බන්ධයෙන්.",
        "ජනාධිපති රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතාගේ කොළඹ පිහිටි පෞද්ගලික නිවසට ගිනි තැබීමේ සිද්ධියට අදාළ විමර්ශනවලට අදාළව ප්‍රකාශයක් සටහන් කර ගැනීම සඳහා අපරාධ පරීක්ෂණ දෙපාර්තමේන්තුව දුලාංජලී ප්‍රේමදාස මහත්මිය කැඳවා තිබේ.",
        "මේ අතර, අද පෙරවරුවේ ද හිරුණිකා ප්‍රේමචන්ද්‍ර මහත්මියගෙන් අපරාධ පරීක්ෂණ දෙපාර්තමේන්තුව පැය 6කට අධික කාලයක් ප්‍රකාශයක් සටහන් කර ගත්තා."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "CID",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "ප්‍රේමදාස ය",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "Hirunika",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "දුලංජලී ප්‍රේමදාස",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "සජිත් ප්‍රේමදාස",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "එස්.ජේ.බී",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "හිරුණිකා ප්‍රේමචන්ද්‍ර",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "අපරාධ පරීක්ෂණ දෙපාර්තමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "CID",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "CID",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ප්‍රේමදාස ය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "කොළඹ",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "CID",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "හිරුණිකා ප්‍රේමචන්ද්‍ර",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "துலாஞ்சலி பிரேமதாச மற்றும் ஹிருணிகாவிடம் CID வாக்குமூலம் பதிவு",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "எதிர்க்கட்சித் தலைவர் சஜித் பிரேமதாசவின் சகோதரியான துலாஞ்சலி பிரேமதாச மற்றும் எஸ்.ஜே.பி உறுப்பினர் ஹிருணிகா பிரேமசந்திர ஆகியோர் இன்று குற்றப் புலனாய்வுத் திணைக்களத்தில் (CID) இடம்பெற்று வரும் விசாரணைகள் தொடர்பில் வாக்குமூலம் வழங்கியுள்ளனர்.",
        "கொழும்பில் உள்ள ஜனாதிபதி ரணில் விக்ரமசிங்கவின் தனிப்பட்ட இல்லத்திற்கு தீ வைக்கப்பட்டது தொடர்பான விசாரணைகள் தொடர்பில் வாக்குமூலம் பதிவு செய்ய துலாஞ்சலி பிரேமதாசவிற்கு குற்றப் புலனாய்வுப் பிரிவினர் அழைப்பு விடுத்துள்ளனர்.",
        "இதேவேளை, குற்றப் புலனாய்வுப் பிரிவினர் இன்று காலையும் ஹிருணிகா பிரேமச்சந்திரவிடம் ஆறு மணித்தியாலங்களுக்கு மேல் வாக்குமூலம் பதிவு செய்துள்ளனர்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "சி.ஐ.டி",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "பிரேமதாச",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "Hirunika",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "துலாஞ்சலி பிரேமதாச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "சஜித் பிரேமதாச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "எஸ்.ஜே.பி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஹிருணிகா பிரேமச்சந்திர",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "குற்றப் புலனாய்வுத் திணைக்களம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "சி.ஐ.டி",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "சி.ஐ.டி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "பிரேமதாச",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "கொழும்பு",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "சி.ஐ.டி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஹிருணிகா பிரேமச்சந்திர",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}