{
  "newspaper_id": "lankadeepa-lk",
  "url": "https://www.lankadeepa.lk/news/ආර්-එම්-වී--විද්‍යුත්-කාඩ්පත්-හඳුන්වා-දෙයි/101-619350",
  "time_ut": 1662387343,
  "original_lang": "si",
  "original_title": "ආර්.එම්.වී. විද්‍යුත් කාඩ්පත් හඳුන්වා දෙයි",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "R.M.V. Introduces e-cards",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "Road Transport Commissioner (Development) Mrs. Trofi de Silva said that the ability to pay by e-card for services obtained from the Department of Motor Transport (RMV) started today (5).",
        "She said that the people will be able to use e-cards in all the services provided by the Motor Commissioner's Department and that the Motor Transport Department has also worked to fulfill that requirement as there are card payment facilities in many transactions."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "R.M.V. Introduces",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Trofi de Silva",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Department of Motor Transport",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "RMV",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "5",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the Motor Commissioner's Department",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Motor Transport Department",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "ආර්.එම්.වී. විද්‍යුත් කාඩ්පත් හඳුන්වා දෙයි",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "මෝටර් රථ ප්‍රවාහන කොමසාරිස් දෙපාර්තමේන්තුවෙන් (ආර්.එම්.වී.)ලබා ගන්නා සේවා සඳහා විද්‍යුත් කාඩ්පත් මගින් ගෙවීමේ හැකියාව අද (5) සිට ආරම්භ කළ බව රථ ප්‍රවාහන කොමසාරිස් (සංවර්ධන) කුසලානි ද සිල්වා මහත්මිය පැවසුවාය.",
        "මෝටර් රථ කොමසාරිස් දෙපාර්තමේන්තුවෙන් ලබාදෙන සියලුම සේවාවලදී ජනතාවට ඉදිරියේදී  විද්‍යුත් කාඩ්පත් යොදාගත හැකි බවත්  බොහෝ ගනුදෙනුවලදී කාඩ්පත් මගින් ගෙවීමේ පහසුකම් තිබීම නිසා මෝටර් රථ ප්‍රවාහන දෙපාර්තමේන්තුව ද එම අවශ්‍යතාවය සම්පූර්ණ කිරීමට කටයුතු කළ බවත් ඇය කීවාය."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ආර්.එම්.වී. හඳුන්වා දෙයි",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ට්‍රොෆි ද සිල්වා",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "මෝටර් රථ ප්රවාහන දෙපාර්තමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ආර්.එම්.වී",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "5",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "මෝටර් කොමසාරිස් දෙපාර්තමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "මෝටර් රථ ප්රවාහන දෙපාර්තමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "ஆர்.எம்.வி. மின் அட்டைகளை அறிமுகப்படுத்துகிறது",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "மோட்டார் போக்குவரத்து திணைக்களத்தில் (RMV) பெறப்படும் சேவைகளுக்கு மின் அட்டை மூலம் பணம் செலுத்தும் வசதி இன்று (5) ஆரம்பமாகியுள்ளதாக வீதி போக்குவரத்து ஆணையாளர் (அபிவிருத்தி) திருமதி ட்ரோபி டி சில்வா தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "மோட்டார் கமிஷனர் துறையின் அனைத்து சேவைகளிலும் மக்கள் மின் அட்டைகளைப் பயன்படுத்த முடியும் என்றும், பல பரிவர்த்தனைகளில் கார்டு செலுத்தும் வசதி இருப்பதால், அந்தத் தேவையை பூர்த்தி செய்ய மோட்டார் போக்குவரத்துத் துறையும் பாடுபட்டுள்ளது என்றும் அவர் கூறினார்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ஆர்.எம்.வி. அறிமுகப்படுத்துகிறது",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "டிராபி டி சில்வா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "மோட்டார் போக்குவரத்து துறை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆர்.எம்.வி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "5",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "மோட்டார் கமிஷனர் துறை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "மோட்டார் போக்குவரத்து துறை",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}