{
  "newspaper_id": "economy-next-com",
  "url": "https://economynext.com/opposition-must-support-pm-govt-give-them-six-months-to-resolve-crisis-minister-96940/",
  "time_ut": 1656998700,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Opposition must support PM, govt, give them six months to resolve crisis: Minister",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Opposition must support PM, govt, give them six months to resolve crisis: Minister",
      "author": "",
      "body_lines": [
        "ECONOMYNEXT – Parties represented in Sri Lanka’s parliament must extend support to Prime Minister Ranil Wickremesinghe and the government to bring the country out of the present economic crisis, Agriculture Minister Mahinda Amaraweera said, asking opposition parties to give Wickremesinghe six months.",
        "Speaking at the weekly cabinet press briefing on Tuesday July 05, Amaraweera claimed that the incumbent government is an all-party government as is the current demand. He was responding to a question about a request by the Buddhist clergy and others for an interim government comprising all parties represented in parliament. On Monday, Opposition Leader Sajith Premadasa and former President Maithripala Sirisena held discussions on the same.",
        "“This is an all party government. Invitations are still open to all parties to join. Prime Minister Wickremesinghe already extended an invitation to other parties when he was appointed,” said Amaraweera.",
        "“Before we engage in politics, we first need to have a country. Instead of thinking about who will be in power next, all people’s representatives must take up the responsibility of [resolving the crisis].”",
        "The minister said opposition parties must support the government without fighting for power at this juncture.",
        "“Give this prime minister and the government six months,” he said, claiming that he had faith that Wickremesinghe and the government could steer Sri Lanka out of its worst economic crisis since Independence.",
        "“Before [the current dispensation], there were 13-hour power cuts. Gas will be distributed soon. Fertilizer is being distributed already. Fuel will from next week.",
        "“There’s a pressing need for everyone to unite without sabotaging this, without trying to use this to their advantage,” he said.",
        "Unprecedented forex shortages in Sri Lanka have led to crippling shortages of essentials including fuel, and public anger is at an all time high with massive protests planned for July 09 demanding the resignation of President Gotabaya Rajapaksa and the government. (Colombo/Jul05/2022)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "six months",
          "label": "DATE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka’s",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Agriculture",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Mahinda Amaraweera",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "six months",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "weekly",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Tuesday July 05",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Amaraweera",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Buddhist",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Monday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sajith Premadasa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Maithripala Sirisena",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Amaraweera",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "first",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "six months",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Independence",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "13-hour",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "next week",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "July 09",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Gotabaya Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Colombo/Jul05/2022",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "විපක්ෂය අගමැතිට සහ රජයට සහාය දිය යුතුය, අර්බුදය විසඳීමට ඔවුන්ට මාස හයක් දෙන්න: ඇමති",
      "author": "",
      "body_lines": [
        "ආර්ථිකය - වත්මන් ආර්ථික අර්බුදයෙන් රට ගොඩ ගැනීමට ශ්‍රී ලංකා පාර්ලිමේන්තුව නියෝජනය කරන පක්ෂ අගමැති රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතාට සහ රජයට සහාය දිය යුතු බව කෘෂිකර්ම අමාත්‍ය මහින්ද අමරවීර මහතා ප්‍රකාශ කළේ වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතාට මාස 6ක කාලයක් ලබා දෙන ලෙස විපක්ෂ පක්ෂවලින් ඉල්ලා සිටිමිනි.",
        "ජුලි 05 අඟහරුවාදා සතිපතා කැබිනට් මාධ්‍ය හමුවට එක්වෙමින් අමරවීර කියා සිටියේ වත්මන් ආණ්ඩුව වත්මන් ඉල්ලීම පරිදි සර්ව පාක්ෂික ආණ්ඩුවක් බවයි. පාර්ලිමේන්තුව නියෝජනය කරන සියලුම පක්‍ෂවලින් සමන්විත අන්තර්වාර පාලනයක් සඳහා බෞද්ධ භික්‍ෂූන් වහන්සේ ඇතුළු පිරිස කළ ඉල්ලීමක් සම්බන්ධයෙන් ඇසූ ප්‍රශ්නයකට පිළිතුරු දෙමින් ඇමැතිවරයා එසේ කීය. සඳුදා විපක්ෂ නායක සජිත් ප්‍රේමදාස මහතා සහ හිටපු ජනාධිපති මෛත්‍රීපාල සිරිසේන මහතා මේ පිළිබඳව සාකච්ඡා කළහ.",
        "“මේක සර්ව පාක්ෂික ආණ්ඩුවක්. සම්බන්ධ වීමට සියලුම පාර්ශවයන්ට තවමත් ආරාධනා විවෘතයි. අගමැති වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතා පත් කරන විටත් වෙනත් පක්ෂවලට ආරාධනා කළා.” අමරවීර පැවසීය.",
        "“දේශපාලනය කරන්න කලින් අපිට රටක් තියෙන්න ඕන. මීළඟට බලයේ සිටින්නේ කවුරුන්ද යන්න ගැන සිතනවා වෙනුවට, සියලු මහජන නියෝජිතයින් [අර්බුද විසඳීමේ] වගකීම භාර ගත යුතුය.",
        "අමාත්‍යවරයා කියා සිටියේ මේ මොහොතේ බලය සඳහා සටන් නොකර විපක්ෂයේ පක්ෂ රජයට සහය දිය යුතු බවයි.",
        "නිදහසින් පසු ශ්‍රී ලංකාව මුහුණ දුන් දරුණුතම ආර්ථික අර්බුදයෙන් වික්‍රමසිංහට සහ ආන්ඩුවට ශ්‍රී ලංකාව ගෙන යා හැකි බවට තමාට විශ්වාසයක් ඇති බව කියමින්, “මේ අගමැතිට සහ ආන්ඩුවට මාස හයක් දෙන්න,” ඔහු පැවසීය.",
        "“[වත්මන් බෙදා හැරීමට] පෙර, පැය 13 ක විදුලිය විසන්ධි විය. ගෑස් ඉක්මනින් බෙදා හරිනු ලැබේ. දැනටමත් පොහොර බෙදාහරිනවා. ලබන සතියේ සිට ඉන්ධන.",
        "\"මෙය කඩාකප්පල් නොකර, මෙය ඔවුන්ගේ වාසියට භාවිතා කිරීමට උත්සාහ නොකර සියලු දෙනා එකමුතු විය යුතුය,\" ඔහු පැවසීය.",
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ පෙර නොවූ විරූ විදේශ විනිමය හිඟයක් ඉන්ධන ඇතුළු අත්‍යවශ්‍ය ද්‍රව්‍ය හිඟයකට තුඩු දී ඇති අතර, ජනාධිපති ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ මහතාට සහ රජයට ඉල්ලා අස්වන ලෙස බල කරමින් ජූලි 09 වැනිදා පැවැත්වීමට නියමිත දැවැන්ත විරෝධතා සමඟ මහජන කෝපය ඉහළ මට්ටමක පවතී. (කොළඹ/ජූලි 05/2022)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "මාස හයක්",
          "label": "DATE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "කෘෂිකර්ම",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "මහින්ද අමරවීර",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "මාස හයක්",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "සතිපතා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජූලි 05 අඟහරුවාදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "අමරවීර",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "බෞද්ධ",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "සඳුදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "සජිත් ප්‍රේමදාස",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "මෛත්‍රීපාල සිරිසේන",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "අමරවීර",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "පළමුවන",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "මාස හයක්",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "නිදහස",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "13-පැය",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඊළඟ සතිය",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජූලි 09",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "කොළඹ/ජූලි 05/2022",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "எதிர்க்கட்சிகள் பிரதமர், அரசுக்கு ஆதரவளிக்க வேண்டும், நெருக்கடியை தீர்க்க 6 மாதங்கள் அவகாசம் கொடுக்க வேண்டும்: அமைச்சர்",
      "author": "",
      "body_lines": [
        "பொருளாதாரம் - தற்போதைய பொருளாதார நெருக்கடியில் இருந்து நாட்டை மீட்டெடுக்க இலங்கையின் பாராளுமன்றத்தில் பிரதிநிதித்துவப்படுத்தும் கட்சிகள் பிரதமர் ரணில் விக்ரமசிங்கவிற்கும் அரசாங்கத்திற்கும் ஆதரவளிக்க வேண்டும் என விவசாய அமைச்சர் மஹிந்த அமரவீர தெரிவித்துள்ளார்.",
        "ஜூலை 05 செவ்வாய்க்கிழமை வாராந்த அமைச்சரவை செய்தியாளர் சந்திப்பில் பேசிய அமரவீர, தற்போதைய அரசாங்கம் தற்போதைய கோரிக்கையைப் போலவே அனைத்துக் கட்சி அரசாங்கமாகும் என்று கூறினார். பாராளுமன்றத்தை பிரதிநிதித்துவப்படுத்தும் அனைத்து கட்சிகளையும் உள்ளடக்கிய இடைக்கால அரசாங்கம் அமைக்கப்பட வேண்டும் என பௌத்த மதகுருமார்கள் மற்றும் ஏனையோர் விடுத்த கோரிக்கை தொடர்பான கேள்விக்கு பதிலளிக்கும் போதே அவர் மேற்கண்டவாறு கூறினார். திங்கட்கிழமை எதிர்க்கட்சித் தலைவர் சஜித் பிரேமதாச மற்றும் முன்னாள் ஜனாதிபதி மைத்திரிபால சிறிசேன ஆகியோர் இது தொடர்பில் கலந்துரையாடியுள்ளனர்.",
        "“இது அனைத்துக் கட்சி ஆட்சி. இன்னும் அனைத்து தரப்பினருக்கும் சேர அழைப்பு விடுக்கப்பட்டுள்ளது. பிரதமர் விக்ரமசிங்க ஏற்கனவே நியமிக்கப்பட்ட போது ஏனைய கட்சிகளுக்கு அழைப்பு விடுத்துள்ளார்” என அமரவீர தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "“நாம் அரசியலில் ஈடுபடுவதற்கு முன், முதலில் நமக்கு ஒரு நாடு வேண்டும். அடுத்து யார் ஆட்சிக்கு வருவார்கள் என்று சிந்திக்காமல், அனைத்து மக்கள் பிரதிநிதிகளும் [நெருக்கடியைத் தீர்க்கும்] பொறுப்பை ஏற்க வேண்டும்.",
        "இத்தருணத்தில் எதிர்க்கட்சிகள் அதிகாரத்திற்காக போராடாமல் அரசுக்கு ஆதரவளிக்க வேண்டும் என்று அமைச்சர் கூறினார்.",
        "\"இந்தப் பிரதமருக்கும் அரசாங்கத்திற்கும் ஆறு மாதங்கள் அவகாசம் கொடுங்கள்,\" என்று அவர் கூறினார், சுதந்திரத்திற்குப் பிறகு இலங்கையை அதன் மோசமான பொருளாதார நெருக்கடியிலிருந்து விக்கிரமசிங்கவும் அரசாங்கமும் வெளியேற்ற முடியும் என்று தான் நம்புவதாகக் கூறினார்.",
        "“[தற்போதைய விநியோகத்திற்கு] முன், 13 மணி நேர மின்வெட்டு இருந்தது. விரைவில் எரிவாயு விநியோகம் செய்யப்படும். ஏற்கனவே உரம் விநியோகம் செய்யப்பட்டு வருகிறது. அடுத்த வாரம் முதல் எரிபொருள் நிரப்பப்படும்.",
        "இதை நாசப்படுத்தாமல், இதை தங்களுக்கு சாதகமாக பயன்படுத்த முயற்சிக்காமல் அனைவரும் ஒன்றிணைய வேண்டிய அவசர தேவை உள்ளது,” என்றார்.",
        "இலங்கையில் முன்னெப்போதும் இல்லாத அந்நிய செலாவணி தட்டுப்பாடு எரிபொருள் உள்ளிட்ட அத்தியாவசியப் பொருட்களின் பற்றாக்குறைக்கு வழிவகுத்தது மற்றும் ஜனாதிபதி கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ஷ மற்றும் அரசாங்கத்தை பதவி விலகக் கோரி ஜூலை 09 ஆம் தேதி பாரிய போராட்டங்களை நடத்த திட்டமிடப்பட்டுள்ளதால் பொதுமக்களின் கோபம் உச்சத்தில் உள்ளது. (கொழும்பு/ஜூலை05/2022)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ஆறு மாதங்கள்",
          "label": "DATE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கையின்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "வேளாண்மை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "மஹிந்த அமரவீர",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆறு மாதங்கள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "வாரந்தோறும்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜூலை 05 செவ்வாய்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "அமரவீர",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "பௌத்த",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "திங்கட்கிழமை",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சஜித் பிரேமதாச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "மைத்திரிபால சிறிசேன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "அமரவீர",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "முதலில்",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஆறு மாதங்கள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சுதந்திரம்",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "13-மணிநேரம்",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "அடுத்த வாரம்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜூலை 09",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "கொழும்பு/ஜூலை05/2022",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}