{
  "newspaper_id": "virakesari-lk",
  "url": "http://www.virakesari.lk/article/132058",
  "time_ut": 1658508187,
  "original_lang": "ta",
  "original_title": "ரணில் விக்ரமசிங்க நிறைவேற்றதிகார ஜனாதிபதியாவதைத் தடுப்பதற்கு நாம் மேற்கொண்ட தீர்மானம் சரியானது என்பதில் எவருக்கேனும் சந்தேகம் உள்ளதா? - சுமந்திரன் கேள்வி",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Does anyone doubt that our decision to prevent Ranil Wickremesinghe from becoming an Acting President was correct? - Sumandran's question",
      "author": "Vishnu",
      "body_lines": [
        "Does anyone now have any doubt that the decision taken by the Tamil Tesiya Federation to prevent the election of Ranil Wickramasinghe as the Executive President of Podujana Peramuna and to take the necessary efforts for it is correct? The media spokesperson of the Federation of Tamil Tessia and Member of Parliament for Yallam District has asked President's Attorney MA Sumanthran.",
        "Called 'Kota Ko Kama' in front of the Presidential Secretariat in Colombo's Kalimughat, the self-insurgency that had been going on for more than 100 days in a very vigorous manner by the public has subsided to some extent with the resignation of former President Gotabaya Rajapaksa.",
        "However, following the inauguration of the new President, Ranil Wickramasinghe, on Friday 22nd midnight, the Presidential Secretariat was surrounded by three forces and the 'Kota Ko Kama' protesters were dispersed from there. Meanwhile, the videos of the soldiers and Special Action Force severely attacking the protesters, the lawyers who had visited there to investigate the situation and appear on behalf of the arrested protesters, and the journalists who were engaged in their work, were widely shared on social media.",
        "Following this, MA Sumanthran, Member of Parliament of Jaffna District of Tamil Tesiya Federation has made a post on his official Twitter page, in which he has raised the following question.",
        "'Does anyone now have any doubt that the decision taken by the Tamil Tesiya Federation to prevent the election of Ranil Wickramasinghe as the executive president of the PDP and to take the necessary steps is correct?' He has questioned that.",
        "Similarly, Sumanthran, who made a post quoting the photo of lawyer Samara Jayasinghe, who was badly beaten by the soldiers in Kalimukhatital area on Friday midnight, pointed out that the lawyer was in her professional dress and said that 'this is how Ranil Wickramasinghe and the Podujana Peramuna government is giving lawyers the opportunity to meet the arrested people'."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Ranil Wickremesinghe",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "Sumandran",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "the Tamil Tesiya Federation",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickramasinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Executive",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Podujana Peramuna",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Federation of Tamil Tessia",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Yallam District",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "MA Sumanthran",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Kota Ko Kama'",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Presidential Secretariat",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Colombo",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "more than 100 days",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Gotabaya Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickramasinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Friday 22nd midnight",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Presidential Secretariat",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "three",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kota Ko Kama'",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "MA Sumanthran",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament of Jaffna District of Tamil Tesiya Federation",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Twitter",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the Tamil Tesiya Federation",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickramasinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "PDP",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sumanthran",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Samara Jayasinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kalimukhatital",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Friday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "midnight",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickramasinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Podujana Peramuna",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතා වැඩබලන ජනාධිපතිවරයකු වීම වැලැක්වීමට අප ගත් තීරණය නිවැරදි බවට කිසිවකුට සැකයක් තිබේද? - සුමන්ද්‍රන්ගේ ප්‍රශ්නය",
      "author": "විෂ්ණු",
      "body_lines": [
        "පොදුජන පෙරමුණේ විධායක සභාපති ලෙස රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතා තේරී පත්වීම වැළැක්වීමට සහ ඒ සඳහා අවශ්‍ය කටයුතු කිරීමට දෙමළ තේසිය සම්මේලනය ගත් තීරණය නිවැරදි බවට දැන් කිසිවෙකුට සැකයක් තිබේද? තමිල් ටෙසියා සම්මේලනයේ මාධ්‍ය ප්‍රකාශක සහ යල්ලම් දිස්ත්‍රික් පාර්ලිමේන්තු මන්ත්‍රීවරයා ජනාධිපති නීතීඥ එම් ඒ සුමන්ත්‍රන්ගෙන් ඉල්ලා ඇත.",
        "කොළඹ කාලිමුගට්හි ජනාධිපති ලේකම් කාර්යාලය ඉදිරිපිට ‘කොට කෝ කමා’ නමින් දින 100කට අධික කාලයක් මහජනතාව විසින් ඉතා ප්‍රබල ලෙස ක්‍රියාත්මක කළ ස්වයං කැරැල්ල හිටපු ජනාධිපති ගෝඨාභයගේ ඉල්ලා අස්වීමත් සමඟ තරමක් දුරට සමනය වී තිබේ. රාජපක්ෂ.",
        "කෙසේ වෙතත්, නව ජනාධිපති රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතා දිවුරුම් දීමත් සමඟ 22 සිකුරාදා මධ්‍යම රාත්‍රියේ ජනාධිපති ලේකම් කාර්යාලය ත්‍රිවිධ හමුදාව වටලා 'කොට කෝ කමා' විරෝධතාකරුවෝ එතැනින් විසිර ගියහ. මේ අතර, හමුදා සෙබළුන් සහ විශේෂ ක්‍රියාකාරී බලකාය විරෝධතාකරුවන්ට දරුණු ලෙස පහර දෙන වීඩියෝ දර්ශන, තත්ත්වය සොයා බැලීමට එහි පැමිණි නීතීඥවරුන් සහ අත්අඩංගුවට ගත් විරෝධතාකරුවන් වෙනුවෙන් පෙනී සිටිමින් සහ ඔවුන්ගේ කාර්යයේ නිරත වූ මාධ්‍යවේදීන්ට දැඩි ලෙස පහර දෙන වීඩියෝ දර්ශන සමාජ ජාල තුළ විශාල වශයෙන් හුවමාරු විය. මාධ්ය.",
        "ඉන් අනතුරුව දෙමළ තේසිය සම්මේලනයේ යාපනය දිස්ත්‍රික් පාර්ලිමේන්තු මන්ත්‍රී එම්ඒ සුමන්ත‍්‍රන් සිය නිල ට්විටර් පිටුවේ සටහනක් තබා ඇති අතර එහිදී ඔහු පහත ප්‍රශ්නය මතු කර තිබේ.",
        "'රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතා PDP විධායක සභාපති ලෙස පත් කිරීම වැළැක්වීමට සහ අවශ්‍ය පියවර ගැනීමට දෙමළ තේසිය සම්මේලනය ගෙන ඇති තීරණය නිවැරදි බවට දැන් කිසිවෙකුට සැකයක් තිබේද?' යනුවෙන් ඔහු ප්‍රශ්න කර ඇත.",
        "එසේම සිකුරාදා මධ්‍යම රාත්‍රියේ කලිමුඛතිටල් ප්‍රදේශයේදී හමුදා සෙබළුන් විසින් දරුණු ලෙස පහර කෑමට ලක්වූ නීතිඥ සමර ජයසිංහගේ ඡායාරූපය උපුටා දක්වමින් සටහනක් තැබූ සුමන්ත‍්‍රන්, නීතිඥවරිය වෘත්තීය ඇඳුමින් සැරසී සිටි බව පෙන්වා දෙමින් ‘මේ රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ සහ අත්අඩංගුවට ගත් පුද්ගලයන් හමුවීමට පොදුජන පෙරමුණ රජය නීතිඥවරුන්ට අවස්ථාව ලබා දෙනවා."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "සුමන්ද්‍රන්",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "දෙමළ තේසිය සම්මේලනය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "විධායක",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "පොදුජන පෙරමුණ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ටැමිල් ටෙසියා සම්මේලනය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "යාලම් දිස්ත්‍රික්කය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "එම් ඒ සුමන්ත‍්‍රන්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "කොට කෝ කාමා'",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජනාධිපති ලේකම් කාර්යාලය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "කොළඹ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "දින 100 කට වඩා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "22 සිකුරාදා මධ්‍යම රාත්‍රිය",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජනාධිපති ලේකම් කාර්යාලය",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "තුන්",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "කොට කෝ කාමා'",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "එම් ඒ සුමන්ත‍්‍රන්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "දෙමළ තේසිය සම්මේලනයේ යාපනය දිස්ත්‍රික්කයේ පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ට්විටර්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "දෙමළ තේසිය සම්මේලනය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "PDP",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "සුමන්ත‍්‍රන්",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "සමර ජයසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "කාලිමුඛතිටල්",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "සිකුරාදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මධ්යම රාත්රිය",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "පොදුජන පෙරමුණ",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "ரணில் விக்ரமசிங்க நிறைவேற்றதிகார ஜனாதிபதியாவதைத் தடுப்பதற்கு நாம் மேற்கொண்ட தீர்மானம் சரியானது என்பதில் எவருக்கேனும் சந்தேகம் உள்ளதா? - சுமந்திரன் கேள்வி",
      "author": "Vishnu",
      "body_lines": [
        "பொதுஜன பெரமுனவின் நிறைவேற்றதிகார ஜனாதிபதியாக ரணில் விக்ரமசிங்க தெரிவுசெய்யப்படுவதைத் தடுப்பதற்கும், அதற்கு அவசியமான முயற்சிகளை மேற்கொள்வதற்கும் தமிழ்த்தேசியக்கூட்டமைப்பு மேற்கொண்ட தீர்மானம் சரியானது என்பதில் இப்போது எவருக்கேனும் சந்தேகம் இருக்கின்றதா? என்று தமிழ்த்தேசியக்கூட்டமைப்பின் ஊடகப்பேச்சாளரும் யாழ்மாவட்டப் பாராளுமன்ற உறுப்பினருமான ஜனாதிபதி சட்டத்தரணி எம்.ஏ.சுமந்திரன் கேள்வி எழுப்பியுள்ளார்.",
        "கொழும்பு காலிமுகத்திடலில் ஜனாதிபதி செயலகத்திற்கு முன்பாக 'கோட்டா கோ கம' என்று பெயரிட்டு, பொதுமக்கள் ஒன்றிணைந்து சுமார் 100 நாட்களுக்கும் மேலாக மிகவும் தீவிரமான முறையில் முன்னெடுத்துவந்த தன்னெழுச்சிப்போராட்டம் முன்னாள் ஜனாதிபதி கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ஷவின் பதவி விலகலுடன் ஓரளவிற்குத் தணிந்தது.",
        "இருப்பினும் புதிய ஜனாதிபதி ரணில் விக்ரமசிங்கவின் பதவியேற்பைத் தொடர்ந்து 22 ஆம் திகதி வெள்ளிக்கிழமை நள்ளிரவு முப்படையினரால் ஜனாதிபதி செயலகம் சுற்றிவளைக்கப்பட்டதுடன் 'கோட்டா கோ கம' போராட்டக்காரர்கள் அங்கிருந்து கலைக்கப்பட்டனர். இதன்போது அங்கிருந்த போராட்டக்காரர்கள், நிலைமையை ஆராய்வதற்காகவும் கைதுசெய்யப்பட்ட போராட்டக்காரர்கள் சார்பில் ஆஜராவதற்காகவும் அங்கு வருகைதந்திருந்த சட்டத்தரணிகள், தமது பணியில் ஈடுபட்டிருந்த ஊடகவியலாளர்கள்மீது இராணுவத்தினர் மற்றும் விசேட அதிரடிப்படையினர் கடுமையாகத் தாக்குதல் நடத்தும் காணொளிகள் சமூகவலைத்தளங்களில் பரவலாகப் பகிரப்பட்டன.",
        "இதனையடுத்து தனது உத்தியோகபூர்வ டுவிட்டர் பக்கத்தில் பதிவொன்றைச் செய்திருக்கும்  தமிழ்த்தேசியக்கூட்டமைப்பின் யாழ்மாவட்டப் பாராளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர் எம்.ஏ.சுமந்திரன், அதில் பின்வருமாறு கேள்வி எழுப்பியிருக்கின்றார்.",
        "'பொதுஜன பெரமுனவின் நிறைவேற்றதிகார ஜனாதிபதியாக ரணில் விக்ரமசிங்க தெரிவுசெய்யப்படுவதைத் தடுப்பதற்கும், அதற்கு அவசியமான முயற்சிகளை மேற்கொள்வதற்கும் தமிழ்த்தேசியக்கூட்டமைப்பு மேற்கொண்ட தீர்மானம் சரியானது என்பதில் இப்போது எவருக்கேனும் சந்தேகம் இருக்கின்றதா?' என்று கேள்வி எழுப்பியிருக்கின்றார்.",
        "அதேபோன்று வெள்ளிக்கிழமை நள்ளிரவு காலிமுகத்திடல் பகுதியில் படையினரால் மிகமோசமாகத் தாக்கப்பட்ட சட்டத்தரணி சாமர ஜயசிங்கவின் புகைப்படத்தை மேற்கோள்காட்டி பதிவொன்றைச் செய்திருக்கும் சுமந்திரன், அந்த சட்டத்தரணி அவரது தொழில்முறை ஆடையில் இருப்பதாகச் சுட்டிக்காட்டியிருப்பதுடன் 'ரணில் விக்ரமசிங்க மற்றும் பொதுஜன பெரமுன அரசாங்கமானது கைதுசெய்யப்பட்டவர்களை சட்டத்தரணிகள் சந்திப்பதற்கான வாய்ப்பை இவ்வாறுதான் வழங்குகின்றது' என்றும் தெரிவித்திருக்கின்றார்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "சுமந்திரன்",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "தமிழ் தெசிய கூட்டமைப்பு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "நிர்வாகி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "பொதுஜன பெரமுன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "தமிழ் டெசியா கூட்டமைப்பு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "யல்லம் மாவட்டம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "எம்.ஏ.சுமந்திரன்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "கோட்டா கோ காமா'",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜனாதிபதி செயலகம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "கொழும்பு",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "100 நாட்களுக்கு மேல்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "வெள்ளிக்கிழமை 22 நள்ளிரவு",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜனாதிபதி செயலகம்",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "மூன்று",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "கோட்டா கோ காமா'",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "எம்.ஏ.சுமந்திரன்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "தமிழ் தெசிய கூட்டமைப்பின் யாழ் மாவட்ட பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ட்விட்டர்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "தமிழ் தெசிய கூட்டமைப்பு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "பிடிபி",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "சுமந்திரன்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சாமர ஜெயசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "காளிமுகத்திடல்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "வெள்ளி",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "நள்ளிரவு",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "பொதுஜன பெரமுன",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}