{
  "newspaper_id": "economy-next-com",
  "url": "https://economynext.com/political-stability-will-help-sri-lanka-turn-a-corner-president-tells-wsj-98085/",
  "time_ut": 1659331140,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Political stability will help Sri Lanka turn a corner, president tells WSJ",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Political stability will help Sri Lanka turn a corner, president tells WSJ",
      "author": "",
      "body_lines": [
        "ECONOMYNEXT – Sri Lanka has experienced the worst of its economic crisis and political stability will help the country turn a corner, starting with finalising negotiations for an International Monetary Fund (IMF) bailout, President Ranil Wickremesinghe has told The Wall Street Journal.",
        "“I think we’ve already hit the bottom. I can see the light at the end of the tunnel; it’s how fast we can get to it,” the New York City-based business daily quoted Wickremesinghe as saying on Sunday July 31.",
        "However, it will be some months before most Sri Lankans begin to see their economic situation noticeably improve, he had said.",
        "President Wickremesinghe told the WSJ that he expects an IMF staff level agreement to be reached by end August, after which the country would be able to further talks with sovereign bondholders and bilateral creditors.",
        "“We are down to the nitty-gritty,” he said. “We would have had it this month [July] if it were not for the unstable political condition.”",
        "On a separate note, Wickremesinghe had said it was not the right time for former President Gotabaya Rajapaksa, who fled the country after protestors stormed his official residence on July 09, to return. Nor had Rajapaksa indicated any plans to return, Wickremesinghe was quoted as saying.",
        "“I don’t believe it’s the time for him to return,” he said. “I have no indication of him returning soon.”",
        "Wickremesinghe also defended the legitimacy of his presidency to the WSJ. His election by parliament following Rajapaksa’s resignation has been controversial, with some opposition members and sections of Sri Lanka’s youth-led protest movement claiming that he lacks a popular mandate and that the current parliament does not reflect the will of the people.",
        "“I came in by chance. Basically the president had resigned. The country was on fire. They were taking over the buildings,” he said. “I have been elected constitutionally… it’s up to us to perform now.”",
        "The president noted that, once an IMF agreement was in place, Sri Lanka would have to work out debt restructuring with creditors who have differing approaches.",
        "“It’s an issue between the different approaches to debt relief between India and Japan on one side, supported by the U.S., and China on the other side,” he said. “It’s a question of getting them to agree on one plan. It’s a question of how do you deal with the haircut? How do you deal with having new money given to pay off the old loans?”",
        "Wickremesinghe told the WSJ that the Central Bank of Sri Lanka (CBSL) was confident of “finding the cash to cover enough fuel imports.”",
        "However, even with an IMF agreement in place, Wickremesinghe said Sri Lanka needs to secure upwards of 3 billion US dollars from other sources next year to help pay for key imports like fuel, food and fertilizers. He is also keeping an eye on the process that unfolded in Zambiya, he added."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Sri Lanka",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "WSJ",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "an International Monetary Fund",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "The Wall Street Journal",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "New York City",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sunday July 31",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "some months",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lankans",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "WSJ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "IMF",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "August",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "July",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Gotabaya Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "July 09",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Rajapaksa",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "WSJ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Rajapaksa",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "India",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Japan",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "one",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "U.S.",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "China",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "one",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "WSJ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Central Bank of Sri Lanka",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "3 billion US dollars",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "next year",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Zambiya",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "දේශපාලන ස්ථාවරත්වය ශ්‍රී ලංකාව මුල්ලකට හැරවීමට උපකාරී වනු ඇති බව ජනාධිපති WSJ වෙත කියයි",
      "author": "",
      "body_lines": [
        "ECONOMYNEXT - ශ්‍රී ලංකාව එහි දරුණුතම ආර්ථික අර්බුදය අත්විඳ ඇති අතර දේශපාලන ස්ථාවරත්වය ජාත්‍යන්තර මූල්‍ය අරමුදලේ (IMF) ඇපදීමක් සඳහා සාකච්ඡා අවසන් කිරීමත් සමඟ රට හැරවීමට උපකාරී වනු ඇතැයි ජනාධිපති රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතා Wall Street Journal වෙත පවසා තිබේ.",
        "“මම හිතන්නේ අපි දැනටමත් පහළට ඇවිත්. උමඟේ කෙළවරේ ආලෝකය මට පෙනේ; එය අපට කෙතරම් වේගයෙන් ළඟා විය හැකිද යන්නයි, ”නිව් යෝර්ක් නගරයේ ව්‍යාපාරික දිනපතා පුවත්පත ජූලි 31 ඉරිදා වික්‍රමසිංහ පැවසූ බව උපුටා දක්වයි.",
        "කෙසේ වෙතත්, බොහෝ ශ්‍රී ලාංකිකයන් තම ආර්ථික තත්ත්වය සැලකිය යුතු ලෙස වැඩිදියුණු වීම දැකීමට මාස කිහිපයක් ගතවනු ඇති බව ඔහු පැවසීය.",
        "ජනාධිපති වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතා WSJ වෙත ප්‍රකාශ කළේ අගෝස්තු මස අවසානය වන විට IMF කාර්ය මණ්ඩල මට්ටමේ ගිවිසුමකට එළැඹෙනු ඇතැයි තමන් අපේක්ෂා කරන බවත්, ඉන් පසුව ස්වෛරී බැඳුම්කර හිමියන් සහ ද්විපාර්ශ්වික ණය හිමියන් සමඟ තවදුරටත් සාකච්ඡා කිරීමට රටට හැකි වනු ඇති බවත්ය.",
        "\"අපි නිට්ටාවටම බැස සිටිමු,\" ඔහු පැවසීය. \"අස්ථාවර දේශපාලන තත්ත්වය නොවන්නට අපට මේ මාසයේ [ජූලි] එය ලැබෙනු ඇත.\"",
        "ජුලි 09 වැනිදා විරෝධතාකරුවන් සිය නිල නිවසට කඩා වැදී රටින් පලා ගිය හිටපු ජනාධිපති ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ මහතාට නැවත පැමිණීමට මෙය සුදුසු කාලය නොවන බව වෙනම සටහනක් තබමින් වික්‍රමසිංහ පවසා තිබුණි. නැවත පැමිණීමට කිසිදු සැලසුමක් රාජපක්ෂ සඳහන් කර නොතිබූ බව වික්‍රමසිංහ උපුටා දක්වමින් කියා සිටියේය.",
        "\"ඔහු නැවත පැමිණීමට කාලය මෙය යැයි මම විශ්වාස නොකරමි,\" ඔහු පැවසීය. \"ඔහු ඉක්මනින් ආපසු එන බවට මට කිසිදු හෝඩුවාවක් නැත.\"",
        "වික්‍රමසිංහ WSJ වෙත තම ජනාධිපති ධූරයේ නීත්‍යානුකූල භාවය ද ආරක්ෂා කළේය. රාජපක්ෂගේ ඉල්ලා අස්වීමෙන් පසු ඔහු පාර්ලිමේන්තුවට තේරී පත්වීම මතභේදාත්මක වී ඇති අතර, ඔහුට ජනවරමක් නොමැති බවත් වත්මන් පාර්ලිමේන්තුව මහජන කැමැත්ත පිළිබිඹු නොකරන බවත් ප්‍රකාශ කරමින් ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ තරුණ නායකත්වයෙන් යුත් විරෝධතා ව්‍යාපාරයේ සමහර විපක්ෂ සාමාජිකයින් සහ කොටස් ප්‍රකාශ කර ඇත.",
        "“මම ආවේ අහම්බෙන්. මූලික වශයෙන් ජනාධිපතිවරයා ඉල්ලා අස්වී තිබුණි. රට ගිනි තිබ්බා. ඔවුන් ගොඩනැගිලි පවරා ගනිමින් සිටියා,” ඔහු පැවසීය. \"මම ව්‍යවස්ථානුකූලව තේරී පත්වී ඇත... දැන් එය ඉටු කිරීම අපට භාරයි.\"",
        "ජාත්‍යන්තර මූල්‍ය අරමුදලේ ගිවිසුමක් ඇති වූ පසු, ශ්‍රී ලංකාවට විවිධ ප්‍රවේශයන් ඇති ණය හිමියන් සමඟ ණය ප්‍රතිව්‍යුහගත කිරීමට සිදුවනු ඇති බව ජනාධිපතිවරයා සඳහන් කළේය.",
        "\"එය එක් පැත්තකින් ඉන්දියාව සහ ජපානය අතර එක්සත් ජනපදයේ සහය ඇතිව සහ අනෙක් පැත්තෙන් චීනය අතර නය සහන සඳහා විවිධ ප්‍රවේශයන් අතර ප්‍රශ්නයක්,\" ඔහු පැවසීය. “එය ඔවුන් එක සැලැස්මකට එකඟ කරවා ගැනීම ප්‍රශ්නයක්. කොණ්ඩය කැපීම සමඟ කටයුතු කරන්නේ කෙසේද යන්න ප්රශ්නයක් ද? පැරණි ණය ගෙවීමට නව මුදල් ලබා දී ඔබ කටයුතු කරන්නේ කෙසේද? ”",
        "වික්‍රමසිංහ WSJ වෙත පැවසුවේ ශ්‍රී ලංකා මහ බැංකුව (CBSL) “ප්‍රමාණවත් ඉන්ධන ආනයනය ආවරණය කිරීම සඳහා මුදල් සොයා ගැනීමට” විශ්වාස කරන බවයි.",
        "කෙසේ වෙතත්, IMF ගිවිසුමක් ක්‍රියාත්මක වුවද, ඉන්ධන, ආහාර සහ පොහොර වැනි ප්‍රධාන ආනයන සඳහා ගෙවීමට උපකාර කිරීම සඳහා ශ්‍රී ලංකාව ලබන වසරේ වෙනත් මූලාශ්‍රවලින් ඩොලර් බිලියන 3 කට වඩා වැඩි මුදලක් ලබා ගත යුතු බව වික්‍රමසිංහ පැවසීය. ඔහු සැම්බියාවේ දිග හැරුණු ක්‍රියාවලිය පිළිබඳව ද අවධානයෙන් සිටින බව ඔහු පැවසීය."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "ඩබ්ලිව්.එස්.ජේ",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජාත්‍යන්තර මුල්‍ය අරමුදලක්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "The Wall Street Journal",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "නිව් යෝර්ක් නගරය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජූලි 31 ඉරිදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "සමහර මාස",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලාංකිකයන්",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඩබ්ලිව්.එස්.ජේ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "IMF",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "අගෝස්තු",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ජුලි",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජූලි 09",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "ඩබ්ලිව්.එස්.ජේ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජපානය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "එක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "එක්සත් ජනපදය.",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "චීනය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "එක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ඩබ්ලිව්.එස්.ජේ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකා මහ බැංකුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඩොලර් බිලියන 3 කි",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "ලබන වසර",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "සැම්බියා",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "அரசியல் ஸ்திரத்தன்மை இலங்கையை ஒரு மூலையில் திருப்ப உதவும், ஜனாதிபதி WSJ க்கு கூறுகிறார்",
      "author": "",
      "body_lines": [
        "ECONOMYNEXT – இலங்கை அதன் மோசமான பொருளாதார நெருக்கடியை அனுபவித்துள்ளது மற்றும் அரசியல் ஸ்திரத்தன்மையானது, சர்வதேச நாணய நிதியத்தின் (IMF) பிணையெடுப்புக்கான பேச்சுவார்த்தைகளை இறுதி செய்வதில் தொடங்கி, நாட்டை ஒரு மூலையில் திருப்ப உதவும் என்று ஜனாதிபதி ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க வோல் ஸ்ட்ரீட் ஜேர்னலுக்கு தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "\"நாங்கள் ஏற்கனவே கீழே வந்துவிட்டோம் என்று நினைக்கிறேன். சுரங்கப்பாதையின் முடிவில் நான் ஒளியைக் காண்கிறேன்; நாம் எவ்வளவு விரைவாக அதை அடைய முடியும், ”என்று ஜூலை 31 ஞாயிற்றுக்கிழமை விக்கிரமசிங்க கூறியதாக நியூயார்க் நகரத்தை தளமாகக் கொண்ட வணிக நாளிதழ் மேற்கோளிட்டுள்ளது.",
        "எவ்வாறாயினும், பெரும்பாலான இலங்கையர்களின் பொருளாதார நிலைமை குறிப்பிடத்தக்க வகையில் மேம்படுவதைக் காண சில மாதங்கள் ஆகும் என்று அவர் கூறினார்.",
        "ஜனாதிபதி விக்கிரமசிங்க WSJ இடம் ஆகஸ்ட் மாத இறுதிக்குள் சர்வதேச நாணய நிதியத்தின் ஊழியர்கள் மட்ட உடன்பாடு எட்டப்படும் என்று தான் எதிர்பார்ப்பதாகவும், அதன் பிறகு நாடு இறையாண்மை பத்திரதாரர்கள் மற்றும் இருதரப்பு கடன் வழங்குநர்களுடன் மேலும் பேச்சுவார்த்தை நடத்த முடியும் என்றும் கூறினார்.",
        "\"நாங்கள் மோசமான நிலையில் இருக்கிறோம்,\" என்று அவர் கூறினார். \"நிலையற்ற அரசியல் நிலைமை இல்லாவிட்டால், இந்த மாதமே [ஜூலை] நாங்கள் பெற்றிருப்போம்.\"",
        "கடந்த ஜூலை 09ஆம் திகதி தனது உத்தியோகபூர்வ இல்லத்தை ஆர்ப்பாட்டக்காரர்கள் முற்றுகையிட்டதை அடுத்து நாட்டை விட்டு வெளியேறிய முன்னாள் ஜனாதிபதி கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ச நாடு திரும்புவதற்கு இது சரியான தருணம் அல்ல என விக்கிரமசிங்க குறிப்பிட்டிருந்தார். ராஜபக்ச திரும்பி வருவதற்கான எந்த திட்டத்தையும் குறிப்பிடவில்லை, விக்கிரமசிங்க கூறியதாக மேற்கோள் காட்டப்பட்டது.",
        "\"அவர் திரும்பி வருவதற்கான நேரம் இது என்று நான் நம்பவில்லை,\" என்று அவர் கூறினார். \"அவர் விரைவில் திரும்பி வருவதற்கான எந்த அறிகுறியும் என்னிடம் இல்லை.\"",
        "விக்கிரமசிங்க WSJ க்கு தனது ஜனாதிபதி பதவிக்கான சட்டபூர்வமான தன்மையையும் பாதுகாத்தார். ராஜபக்சேவின் ராஜினாமாவைத் தொடர்ந்து அவர் பாராளுமன்றத்தில் தேர்ந்தெடுக்கப்பட்டது சர்ச்சைக்குரியது, சில எதிர்க்கட்சி உறுப்பினர்கள் மற்றும் இலங்கையின் இளைஞர்கள் தலைமையிலான எதிர்ப்பு இயக்கத்தின் சில பிரிவுகள் அவருக்கு மக்கள் ஆணை இல்லை என்றும் தற்போதைய நாடாளுமன்றம் மக்களின் விருப்பத்தை பிரதிபலிக்கவில்லை என்றும் கூறினர்.",
        "“நான் தற்செயலாக வந்தேன். அடிப்படையில் ஜனாதிபதி பதவி விலகினார். நாடு தீப்பற்றி எரிந்தது. அவர்கள் கட்டிடங்களை கையகப்படுத்தினர்,'' என்றார். \"நான் அரசியலமைப்பு ரீதியாக தேர்ந்தெடுக்கப்பட்டேன் ... இப்போது செயல்படுவது நம் கையில் உள்ளது.\"",
        "IMF உடன்படிக்கை நடைமுறைக்கு வந்தவுடன், வேறுபட்ட அணுகுமுறைகளைக் கொண்ட கடனாளிகளுடன் இலங்கை கடன் மறுசீரமைப்பை மேற்கொள்ள வேண்டும் என்று ஜனாதிபதி குறிப்பிட்டார்.",
        "\"இது ஒருபுறம் அமெரிக்கா மற்றும் சீனாவின் ஆதரவுடன் இந்தியாவிற்கும் ஜப்பானுக்கும் இடையிலான கடன் நிவாரணத்திற்கான வெவ்வேறு அணுகுமுறைகளுக்கு இடையிலான பிரச்சினை\" என்று அவர் கூறினார். “அவர்கள் ஒரு திட்டத்தில் உடன்படுவது ஒரு கேள்வி. ஹேர்கட் எப்படி சமாளிப்பது என்பது ஒரு கேள்வி? பழைய கடனை அடைக்க கொடுக்கப்பட்ட புதிய பணத்தை எப்படி சமாளிப்பது?\"",
        "விக்கிரமசிங்க WSJ இடம், இலங்கை மத்திய வங்கி (CBSL) \"போதுமான எரிபொருள் இறக்குமதியை ஈடுகட்ட பணத்தைக் கண்டுபிடிப்பதில்\" நம்பிக்கை கொண்டுள்ளது என்று கூறினார்.",
        "எவ்வாறாயினும், சர்வதேச நாணய நிதியத்தின் உடன்படிக்கை நடைமுறையில் இருந்தாலும், எரிபொருள், உணவு மற்றும் உரங்கள் போன்ற முக்கிய இறக்குமதிகளுக்கு பணம் செலுத்துவதற்கு அடுத்த ஆண்டு மற்ற மூலங்களிலிருந்து 3 பில்லியன் அமெரிக்க டொலர்களை இலங்கை பெற வேண்டும் என்று விக்கிரமசிங்க கூறினார். ஜாம்பியாவில் வெளிப்பட்ட செயல்முறையையும் அவர் கண்காணித்து வருகிறார், அவர் மேலும் கூறினார்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "இலங்கை",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "WSJ",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஒரு சர்வதேச நாணய நிதியம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "தி வால் ஸ்ட்ரீட் ஜர்னல்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "நியூயார்க் நகரம்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜூலை 31 ஞாயிறு",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "சில மாதங்கள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கையர்கள்",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "WSJ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "IMF",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆகஸ்ட்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஜூலை",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜூலை 09",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ராஜபக்சே",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "WSJ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ராஜபக்சே",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இந்தியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜப்பான்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஒன்று",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "எங்களுக்கு.",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சீனா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஒன்று",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "WSJ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை மத்திய வங்கி",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "3 பில்லியன் அமெரிக்க டாலர்கள்",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "அடுத்த வருடம்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜாம்பியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}