{
  "newspaper_id": "d-b-s-jeyaraj-com",
  "url": "https://dbsjeyaraj.com/dbsj/archives/78748",
  "time_ut": 1658863440,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Key figures of the “aragalaya” (struggle) facing intimidation at the hands of the Govt,Police and military;arrests,surveillance measures, including wiretapping of phones taking place;Among Targets are  Attorney Nuwan Bopage, Catholic priest Fr. Amila Jeewantha Peiris, Inter-University Students’ Federation (IUSF) Convener Wasantha Mudalige and former IUSF Convenor Lahiru Weerasekara",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Key figures of the “aragalaya” (struggle) facing intimidation at the hands of the Govt,Police and military;arrests,surveillance measures, including wiretapping of phones taking place;Among Targets are  Attorney Nuwan Bopage, Catholic priest Fr. Amila Jeewantha Peiris, Inter-University Students’ Federation (IUSF) Convener Wasantha Mudalige and former IUSF Convenor Lahiru Weerasekara",
      "author": "Administrator",
      "body_lines": [
        "Key figures of the “aragalaya” (struggle) are facing intimidation at the hands of the Government, the Police, and the military, activists allege, with arrests as well as surveillance measures, including wiretapping their phones, taking place.",
        "According to sources, Attorney Nuwan Bopage, Catholic priest Fr. Amila Jeewantha Peiris, Inter-University Students’ Federation (IUSF) Convener Wasantha Mudalige, and former IUSF Convenor Lahiru Weerasekara are facing intimidation by the Government.",
        "It is also alleged that the security forces are following these activists while tapping their phones and trying to intimidate the people who support them.",
        "Yesterday (27), freelance journalist and IUSF activist Veranga Pushpika was taken away in a blue jeep by a group of six persons suspected to be Police officers. The activists of the “RanilGoGama” public protest site at the Galle Face Green in Colombo claimed that Pushpika was travelling in a bus after taking part in a demonstration in front of the Colombo Fort Railway Station yesterday afternoon, when he was taken away by a group of six persons in plain clothes, in a jeep numbered GC 0342.",
        "Meanwhile, the “RanilGoGama” activists said that the members of several trade unions (TUs) and other civil organisations had gone to the Human Rights Commission of Sri Lanka (HRCSL) yesterday (27) and informed it regarding the continued arrest of activists involved in the public protests that initially demanded the resignation of then-President Gotabaya Rajapaksa, and are now demanding the resignation of President Ranil Wickremesinghe.",
        "It was also reported that after the HRCSL inquired from the Police, it was confirmed that Pushpika was arrested by the Divisional Crime Detection Bureau (DCDB) – Colombo South, and that a HRCSL team was to visit the DCDB. However, when contacted by The Morning, an official of the Kirulapone Police, where the DCDB is located, said that such a person was not detained at that Police Station as of yesterday evening. Furthermore, when contacted by The Morning, Police Media Spokesman, Senior Superintendent of Police and Attorney-at-Law Nihal Thalduwa said that he was unaware of such an arrest as of yesterday afternoon.",
        "Elsewhere, it was reported that a Police team had raided a Catholic church in the Ratnapura Diocese searching for prominent “Aragalaya” protestor Catholic priest Fr. Amila Jeewantha Peiris yesterday. According to reports, the Police team had told those at the church that there was an order to arrest Peiris on sight. However, when contacted by The Morning, an official of the Ratnapura Police stated that they had not carried out such a raid.",
        "Most of the Galle Face protestors have faced intimidation by the military after the recent tense situations at the protest site and they claim the military is blocking the protestors from re-organising the protest site. “At the moment, we are reorganising and restructuring our protest and protest site. Most of the tents were damaged by the attack conducted jointly by the Army, the Police, and the Special Task Force (STF). But the protestors were not allowed to take the materials for the tent, and they were intimidated by the military at the entrances to the Galle Face protest site,” a protestor told The Morning.",
        "A tense situation was reported early morning on 22 July as the Armed Forces stormed the protest site at the Galle Face Green to clear the Presidential Secretariat and its main entrance of demonstrators. Several protestors were attacked by the Security Forces and beaten.",
        "Speaking to The Morning, a witness claimed that he was assaulted at around 1.30 a.m. by the Security Forces. “It was early morning when the armed troops came and attacked us. I was just next to the Presidential Secretariat. They beat us all, including women and children,” he further claimed.",
        "Protestors have held several protests near the camping site at Galle Face since 22 July.",
        "The massive public protests that began demanding the resignation of Rajapaksa have now turned into those demanding the resignation of Wickremesinghe. Earlier, on 22 July, the Police had arrested a few activists, as well as journalists and lawyers, during the attack carried out on the “RailGoGama” protest site by the Security Forces that morning. The arrestees’ whereabouts were made known on that day only after a few hours of their arrest."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "military;arrests",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "Nuwan Bopage",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "Catholic",
          "label": "NORP"
        },
        {
          "text": "Amila Jeewantha Peiris",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "Inter-University Students’ Federation",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "Wasantha Mudalige",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "IUSF",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "Lahiru Weerasekara",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "Nuwan Bopage",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Catholic",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Amila Jeewantha Peiris",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Inter-University Students’ Federation",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Wasantha Mudalige",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "IUSF",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Lahiru Weerasekara",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "Yesterday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "27",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "IUSF",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Veranga Pushpika",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "six",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Galle Face Green",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "Pushpika",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Colombo Fort Railway Station",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "yesterday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "afternoon",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "six",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "GC",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the Human Rights Commission of Sri Lanka",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "HRCSL",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "yesterday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "27",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Gotabaya Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Pushpika",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Divisional Crime Detection Bureau",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Colombo South",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "The Morning",
            "label": "WORK_OF_ART"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Kirulapone Police",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "DCDB",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "yesterday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "evening",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "The Morning",
            "label": "WORK_OF_ART"
          },
          {
            "text": "yesterday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "afternoon",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Catholic",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ratnapura Diocese",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Aragalaya",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Catholic",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Amila",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Peiris",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "yesterday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Peiris",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "The Morning",
            "label": "WORK_OF_ART"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Ratnapura Police",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Galle Face",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Army",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Police",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Special Task Force",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "The Morning",
            "label": "WORK_OF_ART"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "early morning",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "22 July",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Armed Forces",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Galle Face Green",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Presidential Secretariat",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "Security Forces",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "around 1.30 a.m.",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Security Forces",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "early morning",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Galle Face",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "22 July",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Rajapaksa",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "22 July",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "that morning",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "that day",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "a few hours",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "රජය, පොලිසිය සහ හමුදාව අතින් බිය ගැන්වීම්වලට මුහුණ දෙන \"අරගලයේ\" (අරගලයේ) ප්‍රධාන චරිත; අත්අඩංගුවට ගැනීම්, දුරකථනවලට සවන්දීම ඇතුළු නිරීක්ෂණ ක්‍රියාමාර්ග; ඉලක්ක අතර නීතීඥ නුවන් බෝපගේ, කතෝලික පූජක පියතුමා වේ. අමිල ජීවන්ත පීරිස්, අන්තර් විශ්වවිද්‍යාල ශිෂ්‍ය බලමණ්ඩලයේ (අවිශිබම) කැඳවුම්කරු වසන්ත මුදලිගේ සහ අවිශිබම හිටපු කැඳවුම්කරු ලහිරු වීරසේකර",
      "author": "පරිපාලක",
      "body_lines": [
        "“අරගලයේ” (අරගලයේ) ප්‍රධාන චරිත රජය, පොලිසිය සහ හමුදාව අතින් බිය ගැන්වීම්වලට මුහුණ දී සිටින බව ක්‍රියාකාරීන් චෝදනා කරන්නේ, අත්අඩංගුවට ගැනීම් මෙන්ම ඔවුන්ගේ දුරකථනවලට ටැප් කිරීම ඇතුළු නිරීක්ෂණ ක්‍රියාමාර්ග ද සිදුවෙමින් පවතින බවයි.",
        "ආරංචි මාර්ගවලට අනුව නීතිඥ නුවන් බෝපගේ, කතෝලික පූජක පියතුමා. අමිල ජීවන්ත පීරිස්, අන්තර් විශ්වවිද්‍යාල ශිෂ්‍ය බලමණ්ඩලයේ (අවිශිබම) කැඳවුම්කරු වසන්ත මුදලිගේ සහ අවිශිබම හිටපු කැඳවුම්කරු ලහිරු වීරසේකර ආන්ඩුවෙන් තර්ජනයට ලක්ව සිටිති.",
        "ආරක්ෂක අංශ මෙම ක්‍රියාකාරීන්ගේ දුරකථනවලට ටැප් කරමින් ඔවුන් පසුපස හඹා යමින් ඔවුන්ට සහය දක්වන පුද්ගලයින් බිය ගැන්වීමට උත්සාහ කරන බවටද චෝදනා එල්ල වේ.",
        "ඊයේ (27) නිදහස් මාධ්‍යවේදියෙකු සහ අවිශිබම ක්‍රියාකාරිකයෙකු වන වේරංග පුෂ්පිකා පොලිස් නිලධාරීන් යැයි සැක කෙරෙන හය දෙනෙකුගෙන් යුත් කණ්ඩායමක් විසින් නිල් ජීප් රථයකින් රැගෙන ගොස් ඇත. කොළඹ ගාලුමුවදොර පිටියේ “රනිල්ගොගම” මහජන විරෝධතා අඩවියේ ක්‍රියාකාරීන් කියා සිටියේ ඊයේ පස්වරුවේ කොළඹ කොටුව දුම්රියපොළ ඉදිරිපිට පැවති විරෝධතාවයකට සහභාගී වී පුෂ්පිකා බස් රථයක යමින් සිටියදී කිසියම් පිරිසක් විසින් ඔහු රැගෙන ගිය බවයි. GC 0342 අංක දරන ජීප් රථයකින් සිවිල් ඇඳුමින් සැරසුණු හය දෙනෙකුගෙන්.",
        "මේ අතර වෘත්තීය සමිති කිහිපයක (TUs) සහ තවත් සිවිල් සංවිධාන කිහිපයක සාමාජිකයින් ඊයේ (27) ශ්‍රී ලංකා මානව හිමිකම් කොමිෂන් සභාව (HRCSL) වෙත ගොස් ක්‍රියාකාරීන් අඛණ්ඩව අත්අඩංගුවට ගැනීම සම්බන්ධයෙන් දැනුම් දුන් බව “රනිල්ගොගම” ක්‍රියාකාරීහු පැවසූහ. එවක ජනාධිපති ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ මහතාට ඉල්ලා අස්විය යුතු යැයි මුලින් ඉල්ලා සිටි මහජන විරෝධතා මේ වන විට ජනාධිපති රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතාට ඉල්ලා අස්වන ලෙස බලකරමින් සිටී.",
        "HRCSL පොලිසියෙන් කළ විමසීමෙන් පසු පුෂ්පිකා අත්අඩංගුවට ගෙන ඇත්තේ දකුණු කොළඹ - කොට්ඨාශ අපරාධ විමර්ශන කාර්යාංශය (DCDB) විසින් බවත්, HRCSL කණ්ඩායමක් DCDB වෙත පැමිණීමට නියමිත බවත් තහවුරු වූ බවද වාර්තා විය. කෙසේ වෙතත්, DCDB පිහිටි කිරුළපන පොලිසියේ නිලධාරියෙකු The Morning කළ විමසීමකදී කියා සිටියේ ඊයේ සවස් වන විට එවැනි පුද්ගලයෙකු එම පොලිස් ස්ථානයේ රඳවා නොමැති බවයි. තවද, The Morning කළ විමසීමකදී පොලිස් මාධ්‍ය ප්‍රකාශක, ජ්‍යෙෂ්ඨ පොලිස් අධිකාරී සහ නීතීඥ නිහාල් තල්දූව කියා සිටියේ එවැනි අත්අඩංගුවට ගැනීමක් ඊයේ පස්වරුවේ වන විට තමන් නොදන්නා බවයි.",
        "ප්‍රමුඛ පෙළේ “අරගලය” විරෝධතාකරු කතෝලික පියතුමා සොයමින් පොලිස් කණ්ඩායමක් රත්නපුර රදගුරු පදවියේ කතෝලික දේවස්ථානයක් වටලා ඇති බව තවත් තැනක වාර්තා විය. අමිල ජීවන්ත පීරිස් ඊයේ. වාර්තා වන අන්දමට පොලිස් කණ්ඩායම දේවස්ථානයේ සිටි අයට පවසා ඇත්තේ පීරිස් දුටු සැණින් අත්අඩංගුවට ගැනීමට නියෝගයක් තිබූ බවයි. කෙසේ වෙතත්, ‘ද මෝනිං’ කළ විමසීමකදී රත්නපුර පොලිසියේ නිලධාරියෙකු සඳහන් කළේ තමන් එවැනි වැටලීමක් සිදු නොකළ බවයි.",
        "ගාලු මුවදොර විරෝධතාවයේ පසුගිය දිනවල ඇති වූ නොසන්සුන්කාරී තත්ත්වයෙන් පසු බොහෝ විරෝධතාකරුවන් හමුදාවේ තර්ජනවලට මුහුණ දී ඇති අතර ඔවුන් කියා සිටින්නේ විරෝධතාකරුවන්ට විරෝධතා ස්ථානය නැවත සංවිධානය කිරීමට හමුදාව බාධා කරන බවයි. “මේ මොහොතේ, අපි අපගේ විරෝධතා සහ විරෝධතා ස්ථානය ප්‍රතිසංවිධානය කර ප්‍රතිව්‍යුහගත කරමින් සිටිමු. යුද හමුදාව, පොලිසිය සහ විශේෂ කාර්ය බළකාය (STF) එක්ව සිදුකළ ප්‍රහාරයෙන් කූඩාරම් බොහොමයකට හානි සිදුවී ඇත. නමුත් විරෝධතාකරුවන්ට කූඩාරමට අවශ්‍ය ද්‍රව්‍ය රැගෙන යාමට ඉඩ නොදුන් අතර, ගාලු මුවදොර විරෝධතා භූමියට ඇතුළු වන දොරටුවලදී හමුදාව විසින් ඔවුන් බිය ගන්වන ලදී,” විරෝධතාකරුවෙක් The Morning වෙත පැවසීය.",
        "ජනාධිපති ලේකම් කාර්යාලය සහ එහි ප්‍රධාන දොරටුව විරෝධතාකරුවන් ඉවත් කිරීම සඳහා ත්‍රිවිධ හමුදාව ගාලුමුවදොර පිටියේ විරෝධතා භූමියට කඩා වැදීමත් සමඟ ජුලි 22 අලුයම නොසන්සුන්කාරී තත්ත්වයක් වාර්තා විය. විරෝධතාකරුවන් කිහිප දෙනෙකුට ආරක්ෂක අංශ විසින් පහර දී පහර දී ඇත.",
        "අලුයම 1.30 ට පමණ ආරක්ෂක අංශ විසින් තමන්ට පහර දුන් බව ද මෝනිං වෙත අදහස් දක්වමින් සාක්ෂිකරුවෙක් කියා සිටියේය. “අලුයම තමයි සන්නද්ධ හමුදා ඇවිත් අපට පහර දුන්නේ. මම හිටියේ ජනාධිපති ලේකම් කාර්යාලයට එහා පැත්තේ. ඔවුන් කාන්තාවන්, ළමයින් ඇතුළු අපි හැමෝටම පහර දුන්නා,” ඔහු වැඩිදුරටත් කියා සිටියේය.",
        "විරෝධතාකරුවන් ජූලි 22 සිට ගාලු මුවදොර කඳවුරු භූමිය අසල විරෝධතා කිහිපයක් පවත්වා ඇත.",
        "රාජපක්ෂ මහතාට ඉල්ලා අස්විය යුතු බව පවසමින් ආරම්භ වූ දැවැන්ත මහජන විරෝධතා මේ වන විට වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතාට ඉල්ලා අස්වන ලෙස ඉල්ලන විරෝධතා බවට පත්ව ඇත. මීට පෙර, ජූලි 22 වන දින, ආරක්ෂක අංශ විසින් එදින උදෑසන “රේල්ගෝගම” විරෝධතා භූමියට එල්ල කරන ලද ප්‍රහාරයේදී ක්‍රියාකාරීන් කිහිප දෙනෙකු මෙන්ම මාධ්‍යවේදීන් සහ නීතිඥයින් කිහිප දෙනෙකු ද පොලිසිය විසින් අත්අඩංගුවට ගෙන තිබුණි. අත්අඩංගුවට පත්වූවන් සිටින ස්ථානය එදින දැන ගැනීමට හැකි වූයේ ඔවුන් අත්අඩංගුවට ගෙන පැය කිහිපයකට පසුවය."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "හමුදා;අත්අඩංගුවට ගැනීම",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "Nuwan Bopage",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "කතෝලික",
          "label": "NORP"
        },
        {
          "text": "අමිල ජීවන්ත පීරිස්",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "අන්තර් විශ්වවිද්‍යාල ශිෂ්‍ය බල මණ්ඩලය",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "වසන්ත මුදලිගේ",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "අවිශිබම",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "ලහිරු වීරසේකර",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "Nuwan Bopage",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "කතෝලික",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "අමිල ජීවන්ත පීරිස්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "අන්තර් විශ්වවිද්‍යාල ශිෂ්‍ය බල මණ්ඩලය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "වසන්ත මුදලිගේ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "අවිශිබම",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ලහිරු වීරසේකර",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "ඊයේ",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "27",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "අවිශිබම",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "වේරංග පුෂ්පිකා",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "හය",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගාලු මුවදොර පිටිය",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "පුෂ්පිකා",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "කොළඹ කොටුව දුම්රිය ස්ථානය",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඊයේ",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "දහවල්",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "හය",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "GC",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකා මානව හිමිකම් කොමිෂන් සභාව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "HRCSL",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඊයේ",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "27",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "පුෂ්පිකා",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "කොට්ඨාශ අපරාධ විමර්ශන කාර්යාංශය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "දකුණු කොළඹ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "උදෑසන",
            "label": "WORK_OF_ART"
          },
          {
            "text": "කිරුළපන පොලිසිය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "DCDB",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඊයේ",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "සවස",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "උදෑසන",
            "label": "WORK_OF_ART"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඊයේ",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "දහවල්",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "කතෝලික",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "රත්නපුර රදගුරු පදවිය",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "අරගලය",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "කතෝලික",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "අමිල",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "පීරිස්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඊයේ",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "පීරිස්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "උදෑසන",
            "label": "WORK_OF_ART"
          },
          {
            "text": "රත්නපුර පොලිසිය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ගාලු මුවදොර",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "හමුදා",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "පොලිසිය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "විශේෂ කාර්ය බලකාය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "උදෑසන",
            "label": "WORK_OF_ART"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "හිමිදිරි උදෑසන",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "22 ජූලි",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "සන්නද්ධ හමුදා",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගාලු මුවදොර පිටිය",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජනාධිපති ලේකම් කාර්යාලය",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "ආරක්ෂක හමුදා",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "1.30 පමණ",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "ආරක්ෂක හමුදා",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "හිමිදිරි උදෑසන",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ගාලු මුවදොර",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "22 ජූලි",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "22 ජූලි",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "එදා උදේ",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "එදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "පැය කිහිපයක්",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "அரசாங்கம், பொலிஸ் மற்றும் இராணுவத்தின் கைகளில் அச்சுறுத்தலை எதிர்கொள்ளும் \"அறகலயா\" (போராட்டம்) முக்கிய நபர்கள்; கைதுகள், தொலைபேசிகளை ஒட்டுக்கேட்டல் உட்பட கண்காணிப்பு நடவடிக்கைகள்; இலக்குகளில் வழக்கறிஞர் நுவான் போபகே, கத்தோலிக்க பாதிரியார் சகோ. அமில ஜீவந்த பீரிஸ், பல்கலைக்கழகங்களுக்கு இடையிலான மாணவர் சம்மேளனத்தின் (IUSF) அழைப்பாளர் வசந்த முதலிகே மற்றும் IUSF முன்னாள் அழைப்பாளர் லஹிரு வீரசேகர",
      "author": "நிர்வாகி",
      "body_lines": [
        "\"அரகலயா\" (போராட்டம்) முக்கிய பிரமுகர்கள் அரசாங்கம், காவல்துறை மற்றும் இராணுவத்தின் கைகளில் அச்சுறுத்தலை எதிர்கொள்கின்றனர், கைது செய்யப்படுவதுடன், அவர்களின் தொலைபேசிகளை ஒட்டுக்கேட்டல் உட்பட கண்காணிப்பு நடவடிக்கைகளும் நடைபெறுவதாக ஆர்வலர்கள் குற்றம் சாட்டுகின்றனர்.",
        "ஆதாரங்களின்படி, வழக்கறிஞர் நுவான் போபகே, கத்தோலிக்க பாதிரியார் Fr. அமில ஜீவந்த பீரிஸ், பல்கலைக்கழகங்களுக்கு இடையிலான மாணவர் சம்மேளனத்தின் (IUSF) அழைப்பாளர் வசந்த முதலிகே மற்றும் IUSF முன்னாள் அழைப்பாளர் லஹிரு வீரசேகர ஆகியோர் அரசாங்கத்தின் அச்சுறுத்தலுக்கு முகங்கொடுத்துள்ளனர்.",
        "பாதுகாப்புப் படையினர் இந்த ஆர்வலர்களின் தொலைபேசிகளை ஒட்டுக்கேட்கும்போது அவர்களைப் பின்தொடர்வதாகவும், அவர்களுக்கு ஆதரவளிக்கும் நபர்களை மிரட்ட முயற்சிப்பதாகவும் கூறப்படுகிறது.",
        "நேற்று (27) சுதந்திர ஊடகவியலாளரும் IUSF செயற்பாட்டாளருமான வெரங்க புஷ்பிகாவை பொலிஸ் அதிகாரிகள் என சந்தேகிக்கப்படும் ஆறு பேர் கொண்ட குழு நீல ஜீப்பில் அழைத்துச் சென்றது. நேற்று பிற்பகல் கொழும்பு கோட்டை புகையிரத நிலையத்திற்கு முன்பாக இடம்பெற்ற ஆர்ப்பாட்டத்தில் ஈடுபட்டுவிட்டு பஸ்ஸில் பயணித்த புஷ்பிகாவை ஒரு குழுவினர் அழைத்துச் சென்றதாக கொழும்பு காலி முகத்திடலில் உள்ள “ரணில் கோகம” பொதுப் போராட்ட தளத்தின் செயற்பாட்டாளர்கள் தெரிவித்தனர். GC 0342 எண் கொண்ட ஜீப்பில் சாதாரண உடையில் ஆறு பேர்.",
        "இதேவேளை, பல தொழிற்சங்கங்கள் மற்றும் ஏனைய சிவில் அமைப்புக்களின் அங்கத்தவர்கள் நேற்று (27) இலங்கை மனித உரிமைகள் ஆணைக்குழுவிற்கு (HRCSL) சென்று சம்பந்தப்பட்ட செயற்பாட்டாளர்கள் தொடர்ந்தும் கைது செய்யப்படுவது தொடர்பில் தெரிவித்துள்ளதாக “ரணில் கோகம” செயற்பாட்டாளர்கள் தெரிவித்தனர். முதலில் அப்போதைய ஜனாதிபதி கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ஷவை பதவி விலகுமாறு கோரி முன்னெடுக்கப்பட்ட பொது மக்கள் போராட்டம் தற்போது ஜனாதிபதி ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்கவை பதவி விலகுமாறு கோரி வருகின்றனர்.",
        "HRCSL பொலிஸாரிடம் வினவியதையடுத்து, கொழும்பு தெற்கு பிரதேச குற்றப் புலனாய்வுப் பிரிவினரால் (DCDB) புஷ்பிகா கைது செய்யப்பட்டுள்ளார் என்பதும், HRCSL குழுவொன்று DCDB க்கு விஜயம் செய்யவுள்ளமையும் உறுதிப்படுத்தப்பட்டதாகவும் தெரிவிக்கப்பட்டுள்ளது. எவ்வாறாயினும், DCDB அமைந்துள்ள கிருலப்பனை பொலிஸ் அதிகாரியொருவரை The Morning தொடர்பு கொண்டபோது, ​​அத்தகைய நபர் நேற்று மாலை வரை அந்த பொலிஸ் நிலையத்தில் தடுத்து வைக்கப்படவில்லை என்று கூறினார். மேலும், தி மோர்னிங் தொடர்பு கொண்ட பொலிஸ் ஊடகப் பேச்சாளர், சிரேஷ்ட பொலிஸ் அத்தியட்சகர் மற்றும் சட்டத்தரணி நிஹால் தல்துவ, நேற்று பிற்பகல் வரையில் அவ்வாறான கைது தொடர்பில் தனக்குத் தெரியாது எனத் தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "மற்றுமொரு இடத்தில், இரத்தினபுரி மறைமாவட்டத்தில் உள்ள கத்தோலிக்க தேவாலயமொன்றில் பொலிஸ் குழுவொன்று சோதனை நடத்தியதாக தெரிவிக்கப்பட்டு, முக்கிய “அரகலயா” எதிர்ப்பாளர் கத்தோலிக்க பாதிரியார் சகோ. அமில ஜீவந்த பீரிஸ் நேற்று. பீரிஸை கண்டதும் கைது செய்ய உத்தரவு இருப்பதாக தேவாலயத்தில் இருந்தவர்களிடம் போலீஸ் குழு கூறியதாக தகவல்கள் தெரிவிக்கின்றன. எவ்வாறாயினும், தி மோர்னிங் தொடர்பு கொண்டபோது, ​​இரத்தினபுரி காவல்துறையின் அதிகாரி ஒருவர் அத்தகைய சோதனையை மேற்கொள்ளவில்லை என்று கூறினார்.",
        "காலி முகத்திடலில் அண்மையில் ஏற்பட்ட பதற்றமான சூழ்நிலைக்குப் பின்னர் பெரும்பாலான காலி முகத்திடல் ஆர்ப்பாட்டக்காரர்கள் இராணுவத்தினரால் அச்சுறுத்தலுக்கு முகங்கொடுத்துள்ளனர் மேலும் போராட்டத் தளத்தை மறுசீரமைப்பதில் இருந்து போராட்டக்காரர்களை இராணுவம் தடுப்பதாக அவர்கள் கூறுகின்றனர். \"இந்த நேரத்தில், நாங்கள் எங்கள் எதிர்ப்பு மற்றும் எதிர்ப்பு தளத்தை மறுசீரமைத்து மறுசீரமைக்கிறோம். இராணுவம், பொலிஸ் மற்றும் விசேட அதிரடிப்படை (STF) இணைந்து நடத்திய தாக்குதலில் பெரும்பாலான கூடாரங்கள் சேதமடைந்துள்ளன. ஆனால் ஆர்ப்பாட்டக்காரர்கள் கூடாரத்திற்கான பொருட்களை எடுத்துச் செல்ல அனுமதிக்கப்படவில்லை, மேலும் அவர்கள் காலி முகத்திடல் போராட்ட தளத்தின் நுழைவாயில்களில் இராணுவத்தால் மிரட்டப்பட்டனர், ”என்று ஒரு எதிர்ப்பாளர் தி மோனிங்கிற்கு தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "ஜனாதிபதி செயலகம் மற்றும் ஆர்ப்பாட்டக்காரர்களின் பிரதான நுழைவாயிலை அகற்றுவதற்காக ஆயுதப்படையினர் காலி முகத்திடலில் உள்ள போராட்டத் தளத்தை ஜூலை 22 அன்று முற்றுகையிட்டதால் பதற்றமான சூழ்நிலை ஏற்பட்டது. பல போராட்டக்காரர்கள் பாதுகாப்புப் படையினரால் தாக்கப்பட்டு தாக்கப்பட்டனர்.",
        "காலை 1.30 மணியளவில் பாதுகாப்புப் படையினரால் அவர் தாக்கப்பட்டதாக சாட்சி ஒருவர் தி மார்னிங்கிடம் கூறினார். “அதிகாலையில் ஆயுதமேந்திய படையினர் வந்து எங்களைத் தாக்கினார்கள். நான் ஜனாதிபதி செயலகத்திற்கு அருகில் தான் இருந்தேன். அவர்கள் பெண்கள் மற்றும் குழந்தைகள் உட்பட எங்கள் அனைவரையும் அடித்தனர், ”என்று அவர் மேலும் கூறினார்.",
        "ஜூலை 22 முதல் காலி முகத்திடலில் உள்ள முகாம்களுக்கு அருகில் எதிர்ப்பாளர்கள் பல போராட்டங்களை நடத்தியுள்ளனர்.",
        "ராஜபக்ச ராஜினாமா செய்யக் கோரி தொடங்கிய மாபெரும் மக்கள் போராட்டங்கள் தற்போது விக்ரமசிங்கேவை பதவி விலகக் கோரும் போராட்டமாக மாறியுள்ளது. முன்னதாக, ஜூலை 22 அன்று, பாதுகாப்புப் படையினரால் \"ரயில் கோகாமா\" போராட்ட தளத்தில் நடத்தப்பட்ட தாக்குதலின் போது, ​​சில ஆர்வலர்கள் மற்றும் பத்திரிகையாளர்கள் மற்றும் வழக்கறிஞர்கள் ஆகியோரை காவல்துறையினர் கைது செய்தனர். கைது செய்யப்பட்ட சில மணி நேரங்களுக்குப் பிறகுதான் கைது செய்யப்பட்டவர்களின் இருப்பிடம் அன்று தெரிய வந்தது."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "இராணுவம்; கைதுகள்",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "Nuwan Bopage",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "கத்தோலிக்க",
          "label": "NORP"
        },
        {
          "text": "அமில ஜீவந்த பீரிஸ்",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "பல்கலைக்கழகங்களுக்கு இடையிலான மாணவர் கூட்டமைப்பு",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "வசந்த முதலிகே",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "IUSF",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "லஹிரு வீரசேகர",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "Nuwan Bopage",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "கத்தோலிக்க",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "அமில ஜீவந்த பீரிஸ்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "பல்கலைக்கழகங்களுக்கு இடையிலான மாணவர் கூட்டமைப்பு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "வசந்த முதலிகே",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "IUSF",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "லஹிரு வீரசேகர",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "நேற்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "27",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "IUSF",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "வெரங்க புஷ்பிகா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆறு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Galle Face Green",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "புஷ்பிகா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "கொழும்பு கோட்டை ரயில் நிலையம்",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "நேற்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "பிற்பகல்",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆறு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜி.சி",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை மனித உரிமைகள் ஆணைக்குழு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "HRCSL",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "நேற்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "27",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "புஷ்பிகா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "பிரிவு குற்றப் புலனாய்வுப் பிரிவு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "கொழும்பு தெற்கு",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "தி மார்னிங்",
            "label": "WORK_OF_ART"
          },
          {
            "text": "கிருலப்பனை பொலிஸ்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "டிசிடிபி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "நேற்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சாயங்காலம்",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "தி மார்னிங்",
            "label": "WORK_OF_ART"
          },
          {
            "text": "நேற்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "பிற்பகல்",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "கத்தோலிக்க",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "இரத்தினபுரி மறைமாவட்டம்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "அரகலயா",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "கத்தோலிக்க",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "அமிலா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "பீரிஸ்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "நேற்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "பீரிஸ்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "தி மார்னிங்",
            "label": "WORK_OF_ART"
          },
          {
            "text": "இரத்தினபுரி பொலிஸ்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "காலி முகம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இராணுவம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "காவல்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "சிறப்பு அதிரடிப்படை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "தி மார்னிங்",
            "label": "WORK_OF_ART"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "அதிகாலை",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "22 ஜூலை",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆயுதப்படைகள்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Galle Face Green",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜனாதிபதி செயலகம்",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாதுகாப்பு படைகள்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "சுமார் 1.30 மணி",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாதுகாப்பு படைகள்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "அதிகாலை",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "காலி முகம்",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "22 ஜூலை",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ராஜபக்சே",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "22 ஜூலை",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "அன்று காலை",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "அந்த நாள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஒரு சில மணி நேரம்",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}