{
  "newspaper_id": "ada-lk",
  "url": "https://www.ada.lk/breaking_news/කුණු-ලොරියේ-ඩීසල්-ඇද්ද-සහයක-මාට්ටූ/11-395756",
  "time_ut": 1658828723,
  "original_lang": "si",
  "original_title": "කුණු ලොරියේ ඩීසල් ඇද්ද සහයක මාට්ටූ",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Helper Mattoo pulled diesel in the garbage truck",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "Wadduwa police said that an employee of the Panadura local council was arrested for stealing 20 liters of diesel from the lorry transporting garbage at night.",
        "The police said that the arrested was an employee working as an assistant in the JCB machine of the Panadura local council.",
        "After informing the Wadduwa police that two employees working in the council were stealing 20 liters of diesel from the lorry parked in the vehicle yard last night on the 24th, the police said that one of the suspects was arrested and the hidden 20 liters of diesel was found.",
        "A senior police officer said that action will be taken to arrest the other suspect involved in the incident.",
        "For the past few days, the Panadura local council was in dire straits without fuel to transport the garbage, a senior official said."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Helper Mattoo",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Panadura",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "20",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "night",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "JCB",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Panadura",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Wadduwa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "two",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "20",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "last night",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "24th",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "one",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "the past few days",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Panadura",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "කුණු ලොරියේ ඩීසල් ඇද්ද සහයක මාට්ටූ",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "පානදුර ප්‍රාදේශීය සභාවේ කසල ප්‍රවාහනය කරන ලොරි රථයෙන් රාත්‍රී කාලයේ ඩීසල් ලීටර් 20 ක් සොරකම් කල එම සභාවේම සේවකයෙකු අත්අඩංගුවට ගත්බව වාද්දූව පොලීසිය පවසයි.",
        "මෙසේ අත්අඩංගුවට ගෙන ඇත්තේ පානදුර ප්‍රාදේශීය සභාවේ ජේ සී බී යන්ත්‍රයේ සහයක ලෙසින් රාජකාරි කරන සේවකයෙකු බව පොලිසිය පැවසීය.",
        "ඉකුත් 24 දා රාත්‍රී වාහන අංගනයේ ගාල්කර තිබූ කසල ප්‍රවාහනය කරන ලොරි රථයෙන් ඩීසල් ලීටර් 20 ක් සභාවේ සේවය කරන සේවකයින් දෙදෙනෙකු සොරකම් කරගෙන යන බවට වාද්දුව පොලිසිය දැනුවත් කිරීමෙන් පසු එක් සැකකරුවෙකු අත්අඩංගුවට ගෙන සඟවා තිබූ ඩීසල් ලීටර 20 සොයාගත් බව පොලිසිය සදහන් කළේය.",
        "සිද්ධියට සම්බන්ධ අනෙක් සැකකරු කඩිනමින් අත්අඩංගුවට ගැනීමට ක්‍රියා කරන බව උසස් පොලිස් නිලධාරියෙක් කීය.",
        "පසුගිය දින කිහිපය පුරාවට කසළ ප්‍රවාහනය කිරීමට ඉන්ධන නොමැතිව පානදුර ප්‍රාදේශීය සභාව දැඩි අපහසුතාවයකට ලක්ව සිටි බව එහි උසස් නිලධාරියෙක් පැවසීය."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "උදව් Mattoo",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "පානදුර",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "20",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "රෑ",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "JCB",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "පානදුර",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "වාද්දුව",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "දෙක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "20",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "අවසන් රාත්රිය",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "24 වැනි",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "එක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "පසුගිය දින කිහිපය",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "පානදුර",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "உதவியாளர் மேட்டூ குப்பை லாரியில் டீசலை இழுத்தார்",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "இரவு வேளையில் குப்பைகளை ஏற்றிச் சென்ற லொறியில் இருந்து 20 லீற்றர் டீசலை திருடிய பாணந்துறை உள்ளுராட்சி மன்ற ஊழியர் ஒருவர் கைது செய்யப்பட்டதாக வாத்துவ பொலிஸார் தெரிவித்தனர்.",
        "கைது செய்யப்பட்டவர் பாணந்துறை உள்ளூராட்சி சபையின் ஜேசிபி இயந்திரத்தில் உதவியாளராக பணிபுரியும் ஊழியர் என பொலிஸார் தெரிவித்தனர்.",
        "நேற்றிரவு 24ஆம் திகதி இரவு வாகன முற்றத்தில் நிறுத்தி வைக்கப்பட்டிருந்த லொறியில் இருந்து 20 லீற்றர் டீசலை சபையில் பணிபுரியும் ஊழியர்கள் இருவர் திருடுவதாக வாத்துவ பொலிஸாருக்கு தகவல் வழங்கியதையடுத்து சந்தேகநபர் ஒருவரை கைது செய்து மறைத்து வைக்கப்பட்டிருந்த 20 லீற்றர் டீசலை பொலிஸார் தெரிவித்தனர். கண்டறியப்பட்டது.",
        "சம்பவத்துடன் தொடர்புடைய மற்றைய சந்தேக நபரையும் கைது செய்ய நடவடிக்கை எடுக்கப்படும் என சிரேஷ்ட பொலிஸ் அதிகாரி ஒருவர் தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "கடந்த சில நாட்களாக பாணந்துறை உள்ளூராட்சி சபை குப்பைகளை கொண்டு செல்வதற்கு எரிபொருளின்றி மிகவும் அவலநிலையில் உள்ளதாக உயர் அதிகாரி ஒருவர் தெரிவித்தார்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "உதவியாளர் மேட்டூ",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "பாணந்துறை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "20",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "இரவு",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஜேசிபி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாணந்துறை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "வாதுவ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இரண்டு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "20",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "நேற்று இரவு",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "24வது",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஒன்று",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "கடந்த சில நாட்களாக",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாணந்துறை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}