{
  "newspaper_id": "ada-derana-lk",
  "url": "http://www.adaderana.lk/news/83687/gl-questions-kariyawasam-on-backing-ranil-for-office-of-president",
  "time_ut": 1657967160,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "GL questions Kariyawasam on backing Ranil for office of president",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "GL questions Kariyawasam on backing Ranil for office of president",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "Chairman of Sri Lanka Podujana Peramuna (SLPP), Prof. G.L. Peris has called for an explanation from the party’s General-Secretary Sagara Kariyawasam regarding his statement on backing the candidature of Acting President Ranil Wickremesinghe in the election in parliament for the office of President.",
        "In a letter directed to Kariyawasam, Prof. Peiris demanded a response for the following:",
        "• The names of the persons who purportedly participated in the making of this decision;",
        "• Particulars relating to the notice convening the purported meeting including the date and time of the notice;",
        "• The provision of the constitution of SLPP, in terms of which this purported decision was made.",
        "After SLPP MP Dullas Alahapperuma announced his decision to vie for the presidency yesterday, Kariyawasam had stated that the party would support Acting President Ranil Wickremesinghe as a candidate in the parliamentary vote scheduled for July 20, to elect a new President for post which currently remains vacant."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Kariyawasam",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "Ranil",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "Podujana Peramuna",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "G.L. Peris",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sagara Kariyawasam",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Kariyawasam",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Peiris",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "Dullas Alahapperuma",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "yesterday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kariyawasam",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "July 20",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "ජී එල් කාරියවසම්ගෙන් ප්‍රශ්න කරන්නේ රනිල්ට ජනාධිපති ධූරයට සහාය දීම ගැනය",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකා පොදුජන පෙරමුණේ (SLPP) සභාපති මහාචාර්ය ජී.එල්. පීරිස් මහතා ජනාධිපති ධූරය සඳහා වන මැතිවරණයේදී වැඩ බලන ජනාධිපති රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතාට සහය පළ කිරීම සම්බන්ධයෙන් කළ ප්‍රකාශය සම්බන්ධයෙන් පක්ෂයේ මහලේකම් සාගර කාරියවසම් මහතාගෙන් පැහැදිලි කිරීමක් ඉල්ලා තිබේ.",
        "කාරියවසම් වෙත යොමු කළ ලිපියක මහාචාර්ය පීරිස් පහත සඳහන් කරුණු සඳහා ප්‍රතිචාරයක් ඉල්ලා සිටියේය.",
        "• මෙම තීරණය ගැනීම සඳහා සහභාගී වූ බව කියන පුද්ගලයින්ගේ නම්;",
        "• දැනුම්දීමේ දිනය සහ වේලාව ඇතුළුව අපේක්ෂිත රැස්වීම කැඳවන දැන්වීමට අදාළ විස්තර;",
        "• ශ්‍රී ලංකා පොදුජන පෙරමුණේ ආණ්ඩුක්‍රම ව්‍යවස්ථාවේ ප්‍රතිපාදන, මෙම ප්‍රකාශිත තීරණය ගන්නා ලදී.",
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකා පොදුජන පෙරමුණේ පාර්ලිමේන්තු මන්ත්‍රී ඩලස් අලහප්පෙරුම මහතා ඊයේ ජනාධිපතිවරණයට තරග කිරීමට තීරණය ප්‍රකාශ කිරීමෙන් පසු දැනට පුරප්පාඩු වී ඇති ධූරය සඳහා නව ජනාධිපතිවරයකු තෝරා ගැනීම සඳහා ජූලි 20 වැනිදා පැවැත්වීමට නියමිත පාර්ලිමේන්තු ඡන්ද විමසීමේදී අපේක්ෂකයකු ලෙස වැඩ බලන ජනාධිපති රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතාට සහය දෙන බව කාරියවසම් මහතා ප්‍රකාශ කළේය. ."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "කාරියවසම්",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "රනිල්",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "පොදුජන පෙරමුණ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජී.එල්. පීරිස්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "සාගර කාරියවසම්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "කාරියවසම්",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "පීරිස්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "ඩලස් අලහප්පෙරුම",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඊයේ",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "කාරියවසම්",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජූලි 20",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "ரணிலை ஜனாதிபதி பதவிக்கு ஆதரிப்பது குறித்து காரியவசம் ஜி.எல்",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "ஜனாதிபதி பதவிக்கான தேர்தலில் ஜனாதிபதி ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்கவின் வேட்புமனுவை ஆதரிப்பது குறித்து ஸ்ரீலங்கா பொதுஜன பெரமுனவின் (SLPP) தலைவர் பேராசிரியர் ஜீ.எல்.பெரிஸ் கட்சியின் பொதுச் செயலாளர் சாகர காரியவசம் தெரிவித்த கருத்து தொடர்பில் விளக்கமளிக்குமாறு கோரியுள்ளார்.",
        "காரியவசத்திற்கு அனுப்பிய கடிதத்தில், பேராசிரியர் பீரிஸ், பின்வருவனவற்றிற்கு பதிலளிக்குமாறு கோரியுள்ளார்.",
        "• இந்த முடிவை எடுப்பதில் பங்கு பெற்றதாக கூறப்படும் நபர்களின் பெயர்கள்;",
        "• அறிவிப்பின் தேதி மற்றும் நேரம் உட்பட உத்தேசிக்கப்பட்ட கூட்டத்தை கூட்டுவதற்கான அறிவிப்பு தொடர்பான விவரங்கள்;",
        "• SLPP இன் அரசியலமைப்பின் ஏற்பாடு, அதன் அடிப்படையில் இந்த கூறப்பட்ட முடிவு எடுக்கப்பட்டது.",
        "ஸ்ரீலங்கா பொதுஜன பெரமுனவின் பாராளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர் டலஸ் அழகப்பெரும நேற்று ஜனாதிபதி தேர்தலில் போட்டியிடுவதாக அறிவித்ததையடுத்து, தற்போது வெற்றிடமாக உள்ள பதவிக்கு புதிய ஜனாதிபதியை தெரிவு செய்வதற்காக எதிர்வரும் ஜூலை 20 ஆம் திகதி நடைபெறவுள்ள பாராளுமன்ற வாக்கெடுப்பில், பதில் ஜனாதிபதி ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்கவை வேட்பாளராக கட்சி ஆதரிக்கும் என காரியவசம் தெரிவித்திருந்தார். ."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "காரியவசம்",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "ரணில்",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "பொதுஜன பெரமுன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜி.எல். பெரிஸ்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "சாகர காரியவசம்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "காரியவசம்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "பீரிஸ்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "டலஸ் அழகப்பெரும",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "நேற்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "காரியவசம்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜூலை 20",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}