{
  "newspaper_id": "news-first-lk",
  "url": "https://www.newsfirst.lk/2022/08/02/modi-assures-pm-gunawardena-of-unwavering-support/",
  "time_ut": 1659427500,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Modi assures PM Gunawardena of unwavering support",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Modi assures PM Gunawardena of unwavering support",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); Indian Prime Minister Narendra Modi on Monday (1) assured newly elected Prime Minister Dinesh Gunawardena of India's continued support to the island nation in a congratulatory letter.",
        "He also expressed that he hopes Sri Lanka will witness quick economic recovery ensuring the prosperity and well-being of its people."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "News 1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Indian",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Narendra Modi",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Monday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "1",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Dinesh Gunawardena",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "India",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "මෝදි අගමැති ගුණවර්ධනට නොසැලෙන සහයෝගය සහතික කරයි",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); ඉන්දීය අග්‍රාමාත්‍ය නරේන්ද්‍ර මෝදි සඳුදා (1) අභිනවයෙන් තේරී පත් වූ අග්‍රාමාත්‍ය දිනේෂ් ගුණවර්ධන මහතාට සුබපැතුම් ලිපියක් මගින් දිවයිනේ ජාතියට ඉන්දියාවේ අඛණ්ඩ සහයෝගය ලබා දෙන බවට සහතික විය.",
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකාව සිය ජනතාවගේ සමෘද්ධිය සහ යහපැවැත්ම සහතික කරමින් ඉක්මන් ආර්ථික ප්‍රකෘතියක් අත්කර ගනු ඇතැයි තමා බලාපොරොත්තු වන බව ද ඔහු ප්‍රකාශ කළේය."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "News 1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දීය",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "නරේන්ද්‍ර මෝදි",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "සඳුදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "1",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "දිනේෂ් ගුණවර්ධන",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "பிரதமர் குணவர்தனவிற்கு அசைக்க முடியாத ஆதரவை வழங்குவதாக மோடி உறுதியளித்துள்ளார்",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); இந்தியப் பிரதமர் நரேந்திர மோடி திங்கட்கிழமை (1) திங்கட்கிழமை (1) புதிதாகத் தேர்ந்தெடுக்கப்பட்ட பிரதமர் தினேஷ் குணவர்தன, தீவு தேசத்திற்கு இந்தியாவின் தொடர்ச்சியான ஆதரவை வாழ்த்துக் கடிதத்தில் உறுதியளித்தார்.",
        "இலங்கை மக்களின் செழிப்பு மற்றும் நல்வாழ்வை உறுதி செய்யும் விரைவான பொருளாதார மீட்சியைக் காணும் என நம்புவதாகவும் அவர் தெரிவித்தார்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "News 1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்தியன்",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "நரேந்திர மோடி",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "திங்கட்கிழமை",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "1",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "தினேஷ் குணவர்தன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்தியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}