{
  "newspaper_id": "lankadeepa-lk",
  "url": "https://www.lankadeepa.lk/latest_news/ජපානයෙන්-මෙරටට-ඩොලර්-මිලියන-3-මානුෂීය-ආධාර/1-615746",
  "time_ut": 1656771225,
  "original_lang": "si",
  "original_title": "ජපානයෙන් මෙරටට ඩොලර් මිලියන 3 මානුෂීය ආධාර",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "3 million dollars in humanitarian aid from Japan to this country",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "Taking into account the current situation in Sri Lanka, the Japanese Embassy said that the United States of America is offering 3 million dollars as emergency humanitarian aid to UNICEF and the World Food Program to provide medicines and food that will directly benefit the Sri Lankan people.",
        "The Japanese Embassy said that the reports published in some media regarding the position of the Japanese government on the current economic crisis that Sri Lanka is facing are incorrect and misleading.",
        "The Japanese Embassy stated that Japan has paid close attention to the current difficult economic situation in Sri Lanka and the resulting humanitarian situation.",
        "The Embassy stated that Japan sincerely hopes that this aid will help to overcome the difficulties faced by the people of Sri Lanka, a long-time friend of Japan.",
        "The Japanese Embassy said that it will decide on the future support in consultation with the Sri Lankan government and other development partners, focusing on the progress of the negotiations between Sri Lanka and the International Monetary Fund and the current situation in the country.",
        "The Japanese Embassy stated that Sri Lanka will continue to receive support from Japan."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "3 million dollars",
          "label": "MONEY"
        },
        {
          "text": "Japan",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Japanese",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "the United States of America",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "3 million dollars",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "UNICEF",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the World Food Program",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lankan",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "The Japanese Embassy",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Japanese",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Japanese",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Japan",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Embassy",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Japan",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Japan",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "The Japanese Embassy",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lankan",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the International Monetary Fund",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Japanese",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Japan",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "ජපානයෙන් මෙරටට ඩොලර් මිලියන 3 මානුෂීය ආධාර",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ වත්මන් තත්ත්වය සැලකිල්ලට ගනිමින්, ශ්‍රී ලාංකීය ජනතාවට සෘජුවම ප්‍රතිලාභ සැලසෙන අයුරින් ඖෂධ,ආහාර ලබාදීම සඳහා ඇමෙරිකා එක්සත් ජනපද ඩොලර් මිලියන 3 ක මුදලක් හදිසි මානුෂීය ආධාර ලෙස යුනිසෙෆ් සංවිධානයට සහ ලෝක ආහාර වැඩසටහනට පිරිනමන බව ජපන් තානාපති කාර්යාලය පැවසීය.",
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකාව මුහුණ දී සිටින වත්මන් ආර්ථික අර්බුදය පිළිබඳ ජපාන රජය දරණ ස්ථාවරය සම්බන්ධයෙන් ඇතැම් මාධ්‍ය වල පළවූ වාර්තා නිවැරදි නොවන නොමග යවනසුළු ඒවා බව ජපන් තානාපති කාර්යාලය පැවසුවේය.",
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ වත්මන් දුෂ්කර ආර්ථික තත්ත්වය සහ ඒ හේතුවෙන් ඇති වී තිබෙන මානුෂීය තත්ත්වය පිළිබඳව ජපානය දැඩි අවධානයක් යොමු කර ඇතැයි ජපන් තානාපති කාර්යාලය ප්‍රකාශ කළේය.",
        "ජපානයේ දිගුකාලීන මිතුරෙකු වන ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ, ජනතාව මුහුණ දෙන දුෂ්කරතා මඟහරවා ගැනීමට මෙම ආධාර උපකාර වනු ඇතැයි ජපානය අවංකවම බලාපොරොත්තු වන බව තානාපති කාර්යාලය සඳහන් කළේය.",
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකාව සහ ජාත්‍යන්තර මූල්‍ය අරමුදල අතර සාකච්ඡාවල ප්‍රගතිය සහ මෙරට වත්මන් තත්ත්වය පිළිබඳව අවධානය යොමු කරමින්,ශ්‍රී ලංකා රජය සහ අනෙකුත් සංවර්ධන හවුල්කරුවන් සමඟ සාකච්ඡා කර ඉදිරියට ලබා දෙන සහාය සම්බන්ධයෙන් තීරණය කරන බව ජපන් තානාපති කාර්යාලය පැවසුවේය.",
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවට ඉදිරියටත් ජපානයේ සහාය හිමිවන බව ජපන් තානාපති කාර්යාලය ප්‍රකාශ කළේය."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ඩොලර් මිලියන 3 කි",
          "label": "MONEY"
        },
        {
          "text": "ජපානය",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජපන්",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඇමරිකා එක්සත් ජනපදය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඩොලර් මිලියන 3 කි",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "යුනිසෙෆ්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ලෝක ආහාර වැඩසටහන",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලාංකික",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ජපන් තානාපති කාර්යාලය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජපන්",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ජපන්",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජපානය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "තානාපති කාර්යාලය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජපානය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජපානය",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ජපන් තානාපති කාර්යාලය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලාංකික",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජාත්‍යන්තර මුල්‍ය අරමුදල",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ජපන්",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජපානය",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "இந்த நாட்டுக்கு ஜப்பானில் இருந்து 3 மில்லியன் டாலர் மனிதாபிமான உதவி",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "இலங்கையின் தற்போதைய நிலைமையை கருத்திற்கொண்டு, இலங்கை மக்களுக்கு நேரடியாகப் பயனளிக்கும் மருந்துகளையும் உணவையும் வழங்குவதற்காக யுனிசெப் மற்றும் உலக உணவுத் திட்டத்திற்கு அமெரிக்கா 3 மில்லியன் டொலர்களை அவசர மனிதாபிமான உதவியாக வழங்குவதாக ஜப்பானிய தூதரகம் தெரிவித்துள்ளது.",
        "இலங்கை எதிர்கொள்ளும் தற்போதைய பொருளாதார நெருக்கடி தொடர்பில் ஜப்பானிய அரசாங்கத்தின் நிலைப்பாடு தொடர்பில் சில ஊடகங்களில் வெளியாகியுள்ள செய்திகள் தவறானவை மற்றும் தவறானவை என ஜப்பானிய தூதரகம் தெரிவித்துள்ளது.",
        "இலங்கையின் தற்போதைய கடினமான பொருளாதார நிலைமை மற்றும் அதனால் ஏற்பட்டுள்ள மனிதாபிமான நிலைமைகள் தொடர்பில் ஜப்பான் உன்னிப்பாக அவதானம் செலுத்தியுள்ளதாக ஜப்பானிய தூதரகம் குறிப்பிட்டுள்ளது.",
        "ஜப்பானின் நீண்டகால நண்பரான இலங்கை மக்கள் எதிர்நோக்கும் சிரமங்களை போக்க இந்த உதவி உதவும் என ஜப்பான் உண்மையாக நம்புவதாக தூதரகம் தெரிவித்துள்ளது.",
        "இலங்கைக்கும் சர்வதேச நாணய நிதியத்துக்கும் இடையிலான பேச்சுவார்த்தைகளின் முன்னேற்றம் மற்றும் நாட்டின் தற்போதைய நிலைமை குறித்து கவனம் செலுத்தி இலங்கை அரசாங்கம் மற்றும் ஏனைய அபிவிருத்தி பங்காளிகளுடன் கலந்துரையாடி எதிர்கால ஆதரவை தீர்மானிக்கவுள்ளதாக ஜப்பானிய தூதரகம் தெரிவித்துள்ளது.",
        "ஜப்பானின் ஆதரவை இலங்கை தொடர்ந்தும் பெறும் என ஜப்பானிய தூதரகம் தெரிவித்துள்ளது."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "3 மில்லியன் டாலர்கள்",
          "label": "MONEY"
        },
        {
          "text": "ஜப்பான்",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜப்பானியர்",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஐக்கிய அமெரிக்கா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "3 மில்லியன் டாலர்கள்",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "யுனிசெஃப்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "உலக உணவு திட்டம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஜப்பானிய தூதரகம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜப்பானியர்",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஜப்பானியர்",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜப்பான்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "தூதரகம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜப்பான்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜப்பான்",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஜப்பானிய தூதரகம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சர்வதேச நாணய நிதியம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஜப்பானியர்",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜப்பான்",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}