{
  "newspaper_id": "economy-next-com",
  "url": "https://economynext.com/sri-lanka-mp-comes-with-saline-to-cast-a-presidential-vote-97708/",
  "time_ut": 1658299860,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Sri Lanka MP comes with saline to cast a presidential vote",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Sri Lanka MP comes with saline to cast a presidential vote",
      "author": "Neshella Perera",
      "body_lines": [
        "ECONOMYNEXT- Samanpriya Herath, a legislator from Sri Lanka Podujana Perumana (SLPP) casted his vote at the parliament whilst receiving saline carried by an aide, the live telecast visual showed on Wednesday.",
        "Sri Lanka MPs are in the process of electing a new president after former leader Gotabaya Rajapaksa fled the country and resigned last week plunging the country into a deep political crisis.",
        "Secretary General of Sri Lanka’s Parliament, Dhammika Dasanayake asked the house, “Samanpriya Herath will be given the chance to place his vote ahead of the list because he is ill and will resume the election at the scheduled order.”",
        "The Members of Parliament agreed to give the Herath the chance to place his vote and was allowed to cast his vote against the name list of parliamentarians.",
        "Herath who cast his vote whilst receiving saline was pardoned to leave to hospital for treatment.",
        "D Weerasingha, another MP from Sri Lanka Podujana Perumana (SLPP) was also given the chance to place his vote for the election due to sickness, to which the house agreed to. (Colombo/Jul20/2022)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ECONOMYNEXT- Samanpriya Herath",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Podujana Perumana",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Wednesday",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Gotabaya Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "last week",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka’s",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Dhammika Dasanayake",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "D Weerasingha",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Podujana Perumana",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "ශ්‍රී ලංකා මන්ත්‍රීවරයෙක් සේලයින් රැගෙන ජනපතිවරණයට පැමිණේ",
      "author": "නෙෂෙල්ලා පෙරේරා",
      "body_lines": [
        "ආර්ථිකය- ශ්‍රී ලංකා පොදුජන පෙරමුණේ (SLPP) මන්ත්‍රීවරයෙකු වන සමන්ප්‍රිය හේරත්, සහායකයකු විසින් සේලයින් රැගෙන යමින් සිටියදී පාර්ලිමේන්තුවේදී ඡන්දය ප්‍රකාශ කළ බව සජීවී විකාශන දසුන බදාදා පෙන්වීය.",
        "හිටපු නායක ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ රටින් පැන ගොස් පසුගිය සතියේ ඉල්ලා අස්වීමෙන් පසු රට ගැඹුරු දේශපාලන අර්බුදයකට ඇද දැමීමෙන් පසු ශ්‍රී ලංකා මන්ත්‍රීවරුන් නව ජනාධිපතිවරයකු තෝරා ගැනීමේ ක්‍රියාවලියක යෙදී සිටිති.",
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකා පාර්ලිමේන්තුවේ මහලේකම් ධම්මික දසනායක මන්ත්‍රීවරයා සභාවෙන් ඉල්ලා සිටියේ “සමන්ප්‍රිය හේරත් අසනීපයෙන් පසුවන නිසා ඔහුගේ ඡන්දය ලැයිස්තුවට වඩා ඉදිරියෙන් තැබීමට ඔහුට අවස්ථාව ලබා දෙන අතර නියමිත නියෝගයට අනුව මැතිවරණය ආරම්භ කරන” බවයි.",
        "හේරත් මහතාට ඡන්දය ප්‍රකාශ කිරීමට අවස්ථාව ලබාදීමට මන්ත්‍රීවරු එකඟ වූ අතර මන්ත්‍රීවරුන්ගේ නාම ලේඛනයට විරුද්ධව ඡන්දය ප්‍රකාශ කිරීමටද මන්ත්‍රීවරු අවසර දුන්හ.",
        "සේලයින් ලබා ගනිමින් ඡන්දය ප්‍රකාශ කළ හේරත්ට ප්‍රතිකාර සඳහා රෝහලට යාමට සමාව හිමි විය.",
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකා පොදුජන පෙරමුණේ (SLPP) තවත් මන්ත්‍රීවරයෙකු වන ඩී වීරසිංහ මහතාට ද අසනීප තත්ත්වයක් හේතුවෙන් මැතිවරණය සඳහා ඡන්දය ප්‍රකාශ කිරීමට අවස්ථාව ලබා දුන් අතර ඊට සභාව එකඟ විය. (කොළඹ/ජූලි20/2022)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ECONOMYNEXT- සමන්ප්‍රිය හේරත්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "පොදුජන පෙරුමනා",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "බදාදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගිය සතිය",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ධම්මික දසනායක",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "ඩී වීරසිංහ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "පොදුජන පෙරුමනා",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "ஜனாதிபதி தேர்தலில் வாக்களிக்க இலங்கை எம்.பி",
      "author": "நெஷெல்லா பெரேரா",
      "body_lines": [
        "பொருளாதாரம்- ஸ்ரீலங்கா பொதுஜன பெருமானின் (SLPP) சட்டமன்ற உறுப்பினர் சமன்பிரியா ஹேரத் பாராளுமன்றத்தில் வாக்களித்தார், அதே நேரத்தில் ஒரு உதவியாளரால் உமிழ்நீரை எடுத்துச் சென்றார், நேரடி ஒளிபரப்பு காட்சி புதன்கிழமை காட்டியது.",
        "இலங்கையின் முன்னாள் தலைவர் கோத்தபய ராஜபக்ச நாட்டை விட்டு வெளியேறி கடந்த வாரம் ராஜினாமா செய்ததையடுத்து புதிய அதிபரை தேர்ந்தெடுக்கும் பணியில் இலங்கை எம்பிக்கள் ஈடுபட்டுள்ளனர்.",
        "இலங்கை நாடாளுமன்றத்தின் பொதுச் செயலாளர் தம்மிக்க தசநாயக்க, “சமன்பிரிய ஹேரத் உடல்நிலை சரியில்லாமல் இருப்பதால், அவரது வாக்குகளை பட்டியலில் முன்னிலைப்படுத்த அவருக்கு வாய்ப்பு வழங்கப்படும் என்றும், திட்டமிட்டபடி தேர்தலை மீண்டும் தொடங்குவார்” என்றும் சபையில் கேட்டுள்ளார்.",
        "ஹேரத்துக்கு வாக்களிக்கும் வாய்ப்பை வழங்குவதற்கு நாடாளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர்கள் இணக்கம் தெரிவித்ததுடன், நாடாளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர்களின் பெயர் பட்டியலுக்கு எதிராக வாக்களிக்க அனுமதிக்கப்பட்டனர்.",
        "சேலைன் வாங்கிக் கொண்டு வாக்களித்த ஹேரத், சிகிச்சைக்காக மருத்துவமனைக்குச் செல்ல மன்னிக்கப்பட்டார்.",
        "ஸ்ரீலங்கா பொதுஜன பெருமான (SLPP) இன் மற்றுமொரு பாராளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர் டி வீரசிங்கவுக்கும் சுகவீனம் காரணமாக தேர்தலில் வாக்களிக்க வாய்ப்பு வழங்கப்பட்டது, அதற்கு சபை ஒப்புக்கொண்டது. (கொழும்பு/ஜூலை20/2022)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "பொருளாதாரம்- சமன்பிரியா ஹேரத்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "பொதுஜன பெருமானா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "புதன்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "கடந்த வாரம்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கையின்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "தம்மிக்க தசநாயக்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "டி வீரசிங்க",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "பொதுஜன பெருமானா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}