{
  "newspaper_id": "daily-mirror-lk",
  "url": "https://www.dailymirror.lk/breaking_news/Main-suspect-in-Bastian-Mawatha-shooting-killed-in-police-confrontation/108-240303",
  "time_ut": 1656914186,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Main suspect in Bastian Mawatha shooting killed in police confrontation",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Main suspect in Bastian Mawatha shooting killed in police confrontation",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "The main suspect in the recent shooting incident at Bastian Mawatha in Pettah, in which a man was shot to death and another injured, has been shot dead by police during a shootout at Bemmulla.",
        "Police said the suspect who died in the exchange of gunfire was identified as a main accomplice of the notorious underworld gangster known as ‘Ganemulla Sanjeewa’",
        "They said the suspect fled in a motorcycle when police tried to apprehend him.",
        "However, the suspect opened fire at the policemen and when the policemen returned fire, the suspect reported to have died.",
        "A 30-year-old man died and another one was injured when unidentified men came in a motorcycle and shot at them at Bastian Mawatha, Pettah during broad daylight on May 30.(DSB)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Bastian Mawatha",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Bastian Mawatha",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Pettah",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Bemmulla",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "30-year-old",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Bastian Mawatha",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Pettah",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "May 30.(DSB",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "බැස්ටියන් මාවතේ වෙඩි තැබීමේ ප්‍රධාන සැකකරු පොලිස් ගැටුමකින් මරුට",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "පසුගියදා පිටකොටුව බැස්ටියන් මාවතේ වෙඩි තැබීමකින් පුද්ගලයෙකු මිය ගොස් තවත් අයෙකු තුවාල ලබා ඇති වෙඩි තැබීමේ සිද්ධියේ ප්‍රධාන සැකකරු බෙම්මුල්ල ප්‍රදේශයේ ඇති වූ වෙඩි හුවමාරුවකදී පොලිස් වෙඩි පහරින් මිය ගොස් තිබේ.",
        "වෙඩි හුවමාරුවේදී මියගිය සැකකරු ‘ගණේමුල්ල සංජීව’ නමැති කුප්‍රකට පාතාල කල්ලියේ ප්‍රධාන ගෝලයකු බවට හඳුනාගෙන ඇති බව පොලිසිය පවසයි.",
        "පොලිසිය ඔහු අත්අඩංගුවට ගැනීමට උත්සාහ කිරීමේදී සැකකරු යතුරුපැදියකින් පලා ගිය බව ඔවුහු පැවසූහ.",
        "කෙසේ වෙතත්, සැකකරු පොලිස් නිලධාරීන්ට වෙඩි තබා ඇති අතර, පොලිස් නිලධාරීන් ආපසු වෙඩි තැබීමත් සමඟ සැකකරු මිය ගොස් ඇති බව වාර්තා වේ.",
        "මැයි 30 වැනිදා මහ දවල් පිටකොටුව බැස්ටියන් මාවතේදී නාඳුනන පුද්ගලයන් යතුරුපැදියකින් පැමිණ වෙඩි තැබීමකින් 30 හැවිරිදි පුද්ගලයකු මිය ගොස් තවත් අයෙක් තුවාල ලබා ඇත.(DSB)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "බැස්ටියන් මාවත",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "බැස්ටියන් මාවත",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "පිටකොටුව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "බෙම්මුල්ල",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "30 හැවිරිදිය",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "බැස්ටියන් මාවත",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "පිටකොටුව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මැයි 30. (DSB",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "பாஸ்டியன் மாவத்தை துப்பாக்கிச் சூட்டுச் சம்பவத்தின் பிரதான சந்தேக நபர் பொலிஸ் மோதலில் கொல்லப்பட்டார்",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "பெம்முல்லையில் இடம்பெற்ற துப்பாக்கிச் சூட்டின் போது, ​​அண்மையில் பெட்டா, பஸ்டியன் மாவத்தையில் இடம்பெற்ற துப்பாக்கிச் சூட்டுச் சம்பவத்தில் ஒருவர் சுட்டுக் கொல்லப்பட்டதுடன் மற்றுமொருவர் காயமடைந்த நிலையில், பிரதான சந்தேக நபர் பொலிஸாரால் சுட்டுக் கொல்லப்பட்டுள்ளார்.",
        "துப்பாக்கிச் சண்டையில் உயிரிழந்த சந்தேக நபர் ‘கனேமுல்ல சஞ்சீவ’ எனப்படும் பிரபல பாதாள உலகக் கும்பலின் பிரதான கூட்டாளி என அடையாளம் காணப்பட்டுள்ளதாக பொலிஸார் தெரிவித்தனர்.",
        "பொலிஸார் அவரைப் பிடிக்க முற்பட்ட போது சந்தேக நபர் மோட்டார் சைக்கிளில் தப்பிச் சென்றதாக அவர்கள் தெரிவித்தனர்.",
        "எவ்வாறாயினும், சந்தேக நபர் பொலிஸாரை நோக்கி துப்பாக்கிச் சூடு நடத்தியதாகவும், பொலிஸார் திருப்பிச் சுட்டதில் சந்தேக நபர் உயிரிழந்துள்ளதாகவும் தெரிவிக்கப்பட்டுள்ளது.",
        "மே 30 அன்று பட்டப்பகலில் பெட்டா, பாஸ்டியன் மாவத்தையில் அடையாளம் தெரியாத நபர்கள் மோட்டார் சைக்கிளில் வந்து அவர்கள் மீது துப்பாக்கிச் சூடு நடத்தியதில் 30 வயதுடைய ஒருவர் உயிரிழந்தார் மேலும் ஒருவர் காயமடைந்தார்.(டிஎஸ்பி)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "பாஸ்டியன் மாவத்தை",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "பாஸ்டியன் மாவத்தை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "பெட்டா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "பெம்முல்லா",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "30 வயது",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாஸ்டியன் மாவத்தை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "பெட்டா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "மே 30.(டி.எஸ்.பி",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}