{
  "newspaper_id": "ada-lk",
  "url": "https://www.ada.lk/breaking_news/මන්නාරමේ-සිට-ඉන්දියාවට-ගිය-අඹු-සැමි-යුවල-මරුට/11-395083",
  "time_ut": 1656925414,
  "original_lang": "si",
  "original_title": "මන්නාරමේ සිට ඉන්දියාවට ගිය අඹු සැමි යුවල මරුට",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Married couple who went to India from Mannar died",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "An elderly couple who went to Dhanushkodi in India from Mannar and fell unconscious on the seashore died yesterday (03) while receiving treatment, Indian security officials say.",
        "On the 27th of June last, the husband and wife couple went from Mannar to Dhanushkodi in India by means of a small boat when they fainted and fell on the beach due to overexertion.",
        "The Indian media had reported that the husband and wife, 67-year-old Parameshwari and 74-year-old Sivan, residents of Murungan area of ​​Mannar, first died while receiving treatment, followed by the wife after 4 hours.",
        "It is also reported that the hospital doctors said that the bodies of the deceased were severely weakened due to fasting and the bodies have been sent for post-mortem examination.",
        "However, while the couple is receiving treatment, it is also reported that several local authorities have come to the hospital and inquired about the patient's condition, and the Indian authorities have not yet made a statement about the manner in which the last rites of the elderly couple will be carried out."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "India",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "Mannar",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "India",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Mannar",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "yesterday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "03",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Indian",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the 27th of June last",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Mannar to Dhanushkodi",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "India",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Indian",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "67-year-old",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parameshwari",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "74-year-old",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sivan",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Murungan",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "​​Mannar",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "4 hours",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "Indian",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "මන්නාරමේ සිට ඉන්දියාවට ගිය අඹු සැමි යුවල මරුට",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "මන්නාරමේ සිට ඉන්දියාවේ ධනුෂ්කොඩි වෙතට ගොස් සිහිසුන්ව මුහුදු වෙරලේ වැටී සිටි වයෝවෘද්ධ අඹුසැමි යුවල ප්‍රතිකාර ලබමින් සිටියදී ඊයේ (03දා)  මිය ගොස් ඇතැයි ඉන්දීය වෙරලාරක්ෂක නිලධාරීන් පවසති.",
        "පසුගිය ජුනි මස 27 වනදා මෙම අඹුසැමි යුවල මන්නාරමේ සිට කුඩා යාත්‍රාවක් මාර්ගයෙන් ඉන්දියාවේ ධනුෂ්කොඩි වෙතට ගොස් සිටියදී අධික වෙහෙසකාරී තත්ත්වය හේතුවෙන් සිහිමුර්ජා වී වෙරලේ වැටී සිටියදී ඉන්දීය වෙරලාරක්ෂක නිලධාරීන් විසින් වහා ක්‍රියාත්මක වී එම යුවල රාමනාදපුරම් රජයේ රෝහලට ඇතුලත් කොට ප්‍රතිකාර ලබාදීමට පියවර ගෙන තිබුණි.",
        "මන්නාරම මුරුංගන් ප්‍රදේශයේ පදිංචි 67 හැවිරිදි පරමේෂෟවරී සහ 74 හැවිරිදි සිවන් යන අඹු සැමි යුවල ප්‍රතිකාර ලබමින් සිටයදී පළමුව සැමියා මිය ගොස් ඇති අතර පසුව පැය 4 කට පුසව බිරිඳද මිය ගොස් ඇතැයි ඉන්දීය මාධ්‍ය වාර්ථා කොට තිබුණි.",
        "මිය ගිය අය නිරාහාරව සිටීම මත සිරුර දැඩි සේ දුර්වල වී තිබූ බවටද රෝහල් වෛද්‍යවරුන් පවසා ඇති අතර මළසිරුරු පශ්චාත් මරණ පරික්ෂණය සඳහා යොමු කොට ඇතැයිද වාර්ථා වෙයි.",
        "කෙසේ වෙතත් මෙම අඹුසැමි යුවල ප්‍රතිකාර ලබමින් සිටින අතරවාරයේදී රෝහල වෙතට එරට බලධාරීන් කිහිප දෙනෙකුද පැමිණ රෝගි තත්වය පිළිබඳ විමසා ඇතැයිද වාර්ථා වන අතර වයෝවෘද්ද අඹුසැමි යුවලගේ අවසන් කටයුතු සිදුකරන ආකාරයක් පිළිබඳව මෙතෙක් ඉන්දීය බලධාරීන් ප්‍රකාශයක් සිදුකොට නොමැත."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ඉන්දියාව",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "මන්නාරම",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මන්නාරම",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඊයේ",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "03",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දීය",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "පසුගිය ජුනි 27 වැනිදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මන්නාරම සිට ධනුෂ්කොඩි දක්වා",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දීය",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "67 හැවිරිදිය",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parameshwari",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "74 හැවිරිදිය",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "සිවන්",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මුරුංගන්",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මන්නාරම",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "පැය 4",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දීය",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "மன்னாரில் இருந்து இந்தியா சென்ற தம்பதியர் உயிரிழந்துள்ளனர்",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "மன்னாரிலிருந்து இந்தியாவின் தனுஷ்கோடிக்கு சென்று கடலோரத்தில் மயங்கி வீழ்ந்த வயோதிப தம்பதியினர் சிகிச்சை பெற்று வந்த நிலையில் நேற்று (03) உயிரிழந்துள்ளதாக இந்திய பாதுகாப்பு அதிகாரிகள் தெரிவித்துள்ளனர்.",
        "கடந்த ஜூன் மாதம் 27ஆம் திகதி மன்னாரிலிருந்து இந்தியாவிலுள்ள தனுஷ்கோடிக்கு சிறிய படகு மூலம் சென்ற கணவன், மனைவி தம்பதியினர் அதிக வேலைப்பளு காரணமாக கடற்கரையில் மயங்கி விழுந்தனர்.",
        "மன்னார் முருங்கன் பகுதியைச் சேர்ந்த 67 வயதான பரமேஸ்வரி மற்றும் 74 வயதான சிவன் ஆகியோர் சிகிச்சை பெற்று வந்த நிலையில் முதலில் உயிரிழந்ததாகவும், 4 மணித்தியாலங்களின் பின்னர் மனைவியும் உயிரிழந்துள்ளதாக இந்திய ஊடகங்கள் செய்தி வெளியிட்டுள்ளன.",
        "உண்ணாவிரதத்தால் உயிரிழந்தவர்களின் உடல்கள் பலத்த பலவீனமடைந்துள்ளதாகவும், சடலங்கள் பிரேத பரிசோதனைக்காக அனுப்பி வைக்கப்பட்டுள்ளதாகவும் வைத்தியசாலை வைத்தியர்கள் தெரிவித்துள்ளதாகவும் தெரிவிக்கப்படுகின்றது.",
        "இருப்பினும், தம்பதியினர் சிகிச்சை பெற்று வரும் நிலையில், பல உள்ளூர் அதிகாரிகள் மருத்துவமனைக்கு வந்து நோயாளியின் உடல்நிலை குறித்து விசாரித்து வருவதாகவும், இந்திய அதிகாரிகள் இறுதி சடங்குகள் நடந்த விதம் குறித்து இதுவரை எந்த அறிக்கையும் வெளியிடவில்லை என்றும் கூறப்படுகிறது. வயதான தம்பதிகள் நடத்தப்படுவார்கள்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "இந்தியா",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "மன்னார்",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "இந்தியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "மன்னார்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "நேற்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "03",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்தியன்",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "கடந்த ஜூன் மாதம் 27ம் தேதி",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "மன்னார் முதல் தனுஷ்கோடி வரை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்தியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இந்தியன்",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "67 வயது",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parameshwari",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "74 வயதானவர்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சிவன்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "முருங்கன்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "மன்னார்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "4 மணி நேரம்",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "இந்தியன்",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}