{
  "newspaper_id": "daily-ft-lk",
  "url": "https://www.ft.lk/news/Sajith-donates-scarce-medicine-worth-Rs-15-6-m-fulfilling-the-pledge/56-737145",
  "time_ut": 1657148421,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Sajith donates scarce medicine worth Rs. 15.6 m fulfilling the pledge",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Sajith donates scarce medicine worth Rs. 15.6 m fulfilling the pledge",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "Opposition Leader Sajith Premadasa yesterday said that neither he nor the Samagi Jana Balawegaya (SJB) or the Samagi Jana Sandhanaya have any “no” or “can’t” talk and will fulfill their responsibilities for the people at any time.",
        "Donating a stock of scarce medicines, the Opposition Leader said the ‘Jana Suwaya’ and ‘Samagi Jana Balawegayen Husmak’ programs are implemented with a view of creating a healthy nation.",
        "Specialist Dr. Anver Hamdanihas earlier informed the Opposition Leader about the acute shortage of Recombinant Streptokinase (IP 1500000IU) which is an essential medicine for heart diseases.",
        "The Prime Minister pointed out the shortage of the aforementioned medicine and requested SJB to provide them through the “Husmak” Program.",
        "“As a fruition of our efforts to find these medicines, 4000 units of Recombinant Streptokinase for Injection (I.P.15000001U) worth Rs. 15.6 million (42,840 USD) were donated to Dr. Anver Hamdani under full patronage of Mr. Nayana Wasalatilake, Executive Coordinator for the Leader of the Opposition,” SJB leader said.",
        "Recombinant Streptokinase is a drug that is essential to save the lives of heart patients battling between life and death.",
        "‘Samagi Jana Balawegayen Husmak’ program is implemented by the group of Members of Parliament, organisers, members, foreign branches, local and foreign donors of Samagi Jana Balawegaya in collaboration with ‘Jana Suwaya’ Project in order to provide health relief to people struggling for their lives.",
        "“We have a huge responsibility to secure the lives of people in this country and we are ready to fulfill it whenever possible,” the Opposition Leader emphasised."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "15.6",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Sajith Premadasa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "yesterday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Samagi Jana Balawegaya",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Opposition",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Jana Suwaya",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Jana Balawegayen Husmak",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Specialist",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Anver Hamdanihas",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Opposition",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Recombinant Streptokinase",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "IP",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "1500000IU",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "4000",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Recombinant Streptokinase for Injection",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "15.6 million",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "42,840 USD",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "Anver Hamdani",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Nayana",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Opposition",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "Samagi Jana Balawegayen Husmak",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Samagi Jana Balawegaya",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Jana Suwaya’ Project",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Opposition",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "සජිත් රුපියල් ලක්ෂයක හිඟ බෙහෙත් පරිත්‍යාග කරයි. පොරොන්දුව ඉටු කරමින් මීටර් 15.6 කි",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "තමාට හෝ සමගි ජන බලවේගයට හෝ සමගි ජන සන්ධානයට \"නෑ\" \"බෑ\" කතාවක් නැති බවත්, ජනතාව වෙනුවෙන් තම වගකීම් ඕනෑම අවස්ථාවක ඉටු කරන බවත් විපක්ෂ නායක සජිත් ප්‍රේමදාස මහතා ඊයේ ප්‍රකාශ කළේය.",
        "හිඟ ඖෂධ තොගයක් පරිත්‍යාග කරමින් විපක්ෂ නායකවරයා කියා සිටියේ සෞඛ්‍ය සම්පන්න ජාතියක් බිහිකිරීමේ අරමුණින් ‘ජන සුවය’ සහ ‘සමගි ජන බලවේගයෙන් හුස්මක්’ වැඩසටහන් ක්‍රියාත්මක කරන බවයි.",
        "හෘද රෝග සඳහා අත්‍යවශ්‍ය ඖෂධයක් වන Recombinant Streptokinase (IP 1500000IU) හි උග්‍ර හිඟය පිළිබඳව විශේෂඥ වෛද්‍ය අන්වර් හම්දානිහස් මහතා මීට පෙර විපක්ෂ නායකවරයා දැනුවත් කළේය.",
        "අග්‍රාමාත්‍යවරයා ඉහත සඳහන් ඖෂධ හිඟය පෙන්වා දුන් අතර “හුස්මාක්” වැඩසටහන හරහා ඒවා ලබාදෙන ලෙස SJB ගෙන් ඉල්ලා සිටියේය.",
        "“මෙම ඖෂධ සොයා ගැනීමට අප දරන උත්සාහයේ ප්‍රතිඵලයක් ලෙස, රු. විපක්ෂ නායක විධායක සම්බන්ධීකාරක නයනා වාසලතිලක මහතාගේ පූර්ණ අනුග්‍රහය යටතේ වෛද්‍ය අන්වර් හම්දානි වෙත රුපියල් මිලියන 15.6ක් (ඇ.ඩො. 42,840) පරිත්‍යාග කරන ලදී.",
        "Recombinant Streptokinase යනු ජීවිතයත් මරණයත් අතර සටන් කරන හෘද රෝගීන්ගේ ජීවිත බේරා ගැනීමට අත්‍යවශ්‍ය ඖෂධයකි.",
        "'සමගි ජන බලවේගයෙන් හුස්මක්' වැඩසටහන පාර්ලිමේන්තු මන්ත්‍රීවරුන්, සංවිධායකයින්, සාමාජිකයින්, විදේශීය ශාඛාවන්, සමගි ජන බලවේගයේ දෙස් විදෙස් පරිත්‍යාගශීලීන් එක්ව 'ජන සුවය' ව්‍යාපෘතිය සමඟ එක්ව ක්‍රියාත්මක කරනු ලබන්නේ සෞඛ්‍ය සහන සැලසීමේ අරමුණින්. ඔවුන්ගේ ජිවිත.",
        "මේ රටේ ජනතාවගේ ජීවිත සුරක්ෂිත කිරීමේ විශාල වගකීමක් අපට තිබෙන බවත්, හැකි සෑම විටම එය ඉටු කිරීමට අපි සූදානම් බවත් විපක්ෂ නායකවරයා අවධාරණය කළේය."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "15.6",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "සජිත් ප්‍රේමදාස",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඊයේ",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "සමගි ජන බලවේගය",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "විපක්ෂ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජන සුවය",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජන බලවේගයෙන් Husmak",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "විශේෂඥ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "අන්වර් හම්දානිහාස්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "විපක්ෂ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Recombinant Streptokinase",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "IP",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "1500000IU",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "4000",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "එන්නත් කිරීම සඳහා Recombinant Streptokinase",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "මිලියන 15.6 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "42,840 USD",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "අන්වර් හම්දානි",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "නයනා",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "විපක්ෂ",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "සමගි ජන බලවේගයෙන් හුස්මක්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "සමගි ජන බලවේගය",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජන සුවය ව්‍යාපෘතිය",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "විපක්ෂ",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "சஜித் ரூபாய் மதிப்புள்ள அரிதான மருந்தை வழங்கினார். உறுதிமொழியை நிறைவேற்றும் 15.6 மீ",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "தானோ அல்லது சமகி ஜன பலவேகயவோ அல்லது சமகி ஜன சந்தனயோ \"வேண்டாம்\" அல்லது \"முடியாது\" என்ற பேச்சுக்கே இடமில்லை என்றும் மக்களுக்கான தங்கள் பொறுப்புகளை எந்த நேரத்திலும் நிறைவேற்றுவோம் என்றும் எதிர்க்கட்சித் தலைவர் சஜித் பிரேமதாச நேற்று தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "பற்றாக்குறையான மருந்துப் பொருட்களை நன்கொடையாக வழங்கிய எதிர்க்கட்சித் தலைவர், ஆரோக்கியமான தேசத்தை உருவாக்கும் நோக்கில் ‘ஜன சுயய’ மற்றும் ‘சமகி ஜன பலவேகயென் ஹஸ்மாக்’ திட்டங்கள் நடைமுறைப்படுத்தப்படுவதாகத் தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "இதய நோய்களுக்கு இன்றியமையாத மருந்தான Recombinant Streptokinase (IP 1500000IU) இன் கடுமையான பற்றாக்குறை குறித்து நிபுணர் டாக்டர் அன்வர் ஹம்தானிஹாஸ் எதிர்க்கட்சித் தலைவருக்கு முன்னதாக தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "மேற்கூறிய மருந்தின் பற்றாக்குறையை சுட்டிக்காட்டிய பிரதமர், “ஹஸ்மாக்” திட்டத்தின் மூலம் அவற்றை வழங்குமாறு SJBயிடம் கோரிக்கை விடுத்தார்.",
        "“இந்த மருந்துகளைக் கண்டுபிடிப்பதற்கான எங்கள் முயற்சியின் பலனாக, ரூ. மதிப்புள்ள ஊசிக்கான 4000 யூனிட் ரீகாம்பினன்ட் ஸ்ட்ரெப்டோகினேஸ் (I.P.15000001U) 15.6 மில்லியன் (42,840 USD) டொக்டர் அன்வர் ஹம்தானிக்கு எதிர்க்கட்சித் தலைவரின் நிறைவேற்று ஒருங்கிணைப்பாளர் திரு. நயன வாசலதிலக அவர்களின் முழு அனுசரணையின் கீழ் நன்கொடையாக வழங்கப்பட்டது,” என்று SJB தலைவர் கூறினார்.",
        "ரீகாம்பினன்ட் ஸ்ட்ரெப்டோகைனேஸ் (Recombinant Streptokinase) என்பது உயிருக்கும் சாவுக்கும் இடையில் போராடும் இதய நோயாளிகளின் உயிரைக் காப்பாற்ற இன்றியமையாத ஒரு மருந்து.",
        "'சமகி ஜன பலவேகயென் ஹஸ்மாக்' திட்டம் நாடாளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர்கள், அமைப்பாளர்கள், உறுப்பினர்கள், வெளிநாட்டுக் கிளைகள், உள்நாட்டு மற்றும் வெளிநாட்டு நன்கொடையாளர்கள் ஆகியோரால் 'ஜன சுயய' திட்டத்துடன் இணைந்து போராடும் மக்களுக்கு சுகாதார நிவாரணம் வழங்குவதற்காக செயல்படுத்தப்படுகிறது. அவர்களுடைய வாழ்க்கை.",
        "இந்த நாட்டிலுள்ள மக்களின் வாழ்க்கையைப் பாதுகாப்பதில் எமக்கு பாரிய பொறுப்பு உள்ளது என்றும், முடிந்தவரை அதனை நிறைவேற்றுவதற்கு நாங்கள் தயாராக உள்ளோம் என்றும் எதிர்க்கட்சித் தலைவர் வலியுறுத்தினார்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "15.6",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "சஜித் பிரேமதாச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "நேற்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சமகி ஜன பலவேகயா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "எதிர்ப்பு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜனா சுவாயா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜனா பலவேகயென் ஹஸ்மாக்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "நிபுணர்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "அன்வர் ஹம்தானிஹாஸ்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "எதிர்ப்பு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "மறுசீரமைப்பு ஸ்ட்ரெப்டோகினேஸ்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஐபி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "1500000IU",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "4000",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "உட்செலுத்தலுக்கான மறுசீரமைப்பு ஸ்ட்ரெப்டோகைனேஸ்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "15.6 மில்லியன்",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "42,840 அமெரிக்க டாலர்",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "அன்வர் ஹம்தானி",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "நயனா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "எதிர்ப்பு",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "சமகி ஜன பலவேகயென் ஹஸ்மாக்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "சமகி ஜன பலவேகயா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜன சுயயா' திட்டம்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "எதிர்ப்பு",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}