{
  "newspaper_id": "daily-mirror-lk",
  "url": "https://www.dailymirror.lk/latest_news/SL-envoy-woos-Chinese-investment-in-solar-wind-energy/342-243918",
  "time_ut": 1661743412,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "SL envoy woos Chinese investment in solar, wind energy",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "SL envoy woos Chinese investment in solar, wind energy",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "Sri Lankan Ambassador to China Dr. Palitha Kohona said Sri Lanka is an ideal spot for solar energy development and also wind energy development and China can be a big help as we transition to clean energy.",
        "“We would be able to address a huge part of our energy crisis by relying on renewable energy,” he said, according to the Chinese media.",
        "The 2022 World Conference on Clean Energy Equipment is underway in Southwest China’s Sichuan Province.",
        "More than 18 hundred guests from 17 countries and regions are taking part in the event to discuss the development and future of the clean energy equipment industry, according to CGTN."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Chinese",
          "label": "NORP"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lankan",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "China",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Palitha Kohona",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "China",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Chinese",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "2022",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "World Conference",
            "label": "EVENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "Southwest China’s",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sichuan Province",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "More than 18 hundred",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "17",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "ශ්‍රී ලංකා නියෝජිතයා සූර්ය, සුළං බලශක්ති සඳහා චීන ආයෝජන ආකර්ෂණය කරයි",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "චීනයේ ශ්‍රී ලංකා තානාපති ආචාර්ය පාලිත කොහොන මහතා පැවසුවේ ශ්‍රී ලංකාව සූර්ය බලශක්ති සංවර්ධනයට මෙන්ම සුළං බලශක්ති සංවර්ධනයට ද කදිම ස්ථානයක් බවත් අපි පිරිසිදු බලශක්තියට සංක්‍රමණය වීමේදී චීනයට විශාල පිටිවහලක් විය හැකි බවත්ය.",
        "\"පුනර්ජනනීය බලශක්තිය මත විශ්වාසය තැබීමෙන් අපගේ බලශක්ති අර්බුදයේ විශාල කොටසක් විසඳීමට අපට හැකි වනු ඇත,\" ඔහු පැවසීය, චීන මාධ්ය වාර්තා කරයි.",
        "2022 පිරිසිදු බලශක්ති උපකරණ පිළිබඳ ලෝක සමුළුව නිරිතදිග චීනයේ සිචුවාන් පළාතේ පැවැත්වේ.",
        "CGTN ට අනුව පිරිසිදු බලශක්ති උපකරණ කර්මාන්තයේ සංවර්ධනය සහ අනාගතය පිළිබඳව සාකච්ඡා කිරීම සඳහා රටවල් 17කින් සහ කලාපවලින් අමුත්තන් 1800කට අධික පිරිසක් මෙම අවස්ථාවට සහභාගි වෙති."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "චීන",
          "label": "NORP"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලාංකික",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "චීනය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාලිත කොහොන",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "චීනය",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "චීන",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "2022",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ලෝක සමුළුව",
            "label": "EVENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "නිරිතදිග චීනයේ",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "සිචුවාන් පළාත",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "18 සියයකට වැඩිය",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "17",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "சூரிய, காற்றாலை ஆற்றலில் சீன முதலீட்டை SL தூதர் ஈர்க்கிறார்",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "சீனாவுக்கான இலங்கைத் தூதுவர் கலாநிதி பாலித கொஹொன, சூரிய சக்தி அபிவிருத்தி மற்றும் காற்றாலை ஆற்றல் அபிவிருத்திக்கு இலங்கை சிறந்த இடமாக உள்ளது என்றும், நாம் தூய்மையான ஆற்றலுக்கு மாறுவதற்கு சீனா பெரும் உதவியாக இருக்கும் என்றும் தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "\"புதுப்பிக்கத்தக்க ஆற்றலை நம்புவதன் மூலம் நமது எரிசக்தி நெருக்கடியின் பெரும் பகுதியை நாம் சமாளிக்க முடியும்,\" என்று அவர் கூறினார், சீன ஊடகம்.",
        "தென்மேற்கு சீனாவின் சிச்சுவான் மாகாணத்தில் 2022 ஆம் ஆண்டுக்கான தூய்மையான ஆற்றல் கருவிகளுக்கான உலக மாநாடு நடைபெற்று வருகிறது.",
        "CGTN படி, சுத்தமான எரிசக்தி உபகரணத் துறையின் வளர்ச்சி மற்றும் எதிர்காலத்தைப் பற்றி விவாதிக்க 17 நாடுகள் மற்றும் பிராந்தியங்களில் இருந்து 18 நூற்றுக்கும் மேற்பட்ட விருந்தினர்கள் இந்த நிகழ்வில் பங்கேற்கின்றனர்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "சீன",
          "label": "NORP"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "சீனா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாலித கொஹோன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சீனா",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "சீன",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "2022",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "உலக மாநாடு",
            "label": "EVENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "தென்மேற்கு சீனாவின்",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "சிச்சுவான் மாகாணம்",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "18 நூற்றுக்கு மேல்",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "17",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}