{
  "newspaper_id": "lankadeepa-lk",
  "url": "https://www.lankadeepa.lk/latest_news/ලංකාව-ගැන-සංචාරක-නීති-ලිහිල්-කළ-ස්විට්සර්ලන්තයට-ප්‍රශංසා/1-618731",
  "time_ut": 1661414692,
  "original_lang": "si",
  "original_title": "ලංකාව ගැන සංචාරක නීති ලිහිල් කළ ස්විට්සර්ලන්තයට ප්‍රශංසා",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Kudos to Switzerland for relaxing Sri Lankan travel laws",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "The Sri Lanka Domestic Tour Operators Association (SLAITO) has expressed its appreciation for the Swiss government's decision to relax the travel advisory against Sri Lanka after President Ranil Wickremesinghe's announcement that the state of emergency will not be extended.",
        "Mr. Nishad Wijetunga, President of the Association of Sri Lanka Domestic Tourism Operations, said that Sri Lanka is working to make Sri Lanka one of the best destinations for Swiss tourists in winter.",
        "Mr. Wijetunga pointed out that this will enable Swiss tour operators to once again promote Sri Lanka.",
        "The Swiss government has recommended its citizens to be aware of the political and social situation in Sri Lanka in view of the latest developments.",
        "\"The Swiss government has informed its citizens to refrain from political discussions including on social networks and to follow the instructions of local authorities."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Switzerland",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "Sri Lankan",
          "label": "LOC"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Domestic Tour Operators Association",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "SLAITO",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Swiss",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Nishad Wijetunga",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Association of Sri Lanka Domestic Tourism Operations",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Swiss",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "winter",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Wijetunga",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Swiss",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Swiss",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Swiss",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "ලංකාව ගැන සංචාරක නීති ලිහිල් කළ ස්විට්සර්ලන්තයට ප්‍රශංසා",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "හදිසි නීතිය තවදුරටත් දීර්ඝ නොකරන බවට ජනාධිපති රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතා කළ ප්‍රකාශයෙන් පසුව ස්විට්සර්ලන්ත රජය විසින්  ශ්‍රී ලංකාවට එරෙහි සංචාරක උපදේශන ලිහිල් කිරීමට ගත් තීරණය සම්බන්ධයෙන් ශ්‍රී ලංකා අභ්‍යන්තර සංචාරක ක්‍රියාකරුවන්ගේ සංගමය (SLAITO) ප්‍රශංසාව පළ කර තිබේ.",
        "ශීත ඍතුවෙිදී  ස්විස් සංචාරකයන්ගේ හොඳම ගමනාන්තයක් බවට ශ්‍රී  ලංකාව පත්කිරිමට කටයුතු කරන බව  ශ්‍රී ලංකා අභ්‍යන්තර සංචාරක ක්‍රියාවරුන්ගේ සංගමයේ සභාපති නිෂාඩ් විජේතුංග මහතා පැවසීය",
        "මෙමගින් ස්විට්සර්ලන්ත සංචාරක ක්‍රියාකරුවන්ට නැවත වරක් ශ්‍රි ලංකාව ප්‍රවර්ධනය කිරීමට හැකිවනු ඇතැයි විජේතුංග මහතා පෙන්වා දුන්නේය.",
        "ශ්‍රි ලංකාවේ නවතම වර්ධනයන් සැලකිල්ලට ගෙන දේශපාලන හා සමාජීය  තත්ත්වයන් පිළිබඳ අවධානයෙන් සිටින ලෙස ස්විට්සර්ලන්ත රජය සිය පුරවැසියන්ට නිර්දේශ කර ඇත.",
        "“සමාජ ජාල ඇතුළු දේශපාලන සාකච්ඡාවලින් වළකින ලෙසත්, පළාත් පාලන ආයතනවල උපදෙස් පිළිපදින ලෙසත් ස්විට්සර්ලන්ත රජය සිය පුරවැසියන්ට දැනුම් දී තිබේ."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ස්විට්සර්ලන්තය",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "ශ්‍රී ලාංකික",
          "label": "LOC"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "දේශීය සංචාරක ක්‍රියාකරුවන්ගේ සංගමය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "SLAITO",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ස්විස්",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "නිෂාද් විජේතුංග",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකා දේශීය සංචාරක මෙහෙයුම් සංගමය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ස්විස්",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශීත ඍතුව",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "විජේතුංග",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ස්විස්",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ස්විස්",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ස්විස්",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "இலங்கை பயணச் சட்டங்களை தளர்த்தியதற்காக சுவிட்சர்லாந்திற்கு பாராட்டுக்கள்",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "ஜனாதிபதி ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்கவின் அவசரகாலச் சட்டம் நீடிக்கப்படாது என அறிவித்ததை அடுத்து, இலங்கைக்கு எதிரான பயண ஆலோசனையை தளர்த்த சுவிஸ் அரசாங்கம் எடுத்த தீர்மானத்திற்கு இலங்கை உள்நாட்டு சுற்றுலா செயற்பாட்டாளர்கள் சங்கம் (SLAITO) தனது பாராட்டுக்களை தெரிவித்துள்ளது.",
        "குளிர்காலத்தில் சுவிஸ் சுற்றுலாப் பயணிகளுக்கு இலங்கையை சிறந்த இடமாக மாற்றுவதற்கு இலங்கை செயற்பட்டு வருவதாக இலங்கை உள்நாட்டு சுற்றுலா நடவடிக்கைகளின் சங்கத்தின் தலைவர் திரு.நிஷாத் விஜேதுங்க தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "இதன் மூலம் சுவிஸ் சுற்றுலா நடத்துபவர்கள் மீண்டும் இலங்கையை மேம்படுத்த முடியும் என திரு.விஜேதுங்க சுட்டிக்காட்டினார்.",
        "சுவிஸ் அரசாங்கம், இலங்கையின் சமீபத்திய முன்னேற்றங்களைக் கருத்தில் கொண்டு, இலங்கையின் அரசியல் மற்றும் சமூக நிலைமைகள் குறித்து விழிப்புடன் இருக்குமாறு தனது குடிமக்களுக்கு பரிந்துரை செய்துள்ளது.",
        "“சமூக வலைதளங்கள் உள்ளிட்ட அரசியல் விவாதங்களைத் தவிர்க்கவும், உள்ளூர் அதிகாரிகளின் அறிவுறுத்தல்களைப் பின்பற்றவும் சுவிஸ் அரசாங்கம் அதன் குடிமக்களுக்கு அறிவுறுத்தியுள்ளது."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "சுவிட்சர்லாந்து",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "இலங்கை",
          "label": "LOC"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "உள்நாட்டு டூர் ஆபரேட்டர்கள் சங்கம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "SLAITO",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "சுவிஸ்",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "நிஷாத் விஜேதுங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை உள்நாட்டு சுற்றுலா நடவடிக்கைகளின் சங்கம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சுவிஸ்",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "குளிர்காலம்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "விஜேதுங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "சுவிஸ்",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "சுவிஸ்",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "சுவிஸ்",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}