{
  "newspaper_id": "lankadeepa-lk",
  "url": "https://www.lankadeepa.lk/latest_news/රාජ්‍ය-ආයතන-කිහිපයකට-නව-පත්වීම්/1-617051",
  "time_ut": 1658818889,
  "original_lang": "si",
  "original_title": "රාජ්‍ය ආයතන කිහිපයකට නව පත්වීම්",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "New appointments to several government agencies",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "Cabinet Spokesman, Minister of Transport, Highways and Mass Media Dr. Bandula Gunawardena said today (26) that new heads have been appointed for several government institutions.",
        "Accordingly, DRS Hapuarachchi has been appointed as the Commissioner General of Inland Revenue, PBSC Nonis as the Director General of Customs, WA Satkumara as the Deputy Secretary of the Treasury and Jude Nilukshan as the Director General of the Information Technology Management Department. The minister mentioned.",
        "The Minister also said that the Cabinet Papers for these appointments were presented by President Ranil Wickremesinghe as the Minister of Finance.",
        "The minister said this while addressing the press conference to inform the Cabinet decisions held today (26) at the Government Information Department."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Cabinet Spokesman",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Bandula Gunawardena",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "26",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "DRS Hapuarachchi",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Satkumara",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Treasury",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Jude Nilukshan",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Information Technology Management Department",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the Cabinet Papers",
            "label": "PRODUCT"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Cabinet",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "26",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Government Information Department",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "රාජ්‍ය ආයතන කිහිපයකට නව පත්වීම්",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "රාජ්‍ය ආයතන කිහිපයක් සඳහා නව ප්‍රධානීන් පත් කර ඇතැයි කැබිනට් ප්‍රකාශක ප්‍රවාහන, මහාමාර්ග සහ ජනමාධ්‍ය අමාත්‍ය ආචාර්ය බන්දුල ගුණවර්ධන මහතා අද (26) පැවසීය.",
        "ඒ අනුව දේශීය ආදායම් කොමසාරිස් ජනරාල්වරයා ලෙස ඩී.ආර් .එස් හපුආරච්චි, රේගු අධ්‍යක්‍ෂ ජනරාල්වරයා ලෙස පී.බී.එස්.සී නොනිස්, මහා භාණ්ඩාගාරයේ නියෝජ්‍ය ලේකම් ලෙස ඩබ්ලිව්.ඒ සත්කුමාර සහ තොරතුරු තාක්‍ෂණ කළමනාකරණ දෙපාර්තමේන්තුවේ අධ්‍යක්‍ෂ ජනරාල් ලෙස ජූඩ් නිලුක්ෂාන් යන මහත්වරුන් පත්කර ඇතැයි අමාත්‍යවරයා සඳහන් කළේය.",
        "මෙම පත්වීම් සඳහා වන කැබිනට් පත්‍රිකා මුදල් අමාත්‍යවරයා ලෙස ජනාධිපති රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතා විසින් ඉදිරිපත් කළ බව ද ඇමතිවරයා කීවේය.",
        "අමාත්‍යවරයා මේ බව පැවසුවේ රජයේ ප්‍රවෘත්ති දෙපාර්තමේන්තුවේ දී අද (26) පැවති කැබිනට් තීරණ දැනුම්දීමේ මාධ්‍ය හමුව අමතමිනි."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "කැබිනට් ප්‍රකාශක",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "බන්දුල ගුණවර්ධන",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "26",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "DRS හපුආරච්චි",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "සත්කුමාර",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "භාණ්ඩාගාර",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජූඩ් නිලුක්ෂාන්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "තොරතුරු තාක්ෂණ කළමනාකරණ දෙපාර්තමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "කැබිනට් පත්‍රිකා",
            "label": "PRODUCT"
          },
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "මණ්ඩල",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "26",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "රජයේ ප්‍රවෘත්ති දෙපාර්තමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "பல அரசு நிறுவனங்களுக்கு புதிய நியமனங்கள்",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "பல அரச நிறுவனங்களுக்கு புதிய தலைவர்கள் நியமிக்கப்பட்டுள்ளதாக அமைச்சரவைப் பேச்சாளர், போக்குவரத்து, நெடுஞ்சாலைகள் மற்றும் வெகுஜன ஊடக அமைச்சர் கலாநிதி பந்துல குணவர்தன இன்று (26) தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "இதன்படி, உள்நாட்டு இறைவரி ஆணையாளர் நாயகமாக டி.ஆர்.எஸ்.ஹப்புஆராச்சியும், சுங்கப் பணிப்பாளர் நாயகமாக பி.பி.எஸ்.சி நோனிஸும், திறைசேரியின் பிரதிச் செயலாளராக டபிள்யூ.ஏ.சத்குமாரவும், தகவல் தொழில்நுட்ப முகாமைத்துவ திணைக்களத்தின் பணிப்பாளர் நாயகமாக ஜூட் நிலுக்ஷனும் நியமிக்கப்பட்டுள்ளதாக அமைச்சர் குறிப்பிட்டார். .",
        "இந்த நியமனங்களுக்கான அமைச்சரவைப் பத்திரங்கள் ஜனாதிபதி ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்கவினால் நிதியமைச்சராக முன்வைக்கப்பட்டதாகவும் அமைச்சர் கூறினார்.",
        "அரசாங்க தகவல் திணைக்களத்தில் இன்று (26) நடைபெற்ற அமைச்சரவை முடிவுகளை அறிவிக்கும் ஊடகவியலாளர் சந்திப்பில் கலந்துகொண்டு கருத்து தெரிவிக்கும் போதே அமைச்சர் மேற்கண்டவாறு தெரிவித்தார்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "அமைச்சரவை செய்தி தொடர்பாளர்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "பந்துல குணவர்தன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "26",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "டிஆர்எஸ் ஹப்புஆராச்சி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "சத்குமார",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "கருவூலம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜூட் நிலுக்ஷன்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "தகவல் தொழில்நுட்ப மேலாண்மை துறை",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "அமைச்சரவை ஆவணங்கள்",
            "label": "PRODUCT"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "மந்திரி சபை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "26",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "அரசாங்க தகவல் திணைக்களம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}