{
  "newspaper_id": "island-lk",
  "url": "http://island.lk/exterminators-wins-national-business-excellence-award/",
  "time_ut": 1659177900,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Exterminators wins National Business Excellence Award",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Exterminators wins National Business Excellence Award",
      "author": "Thilina Walpola",
      "body_lines": [
        "Exterminators PLC., Sri Lanka’s premier pest management and environmental enhancement technology company won a silver award under ‘Other Service Sector’ at the National Business Excellence Awards organized by the National Chamber of Commerce in Sri Lanka. Exterminators PLC is Asia’s 1st ‘Great Place To Work’ certified and Asia’s 1st ‘Carbon Neutral’ certified pest management company is the winner of 60 national/international awards and company is certified ISO 9001, ISO 14001, ISO 45001, ISO 22000, COVID-19 SLS safety management system. Exterminators PLC is South Asia’s 1st first among the few pest management companies in the world to be listed in a stock exchange. Exterminators ventured into the fierce but amazing pest control industry in 1998 with just one man with a spray gun and motor bike but with more force, drive and passion it has become Sri Lanka’s premier pest control and environmental enhancement company winning 60 awards for business, brand, industrial excellence and entrepreneurship. The brand also won five international awards for environmental, social and ethical governance (ESG), such as ‘environmental best practices and leadership and corporate social responsibility. The brand is the trend-setter in the pest management industry and the SME sector in Sri Lanka and the emerging world.",
        "Exterminators is Asia’s 1st ‘Carbon Neutral’ certified pest control company and the World’s 1st ‘Carbon Neutral’ certified Anti-Microbial Disinfection Company. ‘Smart Missile’ designed and manufactured by Exterminators is the World’s 1st ‘Carbon Neutral’ termite station. Since 2014 the company off-settled 422 tons Carbon Emissions. All staff at Exterminators have undergone intensive training related to preventive pest management, pest risk assessment, occupational health and safety, food safety, quality management and environmental management under direct supervision of the senior management. The senior management has undergone intensive residential training in all aspects of pest control in UK, USA, EU, Australia, Singapore and Malaysia. Exterminators is a member of the National Pest Management Association – USA, Singapore Pest Management Association, British Pest Control Association and Sri Lanka’s 1st and South Asia’s 3rd pest management company of the ‘Federation of Asia Oceania Pest Managers Association.",
        "Leave a Reply Cancel replyYour email address will not be published. Required fields are marked *Comment Name *",
        "Save my name, email, and website in this browser for the next time I comment."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "National Business Excellence Award",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Exterminators PLC",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka’s",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the National Business Excellence Awards",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the National Chamber of Commerce",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Exterminators PLC",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Asia",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Asia",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "1st ‘Carbon Neutral’",
            "label": "EVENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "60",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ISO 9001",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ISO 14001",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ISO 45001",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ISO 22000",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Exterminators PLC",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "South Asia’s",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "pest",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "1998",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "one",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka’s",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "60",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "five",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "SME",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Asia",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "1st ‘Carbon Neutral’",
            "label": "EVENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "World",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "‘Carbon Neutral’",
            "label": "EVENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "Anti-Microbial Disinfection Company",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "‘Carbon Neutral’",
            "label": "EVENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "2014",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "422 tons",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "Carbon Emissions",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Exterminators",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "pest",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "pest",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "UK",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "USA",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "EU",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Australia",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Singapore",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Malaysia",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the National Pest Management Association – USA",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Singapore Pest Management Association",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "British Pest Control Association",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka’s",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "South Asia’s",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "3rd",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "the ‘Federation of Asia Oceania Pest Managers Association",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [],
        []
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "Exterminators ජාතික ව්‍යාපාර විශිෂ්ටතා සම්මානය දිනා ගනී",
      "author": "තිළිණ වල්පොල",
      "body_lines": [
        "Exterminators PLC., ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ ප්‍රමුඛතම පළිබෝධ කළමනාකරණය සහ පාරිසරික වැඩිදියුණු කිරීමේ තාක්‍ෂණ සමාගම, ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ ජාතික වාණිජ මණ්ඩලය විසින් සංවිධානය කරන ලද ජාතික ව්‍යාපාර විශිෂ්ටතා සම්මාන උළෙලේදී ‘අනෙකුත් සේවා අංශය’ යටතේ රිදී සම්මානයක් දිනා ගත්තේය. Exterminators PLC යනු ආසියාවේ 1 වන 'වැඩ කිරීමට විශිෂ්ට ස්ථානය' සහතිකය ලබා ඇති අතර ආසියාවේ 1 වන 'කාබන් නියුට්‍රල්' සහතික ලත් පළිබෝධ කළමනාකරණ සමාගම ජාතික/ජාත්‍යන්තර සම්මාන 60 ක ජයග්‍රාහකයා වන අතර සමාගම ISO 9001, ISO 14001, ISO 45001, ISO 45020, COVID-2020 සහතික කර ඇත. 19 SLS ආරක්ෂණ කළමනාකරණ පද්ධතිය. Exterminators PLC යනු කොටස් හුවමාරුවක ලැයිස්තුගත කර ඇති ලෝකයේ පළිබෝධ කළමනාකරණ සමාගම් කිහිපය අතර දකුණු ආසියාවේ පළමුවැනියා වේ. Exterminators 1998 දී ඉසින තුවක්කුවක් සහ මෝටර් බයිසිකලයක් සහිත එක් මිනිසෙකු සමඟ දරුණු නමුත් විස්මිත පළිබෝධ පාලන කර්මාන්තයට අවතීර්ණ වූ නමුත් වැඩි බලයෙන්, ධාවනයෙන් සහ ආශාවෙන් එය ව්‍යාපාර, සන්නාමය සඳහා සම්මාන 60 ක් දිනා ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ ප්‍රමුඛතම පළිබෝධ පාලනය සහ පාරිසරික වැඩිදියුණු කිරීමේ සමාගම බවට පත්ව ඇත. , කාර්මික විශිෂ්ටත්වය සහ ව්‍යවසායකත්වය. සන්නාමය පාරිසරික, සමාජීය සහ සදාචාරාත්මක පාලනය (ESG) සඳහා ‘පාරිසරික හොඳම භාවිතයන් සහ නායකත්වය සහ ආයතනික සමාජ වගකීම’ වැනි ජාත්‍යන්තර සම්මාන පහක් ද දිනා ගත්තේය. මෙම සන්නාමය ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ සහ නැගී එන ලෝකයේ පළිබෝධ කළමනාකරණ කර්මාන්තයේ සහ කුඩා හා මධ්‍ය පරිමාණ ව්‍යවසාය අංශයේ ප්‍රවණතා සකසන්නෙකු වේ.",
        "Exterminators යනු ආසියාවේ 1 වැනි ‘කාබන් නියුට්‍රල්’ සහතික ලත් පළිබෝධ පාලන සමාගම වන අතර ලොව 1 වැනි ‘කාබන් නියුට්‍රල්’ සහතික ලත් ක්ෂුද්‍ර ජීවී විෂබීජ නාශක නාශක සමාගමයි. Exterminators විසින් නිර්මාණය කරන ලද සහ නිෂ්පාදනය කරන ලද ‘Smart Missile’ යනු ලොව 1 වැනි ‘Carbon Neutral’ ටර්මයිට් ස්ථානයයි. 2014 වසරේ සිට සමාගම කාබන් විමෝචනය ටොන් 422 ක් නිරාකරණය කර ඇත. Exterminators හි සියලුම කාර්ය මණ්ඩලය ජ්‍යෙෂ්ඨ කළමනාකාරීත්වයේ සෘජු අධීක්ෂණය යටතේ වැළැක්වීමේ පළිබෝධ කළමනාකරණය, පළිබෝධ අවදානම තක්සේරු කිරීම, වෘත්තීය සෞඛ්‍ය සහ ආරක්ෂාව, ආහාර සුරක්ෂිතතාව, තත්ත්ව කළමනාකරණය සහ පාරිසරික කළමනාකරණය සම්බන්ධ දැඩි පුහුණුවක් ලබා ඇත. ජ්‍යෙෂ්ඨ කළමනාකාරීත්වය එක්සත් රාජධානිය, ඇමරිකා එක්සත් ජනපදය, යුරෝපා සංගමය, ඕස්ට්‍රේලියාව, සිංගප්පූරුව සහ මැලේසියාව යන රටවල පළිබෝධ පාලනය පිළිබඳ සියලු අංශ පිළිබඳව දැඩි නේවාසික පුහුණුවක් ලබා ඇත. Exterminators යනු ජාතික පළිබෝධ කළමනාකරණ සංගමයේ සාමාජිකයෙකි - ඇමරිකා එක්සත් ජනපදය, සිංගප්පූරු පළිබෝධ කළමනාකරණ සංගමය, බ්‍රිතාන්‍ය පළිබෝධ පාලන සංගමය සහ 'Federation of Asia Oceania Pest Manager Association' හි ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ 1 වන සහ දකුණු ආසියාවේ 3 වන පළිබෝධ කළමනාකරණ සමාගමයි.",
        "පිළිතුරක් දෙන්න පිළිතුර අවලංගු කරන්න ඔබගේ විද්‍යුත් තැපැල් ලිපිනය ප්‍රකාශයට පත් නොකෙරේ. අවශ්‍ය ක්ෂේත්‍ර සලකුණු කර ඇත *අදහස් නම *",
        "මම ඊළඟ වතාවේ අදහස් දැක්වීම සඳහා මගේ නම, විද්‍යුත් තැපෑල සහ වෙබ් අඩවිය මෙම බ්‍රවුසරයේ සුරකින්න."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ජාතික ව්‍යාපාර විශිෂ්ටතා සම්මානය",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Exterminators PLC",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජාතික ව්‍යාපාර විශිෂ්ටතා සම්මාන",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජාතික වාණිජ මණ්ඩලය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Exterminators PLC",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ආසියාව",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "1 වැනි",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ආසියාව",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "1 වන 'කාබන් උදාසීන'",
            "label": "EVENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "60",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ISO 9001",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ISO 14001",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ISO 45001",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ISO 22000",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Exterminators PLC",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "දකුණු ආසියාවේ",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "1 වැනි",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "පළිබෝධ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "1998",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "එක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "60",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "පහ",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "SME",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ආසියාව",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "1 වන 'කාබන් උදාසීන'",
            "label": "EVENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "ලෝක",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "1 වැනි",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "'කාබන් උදාසීන'",
            "label": "EVENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "ක්ෂුද්ර ජීවී විෂබීජ නාශක සමාගම",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "1 වැනි",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "'කාබන් උදාසීන'",
            "label": "EVENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "2014",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ටොන් 422 කි",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "කාබන් විමෝචනය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "විනාශ කරන්නන්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "පළිබෝධ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "පළිබෝධ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "එක්සත් රාජධානිය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඇඑජ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "EU",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඕස්ට්රේලියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "සිංගප්පූරුව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මැලේසියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජාතික පළිබෝධ කළමනාකරණ සංගමය - ඇමරිකා එක්සත් ජනපදය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "සිංගප්පූරු පළිබෝධ කළමනාකරණ සංගමය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "බ්‍රිතාන්‍ය පළිබෝධ පාලන සංගමය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "දකුණු ආසියාවේ",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "3 වැනි",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ආසියා ඕෂනියා පළිබෝධ කළමනාකරුවන්ගේ සංගමයේ සම්මේලනය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [],
        []
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "எக்ஸ்டெர்மினேட்டர்ஸ் நேஷனல் பிசினஸ் எக்ஸலன்ஸ் விருதை வென்றார்",
      "author": "திலின வல்பொல",
      "body_lines": [
        "Exterminators PLC., இலங்கையின் முதன்மையான பூச்சி முகாமைத்துவம் மற்றும் சுற்றாடல் மேம்படுத்தல் தொழில்நுட்ப நிறுவனமான இலங்கையின் தேசிய வர்த்தக சம்மேளனத்தினால் ஏற்பாடு செய்யப்பட்ட தேசிய வர்த்தக சிறப்பு விருதுகளில் ‘மற்ற சேவைத் துறையின்’ கீழ் வெள்ளி விருதை வென்றுள்ளது. Exterminators PLC ஆனது ஆசியாவின் 1வது 'கிரேட் பிளேஸ் டு வொர்க்' சான்றிதழ் பெற்றது மற்றும் ஆசியாவின் 1வது 'கார்பன் நியூட்ரல்' சான்றளிக்கப்பட்ட பூச்சி மேலாண்மை நிறுவனம் 60 தேசிய/சர்வதேச விருதுகளை வென்றுள்ளது. 19 SLS பாதுகாப்பு மேலாண்மை அமைப்பு. எக்ஸ்டெர்மினேட்டர்ஸ் பிஎல்சி, பங்குச் சந்தையில் பட்டியலிடப்பட்ட உலகின் சில பூச்சி மேலாண்மை நிறுவனங்களில் தெற்காசியாவின் முதல் நிறுவனமாகும். அழிப்பாளர்கள் 1998 ஆம் ஆண்டில் ஒரு ஸ்ப்ரே துப்பாக்கி மற்றும் மோட்டார் சைக்கிளுடன் ஒரு மனிதருடன் கடுமையான ஆனால் அற்புதமான பூச்சிக் கட்டுப்பாட்டுத் துறையில் இறங்கினார்கள், ஆனால் அதிக சக்தி, இயக்கம் மற்றும் ஆர்வத்துடன் இது வணிகம், பிராண்ட் ஆகியவற்றிற்காக 60 விருதுகளை வென்ற இலங்கையின் முதன்மையான பூச்சி கட்டுப்பாடு மற்றும் சுற்றுச்சூழல் மேம்பாட்டு நிறுவனமாக மாறியுள்ளது. , தொழில்துறை சிறப்பு மற்றும் தொழில்முனைவு. சுற்றுச்சூழல், சமூக மற்றும் நெறிமுறை ஆளுகைக்கான (ESG) ஐந்து சர்வதேச விருதுகளையும் இந்த பிராண்ட் வென்றது, அதாவது 'சுற்றுச்சூழல் சிறந்த நடைமுறைகள் மற்றும் தலைமைத்துவம் மற்றும் பெருநிறுவன சமூகப் பொறுப்பு. இந்த வர்த்தக நாமமானது பூச்சி முகாமைத்துவ தொழிற்துறை மற்றும் இலங்கை மற்றும் வளர்ந்து வரும் உலகில் SME துறையில் போக்கு-செட்டராக உள்ளது.",
        "எக்ஸ்டெர்மினேட்டர்ஸ் என்பது ஆசியாவின் 1வது ‘கார்பன் நியூட்ரல்’ சான்றிதழ் பெற்ற பூச்சிக் கட்டுப்பாட்டு நிறுவனம் மற்றும் உலகின் 1வது ‘கார்பன் நியூட்ரல்’ சான்றளிக்கப்பட்ட நுண்ணுயிர் கிருமி நீக்கம் செய்யும் நிறுவனமாகும். எக்ஸ்டெர்மினேட்டர்களால் வடிவமைக்கப்பட்டு தயாரிக்கப்பட்ட ‘ஸ்மார்ட் ஏவுகணை’ உலகின் முதல் ‘கார்பன் நியூட்ரல்’ டெர்மைட் நிலையமாகும். 2014 முதல் நிறுவனம் 422 டன் கார்பன் உமிழ்வைத் தீர்த்து வைத்துள்ளது. Exterminators இல் உள்ள அனைத்து ஊழியர்களும் தடுப்பு பூச்சி மேலாண்மை, பூச்சி ஆபத்து மதிப்பீடு, தொழில்சார் சுகாதாரம் மற்றும் பாதுகாப்பு, உணவு பாதுகாப்பு, தர மேலாண்மை மற்றும் சுற்றுச்சூழல் மேலாண்மை தொடர்பான தீவிர பயிற்சியை மூத்த நிர்வாகத்தின் நேரடி மேற்பார்வையில் பெற்றுள்ளனர். மூத்த நிர்வாகம் UK, USA, EU, ஆஸ்திரேலியா, சிங்கப்பூர் மற்றும் மலேசியா ஆகிய நாடுகளில் பூச்சி கட்டுப்பாடு தொடர்பான அனைத்து அம்சங்களிலும் தீவிர குடியிருப்பு பயிற்சி பெற்றுள்ளது. Exterminators தேசிய பூச்சி மேலாண்மை சங்கம் - USA, சிங்கப்பூர் பூச்சி மேலாண்மை சங்கம், பிரிட்டிஷ் பூச்சி கட்டுப்பாடு சங்கம் மற்றும் இலங்கையின் 1வது மற்றும் தெற்காசியாவின் 3வது பூச்சி மேலாண்மை நிறுவனமான ‘Federation of Asia Oceania Pest Managers Association’ ஆகியவற்றில் உறுப்பினராக உள்ளது.",
        "ஒரு பதிலை விடுங்கள் பதிலை ரத்துசெய் உங்கள் மின்னஞ்சல் முகவரி வெளியிடப்படாது. தேவையான புலங்கள் குறிக்கப்பட்டுள்ளன *கருத்து பெயர் *",
        "அடுத்த முறை நான் கருத்து தெரிவிக்க, எனது பெயர், மின்னஞ்சல் மற்றும் இணையதளத்தை இந்த உலாவியில் சேமிக்கவும்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "தேசிய வணிக சிறப்பு விருது",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Exterminators PLC",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கையின்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "தேசிய வணிக சிறப்பு விருதுகள்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "தேசிய வர்த்தக சபை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Exterminators PLC",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆசியா",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "1வது",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆசியா",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "1வது 'கார்பன் நியூட்ரல்'",
            "label": "EVENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "60",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ISO 9001",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ISO 14001",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ISO 45001",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ISO 22000",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Exterminators PLC",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "தெற்காசியாவின்",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "1வது",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "பூச்சி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "1998",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஒன்று",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கையின்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "60",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஐந்து",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "SME",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஆசியா",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "1வது 'கார்பன் நியூட்ரல்'",
            "label": "EVENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "உலகம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "1வது",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "'கார்பன் நியூட்ரல்'",
            "label": "EVENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆன்டி-மைக்ரோபியல் கிருமிநாசினி நிறுவனம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "1வது",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "'கார்பன் நியூட்ரல்'",
            "label": "EVENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "2014",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "422 டன்",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "கார்பன் உமிழ்வை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "அழிப்பவர்கள்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "பூச்சி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "பூச்சி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "யுகே",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "அமெரிக்கா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "EU",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆஸ்திரேலியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சிங்கப்பூர்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "மலேசியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "தேசிய பூச்சி மேலாண்மை சங்கம் - அமெரிக்கா",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "சிங்கப்பூர் பூச்சி மேலாண்மை சங்கம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "பிரிட்டிஷ் பூச்சி கட்டுப்பாடு சங்கம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கையின்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "தெற்காசியாவின்",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "3வது",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆசிய ஓசியானியா பூச்சி மேலாளர்கள் சங்கத்தின் கூட்டமைப்பு",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [],
        []
      ]
    }
  }
}