{
  "newspaper_id": "news-first-lk",
  "url": "https://www.newsfirst.lk/2022/06/29/one-country-one-law-task-force-submits-report-to-president/",
  "time_ut": 1656497880,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "‘One Country, One Law’ Task Force submits report to President",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "‘One Country, One Law’ Task Force submits report to President",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); The reported prepared by the Presidential Task Force on the ‘One country, One law’ policy was handed over to President Gotabaya Rajapaksa on Wednesday (29).",
        "Sri Lankan President Gotabaya Rajapaksa has appointed a 13-member Presidential Task Force to study the implementation of the concept “One Country, One Law” and to prepare a draft Act.",
        "The task force will be chaired by Ven. Galagodaaththe Gnanasara Thero.",
        "Jeewanthi Senanayake, Senior Assistant Secretary to the President was appointed as its Secretary.",
        "The other members of the Task Force are: Professor Dayananda Banda, Professor Shanthinandana Wijesinghe, Professor Sumedha Siriwardana, 5. N.G. Sujeewa Panditharathna, 6. Attorney-at-Law Iresh Senevirathne, Attorney-at-Law Sanjaya Marambe, Eranda Navarathna, Pani Wewala, Moulavi Mohomad Ulama Council, Galle, Mohomad Inthikab, Lecturer, Kaleel Rahuman, and Azeez Nizardeen.",
        "According to the Gazette notification on the appointment of the Task Force, it is entrusted with the following tasks:",
        "1. To make a study of the implementation of the concept; One Country, One Law within Sri Lanka and prepare a draft Act for the said purpose, and",
        "2. To study the draft Acts and amendments that have already been prepared by the Ministry of Justice in relation to this subject and their appropriateness and if there are suitable amendments to submit proposal for the purpose and include them in such relevant draft as is deemed appropriate.",
        "‘One Country, One Law’ Task Force submits report to President"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "One",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "One",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "the Presidential Task Force",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "One",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "One",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Gotabaya Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Wednesday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "29",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lankan",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Gotabaya Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "13",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Presidential Task Force",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "One",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "One",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Galagodaaththe Gnanasara Thero",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Jeewanthi Senanayake",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the Task Force",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Dayananda Banda",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Shanthinandana Wijesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sumedha Siriwardana",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "5",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "N.G. Sujeewa Panditharathna",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "6",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Eranda Navarathna",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Pani Wewala",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Moulavi",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Galle",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Mohomad Inthikab",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Lecturer",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kaleel Rahuman",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Azeez Nizardeen",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Gazette",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Task Force",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "1",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "One",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "One",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Act",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "2",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Ministry of Justice",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "One",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "One",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "‘එකම රටක්, එකම නීතියක්’ කාර්ය සාධක බලකාය ජනපතිට වාර්තාවක්",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); ‘එකම රටක් එකම නීතියක්’ ප්‍රතිපත්තිය පිළිබඳව ජනාධිපති කාර්ය සාධක බලකාය විසින් සකස් කරන ලද වාර්තාව බදාදා (29) ජනාධිපති ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ මහතා වෙත භාර දෙන ලදී.",
        "“එක් රටක්, එකම නීතියක්” සංකල්පය ක්‍රියාත්මක කිරීම අධ්‍යයනය කිරීම සහ පනත් කෙටුම්පතක් සකස් කිරීම සඳහා ශ්‍රී ලංකා ජනාධිපති ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ මහතා විසින් 13 දෙනෙකුගෙන් යුත් ජනාධිපති කාර්ය සාධක බලකායක් පත් කර තිබේ.",
        "කාර්ය සාධක බළකායේ සභාපති පූජ්‍ය නාහිමියෝ වෙති. ගලගොඩඅත්තේ ඥානසාර හිමි.",
        "එහි ලේකම්වරයා ලෙස පත් කෙරුණේ ජනාධිපති ජ්‍යෙෂ්ඨ සහකාර ලේකම් ජීවන්ති සේනානායක මහත්මියයි.",
        "කාර්ය සාධක බලකායේ සෙසු සාමාජිකයින් වන්නේ: මහාචාර්ය දයානන්ද බණ්ඩා, මහාචාර්ය ශාන්තිනන්දන විජේසිංහ, මහාචාර්ය සුමේධා සිරිවර්ධන, 5. එන්.ජී. සුජීව පණ්ඩිතරත්න, 6. නීතීඥ ඉරේෂ් සෙනෙවිරත්න, නීතීඥ සංජය මාරඹේ, එරන්ද නවරත්න, පානි වෑවල, ගාල්ල මවුලවි මොහොමඩ් උලමා සභාව, මොහොමඩ් ඉන්තිකාබ්, කථිකාචාර්ය කලීල් රහුමාන්, සහ අසීස්ඩීන්.",
        "කාර්ය සාධක බළකාය පත්කිරීමේ ගැසට් නිවේදනයට අනුව පහත සඳහන් කාර්යයන් එයට පවරා ඇත.",
        "1. සංකල්පය ක්රියාත්මක කිරීම පිළිබඳ අධ්යයනයක් කිරීමට; එක රටක්, ශ්‍රී ලංකාව තුළ එකම නීතියක් සහ එකී අරමුණ සඳහා පනත් කෙටුම්පතක් සකස් කිරීම සහ",
        "2. මෙම විෂයට අදාළව අධිකරණ අමාත්‍යාංශය විසින් දැනටමත් සකස් කර ඇති පනත් කෙටුම්පත් සහ සංශෝධන සහ ඒවායේ යෝග්‍යතාවය අධ්‍යයනය කිරීම සහ ඒ සඳහා යෝජනාවක් ඉදිරිපත් කිරීමට සුදුසු සංශෝධන තිබේ නම් ඒවා සුදුසු යැයි හැඟෙන පරිදි අදාළ කෙටුම්පතට ඇතුළත් කිරීම. .",
        "‘එකම රටක්, එකම නීතියක්’ කාර්ය සාධක බලකාය ජනපතිට වාර්තාවක්"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "එක",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "එක",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ජනාධිපති කාර්ය සාධක බලකාය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "එක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "එක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "බදාදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "29",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලාංකික",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "13",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජනාධිපති කාර්ය සාධක බලකාය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "එක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "එක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ගලගොඩඅත්තේ ඥානසාර හිමි",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ජීවන්ති සේනානායක",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "කාර්ය සාධක බලකාය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "දයානන්ද බණ්ඩා",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශාන්තිනන්දන විජේසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "සුමේධා සිරිවර්ධන",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "5",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "එන්.ජී. සුජීව පණ්ඩිතරත්න",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "6",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "එරන්ද නවරත්න",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "පැනි වෑවල",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "මවුලවි",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගාල්ල",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මොහොමඩ් ඉන්තිකාබ්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "කථිකාචාර්ය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "කලීල් රහුමාන්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Azeez Nizardeen",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ගැසට්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "කාර්ය සාධක බලකාය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "1",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "එක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "එක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "පනත",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "2",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "අධිකරණ අමාත්යාංශය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "එක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "එක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "‘ஒரே நாடு, ஒரே சட்டம்’ பணிக்குழு ஜனாதிபதியிடம் அறிக்கை சமர்ப்பித்தது",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); ‘ஒரே நாடு ஒரே சட்டம்’ கொள்கை தொடர்பில் ஜனாதிபதி செயலணியினால் தயாரிக்கப்பட்ட அறிக்கை புதன்கிழமை (29) ஜனாதிபதி கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ஷவிடம் கையளிக்கப்பட்டது.",
        "“ஒரு நாடு, ஒரே சட்டம்” என்ற கருத்தை நடைமுறைப்படுத்துவது குறித்து ஆராய்வதற்கும் சட்ட வரைவை தயாரிப்பதற்கும் 13 பேர் கொண்ட ஜனாதிபதி செயலணியை இலங்கை ஜனாதிபதி கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ச நியமித்துள்ளார்.",
        "பணிக்குழுவின் தலைவர் வண. கலகொடஅத்தே ஞானசார தேரர்.",
        "இதன் செயலாளராக ஜனாதிபதியின் சிரேஷ்ட உதவிச் செயலாளர் ஜீவந்தி சேனாநாயக்க நியமிக்கப்பட்டுள்ளார்.",
        "செயலணியின் ஏனைய உறுப்பினர்கள்: பேராசிரியர் தயானந்த பண்டா, பேராசிரியர் சாந்திநந்தன விஜேசிங்க, பேராசிரியர் சுமேதா சிறிவர்தன, 5. என்.ஜி. சுஜீவ பண்டிதரத்ன, 6. சட்டத்தரணி இரேஷ் செனவிரத்ன, சட்டத்தரணி சஞ்சய மரம்பே, எரந்த நவரத்தின, பாணி வெவல, மௌலவி மொஹமட் உலமா சபை, காலி, மொஹமட் இந்திகாப், விரிவுரையாளர், கலீல் ரகுமான், மற்றும் அசீன்.",
        "பணிக்குழுவின் நியமனம் தொடர்பான வர்த்தமானி அறிவித்தலின் படி, பின்வரும் பணிகள் அதற்கு ஒப்படைக்கப்பட்டுள்ளன:",
        "1. கருத்தை செயல்படுத்துவது பற்றிய ஆய்வு செய்ய; ஒரு நாடு, இலங்கைக்குள் ஒரு சட்டம் மற்றும் அந்த நோக்கத்திற்காக ஒரு வரைவு சட்டத்தை தயார் செய்தல், மற்றும்",
        "2. இந்த விடயம் தொடர்பாக நீதி அமைச்சினால் ஏற்கனவே தயாரிக்கப்பட்ட வரைவு சட்டங்கள் மற்றும் திருத்தங்களை ஆய்வு செய்தல் மற்றும் அவற்றின் பொருத்தமான தன்மை மற்றும் அதற்கான முன்மொழிவைச் சமர்ப்பிக்க பொருத்தமான திருத்தங்கள் இருந்தால் அவற்றைப் பொருத்தமானதாகக் கருதப்படும் வரைவுச் சட்டத்தில் சேர்ப்பது. .",
        "‘ஒரே நாடு, ஒரே சட்டம்’ பணிக்குழு ஜனாதிபதியிடம் அறிக்கை சமர்ப்பித்தது"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ஒன்று",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "ஒன்று",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ஜனாதிபதி செயலணி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஒன்று",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஒன்று",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "புதன்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "29",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "13",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜனாதிபதி செயலணி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஒன்று",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஒன்று",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "கலகொடஅத்தே ஞானசார தேரர்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஜீவந்தி சேனாநாயக்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பணிக்குழு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "தயானந்த பண்டா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "சாந்திநந்தன விஜேசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "சுமேதா சிறிவர்தன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "5",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "என்.ஜி. சுஜீவ பண்டிதரத்ன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "6",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஏரந்த நவரத்தினம்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "பணி வெவல",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "மௌலவி",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "காலி",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "முகமது இந்திகாப்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "விரிவுரையாளர்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "கலீல் ரகுமான்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "அஜீஸ் நிசார்தீன்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "அரசிதழ்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "பணிக்குழு",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "1",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஒன்று",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஒன்று",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "நாடகம்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "2",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "நீதி அமைச்சகம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஒன்று",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஒன்று",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}