{
  "newspaper_id": "island-lk",
  "url": "http://island.lk/a-dream-come-true-for-ranil/",
  "time_ut": 1658342820,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "A dream come true — for Ranil",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "A dream come true — for Ranil",
      "author": "Sahan Weerasooriya",
      "body_lines": [
        "President Ranil Wickremesinghe is in seventh heaven. Everybody wrote him off when he lost the last general election (2020), having contested two presidential elections unsuccessfully in 1999 and 2005, and baulked at running for President in 2010, 2015, and 2019. He became the Prime Minister in May and President in July. But for his age, a jubilant Wickremesinghe may have turned cartwheels and somersaults on the parliament lawn when the outcome of yesterday’s vote was announced. Let him be congratulated!",
        "The SLPP is cock-a-hoop, having scored a win, nay flexed its political muscles, in Parliament. Politically speaking, Diyawanna is fast becoming ‘Nandikadal’ for the Rajapaksas. Their power is now limited to Parliament, where they are putting up stiff resistance desperately.",
        "President Wickremesinghe is lucky and unlucky at the same time, paradoxical as it may sound. He is lucky because he has been able to take a shortcut to the much-coveted presidency. He is unlucky because he has achieved his goal amidst the country’s worst-ever politico-economic crisis, which caused his elected predecessor to resign. All socio-economic factors that led to several popular uprisings during the past few months and the resignation of President Gotabaya Rajapaksa are still there. There has been a let-up of sorts in mass protests, but what we are experiencing at present could be the calm before the storm. The massive build-up of public anger remains intact, posing a grave danger to the unstable social order, which has to be restored for economic recovery to become a reality. The only way to defuse tensions in the polity safely is to eliminate the causes of the worsening economic crisis. This task cannot be accomplished without a significant increase in the country’s foreign currency reserves. There’s the rub.",
        "President Wickremesinghe will be leading a government that lacks legitimacy. The resignations of President Gotabaya Rajapaksa and Prime Minister Mahinda Rajapaksa caused the current SLPP regime to lose its legitimacy. It is they who led the SLPP’s presidential and parliamentary election campaigns and secured popular mandates. The SLPP started fearing people long before they took to the streets. It betrayed its fear of the public by postponing the Local Government polls, last year. It has also been losing co-operative society elections, which are considered a barometer of popular support. Thus, President Wickremesinghe should not lose sight of the fact that he owes his win in Parliament yesterday to a bunch of rejected politicians, who are too scared to go before the people; their decisions do not reflect the will of the masses.",
        "Parliamentary majorities do not necessarily translate into public acceptance and legitimacy. It may be recalled that the UNP-led UNF government mustered a working majority in the House and torpedoed the hurriedly-formed Sirisena-Rajapaksa government in 2018, but the UNP could not win a single seat at the general election that followed. The Rajapaksas had two amendments to the Constitution passed with a two-thirds majority each, but the 18th Amendment was deep-sixed in 2015, and the current SLPP government itself has undertaken to replace the 20th Amendment. In 2013, Parliament impeached Chief Justice Dr. Shirani Bandaranayake at the behest of the Rajapaksa family, but two years later the then President Maithripala Sirisena reinstated her; Wickremesinghe was the Prime Minister at the time.",
        "The SLPP bigwigs, troubled by the smart of being unable to go on abusing power, stealing public funds and indulging in corruption, due to public protests, will seek to exact revenge by means of brutal crackdowns on anti-government protesters. They tried to pressure President Gotabaya Rajapaksa to grant their wish, but thankfully he chose to resign instead of unleashing the military on the protesters. One can only hope that President Wickremesinghe, too, will not give in to their pressure.",
        "The SLPP MPs who voted for Wickremesinghe yesterday made a tremendous contribution to President Gotabaya Rajapaksa’s downfall. They are obviously salivating at the prospect of being able to make up for lost time. The biggest challenge before President Wickremesinghe will be to make good on his promises with the help of those elements, whose allegiance is to Basil Rajapaksa. Most of them are sure to demand Cabinet posts.",
        "Almost all MPs who backed Wickremesinghe yesterday are from the SLPP, and he will be dependent on them for his political survival. The person who controls the ruling party is more powerful than the Executive President. It is Basil who has the SLPP under his thumb. Even President Gotabaya Rajapaksa, elected by 6.9 million people, was at the mercy of his sibling, Basil. President Wickremesinghe may be able to prevent himself from being overdependent on Basil by forming an all-party government so that a concerted effort could be made to rescue the economy and ameliorate people’s suffering, which finds expression in popular uprisings. But he will have his work cut out to rope in the SJB, the SLPP rebel group and the JVP-led NPP.",
        "The Aragalaya is only the tip of the iceberg of public anger, and the incumbent regime is a mere battered bark with broken masts and tattered sails. This is something the new President should bear in mind if he is to avoid the fate that befell his immediate predecessor.",
        "Leave a Reply Cancel replyYour email address will not be published. Required fields are marked *Comment Name *",
        "Save my name, email, and website in this browser for the next time I comment."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "seventh",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "2020",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "two",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "1999",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "2005",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "2010",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "2015",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "2019",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "May",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "July",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "yesterday",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Diyawanna",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Rajapaksas",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the past few months",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Gotabaya Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Gotabaya Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Mahinda Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "SLPP",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Local Government",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "last year",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "yesterday",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "UNP",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "UNF",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "House",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sirisena-Rajapaksa",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "2018",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "UNP",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Rajapaksas",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "two",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Constitution",
            "label": "LAW"
          },
          {
            "text": "a two-thirds",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "18th",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "2015",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the 20th Amendment",
            "label": "LAW"
          },
          {
            "text": "2013",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Shirani Bandaranayake",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "two years later",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Maithripala Sirisena",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Gotabaya Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "yesterday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Gotabaya Rajapaksa’s",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Basil Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Cabinet",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "yesterday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Basil",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Gotabaya Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "6.9 million",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Basil",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Basil",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "SJB",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "JVP",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "NPP",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [],
        []
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "සිහිනයක් සැබෑවක් - රනිල්ට",
      "author": "සහන් වීරසූරිය",
      "body_lines": [
        "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ ජනාධිපතිතුමා ඉන්නේ හත්වැනි දෙව්ලොව. 1999 සහ 2005 ජනාධිපතිවරණ දෙකකට අසාර්ථක ලෙස ඉදිරිපත් වී, පසුගිය මහ මැතිවරණයේදී (2020) ඔහු පැරදුණු විට, 2010, 2015 සහ 2019 දී ජනාධිපති අපේක්ෂකත්වයට ඉදිරිපත් වීම ගැන බෙරිහන් දුන් ඔහු පසුගිය මහ මැතිවරණයෙන් (2020) සියල්ලෝම ලියූහ. ජුලි. එහෙත් ඔහුගේ වයස අනුව ප්‍රීති ඝෝෂා නඟන වික්‍රමසිංහ ඊයේ ඡන්ද ප්‍රතිඵලය ප්‍රකාශයට පත් කරන විට පාර්ලිමේන්තු තණකොළ මත කරත්ත රෝද සහ රෝද පෙරළන්නට ඇත. ඔහුට සුබ පතමු!",
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකා පොදුජන පෙරමුණ පාර්ලිමේන්තුව තුළ ජයග්‍රහණයක් ලබාගෙන, දේශපාලන ශක්තිය නොනැමූ, කුකුළා ය. දේශපාලන වශයෙන් ගත් කල දියවන්නාව වේගයෙන් රාජපක්ෂලාගේ ‘නන්දිකඩාල්’ බවට පත්වෙමින් තිබේ. ඔවුන්ගේ බලය දැන් පාර්ලිමේන්තුවට සීමා වී ඇති අතර එහිදී ඔවුන් දැඩි ප්‍රතිරෝධයක් දක්වන්නේ මංමුලා සහගත ලෙස ය.",
        "වික්‍රමසිංහ ජනාධිපතිවරයා එකවරම වාසනාවන්ත මෙන්ම අවාසනාවන්තද, එය කෙතරම් පරස්පර විරෝධීද යන්නයි. ඔහු වාසනාවන්ත වන්නේ බොහෝ ආශා කළ ජනාධිපති ධුරයට කෙටි මගක් ගැනීමට ඔහුට හැකි වී ඇති බැවිනි. ඔහු අවාසනාවන්ත වන්නේ, ඔහුගේ තේරී පත් වූ පූර්වගාමියා ඉල්ලා අස්වීමට හේතු වූ රටේ දරුණුතම දේශපාලන-ආර්ථික අර්බුදය මධ්‍යයේ ඔහු තම ඉලක්කය සපුරා ගත් බැවිනි. පසුගිය මාස කිහිපය තුළ ජන නැගිටීම් කිහිපයකට සහ ජනාධිපති ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂගේ ඉල්ලා අස්වීමට තුඩු දුන් සියලු සමාජ-ආර්ථික සාධක තවමත් පවතී. මහජන විරෝධතාවල යම් ආකාරයක අඩුවීමක් සිදුවී ඇත, නමුත් වර්තමානයේ අප අත්විඳිමින් සිටින්නේ කුණාටුවට පෙර සන්සුන් භාවය විය හැකිය. ආර්ථික ප්‍රකෘතිය යථාර්තයක් බවට පත් කිරීම සඳහා ප්‍රතිෂ්ඨාපනය කළ යුතු අස්ථාවර සමාජ පර්යායට බරපතල අනතුරක් කරමින් මහජන කෝපයේ දැවැන්ත ගොඩ නැගීම නොවෙනස්ව පවතී. දේශපාලනයේ ආතතීන් ආරක්ෂිතව සමනය කළ හැකි එකම මාර්ගය වන්නේ නරක අතට හැරෙන ආර්ථික අර්බුදයේ හේතු ඉවත් කිරීමයි. රටේ විදේශ මුදල් සංචිතවල සැලකිය යුතු වැඩි වීමක් නොමැතිව මෙම කාර්යය ඉටු කළ නොහැකිය. අඹරන එක තියෙනවා.",
        "නීත්‍යානුකූල භාවයක් නැති ආණ්ඩුවකට වික්‍රමසිංහ ජනාධිපතිතුමා නායකත්වය දෙනවා. ජනාධිපති ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂගේ සහ අගමැති මහින්ද රාජපක්ෂගේ ඉල්ලා අස්වීම් වත්මන් ශ්‍රී ලංකා පොදුජන පෙරමුණේ පාලනයේ නීත්‍යානුකූලභාවය නැතිවීමට හේතු විය. ශ්‍රී ලංකා පොදුජන පෙරමුණේ ජනාධිපතිවරණ සහ පාර්ලිමේන්තු මැතිවරණ ප්‍රචාරක ව්‍යාපාරයට නායකත්වය දුන්නේත්, ජනවරම ලබා ගත්තේත් ඔවුන් ය. ශ්‍රී ලංකා පොදුජන පෙරමුණ මිනිසුන්ට බිය වීමට පටන් ගත්තේ ඔවුන් පාරට බැසීමට බොහෝ කලකට පෙරය. එය පසුගිය වසරේ පළාත් පාලන මැතිවරණය කල් දැමීමෙන් මහජනතාව කෙරෙහි ඇති බිය පාවා දුන්නේය. මහජන සහයෝගයේ පරාමිතියක් ලෙස සැලකෙන සමුපකාර සමිති මැතිවරණ ද පරාජය වෙමින් තිබේ. මේ අනුව, ඊයේ පාර්ලිමේන්තුවේදී තමන් ලැබූ ජයග්‍රහණය ජනතාව ඉදිරියට යාමට බියෙන් සිටින ප්‍රතික්ෂේප වූ දේශපාලඥයින් රැළකට ණයගැති බව ජනාධිපති වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතා අමතක නොකළ යුතුය. ඔවුන්ගේ තීරණ ජනතාවගේ කැමැත්ත පිළිබිඹු නොකරයි.",
        "පාර්ලිමේන්තු බහුතරය මහජන පිළිගැනීම සහ නීත්‍යානුකූලභාවය බවට පරිවර්තනය වීම අවශ්‍ය නොවේ. එජාපය ප්‍රමුඛ එජාප ආණ්ඩුව 2018 දී පාර්ලිමේන්තුවේ වැඩ කරන බහුතරයක් රැස්කරගෙන කඩිමුඩියේ පිහිටවූ සිරිසේන-රාජපක්ෂ ආණ්ඩුව ටොපිඩෝ කළ නමුත් ඉන් පසුව පැවැති මහ මැතිවරණයේදී එජාපයට එකදු ආසනයක්වත් දිනාගත නොහැකි වූ බව සිහිපත් කළ හැකිය. රාජපක්ෂලාට තුනෙන් දෙකේ බහුතරයකින් ආණ්ඩුක්‍රම ව්‍යවස්ථාවේ සංශෝධන දෙකක් සම්මත වූ නමුත් 18 වැනි ව්‍යවස්ථා සංශෝධනය 2015 දී ගැඹුරට හයක් වූ අතර වත්මන් ශ්‍රී ලංකා පොදුජන පෙරමුණ රජය විසින්ම 20 වැනි සංශෝධනය ප්‍රතිස්ථාපනය කිරීමට කටයුතු කර ඇත. 2013 දී රාජපක්ෂ පවුලේ ඉල්ලීම පරිදි පාර්ලිමේන්තුව විසින් අගවිනිසුරු ආචාර්ය ශිරාණි බණ්ඩාරනායක මහත්මියට දෝෂාභියෝගයක් ගෙන ආ නමුත් වසර දෙකකට පසු එවකට ජනාධිපති මෛත්‍රීපාල සිරිසේන විසින් ඇයව යළි සේවයේ පිහිටුවන ලදී; එවකට අගමැති වූයේ වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතාය.",
        "මහජන විරෝධතා හේතුවෙන් බලය අයුතු ලෙස භාවිතා කිරීමට, මහජන මුදල් සොරකම් කිරීමට සහ දූෂණයට ලක්වීමට නොහැකිව සූක්ෂ්මතාවයෙන් කැළඹී සිටින ශ්‍රී ලංකා පොදුජන පෙරමුණේ ප්‍රධානීන්, ආණ්ඩු විරෝධී උද්ඝෝෂකයන්ට එරෙහිව කුරිරු මර්දනයන් මගින් පළිගැනීමට උත්සාහ කරනු ඇත. ඔවුන්ගේ කැමැත්ත ඉටු කරන ලෙස ඔවුන් ජනාධිපති ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂට බලපෑම් කිරීමට උත්සාහ කළ නමුත්, ස්තූතිවන්ත වන පරිදි ඔහු විරෝධතාකරුවන්ට හමුදාව මුදා හැරීම වෙනුවට ඉල්ලා අස්වීමට තීරණය කළේය. වික්‍රමසිංහ ජනාධිපතිවරයාද ඔවුන්ගේ බලපෑම්වලට යටත් නොවනු ඇතැයි බලාපොරොත්තු විය හැකිය.",
        "ඊයේ වික්‍රමසිංහට ඡන්දය දුන් ශ්‍රී ලංකා පොදුජන පෙරමුණේ මන්ත්‍රීවරුන් ජනාධිපති ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ මහතාගේ බිඳවැටීමට විශාල දායකත්වයක් ලබාදුන්නා. අහිමි වූ කාලය පිරිමැසීමේ අපේක්ෂාවෙන් ඔවුන් පැහැදිලිවම කෙළ ගසමින් සිටිති. ජනාධිපති වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතා ඉදිරියේ ඇති ලොකුම අභියෝගය වනු ඇත්තේ බැසිල් රාජපක්ෂ මහතාට පක්ෂපාතීව සිටින එම කොටස්වල සහය ඇතිව තම පොරොන්දු ඉටු කිරීමය. ඔවුන්ගෙන් බහුතරයක් කැබිනට් තනතුරු ඉල්ලා සිටිනු නිසැකය.",
        "ඊයේ වික්‍රමසිංහට සහාය දුන් මන්ත්‍රීවරුන් සියලු දෙනාම පාහේ ශ්‍රී ලංකා පොදුජන පෙරමුණේ අය වන අතර, ඔහු තම දේශපාලන පැවැත්ම සඳහා ඔවුන් මත යැපෙනු ඇත. විධායක ජනාධිපතිවරයාට වඩා ආණ්ඩු පක්ෂය පාලනය කරන පුද්ගලයා බලවත්. ශ්‍රී ලංකා පොදුජන පෙරමුණ තම මාපටැඟිල්ල යට තබාගෙන සිටින්නේ බැසිල්ය. මිලියන 6.9 ක ජනතාවකින් තේරී පත් වූ ජනාධිපති ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ පවා සිටියේ ඔහුගේ සහෝදරයා වූ බැසිල්ගේ අනුකම්පාවෙනි. සර්ව පාක්ෂික ආණ්ඩුවක් පිහිටුවීමෙන් බැසිල් මත ඕනෑවට වඩා යැපීම වළක්වා ගැනීමට ජනාධිපති වික්‍රමසිංහට හැකි වනු ඇත, එවිට ආර්ථිකය මුදා ගැනීමට සහ ජනතා නැගිටීම්වලින් ප්‍රකාශනය වන ජනතාවගේ දුක් වේදනා සමනය කිරීමට දැඩි උත්සාහයක් ගත හැකිය. නමුත් ඔහුට SJB, SLPP කැරලිකාර කණ්ඩායම සහ JVP ප්‍රමුඛ NPP හි ලණු කිරීමට ඔහුගේ වැඩ කපා හැරෙනු ඇත.",
        "අරගලය යනු මහජන කෝපයේ තුඩක් පමණක් වන අතර වත්මන් පාලනය යනු කුඹගස් සහ ඉරිතැලී ගිය රුවල් සහිත හුදු බැට කෑ පොත්තකි. තමාගේ ආසන්නතම පූර්වගාමියාට අත් වූ ඉරණම වළක්වා ගැනීමට නම් නව ජනාධිපතිවරයා මතක තබා ගත යුතු කරුණකි.",
        "පිළිතුරක් දෙන්න පිළිතුර අවලංගු කරන්න ඔබගේ විද්‍යුත් තැපැල් ලිපිනය ප්‍රකාශයට පත් නොකෙරේ. අවශ්‍ය ක්ෂේත්‍ර සලකුණු කර ඇත *අදහස් නම *",
        "මම ඊළඟ වතාවේ අදහස් දැක්වීම සඳහා මගේ නම, විද්‍යුත් තැපෑල සහ වෙබ් අඩවිය මෙම බ්‍රවුසරයේ සුරකින්න."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "හත්වන",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "2020",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "දෙක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "1999",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "2005",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "2010",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "2015",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "2019",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මැයි",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජුලි",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඊයේ",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "දියවන්නාවේ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "රාජපක්ෂලා",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "පසුගිය මාස කිහිපය",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "මහින්ද රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "SLPP",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "පළාත් පාලන",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගිය අවුරුද්දේ",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඊයේ",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "එජාප",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "යූඑන්එෆ්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "නිවස",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "සිරිසේන-රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "2018",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "එජාප",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "රාජපක්ෂලා",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "දෙක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ව්යවස්ථාව",
            "label": "LAW"
          },
          {
            "text": "තුනෙන් දෙකක්",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "18 වැනි",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "2015",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "20 වැනි සංශෝධනය",
            "label": "LAW"
          },
          {
            "text": "2013",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශිරාණි බණ්ඩාරනායක",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "වසර දෙකකට පසුව",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මෛත්‍රීපාල සිරිසේන",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඊයේ",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂගේ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "බැසිල් රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "මණ්ඩල",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඊයේ",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "බැසිල්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "මිලියන 6.9 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "බැසිල්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "බැසිල්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "එස්.ජේ.බී",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජ.වි.පෙ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "එන්පීපී",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [],
        []
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "ஒரு கனவு நனவாகும் - ரணிலுக்கு",
      "author": "சஹான் வீரசூரிய",
      "body_lines": [
        "ஜனாதிபதி ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க ஏழாவது சொர்க்கத்தில் இருக்கிறார். கடந்த பொதுத் தேர்தலில் (2020), 1999 மற்றும் 2005ல் இரண்டு முறை ஜனாதிபதித் தேர்தலில் போட்டியிட்டு தோல்வியடைந்து, 2010, 2015, 2019 ஆகிய ஆண்டுகளில் ஜனாதிபதி தேர்தலில் போட்டியிட்டுத் துடித்ததால், கடந்த பொதுத் தேர்தலில் (2020) அவர் தோல்வியடைந்தபோது, ​​அவரை அனைவரும் எழுதிக்கொடுத்தனர். ஜூலை. ஆனால், அவரது வயதைப் பொருத்தவரை, நேற்றைய வாக்கெடுப்பின் முடிவு அறிவிக்கப்பட்டபோது, ​​நாடாளுமன்ற புல்வெளியில் வண்டிச் சக்கரங்களைச் சுழற்றிக்கொண்டு விக்கிரமசிங்கவைத் திருப்பியிருக்கலாம். அவரை வாழ்த்தட்டும்!",
        "SLPP ஒரு வெற்றியைப் பெற்று, பாராளுமன்றத்தில் அதன் அரசியல் தசைகளை வளைக்கவில்லை. அரசியல் ரீதியாகப் பார்த்தால், ராஜபக்சக்களுக்கு தியவன்னா வேகமாக ‘நந்திக்கடல்’ ஆகி வருகிறது. அவர்களின் அதிகாரம் இப்போது பாராளுமன்றத்திற்கு மட்டுப்படுத்தப்பட்டுள்ளது, அங்கு அவர்கள் கடுமையான எதிர்ப்பை கடுமையாக எதிர்க்கின்றனர்.",
        "ஜனாதிபதி விக்கிரமசிங்க ஒரே நேரத்தில் அதிர்ஷ்டசாலி மற்றும் துரதிர்ஷ்டவசமானவர், அது முரண்பாடாகத் தோன்றலாம். அவர் மிகவும் விரும்பப்பட்ட ஜனாதிபதி பதவிக்கு குறுக்குவழியை எடுக்க முடிந்ததால் அவர் அதிர்ஷ்டசாலி. அவர் துரதிர்ஷ்டவசமானவர், ஏனெனில் அவர் தேர்ந்தெடுக்கப்பட்ட முன்னோடி ராஜினாமா செய்த நாட்டின் மிக மோசமான அரசியல்-பொருளாதார நெருக்கடியின் மத்தியில் தனது இலக்கை அடைந்துவிட்டார். கடந்த சில மாதங்களில் பல மக்கள் எழுச்சிகள் மற்றும் ஜனாதிபதி கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ஷவின் இராஜினாமாவிற்கு வழிவகுத்த அனைத்து சமூக-பொருளாதார காரணிகளும் இன்னும் உள்ளன. வெகுஜன எதிர்ப்புக்களில் ஒருவித விடுப்பு ஏற்பட்டுள்ளது, ஆனால் தற்போது நாம் அனுபவிப்பது புயலுக்கு முந்தைய அமைதியாக இருக்கலாம். பொதுமக்களின் கோபத்தின் பாரிய உருவாக்கம் அப்படியே உள்ளது, இது நிலையற்ற சமூக ஒழுங்கிற்கு பெரும் ஆபத்தை ஏற்படுத்துகிறது, இது பொருளாதார மீட்சி யதார்த்தமாக மாறுவதற்கு மீட்டெடுக்கப்பட வேண்டும். அரசியலில் பதட்டங்களைத் தணிக்க ஒரே வழி, மோசமான பொருளாதார நெருக்கடிக்கான காரணங்களை அகற்றுவதுதான். நாட்டின் வெளிநாட்டு நாணய கையிருப்பில் குறிப்பிடத்தக்க அதிகரிப்பு இல்லாமல் இந்த பணியை நிறைவேற்ற முடியாது. தேய்த்தல் இருக்கிறது.",
        "ஜனாதிபதி விக்கிரமசிங்க சட்டபூர்வமற்ற அரசாங்கத்தை வழிநடத்துவார். ஜனாதிபதி கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ச மற்றும் பிரதமர் மஹிந்த ராஜபக்ஷ ஆகியோரின் இராஜினாமாக்கள் தற்போதைய SLPP ஆட்சி அதன் சட்டபூர்வமான தன்மையை இழக்க காரணமாக அமைந்தது. அவர்கள்தான் SLPP இன் ஜனாதிபதி மற்றும் பாராளுமன்ற தேர்தல் பிரச்சாரங்களுக்கு தலைமை தாங்கி மக்கள் ஆணையைப் பெற்றனர். ஸ்ரீலங்கா பொதுஜன பெரமுன மக்கள் வீதிக்கு வருவதற்கு முன்னரே மக்கள் பயப்பட ஆரம்பித்தனர். கடந்த ஆண்டு, உள்ளாட்சித் தேர்தலை ஒத்திவைத்ததன் மூலம், பொதுமக்களுக்கு அதன் அச்சத்தை காட்டிக் கொடுத்தது. மக்கள் ஆதரவின் காற்றழுத்தமானியாகக் கருதப்படும் கூட்டுறவுச் சங்கத் தேர்தல்களிலும் தோல்வியடைந்து வருகிறது. இவ்வாறு, ஜனாதிபதி விக்கிரமசிங்க நேற்று பாராளுமன்றத்தில் வெற்றி பெற்றமைக்கு மக்கள் முன் செல்ல மிகவும் அஞ்சும் நிராகரிக்கப்பட்ட அரசியல்வாதிகள் கூட்டத்திற்கு கடன்பட்டிருப்பதை மறந்துவிடக் கூடாது. அவர்களின் முடிவுகள் மக்களின் விருப்பத்தை பிரதிபலிக்கவில்லை.",
        "பாராளுமன்ற பெரும்பான்மை என்பது பொதுமக்களின் அங்கீகாரம் மற்றும் சட்டப்பூர்வமானதாக மொழிபெயர்க்கப்பட வேண்டிய அவசியமில்லை. UNP தலைமையிலான UNF அரசாங்கம் 2018 இல் பாராளுமன்றத்தில் பெரும்பான்மை பலத்தை சேகரித்து 2018 இல் அவசரமாக அமைக்கப்பட்ட சிறிசேன-ராஜபக்ஷ அரசாங்கத்தை டார்பிடோ செய்தது, ஆனால் UNP பொதுத் தேர்தலில் ஒரு இடத்தைக் கூட வெல்ல முடியவில்லை என்பது நினைவிருக்கலாம். ராஜபக்சக்கள் அரசியலமைப்பில் இரண்டு திருத்தங்களை தலா மூன்றில் இரண்டு பெரும்பான்மையுடன் நிறைவேற்றினர், ஆனால் 18 வது திருத்தம் 2015 இல் ஆழமாக ஆறாக இருந்தது, மேலும் தற்போதைய SLPP அரசாங்கமே 20 வது திருத்தத்தை மாற்றியமைத்துள்ளது. 2013 இல், ராஜபக்ச குடும்பத்தின் வேண்டுகோளின் பேரில், பிரதம நீதியரசர் டாக்டர் ஷிராணி பண்டாரநாயக்காவை பாராளுமன்றம் பதவி நீக்கம் செய்தது, ஆனால் இரண்டு ஆண்டுகளுக்குப் பிறகு அப்போதைய ஜனாதிபதி மைத்திரிபால சிறிசேன அவரை மீண்டும் பதவியில் அமர்த்தினார்; அப்போது விக்ரமசிங்கே பிரதமராக இருந்தார்.",
        "SLPP பெருமுதலாளிகள், அதிகாரத்தை துஷ்பிரயோகம் செய்ய முடியாமல், பொது நிதியை திருட முடியாமல், ஊழலில் ஈடுபட முடியாமல், பொதுமக்கள் எதிர்ப்பு காரணமாக, அரசுக்கு எதிரான போராட்டக்காரர்களை கொடூரமான ஒடுக்குமுறை மூலம் பழிவாங்க முயல்வார்கள். ஜனாதிபதி கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ஷ அவர்களின் விருப்பத்தை நிறைவேற்றுமாறு அவர்கள் அழுத்தம் கொடுக்க முயன்றனர், ஆனால் அதிர்ஷ்டவசமாக அவர் எதிர்ப்பாளர்கள் மீது இராணுவத்தை கட்டவிழ்த்து விடுவதற்கு பதிலாக ராஜினாமா செய்தார். ஜனாதிபதி விக்கிரமசிங்கவும் அவர்களின் அழுத்தத்திற்கு அடிபணிய மாட்டார் என்று நம்பலாம்.",
        "நேற்று விக்கிரமசிங்கவுக்கு வாக்களித்த ஸ்ரீலங்கா பொதுஜன பெரமுனவின் பாராளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர்கள் ஜனாதிபதி கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ஷவின் வீழ்ச்சிக்கு பாரிய பங்களிப்பை வழங்கியுள்ளனர். இழந்த நேரத்தை ஈடுசெய்ய முடியும் என்ற எதிர்பார்ப்பில் அவர்கள் வெளிப்படையாக எச்சில் ஊறுகிறார்கள். பசில் ராஜபக்சவுக்கு விசுவாசமாக இருக்கும் அந்த கூறுகளின் உதவியுடன் தனது வாக்குறுதிகளை நிறைவேற்றுவதே ஜனாதிபதி விக்கிரமசிங்கவின் முன் இருக்கும் மிகப்பெரிய சவாலாக இருக்கும். அவர்களில் பெரும்பாலானோர் கேபினட் பதவிகளை கோருவது உறுதி.",
        "நேற்று விக்கிரமசிங்கவை ஆதரித்த அனைத்து பாராளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர்களும் ஸ்ரீலங்கா பொதுஜன பெரமுனவைச் சேர்ந்தவர்கள், மேலும் அவர் தனது அரசியல் பிழைப்புக்காக அவர்களைச் சார்ந்தே இருப்பார். நிறைவேற்று அதிகாரம் கொண்ட ஜனாதிபதியை விட ஆளும் கட்சியை கட்டுப்படுத்தும் நபர் பலசாலி. SLPPயை தனது கட்டைவிரலின் கீழ் வைத்திருப்பவர் பசில் தான். 6.9 மில்லியன் மக்களால் தெரிவுசெய்யப்பட்ட ஜனாதிபதி கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ஷ கூட, அவரது உடன்பிறந்த பசிலின் தயவில் இருந்தார். ஜனாதிபதி விக்கிரமசிங்க அனைத்துக் கட்சி அரசாங்கத்தை அமைப்பதன் மூலம் பசிலை அதிகமாகச் சார்ந்திருப்பதைத் தடுக்க முடியும், இதன் மூலம் பொருளாதாரத்தை மீட்பதற்கும், மக்கள் எழுச்சிகளில் வெளிப்படும் மக்களின் துன்பங்களை சரிசெய்வதற்கும் ஒரு ஒருங்கிணைந்த முயற்சியை மேற்கொள்ள முடியும். ஆனால் SJB, SLPP கிளர்ச்சிக் குழு மற்றும் ஜேவிபி தலைமையிலான NPP ஆகியவற்றில் கயிறு போடுவதற்கு அவர் தனது பணியைக் குறைக்கிறார்.",
        "அரகலயா என்பது பொதுமக்களின் கோபத்தின் நுனி மட்டுமே, மற்றும் தற்போதைய ஆட்சியானது உடைந்த மாஸ்ட்டுகள் மற்றும் கிழிந்த பாய்கள் கொண்ட வெறும் பட்டையாக உள்ளது. புதிய ஜனாதிபதி தனது உடனடி முன்னோடிக்கு நேர்ந்த தலைவிதியைத் தவிர்க்க வேண்டுமானால் இதை மனதில் கொள்ள வேண்டும்.",
        "ஒரு பதிலை விடுங்கள் பதிலை ரத்துசெய் உங்கள் மின்னஞ்சல் முகவரி வெளியிடப்படாது. தேவையான புலங்கள் குறிக்கப்பட்டுள்ளன *கருத்து பெயர் *",
        "அடுத்த முறை நான் கருத்து தெரிவிக்க, எனது பெயர், மின்னஞ்சல் மற்றும் இணையதளத்தை இந்த உலாவியில் சேமிக்கவும்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஏழாவது",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "2020",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இரண்டு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "1999",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "2005",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "2010",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "2015",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "2019",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "மே",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜூலை",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "நேற்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "தியவன்னா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ராஜபக்சேக்கள்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "கடந்த சில மாதங்களாக",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "மஹிந்த ராஜபக்ஷ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "எஸ்.எல்.பி.பி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "உள்ளூர் அரசு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "கடந்த ஆண்டு",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "நேற்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஐ.தே.க",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஐ.தே.மு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "வீடு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "சிறிசேன-ராஜபக்ச",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "2018",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஐ.தே.க",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ராஜபக்சேக்கள்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இரண்டு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "அரசியலமைப்பு",
            "label": "LAW"
          },
          {
            "text": "மூன்றில் இரண்டு பங்கு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "18வது",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "2015",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "20 வது திருத்தம்",
            "label": "LAW"
          },
          {
            "text": "2013",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஷிராணி பண்டாரநாயக்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ராஜபக்சே",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இரண்டு வருடங்கள் கழித்து",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "மைத்திரிபால சிறிசேன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "நேற்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்சவின்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "பசில் ராஜபக்ஷ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "மந்திரி சபை",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "நேற்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "துளசி",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "6.9 மில்லியன்",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "துளசி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "துளசி",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "எஸ்.ஜே.பி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜே.வி.பி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "NPP",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [],
        []
      ]
    }
  }
}