{
  "newspaper_id": "daily-mirror-lk",
  "url": "https://www.dailymirror.lk/breaking_news/Several-trains-off-track-incl-Udaya-Devi-Yal-Devi-this-morning/108-240010",
  "time_ut": 1656476067,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Several trains off track incl. Udaya Devi, Yal Devi this morning",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Several trains off track incl. Udaya Devi, Yal Devi this morning",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "The trains scheduled to leave for Batticaloa and Kankesanthurai (KKS) from Colombo Fort to be cancelled following difficulties faced by the Station Masters (SMs) and junior staff reporting for work due to the prevailing fuel crisis, the Sri Lanka Railways Station Masters' Union (SLRSMU) said.",
        "They said Udaya Devi express train, which was scheduled to leave for Batticaloa from Fort at 6.35 am and Yaal Devi scheduled to leave for KKS at 6.05 am would be cancelled.",
        "Accordingly, the slow train that was scheduled to leave for Polgahawela from Colombo Fort at 9.45 pm yesterday has been cancelled due to the absence of  controllers.",
        "Commuters blamed the railway station staff last night for the sudden cancellation of trains, the union said.",
        "Moreover, it has been unofficially learned that several trains are also scheduled to be cancelled this morning.  (Chaturanga Samarawickrama)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Udaya Devi",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "Yal Devi",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "this morning",
          "label": "TIME"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Kankesanthurai",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Colombo Fort",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Station Masters",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "SMs",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Sri Lanka Railways Station Masters' Union",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "SLRSMU",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Udaya Devi",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Batticaloa",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Fort",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "6.35 am",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "Yaal Devi",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "KKS",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "6.05 am",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "9.45 pm",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "yesterday",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "last night",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "this morning",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "Chaturanga Samarawickrama",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "ඇතුළුව මාර්ගයෙන් බැහැර දුම්රිය කිහිපයක්. අද උදේ උදය දේවි, යාල්දේවි",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "පවතින ඉන්ධන අර්බුදය හේතුවෙන් සේවයට වාර්තා කරන දුම්රිය ස්ථානාධිපතිවරුන් සහ කනිෂ්ඨ කාර්ය මණ්ඩලය මුහුණ දෙන දුෂ්කරතා හේතුවෙන් කොළඹ කොටුවේ සිට මඩකලපුව සහ කන්කසන්තුරය (KKS) බලා පිටත් වීමට නියමිතව තිබූ දුම්රිය අවලංගු කරන බව ශ්‍රී ලංකා දුම්රිය ස්ථානාධිපතිවරුන්ගේ සංගමය පවසයි. SLRSMU) පැවසීය.",
        "කොටුවේ සිට පෙරවරු 6.35 ට මඩකලපුව බලා පිටත් වීමට නියමිතව තිබූ උදයදේවි සීඝ්‍රගාමී දුම්රිය සහ පෙරවරු 6.05 ට KKS බලා පිටත් වීමට නියමිත යාල්දේවි දුම්රිය අවලංගු කරන බව ඔවුහු පැවසූහ.",
        "ඒ අනුව ඊයේ රාත්‍රී 9.45ට කොළඹ කොටුවේ සිට පොල්ගහවෙල බලා පිටත්වීමට නියමිතව තිබූ මන්දගාමී දුම්රිය පාලකවරුන් නොමැතිවීම හේතුවෙන් අවලංගු කර ඇත.",
        "ඊයේ රාත්‍රියේ හදිසියේම දුම්රිය අවලංගු කිරීම සම්බන්ධයෙන් මගීහු දුම්රිය ස්ථාන කාර්ය මණ්ඩලයට දොස් පැවරූ බව එම සංගමය පවසයි.",
        "මීට අමතරව අද පෙරවරුවේ දුම්රිය කිහිපයක් ද අවලංගු කිරීමට නියමිත බව නිල නොවන ලෙස දැනගන්නට ඇත. (චතුරංග සමරවික්‍රම)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "උදය දේවි",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "යාල් දේවි",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "මේ උදෑසන",
          "label": "TIME"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "කන්කසන්තුරේ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "කොළඹ කොටුව",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "දුම්රිය ස්ථානාධිපතිවරු",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "කෙටි පණිවිඩ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකා දුම්රිය ස්ථානාධිපතිවරුන්ගේ සංගමය",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "SLRSMU",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "උදය දේවි",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "මඩකලපුව",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "බලකොටුව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "6.35 ට",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "යාල් දේවි",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "කේ.කේ.එස්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "6.05 පෙ.ව",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ප.ව.9.45",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඊයේ",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "අවසන් රාත්රිය",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "මේ උදෑසන",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "චතුරංග සමරවික්‍රම",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "பல ரயில்கள் தடம்புரண்டது உட்பட. இன்று காலை உதயாதேவி, யாழ்தேவி",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "நிலவும் எரிபொருள் நெருக்கடி காரணமாக பணிக்கு வரவிருக்கும் நிலைய அதிபர்கள் (SMs) மற்றும் இளநிலை ஊழியர்களுக்கு ஏற்பட்ட சிரமங்களைத் தொடர்ந்து கொழும்பு கோட்டையிலிருந்து மட்டக்களப்பு மற்றும் காங்கேசன்துறைக்கு (KKS) புறப்படவிருந்த புகையிரதங்கள் இரத்து செய்யப்படுவதாக இலங்கை புகையிரத நிலைய அதிபர்கள் சங்கம் தெரிவித்துள்ளது. SLRSMU) கூறினார்.",
        "கோட்டையில் இருந்து காலை 6.35 மணிக்கு மட்டக்களப்புக்கு புறப்படவிருந்த உதயதேவி விரைவு ரயிலும், 6.05 மணிக்கு KKS க்கு செல்லவிருந்த யாழ்தேவி ரயிலும் ரத்து செய்யப்படுவதாக அவர்கள் தெரிவித்தனர்.",
        "அதன்படி, நேற்று இரவு 9.45 மணிக்கு கொழும்பு கோட்டையிலிருந்து பொல்கஹவெல நோக்கி புறப்படவிருந்த ஸ்லோ ரயில் கட்டுப்பாட்டாளர்கள் இல்லாத காரணத்தினால் ரத்து செய்யப்பட்டுள்ளது.",
        "நேற்றிரவு திடீரென ரயில்கள் ரத்து செய்யப்பட்டதற்கு ரயில் நிலைய ஊழியர்கள் மீது பயணிகள் குற்றம் சாட்டியுள்ளனர்.",
        "மேலும், இன்று காலை பல ரயில்கள் ரத்து செய்யப்பட உள்ளதாக அதிகாரப்பூர்வமற்ற தகவல் வெளியாகியுள்ளது. (சதுரங்க சமரவிக்ரம)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "உதயா தேவி",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "யாழ் தேவி",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "இன்று காலை",
          "label": "TIME"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "காங்கேசன்துறை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "கொழும்பு கோட்டை",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஸ்டேஷன் மாஸ்டர்கள்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "எஸ்.எம்.எஸ்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை ரயில்வே ஸ்டேஷன் மாஸ்டர்ஸ் யூனியன்",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "எஸ்.எல்.ஆர்.எஸ்.எம்.யு",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "உதயா தேவி",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "மட்டக்களப்பு",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "கோட்டை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "காலை 6.35 மணி",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "யாழ் தேவி",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "கே.கே.எஸ்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "காலை 6.05 மணி",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இரவு 9.45",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "நேற்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "நேற்று இரவு",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இன்று காலை",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "சதுரங்க சமரவிக்ரம",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}