{
  "newspaper_id": "ada-lk",
  "url": "https://www.ada.lk/breaking_news/ශ්‍රී-ලංකාව-බංකොලොත්වීමට-චීන-ණය-හා-ව්‍යාපෘති-හේතුවක්-නෙමෙයි/11-395853",
  "time_ut": 1659089874,
  "original_lang": "si",
  "original_title": "ශ්‍රී ලංකාව බංකොලොත්වීමට චීන ණය හා ව්‍යාපෘති හේතුවක් නෙමෙයි",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Chinese loans and projects are not the reason for Sri Lanka's bankruptcy",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "China rejected the allegation made by Samantha Power of the United States that one of the main reasons for Sri Lanka's bankruptcy was opaque loans and unproductive projects by China.",
        "China's Ministry of Foreign Affairs spokesman Zhao Lijian said that the economic development of Sri Lanka increased through the development projects implemented by China in Sri Lanka.",
        "\"China-Sri Lanka practical cooperation has always been conducted by Sri Lanka based on scientific plans and has nothing to do with full verification,\" Chinese Foreign Ministry spokesperson said at the daily press conference.",
        "\"Chinese projects have boosted Sri Lanka's economic development and brought tangible benefits to the Sri Lankan people,\" he said. Rejecting Samantha Power's allegations, Zhao said, \"Sri Lanka's foreign debt has multiple components, and China-related debt is a much smaller share than international capital markets and multilateral development banks.\" Namely.",
        "\"China has provided Sri Lanka with low interest rates and long-term preferential loans, which have played a positive role in improving Sri Lanka's infrastructure and livelihoods,\" he said.",
        "He also said that US policies, including interest rate hikes, unilateral sanctions and massive stimulus policies, which have seriously affected many developing countries such as Sri Lanka, are the cause of the world economic crisis.",
        "\"The recent sudden interest rate hikes in the United States have caused great damage to global economic and financial markets,\" he noted.",
        "\"Rising prices of energy, food and other commodities have worsened through US unilateral sanctions and tariff barriers. This has further aggravated the financial and economic situation of many developing countries, including Sri Lanka.\" He said."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Chinese",
          "label": "NORP"
        },
        {
          "text": "Sri Lanka's",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "China",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Samantha Power",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the United States",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "one",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka's",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "China",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "China",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ministry of Foreign Affairs",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Zhao Lijian",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "China",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "China-Sri Lanka",
            "label": "WORK_OF_ART"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Chinese",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Foreign Ministry",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "daily",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Chinese",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka's",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lankan",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Samantha Power's",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka's",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "China",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "China",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka's",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "US",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the United States",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "US",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "ශ්‍රී ලංකාව බංකොලොත්වීමට චීන ණය හා ව්‍යාපෘති හේතුවක් නෙමෙයි",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකාව බංකොලොත්වීමට ප්‍රධාන හේතුවෙක් වූයෙ චීනය විසින් ශ්‍රී ලංකාවට පාරාන්ධ ණය හා ඵලදායි නොවන ව්‍යාපෘති බව ඇමෙරිකාවේ සමන්තා පවර් කළ චෝදනාව චීනය ප්‍රතික්ෂේප කළේය.",
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකාව තුළ චීනය ක්‍රියාත්මක කළ සංවර්ධන ව්‍යාපෘති හරහා ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ ආර්ථික සංවර්ධනය ඉහළ ගිය බව චීන විදේශ කටයුතු අමාත්‍යාංශයෙ ප්‍රකාශක ෂාවෝ ලිජියන් පැවැසීය.",
        "\"චීන-ශ්‍රී ලංකා ප්‍රායෝගික සහයෝගීතාව සෑම විටම ශ්‍රී ලංකාව විසින් මෙහෙයවනු ලැබුවේ විද්‍යාත්මක සැලසුම්  අනුවයි. ඒ වගේම සම්පූර්ණ සත්‍යාපනයක් සමඟ කිසිදු සම්බන්ධයක් නොමැතිවයි\" චීන විදේශ අමාත්‍යාංශයේ ප්‍රකාශකවරයා දිනපතා පැවැත්වෙන මාධ්‍ය හමුවට එක්වෙමින් පැවැසීය.",
        "\"චීන ව්‍යාපෘති ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ ආර්ථික සංවර්ධනය ඉහළ නංවා ඇති අතර ශ්‍රී ලාංකික ජනතාවට ප්‍රත්‍යක්ෂ ප්‍රතිලාභ ගෙන දී ඇත\" යැයි ඔහු පැවැසීය. සමන්තා පවර්ගේ චෝදනා ප්‍රතික්ෂේප කරමින් ෂාඕ පැවසුවේ, \"ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ විදේශ ණය සඳහා බහුවිධ සංරචක ඇති අතර, චීනය හා සම්බන්ධ ණය ජාත්‍යන්තර ප්‍රාග්ධන වෙළඳපොළට සහ බහුපාර්ශ්වික සංවර්ධන බැංකුවලට වඩා බෙහෙවින් අඩු පංගුවක් වෙයි.\" යනුවෙනි.",
        "\"ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ යටිතල පහසුකම් සහ ජීවනෝපාය වැඩිදියුණු කිරීම සඳහා ධනාත්මක කාර්යභාරයක් ඉටු කර ඇති අඩු පොලී අනුපාත සහ දිගු කාලීන වරණීය ණය ශ්‍රී ලංකාව සඳහා චීනය සපයා තිබෙනවා\" ඔහු පැවසීය.",
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකාව වැනි බොහෝ සංවර්ධනය වෙමින් පවතින රටවලට බරපතල ලෙස බලපා ඇති පොලී අනුපාත ඉහළ දැමීම්, ඒකපාර්ශ්වික සම්බාධක සහ දැවැන්ත උත්තේජක ප්‍රතිපත්ති ඇතුළු එක්සත් ජනපද ප්‍රතිපත්ති ලෝක ආර්ථික අර්බුදයට හේතුවක් බවද ඔහු පැවැසීය.",
        "\"එක්සත් ජනපදයේ මෑත කාලීන හදිසි පොලී අනුපාත ඉහල දැමීම් ගෝලීය ආර්ථික හා මූල්‍ය වෙලඳපොලවල් විශාල හානියක් ඇතිකර තිබෙනවා. \" ඔහු සඳහන් කළේය.",
        "\"එක්සත් ජනපදයේ ඒකපාර්ශ්වික සම්බාධක සහ තීරුබදු බාධක හරහා බලශක්ති, ආහාර සහ අනෙකුත් භාණ්ඩවල මිල ඉහළ යාම නරක අතට හැරී තිබෙනවා. මෙය ශ්‍රී ලංකාව ඇතුළු බොහෝ සංවර්ධනය වෙමින් පවතින රටවල මූල්‍ය හා ආර්ථික තත්ත්වය තවදුරටත් උග්‍ර කර තිබෙනවා.\" ඔහු පැවසීය."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "චීන",
          "label": "NORP"
        },
        {
          "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "චීනය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "සමන්තා පවර්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "එක්සත් ජනපදය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "එක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "චීනය",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "චීනය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "විදේශ කටයුතු අමාත්යංශය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Zhao Lijian",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "චීනය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "චීනය - ශ්‍රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "WORK_OF_ART"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "චීන",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "විදේශ අමාත්‍යාංශය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "දිනපතා",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "චීන",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලාංකික",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "සමන්තා පවර්ගේ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "චීනය",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "චීනය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "එක්සත් ජනපදය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "එක්සත් ජනපදය",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "එක්සත් ජනපදය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "இலங்கையின் திவால் நிலைக்கு சீனக் கடன்களும் திட்டங்களும் காரணம் அல்ல",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "இலங்கையின் வங்குரோத்து நிலைக்கு சீனாவின் ஒளிபுகா கடன்கள் மற்றும் பலனளிக்காத திட்டங்களே பிரதான காரணம் என அமெரிக்காவின் சமந்தா பவர் முன்வைத்த குற்றச்சாட்டை சீனா நிராகரித்தது.",
        "இலங்கையில் சீனாவினால் முன்னெடுக்கப்படும் அபிவிருத்தித் திட்டங்களினூடாக இலங்கையின் பொருளாதார அபிவிருத்தி அதிகரித்துள்ளதாக சீனாவின் வெளிவிவகார அமைச்சின் பேச்சாளர் சாவோ லிஜியன் தெரிவித்துள்ளார்.",
        "சீன வெளிவிவகார அமைச்சின் செய்தித் தொடர்பாளர் தினசரி செய்தியாளர் மாநாட்டில், சீன வெளிவிவகார அமைச்சின் செய்தித் தொடர்பாளர், “சீனா-இலங்கை நடைமுறை ஒத்துழைப்பு எப்போதும் விஞ்ஞானத் திட்டங்களின் அடிப்படையில் இலங்கையால் நடத்தப்படுகிறது.",
        "\"சீன திட்டங்கள் இலங்கையின் பொருளாதார வளர்ச்சியை உயர்த்தியதுடன், இலங்கை மக்களுக்கு உறுதியான நன்மைகளையும் கொண்டு வந்துள்ளது\" என்று அவர் கூறினார். சமந்தா பவரின் குற்றச்சாட்டுகளை நிராகரித்த ஜாவோ, \"இலங்கையின் வெளிநாட்டுக் கடன் பல கூறுகளைக் கொண்டுள்ளது, மேலும் சீனா தொடர்பான கடன் சர்வதேச மூலதனச் சந்தைகள் மற்றும் பலதரப்பு வளர்ச்சி வங்கிகளை விட மிகக் குறைவான பங்காகும்\" என்றார். அதாவது.",
        "\"சீனா இலங்கைக்கு குறைந்த வட்டி விகிதங்கள் மற்றும் நீண்ட கால முன்னுரிமை கடன்களை வழங்கியுள்ளது, இது இலங்கையின் உள்கட்டமைப்பு மற்றும் வாழ்வாதாரத்தை மேம்படுத்துவதில் சாதகமான பங்கைக் கொண்டுள்ளது,\" என்று அவர் கூறினார்.",
        "இலங்கை போன்ற பல வளரும் நாடுகளை கடுமையாக பாதித்துள்ள அமெரிக்க கொள்கைகள், வட்டி விகித உயர்வு, ஒருதலைப்பட்ச தடைகள் மற்றும் பாரிய ஊக்கக் கொள்கைகள் உள்ளிட்டவை உலகப் பொருளாதார நெருக்கடிக்குக் காரணம் என்றும் அவர் கூறினார்.",
        "\"அமெரிக்காவில் சமீபத்திய திடீர் வட்டி விகித உயர்வுகள் உலகளாவிய பொருளாதார மற்றும் நிதிச் சந்தைகளில் பெரும் சேதத்தை ஏற்படுத்தியுள்ளன\" என்று அவர் குறிப்பிட்டார்.",
        "\"அமெரிக்காவின் ஒருதலைப்பட்ச தடைகள் மற்றும் கட்டணத் தடைகள் மூலம் எரிசக்தி, உணவு மற்றும் பிற பொருட்களின் விலையேற்றம் மோசமடைந்துள்ளது. இது இலங்கை உட்பட பல வளரும் நாடுகளின் நிதி மற்றும் பொருளாதார நிலைமையை மேலும் மோசமாக்கியுள்ளது.\" அவன் சொன்னான்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "சீன",
          "label": "NORP"
        },
        {
          "text": "இலங்கையின்",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "சீனா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சமந்தா பவர்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஐக்கிய நாடுகள்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஒன்று",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கையின்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சீனா",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "சீனா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "வெளிநாட்டு அலுவல்கள் அமைச்சு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Zhao Lijian",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சீனா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "சீனா-இலங்கை",
            "label": "WORK_OF_ART"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சீன",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "வெளியுறவு அமைச்சகம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "தினசரி",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "சீன",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கையின்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "சமந்தா பவர் தான்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கையின்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சீனா",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "சீனா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கையின்",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "எங்களுக்கு",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஐக்கிய நாடுகள்",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "எங்களுக்கு",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}