{
  "newspaper_id": "ada-lk",
  "url": "https://www.ada.lk/breaking_news/ඉන්ධන-අර්බුදයෙන්-බැටකන-ධීවරයින්/11-395537",
  "time_ut": 1658212029,
  "original_lang": "si",
  "original_title": "ඉන්ධන අර්බුදයෙන් බැටකන ධීවරයින්",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Fishermen suffering from fuel crisis",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "Mannar Fishermen's Associations point out that nearly 2000 fishermen families are suffering due to severe shortage of fuel in Mannar due to which the fishermen in Mannar have not traveled for almost one and a half months.",
        "Due to the lack of fuel for the fishing vessels, a large number of fishermen have been unable to go to sea and the economy of the fishermen has been severely affected, according to the Mannar Fishermen's Association.",
        "Also, due to fishermen not going to sea, the price of fish in Mannar has increased excessively, where Kutti fish, Thalapat, Thora, Mora, Kelawalla, Balaya etc. fish are sold at a price of nearly 2500 rupees, the consumers are also in dire straits.",
        "Also, although fish was transported from Mannar to Colombo to various areas in the past, the fish transport has stopped completely due to lack of fuel, Mannar fishermen say.",
        "Meanwhile, the Mannar fishermen's associations have further requested the authorities to implement some assistance program for the fishermen in Mannar as their daily economy has been severely affected due to their inability to go to the sea to catch fish."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Mannar Fishermen's",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Associations",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "nearly 2000",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Mannar",
            "label": "WORK_OF_ART"
          },
          {
            "text": "Mannar",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the Mannar Fishermen's Association",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Mannar",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kutti",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Thalapat",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Mora",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kelawalla",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "2500",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Mannar",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Mannar",
            "label": "WORK_OF_ART"
          },
          {
            "text": "Mannar",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "daily",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "ඉන්ධන අර්බුදයෙන් බැටකන ධීවරයින්",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "පවතින දැඩි ඉන්ධන හිගය හේතුවෙන් මන්නාරමේ ධීවරයින් මාස එකහමාරකට ආසන්න කාලයක් මුහුදු ගමන් නොයෑම හේතුවෙන් ධීවර පවුල් 2000 කට ආසන්න ප්‍රමාණයක් දැඩි පීඩාවන්ට පත්ව සිටින බවට මන්නාරම් ධීවර සංගම් පෙන්වා දෙයි.",
        "ධීවර යාත්‍රා වෙනුවෙන් අවශ්‍ය ඉන්ධන නොමැතිකම හේතුවෙන් ධීවරයින් විශාල පිරිසකට මුහුදු යාමට නොහැකි වී තිබෙන අතරම එම ධීවරයින්ගේ ආර්ථිකයට දැඩි බලපෑමක් එල්ල වී ඇතැයිද මන්නාරම් ධීවර සංගම් විසින් පවසයි.",
        "එමෙන්ම ධීවරයින් මුහුදු ගමන් නොයෑම හේතුවෙන් මන්නාරමේ මාළු මිල ගණණ් අධික ලෙසින් ඉහල ගොස් ඇති අතර එහිදී කුට්ටි මාළු  තලපත්, තෝරා , මෝරා, කෙලවල්ලා, බලයා ආදි මත්ස්‍ය කිලෝව රුපියල් 2500 කට ආසන්න මිලකට අලෙවි වීම හේතුවෙන් පාරිභෝගිකයින්ද දැඩි අසීරුතාවන්ට පත්ව සිටිති.",
        "එමෙන්ම මන්නාරමේ සිට කොළඹ දක්වා පසුගිය කාලයේදී විවිධ ප්‍රදේශයන් වෙත මාළු ප්‍රවාහනය කෙරුනද මේ වන විට මත්ස්‍ය ප්‍රවාහනයද ඉන්ධන නොමැතිකම හේතුවෙන් සම්පූරණයෙන්ම නැවතී ඇතැයි මන්නාරම් ධීවරයින් පවසති.",
        "මේ අතර මන්නාරමේ ධීවරයින්ට මසුන් ඇල්ලීමට මුහුදු යාමට නොහැකි වීම හේතුවෙන් ඔවුන්ගේ දෛනික ආර්ථිකයට දැඩි බලපෑමක් එල්ල වීමත් සමග එම ධීවරයින් වෙනුවෙන් කිසියම් ආධාර වැඩසටහනක් ක්‍රියාත්මක කරන ලෙසටද මන්නාරම් ධීවර සංගම් විසින් බලධාරීන්ගෙන් වැඩිදුරටත් ඉල්ලා සිටියි."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "මන්නාරම ධීවරයින්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "සංගම්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "2000 පමණ",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "මන්නාරම",
            "label": "WORK_OF_ART"
          },
          {
            "text": "මන්නාරම",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "මන්නාරම ධීවර සංගමය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "මන්නාරම",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "කුට්ටි",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "තලපත්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "මෝරා",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "කෙලවල්ල",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "2500",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "මන්නාරම",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "මන්නාරම",
            "label": "WORK_OF_ART"
          },
          {
            "text": "මන්නාරම",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "දිනපතා",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "எரிபொருள் பற்றாக்குறையால் மீனவர்கள் தவித்து வருகின்றனர்",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "மன்னாரில் ஏற்பட்டுள்ள கடும் எரிபொருள் தட்டுப்பாடு காரணமாக சுமார் ஒன்றரை மாதங்களாக மன்னாரில் உள்ள மீனவர்கள் சுற்றுலா செல்லாமல் சுமார் 2000 மீனவ குடும்பங்கள் தவித்து வருவதாக மன்னார் கடற்றொழிலாளர் சங்கங்கள் சுட்டிக்காட்டுகின்றன.",
        "மீன்பிடி படகுகளுக்கு எரிபொருள் இல்லாததால் பெருமளவான மீனவர்கள் கடலுக்கு செல்ல முடியாமல் மீனவர்களின் பொருளாதாரம் பெரிதும் பாதிக்கப்பட்டுள்ளதாக மன்னார் மீனவர் சங்கம் தெரிவித்துள்ளது.",
        "மேலும், மீனவர்கள் கடலுக்குச் செல்லாத காரணத்தினால், மன்னாரில் மீன்களின் விலை அதீதமாக அதிகரித்துள்ள நிலையில், அங்குள்ள குட்டி மீன், தலபட், தோர, மோர, கெலவல்ல, பலயா போன்ற மீன்கள் சுமார் 2500 ரூபாவுக்கு விற்பனை செய்யப்படுவதால், நுகர்வோரும் அதிகளவில் உள்ளனர். இக்கட்டான நிலையில்.",
        "மேலும், கடந்த காலங்களில் மன்னாரிலிருந்து கொழும்புக்கு பல்வேறு பகுதிகளுக்கு மீன்கள் கொண்டு செல்லப்பட்ட போதிலும், எரிபொருள் பற்றாக்குறையால் மீன் போக்குவரத்து முற்றாக நிறுத்தப்பட்டுள்ளதாக மன்னார் மீனவர்கள் தெரிவிக்கின்றனர்.",
        "இதேவேளை, மன்னார் கடற்றொழிலாளர்கள் கடலுக்குச் சென்று மீன் பிடிக்க முடியாமல் அன்றாடப் பொருளாதாரம் பாரியளவில் பாதிக்கப்பட்டுள்ள நிலையில், மன்னார் மீனவர்களுக்கு ஏதாவது உதவித் திட்டத்தை நடைமுறைப்படுத்துமாறு மன்னார் கடற்றொழிலாளர் சங்கங்கள் மேலும் அதிகாரிகளிடம் கோரிக்கை விடுத்துள்ளன."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "மன்னார் மீனவர்கள்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "சங்கங்கள்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "கிட்டத்தட்ட 2000",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "மன்னார்",
            "label": "WORK_OF_ART"
          },
          {
            "text": "மன்னார்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "மன்னார் மீனவர் சங்கம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "மன்னார்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "குட்டி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "தலபத்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "மோரா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "கெலவல்லா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "2500",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "மன்னார்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "மன்னார்",
            "label": "WORK_OF_ART"
          },
          {
            "text": "மன்னார்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "தினசரி",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}