{
  "newspaper_id": "lankadeepa-lk",
  "url": "https://www.lankadeepa.lk/latest_news/පාර්ලිමේන්තුව-වාර-අවසන්-කරයි/1-617199",
  "time_ut": 1659022169,
  "original_lang": "si",
  "original_title": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව වාර අවසන් කරයි",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Parliament ends its term",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "Parliament (the second session of the Ninth Parliament) was adjourned today (28) from midnight.",
        "As indicated in the gazette announcement, the parliament which has ended its term will be ceremonially reopened by the President on Wednesday, the 3rd of next month.",
        "After ceremonially opening the Parliament, President Ranil Wickremesinghe will present his manifesto.",
        "A parliamentary official said that after a new president is appointed, it is a common tradition to open the parliament at the end of the term.",
        "With the end of the term of Parliament, more than 50 committees, including CoP, Copa, were abolished. In order for those committees to become active, their members must be appointed and re-established."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Parliament",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "second",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Ninth Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "28",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Wednesday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the 3rd of next month",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "more than 50",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "CoP",
            "label": "WORK_OF_ART"
          },
          {
            "text": "Copa",
            "label": "LOC"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව වාර අවසන් කරයි",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව ( නවවෙනි පාර්ලිමේන්තුවේ දෙවැනි සැසිවාරය) අද (28)  මධ්‍යම රාත්‍රියේ සිට වාර අවසාන කෙරිණ.",
        "වාර අවසාන කෙරුණු  පාර්ලිමේන්තුව ගැසට් නිවේදනයේ  දැක්වෙන අන්දමට  ජනපතිවරයා විසින්  උත්සවාකාරයෙන් නැවත විවෘත කෙරෙන්නේ ලබන මස 3  වැනිදා බදාදාය.",
        "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව උත්සවාකාරයෙන් විවෘත කිරීමෙන් අනතුරුව ජනාධිපති රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතා  සිය ප්‍රතිපත්ති ප්‍රකාශනය ඉදිරිපත්  කරනු ඇත.",
        "නව ජනාධිපතිවරයකු පත් වූ පසු පාර්ලිමේන්තුව වාරඅවසාන කර උත්සවාකාරයෙන් විවෘත කිරීම  සාමාන්‍ය සම්ප්‍රදායක් බව පාර්ලිමේන්තු නිලධාරියෙක් පැවැසීය.",
        "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව  වාර අවසාන කිරීමත් සමගම එහි කෝප්, කෝපා ඇතුළු   කමිටු 50 කට වැඩි සංඛ්‍යාවක් අහෝසිවී ගියේය. එම කමිටු සක්‍රියවීමට නම් ඒවායේ  සාමාජිකයන් පත්කර නැවතත් පිහිටවනු ලැබිය යුතු වෙයි."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "දෙවැනි",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "නවවැනි පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "28",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "බදාදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ලබන මාසේ 3 වෙනිදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "50 ට වැඩි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "CoP",
            "label": "WORK_OF_ART"
          },
          {
            "text": "කෝපා",
            "label": "LOC"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "பாராளுமன்றத்தின் பதவிக்காலம் முடிவடைகிறது",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "பாராளுமன்றம் (ஒன்பதாவது பாராளுமன்றத்தின் இரண்டாவது அமர்வு) இன்று (28) நள்ளிரவு முதல் ஒத்திவைக்கப்பட்டது.",
        "வர்த்தமானி அறிவிப்பில் சுட்டிக்காட்டப்பட்டுள்ளபடி, பதவிக்காலம் நிறைவடைந்துள்ள பாராளுமன்றம் எதிர்வரும் 3ஆம் திகதி புதன்கிழமை ஜனாதிபதியினால் சம்பிரதாயபூர்வமாக மீண்டும் திறக்கப்படும்.",
        "பாராளுமன்றத்தை சம்பிரதாயபூர்வமாக திறந்து வைத்ததன் பின்னர் ஜனாதிபதி ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க தனது விஞ்ஞாபனத்தை சமர்ப்பிக்கவுள்ளார்.",
        "புதிய ஜனாதிபதி நியமிக்கப்பட்ட பின்னர், பதவிக்காலம் முடிந்ததும் பாராளுமன்றத்தை திறப்பது வழமையான மரபு என பாராளுமன்ற அதிகாரி ஒருவர் தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "நாடாளுமன்றத்தின் பதவிக்காலம் முடிவடைந்த நிலையில், கோப், கோபா உள்ளிட்ட 50க்கும் மேற்பட்ட கமிட்டிகள் ரத்து செய்யப்பட்டன. அந்த கமிட்டிகள் செயல்படுவதற்கு, அவற்றின் உறுப்பினர்கள் நியமிக்கப்பட்டு மீண்டும் நிறுவப்பட வேண்டும்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இரண்டாவது",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஒன்பதாவது பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "28",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "புதன்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "அடுத்த மாதம் 3ம் தேதி",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "50க்கு மேல்",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "சிஓபி",
            "label": "WORK_OF_ART"
          },
          {
            "text": "கோபா",
            "label": "LOC"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}