{
  "newspaper_id": "virakesari-lk",
  "url": "http://www.virakesari.lk/article/131300",
  "time_ut": 1657610847,
  "original_lang": "ta",
  "original_title": "இந்தியாவால் வழங்கப்பட்ட உரம் இன்று விநியோகம் - விவசாய அமைச்சு",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Fertilizer Distribution Today by India - Ministry of Agriculture",
      "author": "Digital Desk 5",
      "body_lines": [
        "The Ministry of Agriculture has informed that the amount of urea fertilizer received by the Government of India to Sri Lanka will be distributed from today.",
        "Landing of fertilizer from the fertilizer ship which arrived in the country a few days ago from India has been completed.",
        "In this case, the Anath Ministry has further informed that they expect to distribute and complete them within the next 10 days.",
        "Regarding the quality of the said fertilizer, a special test was conducted yesterday and a certificate has been issued that the amount of fertilizer is of appropriate quality.",
        "Director General of National Fertilizer Secretariat Chandana Lokhu Hevake said that a 50 kg fertilizer bag will be available to the farmers for 10,000 rupees."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Today",
          "label": "DATE"
        },
        {
          "text": "India - Ministry of Agriculture",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "The Ministry of Agriculture",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Government of India to Sri Lanka",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "a few days ago",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "India",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the Anath Ministry",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the next 10 days",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "yesterday",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "National Fertilizer Secretariat Chandana Lokhu Hevake",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "50 kg",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "10,000",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "ඉන්දියාවෙන් අද පොහොර බෙදා හැරීම - කෘෂිකර්ම අමාත්‍යාංශය",
      "author": "ඩිජිටල් මේසය 5",
      "body_lines": [
        "ඉන්දීය රජය ශ්‍රී ලංකාවට ලැබුණු යූරියා පොහොර ප්‍රමාණය අද සිට බෙදාහරින බව කෘෂිකර්ම අමාත්‍යාංශය දැනුම් දී ඇත.",
        "ඉන්දියාවේ සිට මීට දින කිහිපයකට පෙර මෙරටට පැමිණි පොහොර නෞකාවෙන් පොහොර ගොඩබෑම අවසන් කර තිබෙනවා.",
        "මෙම නඩුවේදී, ඉදිරි දින 10 තුළ ඒවා බෙදාහැර අවසන් කිරීමට බලාපොරොත්තු වන බව අනාත් අමාත්‍යාංශය වැඩිදුරටත් දන්වා ඇත.",
        "එම පොහොරවල ප්‍රමිතිය සම්බන්ධයෙන් ඊයේ විශේෂ පරීක්ෂණයක් පවත්වා එම පොහොර ප්‍රමාණය සුදුසු තත්ත්වයේ බවට සහතිකයක් නිකුත් කර තිබේ.",
        "ජාතික පොහොර ලේකම් කාර්යාලයේ අධ්‍යක්ෂ ජනරාල් චන්දන ලොකු හේවාකේ මහතා පැවසුවේ කිලෝ ග්‍රෑම් 50ක පොහොර මිටියක් රුපියල් 10,000කට ගොවීන්ට ලබා දෙන බවයි."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "අද",
          "label": "DATE"
        },
        {
          "text": "ඉන්දියාව - කෘෂිකර්ම අමාත්‍යාංශය",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "කෘෂිකර්ම අමාත්‍යාංශය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දීය රජය ශ්‍රී ලංකාවට",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "දින කිහිපයකට පෙර",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "අනාත් අමාත්‍යාංශය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉදිරි දින 10",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ඊයේ",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ජාතික පොහොර ලේකම් කාර්යාලය චන්දන ලොකු හේවාකේ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "කිලෝ ග්රෑම් 50 කි",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "10,000 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "இந்தியாவால் வழங்கப்பட்ட உரம் இன்று விநியோகம் - விவசாய அமைச்சு",
      "author": "Digital Desk 5",
      "body_lines": [
        "இந்திய அரசாங்கத்தால் இலங்கைக்கு பெற்றுக்கொடுக்கப்பட்ட யூரியா உரத் தொகை இன்று முதல் விநியோகிக்கப்படவுள்ளதாக விவசாய அமைச்சு தெரிவித்துள்ளது.",
        "இந்தியாவில் இருந்து கடந்த சில தினங்களுக்கு முன் நாட்டிற்கு வந்தடைந்த உரக் கப்பலில் இருந்து உரத்தை தரையிறக்கும் பணிகள் நிறைவடைந்துள்ளன.",
        "இந்நிலையில் அவற்றை எதிர்வரும் 10 நாட்களுக்குள் விநியோகித்து நிறைவு செய்ய எதிர்ப்பார்த்துள்ளதாக அநத் அமைச்சு மேலும் தெரிவித்துள்ளது.",
        "குறித்த உரத்தின் தரம் தொடர்பில் நேற்றைய தினம் விசேட பரிசோதனை மேற்கொள்ளப்பட்ட நிலையில் உரத் தொகை உரிய தரத்துடன் உள்ளதாக சான்றிதழ் வழங்கப்பட்டுள்ளது.",
        "50 கிலோ கிராம் உர மூடை ஒன்று 10 ஆயிரம் ரூபாவுக்கு விவசாயிகளுக்கு பெற்றுக்கொடுக்கப்படவுள்ளதாக தேசிய உர செயலகத்தின் பணிப்பாளர் நாயகம் சந்தன லொகு ஹேவகே தெரிவித்தார்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "இன்று",
          "label": "DATE"
        },
        {
          "text": "இந்தியா - விவசாய அமைச்சகம்",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "விவசாய அமைச்சகம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்திய அரசு இலங்கைக்கு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஒரு சில நாட்களுக்கு முன்பு",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்தியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "அனத் அமைச்சகம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "அடுத்த 10 நாட்கள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "நேற்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "தேசிய உர செயலகம் சந்தன லொகு ஹேவகே",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "50 கிலோ",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "10,000",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}