{
  "newspaper_id": "economy-next-com",
  "url": "https://economynext.com/sri-lanka-to-appoint-cost-of-living-committee-chaired-by-president-as-prices-soar-96939/",
  "time_ut": 1657003620,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Sri Lanka to appoint cost of living committee chaired by president as prices soar",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Sri Lanka to appoint cost of living committee chaired by president as prices soar",
      "author": "",
      "body_lines": [
        "ECONOMYNEXT – Sri Lanka’s cabinet of ministers has approved the appointment of an eight-member committee headed by President Gotabaya Rajapaksa on the cost of living, after inflation in the currency crisis-hit country rose to 54.6 percent.",
        "The committee is tasked with recommending policy and practical solutions to maintaining a stable cost of living, co-cabinet spokesman Minister Bandula Gunawardena said.",
        "The committee, headed by the president, will comprise Prime Minister Ranil Wickremesinghe, and the ministers of fisheries, transport & highways, agriculture, plantations, power & energy, and trade, commerce & food security.",
        "The cabinet has also approved a food security committee to be chaired by Minister of Trade, Commerce & Food Security Nalin Fernando and relevant ministry secretaries, said Gunawardena.",
        "Food prices in Sri Lanka rose 80.1 percent in the 12 months from June 2021 to June 2022.",
        "Food prices have risen 102.7 percent since February 2020 when aggressive open market operations to create a ‘developmental state’ began.",
        "Sri Lanka’s inflation grew 54.6 percent inflation in the 12 months to June 2022, with the central bank driving up consumer prices in the capital Colombo 12.8 percent during the month, official data showed.",
        "The Colombo Consumer Price Index, the most widely watched price gauge rose to 220.2 points from 195.2 points a month earlier after two years of money printing and a collapse of a soft-peg.",
        "Sri Lanka inflation hits 54.6-pct in June 2022 after money printing",
        "Unprecedented forex shortages in Sri Lanka have led to crippling shortages of essentials including fuel, and public anger is at an all time high with massive protests planned for July 09 demanding the resignation of President Gotabaya Rajapaksa and the government. (Colombo/Jul05/2022)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Sri Lanka",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka’s",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "eight",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Gotabaya Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "54.6 percent",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Bandula Gunawardena",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "transport &",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "power & energy",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "commerce &",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Trade, Commerce & Food",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Nalin Fernando",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Gunawardena",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "80.1 percent",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "the 12 months from June 2021 to June 2022",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "102.7 percent",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "February 2020",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "54.6 percent",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "the 12 months to June 2022",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Colombo",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "12.8 percent",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "the month",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "220.2",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "195.2",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "a month earlier after two years",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "54.6",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "June 2022",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "July 09",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Gotabaya Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "මිල ඉහළ යන විට ශ්‍රී ලංකාව ජනාධිපතිවරයාගේ ප්‍රධානත්වයෙන් ජීවන වියදම් කමිටුවක් පත් කරයි",
      "author": "",
      "body_lines": [
        "ECONOMYNEXT - මුදල් අර්බුදයෙන් පීඩාවට පත් රටේ උද්ධමනය සියයට 54.6 දක්වා ඉහළ යාමෙන් පසු ජීවන වියදම පිළිබඳ ජනාධිපති ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ මහතාගේ ප්‍රධානත්වයෙන් අට දෙනෙකුගෙන් යුත් කමිටුවක් පත් කිරීමට ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ අමාත්‍ය මණ්ඩලය අනුමැතිය ලබා දී ඇත.",
        "ස්ථාවර ජීවන වියදමක් පවත්වාගෙන යාම සඳහා ප්‍රතිපත්තිමය සහ ප්‍රායෝගික විසඳුම් නිර්දේශ කිරීම මෙම කමිටුවට පැවරී ඇති බව සම කැබිනට් ප්‍රකාශක අමාත්‍ය බන්දුල ගුණවර්ධන මහතා පැවසීය.",
        "ජනාධිපතිවරයාගේ ප්‍රධානත්වයෙන් යුත් කමිටුවට අග්‍රාමාත්‍ය රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතා සහ ධීවර, ප්‍රවාහන සහ මහාමාර්ග, කෘෂිකර්ම, වැවිලි, විදුලිබල හා බලශක්ති, වෙළෙඳ, වාණිජ සහ ආහාර සුරක්ෂිතතා යන අමාත්‍යවරුන් ඇතුළත් වේ.",
        "වෙළඳ, වාණිජ සහ ආහාර සුරක්ෂිතතා අමාත්‍ය නලින් ප්‍රනාන්දු සහ අදාළ අමාත්‍යාංශ ලේකම්වරුන්ගේ ප්‍රධානත්වයෙන් ආහාර සුරක්ෂිතතා කමිටුවක් ද කැබිනට් මණ්ඩලය විසින් අනුමත කර ඇති බව ගුණවර්ධන මහතා පැවසීය.",
        "2021 ජුනි සිට 2022 ජුනි දක්වා මාස 12 තුළ ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ ආහාර මිල සියයට 80.1 කින් ඉහළ ගොස් ඇත.",
        "‘සංවර්ධන රාජ්‍යයක්’ නිර්මාණය කිරීමේ ආක්‍රමණශීලී විවෘත වෙළෙඳපොළ මෙහෙයුම් ආරම්භ වූ 2020 පෙබරවාරි මාසයේ සිට ආහාර මිල ගණන් සියයට 102.7 කින් ඉහළ ගොස් ඇත.",
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ උද්ධමනය 2022 ජුනි දක්වා මාස 12 තුළ සියයට 54.6කින් උද්ධමනය වර්ධනය වී ඇති අතර, මහ බැංකුව විසින් කොළඹ අගනුවර පාරිභෝගික මිල ගණන් මාසය තුළ සියයට 12.8කින් ඉහළ දමා ඇති බව නිල දත්ත පෙන්වා දෙයි.",
        "කොළඹ පාරිභෝගික මිල දර්ශකය, වැඩිම පිරිසක් විසින් නරඹන ලද මිල දර්ශකය, වසර දෙකකට පෙර මුදල් මුද්‍රණයෙන් සහ සොෆ්ට්-පෙග් බිඳවැටීමෙන් පසු මාසයකට පෙර ඒකක 195.2 සිට ඒකක 220.2 දක්වා ඉහළ ගියේය.",
        "මුදල් මුද්‍රණයෙන් පසු 2022 ජුනි මාසයේදී ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ උද්ධමනය සියයට 54.6ක් විය",
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ පෙර නොවූ විරූ විදේශ විනිමය හිඟයක් ඉන්ධන ඇතුළු අත්‍යවශ්‍ය ද්‍රව්‍ය හිඟයකට තුඩු දී ඇති අතර, ජනාධිපති ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ මහතාට සහ රජයට ඉල්ලා අස්වන ලෙස බල කරමින් ජූලි 09 වැනිදා පැවැත්වීමට නියමිත දැවැන්ත විරෝධතා සමඟ මහජන කෝපය ඉහළ මට්ටමක පවතී. (කොළඹ/ජූලි 05/2022)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "අට",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "සියයට 54.6 කි",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "බන්දුල ගුණවර්ධන",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ප්‍රවාහනය සහ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "බලය සහ ශක්තිය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "වාණිජ හා",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "වෙළඳ, වාණිජ සහ ආහාර",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "නලින් ප්‍රනාන්දු",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගුණවර්ධන ය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "සියයට 80.1 කි",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "2021 ජුනි සිට 2022 ජුනි දක්වා මාස 12",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "සියයට 102.7 කි",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "2020 පෙබරවාරි",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "සියයට 54.6 කි",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "2022 ජූනි සිට මාස 12",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "කොළඹ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "සියයට 12.8 කි",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "මාසය",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "220.2",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "195.2",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "වසර දෙකකට පසු මාසයකට පෙර",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "54.6",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "2022 ජූනි",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජූලි 09",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "விலைவாசி உயர்வினால் ஜனாதிபதி தலைமையில் வாழ்க்கைச் செலவுக் குழுவை இலங்கை நியமிக்கவுள்ளது",
      "author": "",
      "body_lines": [
        "பொருளாதாரம் - நாணய நெருக்கடியால் பாதிக்கப்பட்ட நாட்டில் பணவீக்கம் 54.6 சதவீதமாக உயர்ந்ததை அடுத்து, வாழ்க்கைச் செலவு தொடர்பாக ஜனாதிபதி கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ஷ தலைமையிலான எட்டு பேர் கொண்ட குழுவை நியமிக்க இலங்கையின் அமைச்சரவை ஒப்புதல் அளித்துள்ளது.",
        "நிலையான வாழ்க்கைச் செலவை பேணுவதற்கான கொள்கை மற்றும் நடைமுறை தீர்வுகளை பரிந்துரைக்கும் பணியை இந்த குழு கொண்டுள்ளது என இணை அமைச்சரவை பேச்சாளர் அமைச்சர் பந்துல குணவர்தன தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "ஜனாதிபதி தலைமையிலான குழுவில் பிரதமர் ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க மற்றும் மீன்பிடி, போக்குவரத்து மற்றும் நெடுஞ்சாலைகள், விவசாயம், பெருந்தோட்டங்கள், மின்சாரம் மற்றும் எரிசக்தி, வர்த்தகம், வர்த்தகம் மற்றும் உணவுப் பாதுகாப்பு அமைச்சர்கள் அங்கம் வகிக்கின்றனர்.",
        "வர்த்தகம், வர்த்தகம் மற்றும் உணவு பாதுகாப்பு அமைச்சர் நலின் பெர்னாண்டோ மற்றும் சம்பந்தப்பட்ட அமைச்சின் செயலாளர்கள் தலைமையில் உணவு பாதுகாப்பு குழுவொன்றுக்கு அமைச்சரவை அங்கீகாரம் வழங்கியுள்ளதாக குணவர்தன தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "ஜூன் 2021 முதல் ஜூன் 2022 வரையிலான 12 மாதங்களில் இலங்கையில் உணவுப் பொருட்களின் விலை 80.1 சதவீதம் அதிகரித்துள்ளது.",
        "பிப்ரவரி 2020 முதல், 'வளர்ச்சி நிலையை' உருவாக்குவதற்கான ஆக்ரோஷமான திறந்த சந்தை நடவடிக்கைகள் தொடங்கியதில் இருந்து உணவு விலைகள் 102.7 சதவீதம் உயர்ந்துள்ளன.",
        "இலங்கையின் பணவீக்கம் ஜூன் 2022 வரையிலான 12 மாதங்களில் 54.6 சதவீத பணவீக்கத்தை அதிகரித்தது, மத்திய வங்கி தலைநகர் கொழும்பில் நுகர்வோர் விலைகளை 12.8 சதவீதமாக உயர்த்தியுள்ளது என்று அதிகாரப்பூர்வ தகவல்கள் தெரிவிக்கின்றன.",
        "கொழும்பு நுகர்வோர் விலைச் சுட்டெண், மிகவும் பரவலாகப் பார்க்கப்படும் விலை மானி, இரண்டு வருட பணம் அச்சடித்தல் மற்றும் ஒரு சாஃப்ட்-பெக் சரிவின் பின்னர் ஒரு மாதத்திற்கு முன்னர் 195.2 புள்ளிகளிலிருந்து 220.2 புள்ளிகளாக உயர்ந்தது.",
        "ஜூன் 2022 இல் பணம் அச்சிடப்பட்ட பின்னர் இலங்கையின் பணவீக்கம் 54.6 சதவீதத்தை எட்டியது",
        "இலங்கையில் முன்னெப்போதும் இல்லாத அந்நிய செலாவணி தட்டுப்பாடு எரிபொருள் உள்ளிட்ட அத்தியாவசியப் பொருட்களின் பற்றாக்குறைக்கு வழிவகுத்தது மற்றும் ஜனாதிபதி கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ஷ மற்றும் அரசாங்கத்தை பதவி விலகக் கோரி ஜூலை 09 ஆம் தேதி பாரிய போராட்டங்களை நடத்த திட்டமிடப்பட்டுள்ளதால் பொதுமக்களின் கோபம் உச்சத்தில் உள்ளது. (கொழும்பு/ஜூலை05/2022)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "இலங்கை",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கையின்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "எட்டு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "54.6 சதவீதம்",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பந்துல குணவர்தன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "போக்குவரத்து மற்றும்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "சக்தி மற்றும் ஆற்றல்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "வணிகம் &",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "வர்த்தகம், வணிகம் & உணவு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "நளின் பெர்னாண்டோ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "குணவர்தன",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "80.1 சதவீதம்",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜூன் 2021 முதல் ஜூன் 2022 வரையிலான 12 மாதங்கள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "102.7 சதவீதம்",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "பிப்ரவரி 2020",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "54.6 சதவீதம்",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜூன் 2022 முதல் 12 மாதங்கள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "கொழும்பு",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "12.8 சதவீதம்",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "மாதம்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "220.2",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "195.2",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "இரண்டு ஆண்டுகளுக்குப் பிறகு ஒரு மாதம் முன்பு",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "54.6",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜூன் 2022",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜூலை 09",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}