{
  "newspaper_id": "news-first-lk",
  "url": "https://www.newsfirst.lk/2022/08/23/mtv-joins-freesat-a-digital-satellite-television-platform/",
  "time_ut": 1661263500,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "MTV joins Freesat – a Digital Satellite Television Platform",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "MTV joins Freesat – a Digital Satellite Television Platform",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); MTV Channel (Pvt) Ltd, comprising of Sirasa TV, Shakthi TV, TV-1, and News 1st, entered into an agreement with Digital Satellite Television Platform freesat in Colombo on Tuesday (23).",
        "Freesat, a digital satellite media platform, broadcasting on the latest DVB-S2X technology, has the unique proposition of offering its channels free to users.",
        "The agreements were officially exchanged between Susara Dinal, the CEO of MTV Channel (Pvt) Ltd. and Kaminda Samarakoon, the CEO of freesat.",
        "\"We wanted to have a service where we are able to provide all the Sri Lankans to have a proper quality picture. Our technology is DVB-S2X. This is the world's second platform, and we are proud to have it in Sri Lanka,\" said Kaminda Samarakoon, the CEO of Freesat.",
        "\"Every single household in Sri Lanka can access SD or HD or 4K pictures in greater quality using this platform. We used the widely accepted DVB-S2X technology. Our compression technology is H265 or HEVC. It is not used by anyone in Sri Lanka at the moment,\" said Pranalanka Warunawansa, the Chief Technical Officer of Freesat",
        "The partnership between MTV Channel Pvt Ltd and Freesat will see your favourite three local TV channels, Sirasa, Shakthi, TV-1 and of course your trusted news provider, News 1st, available absolutely free and with crystal clear reception on Freesat.",
        "Stop using PTA, and immediately rescind Detention Orders – BASL tells President"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "MTV",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "Freesat",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "Digital Satellite Television Platform",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "News 1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "MTV Channel (Pvt) Ltd",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sirasa TV",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Shakthi TV",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "News 1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Digital Satellite Television Platform",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Colombo",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Tuesday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "23",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Freesat",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Susara Dinal",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "MTV Channel (Pvt) Ltd.",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kaminda Samarakoon",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lankans",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "second",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kaminda Samarakoon",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Freesat",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "H265",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "HEVC",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Pranalanka Warunawansa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Freesat",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "MTV Channel Pvt Ltd",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "three",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sirasa",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "News 1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Freesat",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "PTA",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "MTV ඩිජිටල් චන්ද්‍රිකා රූපවාහිනී වේදිකාවක් වන Freesat හා සම්බන්ධ වේ",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); MTV Channel (Pvt) Ltd, Sirasa TV, Shakthi TV, TV-1, සහ News 1st සමන්විත වන අතර, Digital Satellite Television Platform freesat සමඟ අඟහරුවාදා (23) කොළඹදී ගිවිසුමකට එළඹුණි.",
        "Freesat, ඩිජිටල් චන්ද්‍රිකා මාධ්‍ය වේදිකාවක්, නවතම DVB-S2X තාක්‍ෂණයෙන් විකාශනය කරයි, එහි නාලිකා පරිශීලකයින්ට නොමිලේ පිරිනැමීමේ සුවිශේෂී යෝජනාවක් ඇත.",
        "MTV Channel (Pvt) Ltd හි ප්‍රධාන විධායක නිලධාරී සුසාර දිනාල් සහ freesat හි ප්‍රධාන විධායක නිලධාරී කමින්ද සමරකෝන් අතර මෙම ගිවිසුම් නිල වශයෙන් හුවමාරු විය.",
        "\"අපට අවශ්‍ය වූයේ සියලුම ශ්‍රී ලාංකිකයින්ට නිසි ගුණාත්මක චිත්‍රයක් ලබා දීමට හැකි සේවාවක් ලබා ගැනීමටයි. අපගේ තාක්‍ෂණය DVB-S2X වේ. මෙය ලෝකයේ දෙවන වේදිකාව වන අතර එය ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ තිබීම ගැන අපි ආඩම්බර වෙමු.\" යැයි Freesat හි ප්‍රධාන විධායක නිලධාරී කමින්ද සමරකෝන් මහතා පැවසීය.",
        "\"මෙම වේදිකාව භාවිතයෙන් ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ සෑම නිවසකටම SD හෝ HD හෝ 4K පින්තූර වඩාත් ගුණාත්මකව ප්‍රවේශ විය හැක. අපි බහුලව පිළිගත් DVB-S2X තාක්ෂණය භාවිතා කළෙමු. අපගේ සම්පීඩන තාක්ෂණය H265 හෝ HEVC වේ. එය ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ කිසිවෙකු විසින් භාවිතා නොකෙරේ. ඒ මොහොත\" යනුවෙන් ෆ්‍රීසැට් හි ප්‍රධාන තාක්ෂණික නිලධාරී ප්‍රනාලංකා වරුණවංශ මහතා පැවසීය",
        "MTV Channel Pvt Ltd සහ Freesat අතර සහයෝගීතාවයෙන් ඔබගේ ප්‍රියතම දේශීය රූපවාහිනී නාලිකා තුන වන Sirasa, Shakthi, TV-1 සහ ඇත්ත වශයෙන්ම ඔබගේ විශ්වාසනීය පුවත් සපයන්නෙකු වන News 1st, සම්පූර්ණයෙන්ම නොමිලේ සහ Freesat හි පැහැදිලි පිළිගැනීමක් සහිතව ලබා ගත හැකිය.",
        "ත්‍රස්තවාදය වැළැක්වීමේ පනත භාවිතා කිරීම නවත්වන්න, රැඳවුම් නියෝග වහාම අවලංගු කරන්න - BASL ජනපතිට කියයි"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "MTV",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "Freesat",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "ඩිජිටල් චන්ද්‍රිකා රූපවාහිනී වේදිකාව",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "News 1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "MTV Channel (Pvt) Ltd",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "සිරස ටී.වී",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශක්ති ටී.වී",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "News 1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඩිජිටල් චන්ද්‍රිකා රූපවාහිනී වේදිකාව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "කොළඹ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "අඟහරුවාදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "23",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Freesat",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "සුසාර දිනාල්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "MTV Channel (Pvt) Ltd.",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "කාමින්ද සමරකෝන්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලාංකිකයන්",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "දෙවැනි",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "කාමින්ද සමරකෝන්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Freesat",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "H265",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "HEVC",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ප්‍රනාලංකා වරුණවංශ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Freesat",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "MTV Channel Pvt Ltd",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "තුන්",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "සිරස",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "News 1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Freesat",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "PTA",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "எம்டிவி ஃப்ரீசாட் - டிஜிட்டல் செயற்கைக்கோள் தொலைக்காட்சி மேடையில் இணைகிறது",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); MTV Channel (Pvt) Ltd, Sirasa TV, Shakthi TV, TV-1 மற்றும் News 1st ஆகியன இணைந்து, டிஜிட்டல் Satellite Television Platform freesat உடன் செவ்வாய்க்கிழமை (23) கொழும்பில் உடன்படிக்கை ஒன்றை மேற்கொண்டது.",
        "ஃப்ரீசாட், டிஜிட்டல் சாட்டிலைட் மீடியா தளம், சமீபத்திய DVB-S2X தொழில்நுட்பத்தில் ஒளிபரப்பு, அதன் சேனல்களை பயனர்களுக்கு இலவசமாக வழங்கும் தனித்துவமான முன்மொழிவைக் கொண்டுள்ளது.",
        "MTV Channel (Pvt) Ltd. இன் பிரதம நிறைவேற்று அதிகாரியான Susara Dinal மற்றும் freesat இன் CEO கமிந்த சமரகோன் ஆகியோருக்கு இடையில் இந்த ஒப்பந்தங்கள் உத்தியோகபூர்வமாக பரிமாறிக்கொள்ளப்பட்டன.",
        "\"எல்லா இலங்கையர்களுக்கும் சரியான தரமான படத்தை வழங்கக்கூடிய ஒரு சேவையை நாங்கள் பெற விரும்புகிறோம். எங்கள் தொழில்நுட்பம் DVB-S2X. இது உலகின் இரண்டாவது தளமாகும், மேலும் இதை இலங்கையில் வைத்திருப்பதில் நாங்கள் பெருமை கொள்கிறோம்.\" ஃப்ரீசாட் நிறுவனத்தின் பிரதம நிறைவேற்று அதிகாரி கமிந்த சமரகோன் தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "\"இலங்கையில் உள்ள ஒவ்வொரு குடும்பமும் இந்த தளத்தைப் பயன்படுத்தி அதிக தரத்தில் SD அல்லது HD அல்லது 4K படங்களை அணுக முடியும். நாங்கள் பரவலாக ஏற்றுக்கொள்ளப்பட்ட DVB-S2X தொழில்நுட்பத்தைப் பயன்படுத்தினோம். எங்கள் சுருக்க தொழில்நுட்பம் H265 அல்லது HEVC ஆகும். இது இலங்கையில் எவராலும் பயன்படுத்தப்படவில்லை அந்த தருணம்\" என்று ஃப்ரீசாட்டின் தலைமை தொழில்நுட்ப அதிகாரி பிரணலங்கா வருணவன்ச தெரிவித்தார்",
        "எம்டிவி சேனல் பிரைவேட் லிமிடெட் மற்றும் ஃப்ரீசாட் இடையேயான கூட்டாண்மை உங்களுக்கு பிடித்த மூன்று உள்ளூர் டிவி சேனல்களான சிரச, சக்தி, டிவி-1 மற்றும் நிச்சயமாக உங்கள் நம்பகமான செய்தி வழங்குநரான நியூஸ் 1st ஆகியவை ஃப்ரீசாட்டில் முற்றிலும் இலவசமாகவும் தெளிவான வரவேற்புடனும் கிடைக்கும்.",
        "PTA ஐப் பயன்படுத்துவதை நிறுத்துங்கள், உடனடியாக தடுப்பு உத்தரவுகளை ரத்து செய்யுங்கள் - BASL ஜனாதிபதியிடம் கூறுகிறது"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "எம்டிவி",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "ஃப்ரீசாட்",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "டிஜிட்டல் செயற்கைக்கோள் தொலைக்காட்சி மேடை",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "News 1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "எம்டிவி சேனல் (பிரைவேட்) லிமிடெட்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "சிரச டி.வி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "சக்தி டி.வி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "News 1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "டிஜிட்டல் செயற்கைக்கோள் தொலைக்காட்சி மேடை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "கொழும்பு",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "செவ்வாய்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "23",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஃப்ரீசாட்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "சுசரா தினால்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "எம்டிவி சேனல் (பிரைவேட்) லிமிடெட்.",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "கமிந்த சமரகோன்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கையர்கள்",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "இரண்டாவது",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "கமிந்த சமரகோன்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஃப்ரீசாட்",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "H265",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "HEVC",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "பிரணலங்கா வருணவன்ச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஃப்ரீசாட்",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "எம்டிவி சேனல் பிரைவேட் லிமிடெட்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "மூன்று",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "சிரச",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "News 1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஃப்ரீசாட்",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "PTA",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}