{
  "newspaper_id": "economy-next-com",
  "url": "https://economynext.com/to-resume-flights-russia-has-sought-sl-assurance-of-not-repeating-aeroflot-action-sirisena-96915/",
  "time_ut": 1656970620,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "To resume flights, Russia has sought SL assurance of not repeating Aeroflot action-Sirisena",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "To resume flights, Russia has sought SL assurance of not repeating Aeroflot action-Sirisena",
      "author": "",
      "body_lines": [
        "ECONOMYNEXT – Russia has sought an assurance from the Sri Lankan government of not repeating the diplomatic spat it followed including legal action after grounding an aircraft operated by Russia’s Aeroflot in Colombo, former president Maithripala Sirisena told the parliament.",
        "The aircraft was grounded in Colombo early in June following a court order obtained by Celestial Aviation Trading 10 Limited of Ireland, the owner of the aircraft, against Aeroflot in a Colombo court, over a lease dispute.",
        "Sri Lanka’s action has created a diplomatic spat with Russia, which has threatened of impact in the bilateral trade and flight services, government sources have said.",
        "Former president Maithripala Sirisena said he wrote a letter to Russian President Vladimir Putin on the issues faced by Sri Lanka after the Aeroflot action. Sri Lanka has rendered apology for its action.",
        "“I got a reply after three days I sent the letter. I have also forwarded that letter to Presient Gotabaya Rajapaksa. There are three key facts mentioned in the latter,” Sirisena told the parliament on Monday (04).",
        "“If we could fulfill the requests, the bilateral trade and flight services could be resumed. The first one they had mentioned was the issue of the Aeroflot could be prevented through diplomatic channels instead of going for legal issue.”",
        "“The second one was the Russian government had asked an assurance that there won’t be any repeat of Aeroflot on which legal action was taken. If there is an assurance, they could start flight services.”",
        "Sirisena also said the third fact written by the Russian President was that the trade does not have to go through the Russian embassy in Colombo and instead individual companies could directly deal with Russian companies for bilateral trade.",
        "Government officials are divided on the way Aeroflot issue was handled. Some say the government should have sought diplomatic channels while others say it was a legal issue hence the way it was handled was appropriate.",
        "On 2 June 2022, the Commercial High Court of the Western Province issued an enjoining order on the Aeroflot flight restraining it from taking off from Sri Lanka’s main airport near Colombo.",
        "The case relates to a commercial dispute between the plaintiff, Celestial Aviation Trading 10 Limited, an Irish company, against the first defendant the public joint stock company “Aeroflot” and the second defendant, N C Abeywardene/Acting Head of Air Navigation/Airport and Aviation Services of Sri Lanka (AASL), Katunayake.",
        "Later the Sri Lankan Court suspended an order preventing the Aeroflot flight from leaving Sri Lanka. The order was suspended after the Colombo Commercial High Court considered a motion filed by the Attorney General.",
        "The Airbus A330-343 operated by Russian state-owned airline Aeroflot was denied permission to fly to Moscow as scheduled on June 2nd amid a legal dispute with a leasing company. The flight had more than 200 passengers onboard. (Colombo/July 5/2022)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Russia",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "SL",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "Aeroflot",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Russia",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lankan",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Russia",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Aeroflot in Colombo",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Maithripala Sirisena",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "June",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Celestial Aviation Trading 10 Limited",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ireland",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Aeroflot",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka’s",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Russia",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Maithripala Sirisena",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Russian",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Vladimir Putin",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Aeroflot",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "three days",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Presient Gotabaya Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "three",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Monday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "04",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "first",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Aeroflot",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "second",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Russian",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Aeroflot",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "third",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Russian",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Russian",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Russian",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Aeroflot",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "2 June 2022",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Commercial High Court",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Western Province",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Aeroflot",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka’s",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Colombo",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Celestial Aviation Trading 10 Limited",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Irish",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "first",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Aeroflot",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "second",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "N C Abeywardene",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Air Navigation/Airport",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Aviation Services of Sri Lanka",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Katunayake",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the Sri Lankan Court",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Aeroflot",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Airbus",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "A330-343",
            "label": "PRODUCT"
          },
          {
            "text": "Russian",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Aeroflot",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Moscow",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "June 2nd",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "more than 200",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "ගුවන් ගමන් නැවත ආරම්භ කිරීම සඳහා රුසියාව Aeroflot ඇක්ෂන් නැවත සිදු නොකරන බවට ශ්‍රී ලංකා සහතිකය ඉල්ලා ඇත-සිරිසේන",
      "author": "",
      "body_lines": [
        "ECONOMYNEXT - රුසියාවේ Aeroflot විසින් ක්‍රියාත්මක කරන ලද ගුවන් යානයක් කොළඹට ගොඩබෑමෙන් පසු නීතිමය ක්‍රියාමාර්ග ඇතුළුව තමන් අනුගමනය කළ රාජ්‍යතාන්ත්‍රික ගැටුම නැවත සිදු නොකිරීමට රුසියාව ශ්‍රී ලංකා රජයෙන් සහතිකයක් ඉල්ලා ඇති බව හිටපු ජනාධිපති මෛත්‍රීපාල සිරිසේන මහතා පාර්ලිමේන්තුවට පැවසීය.",
        "කල්බදු ආරවුලක් මත Aeroflot සමාගමට එරෙහිව Aeroflot සමාගමට එරෙහිව ගුවන් යානයේ හිමිකරු වන අයර්ලන්තයේ Celestial Aviation Trading 10 Limited විසින් ලබාගත් අධිකරණ නියෝගයකට අනුව ජුනි මස මුලදී මෙම යානය කොළඹට ගොඩබස්වන ලදී.",
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ ක්‍රියාව රුසියාව සමඟ රාජ්‍ය තාන්ත්‍රික ගැටුමක් නිර්මාණය කර ඇති අතර එය ද්විපාර්ශ්වික වෙළඳ සහ ගුවන් සේවාවලට බලපෑම් කිරීමේ තර්ජනයට ලක්ව ඇති බව රජයේ ආරංචි මාර්ග පවසයි.",
        "Aeroflot ක්‍රියාමාර්ගයෙන් පසු ශ්‍රී ලංකාව මුහුණ දී ඇති ගැටලු සම්බන්ධයෙන් රුසියානු ජනාධිපති ව්ලැඩිමීර් පුටින් වෙත ලිපියක් යොමු කළ බව හිටපු ජනාධිපති මෛත්‍රීපාල සිරිසේන මහතා පවසයි. ශ්‍රී ලංකාව සිය ක්‍රියාව සම්බන්ධයෙන් සමාව අයැද සිටී.",
        "“මම ලිපිය යවා දින තුනකට පසු මට පිළිතුරක් ලැබුණා. මම ඒ ලිපිය ජනාධිපති ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ මහතාටත් යොමු කර තිබෙනවා. දෙවැන්නෙහි සඳහන් වන ප්‍රධාන කරුණු තුනක් තිබේ,” සිරිසේන සඳුදා (04) පාර්ලිමේන්තුවට පැවසීය.",
        "“අපට ඉල්ලීම් ඉටු කළ හැකි නම්, ද්විපාර්ශ්වික වෙළඳ සහ ගුවන් සේවා නැවත ආරම්භ කළ හැකිය. ඔවුන් මුලින්ම සඳහන් කළේ Aeroflot ප්‍රශ්නය නීතිමය ප්‍රශ්නයකට නොගොස් රාජ්‍ය තාන්ත්‍රික මාර්ග හරහා වළක්වා ගත හැකි බවයි.",
        "“දෙවැන්න නම් රුසියානු රජය නීතිමය ක්‍රියාමාර්ග ගත් Aeroflot නැවත සිදු නොවන බවට සහතිකයක් ඉල්ලා සිටීමයි. සහතිකයක් තිබේ නම්, ඔවුන්ට ගුවන් සේවා ආරම්භ කළ හැකිය.",
        "රුසියානු ජනාධිපතිවරයා විසින් ලියා ඇති තුන්වන කරුණ වන්නේ වෙළඳාම කොළඹ පිහිටි රුසියානු තානාපති කාර්යාලය හරහා යා යුතු නැති බවත් ඒ වෙනුවට තනි තනි සමාගම්වලට ද්විපාර්ශ්වික වෙළඳාම සඳහා රුසියානු සමාගම් සමඟ සෘජුව ගනුදෙනු කළ හැකි බවත් සිරිසේන පැවසීය.",
        "Aeroflot ප්‍රශ්නය හසුරුවන ආකාරය සම්බන්ධයෙන් රජයේ නිලධාරීන් බෙදී ඇත. ඇතැමුන් පවසන්නේ රජය රාජ්‍ය තාන්ත්‍රික මාර්ග සොයා යා යුතුව තිබූ බවයි. තවත් සමහරු පවසන්නේ එය නීතිමය ප්‍රශ්නයක් බැවින් එය හසුරුවන ආකාරය සුදුසු බවයි.",
        "2022 ජූනි 2 වැනි දින බස්නාහිර පළාතේ වාණිජ මහාධිකරණය විසින් Aeroflot ගුවන් යානය කොළඹට ආසන්න ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ ප්‍රධාන ගුවන් තොටුපළෙන් ගුවන්ගත වීම වළක්වමින් වාරණ නියෝගයක් නිකුත් කළේය.",
        "මෙම නඩුව පළමු විත්තිකරු වන පොදු හවුල් කොටස් සමාගමක් වන “Aeroflot” සහ දෙවන විත්තිකරු වන N C අබේවර්ධන / ගුවන් නාවික/ගුවන් තොටුපළ සහ ගුවන් සේවා වැඩබලන ප්‍රධානියාට එරෙහිව අයර්ලන්ත සමාගමක් වන Celestial Aviation Trading 10 Limited සමාගම අතර වාණිජමය ආරවුලක් සම්බන්ධයෙනි. ශ්‍රී ලංකා සේවා (AASL), කටුනායක.",
        "පසුව Aeroflot ගුවන් යානය ශ්‍රී ලංකාවෙන් පිටවීම වළක්වාලමින් ශ්‍රී ලංකා අධිකරණය විසින් නිකුත් කර තිබූ නියෝගය අත්හිටුවනු ලැබුවා. කොළඹ වාණිජ මහාධිකරණය විසින් නීතිපතිවරයා විසින් ගොනු කරන ලද මෝසමක් සලකා බැලීමෙන් අනතුරුව එම නියෝගය අත්හිටුවා ඇත.",
        "රුසියානු රජය සතු ගුවන් සමාගමක් වන Aeroflot විසින් මෙහෙයවනු ලබන එයාර්බස් A330-343 ලීසිං සමාගමක් සමඟ ඇති වූ නීතිමය ආරවුලක් මධ්‍යයේ ජුනි 2 වැනිදා නියමිත පරිදි මොස්කව් වෙත පියාසර කිරීමට අවසර ලබා නොදෙන ලදී. ගුවන් යානයේ මගීන් 200 කට වැඩි පිරිසක් සිටියහ. (කොළඹ/ජූලි 5/2022)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "රුසියාව",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "එස්.එල්",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "Aeroflot",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "රුසියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලාංකික",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "රුසියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "කොළඹ Aeroflot",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "මෛත්‍රීපාල සිරිසේන",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ජූනි",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Celestial Aviation Trading 10 Limited",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "අයර්ලන්තය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Aeroflot",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "රුසියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "මෛත්‍රීපාල සිරිසේන",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "රුසියානු",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ව්ලැඩිමීර් පුටින්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Aeroflot",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "දවස් තුනක්",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජනාධිපති ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "තුන්",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "සඳුදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "04",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "පළමුවන",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Aeroflot",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "දෙවැනි",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "රුසියානු",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Aeroflot",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "තෙවන",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "රුසියානු",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "රුසියානු",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "රුසියානු",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Aeroflot",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "2 ජූනි 2022",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "වාණිජ මහාධිකරණය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "බස්නාහිර පළාත",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Aeroflot",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "කොළඹ",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Celestial Aviation Trading 10 Limited",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "අයර්ලන්ත",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "පළමුවන",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Aeroflot",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "දෙවැනි",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "එන් සී අබේවර්ධන",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගුවන් සංචලනය/ගුවන් තොටුපළ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ ගුවන් සේවා",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "කටුනායක",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකා අධිකරණය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Aeroflot",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "එයාර් බස්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "A330-343",
            "label": "PRODUCT"
          },
          {
            "text": "රුසියානු",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Aeroflot",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "මොස්කව්",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජූනි 2 වැනිදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "200 ට වැඩි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "விமானங்களை மீண்டும் தொடங்க, ஏரோஃப்ளோட் நடவடிக்கையை மீண்டும் செய்ய மாட்டோம் என்ற உறுதிமொழியை ரஷ்யா கோரியுள்ளது-சிறிசேன",
      "author": "",
      "body_lines": [
        "பொருளாதாரம் - கொழும்பில் ரஷ்யாவின் ஏரோஃப்ளோட் விமானத்தை தரையிறக்கிய பின்னர், சட்ட நடவடிக்கை உட்பட, தான் பின்பற்றிய இராஜதந்திர தகராறுகளை மீண்டும் செய்யமாட்டோம் என்ற உத்தரவாதத்தை இலங்கை அரசாங்கத்திடம் ரஷ்யா கோரியுள்ளதாக முன்னாள் ஜனாதிபதி மைத்திரிபால சிறிசேன நாடாளுமன்றத்தில் தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "விமானத்தின் உரிமையாளரான அயர்லாந்தின் செலஸ்டியல் ஏவியேஷன் டிரேடிங் 10 லிமிடெட், ஏரோஃப்ளோட்டிற்கு எதிராக, குத்தகை தகராறு தொடர்பாக, கொழும்பு நீதிமன்றத்தில் பெற்ற நீதிமன்ற உத்தரவைத் தொடர்ந்து, ஜூன் மாத தொடக்கத்தில், கொழும்பில் விமானம் தரையிறக்கப்பட்டது.",
        "இலங்கையின் இந்த நடவடிக்கையானது ரஷ்யாவுடன் இராஜதந்திர ரீதியான முரண்பாட்டை உருவாக்கியுள்ளது, இது இருதரப்பு வர்த்தகம் மற்றும் விமான சேவைகளில் தாக்கத்தை ஏற்படுத்தும் என்று அரசாங்க வட்டாரங்கள் தெரிவித்துள்ளன.",
        "ஏரோஃப்ளோட் நடவடிக்கையின் பின்னர் இலங்கை எதிர்நோக்கும் பிரச்சினைகள் குறித்து ரஷ்ய ஜனாதிபதி விளாடிமிர் புட்டினுக்கு கடிதம் எழுதியுள்ளதாக முன்னாள் ஜனாதிபதி மைத்திரிபால சிறிசேன தெரிவித்துள்ளார். இலங்கை தனது செயலுக்கு மன்னிப்பு கோரியுள்ளது.",
        "\"நான் கடிதம் அனுப்பிய மூன்று நாட்களுக்குப் பிறகு எனக்கு பதில் கிடைத்தது. அந்தக் கடிதத்தை ஜனாதிபதி கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ஷவுக்கும் அனுப்பியுள்ளேன். பிந்தையவற்றில் மூன்று முக்கிய உண்மைகள் குறிப்பிடப்பட்டுள்ளன, ”என்று சிறிசேன நாடாளுமன்றத்தில் திங்கள்கிழமை (04) தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "“நாங்கள் கோரிக்கைகளை நிறைவேற்றினால், இருதரப்பு வர்த்தகம் மற்றும் விமான சேவைகளை மீண்டும் தொடங்க முடியும். அவர்கள் முதலில் குறிப்பிட்டது ஏரோஃப்ளோட் பிரச்சினை சட்டப் பிரச்சினைக்கு செல்வதற்குப் பதிலாக இராஜதந்திர வழிகள் மூலம் தடுக்கப்படலாம்.",
        "\"இரண்டாவது ஏரோஃப்ளோட் மீண்டும் நடக்காது என்று ரஷ்ய அரசாங்கம் உத்தரவாதம் கேட்டது, அதன் மீது சட்ட நடவடிக்கை எடுக்கப்பட்டது. உத்தரவாதம் இருந்தால், அவர்கள் விமான சேவையைத் தொடங்கலாம்.",
        "கொழும்பில் உள்ள ரஷ்ய தூதரகத்தின் ஊடாக வர்த்தகம் செல்ல வேண்டியதில்லை என்றும் அதற்கு பதிலாக தனிப்பட்ட நிறுவனங்கள் ரஷ்ய நிறுவனங்களுடன் இருதரப்பு வர்த்தகத்திற்காக நேரடியாக தொடர்பு கொள்ளலாம் என்பதும் ரஷ்ய ஜனாதிபதியால் எழுதப்பட்ட மூன்றாவது உண்மை என்றும் சிறிசேன கூறினார்.",
        "ஏரோஃப்ளாட் விவகாரம் கையாளப்பட்ட விதத்தில் அரசு அதிகாரிகள் பிளவுபட்டுள்ளனர். அரசாங்கம் இராஜதந்திர வழிகளை நாடியிருக்க வேண்டும் என்று சிலர் கூறுகின்றனர், மற்றவர்கள் இது ஒரு சட்டப் பிரச்சினை, எனவே அதைக் கையாண்ட விதம் பொருத்தமானது என்று கூறுகிறார்கள்.",
        "2 ஜூன் 2022 அன்று, மேல் மாகாணத்தின் வர்த்தக உயர் நீதிமன்றம், கொழும்புக்கு அருகிலுள்ள இலங்கையின் முக்கிய விமான நிலையத்திலிருந்து புறப்படுவதைத் தடைசெய்து ஏரோஃப்ளோட் விமானத்திற்கு தடை உத்தரவு பிறப்பித்தது.",
        "முதல் பிரதிவாதியான பொதுக் கூட்டுப் பங்கு நிறுவனமான “ஏரோஃப்ளோட்” மற்றும் இரண்டாவது பிரதிவாதியான NC அபேவர்த்தனே/ஏர் நேவிகேஷன்/ஏர்போர்ட் மற்றும் ஏவியேஷனின் செயல் தலைவர் ஆகியோருக்கு எதிராக ஐரிஷ் நிறுவனமான செலஸ்டியல் ஏவியேஷன் டிரேடிங் 10 லிமிடெட் என்ற வாதிக்கு இடையே வணிக தகராறு தொடர்பான வழக்கு. இலங்கையின் சேவைகள் (AASL), கட்டுநாயக்க.",
        "பின்னர் இலங்கை நீதிமன்றம் ஏரோஃப்ளோட் விமானம் இலங்கையை விட்டு வெளியேற தடை விதித்தது. சட்டமா அதிபரினால் தாக்கல் செய்யப்பட்ட மனுவை கொழும்பு வர்த்தக மேல் நீதிமன்றம் பரிசீலித்ததை அடுத்து இந்த உத்தரவு இடைநிறுத்தப்பட்டுள்ளது.",
        "ரஷ்ய அரசுக்குச் சொந்தமான ஏரோஃப்ளோட் மூலம் இயக்கப்படும் ஏர்பஸ் ஏ330-343 லீசிங் நிறுவனத்துடனான சட்டப் பிரச்சனையின் காரணமாக ஜூன் 2ஆம் தேதி திட்டமிடப்பட்டபடி மாஸ்கோவிற்குப் பறக்க அனுமதி மறுக்கப்பட்டது. அந்த விமானத்தில் 200க்கும் மேற்பட்ட பயணிகள் இருந்தனர். (கொழும்பு/ஜூலை 5/2022)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ரஷ்யா",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "எஸ்.எல்",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "ஏரோஃப்ளோட்",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ரஷ்யா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரஷ்யா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "கொழும்பில் உள்ள ஏரோஃப்ளோட்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "மைத்திரிபால சிறிசேன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஜூன்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Celestial Aviation Trading 10 Limited",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "அயர்லாந்து",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஏரோஃப்ளோட்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கையின்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரஷ்யா",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "மைத்திரிபால சிறிசேன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரஷ்யன்",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "விளாடிமிர் புடின்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஏரோஃப்ளோட்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "மூன்று நாட்கள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜனாதிபதி கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ஷ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "மூன்று",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "திங்கட்கிழமை",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "04",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "முதலில்",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஏரோஃப்ளோட்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இரண்டாவது",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரஷ்யன்",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஏரோஃப்ளோட்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "மூன்றாவது",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரஷ்யன்",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரஷ்யன்",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரஷ்யன்",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஏரோஃப்ளோட்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "2 ஜூன் 2022",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "வணிக உயர் நீதிமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "மேல் மாகாணம்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஏரோஃப்ளோட்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கையின்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "கொழும்பு",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Celestial Aviation Trading 10 Limited",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஐரிஷ்",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "முதலில்",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஏரோஃப்ளோட்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இரண்டாவது",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "என் சி அபேவர்தன",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "விமான வழிசெலுத்தல்/விமான நிலையம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கையின் விமான சேவைகள்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "கட்டுநாயக்கா",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை நீதிமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஏரோஃப்ளோட்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஏர்பஸ்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "A330-343",
            "label": "PRODUCT"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரஷ்யன்",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஏரோஃப்ளோட்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "மாஸ்கோ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜூன் 2 ஆம் தேதி",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "200க்கு மேல்",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}