{
  "newspaper_id": "news-first-lk",
  "url": "https://www.newsfirst.lk/2022/08/29/lawyer-goes-to-court-against-slpp-mp-sanath-nishantha/",
  "time_ut": 1661771700,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Lawyer goes to court against SLPP MP Sanath Nishantha",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Lawyer goes to court against SLPP MP Sanath Nishantha",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); A Sri Lankan lawyer has filed a petition with the Court of Appeal seeking a punishment on Sri Lanka Podujana Peramuna Parliamentarian Sanath Nishantha for contempt of court.",
        "SLPP MP Sanath Nishantha, the Bar Association of Sri Lanka, and the Attorney General of Sri Lanka have been named as respondents.",
        "The petitioner is also seeking an order to prevent the MP from traveling overseas.",
        "Attorney-at-Law Priyalala Sirisena in the petition states that MP Sanath Nishantha is named as a suspect in the case filed by the Criminal Investigations Department on the attack on the GotaGoGama protest site on the 9th of May 2022.",
        "Weerawansa & Co. to form new ‘Historic Alliance’ on 4th September"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Sanath Nishantha",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "News 1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lankan",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "Court",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "Podujana Peramuna Parliamentarian Sanath Nishantha",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sanath Nishantha",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Bar Association of Sri Lanka",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sanath Nishantha",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Criminal Investigations Department",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "9th",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "May 2022",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Weerawansa & Co.",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "4th",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "September",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "ශ්‍රී ලංකා පොදුජන පෙරමුණේ පාර්ලිමේන්තු මන්ත්‍රී සනත් නිශාන්තට එරෙහිව නීතීඥ අධිකරණයට",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); අධිකරණයට අපහාස කිරීම සම්බන්ධයෙන් ශ්‍රී ලංකා පොදුජන පෙරමුණේ පාර්ලිමේන්තු මන්ත්‍රී සනත් නිශාන්තට දඬුවම් කරන ලෙස ඉල්ලා ශ්‍රී ලාංකික නීතිඥයෙකු අභියාචනාධිකරණයට පෙත්සමක් ගොනු කර තිබෙනවා.",
        "එහි වගඋත්තරකරුවන් ලෙස ශ්‍රී ලංකා පොදුජන පෙරමුණේ පාර්ලිමේන්තු මන්ත්‍රී සනත් නිශාන්ත, ශ්‍රී ලංකා නීතීඥ සංගමය සහ ශ්‍රී ලංකා නීතිපතිවරයා නම් කර තිබේ.",
        "මන්ත‍්‍රීවරයාට විදෙස්ගත වීම වළක්වන නියෝගයක් නිකුත් කරන ලෙස ද පෙත්සම්කරු ඉල්ලා සිටියි.",
        "2022 මැයි 9 වනදා ගෝඨාගම විරෝධතා භූමියට එල්ල වූ ප්‍රහාරය සම්බන්ධයෙන් අපරාධ පරීක්ෂණ දෙපාර්තමේන්තුව ගොනු කර ඇති නඩුවේ විත්තිකරුවෙකු ලෙස පාර්ලිමේන්තු මන්ත්‍රී සනත් නිශාන්ත නම් කර ඇති බව නීතීඥ ප්‍රියලාලා සිරිසේන මහතා පෙත්සමෙන් සඳහන් කරයි.",
        "වීරවංශ සහ සමාගම සැප්තැම්බර් 4 වැනිදා නව ‘ඓතිහාසික සන්ධානයක්’ පිහිටුවීමට"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "සනත් නිශාන්ත",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "News 1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලාංකික",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "අධිකරණය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "පොදුජන පෙරමුණේ පාර්ලිමේන්තු මන්ත්‍රී සනත් නිශාන්ත",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "සනත් නිශාන්ත",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකා නීතිඥ සංගමය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "සනත් නිශාන්ත",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "අපරාධ පරීක්ෂණ දෙපාර්තමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "9 වැනි",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "2022 මැයි",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "වීරවංශ සහ සමාගම",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "4 වැනි",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "සැප්තැම්බර්",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "SLPP பாராளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர் சனத் நிஷாந்தவிற்கு எதிராக சட்டத்தரணி நீதிமன்றத்திற்கு சென்றுள்ளார்",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); நீதிமன்றத்தை அவமதித்த குற்றச்சாட்டின் பேரில் ஸ்ரீலங்கா பொதுஜன பெரமுனவின் நாடாளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர் சனத் நிஷாந்தவுக்கு தண்டனை வழங்குமாறு கோரி இலங்கை சட்டத்தரணி ஒருவர் மேன்முறையீட்டு நீதிமன்றில் மனு தாக்கல் செய்துள்ளார்.",
        "SLPP பாராளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர் சனத் நிஷாந்த, இலங்கை சட்டத்தரணிகள் சங்கம் மற்றும் இலங்கையின் சட்டமா அதிபர் ஆகியோர் பிரதிவாதிகளாக குறிப்பிடப்பட்டுள்ளனர்.",
        "எம்.பி., வெளிநாடு செல்வதை தடுக்க உத்தரவிட வேண்டும் என்றும் மனுதாரர் கோரியுள்ளார்.",
        "2022 ஆம் ஆண்டு மே மாதம் 9 ஆம் திகதி கோட்டகோகம போராட்டத் தளத்தின் மீதான தாக்குதல் தொடர்பில் குற்றப் புலனாய்வு திணைக்களத்தினால் தாக்கல் செய்யப்பட்ட வழக்கில் பாராளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர் சனத் நிஷாந்த சந்தேக நபராக குறிப்பிடப்பட்டுள்ளதாக சட்டத்தரணி பிரியலாலா சிறிசேன மனுவில் குறிப்பிட்டுள்ளார்.",
        "வீரவன்ச & கோ. செப்டம்பர் 4 ஆம் தேதி புதிய ‘வரலாற்று கூட்டணியை’ உருவாக்க உள்ளது"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "சனத் நிஷாந்த",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "News 1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "நீதிமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "பொதுஜன பெரமுனவின் நாடாளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர் சனத் நிஷாந்த",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "சனத் நிஷாந்த",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை சட்டத்தரணிகள் சங்கம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "சனத் நிஷாந்த",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "குற்றப் புலனாய்வுத் திணைக்களம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "9வது",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "மே 2022",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "வீரவன்ச & கோ.",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "4வது",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "செப்டம்பர்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}