{
  "newspaper_id": "news-first-lk",
  "url": "https://www.newsfirst.lk/2022/07/24/be-accountable-for-assets-maintained-from-public-money-defence-secretary/",
  "time_ut": 1658667480,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Be accountable for assets maintained from public money – Defence Secretary",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Be accountable for assets maintained from public money – Defence Secretary",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); Being a developing country, where the government constantly allocates a considerable portion of its revenue for the country’s defence, even amidst the current economic and political crisis, it is your responsibility to be accountable for your assets which are maintained from the public money, said the Defence Secretary Gen. Kamal Gunaratne on 22nd July.",
        "“The more you reach higher in the ladder; the more you are expected to act responsibly” he also said.",
        "Gen. Gunaratne expressed these remarks while gracing a vibrant Commissioning Ceremony of the Navy’s Midshipmen, as the Chief Guest, held at the prestigious ‘Naval and Maritime Academy’ (NMA) in Trincomalee. Chairperson of the MOD Seva vanitha unit Mrs. Chithrani Gunaratne was also present at the occasion.",
        "Further addressing the new young officers he went on saying “Navy will always trust you with its assets at your hands and you must ensure the proper utilisation of those to attain desired aims while preserving the same for the long run”.",
        "Gen. Gunaratne was received by the Navy Chief Vice Admiral Nishantha Ulugetenne and the Commandant of the NMA Commodore Damian Fernando, upon his arrival at the Navy’s highest seat of training and education situated at the vicinity of enticing port city of Trincomalee.",
        "Afterwards, the Chief Guest was accorded a ceremonial Guard of Honour in keeping with the long held naval traditions. The glamorous turn out of the night passing out parade saw the commissioning of 36 Midshipmen.",
        "The dignified ceremony held in keeping with time honoured naval traditions saw another batch of dynamic naval officers being commissioned and pass out at the NMA main parade ground, amidst cheers of their parents and a galaxy of distinguished guests.",
        "The batch of commissioned officers is comprised of 11 midshipmen of the 35th (Technical) Intake and 25 midshipmen of the 36th Intake of General Sir John Kotelawala Defence University (KDU).",
        "The climax of the day’s events began with the presentation of special awards by the Defence Secretary in recognition of outstanding performances of the Midshipmen.",
        "Accordingly, Midshipman HASV Hapuarachchi was adjudged the best Technical Officer of the 35th Intake of the KDU.",
        "Meanwhile, Midshipman IS Weerasinghe of the 36th Intake of KDU won the Sword of Honour, having been adjudged the Best Midshipman, and the award for the Best Sportsman as well.",
        "Midshipman SN Abeywarna secured two awards for achieving the highest aggregate in both professional and overall subjects. The award for the Best Marksman of the Intake was won by Midshipman RPPS Rajapaksha.",
        "Customarily, Midshipmen are elevated to the commissioned rank of Acting Sub Lieutenant with pride, following the successful completion of their military training, and commissioning swords are given in a colourful ceremony by a distinguished nominee of the Commander in Chief of the Armed Forces, who is also the Head of State.",
        "Further speaking to navy’s new leaders he stressed “Your loyalty towards the nation is never to be questioned and it is mandatory that you respect the rules and regulations which you are bound to obey in addition to the civil law; in your case, the Navy Act”.",
        "On the same note recalling the Navy’s contribution during this three-decade long conflict against ruthless terrorism, which is commendable, he emphasised to the newly commissioned officers to uphold the excellence of their predecessors, the same or even a higher extent of devotion is expected from them to ensure the security and sovereignty of the nation and to skirmish the non-traditional challenges faced by the country in the Indian Ocean Region, such as people smuggling, drug peddling, other transnational crimes and also many other threats such as natural disasters.",
        "Religious dignitaries including Ven. Maha Sanga, Senior State Officials of the Eastern Province, Navy’s Chief of Staff, Commander of the Eastern Naval Area, Defence Advisors and Attachés of friendly foreign countries, senior military and Police officers, distinguished invitees and relatives of the passing out officers were also present to witness the glamorous night Passing Out ceremony.",
        "Be accountable for assets maintained from public money – Defence Secretary"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Defence",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "News 1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Defence",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kamal Gunaratne",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "22nd July",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "Gunaratne",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Commissioning Ceremony",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Navy",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Maritime Academy’",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "NMA",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Trincomalee",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Chithrani Gunaratne",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Navy",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Gunaratne",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Navy",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Nishantha Ulugetenne",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "NMA",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Damian Fernando",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Navy",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Trincomalee",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Guard of Honour",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "36",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "NMA",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "11",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "the 35th",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "25",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "36th",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "John Kotelawala",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "KDU",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "day",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Defence",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Midshipmen",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Midshipman HASV Hapuarachchi",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "35th",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "KDU",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Midshipman",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Weerasinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "36th",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Intake of KDU",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Sword of Honour",
            "label": "WORK_OF_ART"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Midshipman SN Abeywarna",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "two",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Intake",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Midshipman RPPS Rajapaksha",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the Armed Forces",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "navy",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Navy Act",
            "label": "LAW"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Navy",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "three-decade",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Indian Ocean Region",
            "label": "LOC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Ven",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Maha Sanga",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Eastern Province",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Navy",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Eastern Naval Area",
            "label": "LOC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Defence",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "මහජන මුදලින් නඩත්තු කරන වත්කම්වලට වගකියන්න – ආරක්ෂක ලේකම්",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); පවතින ආර්ථික හා දේශපාලන අර්බුද මධ්‍යයේ වුව රජය තම ආදායමෙන් සැලකිය යුතු කොටසක් නිරතුරුවම රටේ ආරක්‍ෂාව සඳහා වෙන් කරන සංවර්ධනය වෙමින් පවතින රටක් වන බැවින් මහජන මුදලින් නඩත්තු වන ඔබේ වත්කම් සම්බන්ධයෙන් වගවීම ඔබේ වගකීම බව ද ප්‍රකාශ කළේය. ආරක්‍ෂක ලේකම් ජනරාල් කමල් ගුණරත්න මහතා ජූලි 22 වැනිදා.",
        "“ඉණිමඟේ ඔබ වැඩි වැඩියෙන් ඉහළට ළඟා වන තරමට; ඔබ වගකීමෙන් කටයුතු කිරීමට බලාපොරොත්තු වන තරමට,\" ඔහු ද පැවසීය.",
        "ජෙනරාල් ගුණරත්න මහතා මෙම අදහස් පළ කළේ ත්‍රිකුණාමලයේ පිහිටි කීර්තිමත් ‘නාවික හා සමුද්‍රීය ඇකඩමියේ’ (NMA) පැවති නාවික හමුදා මධ්‍ය නිලධාරීන්ගේ විචිත්‍රවත් කොමිස්‌ෂන් උත්සවයක් ප්‍රධාන ආරාධිත අමුත්තා ලෙස සහභාගි කරමිනි. මෙම අවස්ථාවට MOD සේවා වනිතා ඒකකයේ සභාපතිනී චිත්‍රානි ගුණරත්න මහත්මිය ද සහභාගී විය.",
        "නව තරුණ නිලධාරීන් අමතමින් ඔහු වැඩිදුරටත් කියා සිටියේ \"නාවික හමුදාව සැමවිටම ඔබ අතේ ඇති වත්කම් සමඟ ඔබව විශ්වාස කරන අතර දිගු කාලීනව ඒවා ආරක්ෂා කර ගනිමින් අපේක්ෂිත අරමුණු සාක්ෂාත් කර ගැනීම සඳහා ඒවා නිසි ලෙස භාවිතා කිරීමට ඔබ සහතික විය යුතු\" බවයි.",
        "ත්‍රිකුණාමලයේ ආකර්ශනීය වරාය නගරය ආසන්නයේ පිහිටි නාවික හමුදාවේ ඉහළම පුහුණු හා අධ්‍යාපන ආසනය වෙත පැමිණි ජෙනරාල් ගුණරත්න මහතා නාවික හමුදා ප්‍රධාන වයිස් අද්මිරාල් නිශාන්ත උළුගේතැන්න සහ NMA හි සේනාවිධායක කොමදෝරු ඩේමියන් ප්‍රනාන්දු විසින් පිළිගන්නා ලදී.",
        "අනතුරුව දීර්ඝ කාලයක් පැවති නාවික සම්ප්‍රදායන්ට අනුකූලව ප්‍රධාන ආරාධිත අමුත්තා වෙත උත්සවාකාරයෙන් ගෞරව සම්මාන මුරයක් පිරිනමන ලදී. රාත්‍රී විසිර යාමේ පෙළපාළියේ ආකර්ෂණීය හැරීමෙන් මිඩ්ෂිප්මන්වරුන් 36 දෙනෙකු පත් කරන ලදී.",
        "කාලයාගේ ඇවෑමෙන් ගෞරවාන්විත නාවික සම්ප්‍රදායන්ට අනුකූලව පැවති මෙම ගෞරවනීය උත්සවයේදී තවත් ගතික නාවික නිලධාරීන් කණ්ඩායමක් සිය දෙමාපියන්ගේ ඔල්වරසන් හඬ මධ්‍යයේ NMA ප්‍රධාන පෙළපාළි පිටියේදී විසිර යන අයුරු දැකගත හැකි විය.",
        "කොමිස් ලත් නිලධාරීන් කණ්ඩායම ජෙනරාල් ශ්‍රීමත් ජෝන් කොතලාවල ආරක්ෂක විශ්ව විද්‍යාලයේ (KDU) 35 වන (තාක්ෂණික) බඳවා ගැනීමේ මධ්‍ය නිලධාරීන් 11 දෙනෙකුගෙන් සහ 36 වන බඳවා ගැනීමේ මධ්‍ය නිලධාරීන් 25 දෙනෙකුගෙන් සමන්විත වේ.",
        "මධ්‍යම භටයින්ගේ විශිෂ්ඨ දස්කම් අගයමින් ආරක්‍ෂක ලේකම්වරයා විසින් විශේෂ සම්මාන ප්‍රදානය කිරීමත් සමග දිනයේ සිදුවීම්වල උච්චතම අවස්ථාව ආරම්භ විය.",
        "ඒ අනුව, KDU හි 35 වන බඳවාගැනීමේ හොඳම තාක්ෂණික නිලධාරියා ලෙස මිඩ්ෂිප්මන් HASV හපුආරච්චි මහතා තේරී පත් විය.",
        "මේ අතර, KDU හි 36 වන Intake හි Midshipman IS වීරසිංහ හොඳම Midshipman ලෙස සම්මානයට පාත්‍ර වූ අතර, දක්ෂතම ක්‍රීඩකයාට හිමි සම්මානය ද හිමි විය.",
        "වෘත්තීය සහ සමස්ත විෂයයන් දෙකෙන්ම ඉහළම සමස්ථයක් සාක්ෂාත් කර ගැනීම වෙනුවෙන් මධ්‍යස්ථ පාලක එස්.එන්.අබේවර්ණ සම්මාන දෙකක් ලබා ගත්තේය. බඳවා ගැනීමේ දක්ෂතම ලකුණුකරුට හිමි සම්මානය මිඩ්ෂිප්මන් ආර්පීපීඑස් රාජපක්ෂ විසින් දිනා ගන්නා ලදී.",
        "සාම්ප්‍රදායිකව, ඔවුන්ගේ හමුදා පුහුණුව සාර්ථකව නිම කිරීමෙන් පසු, මිඩ්ෂිප්මන්ලා අභිමානයෙන් වැඩබලන උප ලුතිනන් තනතුරට උසස් කරනු ලබන අතර, සන්නද්ධ හමුදා ප්‍රධානීගේ කීර්තිමත් නාමිකයෙකු විසින් වර්ණවත් උත්සවයකදී කොමිස් කඩු ප්‍රදානය කරනු ලැබේ. රාජ්ය නායකයා ද වේ.",
        "නාවික හමුදාවේ නව නායකයින් අමතා වැඩිදුරටත් අදහස් දක්වමින් ඔහු අවධාරණය කළේ “ජාතිය කෙරෙහි ඔබේ පක්ෂපාතිත්වය කිසි විටෙකත් ප්‍රශ්න නොකළ යුතු අතර සිවිල් නීතියට අමතරව ඔබ කීකරු වීමට බැඳී සිටින නීති රීතිවලට ගරු කිරීම අනිවාර්ය වේ. ඔබගේ නඩුවේදී, නාවික හමුදා පනත\".",
        "මෙම දශක තුනක කුරිරු ත්‍රස්තවාදයට එරෙහි සටනේදී නාවික හමුදාවේ දායකත්වය ප්‍රශංසනීය බව සිහිපත් කළ ඔහු, අලුතින් පත් වූ නිලධාරීන්ට ඔවුන්ගේ පූර්වගාමීන්ගේ විශිෂ්ටත්වය ආරක්ෂා කරන ලෙස අවධාරණය කළේය. ජාතියේ ආරක්‍ෂාව සහ ස්වෛරීභාවය තහවුරු කිරීම සහ ඉන්දීය සාගර කලාපය තුළ රට මුහුණ දෙන සාම්ප්‍රදායික නොවන අභියෝග වන පුද්ගල ජාවාරම්, මත්ද්‍රව්‍ය ජාවාරම්, වෙනත් ජාත්‍යන්තර අපරාධ සහ ස්වභාවික විපත් වැනි තවත් බොහෝ තර්ජන මැඩලීම සඳහා ය.",
        "පූජ්‍ය නාහිමියන් ඇතුළු ආගමික නායකයන් මහා සංඝරත්නය, නැඟෙනහිර පළාතේ ජ්‍යෙෂ්ඨ රාජ්‍ය නිලධාරීන්, නාවික හමුදා මාණ්ඩලික ප්‍රධානී, නැගෙනහිර නාවික විධානය භාර ආඥාපති, ආරක්‍ෂක උපදේශකවරුන් සහ මිත්‍ර විදේශ රටවල අනුයුක්තවරුන්, ජ්‍යෙෂ්ඨ හමුදා සහ පොලිස් නිලධාරීන්, සම්භාවනීය ආරාධිතයන් සහ විසිර යන නිලධාරීන්ගේ ඥාතීන් ද මෙම අවස්ථාවට එක්ව සිටියහ. ආකර්ෂණීය රාත්‍රිය විසිර යාමේ උත්සවය නැරඹීමට.",
        "මහජන මුදලින් නඩත්තු කරන වත්කම්වලට වගකියන්න – ආරක්ෂක ලේකම්"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ආරක්ෂක",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "News 1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ආරක්ෂක",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "කමල් ගුණරත්න",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජූලි 22",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "ගුණරත්න ය",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "කොමිස් කිරීමේ උත්සවය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "නාවික",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "සමුද්‍ර ඇකඩමිය'",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "NMA",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ත්රිකුණාමලය",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "චිත්‍රානි ගුණරත්න",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "නාවික",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ගුණරත්න ය",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "නාවික",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "නිශාන්ත උළුගේතැන්න",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "NMA",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඩේමියන් ප්‍රනාන්දු",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "නාවික",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ත්රිකුණාමලය",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ගරු ගාඩ්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "36",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "NMA",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "11",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "35 වන",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "25",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "36 වැනි",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජෝන් කොතලාවල",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "KDU",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "දින",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ආරක්ෂක",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "මධ්‍ය නිලධාරීන්",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "මිඩ්ෂිප්මන් HASV හපුආරච්චි",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "35 වැනි",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "KDU",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "මිඩ්ෂිප්මන්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "වීරසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "36 වැනි",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "KDU ලබා ගැනීම",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගෞරවනීය කඩුව",
            "label": "WORK_OF_ART"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "මධ්‍ය නිලධාරි එස්.එන්.අබේවර්ණ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "දෙක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "බඳවා ගැනීම",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "මිඩ්ෂිප්මන් ආර්පීපීඑස් රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "සන්නද්ධ හමුදා",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "නාවික",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "නාවික හමුදා පනත",
            "label": "LAW"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "නාවික",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "දශක තුනක්",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දියානු සාගර කලාපය",
            "label": "LOC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "හාමුදුරුවෝ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "මහා සංඝරත්නය",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "නැගෙනහිර පළාත",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "නාවික",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "නැගෙනහිර නාවික ප්රදේශය",
            "label": "LOC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ආරක්ෂක",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "பொதுப் பணத்தில் இருந்து பராமரிக்கப்படும் சொத்துக்களுக்கு பொறுப்புக்கூற வேண்டும் - பாதுகாப்புச் செயலாளர்",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); வளர்ந்து வரும் நாடாக இருப்பதால், தற்போதைய பொருளாதார மற்றும் அரசியல் நெருக்கடிகளுக்கு மத்தியிலும், அரசாங்கம் தனது வருவாயில் கணிசமான பகுதியை நாட்டின் பாதுகாப்பிற்காக தொடர்ந்து ஒதுக்குகிறது, பொது பணத்தில் இருந்து பராமரிக்கப்படும் உங்கள் சொத்துகளுக்கு பொறுப்புக் கூறுவது உங்கள் பொறுப்பு. பாதுகாப்புச் செயலாளர் ஜெனரல் கமல் குணரத்ன ஜூலை 22ஆம் திகதி.",
        "“ஏணியில் எவ்வளவு உயரத்தை அடைகிறீர்களோ; மேலும் நீங்கள் பொறுப்புடன் செயல்படுவீர்கள் என்று எதிர்பார்க்கப்படுகிறது” என்றும் அவர் கூறினார்.",
        "திருகோணமலையில் உள்ள புகழ்பெற்ற ‘நேவல் அன்ட் மரிடைம் அகாடமி’யில் (NMA) நடைபெற்ற கடற்படையின் மிட்ஷிப்மேன்களின் துடிப்பான ஆணையிடும் விழாவில் பிரதம அதிதியாக கலந்து கொண்டு ஜெனரல் குணரத்ன இந்தக் கருத்துக்களைத் தெரிவித்தார். MOD சேவா வனிதா பிரிவின் தலைவி திருமதி சித்ராணி குணரத்னவும் இந்நிகழ்வில் கலந்துகொண்டார்.",
        "புதிய இளம் அதிகாரிகளிடம் மேலும் உரையாற்றிய அவர், \"கடற்படை எப்போதும் உங்கள் கைகளில் உள்ள சொத்துக்களுடன் உங்களை நம்பும், மேலும் நீண்ட காலத்திற்கு அவற்றைப் பாதுகாத்து, விரும்பிய இலக்குகளை அடைய அவற்றை சரியான முறையில் பயன்படுத்துவதை நீங்கள் உறுதிப்படுத்த வேண்டும்\" என்று கூறினார்.",
        "திருகோணமலை துறைமுக நகருக்கு அருகாமையில் அமைந்துள்ள கடற்படையின் அதியுயர் பயிற்சி மற்றும் கல்விக்கான இருக்கைக்கு வந்தடைந்த ஜெனரல் குணரத்னவை கடற்படைத் தலைமை வைஸ் அட்மிரல் நிஷாந்த உலுகேதென்ன மற்றும் NMA கொமடோர் டாமியன் பெர்னாண்டோ ஆகியோர் வரவேற்றனர்.",
        "அதன் பின்னர், பிரதம அதிதிக்கு நீண்டகாலமாக கடைப்பிடிக்கப்பட்ட கடற்படை மரபுகளுக்கு அமைவாக சம்பிரதாய ரீதியிலான கௌரவ மரியாதை வழங்கப்பட்டது. இரவு பாஸிங் அவுட் அணிவகுப்பின் கவர்ச்சியான திருப்பம் 36 மிட்ஷிப்மேன்களை நியமித்தது.",
        "மரியாதைக்குரிய கடற்படை மரபுகளுக்கு இணங்க நடைபெற்ற கௌரவமான விழாவில், அவர்களின் பெற்றோரின் ஆரவாரம் மற்றும் சிறப்பு விருந்தினர்களின் ஆரவாரத்திற்கு மத்தியில், என்எம்ஏ பிரதான அணிவகுப்பு மைதானத்தில் மற்றொரு குழு ஆற்றல்மிக்க கடற்படை அதிகாரிகள் பணியமர்த்தப்பட்டு வெளியேறினர்.",
        "பணியமர்த்தப்பட்ட அதிகாரிகளின் குழுவானது, ஜெனரல் சர் ஜோன் கொத்தலாவல பாதுகாப்பு பல்கலைக்கழகத்தின் (KDU) 35வது (தொழில்நுட்ப) இன்டேக்கின் 11 மிட்ஷிப்மேன்களையும், 36வது இன்டேக்கின் 25 மிட்ஷிப்மேன்களையும் உள்ளடக்கியது.",
        "மிட்ஷிப்மேன்களின் சிறந்த செயல்திறனுக்காக பாதுகாப்பு செயலாளரால் சிறப்பு விருதுகள் வழங்கலுடன் அன்றைய நிகழ்வுகளின் உச்சக்கட்டம் தொடங்கியது.",
        "அதன்படி, மிட்ஷிப்மேன் HASV ஹப்புஆராச்சி KDU இன் 35வது இன்டேக்கின் சிறந்த தொழில்நுட்ப அதிகாரியாகத் தேர்ந்தெடுக்கப்பட்டார்.",
        "இதற்கிடையில், KDU இன் 36வது இன்டேக்கின் மிட்ஷிப்மேன் ஐ.எஸ். வீரசிங்க சிறந்த மிட்ஷிப்மேன் என்ற விருதையும், சிறந்த விளையாட்டு வீரருக்கான விருதையும் வென்றார்.",
        "மிட்ஷிப்மேன் எஸ்.என். அபேவர்ண தொழில்முறை மற்றும் ஒட்டுமொத்த பாடங்கள் இரண்டிலும் அதிக மதிப்பெண் பெற்றதற்காக இரண்டு விருதுகளைப் பெற்றார். உள்வாங்கலின் சிறந்த துப்பாக்கி சுடும் வீரருக்கான விருதை மிட்ஷிப்மேன் ஆர்பிபிஎஸ் ராஜபக்ஷ வென்றார்.",
        "வழக்கமாக, மிட்ஷிப்மேன்கள் தங்கள் இராணுவப் பயிற்சியை வெற்றிகரமாக முடித்ததைத் தொடர்ந்து, பெருமையுடன் ஆக்டிங் சப் லெப்டினன்ட் பதவிக்கு உயர்த்தப்படுகிறார்கள், மேலும் ஆயுதப் படைகளின் தலைமைத் தளபதியின் புகழ்பெற்ற வேட்பாளரால் ஒரு வண்ணமயமான விழாவில் ஆணையிடும் வாள்கள் வழங்கப்படுகின்றன. மேலும் மாநில தலைவர்.",
        "கடற்படையின் புதிய தலைவர்களிடம் மேலும் பேசிய அவர், “தேசத்தின் மீதான உங்கள் விசுவாசம் ஒருபோதும் கேள்விக்குள்ளாக்கப்படாது, மேலும் சிவில் சட்டத்திற்கு மேலதிகமாக நீங்கள் கீழ்ப்படிய வேண்டிய விதிகள் மற்றும் ஒழுங்குமுறைகளை நீங்கள் மதிக்க வேண்டியது கட்டாயமாகும்; உங்கள் விஷயத்தில், கடற்படை சட்டம்\".",
        "இரக்கமற்ற பயங்கரவாதத்திற்கு எதிரான இந்த மூன்று தசாப்த கால மோதலின் போது கடற்படையின் பங்களிப்பை நினைவுகூர்ந்த அதே குறிப்பில், புதிதாக நியமிக்கப்பட்ட அதிகாரிகளுக்கு அவர்களின் முன்னோடிகளின் சிறப்பை நிலைநிறுத்த அவர் வலியுறுத்தினார், அதே அல்லது அதிக அளவு பக்தி எதிர்பார்க்கப்படுகிறது. தேசத்தின் பாதுகாப்பு மற்றும் இறையாண்மையை உறுதி செய்வதற்கும், இந்தியப் பெருங்கடல் பகுதியில் நாடு எதிர்கொள்ளும் பாரம்பரியமற்ற சவால்களான ஆட்கடத்தல், போதைப்பொருள் கடத்தல், பிற நாடுகடந்த குற்றங்கள் மற்றும் இயற்கை பேரழிவுகள் போன்ற பல அச்சுறுத்தல்களை முறியடிப்பதற்கும்.",
        "வணக்கம் உட்பட சமயப் பெருமக்கள். மகாசங்க, கிழக்கு மாகாண சிரேஷ்ட அரச அதிகாரிகள், கடற்படையின் பிரதானி, கிழக்கு கடற்படை கட்டளைத் தளபதி, பாதுகாப்பு ஆலோசகர்கள் மற்றும் நட்பு நாடுகளின் உதவியாளர்கள், சிரேஷ்ட இராணுவ மற்றும் பொலிஸ் உத்தியோகத்தர்கள், சிறப்பு அழைப்பாளர்கள் மற்றும் வெளியேறிய அதிகாரிகளின் உறவினர்கள் ஆகியோர் கலந்துகொண்டனர். கவர்ச்சியான இரவு பாஸ்சிங் அவுட் விழாவைக் காண.",
        "பொதுப் பணத்தில் இருந்து பராமரிக்கப்படும் சொத்துக்களுக்கு பொறுப்புக்கூற வேண்டும் - பாதுகாப்புச் செயலாளர்"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "பாதுகாப்பு",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "News 1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாதுகாப்பு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "கமல் குணரத்ன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "22 ஜூலை",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "குணரத்ன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆணையிடும் விழா",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "கடற்படை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "கடல்சார் அகாடமி'",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "என்.எம்.ஏ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "திருகோணமலை",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "சித்ராணி குணரத்ன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "கடற்படை",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "குணரத்ன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "கடற்படை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "நிஷாந்த உலுகெதென்ன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "என்.எம்.ஏ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "டாமியன் பெர்னாண்டோ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "கடற்படை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "திருகோணமலை",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "மரியாதைக்குரிய காவலர்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "36",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "என்.எம்.ஏ",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "11",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "35வது",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "25",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "36வது",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜோன் கொத்தலாவல",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "KDU",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "நாள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாதுகாப்பு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "மிட்ஷிப்மேன்கள்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "மிட்ஷிப்மேன் HASV ஹப்புஆராச்சி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "35வது",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "KDU",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "மிட்ஷிப்மேன்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "வீரசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "36வது",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "KDU இன் உட்கொள்ளல்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "மரியாதை வாள்",
            "label": "WORK_OF_ART"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "மிட்ஷிப்மேன் எஸ்.என்.அபேவர்ண",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இரண்டு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "உட்கொள்ளல்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "மிட்ஷிப்மேன் RPPS ராஜபக்ஷ",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஆயுதப்படைகள்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "கடற்படை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "கடற்படை சட்டம்",
            "label": "LAW"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "கடற்படை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "மூன்று தசாப்தங்கள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்தியப் பெருங்கடல் பகுதி",
            "label": "LOC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "வண",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "மகா சங்கை",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "கிழக்கு மாகாணம்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "கடற்படை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "கிழக்கு கடற்படை பகுதி",
            "label": "LOC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பாதுகாப்பு",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}