{
  "newspaper_id": "economy-next-com",
  "url": "https://economynext.com/crisis-hit-sri-lanka-allows-companies-to-pay-in-dollars-to-obtain-weekly-fuel-supply-96807/",
  "time_ut": 1656852180,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Crisis-hit Sri Lanka allows companies to pay in dollars to obtain weekly fuel supply",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Crisis-hit Sri Lanka allows companies to pay in dollars to obtain weekly fuel supply",
      "author": "",
      "body_lines": [
        "ECONOMYNEXT – Sri Lankan companies will be able to purchase fuel on a weekly or daily basis if they are able to pay for the commodity in dollars one-month in advance, Minister of Fuel and Energy Kanchana Wijesekera said, as the crisis-hit country scrambles to find dollars to pay its bills.",
        "From July 12, any company that has the ability to pay for its fuel requirements can open a consumer account at Ceylon Petroleum Corporation to obtain a guaranteed quota.",
        "“They need to pay a month in advance & fuel will be issued on a daily or weekly basis from the 12th (July). Already paid customers will receive their quota from the 12th,” Wijesekera said on Sunday (July 03).",
        "Any Company/Industry that can pay In USD can open a consumer account at CPC to obtain a weekly guaranteed quota. They need to pay a month in advance & fuel will be issued on a daily or weekly basis from the 12th. Already paid customers will receive their quota from the 12th.",
        "Sri Lanka’s fuel stocks have almost run dry while the fuel queues continue to grow.",
        "Previously, the minister said that the country’s money-printing central bank shot down a proposal to allow a few fuel stations to sell petrol in dollars on the grounds that dollars cannot be used for internal transactions at retail levels.",
        "The minister highlighted that the state-run national carrier SriLankan Airlines and exporters were already paying for fuel in dollars, which is helping the CPC’s currency reserve.",
        "Some new suppliers had previously asked for upfront payment to supply fuel while foreign banks are refusing to confirm Sri Lanka’s letter of credit.",
        "Related: Foreign banks refuse to confirm Sri Lanka state bank letters of credit: Minister",
        "Suppliers like Petro China, who used to give Sri Lanka 180 days of credit through LCs, are now asking for advance payment, Minister Wijesekera said. (Colombo/Jul03/2022)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Sri Lanka",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "weekly",
          "label": "DATE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lankan",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "weekly",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "daily",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "one-month",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "July 12",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ceylon Petroleum Corporation",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "a month",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "daily",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "weekly",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the 12th (July",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the 12th",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Wijesekera",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sunday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "July 03",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Company/Industry",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "USD",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "CPC",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "weekly",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "a month",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "daily",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "weekly",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the 12th",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the 12th",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka’s",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "SriLankan Airlines",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "CPC",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka’s",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Petro China",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "180 days",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Wijesekera",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Colombo/Jul03/2022",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "අර්බුදකාරී ශ්‍රී ලංකාව සතිපතා ඉන්ධන සැපයීම සඳහා ඩොලර් වලින් ගෙවීමට සමාගම්වලට අවසර දෙයි",
      "author": "",
      "body_lines": [
        "ECONOMYNEXT - අර්බුදකාරී රට පොරබදමින් සිටින විට ශ්‍රී ලංකා සමාගම්වලට ඩොලර් වලින් භාණ්ඩ සඳහා මාසයකට පෙර ගෙවීමට හැකි නම් සතිපතා හෝ දෛනික පදනමින් ඉන්ධන මිලදී ගැනීමට හැකි වනු ඇතැයි ඉන්ධන හා බලශක්ති අමාත්‍ය කාංචන විජේසේකර මහතා පැවසීය. එහි බිල්පත් ගෙවීමට ඩොලර් සොයා ගැනීමට.",
        "ජූලි 12 වැනිදා සිට ඉන්ධන අවශ්‍යතා සඳහා ගෙවීමට හැකියාව ඇති ඕනෑම සමාගමකට සහතික කළ කෝටාවක් ලබා ගැනීම සඳහා ලංකා ඛනිජ තෙල් නීතිගත සංස්ථාවේ පාරිභෝගික ගිණුමක් ආරම්භ කළ හැකිය.",
        "“ඔවුන් මාසයකට පෙර ගෙවිය යුතු අතර 12 (ජූලි) සිට දිනපතා හෝ සතිපතා ඉන්ධන නිකුත් කෙරේ. දැනටමත් ගෙවන ලද ගනුදෙනුකරුවන්ට ඔවුන්ගේ කෝටාව 12 වැනිදා සිට ලැබෙනු ඇත,” විජේසේකර ඉරිදා (ජූලි 03) පැවසීය.",
        "USD වලින් ගෙවිය හැකි ඕනෑම සමාගමකට/කර්මාන්තයකට සතිපතා සහතික කළ කෝටාවක් ලබා ගැනීම සඳහා CPC හි පාරිභෝගික ගිණුමක් විවෘත කළ හැක. ඔවුන් මාසයකට පෙර ගෙවිය යුතු අතර ඉන්ධන 12 වැනිදා සිට දිනපතා හෝ සතිපතා නිකුත් කෙරේ. දැනටමත් ගෙවා ඇති පාරිභෝගිකයින්ට ඔවුන්ගේ කෝටාව 12 වනදා සිට ලැබෙනු ඇත.",
        "ඉන්ධන පෝලිම් අඛණ්ඩව වර්ධනය වන අතර ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ ඉන්ධන තොග පාහේ වියළී ගොස් ඇත.",
        "මීට පෙර අමාත්‍යවරයා කියා සිටියේ සිල්ලර මට්ටමින් අභ්‍යන්තර ගනුදෙනු සඳහා ඩොලර් භාවිතා කළ නොහැකි බව පවසමින් ඉන්ධන පිරවුම්හල් කිහිපයකට ඩොලර් වලින් පෙට්‍රල් විකිණීමට අවසර දීමේ යෝජනාව රටේ මුදල් මුද්‍රණ මහ බැංකුව විසින් ප්‍රතික්ෂේප කළ බවයි.",
        "රජය විසින් පවත්වාගෙන යනු ලබන ජාතික ගුවන් සේවය වන ශ්‍රී ලංකන් ගුවන් සමාගම සහ අපනයනකරුවන් දැනටමත් ඩොලර් වලින් ඉන්ධන සඳහා ගෙවමින් සිටින අතර එය CPC හි මුදල් සංචිතයට උපකාරී වන බව අමාත්‍යවරයා අවධාරණය කළේය.",
        "විදේශීය බැංකු ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ ණයවර ලිපිය තහවුරු කිරීම ප්‍රතික්ෂේප කරන අතර සමහර නව සැපයුම්කරුවන් ඉන්ධන සැපයීම සඳහා කලින් ගෙවීමක් ඉල්ලා තිබුණි.",
        "ආශ්‍රිත: ශ්‍රී ලංකා රාජ්‍ය බැංකු ණයවර ලිපි තහවුරු කිරීම විදේශීය බැංකු ප්‍රතික්ෂේප කරයි: ඇමති",
        "LC හරහා ශ්‍රී ලංකාවට දින 180ක ණය ලබාදුන් පෙට්‍රෝ චයිනා වැනි සැපයුම්කරුවන් දැන් අත්තිකාරම් මුදලක් ඉල්ලා සිටින බවද විජේසේකර ඇමැතිවරයා කීය. (කොළඹ/ජූලි03/2022)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "සතිපතා",
          "label": "DATE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලාංකික",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "සතිපතා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "දිනපතා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "එක්-මාසයක්",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ජූලි 12",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ලංකා ඛනිජ තෙල් නීතිගත සංස්ථාව",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "මාසයක්",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "දිනපතා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "සතිපතා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "12 (ජූලි",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "12 වැනි",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "විජේසේකර",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉරිදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජූලි 03",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "සමාගම/කර්මාන්තය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "USD",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "CPC",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "සතිපතා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මාසයක්",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "දිනපතා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "සතිපතා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "12 වැනි",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "12 වැනි",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකන් ගුවන් සේවය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "CPC",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "පෙට්රෝ චීනය",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "දින 180 යි",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "විජේසේකර",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "කොළඹ/ජූලි 03/2022",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "நெருக்கடியால் பாதிக்கப்பட்டுள்ள இலங்கை நிறுவனங்கள் வாராந்த எரிபொருள் விநியோகத்தைப் பெறுவதற்கு டொலரில் பணம் செலுத்த அனுமதிக்கிறது",
      "author": "",
      "body_lines": [
        "ECONOMYNEXT – இலங்கை நிறுவனங்கள் ஒரு மாதத்திற்கு முன்னதாக பொருட்களை டொலரில் செலுத்த முடிந்தால், வாரந்தோறும் அல்லது நாளாந்த அடிப்படையில் எரிபொருளை கொள்வனவு செய்ய முடியும் என எரிபொருள் மற்றும் எரிசக்தி அமைச்சர் காஞ்சன விஜேசேகர தெரிவித்துள்ளார். அதன் பில்களை செலுத்த டாலர்களை கண்டுபிடிக்க.",
        "ஜூலை 12 முதல், எரிபொருள் தேவைகளுக்கு பணம் செலுத்தும் திறன் கொண்ட எந்தவொரு நிறுவனமும், உத்தரவாதமான ஒதுக்கீட்டைப் பெறுவதற்கு இலங்கை பெற்றோலியக் கூட்டுத்தாபனத்தில் நுகர்வோர் கணக்கைத் திறக்க முடியும்.",
        "“அவர்கள் ஒரு மாதத்திற்கு முன் பணம் செலுத்த வேண்டும் மற்றும் எரிபொருள் தினசரி அல்லது வாராந்திர அடிப்படையில் 12 (ஜூலை) முதல் வழங்கப்படும். ஏற்கனவே பணம் செலுத்திய வாடிக்கையாளர்கள் 12 ஆம் தேதி முதல் தங்கள் ஒதுக்கீட்டைப் பெறுவார்கள், ”என்று விஜேசேகர ஞாயிற்றுக்கிழமை (ஜூலை 03) கூறினார்.",
        "USD இல் செலுத்தக்கூடிய எந்தவொரு நிறுவனம்/தொழில் நிறுவனமும் வாராந்திர உத்தரவாத ஒதுக்கீட்டைப் பெற CPC இல் நுகர்வோர் கணக்கைத் திறக்கலாம். அவர்கள் ஒரு மாதத்திற்கு முன்பணமாக செலுத்த வேண்டும் & 12 ஆம் தேதி முதல் தினசரி அல்லது வாராந்திர அடிப்படையில் எரிபொருள் வழங்கப்படும். ஏற்கனவே பணம் செலுத்திய வாடிக்கையாளர்கள் 12ம் தேதி முதல் தங்களின் ஒதுக்கீட்டைப் பெறுவார்கள்.",
        "எரிபொருள் வரிசைகள் தொடர்ந்து அதிகரித்து வரும் நிலையில் இலங்கையின் எரிபொருள் பங்குகள் கிட்டத்தட்ட வறண்டு போயுள்ளன.",
        "முன்னதாக, நாட்டின் பணம் அச்சிடும் மத்திய வங்கி, சில்லறை அளவில் உள்நாட்டு பரிவர்த்தனைகளுக்கு டாலர்களை பயன்படுத்த முடியாது என்ற அடிப்படையில், ஒரு சில எரிபொருள் நிலையங்களை டாலரில் பெட்ரோல் விற்க அனுமதிக்கும் திட்டத்தை நிராகரித்ததாக அமைச்சர் கூறினார்.",
        "அரசால் நடத்தப்படும் தேசிய விமான நிறுவனமான ஸ்ரீலங்கன் ஏர்லைன்ஸ் மற்றும் ஏற்றுமதியாளர்கள் ஏற்கனவே டாலரில் எரிபொருளை செலுத்தி வருவதாகவும், இது CPC யின் நாணய இருப்புக்கு உதவுவதாகவும் அமைச்சர் எடுத்துரைத்தார்.",
        "வெளிநாட்டு வங்கிகள் இலங்கையின் கடன் கடிதத்தை உறுதிப்படுத்த மறுத்து வரும் அதே வேளையில், சில புதிய சப்ளையர்கள் எரிபொருள் விநியோகத்திற்காக முன்பணம் செலுத்துமாறு கேட்டிருந்தனர்.",
        "தொடர்புடையது: வெளிநாட்டு வங்கிகள் இலங்கை அரச வங்கி கடன் கடிதங்களை உறுதிப்படுத்த மறுக்கின்றன: அமைச்சர்",
        "இலங்கைக்கு LCக்கள் மூலம் 180 நாட்கள் கடனுதவி வழங்கிய பெட்ரோ சைனா போன்ற சப்ளையர்கள் தற்போது முன்பணம் கேட்கின்றனர் என அமைச்சர் விஜேசேகர தெரிவித்தார். (கொழும்பு/ஜூலை03/2022)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "இலங்கை",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "வாரந்தோறும்",
          "label": "DATE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "வாரந்தோறும்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "தினசரி",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஒரு மாதம்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஜூலை 12",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை பெற்றோலியக் கூட்டுத்தாபனம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஒரு மாதம்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "தினசரி",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "வாரந்தோறும்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "12ஆம் தேதி (ஜூலை",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "12வது",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "விஜேசேகர",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஞாயிற்றுக்கிழமை",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜூலை 03",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "நிறுவனம் தொழில்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "அமெரிக்க டாலர்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "CPC",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "வாரந்தோறும்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஒரு மாதம்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "தினசரி",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "வாரந்தோறும்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "12வது",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "12வது",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கையின்",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஸ்ரீலங்கன் ஏர்லைன்ஸ்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "CPC",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கையின்",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பெட்ரோ சீனா",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "180 நாட்கள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "விஜேசேகர",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "கொழும்பு/ஜூலை03/2022",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}