{
  "newspaper_id": "ada-lk",
  "url": "https://www.ada.lk/breaking_news/ලොරි---බස්-ගැටී-අයෙක්-මරුට/11-396745",
  "time_ut": 1661852970,
  "original_lang": "si",
  "original_title": "ලොරි - බස් ගැටී අයෙක් මරුට",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Lorry-bus collided and one person died",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "A private bus traveling from Galle to Matara collided with a lorry on the Galle Sea Road this morning (30th) when it collided with another vehicle. The driver of the bus was killed. Police said.",
        "The deceased is the driver of the private bus named Miran Chanaka (33) resident of Nagoda area of ​​Gammaddagoda. The 48-year-old lorry driver and the 40-year-old lorry assistant who are residents of Horangalla Minuwangoda area were seriously injured in this accident.",
        "At the time of the accident, the bus was also in the bus and there was no accident. The lorry is a newspaper distribution lorry and the police said that the accident occurred while the lorry was driving from Mataradesa towards Galle after the distribution of newspapers.",
        "The investigation will be conducted under the direction of Mr. Kapila Senapati De Silva, Head of Galle Police Inspector."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Lorry",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "one",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Galle",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Matara",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Galle Sea Road",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "this morning",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "30th",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Miran Chanaka",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "33",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "48-year-old",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "40-year-old",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Horangalla Minuwangoda",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Mataradesa",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Galle",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Kapila Senapati De Silva",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Galle Police Inspector",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "ලොරි - බස් ගැටී අයෙක් මරුට",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "ගාල්ල සිට මාතර බලාධාවනය වෙමින් තිබු පුද්ගලික  බස්රථයක් අද (30දා) උදැසන ගාල්ල සමුද්‍ර රමාවතේ දි වෙනත් රථයකට ඉස්සරකිරිමට යාමේ දි  ගාල්ල දෙසට ධාවනය වෙමින් තිබු  ලොරිරථයක ගැටිමෙන් වු අනතුරකින් බසයේ රියදුරු මියගොස්  ලොරිරථයේ රියදුරු හා තවත් අයෙකු බරපතල තුවාල ලබා ගාල්ල කරාපිටිය ශික්ෂණ රෝහලට ඇතුලත්කොට ඇති බැව් ගාල්ල  පොලිසිය පවසයි.",
        "මියගොස් ඇත්තේ පුද්ගලික බස්රථයේ රියදුරුවන මිරාන් චානක  (33)  නැමති ගම්මැද්දගොඩ නාගොඩ ප්‍රදේශයේ පදිංචිකරුවෙකි. මෙම අනතුරෙන් බරපතල තුවාල ලබා ඇත්තේ හොරංගල්ල මිනුවන්ගොඩ ප්‍රදේශයේ පදිංචි 48 හැවිරිදිවියේ පසුවන ලොරිරථයේ රියදුරු හා 40 හැවිරිදිවියේ පසුවන ලොරිරථ සහායකයාය.",
        "අනතුරවන අවස්ථාවේ දි බස්රථයේ මගින් ද සිට ඇති අතර මගින්ට අනතුරුක් වි නැත. ලොරිරථය පුවත්පත් බේදාහැරිමේ කටයුතු  සිදුකරණ ලොරිරථයක් වන අතර  පුවත්පත් බෙදිමේ කටයුතු අවසන්කොට  මාතරදෙස සිට ගාල්ල දෙසට  ලොරිරථය ධාවනය වෙමින් තිබියදි මෙම අනතුරට ලක්ව ඇති බව පොලිසිය පවසයි.",
        "ගාල්ල  මුලස්ථාන පොලිස් පරික්ෂක කපිල සේනාපතිද සිල්වා මහතාගේ මෙහෙයවිම යටතේ පරික්ෂණ පැවැත්වේ."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ලොරි",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "එක",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ගාල්ල",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මාතර",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගාලු මුහුදු පාර",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "මේ උදෑසන",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "30 වැනි",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Miran Chanaka",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "33",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "48 හැවිරිදිය",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "40 හැවිරිදිය",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "හොරංගල්ල මිනුවන්ගොඩ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "මාතරදෙස",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගාල්ල",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "කපිල සේනාපති ද සිල්වා",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගාල්ල පොලිස් පරීක්ෂක",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "லாரியும் பேருந்தும் மோதியதில் ஒருவர் உயிரிழந்தார்",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "இன்று (30) காலை காலி கடல் வீதியில் காலியில் இருந்து மாத்தறை நோக்கி பயணித்த தனியார் பஸ் ஒன்று லொறியொன்றுடன் மோதியதில் மற்றுமொரு வாகனம் மோதியதில் பஸ்ஸின் சாரதி உயிரிழந்துள்ளதாக பொலிஸார் தெரிவித்தனர்.",
        "கம்மத்தகொட நாகொட பகுதியைச் சேர்ந்த மீரான் சானக்க (33) என்ற தனியார் பேருந்தின் சாரதியே உயிரிழந்துள்ளார். இந்த விபத்தில் ஹொரங்கல்ல மினுவாங்கொட பகுதியைச் சேர்ந்த 48 வயதான லொறி சாரதியும் 40 வயதுடைய லொறி உதவியாளரும் படுகாயமடைந்துள்ளனர்.",
        "விபத்தின் போது பேருந்தும் பேருந்தில் இருந்ததால் விபத்து ஏதும் ஏற்படவில்லை. இந்த லொறி பத்திரிகை விநியோகம் செய்யும் லொறி எனவும், பத்திரிகை விநியோகம் முடிந்து மாதரதேசத்தில் இருந்து காலி நோக்கி லொறி சென்று கொண்டிருந்த போதே இவ்விபத்து நேர்ந்துள்ளதாக பொலிஸார் தெரிவித்தனர்.",
        "காலி பொலிஸ் பரிசோதகர் திரு.கபில சேனாபதி டி சில்வா தலைமையில் விசாரணை நடத்தப்படவுள்ளது."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "சரக்குந்து",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "ஒன்று",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "காலி",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "மாத்தறை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "காலி கடல் பாதை",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று காலை",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "30வது",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Miran Chanaka",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "33",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "48 வயது",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "40 வயது",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஹொரங்கல்ல மினுவாங்கொட",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "மாதரதேச",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "காலி",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "கபில சேனாபதி டி சில்வா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "காலி பொலிஸ் பரிசோதகர்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}