{
  "newspaper_id": "news-first-lk",
  "url": "https://www.newsfirst.lk/2022/06/27/us-to-provide-technical-assistance-for-fiscal-management-high-level-delegates-meet-pm/",
  "time_ut": 1656325500,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "US to provide technical assistance for fiscal management; High-Level delegates meet PM",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "US to provide technical assistance for fiscal management; High-Level delegates meet PM",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); The United States has agreed to provide technical assistance for fiscal management in Sri Lanka, said the Prime Minister’s Media Division.",
        "Kelly Keiderling, Deputy Secretary of State for South and Central Asia at the U.S. State Department, who arrived in Sri Lanka yesterday, held a discussion with Prime Minister Ranil Wickremesinghe today (27).",
        "The US Diplomatic Group also stated its support for the ongoing talks between the Government of Sri Lanka and the International Monetary Fund.",
        "Robert Kaproth, Deputy Assistant Secretary of the Treasury for Asia in the United States and Julie Chung, US Ambassador to Sri Lanka, also participated in the discussion held at the Prime Minister’s Office.",
        "In addition, Secretary to the Prime Minister Saman Ekanayake and Senior Adviser to the Prime Minister Dr. R.H. Samaratunga was also present.",
        "US to provide technical assistance for fiscal management; High-Level delegates meet PM",
        "Fuel Crisis leading to deterioration of Law and Order – BASL"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "US",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "The United States",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Kelly Keiderling",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "State",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Central Asia",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "the U.S. State Department",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "yesterday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "27",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "The US Diplomatic Group",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Government of Sri Lanka",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the International Monetary Fund",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Robert Kaproth",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Treasury",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Asia",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "the United States",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Julie Chung",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "US",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Prime Minister’s Office",
            "label": "FAC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Saman Ekanayake",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "R.H. Samaratunga",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "US",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        []
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "රාජ්‍ය මූල්‍ය කළමනාකරණය සඳහා තාක්ෂණික සහාය ලබාදීමට එක්සත් ජනපදය; ඉහළ පෙළේ නියෝජිතයන් අගමැති හමුවෙයි",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ රාජ්‍ය මූල්‍ය කළමනාකරණය සඳහා තාක්ෂණික සහය ලබාදීමට එක්සත් ජනපදය එකඟ වී ඇති බව අග්‍රාමාත්‍ය මාධ්‍ය අංශය පවසයි.",
        "ඊයේ ශ්‍රී ලංකාවට පැමිණි අමෙරිකානු රාජ්‍ය දෙපාර්තමේන්තුවේ දකුණු සහ මධ්‍යම ආසියාව භාර නියෝජ්‍ය රාජ්‍ය ලේකම් කෙලී කීඩර්ලින් මහතා අද (27) අග්‍රාමාත්‍ය රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතා සමඟ සාකච්ඡාවක නිරත විය.",
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකා රජය සහ ජාත්‍යන්තර මුල්‍ය අරමුදල අතර පැවැත්වෙන සාකච්ඡා සඳහා සහය පළ කරන බව ද ඇමෙරිකානු රාජ්‍යතාන්ත්‍රික කණ්ඩායම ප්‍රකාශ කළේය.",
        "අග්‍රාමාත්‍ය කාර්යාලයේ පැවති මෙම සාකච්ඡාවට ඇමරිකා එක්සත් ජනපදයේ ආසියා භාණ්ඩාගාරයේ නියෝජ්‍ය සහකාර ලේකම් Robert Kaproth සහ ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ ඇමරිකානු තානාපතිනි Julie Chung යන මහත්ම මහත්මීන් ද සහභාගී වූහ.",
        "ඊට අමතරව අග්‍රාමාත්‍ය ලේකම් සමන් ඒකනායක, අග්‍රාමාත්‍ය ජ්‍යෙෂ්ඨ උපදේශක ආචාර්ය ආර්.එච්.",
        "රාජ්‍ය මූල්‍ය කළමනාකරණය සඳහා තාක්ෂණික සහාය ලබාදීමට එක්සත් ජනපදය; ඉහළ පෙළේ නියෝජිතයන් අගමැති හමුවෙයි",
        "නීතිය හා සාමය පිරිහීමට තුඩු දෙන ඉන්ධන අර්බුදය - BASL"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "එක්සත් ජනපදය",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "එක්සත් ජනපදය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "කෙලී කීඩර්ලින්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "රජයේ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "මධ්යම ආසියාව",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "එක්සත් ජනපද රාජ්ය දෙපාර්තමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඊයේ",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "27",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "එක්සත් ජනපද රාජ්‍යතාන්ත්‍රික කණ්ඩායම",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකා රජය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජාත්‍යන්තර මුල්‍ය අරමුදල",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "රොබට් කප්රොත්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "භාණ්ඩාගාර",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ආසියාව",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "එක්සත් ජනපදය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජූලි චුන්ග්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "එක්සත් ජනපදය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "අගමැති කාර්යාලය",
            "label": "FAC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "සමන් ඒකනායක",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ආර්.එච් සමරතුංග",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "එක්සත් ජනපදය",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        []
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "நிதி நிர்வாகத்திற்கான தொழில்நுட்ப உதவியை வழங்க அமெரிக்கா; உயர்மட்ட பிரதிநிதிகள் பிரதமரை சந்திக்கின்றனர்",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); இலங்கையில் நிதி முகாமைத்துவத்திற்கான தொழில்நுட்ப உதவிகளை வழங்க அமெரிக்கா இணக்கம் தெரிவித்துள்ளதாக பிரதமரின் ஊடகப் பிரிவு தெரிவித்துள்ளது.",
        "நேற்று இலங்கை வந்துள்ள அமெரிக்க இராஜாங்கத் திணைக்களத்தின் தெற்கு மற்றும் மத்திய ஆசியாவுக்கான பிரதி இராஜாங்கச் செயலாளர் கெல்லி கெய்டர்லிங் இன்று (27) பிரதமர் ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்கவுடன் கலந்துரையாடினார்.",
        "இலங்கை அரசாங்கத்திற்கும் சர்வதேச நாணய நிதியத்திற்கும் இடையில் இடம்பெற்று வரும் பேச்சுவார்த்தைகளுக்கு ஆதரவளிப்பதாகவும் அமெரிக்க இராஜதந்திர குழு தெரிவித்துள்ளது.",
        "பிரதமர் அலுவலகத்தில் நடைபெற்ற இந்த கலந்துரையாடலில் அமெரிக்காவிற்கான ஆசிய திறைசேரியின் பிரதி உதவி செயலாளர் ரொபேர்ட் கப்ரோத் மற்றும் இலங்கைக்கான அமெரிக்க தூதுவர் ஜூலி சுங் ஆகியோரும் கலந்துகொண்டனர்.",
        "மேலும், பிரதமரின் செயலாளர் சமன் ஏக்கநாயக்க மற்றும் பிரதமரின் சிரேஷ்ட ஆலோசகர் கலாநிதி ஆர்.எச்.சமரதுங்க ஆகியோரும் கலந்துகொண்டனர்.",
        "நிதி நிர்வாகத்திற்கான தொழில்நுட்ப உதவியை வழங்க அமெரிக்கா; உயர்மட்ட பிரதிநிதிகள் பிரதமரை சந்திக்கின்றனர்",
        "சட்டம் மற்றும் ஒழுங்கு சீர்குலைவதற்கு வழிவகுக்கும் எரிபொருள் நெருக்கடி - BASL"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "எங்களுக்கு",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ஐக்கிய நாடுகள்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "கெல்லி கெய்டர்லிங்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "நிலை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "மைய ஆசியா",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "அமெரிக்க வெளியுறவுத்துறை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "நேற்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "27",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "அமெரிக்க இராஜதந்திர குழு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை அரசாங்கம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "சர்வதேச நாணய நிதியம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ராபர்ட் கப்ரோத்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "கருவூலம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆசியா",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஐக்கிய நாடுகள்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜூலி சுங்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "எங்களுக்கு",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "பிரதமர் அலுவலகம்",
            "label": "FAC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "சமன் ஏக்கநாயக்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆர்.எச் சமரதுங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "எங்களுக்கு",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        []
      ]
    }
  }
}