{
  "newspaper_id": "colombo-telegraph-com",
  "url": "https://www.colombotelegraph.com/index.php/26-6-million-of-sri-lankan-taxpayers-money-spent-on-former-prime-minister-mahinda-rajapaksas-trip-to-italy/",
  "time_ut": 1659239214,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "26.6 Million Of Sri Lankan Taxpayers’ Money Spent On Former Prime Minister Mahinda Rajapaksa’s Trip To Italy",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "26.6 Million Of Sri Lankan Taxpayers’ Money Spent On Former Prime Minister Mahinda Rajapaksa’s Trip To Italy",
      "author": "COLOMBO TELEGRAPH",
      "body_lines": [
        "Information handed over by the Prime Minister’s Office (PMO) to Sri Lanka’s RTI Commission on 26th July 2022 has revealed that approximately 26.6 million of public funds had been spent by the Government for the travel, accommodation, food and other expenses of former Prime Minister Mahinda Rajapaksa, his wife Shiranthi Rajapaksa, his son, Yoshitha Rajapaksa who was also his Chief of Staff, his Secretary Gamini Senerath, his Chief Coordinating Officer Malaka Chandradasa and other officials to travel to Italy in September 2021.",
        "The information was released on the RTI Commission directing the PMO to respond, on June 15th 2022, dismissing its objection that national security/security of the Prime Minister prevented the release of the information. The appeal to the Commission had been filed in February 2022 by K Dileepamuthan, a journalist based in the country’s Northern Province",
        "Media reports at the time were to the effect that the former Prime Minister’s travel to Italy for a period of several days had been for a ‘diplomatic’ visit though no exact details were given except attendance at a conference organised by a non-governmental organisation. His travel had incurred expenditure to the tune of approx 1.3 million for food and other expenses, 8.6 million for airfare expenses and 16.6 million for other expenses. Several controversies occurred during this trip including reports that Rajapaksa had been booed by Sri Lankans living in Italy",
        "The wastage of taxpayers’ money on foreign jaunts of Sri Lankan politicians had been a major focus of the peoples’ struggle against corruption and squandering of public money during the past several months in the country, drawing thousands of ordinary Sri Lankans to the streets.  Presently, a sizable segment of the population has catapulted into poverty, unable to afford a single square meal for the day.",
        "Reports abound of desperate mothers and fathers committing suicide as they are unable to feed their children with skyrocketing inflation and the lack of steady income. The nation’s once admired free public health care system is also in dire straits with patients unable to be given free medication from hospitals and unable to pay for that themselves.",
        "Notably the request for information in this instance had been filed by a journalist of minority Tamil ethnicity in Jaffna who had asked for the information based on the public interest under the RTI Act and upon being refused, had appealed to the Colombo based RTI Commission which had ordered the release of the information."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "26.6 Million",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "Mahinda Rajapaksa",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "Trip To Italy",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "PMO",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka’s",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "RTI Commission",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "26th July 2022",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "approximately 26.6 million",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Mahinda Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Shiranthi Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Yoshitha Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Gamini Senerath",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Chandradasa",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Italy",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "September 2021",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the RTI Commission",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "PMO",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "June 15th 2022",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "February 2022",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "K Dileepamuthan",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Northern Province",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Italy",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "1.3 million",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "8.6 million",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "16.6 million",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Rajapaksa",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lankans",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Italy",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lankan",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "the past several months",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "thousands",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lankans",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "the day",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "Tamil",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Jaffna",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the RTI Act",
            "label": "LAW"
          },
          {
            "text": "Colombo",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "RTI Commission",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "හිටපු අගමැති මහින්ද රාජපක්ෂගේ ඉතාලි සංචාරය සඳහා ශ්‍රී ලාංකික බදු ගෙවන්නන්ගේ මුදල් මිලියන 26.6ක්",
      "author": "COLOMBO Telegraph",
      "body_lines": [
        "2022 ජුලි 26 වන දින අග්‍රාමාත්‍ය කාර්යාලය (PMO) විසින් ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ තොරතුරු දැනගැනීමේ කොමිෂන් සභාව වෙත භාර දුන් තොරතුරුවලින් හෙළි වී ඇත්තේ හිටපු අගමැති මහින්දගේ ගමන්, නවාතැන්, ආහාර සහ අනෙකුත් වියදම් සඳහා රජය විසින් දළ වශයෙන් මිලියන 26.6 ක මහජන මුදල් වැය කර ඇති බවයි. රාජපක්ෂ, ඔහුගේ බිරිඳ ශිරන්ති රාජපක්ෂ, ඔහුගේ පුත්, ඔහුගේ කාර්ය මණ්ඩල ප්‍රධානියා වූ යෝෂිත රාජපක්ෂ, ඔහුගේ ලේකම් ගාමිණී සෙනරත්, ඔහුගේ ප්‍රධාන සම්බන්ධීකරණ නිලධාරී මාලක චන්ද්‍රදාස ඇතුළු නිලධාරීන් 2021 සැප්තැම්බර් මාසයේදී ඉතාලියට යාමට නියමිතය.",
        "2022 ජූනි 15 වැනි දින PMO වෙත ප්‍රතිචාර දක්වන ලෙස RTI කොමිසමට නියෝග කරමින් තොරතුරු නිකුත් කරන ලදී, අග්‍රාමාත්‍යවරයාගේ ජාතික ආරක්ෂාව/ආරක්ෂාව තොරතුරු නිකුත් කිරීම වැළැක්වූ බවට එහි විරෝධය ප්‍රතික්ෂේප කළේය. කොමිසමට අභියාචනය ගොනු කර තිබුණේ 2022 පෙබරවාරි මාසයේදී රටේ උතුරු පළාතේ මාධ්‍යවේදියෙකු වන කේ දිලීපමුදන් විසිනි.",
        "රාජ්‍ය නොවන සංවිධානයක් විසින් සංවිධානය කරන ලද සම්මන්ත්‍රණයකට සහභාගි වීම හැර නිශ්චිත තොරතුරු කිසිවක් ප්‍රකාශ නොකළද හිටපු අගමැතිවරයා දින කිහිපයක ඉතාලියේ සංචාරය කළේ ‘රාජ්‍ය තාන්ත්‍රික’ සංචාරයක් සඳහා බව එකල මාධ්‍ය වාර්තා පළ විය. ඔහුගේ සංචාරය සඳහා ආහාර සහ අනෙකුත් වියදම් සඳහා මිලියන 1.3 ක් ද, ගුවන් ගමන් වියදම් සඳහා මිලියන 8.6 ක් ද, අනෙකුත් වියදම් සඳහා මිලියන 16.6 ක් ද වැය කර ඇත. ඉතාලියේ වෙසෙන ශ්‍රී ලාංකිකයන් විසින් රාජපක්ෂ මහතාට බැණ වැදුණු බවට පළ වූ වාර්තා ඇතුළු ආන්දෝලනාත්මක සිදුවීම් රැසක් මෙම සංචාරයේදී සිදු විය.",
        "සාමාන්‍ය ශ්‍රී ලාංකිකයන් දහස් ගණනක් පාරට ඇද දමමින් පසුගිය මාස කිහිපය තුළ රට තුළ දූෂණයට සහ මහජන මුදල් නාස්තියට එරෙහි ජනතා අරගලයේ ප්‍රධාන අවධානය යොමු වූයේ ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ දේශපාලකයන්ගේ විදේශ සංචාර සඳහා බදු ගෙවන්නන්ගේ මුදල් නාස්ති කිරීමයි. වර්තමානයේ, ජනගහනයෙන් සැලකිය යුතු කොටසක් දිළිඳුකමට ඇද වැටී ඇති අතර, දවසට එක වර්ග ආහාර වේලක් ලබා ගැනීමට නොහැකි වී ඇත.",
        "ඉහළ යන උද්ධමනය සහ ස්ථාවර ආදායමක් නොමැතිකම හේතුවෙන් තම දරුවන්ට පෝෂණය කිරීමට නොහැකිව මංමුලා සහගත මව්වරුන් සහ පියවරුන් සියදිවි නසා ගන්නා බවට වාර්තා ඕනෑ තරම් තිබේ. කලක් ජාතියේ ගෞරවයට පාත්‍ර වූ නිදහස් මහජන සෞඛ්‍ය සේවා පද්ධතිය ද රෝහල්වලින් නොමිලයේ ඖෂධ ලබා දීමට නොහැකිව සහ ඒ සඳහා ගෙවීමට නොහැකිව රෝගීන් දැඩි අසීරුතාවයකට පත්ව ඇත.",
        "යාපනයේ සුළුතර දෙමළ ජනවාර්ගික මාධ්‍යවේදියෙකු විසින් තොරතුරු දැනගැනීමේ පනත යටතේ මහජන අවශ්‍යතා මත තොරතුරු ඉල්ලා මෙම තොරතුරු ඉල්ලා සිටීමත් එය ප්‍රතික්ෂේප කිරීමත් සමඟ කොළඹ පදනම් වූ RTI කොමිසමට අභියාචනයක් ඉදිරිපත් කර තිබීම විශේෂත්වයකි. තොරතුරු නිකුත් කරන ලෙස නියෝග කළේය."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "මිලියන 26.6 කි",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "මහින්ද රාජපක්ෂ",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "ඉතාලියට සංචාරය",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "PMO",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "RTI කොමිසම",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "2022 ජූලි 26",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ආසන්න වශයෙන් මිලියන 26.6 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "මහින්ද රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශිරන්ති රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "යෝෂිත රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගාමිණී සෙනරත්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "චන්ද්‍රදාස ය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉතාලිය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "සැප්තැම්බර් 2021",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "RTI කොමිසම",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "PMO",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "2022 ජූනි 15",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "2022 පෙබරවාරි",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "කේ දිලීපමුතන්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "උතුරු පළාත",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ඉතාලිය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මිලියන 1.3 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "මිලියන 8.6 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "මිලියන 16.6 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලාංකිකයන්",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉතාලිය",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලාංකික",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "පසුගිය මාස කිහිපය",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "දහස්",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලාංකිකයන්",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "දවස",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "දෙමළ",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "යාපනය",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "RTI පනත",
            "label": "LAW"
          },
          {
            "text": "කොළඹ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "RTI කොමිසම",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "முன்னாள் பிரதமர் மகிந்த ராஜபக்சவின் இத்தாலி பயணத்திற்காக இலங்கை வரி செலுத்துவோரின் 26.6 மில்லியன் பணம் செலவிடப்பட்டுள்ளது.",
      "author": "கொழும்பு டெலிகிராப்",
      "body_lines": [
        "பிரதமர் அலுவலகம் (PMO) 26 ஜூலை 2022 அன்று இலங்கையின் RTI ஆணைக்குழுவிடம் ஒப்படைத்த தகவல், முன்னாள் பிரதமர் மஹிந்தவின் பயணம், தங்குமிடம், உணவு மற்றும் பிற செலவுகளுக்காக சுமார் 26.6 மில்லியன் பொது நிதி அரசாங்கத்தால் செலவிடப்பட்டுள்ளதாக தெரியவந்துள்ளது. ராஜபக்ஷ, அவரது மனைவி ஷிரந்தி ராஜபக்ஷ, அவரது மகன், அவரது தலைமை அதிகாரியாக இருந்த யோஷித ராஜபக்ஷ, அவரது செயலாளர் காமினி செனரத், அவரது தலைமை ஒருங்கிணைப்பாளர் மாலக சந்திரதாச மற்றும் பிற அதிகாரிகள் செப்டம்பர் 2021 இல் இத்தாலிக்கு பயணம் செய்ய உள்ளனர்.",
        "பிரதமரின் தேசிய பாதுகாப்பு/பாதுகாப்பு, தகவல்களை வெளியிடுவதைத் தடுக்கிறது என்ற அதன் ஆட்சேபனையை நிராகரித்து, ஜூன் 15 2022 அன்று, பதிலளிக்குமாறு PMO க்கு ஆணையிடும் RTI கமிஷன் குறித்த தகவல் வெளியிடப்பட்டது. 2022 ஆம் ஆண்டு பெப்ரவரி மாதம் நாட்டின் வடமாகாணத்தைச் சேர்ந்த ஊடகவியலாளர் கே திலீபமுதனினால் ஆணைக்குழுவில் மேன்முறையீடு செய்யப்பட்டது.",
        "அரச சார்பற்ற நிறுவனமொன்றினால் ஏற்பாடு செய்யப்பட்டிருந்த மாநாட்டில் கலந்துகொண்டதைத் தவிர சரியான விபரங்கள் எதுவும் தெரிவிக்கப்படாத போதிலும், முன்னாள் பிரதமரின் பல நாட்கள் இத்தாலிக்கான பயணம் ‘இராஜதந்திர’ விஜயமாக இருந்ததாக அப்போதைய ஊடகச் செய்திகள் தெரிவிக்கின்றன. அவரது பயணத்திற்கு உணவு மற்றும் இதர செலவுகளுக்கு சுமார் 1.3 மில்லியன் செலவாகும், விமான கட்டண செலவுகளுக்காக 8.6 மில்லியன் மற்றும் பிற செலவுகளுக்கு 16.6 மில்லியன் செலவானது. இந்த பயணத்தின் போது, ​​இத்தாலியில் வசிக்கும் இலங்கையர்கள் ராஜபக்சேவை கொச்சைப்படுத்தியதாக பல சர்ச்சைகள் எழுந்தன.",
        "இலங்கை அரசியல்வாதிகளின் வெளிநாட்டு பயணங்களுக்கு வரி செலுத்துவோரின் பணத்தை வீணடிப்பது, நாட்டில் கடந்த சில மாதங்களாக ஊழல் மற்றும் பொதுப் பணத்தை விரயமாக்குவதற்கு எதிரான மக்களின் போராட்டத்தின் முக்கிய மையமாக இருந்தது, ஆயிரக்கணக்கான சாதாரண இலங்கையர்களை வீதிக்கு இழுத்தது. தற்போது, ​​மக்கள்தொகையில் கணிசமான பகுதியினர் ஒரு நாளைக்கு ஒரு சதுர உணவைக் கூட வாங்க முடியாமல் வறுமையில் தள்ளப்பட்டுள்ளனர்.",
        "பணவீக்கம் மற்றும் நிலையான வருமானம் இல்லாததால் தங்கள் குழந்தைகளுக்கு உணவளிக்க முடியாமல் விரக்தியடைந்த தாய்மார்கள் மற்றும் தந்தைகள் தற்கொலை செய்துகொள்வதாக செய்திகள் ஏராளம். தேசம் ஒரு காலத்தில் போற்றப்பட்ட இலவச பொது சுகாதாரப் பாதுகாப்பு முறையும் நோயாளிகள் மருத்துவமனைகளில் இருந்து இலவச மருந்துகளை வழங்க முடியாமல், அதற்கான கட்டணத்தை தாங்களே செலுத்த முடியாமல் திணறுகின்றனர்.",
        "யாழ்ப்பாணத்தில் உள்ள சிறுபான்மை தமிழ் இனத்தைச் சேர்ந்த ஊடகவியலாளர் ஒருவர் தகவல் அறியும் உரிமைச் சட்டத்தின் கீழ் பொது நலன்களின் அடிப்படையில் தகவல்களைக் கோரிய இந்தச் சந்தர்ப்பத்தில் தகவல் கோரியிருந்த நிலையில், அது நிராகரிக்கப்பட்டதையடுத்து, கொழும்பைத் தளமாகக் கொண்ட RTI ஆணைக்குழுவில் முறையீடு செய்திருந்தது குறிப்பிடத்தக்கது. தகவல்களை வெளியிட உத்தரவிட்டார்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "26.6 மில்லியன்",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "மஹிந்த ராஜபக்ஷ",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "இத்தாலி பயணம்",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "PMO",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கையின்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "RTI கமிஷன்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "26 ஜூலை 2022",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "தோராயமாக 26.6 மில்லியன்",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "மஹிந்த ராஜபக்ஷ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஷிரந்தி ராஜபக்ச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "யோஷித ராஜபக்ச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "காமினி செனரத்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "சந்திரதாச",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இத்தாலி",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "செப்டம்பர் 2021",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "RTI கமிஷன்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "PMO",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜூன் 15 2022",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "பிப்ரவரி 2022",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "கே திலீபமுதன்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "வட மாகாணம்",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இத்தாலி",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "1.3 மில்லியன்",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "8.6 மில்லியன்",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "16.6 மில்லியன்",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ராஜபக்சே",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கையர்கள்",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "இத்தாலி",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "கடந்த பல மாதங்களாக",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆயிரக்கணக்கான",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கையர்கள்",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "தினம்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "தமிழ்",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "யாழ்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "RTI சட்டம்",
            "label": "LAW"
          },
          {
            "text": "கொழும்பு",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "RTI கமிஷன்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}