{
  "newspaper_id": "lankadeepa-lk",
  "url": "https://www.lankadeepa.lk/latest_news/නීතිඥයෝ-350ක්-අරගලකරුවන්-වෙනුවෙන්-පෙනී-සිටිති/1-616889",
  "time_ut": 1658498448,
  "original_lang": "si",
  "original_title": "නීතිඥයෝ 350ක් අරගලකරුවන් වෙනුවෙන් පෙනී සිටිති",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "350 lawyers represent the strugglers",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "Colombo Fort Acting Magistrate Mr. Jayantha Dias Nanayakkara today (22) released the nine suspects, including lawyer Nuwan Bopage, who were arrested in the early morning incident at the Galumuwadora protest site on a cash bail of 10,000 rupees each and 2 body bails of 5 lakh rupees. ) ordered.",
        "The court called the case related to this incident and ordered the bail of the suspects to be deposited in the court on the next day, and also ordered them to be released on personal bail.",
        "Among these nine suspects, two suspects are being treated in hospital and both of them were granted bail by the court.",
        "On behalf of the suspects, a panel of over three hundred and fifty lawyers led by President's Lawyers Saliya Peiris, Sarath Jayamanna, Rienzi Arsakularatne and Upul Jayasuriya appeared before the court and presented the facts.",
        "Deputy Solicitor General Mr. Janaka Bandara representing the Attorney General, Colombo Central Division Senior Superintendent of Police Roshanda Dias, Assistant Superintendent of Police Villakawaarachichi and Fort Police Station Commander Sagara Liyanage appeared before the court."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "350",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Jayantha Dias Nanayakkara",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "22",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "nine",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Nuwan Bopage",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Galumuwadora",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "10,000",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "2",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "5",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the next day",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "nine",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "two",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "three hundred and fifty",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Lawyers Saliya Peiris",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sarath Jayamanna",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Upul Jayasuriya",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Janaka Bandara",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Colombo Central Division Senior Superintendent of Police",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Roshanda Dias",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Fort Police Station",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sagara Liyanage",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "නීතිඥයෝ 350ක් අරගලකරුවන් වෙනුවෙන් පෙනී සිටිති",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "ගාලුමුවදොර අරගල භූමියේදී අද (22) අලුයම සිදුවූ සිද්ධියෙන් අත්අඩංගුවට ගත් නීතීඥ නුවන් බෝපගේ ඇතුළු සැකකරුවන් නව දෙනා එක් අයකුට රුපියල් 10,000/=ක මුදල් ඇපයක් සහ රුපියල් ලක්ෂ 5 ක ශරීර ඇප 2ක් මත මුදා හැරීමට කොළඹ කොටුව වැඩබලන මහේස්ත්‍රාත් ජයන්ත ඩයස් නානායක්කාර මහතා අද (22) නියෝග කළේය.",
        "මෙම සිද්ධියට අදාළ නඩුව කැඳවලා  ඉදිරි දිනයේදී සැකකරුවන්ගේ ඇප අධිකරණයට තැන්පත් කිරීමට නියම කළ අධිකරණය, ඔවුන් පුද්ගලික ඇප මත මුදා මැරීමට ද මෙහිදී නියම කළේය.",
        "මෙම සැකකරුවන් නවදෙනා අතර සිටි සැකකරුවන් දෙදෙනකු රෝහල් ගතව ප්‍රතිකාර ලබන  අතර ඔවුන් දෙදෙනාටද අධිකරණයෙන් ඇප නියම විණි.",
        "සැකකරුවන් වෙනුවෙන් ජනාධිපති නීතිඥවරුන් වන සාලිය පීරිස්, සරත් ජයමාන්න, රියෙන්සි අර්සකුලරත්න සහ උපුල් ජයසූරිය යන මහත්වරුන් ප්‍රමුඛ තුන්සිය පනහකට අධික නීතිඥ මඩුල්ලක් අධිකරණය හමුවේ පෙනී සිටිමින් කරුණු ඉදිරිපත් කළහ.",
        "පැමිණිල්ල වෙනුවෙන් නීතිපතිවරයා නියෝජනය කරමින් නියෝජ්‍ය සොලිසිටර් ජෙනරාල් ජනක බණ්ඩාර මහතා සමග කොළඹ මධ්‍යම කොට්ඨාස භාර ජ්‍යෙෂ්ඨ පොලිස් අධිකාරි රෝෂාන්ද ඩයස්, සහකාර පොලිස් අධිකාරී විල්ලකවාඅරචිචි, කොටුව පොලිස් ස්ථානාධිපති සාගර ලියනගේ යන මහත්වරුන් ඇතුළු නිලධාරීහු අධිකරණය හමුවේ පෙනී සිටියහ."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "350",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ජයන්ත ඩයස් නානායක්කාර",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "22",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "නවය",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Nuwan Bopage",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Galumuwadora",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "10,000 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "2",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "5",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ඊළඟ දිනය",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "නවය",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "දෙක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "තුන්සිය පනහයි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "නීතිඥ සාලිය පීරිස්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "සරත් ජයමාන්න",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "උපුල් ජයසූරිය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ජනක බණ්ඩාර",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "කොළඹ මධ්‍යම කොට්ඨාශ ජ්‍යෙෂ්ඨ පොලිස් අධිකාරි",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "රොෂාන්ද ඩයස්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "කොටුව පොලිස් ස්ථානය",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "සාගර ලියනගේ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "போராட்டக்காரர்கள் சார்பில் 350 வழக்கறிஞர்கள்",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "இன்று (22) காலை கலுமுவதொர போராட்ட தளத்தில் வைத்து கைது செய்யப்பட்ட சட்டத்தரணி நுவான் போபகே உட்பட ஒன்பது சந்தேக நபர்களையும் தலா 10,000 ரூபா ரொக்கப் பிணையிலும் 5 சரீரப் பிணையிலும் 2 சரீரப் பிணைகளிலும் கொழும்பு கோட்டை பதில் நீதவான் திரு. லட்சம் ரூபாய்.) உத்தரவிட்டார்.",
        "இந்த சம்பவம் தொடர்பான வழக்கை விசாரணைக்கு எடுத்துக்கொண்ட நீதிமன்றம், சந்தேகநபர்களின் பிணையை நாளை மறுதினம் நீதிமன்றில் வைக்குமாறு உத்தரவிட்டதுடன், அவர்களை சொந்த பிணையில் விடுவிக்கவும் உத்தரவிட்டுள்ளது.",
        "இந்த ஒன்பது சந்தேக நபர்களில் இரண்டு சந்தேகநபர்கள் வைத்தியசாலையில் சிகிச்சை பெற்று வருகின்ற நிலையில் அவர்கள் இருவருக்கும் நீதிமன்றத்தினால் பிணை வழங்கப்பட்டுள்ளது.",
        "சந்தேகநபர்கள் சார்பில் ஜனாதிபதி சட்டத்தரணிகளான சாலிய பீரிஸ், சரத் ஜயமான்ன, றின்சி அர்சகுலரத்ன மற்றும் உபுல் ஜயசூரிய ஆகியோர் தலைமையிலான முந்நூற்று ஐம்பதுக்கும் மேற்பட்ட சட்டத்தரணிகள் அடங்கிய குழு நீதிமன்றில் ஆஜராகி உண்மைகளை முன்வைத்தது.",
        "சட்டமா அதிபர் சார்பில் பிரதி சொலிசிட்டர் ஜெனரல் திரு.ஜனக பண்டார, கொழும்பு மத்திய பிரிவின் சிரேஷ்ட பொலிஸ் அத்தியட்சகர் ரொஷாந்த டயஸ், உதவி பொலிஸ் அத்தியட்சகர் வில்லகவராச்சி மற்றும் கோட்டை பொலிஸ் நிலைய கட்டளைத் தளபதி சாகர லியனகே ஆகியோர் நீதிமன்றில் முன்னிலையாகினர்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "350",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ஜயந்த டயஸ் நாணயக்கார",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "22",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஒன்பது",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Nuwan Bopage",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Galumuwadora",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "10,000",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "2",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "5",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "அடுத்த நாள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஒன்பது",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "இரண்டு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "முந்நூற்று ஐம்பது",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "சட்டத்தரணிகள் சாலிய பீரிஸ்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "சரத் ​​ஜயமான்ன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "உபுல் ஜயசூரிய",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஜனக பண்டார",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "கொழும்பு மத்திய பிரிவு சிரேஷ்ட பொலிஸ் அத்தியட்சகர்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரொஷாந்த டயஸ்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "கோட்டை காவல் நிலையம்",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "சாகர லியனகே",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}