{
  "newspaper_id": "ada-derana-lk",
  "url": "http://www.adaderana.lk/news/83792/new-cabinet-of-ministers-to-be-sworn-in-tomorrow",
  "time_ut": 1658405940,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "New Cabinet of Ministers to be sworn in tomorrow",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "New Cabinet of Ministers to be sworn in tomorrow",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "A new Cabinet of Ministers will be sworn in tomorrow (July 22) at the Prime Minister’s Office in Kollupitiya.",
        "According to the President’s Media Division (PMD), the swearing-in ceremony is scheduled to commence at 9.00 a.m.",
        "Newly-elected President Ranil Wickremesinghe, who was voted in by Sri Lanka’s parliament to the office of President vacated by his predecessor Gotabaya Rajapaksa, took oaths this morning at the parliament complex.",
        "Accordingly, a new Cabinet of Ministers will be formed under administration of President Wickremesinghe."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "tomorrow",
          "label": "DATE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "tomorrow",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "July 22",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kollupitiya",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Media Division",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "PMD",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "9.00 a.m.",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka’s",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Gotabaya Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "this morning",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "නව අමාත්‍ය මණ්ඩලය හෙට දිවුරුම් දීමට නියමිතයි",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "නව අමාත්‍ය මණ්ඩලයක් හෙට (ජුලි 22) කොල්ලුපිටිය අග්‍රාමාත්‍ය කාර්යාලයේදී දිවුරුම් දීමට නියමිතයි.",
        "ජනාධිපති මාධ්‍ය අංශය (PMD) පවසන පරිදි, දිවුරුම් දීමේ උත්සවය පෙරවරු 9.00 ට ආරම්භ වීමට නියමිතයි.",
        "සිය පූර්වගාමියා වූ ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ මහතා විසින් පුරප්පාඩු වූ ජනාධිපති කාර්යාලයට ශ්‍රී ලංකා පාර්ලිමේන්තුව විසින් ඡන්දය ප්‍රකාශ කරන ලද අභිනවයෙන් තේරී පත් වූ ජනාධිපති රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතා අද පෙරවරුවේ පාර්ලිමේන්තු සංකීර්ණයේදී දිවුරුම් දුන්නේය.",
        "ඒ අනුව ජනාධිපති වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතාගේ පාලනය යටතේ නව අමාත්‍ය මණ්ඩලයක් පිහිටුවනු ඇත."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "හෙට",
          "label": "DATE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "හෙට",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජූලි 22",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "කොල්ලුපිටිය",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "මාධ්ය අංශය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "පීඑම්ඩී",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "9.00 පෙ.ව.",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "මේ උදෑසන",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "புதிய அமைச்சரவை நாளை பதவியேற்கவுள்ளது",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "புதிய அமைச்சரவை நாளை (ஜூலை 22) கொள்ளுப்பிட்டியில் உள்ள பிரதமர் அலுவலகத்தில் பதவியேற்கவுள்ளது.",
        "ஜனாதிபதியின் ஊடகப் பிரிவு (PMD) படி, பதவியேற்பு விழா காலை 9.00 மணிக்கு ஆரம்பமாகும்.",
        "இலங்கையின் முன்னாள் ஜனாதிபதி கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ஷவினால் காலி செய்யப்பட்ட ஜனாதிபதி பதவிக்கு இலங்கை பாராளுமன்றத்தால் வாக்களிக்கப்பட்ட புதிய ஜனாதிபதி ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க இன்று காலை பாராளுமன்ற வளாகத்தில் பதவிப்பிரமாணம் செய்துகொண்டார்.",
        "இதன்படி, ஜனாதிபதி விக்கிரமசிங்கவின் நிர்வாகத்தின் கீழ் புதிய அமைச்சரவை உருவாக்கப்படும்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "நாளை",
          "label": "DATE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "நாளை",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜூலை 22",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "கொள்ளுப்பிட்டி",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஊடகப் பிரிவு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "பிஎம்டி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "காலை 9.00 மணி",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கையின்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று காலை",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}