{
  "newspaper_id": "ada-lk",
  "url": "https://www.ada.lk/breaking_news/ලංවිම-සේවකයන්-අඩකින්-අඩු-කළ-හැකියි/11-396655",
  "time_ut": 1661599532,
  "original_lang": "si",
  "original_title": "ලංවිම සේවකයන් අඩකින් අඩු කළ හැකියි",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "CEB employees can be reduced by half",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "Mr. Kanchana Wijesekera, the Minister of Electricity and Energy, says that the current 26,000 staff of the Ceylon Electricity Board can be reduced by half and the work done by the 4,200 employees of the Ceylon Petroleum Corporation as well as the warehouse terminal can be done by 500 employees.",
        "He says on his Twitter account that this can be done by increasing the efficiency of workers and that trade unions grow because of inefficient workers.",
        "He says that although the Ceylon Electricity Board, the Petroleum Corporation and the Petroleum Bulk Storage Terminal have efficient employees, the majority are inefficient.",
        "He says that all government enterprises should be restructured and these institutions have fallen down due to inefficiency, political decisions, political appointments, inefficient administration.",
        "He further says that it is necessary to give merit pay in the public sector as well."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "CEB",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "half",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Kanchana Wijesekera",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "26,000",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Ceylon Electricity Board",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "half",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "4,200",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Ceylon Petroleum Corporation",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "500",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Twitter",
            "label": "PRODUCT"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the Ceylon Electricity Board",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Petroleum Corporation",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Petroleum Bulk Storage Terminal",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [],
        []
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "ලංවිම සේවකයන් අඩකින් අඩු කළ හැකියි",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "ලංකා විදුලි බල මණ්ඩලයේ දැනට සිටින 26000ක් වන කාර්ය මණ්ඩලය අඩකින් අඩු කළ හැකි බවත් ලංකා ඛනිජ තෙල් සංස්ථාවේ මෙන්ම තොග ගබඩා පර්යන්තයේ සේවකයන් 4200යකගෙන් කරන කාර්යයන් සේවකයන් 500කින් සිදුකළ හැකි බවත් විදුලි බල හා බලශක්ති අමාත්‍ය කංචන විජේසේකර මහතා පවසයි.",
        "ඔහු සිය ට්විටර් ගිණුමෙන් පවසන්නේ සේවකයන්ගේ කාර්යක්ෂතාව වැඩි කිරීමෙන් මෙය සිදුකළ හැකි බවත් අකාර්යක්ෂම සේවකයන් හේතුවෙන් වෘත්තීය සමිති වර්ධනය වන බවත් ඔහු පවසයි.",
        "ලංකා විදුලි බල මණ්ඩලය, ඛනිජ තෙල් සංස්ථාව හා ඛනිජ තෙල් ‌තොග ගබඩා පර්යන්තයේ කාර්යක්ෂම සේවකයන් සිටියත් බහුතරයක් අකාර්යක්ෂම බවත් ඔහු පවසයි.",
        "සියලු රාජ්‍ය ව්‍යාපාර ප්‍රතිව්‍යුහ ගත කළ යුතු බවත් අකාර්යක්ෂමතාව, දේශපාලන තීරණ, දේශපාලන පත්කිරීම්, අකාර්යක්ෂම පරිපාලනය හේතුවෙන් මෙම ආයතන පහතට වැටී ඇති බවත් ඔහු පවසයි.",
        "රාජ්‍ය අංශය තුළද දක්ෂතාව අනුව වැටප් ලබා දීම අවශ්‍ය බව ඔහු වැඩිදුරටත් පවසයි."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ලංවිම",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "අඩක්",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "කාංචන විජේසේකර",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "26,000 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ලංකා විදුලිබල මණ්ඩලය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "අඩක්",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "4,200 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ලංකා ඛනිජ තෙල් නීතිගත සංස්ථාව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "500",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ට්විටර්",
            "label": "PRODUCT"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ලංකා විදුලිබල මණ්ඩලය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඛනිජ තෙල් සංස්ථාව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඛනිජ තෙල් තොග ගබඩා පර්යන්තය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [],
        []
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "CEB ஊழியர்களை பாதியாக குறைக்கலாம்",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "இலங்கை மின்சார சபையில் தற்போது உள்ள 26,000 ஊழியர்களை பாதியாக குறைக்க முடியும் என்றும், இலங்கை பெற்றோலிய கூட்டுத்தாபனத்தின் 4,200 பணியாளர்கள் மற்றும் களஞ்சிய முனையம் போன்றவற்றின் பணிகளையும் செய்ய முடியும் என மின்சாரம் மற்றும் எரிசக்தி அமைச்சர் திரு.காஞ்சன விஜேசேகர தெரிவித்துள்ளார். 500 ஊழியர்களால்.",
        "தொழிலாளர்களின் செயல்திறனை அதிகரிப்பதன் மூலம் இதைச் செய்ய முடியும் என்றும் திறமையற்ற தொழிலாளர்களால்தான் தொழிற்சங்கங்கள் வளர்கின்றன என்றும் அவர் தனது ட்விட்டர் கணக்கில் கூறுகிறார்.",
        "இலங்கை மின்சார சபை, பெற்றோலியக் கூட்டுத்தாபனம் மற்றும் பெற்றோலிய மொத்த சேமிப்பக முனையம் ஆகியவற்றில் திறமையான பணியாளர்கள் இருந்தாலும், பெரும்பான்மையானவர்கள் திறமையற்றவர்கள் என்று அவர் கூறுகிறார்.",
        "அனைத்து அரசாங்க நிறுவனங்களும் மறுசீரமைக்கப்பட வேண்டும் என்றும், திறமையின்மை, அரசியல் முடிவுகள், அரசியல் நியமனங்கள், திறமையற்ற நிர்வாகம் போன்ற காரணங்களால் இந்த நிறுவனங்கள் வீழ்ச்சியடைந்துள்ளன என்றும் அவர் கூறுகிறார்.",
        "மேலும் பொதுப்பணித்துறையிலும் தகுதி ஊதியம் வழங்குவது அவசியம் என்கிறார்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "CEB",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "பாதி",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "காஞ்சனா விஜேசேகர",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "26,000",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை மின்சார சபை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாதி",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "4,200",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை பெற்றோலியக் கூட்டுத்தாபனம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "500",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ட்விட்டர்",
            "label": "PRODUCT"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை மின்சார சபை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "பெட்ரோலிய கூட்டுத்தாபனம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "பெட்ரோலிய மொத்த சேமிப்பு முனையம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [],
        []
      ]
    }
  }
}