{
  "newspaper_id": "economy-next-com",
  "url": "https://economynext.com/us-to-redouble-efforts-to-support-crisis-hit-sri-lanka-ambassador-99167/",
  "time_ut": 1661832360,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "US to redouble efforts to support crisis-hit Sri Lanka: Ambassador",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "US to redouble efforts to support crisis-hit Sri Lanka: Ambassador",
      "author": "",
      "body_lines": [
        "ECONOMYNEXT – The United States will redouble its efforts to support Sri Lanka through bilateral trade, business collaboration, SME financing and other avenues, US Ambassador to Sri Lanka Julie Chung said.",
        "Chung tweeted Monday August 29 evening after a meeting of the US-Sri Lanka Business Council on ways businesses of the two countries can collaborate to ensure the cash-strapped country gets back on a path to prosperity. Sri Lanka is currently going through its worst economic crisis since Independence, with high inflation and shortages having hit the public hard.",
        "US-Sri Lanka bilateral trade already supports more than 180,000 workers supplying exports to the US and contribute billions to the island nation’s economy, said Chung.",
        "“The US will redouble efforts to support SL along this path through ongoing efforts like financing for SMEs, fertilizer & seeds for farmers, education exchange & training to strengthen public financial management, as well as support through IMF if agreement can be reached (sp),” she said.",
        "The US was recently central to a diplomatic standoff between India, China and Sri Lanka over a Chinese tracking vessel that the Indian media had dubbed a ‘spy ship’ which made a port call at the Chinese-built Hambantoa Port in the island’s deep south.",
        "Chinese tracking vessel Yuan Wang 5 docks at Sri Lanka’s Hambantota Port"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "US",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "Sri Lanka",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "The United States",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "SME",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "US",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "Julie Chung",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Chung",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Monday August 29 evening",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "US",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "two",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Independence",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "US",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "more than 180,000",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "US",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Chung",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "US",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "fertilizer &",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "education exchange & training",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "IMF",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "US",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "India",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "China",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Chinese",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Indian",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Chinese",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Hambantoa Port",
            "label": "FAC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Chinese",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Yuan Wang",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka’s",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Hambantota Port",
            "label": "FAC"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "අර්බුදකාරී ශ්‍රී ලංකාවට සහාය දැක්වීමේ උත්සාහයන් දෙගුණ කිරීමට එක්සත් ජනපදය: තානාපති",
      "author": "",
      "body_lines": [
        "ECONOMYNEXT – ද්විපාර්ශ්වික වෙළෙඳාම, ව්‍යාපාරික සහයෝගීතාව, කුඩා හා මධ්‍ය පරිමාණ ව්‍යාපාර මූල්‍යකරණය සහ වෙනත් මාර්ග හරහා ශ්‍රී ලංකාවට සහාය දැක්වීමට එක්සත් ජනපදය දරන උත්සාහය දෙගුණ කරන බව ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ එක්සත් ජනපද තානාපතිනී ජුලී චුන්ග් පැවසීය.",
        "මුදල් හිඟ රට යළි සෞභාග්‍යයේ මාවතකට ගෙන ඒම සහතික කිරීම සඳහා දෙරටේ ව්‍යාපාරවලට සහයෝගයෙන් ක්‍රියා කළ හැකි ක්‍රම පිළිබඳව එක්සත් ජනපද-ශ්‍රී ලංකා ව්‍යාපාරික කවුන්සිලයේ රැස්වීමකින් පසු අගෝස්තු 29 සඳුදා සවස චුන්ග් ට්වීට් කළේය. ශ්‍රී ලංකාව මේ වන විට නිදහසින් පසු එහි දරුණුතම ආර්ථික අර්බුදය හරහා ගමන් කරමින් සිටින අතර, ඉහළ උද්ධමනය සහ හිඟය මහජනතාවට දැඩි ලෙස බලපා ඇත.",
        "එක්සත් ජනපද-ශ්‍රී ලංකා ද්විපාර්ශ්වික වෙළඳාම දැනටමත් එක්සත් ජනපදයට අපනයන සපයන කම්කරුවන් 180,000 කට වැඩි පිරිසකට සහාය වන අතර දිවයිනේ ආර්ථිකයට බිලියන ගණනින් දායක වන බව චුන්ග් පැවසීය.",
        "“එක්සත් ජනපදය කුඩා හා මධ්‍ය පරිමාණ ව්‍යවසායකයින් සඳහා මූල්‍යකරණය, ගොවීන් සඳහා පොහොර සහ බීජ, අධ්‍යාපන හුවමාරුව සහ රාජ්‍ය මූල්‍ය කළමනාකරණය ශක්තිමත් කිරීම සඳහා පුහුණුව මෙන්ම එකඟතාවකට පැමිණිය හැකි නම් ජාත්‍යන්තර මූල්‍ය අරමුදල හරහා සහය වැනි අඛණ්ඩ ප්‍රයත්නයන් හරහා මෙම මාවත ඔස්සේ ශ්‍රී ලංකාවට සහාය දැක්වීමේ උත්සාහයන් දෙගුණ කරයි (sp) ,\" ඇය කිව්වා.",
        "ඉන්දියාව, චීනය සහ ශ්‍රී ලංකාව අතර රාජ්‍ය තාන්ත්‍රික ගැටුමකට මෑතකදී එක්සත් ජනපදය කේන්ද්‍රගත වූයේ චීන ලුහුබැඳීමේ යාත්‍රාවක් සම්බන්ධයෙන් ඉන්දීය මාධ්‍ය විසින් 'ඔත්තු නැවක්' ලෙස නම් කර ඇති අතර එය දිවයිනේ ගැඹුරු දකුණේ චීනය විසින් ඉදිකරන ලද හම්බන්තොට වරායට වරාය ඇමතුමක් ලබා දුන්නේය.",
        "චීන ලුහුබැඳීමේ යාත්‍රාව යුවාන් වැන්ග් 5 ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ හම්බන්තොට වරායට නැංගේ"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "එක්සත් ජනපදය",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "එක්සත් ජනපදය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "SME",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "එක්සත් ජනපදය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජූලි චුන්ග්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "චුන්ග්",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "අගෝස්තු 29 සඳුදා සවස",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "එක්සත් ජනපදය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "දෙක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "නිදහස",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "එක්සත් ජනපදය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "180,000 ට වැඩි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "එක්සත් ජනපදය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "චුන්ග්",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "එක්සත් ජනපදය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "පොහොර &",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "අධ්යාපන හුවමාරුව සහ පුහුණුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "IMF",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "එක්සත් ජනපදය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "චීනය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "චීන",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දීය",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "චීන",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "හම්බන්තොට වරාය",
            "label": "FAC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "චීන",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Yuan Wang",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "හම්බන්තොට වරාය",
            "label": "FAC"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "நெருக்கடியால் பாதிக்கப்பட்டுள்ள இலங்கைக்கு ஆதரவளிப்பதற்கான முயற்சிகளை இரட்டிப்பாக்க அமெரிக்கா: தூதுவர்",
      "author": "",
      "body_lines": [
        "பொருளாதாரம் - இருதரப்பு வர்த்தகம், வணிக ஒத்துழைப்பு, SME நிதியளிப்பு மற்றும் பிற வழிகள் மூலம் இலங்கைக்கு ஆதரவளிப்பதற்கான தனது முயற்சிகளை அமெரிக்கா இரட்டிப்பாக்கும் என்று இலங்கைக்கான அமெரிக்கத் தூதுவர் ஜூலி சுங் தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "அமெரிக்க-இலங்கை வர்த்தக கவுன்சிலின் கூட்டத்திற்குப் பிறகு ஆகஸ்ட் 29 திங்கட்கிழமை மாலை சுங் ட்வீட் செய்துள்ளார், பணப் பற்றாக்குறை உள்ள நாடு மீண்டும் செழிப்புக்கான பாதையில் செல்வதை உறுதிசெய்ய இரு நாடுகளின் வணிகங்கள் ஒத்துழைக்கக்கூடிய வழிகள் குறித்து. இலங்கை தற்போது சுதந்திரத்திற்குப் பின்னர் மிக மோசமான பொருளாதார நெருக்கடியை எதிர்கொண்டுள்ளது, அதிக பணவீக்கம் மற்றும் பற்றாக்குறை பொதுமக்களை கடுமையாக பாதித்துள்ளது.",
        "அமெரிக்க-இலங்கை இருதரப்பு வர்த்தகம் ஏற்கனவே 180,000 க்கும் மேற்பட்ட தொழிலாளர்களை அமெரிக்காவிற்கு ஏற்றுமதி செய்வதை ஆதரிக்கிறது மற்றும் தீவு நாட்டின் பொருளாதாரத்திற்கு பில்லியன்களை பங்களிக்கிறது என்று சுங் கூறினார்.",
        "\"எஸ்எம்இகளுக்கு நிதியுதவி, விவசாயிகளுக்கு உரம் மற்றும் விதைகள், கல்வி பரிமாற்றம் மற்றும் பொது நிதி நிர்வாகத்தை வலுப்படுத்த பயிற்சி, அத்துடன் உடன்பாடு எட்டப்பட்டால் IMF மூலம் ஆதரவு போன்ற தொடர்ச்சியான முயற்சிகள் மூலம் இந்த பாதையில் SL ஐ ஆதரிக்கும் முயற்சிகளை அமெரிக்கா இரட்டிப்பாக்கும் (sp) ,” என்றாள்.",
        "தீவின் ஆழமான தெற்கில் உள்ள சீனாவால் கட்டப்பட்ட ஹம்பாந்தோவா துறைமுகத்தில் துறைமுக அழைப்பை மேற்கொண்ட இந்திய ஊடகங்கள் 'உளவு கப்பல்' என்று அழைக்கப்பட்ட சீன கண்காணிப்பு கப்பல் தொடர்பாக இந்தியா, சீனா மற்றும் இலங்கை இடையேயான இராஜதந்திர மோதலுக்கு அமெரிக்கா சமீபத்தில் மையமாக இருந்தது.",
        "சீன கண்காணிப்பு கப்பல் யுவான் வாங் 5 இலங்கையின் அம்பாந்தோட்டை துறைமுகத்தில் நிறுத்தப்பட்டுள்ளது"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "எங்களுக்கு",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "இலங்கை",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ஐக்கிய நாடுகள்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "SME",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "எங்களுக்கு",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜூலி சுங்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "சுங்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆகஸ்ட் 29 திங்கட்கிழமை மாலை",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "எங்களுக்கு",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இரண்டு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சுதந்திரம்",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "எங்களுக்கு",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "180,000க்கு மேல்",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "எங்களுக்கு",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சுங்",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "எங்களுக்கு",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "உரம் &",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "கல்வி பரிமாற்றம் மற்றும் பயிற்சி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "IMF",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "எங்களுக்கு",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்தியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சீனா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சீன",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்தியன்",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "சீன",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஹம்பாந்தோ துறைமுகம்",
            "label": "FAC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "சீன",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Yuan Wang",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கையின்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "அம்பாந்தோட்டை துறைமுகம்",
            "label": "FAC"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}