{
  "newspaper_id": "lankadeepa-lk",
  "url": "https://www.lankadeepa.lk/latest_news/ස්ථිර-කැබිනට්ටුව-ලබන-සතියේ/1-618295",
  "time_ut": 1660741700,
  "original_lang": "si",
  "original_title": "ස්ථිර කැබිනට්ටුව ලබන සතියේ",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "The permanent cabinet next week",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "According to government sources, a new cabinet will be appointed next week to replace the currently appointed temporary cabinet.",
        "President Ranil Wickramasinghe has discussed with all political parties regarding the formation of an all-party government, but since no final agreement has been reached regarding the all-party government, it is known that the new cabinet is likely to be appointed under an all-party system.",
        "It is learned that during the appointment of this cabinet, the Sri Lanka Podujana Peramuna has also submitted a list of district leaders who should be given cabinet ministerships to the President.",
        "It is also known that the names of Dr. Ramesh Pathirana, Prasanna Ranatunga, Janaka Bandara Thennakoon, Johnston Fernando, Rohitha Abeygunawardena, CB Ratnayake, Pavitra Vanniarachchi, SM Chandrasena, Namal Rajapaksa, Dr. Bandula Gunawardena, Sanath Nishantha, Kanchana Wijesekara have been included in it. .",
        "It has been learned that several members of Samagi Balawega are to be included in the new cabinet, Jeevan Thondaman of Sri Lanka Labor Congress and ALM Athaullah, leader of National Congress, are also to be appointed ministers.",
        "It is learned that if it is not possible to form an all-party government, the government is also discussing the formation of a national government."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "next week",
          "label": "DATE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "next week",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickramasinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "Podujana Peramuna",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Ramesh Pathirana",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Prasanna Ranatunga",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Janaka Bandara Thennakoon",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Johnston Fernando",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Rohitha Abeygunawardena",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "CB Ratnayake",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Vanniarachchi",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "SM Chandrasena",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Namal Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Bandula Gunawardena",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sanath Nishantha",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kanchana Wijesekara",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Samagi Balawega",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Jeevan Thondaman of Sri Lanka",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ALM Athaullah",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "National Congress",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        []
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "ස්ථිර කැබිනට්ටුව ලබන සතියේ",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "දැනට පත් කර ඇති තාවකාලික කැබිනට් මණ්ඩලය වෙනුවට නව අමාත්‍ය මණ්ඩලයක් ලබන සතියේ දී පත් කිරීමට නියමිතව ඇතැයි රජයේ ආරංචි මාර්ග සඳහන් කරයි.",
        "සර්ව පාක්ෂික ආණ්ඩුවක් පිහිටුවීම සම්බන්ධයෙන් ජනාධිපති රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතා සියලු දේශපාලන පක්ෂ සමඟ සාකච්ඡා කර ඇති නමුත්,සර්ව පාක්ෂික ආණ්ඩුව සම්බන්ධයෙන් අවසන් එකඟතාවකට පැමිණ නැති බැවින්,සර්ව පාක්ෂික වැඩපිළිවෙළක් යටතේ නව කැබිනට් මණ්ඩලය පත් කිරීමට බොහෝ දුරට ඉඩ ඇතැයි දැනගන්නට ඇත.",
        "මෙම කැබිනට් මණ්ඩලය පත් කිරීමේදී ශ්‍රී ලංකා පොදුජන පෙරමුණෙන් කැබිනට් අමාත්‍යධුර හිමිවිය යුතු දිස්ත්‍රික් නායකයන්ගේ ලැයිස්තුවක්ද ජනාධිපතිවරයා වෙත ඉදිරිපත් කර ඇතැයි දැනගන්නට ඇත.",
        "වෛද්‍ය රමේෂ් පතිරණ, ප්‍රසන්න රණතුංග , ජනක බණ්ඩාර තෙන්නකෝන් ,,ජොන්ස්ටන් ප්‍රනාන්දු, රෝහිත අබේගුණවර්ධන, සී බී රත්නායක, පවිත්‍රා වන්නිආරච්චි, එස් එම් චන්ද්‍රසේන,නාමල් රාජපක්ෂ, ආචාර්ය බන්දුල ගුණවර්ධන,සනත් නිශාන්ත,කංචන විජේසේකර යන මහත්වරුන්ගේ නම් ඊට ඇතුළත් වී ඇතැයිද දැනගන්නට තිබේ.",
        "සමගි බලවේගයේ මන්ත්‍රීවරුන් කිහිපදෙනකු ද, නව කැබිනට් මණ්ඩල ට ඇතුළත්වීමට නියමිතව ඇති අතර,ලංකා කම්කරු කොංග්‍රසයේ ජීවන් තොන්ඩමන්,ජාතික කොංග්‍රසයේ නායක ඒ එල් එම් අතාවුල්ලා යන මහත්වරුන්ටද අමාත්‍යධුර හිමිවීමට නියමිතව ඇතැයි දැනගන්නට ඇත.",
        "සර්ව පාක්ෂික ආණ්ඩුවක් පිහිටුවීමට නොහැකි වුවහොත් ජාතික ආණ්ඩුවක් පිහිටුවීම සම්බන්ධයෙන් ද ආණ්ඩුව තුළ සාකච්ඡා වෙමින් පවතින බව දැනගන්නට ඇත."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ඊළඟ සතිය",
          "label": "DATE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ඊළඟ සතිය",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "පොදුජන පෙරමුණ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "රමේෂ් පතිරණ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ප්‍රසන්න රණතුංග",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජනක බණ්ඩාර තෙන්නකෝන්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජොන්ස්ටන් ප්‍රනාන්දු",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "රෝහිත අබේගුණවර්ධන",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "සී.බී රත්නායක",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "වන්නිආරච්චි",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "එස්.එම් චන්ද්‍රසේන",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "නාමල් රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "බන්දුල ගුණවර්ධන",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "සනත් නිශාන්ත",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "කාංචන විජේසේකර",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "සමගි බලවේගය",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජීවන් තොණ්ඩමන් ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඒඑල්එම් අතාවුල්ලා",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජාතික කොංග්රසය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        []
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "நிரந்தர அமைச்சரவை அடுத்த வாரம்",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "தற்போது நியமிக்கப்பட்டுள்ள தற்காலிக அமைச்சரவைக்கு பதிலாக அடுத்த வாரம் புதிய அமைச்சரவை நியமிக்கப்படவுள்ளதாக அரசாங்க தகவல்கள் தெரிவிக்கின்றன.",
        "சர்வகட்சி அரசாங்கம் அமைப்பது தொடர்பில் ஜனாதிபதி ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க அனைத்து அரசியல் கட்சிகளுடனும் கலந்துரையாடிய போதிலும், சர்வகட்சி அரசாங்கம் தொடர்பில் இறுதி இணக்கப்பாடு எட்டப்படாத நிலையில், அனைத்துக் கட்சிகளின் கீழ் புதிய அமைச்சரவை நியமிக்கப்பட வாய்ப்பு உள்ளதாக அறியமுடிகின்றது. கட்சி அமைப்பு.",
        "இந்த அமைச்சரவை நியமனத்தின் போது ஸ்ரீலங்கா பொதுஜன பெரமுனவும் அமைச்சரவை அமைச்சுப் பதவிகளை வழங்க வேண்டிய மாவட்ட தலைவர்களின் பட்டியலை ஜனாதிபதியிடம் சமர்ப்பித்துள்ளதாக தெரியவருகிறது.",
        "கலாநிதி ரமேஷ் பத்திரன, பிரசன்ன ரணதுங்க, ஜனக பண்டார தென்னகோன், ஜோன்ஸ்டன் பெர்னாண்டோ, ரோஹித அபேகுணவர்தன, சி.பி.ரத்நாயக்க, பவித்ரா வன்னியாராச்சி, எஸ்.எம்.சந்திரசேன, நாமல் ராஜபக்ஷ, கலாநிதி பந்துல குணவர்தன, சனத் நிஷாந்த, காஞ்சனா விஜேசேகர ஆகியோரின் பெயர்கள் இடம்பெற்றுள்ளதாகவும் அறியமுடிகிறது. அதில் சேர்க்கப்பட்டுள்ளது..",
        "புதிய அமைச்சரவையில் சமகி பலவேக உறுப்பினர்கள் பலர் உள்வாங்கப்பட உள்ளதாகவும், இலங்கை தொழிலாளர் காங்கிரஸின் ஜீவன் தொண்டமான் மற்றும் தேசிய காங்கிரஸின் தலைவர் ஏ.எல்.எம்.அதாவுல்லா ஆகியோரும் அமைச்சர்களாக நியமிக்கப்பட உள்ளதாகவும் தெரியவருகிறது.",
        "சர்வகட்சி அரசாங்கமொன்றை அமைக்க முடியாத பட்சத்தில் தேசிய அரசாங்கத்தை அமைப்பது தொடர்பிலும் அரசாங்கம் ஆலோசித்து வருவதாக தெரியவருகிறது."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "அடுத்த வாரம்",
          "label": "DATE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "அடுத்த வாரம்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "பொதுஜன பெரமுன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ரமேஷ் பத்திரன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "பிரசன்ன ரணதுங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜனக பண்டார தென்னகோன்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜோன்ஸ்டன் பெர்னாண்டோ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரோஹித அபேகுணவர்தன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "சிபி ரத்நாயக்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "வன்னியாராச்சி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "எஸ்.எம்.சந்திரசேன",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "நாமல் ராஜபக்ச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "பந்துல குணவர்தன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "சனத் நிஷாந்த",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "காஞ்சனா விஜேசேகர",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "சமகி பலவேகா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கையின் ஜீவன் தொண்டமான்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஏ.எல்.எம்.அதாஉல்லா",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "தேசிய காங்கிரஸ்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        []
      ]
    }
  }
}