{
  "newspaper_id": "virakesari-lk",
  "url": "http://www.virakesari.lk/article/131591",
  "time_ut": 1657956214,
  "original_lang": "ta",
  "original_title": "புதிய இடைக்கால ஜனாதிபதி பதவிக்கு அநுரகுமாரவும் போட்டி",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Anura Kumara is also in the running for the new interim president post",
      "author": "",
      "body_lines": [
        "People's Liberation Front's leader Anura Kumara Dissanayake will also contest as a candidate for the new interim presidential post, said MP Vijitha Herath of the People's Liberation Front.",
        "Parliamentary Secretary General Thammika Dasanayake announced today that there is a vacancy for the post of President after the resignation of Gotabaya Rajapaksa.",
        "In this case, it is noted that it has already been announced that President Ranil Wickremesinghe, United People's Shakti President Sajith Premadasa and Podujana Peramuna's Dulles Alagapperuma will contest for the new interim presidency."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Anura Kumara",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "People's Liberation Front's",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Anura Kumara Dissanayake",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the People's Liberation Front",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Gotabaya Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "United People's Shakti",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sajith Premadasa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Podujana Peramuna's",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Dulles Alagapperuma",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "අනුර කුමාර ද නව අන්තර්වාර සභාපති ධුරය සඳහා තරග වදියි",
      "author": "",
      "body_lines": [
        "නව අතුරු ජනාධිපති ධුරය සඳහා අපේක්ෂකයෙකු ලෙස ජනතා විමුක්ති පෙරමුණේ නායක අනුර කුමාර දිසානායක ද තරඟ කරන බව ජනතා විමුක්ති පෙරමුණේ පාර්ලිමේන්තු මන්ත්‍රී විජිත හේරත් මහතා පවසයි.",
        "ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ මහතා ඉල්ලා අස්වීමෙන් පසු ජනාධිපති ධූරයේ පුරප්පාඩුව පවතින බව පාර්ලිමේන්තු මහලේකම් තම්මික දසනායක මහතා අද නිවේදනය කළේය.",
        "මෙම නඩුවේදී නව අන්තර්වාර ජනාධිපතිධුරය සඳහා ජනාධිපති රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ, එක්සත් ජනතා ශක්ති සභාපති සජිත් ප්‍රේමදාස සහ පොදුජන පෙරමුණේ ඩලස් අලගප්පෙරුම තරග කරන බව දැනටමත් ප්‍රකාශ කර ඇති බව සඳහන්."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "අනුර කුමාර",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ජනතා විමුක්ති පෙරමුණේ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "අනුර කුමාර දිසානායක",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "මහජන විමුක්ති පෙරමුණ",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "එක්සත් ජනතා ශක්ති",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "සජිත් ප්‍රේමදාස",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "පොදුජන පෙරමුණේ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඩලස් අලගප්පෙරුම",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "புதிய இடைக்கால ஜனாதிபதி பதவிக்கு அநுரகுமாரவும் போட்டி",
      "author": "",
      "body_lines": [
        "புதிய இடைக்கால ஜனாதிபதி பதவிக்கான வேட்பாளராக மக்கள் விடுதலை முன்னணியின் தலைவர் அநுரகுமார திஸாநாயக்கவும் போட்டியிடுவார் என மக்கள் விடுதலை முன்னணியின் பாராளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர் விஜித ஹேரத் தெரிவித்துள்ளார்.",
        "கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ஷ ஜனாதிபதி பதவியில் இருந்து விலகியதையடுத்து ஜனாதிபதி பதவிக்கு வெற்றிடம் நிலவுவதாக இன்றையதினம் பாராளுமன்ற செயலாளர் நாயகம் தம்மிக்க தசநாயக்க அறிவித்தார்.",
        "இந்நிலையில், புதிய இடைக்கால ஜனாதிபதி பதவிக்கு பதில் ஜனாதிபதி ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க,  ஐக்கிய மக்கள் சக்தியின் தலைவர் சஜித் பிரேமதாச மற்றும் பொதுஜன பெரமுன சார்பில் டலஸ் அழகப்பெரும ஆகியோரும் போட்டியிடவுள்ளதாக ஏற்கனவே அறிவிக்கப்பட்டுள்ளமை குறிப்பிடத்தக்கது."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "அனுர குமார",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "மக்கள் விடுதலை முன்னணியின்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "அனுரகுமார திஸாநாயக்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "மக்கள் விடுதலை முன்னணி",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஐக்கிய மக்கள் சக்தி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "சஜித் பிரேமதாச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "பொதுஜன பெரமுனவின்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "டல்லஸ் அழகப்பெரும",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}