{
  "newspaper_id": "ada-derana-lk",
  "url": "http://www.adaderana.lk/news/83234/sri-lanka-receives-lkr-3-bn-worth-humanitarian-supplies-from-india",
  "time_ut": 1656059520,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Sri Lanka receives LKR 3 Bn worth humanitarian supplies from India",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Sri Lanka receives LKR 3 Bn worth humanitarian supplies from India",
      "body_lines": [
        "India today (June 24) delivered a humanitarian consignment of 15,000 metric tons of essential items including rice, milk powder and pharmaceuticals to Sri Lanka.",
        "Indian High Commissioner to Sri Lanka Gopal Baglay, Minister of Health Keheliya Rambukwella, Minister of Trade Nalin Fernando, MPs M.A Sumanthiran, V. Radhakrishnan, M. Udaya Kumar, Angajan Ramanathan, and several others including Senthil Thondaman welcomed the donation.",
        "It consists of 14,700 metric tons of rice, 250 metric tons of milk powder and 38 metric tons of medicines donated by the people of India.",
        "The total value of this consignment is more than LKR 3 billion, the Indian High Commission in Colombo said in a statement.",
        "The consignment of humanitarian supplies underscores abiding people-to-people bonds between India and Sri Lanka as also concerns of the people of India for the well-being of their brethren in Sri Lanka, the statement read further.",
        "These supplies are planned to be distributed among beneficiaries by the Sri Lankan government in the coming days.",
        "This is the second consignment provided under a larger commitment of 40,000 metric tons of rice, 500 metric tons of milk powder and medicines by the government of Tamil Nadu.",
        "India’s unprecedented economic, financial and humanitarian assistance to the people of Sri Lanka stands at over USD 3.5 billion in 2022.",
        "In addition to the three credit lines to the tune of more than USD 1.5 billion and forex support of around USD 2 billion, assistance from the government and people of India has taken the form of supply of medicines to several health-related establishments in various parts of Sri Lanka, distribution of kerosene among the fishermen of Sri Lanka, handing over of dry rations to needy sections etc."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Sri Lanka",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "3",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "India",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "India",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "June 24",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "15,000 metric tons",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Indian",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka Gopal Baglay",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Health Keheliya Rambukwella",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "V. Radhakrishnan",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "M. Udaya Kumar",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Angajan Ramanathan",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Senthil Thondaman",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "14,700 metric tons",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "250 metric tons",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "38 metric tons",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "India",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the Indian High Commission",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "India",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "India",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lankan",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the coming days",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "second",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "40,000 metric tons",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "500 metric tons",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "Tamil Nadu",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "India",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "USD 3.5 billion",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "2022",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "three",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "India",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවට රුපියල් බිලියන 3ක් වටිනා මානුෂීය සැපයුම් ඉන්දියාවෙන් ලැබේ",
      "body_lines": [
        "ඉන්දියාව අද (ජුනි 24) සහල්, කිරිපිටි සහ ඖෂධ ඇතුළු අත්‍යාවශ්‍ය ද්‍රව්‍ය මෙට්‍රික් ටොන් 15,000ක මානුෂීය තොගයක් ශ්‍රී ලංකාවට භාර දුන්නේය.",
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ ඉන්දීය මහ කොමසාරිස් ගෝපාල් බග්ලේ, සෞඛ්‍ය අමාත්‍ය කෙහෙළිය රඹුක්වැල්ල, වෙළඳ අමාත්‍ය නලින් ප්‍රනාන්දු, පාර්ලිමේන්තු මන්ත්‍රීවරුන් වන එම්.ඒ.සුමන්තිරන්, වී.රාධක්‍රිෂ්ණන්, එම්.උදය කුමාර්, අංගජන් රාමනාදන්, සෙන්තිල් තොණ්ඩමන් ඇතුළු පිරිසක් මෙම පරිත්‍යාගය පිළිගනු ලැබුවා.",
        "එය ඉන්දියාවේ ජනතාව විසින් පරිත්‍යාග කරන ලද සහල් මෙට්‍රික් ටොන් 14,700 කින්, කිරිපිටි මෙට්‍රික් ටොන් 250 කින් සහ ඖෂධ මෙට්‍රික් ටොන් 38 කින් සමන්විත වේ.",
        "මෙම තොගයේ මුළු වටිනාකම රුපියල් බිලියන 3කට අධික බව කොළඹ ඉන්දීය මහ කොමසාරිස් කාර්යාලය නිවේදනයක් නිකුත් කරමින් කියා සිටී.",
        "මානුෂීය සැපයුම් තොගය ඉන්දියාව සහ ශ්‍රී ලංකාව අතර පවතින මිනිසුන් අතර පවතින බැඳීම් මෙන්ම ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ සිටින තම සහෝදරයන්ගේ යහපැවැත්ම සඳහා ඉන්දියාවේ ජනතාවගේ සැලකිල්ල ද අවධාරණය කරයි.",
        "මෙම සැපයුම් ඉදිරි දිනවලදී ශ්‍රී ලංකා රජය විසින් ප්‍රතිලාභීන් අතර බෙදා හැරීමට සැලසුම් කර ඇත.",
        "තමිල්නාඩු රජය විසින් සහල් මෙට්‍රික් ටොන් 40,000ක්, කිරිපිටි මෙට්‍රික් ටොන් 500ක් සහ ඖෂධ වැනි විශාල කැපවීමක් යටතේ ලබාදුන් දෙවන තොගය මෙයයි.",
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ ජනතාවට ඉන්දියාවේ පෙර නොවූ විරූ ආර්ථික, මූල්‍ය සහ මානුෂීය ආධාර 2022 දී ඩොලර් බිලියන 3.5 ඉක්මවයි.",
        "ඩොලර් බිලියන 1.5 කට වැඩි ණය මාර්ග තුනකට අමතරව ඩොලර් බිලියන 2 ක පමණ විදේශ විනිමය ආධාරකයකට අමතරව, ඉන්දියාවේ රජය සහ ජනතාව වෙතින් විවිධ කොටස්වල සෞඛ්‍ය සම්බන්ධ ආයතන කිහිපයකට ඖෂධ සැපයීමේ ස්වරූපය ගෙන ඇත. ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ, ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ ධීවරයින් අතර භූමිතෙල් බෙදා හැරීම, අවශ්‍යතා ඇති කොටස් වෙත වියළි සලාක ලබා දීම යනාදිය."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "3",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "ඉන්දියාව",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජූනි 24",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මෙට්‍රික් ටොන් 15,000 කි",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දීය",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකා ගෝපාල් බග්ලේ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "සෞඛ්‍ය කෙහෙළිය රඹුක්වැල්ල",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "වී රාධක්‍රිෂ්ණන්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "එම් උදය කුමාර",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "අංගජන් රාමනාදන්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "සෙන්තිල් තොණ්ඩමන්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "මෙට්‍රික් ටොන් 14,700 කි",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "මෙට්‍රික් ටොන් 250 කි",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "මෙට්රික් ටොන් 38 කි",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දීය මහ කොමසාරිස් කාර්යාලය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලාංකික",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉදිරි දින",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "දෙවැනි",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "මෙට්‍රික් ටොන් 40,000 කි",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "මෙට්රික් ටොන් 500 කි",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "තමිල්නාඩුව",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඩොලර් බිලියන 3.5 කි",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "2022",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "තුන්",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "இலங்கை இந்தியாவிடமிருந்து 3 பில்லியன் ரூபாய் மதிப்பிலான மனிதாபிமான பொருட்களைப் பெறுகிறது",
      "body_lines": [
        "இந்தியா இன்று (ஜூன் 24) மனிதாபிமான அடிப்படையில் 15,000 மெட்ரிக் தொன் அரிசி, பால் பவுடர் மற்றும் மருந்துப் பொருட்கள் உள்ளிட்ட அத்தியாவசியப் பொருட்களை இலங்கைக்கு வழங்கியது.",
        "இலங்கைக்கான இந்திய உயர்ஸ்தானிகர் கோபால் பாக்லே, சுகாதார அமைச்சர் கெஹலிய ரம்புக்வெல்ல, வர்த்தக அமைச்சர் நளின் பெர்னாண்டோ, பாராளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர்களான எம்.ஏ.சுமந்திரன், வி.ராதாகிருஷ்ணன், எம்.உதய குமார், அங்கஜன் இராமநாதன், செந்தில் தொண்டமான் உட்பட பலர் நன்கொடையை வரவேற்றனர்.",
        "இதில் இந்திய மக்களால் வழங்கப்பட்ட 14,700 மெட்ரிக் டன் அரிசி, 250 மெட்ரிக் டன் பால் பவுடர் மற்றும் 38 மெட்ரிக் டன் மருந்துகள் உள்ளன.",
        "இந்தச் சரக்குகளின் மொத்தப் பெறுமதி 3 பில்லியன் ரூபாவுக்கும் அதிகமாகும் என கொழும்பில் உள்ள இந்திய உயர்ஸ்தானிகராலயம் தனது அறிக்கையில் தெரிவித்துள்ளது.",
        "இந்த மனிதாபிமானப் பொருட்கள் இந்தியாவிற்கும் இலங்கைக்கும் இடையிலான நிலையான மக்களுக்கும் மக்களுக்கும் இடையிலான பிணைப்புகளை அடிக்கோடிட்டுக் காட்டுவதுடன், இலங்கையில் உள்ள தமது சகோதரர்களின் நல்வாழ்வுக்கான இந்திய மக்களின் அக்கறைகளையும் சுட்டிக்காட்டுகிறது.",
        "இந்த பொருட்கள் எதிர்வரும் நாட்களில் இலங்கை அரசாங்கத்தினால் பயனாளிகளுக்கு விநியோகிக்க திட்டமிடப்பட்டுள்ளது.",
        "தமிழக அரசால் 40,000 மெட்ரிக் டன் அரிசி, 500 மெட்ரிக் டன் பால் பவுடர் மற்றும் மருந்துகள் என்ற பெரிய உறுதிப்பாட்டின் கீழ் வழங்கப்படும் இரண்டாவது சரக்கு இது.",
        "இலங்கை மக்களுக்கு இந்தியாவின் முன்னோடியில்லாத பொருளாதார, நிதி மற்றும் மனிதாபிமான உதவிகள் 2022 இல் 3.5 பில்லியன் அமெரிக்க டாலர்களாக உள்ளது.",
        "1.5 பில்லியனுக்கும் அதிகமான அமெரிக்க டாலர்கள் மற்றும் சுமார் 2 பில்லியன் டாலர்கள் அந்நியச் செலாவணி ஆதரவு மூன்று கடன் வரிகளுக்கு கூடுதலாக, அரசாங்கம் மற்றும் இந்திய மக்களின் உதவி பல்வேறு பகுதிகளில் உள்ள பல உடல்நலம் தொடர்பான நிறுவனங்களுக்கு மருந்துகளை வழங்குவதற்கான வடிவத்தை எடுத்துள்ளது. இலங்கையின், இலங்கை மீனவர்களுக்கு மண்ணெண்ணெய் விநியோகம், உலர் உணவுகளை தேவைப்படும் பிரிவினருக்கு வழங்குதல் போன்றவை."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "இலங்கை",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "3",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "இந்தியா",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "இந்தியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜூன் 24",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "15,000 மெட்ரிக் டன்",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இந்தியன்",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை கோபால் பாக்லே",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "சுகாதார கெஹலிய ரம்புக்வெல்ல",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "வி.ராதாகிருஷ்ணன்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "எம்.உதய குமார்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "அங்கஜன் இராமநாதன்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "செந்தில் தொண்டமான்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "14,700 மெட்ரிக் டன்",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "250 மெட்ரிக் டன்",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "38 மெட்ரிக் டன்",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்தியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இந்திய உயர் ஸ்தானிகராலயம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இந்தியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்தியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "வரும் நாட்கள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இரண்டாவது",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "40,000 மெட்ரிக் டன்",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "500 மெட்ரிக் டன்",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "தமிழ்நாடு",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இந்தியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "USD 3.5 பில்லியன்",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "2022",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "மூன்று",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்தியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  },
  "title": "Sri Lanka receives LKR 3 Bn worth humanitarian supplies from India",
  "body_lines": [
    "India today (June 24) delivered a humanitarian consignment of 15,000 metric tons of essential items including rice, milk powder and pharmaceuticals to Sri Lanka.",
    "Indian High Commissioner to Sri Lanka Gopal Baglay, Minister of Health Keheliya Rambukwella, Minister of Trade Nalin Fernando, MPs M.A Sumanthiran, V. Radhakrishnan, M. Udaya Kumar, Angajan Ramanathan, and several others including Senthil Thondaman welcomed the donation.",
    "It consists of 14,700 metric tons of rice, 250 metric tons of milk powder and 38 metric tons of medicines donated by the people of India.",
    "The total value of this consignment is more than LKR 3 billion, the Indian High Commission in Colombo said in a statement.",
    "The consignment of humanitarian supplies underscores abiding people-to-people bonds between India and Sri Lanka as also concerns of the people of India for the well-being of their brethren in Sri Lanka, the statement read further.",
    "These supplies are planned to be distributed among beneficiaries by the Sri Lankan government in the coming days.",
    "This is the second consignment provided under a larger commitment of 40,000 metric tons of rice, 500 metric tons of milk powder and medicines by the government of Tamil Nadu.",
    "India’s unprecedented economic, financial and humanitarian assistance to the people of Sri Lanka stands at over USD 3.5 billion in 2022.",
    "In addition to the three credit lines to the tune of more than USD 1.5 billion and forex support of around USD 2 billion, assistance from the government and people of India has taken the form of supply of medicines to several health-related establishments in various parts of Sri Lanka, distribution of kerosene among the fishermen of Sri Lanka, handing over of dry rations to needy sections etc."
  ],
  "translate": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Sri Lanka receives LKR 3 Bn worth humanitarian supplies from India",
      "body_lines": [
        "India today (June 24) delivered a humanitarian consignment of 15,000 metric tons of essential items including rice, milk powder and pharmaceuticals to Sri Lanka.",
        "Indian High Commissioner to Sri Lanka Gopal Baglay, Minister of Health Keheliya Rambukwella, Minister of Trade Nalin Fernando, MPs M.A Sumanthiran, V. Radhakrishnan, M. Udaya Kumar, Angajan Ramanathan, and several others including Senthil Thondaman welcomed the donation.",
        "It consists of 14,700 metric tons of rice, 250 metric tons of milk powder and 38 metric tons of medicines donated by the people of India.",
        "The total value of this consignment is more than LKR 3 billion, the Indian High Commission in Colombo said in a statement.",
        "The consignment of humanitarian supplies underscores abiding people-to-people bonds between India and Sri Lanka as also concerns of the people of India for the well-being of their brethren in Sri Lanka, the statement read further.",
        "These supplies are planned to be distributed among beneficiaries by the Sri Lankan government in the coming days.",
        "This is the second consignment provided under a larger commitment of 40,000 metric tons of rice, 500 metric tons of milk powder and medicines by the government of Tamil Nadu.",
        "India’s unprecedented economic, financial and humanitarian assistance to the people of Sri Lanka stands at over USD 3.5 billion in 2022.",
        "In addition to the three credit lines to the tune of more than USD 1.5 billion and forex support of around USD 2 billion, assistance from the government and people of India has taken the form of supply of medicines to several health-related establishments in various parts of Sri Lanka, distribution of kerosene among the fishermen of Sri Lanka, handing over of dry rations to needy sections etc."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Sri Lanka",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "3",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "India",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "India",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "June 24",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "15,000 metric tons",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Indian",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka Gopal Baglay",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Health Keheliya Rambukwella",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "V. Radhakrishnan",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "M. Udaya Kumar",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Angajan Ramanathan",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Senthil Thondaman",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "14,700 metric tons",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "250 metric tons",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "38 metric tons",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "India",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the Indian High Commission",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "India",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "India",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lankan",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the coming days",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "second",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "40,000 metric tons",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "500 metric tons",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "Tamil Nadu",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "India",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "USD 3.5 billion",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "2022",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "three",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "India",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවට රුපියල් බිලියන 3ක් වටිනා මානුෂීය සැපයුම් ඉන්දියාවෙන් ලැබේ",
      "body_lines": [
        "ඉන්දියාව අද (ජුනි 24) සහල්, කිරිපිටි සහ ඖෂධ ඇතුළු අත්‍යාවශ්‍ය ද්‍රව්‍ය මෙට්‍රික් ටොන් 15,000ක මානුෂීය තොගයක් ශ්‍රී ලංකාවට භාර දුන්නේය.",
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ ඉන්දීය මහ කොමසාරිස් ගෝපාල් බග්ලේ, සෞඛ්‍ය අමාත්‍ය කෙහෙළිය රඹුක්වැල්ල, වෙළඳ අමාත්‍ය නලින් ප්‍රනාන්දු, පාර්ලිමේන්තු මන්ත්‍රීවරුන් වන එම්.ඒ.සුමන්තිරන්, වී.රාධක්‍රිෂ්ණන්, එම්.උදය කුමාර්, අංගජන් රාමනාදන්, සෙන්තිල් තොණ්ඩමන් ඇතුළු පිරිසක් මෙම පරිත්‍යාගය පිළිගනු ලැබුවා.",
        "එය ඉන්දියාවේ ජනතාව විසින් පරිත්‍යාග කරන ලද සහල් මෙට්‍රික් ටොන් 14,700 කින්, කිරිපිටි මෙට්‍රික් ටොන් 250 කින් සහ ඖෂධ මෙට්‍රික් ටොන් 38 කින් සමන්විත වේ.",
        "මෙම තොගයේ මුළු වටිනාකම රුපියල් බිලියන 3කට අධික බව කොළඹ ඉන්දීය මහ කොමසාරිස් කාර්යාලය නිවේදනයක් නිකුත් කරමින් කියා සිටී.",
        "මානුෂීය සැපයුම් තොගය ඉන්දියාව සහ ශ්‍රී ලංකාව අතර පවතින මිනිසුන් අතර පවතින බැඳීම් මෙන්ම ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ සිටින තම සහෝදරයන්ගේ යහපැවැත්ම සඳහා ඉන්දියාවේ ජනතාවගේ සැලකිල්ල ද අවධාරණය කරයි.",
        "මෙම සැපයුම් ඉදිරි දිනවලදී ශ්‍රී ලංකා රජය විසින් ප්‍රතිලාභීන් අතර බෙදා හැරීමට සැලසුම් කර ඇත.",
        "තමිල්නාඩු රජය විසින් සහල් මෙට්‍රික් ටොන් 40,000ක්, කිරිපිටි මෙට්‍රික් ටොන් 500ක් සහ ඖෂධ වැනි විශාල කැපවීමක් යටතේ ලබාදුන් දෙවන තොගය මෙයයි.",
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ ජනතාවට ඉන්දියාවේ පෙර නොවූ විරූ ආර්ථික, මූල්‍ය සහ මානුෂීය ආධාර 2022 දී ඩොලර් බිලියන 3.5 ඉක්මවයි.",
        "ඩොලර් බිලියන 1.5 කට වැඩි ණය මාර්ග තුනකට අමතරව ඩොලර් බිලියන 2 ක පමණ විදේශ විනිමය ආධාරකයකට අමතරව, ඉන්දියාවේ රජය සහ ජනතාව වෙතින් විවිධ කොටස්වල සෞඛ්‍ය සම්බන්ධ ආයතන කිහිපයකට ඖෂධ සැපයීමේ ස්වරූපය ගෙන ඇත. ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ, ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ ධීවරයින් අතර භූමිතෙල් බෙදා හැරීම, අවශ්‍යතා ඇති කොටස් වෙත වියළි සලාක ලබා දීම යනාදිය."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "3",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "ඉන්දියාව",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජූනි 24",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මෙට්‍රික් ටොන් 15,000 කි",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දීය",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකා ගෝපාල් බග්ලේ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "සෞඛ්‍ය කෙහෙළිය රඹුක්වැල්ල",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "වී රාධක්‍රිෂ්ණන්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "එම් උදය කුමාර",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "අංගජන් රාමනාදන්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "සෙන්තිල් තොණ්ඩමන්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "මෙට්‍රික් ටොන් 14,700 කි",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "මෙට්‍රික් ටොන් 250 කි",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "මෙට්රික් ටොන් 38 කි",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දීය මහ කොමසාරිස් කාර්යාලය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලාංකික",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉදිරි දින",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "දෙවැනි",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "මෙට්‍රික් ටොන් 40,000 කි",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "මෙට්රික් ටොන් 500 කි",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "තමිල්නාඩුව",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඩොලර් බිලියන 3.5 කි",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "2022",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "තුන්",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "இலங்கை இந்தியாவிடமிருந்து 3 பில்லியன் ரூபாய் மதிப்பிலான மனிதாபிமான பொருட்களைப் பெறுகிறது",
      "body_lines": [
        "இந்தியா இன்று (ஜூன் 24) மனிதாபிமான அடிப்படையில் 15,000 மெட்ரிக் தொன் அரிசி, பால் பவுடர் மற்றும் மருந்துப் பொருட்கள் உள்ளிட்ட அத்தியாவசியப் பொருட்களை இலங்கைக்கு வழங்கியது.",
        "இலங்கைக்கான இந்திய உயர்ஸ்தானிகர் கோபால் பாக்லே, சுகாதார அமைச்சர் கெஹலிய ரம்புக்வெல்ல, வர்த்தக அமைச்சர் நளின் பெர்னாண்டோ, பாராளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர்களான எம்.ஏ.சுமந்திரன், வி.ராதாகிருஷ்ணன், எம்.உதய குமார், அங்கஜன் இராமநாதன், செந்தில் தொண்டமான் உட்பட பலர் நன்கொடையை வரவேற்றனர்.",
        "இதில் இந்திய மக்களால் வழங்கப்பட்ட 14,700 மெட்ரிக் டன் அரிசி, 250 மெட்ரிக் டன் பால் பவுடர் மற்றும் 38 மெட்ரிக் டன் மருந்துகள் உள்ளன.",
        "இந்தச் சரக்குகளின் மொத்தப் பெறுமதி 3 பில்லியன் ரூபாவுக்கும் அதிகமாகும் என கொழும்பில் உள்ள இந்திய உயர்ஸ்தானிகராலயம் தனது அறிக்கையில் தெரிவித்துள்ளது.",
        "இந்த மனிதாபிமானப் பொருட்கள் இந்தியாவிற்கும் இலங்கைக்கும் இடையிலான நிலையான மக்களுக்கும் மக்களுக்கும் இடையிலான பிணைப்புகளை அடிக்கோடிட்டுக் காட்டுவதுடன், இலங்கையில் உள்ள தமது சகோதரர்களின் நல்வாழ்வுக்கான இந்திய மக்களின் அக்கறைகளையும் சுட்டிக்காட்டுகிறது.",
        "இந்த பொருட்கள் எதிர்வரும் நாட்களில் இலங்கை அரசாங்கத்தினால் பயனாளிகளுக்கு விநியோகிக்க திட்டமிடப்பட்டுள்ளது.",
        "தமிழக அரசால் 40,000 மெட்ரிக் டன் அரிசி, 500 மெட்ரிக் டன் பால் பவுடர் மற்றும் மருந்துகள் என்ற பெரிய உறுதிப்பாட்டின் கீழ் வழங்கப்படும் இரண்டாவது சரக்கு இது.",
        "இலங்கை மக்களுக்கு இந்தியாவின் முன்னோடியில்லாத பொருளாதார, நிதி மற்றும் மனிதாபிமான உதவிகள் 2022 இல் 3.5 பில்லியன் அமெரிக்க டாலர்களாக உள்ளது.",
        "1.5 பில்லியனுக்கும் அதிகமான அமெரிக்க டாலர்கள் மற்றும் சுமார் 2 பில்லியன் டாலர்கள் அந்நியச் செலாவணி ஆதரவு மூன்று கடன் வரிகளுக்கு கூடுதலாக, அரசாங்கம் மற்றும் இந்திய மக்களின் உதவி பல்வேறு பகுதிகளில் உள்ள பல உடல்நலம் தொடர்பான நிறுவனங்களுக்கு மருந்துகளை வழங்குவதற்கான வடிவத்தை எடுத்துள்ளது. இலங்கையின், இலங்கை மீனவர்களுக்கு மண்ணெண்ணெய் விநியோகம், உலர் உணவுகளை தேவைப்படும் பிரிவினருக்கு வழங்குதல் போன்றவை."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "இலங்கை",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "3",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "இந்தியா",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "இந்தியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜூன் 24",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "15,000 மெட்ரிக் டன்",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இந்தியன்",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை கோபால் பாக்லே",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "சுகாதார கெஹலிய ரம்புக்வெல்ல",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "வி.ராதாகிருஷ்ணன்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "எம்.உதய குமார்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "அங்கஜன் இராமநாதன்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "செந்தில் தொண்டமான்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "14,700 மெட்ரிக் டன்",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "250 மெட்ரிக் டன்",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "38 மெட்ரிக் டன்",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்தியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இந்திய உயர் ஸ்தானிகராலயம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இந்தியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்தியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "வரும் நாட்கள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இரண்டாவது",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "40,000 மெட்ரிக் டன்",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "500 மெட்ரிக் டன்",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "தமிழ்நாடு",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இந்தியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "USD 3.5 பில்லியன்",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "2022",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "மூன்று",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்தியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}