{
  "newspaper_id": "ada-derana-lk",
  "url": "http://www.adaderana.lk/news/83692/ex-president-gotabaya-says-he-took-all-possible-steps-to-prevent-crisis",
  "time_ut": 1657992900,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Ex-President Gotabaya says he ‘took all possible steps’ to prevent crisis",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Ex-President Gotabaya says he ‘took all possible steps’ to prevent crisis",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "Sri Lanka’s ousted president, who fled overseas this week to escape a popular uprising against his government, has said he took “all possible steps” to avert the economic crisis that has engulfed the island nation.",
        "Gotabaya Rajapaksa’s resignation was accepted by parliament on Friday. He flew to the Maldives and then Singapore after hundreds of thousands of anti-government protesters came out onto the streets of Colombo a week ago and occupied his official residence and offices.",
        "Sri Lanka’s parliament met on Saturday to begin the process of electing a new president, and a shipment of fuel arrived to provide some relief to the crisis-hit nation.",
        "Dhammika Dasanayake, the secretary general of Sri Lanka’s parliament, formally read out Rajapaksa’s resignation letter, the contents of which had not previously been made public.",
        "In the letter, Rajapaksa said Sri Lanka’s financial crisis was rooted in years of economic mismanagement that pre-dated his presidency and in the COVID-19 pandemic that drastically reduced Sri Lanka’s tourist arrivals and remittances from foreign workers.",
        "“It is my personal belief that I took all possible steps to address this crisis, including inviting parliamentarians to form an all-party or unity government,” the letter said.",
        "Parliament will next meet on Tuesday to accept nominations for the post of the president. A vote to decide the country’s leader is set to take place on Wednesday.",
        "Prime minister Ranil Wickremesinghe, an ally of Rajapaksa who is the sole representative of his party in parliament, has been sworn in as acting president until then.",
        "Wickremesinghe is one of the top contenders to take on the role full-time but protesters also want him gone, leading to the prospect of further unrest should he be elected.",
        "The opposition’s presidential nominee is Sajith Premadasa. The potential dark horse is senior ruling party lawmaker Dullas Alahapperuma.",
        "Wickremesinghe said on Saturday he would implement an urgent relief programme to provide fuel, gas and essential food items to Sri Lankans who are struggling because of the economic situation. He also promised to enter dialogue with protesters on reducing government corruption.",
        "Sri Lanka’s economy is likely to contract by more than 6% this year as political instability and social unrest affect discussions on financial relief with the IMF, the governor of the country’s central bank told The Wall Street Journal.",
        "Over 100 police and security personnel with assault rifles were deployed on the approach road to parliament on Saturday, manning barricades and a water cannon to prevent any unrest. Columns of security forces patrolled another approach road to parliament, though there were no signs of any protesters.",
        "Street protests over Sri Lanka’s economic meltdown simmered for months before boiling over on July 9, with protesters blaming the Rajapaksa family and allies for runaway inflation, shortages of basic goods, and corruption.",
        "The Rajapaksa family had dominated politics in Sri Lanka for years and Basil Rajapaska, brother of Gotabaya Rajapaksa, resigned as finance minister in April as street protests surged and quit his seat in parliament in June.",
        "Days-long fuel queues have become the norm in the island nation of 22 million, while foreign exchange reserves have dwindled to close to zero and headline inflation hit 54.6% last month.",
        "Sri Lanka received the first of three fuel shipments on Saturday, Energy Minister Kanchana Wijesekera said. These are the first shipments to reach the country in about three weeks.",
        "A second diesel consignment will also arrive on Saturday, with a shipment of petrol due by Tuesday.",
        "“Payments completed for all 3,” the minister said in a tweet."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Gotabaya",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka’s",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "this week",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Gotabaya Rajapaksa’s",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Friday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Singapore",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "hundreds of thousands",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Colombo",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "a week ago",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Saturday",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Dhammika Dasanayake",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka’s",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Rajapaksa",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka’s",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "years",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka’s",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Tuesday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Wednesday",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "one",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sajith Premadasa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Dullas Alahapperuma",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Saturday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lankans",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka’s",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "more than 6%",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "this year",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "IMF",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "The Wall Street Journal",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Saturday",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "months",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "July 9",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "years",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Basil Rajapaska",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Gotabaya Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "April",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "June",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Days-long",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "22 million",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "close to zero",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "54.6%",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "last month",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "first",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "three",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Saturday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Energy",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kanchana Wijesekera",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "first",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "about three weeks",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "second",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Saturday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Tuesday",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "3",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "අර්බුදය වැළැක්වීම සඳහා ගත හැකි සෑම පියවරක්ම ගත් බව හිටපු ජනාධිපති ගෝඨාභය පවසයි",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "තම ආන්ඩුවට එරෙහි මහජන නැගිටීමකින් බේරීම සඳහා මේ සතියේ විදේශගත වූ ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ නෙරපා හරින ලද ජනාධිපතිවරයා, දිවයින ජාතිය ගිලගෙන ඇති ආර්ථික අර්බුදය වැලැක්වීම සඳහා \"හැකි සෑම පියවරක්ම\" ගත් බව පවසා තිබේ.",
        "ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂගේ ඉල්ලා අස්වීම සිකුරාදා පාර්ලිමේන්තුව විසින් පිළිගනු ලැබීය. ඔහු මාලදිවයිනට සහ සිංගප්පූරුවට පියාසර කළේ සතියකට පෙර ලක්ෂ සංඛ්‍යාත ආණ්ඩු විරෝධී විරෝධතාකරුවන් කොළඹ වීදිවලට ​​පැමිණ ඔහුගේ නිල නිවස සහ කාර්යාල අල්ලා ගැනීමෙන් පසුවය.",
        "නව ජනාධිපතිවරයෙකු තෝරා පත් කර ගැනීමේ ක්‍රියාවලිය ආරම්භ කිරීම සඳහා ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ පාර්ලිමේන්තුව සෙනසුරාදා රැස් වූ අතර, අර්බුදයට ලක් වූ ජාතියට යම් සහනයක් ලබා දීම සඳහා ඉන්ධන තොගයක් පැමිණියේය.",
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකා පාර්ලිමේන්තුවේ මහලේකම් ධම්මික දසනායක විසින් රාජපක්ෂගේ ඉල්ලා අස්වීමේ ලිපිය නිල වශයෙන් කියවන ලද අතර, එහි අන්තර්ගතය මීට පෙර ප්‍රසිද්ධියට පත් කර නොතිබුණි.",
        "ලිපියේ රාජපක්ෂ කියා සිටියේ, ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ මූල්‍ය අර්බුදය මුල් බැස ඇත්තේ ඔහුගේ ජනාධිපති වීමට පෙර වසර ගණනාවක ආර්ථික වැරදි කළමනාකරණය සහ ශ්‍රී ලංකාවට සංචාරක පැමිණීම් සහ විදේශ ශ්‍රමිකයන්ගේ ප්‍රේෂණ විශාල ලෙස අඩු කළ COVID-19 වසංගතය තුළ බවයි.",
        "\"සර්ව පාක්ෂික හෝ එක්සත් ආන්ඩුවක් පිහිටුවීමට පාර්ලිමේන්තු මන්ත්‍රීවරුන්ට ආරාධනා කිරීම ඇතුළුව මෙම අර්බුදය විසඳීමට මා ගත හැකි සෑම පියවරක්ම ගත් බව මගේ පෞද්ගලික විශ්වාසයයි\" යනුවෙන් ලිපියේ සඳහන් වේ.",
        "ජනාධිපති ධුරය සඳහා නාමයෝජනා භාර ගැනීම සඳහා පාර්ලිමේන්තුව මීළඟ අඟහරුවාදා රැස්වේ. රටේ නායකයා තීරණය කිරීමේ ඡන්ද විමසීම බදාදා පැවැත්වීමට නියමිතයි.",
        "එතෙක් වැඩබලන ජනාධිපතිවරයා ලෙස දිවුරුම් දී ඇත්තේ පාර්ලිමේන්තුවේ තම පක්ෂයේ එකම නියෝජිතයා වන රාජපක්ෂගේ හිතවතෙකු වන අගමැති රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහයි.",
        "වික්‍රමසිංහ පූර්ණ කාලීනව එම භූමිකාව භාර ගැනීමට ප්‍රමුඛ පෙළේ තරඟකරුවන්ගෙන් කෙනෙකි, නමුත් විරෝධතාකරුවන්ටද ඔහුව ඉවත් කිරීමට අවශ්‍ය වන අතර, ඔහු තේරී පත් වුවහොත් තවදුරටත් නොසන්සුන්තාවයේ අපේක්ෂාවකට තුඩු දෙයි.",
        "විපක්ෂයේ ජනාධිපති අපේක්ෂකයා සජිත් ප්‍රේමදාස ය. විභව අඳුරු අශ්වයා ආණ්ඩු පක්ෂයේ ජ්‍යෙෂ්ඨ පාර්ලිමේන්තු මන්ත්‍රී ඩලස් අලහප්පෙරුම ය.",
        "ආර්ථික තත්ත්වය හේතුවෙන් දුෂ්කරතාවට පත්ව සිටින ශ්‍රී ලාංකිකයින්ට ඉන්ධන, ගෑස් සහ අත්‍යවශ්‍ය ආහාර ද්‍රව්‍ය ලබා දීම සඳහා කඩිනම් සහන වැඩසටහනක් ක්‍රියාත්මක කරන බව වික්‍රමසිංහ සෙනසුරාදා ප්‍රකාශ කළේය. රජයේ දූෂණ අවම කිරීම සම්බන්ධයෙන් විරෝධතාකරුවන් සමඟ සංවාදයකට එළඹීමට ද ඔහු පොරොන්දු විය.",
        "දේශපාලන අස්ථාවරත්වය සහ සමාජ නොසන්සුන්තාව IMF සමඟ මූල්‍ය සහන පිළිබඳ සාකච්ඡාවලට බලපාන බැවින් ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ ආර්ථිකය මේ වසරේ 6% කට වඩා හැකිලෙනු ඇතැයි රටේ මහ බැංකු අධිපතිවරයා The Wall Street Journal වෙත පැවසීය.",
        "සෙනසුරාදා පාර්ලිමේන්තුවට ප්‍රවේශ වන මාර්ගයේ පොලිස් සහ ආරක්ෂක භටයන් 100කට අධික පිරිසක් යොදවා තිබූ අතර, කිසියම් නොසන්සුන්තාවයක් ඇතිවීම වැලැක්වීම සඳහා බාධක සහ ජල ප්‍රහාරක රථ යොදාගෙන ඇත. විරෝධතාකරුවන්ගේ කිසිදු සලකුණක් නොතිබුණද, ආරක්ෂක අංශවල තීරු පාර්ලිමේන්තුවට පිවිසෙන තවත් මාර්ගයක මුර සංචාරයේ යෙදී සිටියහ.",
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ ආර්ථික බිඳවැටීම පිලිබඳ වීදි විරෝධතා ජූලි 9 වෙනිදා උතුරා යාමට පෙර මාස ගනනාවක් ගිනිබත් විය, විරෝධතාකරුවන් රාජපක්ෂ පවුලට සහ හිතවතුන්ට පැන ගිය උද්ධමනය, මූලික භාණ්ඩ හිඟය සහ දූෂණය සම්බන්ධයෙන් දොස් පවරන ලදී.",
        "රාජපක්ෂ පවුල වසර ගණනාවක් ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ දේශපාලනයේ ආධිපත්‍යය දැරූ අතර වීදි විරෝධතා ඉහළ යාමත් සමඟ ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂගේ සහෝදරයා වූ බැසිල් රාජපක්ෂ අප්‍රේල් මාසයේදී මුදල් අමාත්‍ය ධුරයෙන් ඉල්ලා අස්වී ජුනි මාසයේදී පාර්ලිමේන්තුවෙන් ඉවත් විය.",
        "මිලියන 22 ක් වූ දිවයිනේ දින ගණනක් ඉන්ධන පෝලිම් සාමාන්‍ය දෙයක් බවට පත්ව ඇති අතර විදේශ විනිමය සංචිත බිංදුවට ආසන්නව අඩු වී ඇති අතර පසුගිය මාසයේ උද්ධමනය 54.6% දක්වා ඉහළ ගියේය.",
        "ඉන්ධන නැව්ගත කිරීම් තුනෙන් පළමුවැන්න සෙනසුරාදා ශ්‍රී ලංකාවට ලැබුණු බව බලශක්ති අමාත්‍ය කංචන විජේසේකර මහතා පැවසීය. සති තුනකින් පමණ මෙරටට පැමිණි පළමු නැව්ගත කිරීම් මේවාය.",
        "දෙවන ඩීසල් තොගයක් ද සෙනසුරාදා පැමිණෙන අතර, අඟහරුවාදා වන විට පෙට්‍රල් නැව්ගත කිරීමට නියමිතයි.",
        "“3 දෙනාටම ගෙවීම් අවසන්,” අමාත්‍යවරයා ට්විටර් පණිවුඩයක් නිකුත් කරමින් කියා සිටියේය."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ගෝඨාභය",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මෙම සතිය",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂගේ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "සිකුරාදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "සිංගප්පූරුව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "සිය දහස් ගණනක්",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "කොළඹ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "සතියකට පෙර",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "සෙනසුරාදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ධම්මික දසනායක",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "වසර",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "අඟහරුවාදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "බදාදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "එක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "සජිත් ප්‍රේමදාස",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඩලස් අලහප්පෙරුම",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "සෙනසුරාදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලාංකිකයන්",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "6% ට වඩා",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "මේ වසරේ",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "IMF",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "The Wall Street Journal",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "සෙනසුරාදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මාස",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජූලි 9",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "වසර",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "බැසිල් රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "අප්රේල්",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජූනි",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "දින-දිගු",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මිලියන 22 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "බිංදුවට ආසන්නයි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "54.6%",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "පසුගිය මාසයේ",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "පළමුවන",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "තුන්",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "සෙනසුරාදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශක්තිය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "කාංචන විජේසේකර",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "පළමුවන",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "සති තුනක් පමණ",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "දෙවැනි",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "සෙනසුරාදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "අඟහරුවාදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "3",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "நெருக்கடியைத் தடுப்பதற்கு தாம் சாத்தியமான அனைத்து நடவடிக்கைகளையும் எடுத்ததாக முன்னாள் ஜனாதிபதி கோட்டாபய தெரிவித்துள்ளார்",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "தனது அரசாங்கத்திற்கு எதிரான மக்கள் எழுச்சியிலிருந்து தப்பிப்பதற்காக இந்த வாரம் வெளிநாடுகளுக்கு தப்பிச் சென்ற இலங்கையின் வெளியேற்றப்பட்ட ஜனாதிபதி, தீவு தேசத்தை மூழ்கடித்துள்ள பொருளாதார நெருக்கடியைத் தவிர்ப்பதற்கு \"எல்லா நடவடிக்கைகளையும்\" எடுத்ததாகக் கூறியுள்ளார்.",
        "கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்சவின் ராஜினாமாவை வெள்ளிக்கிழமை நாடாளுமன்றம் ஏற்றுக்கொண்டது. ஒரு வாரத்திற்கு முன்னர் நூறாயிரக்கணக்கான அரசாங்க எதிர்ப்பு ஆர்ப்பாட்டக்காரர்கள் கொழும்பு வீதிக்கு வந்து அவரது உத்தியோகபூர்வ இல்லம் மற்றும் அலுவலகங்களை ஆக்கிரமித்த பின்னர் அவர் மாலைதீவுக்கும் பின்னர் சிங்கப்பூருக்கும் பறந்தார்.",
        "புதிய ஜனாதிபதியைத் தேர்ந்தெடுப்பதற்கான செயல்முறையைத் தொடங்குவதற்கு இலங்கையின் பாராளுமன்றம் சனிக்கிழமை கூடியது, மேலும் நெருக்கடியால் பாதிக்கப்பட்ட தேசத்திற்கு ஓரளவு நிவாரணம் வழங்குவதற்காக எரிபொருள் அனுப்பப்பட்டது.",
        "இலங்கை நாடாளுமன்றத்தின் பொதுச்செயலாளர் தம்மிக்க தசநாயக்க, ராஜபக்சேவின் ராஜினாமா கடிதத்தை முறையாக வாசித்தார், அதன் உள்ளடக்கங்கள் முன்னர் பகிரங்கப்படுத்தப்படவில்லை.",
        "கடிதத்தில், ராஜபக்ச, இலங்கையின் நிதி நெருக்கடியானது தனது ஜனாதிபதி பதவிக்கு முந்திய பல வருட பொருளாதார முறைகேடுகளாலும், கோவிட்-19 தொற்றுநோய்களாலும் இலங்கையின் சுற்றுலாப் பயணிகளின் வருகை மற்றும் வெளிநாட்டு ஊழியர்களிடமிருந்து பணம் செலுத்துவதைக் கடுமையாகக் குறைத்துள்ளது.",
        "\"இந்த நெருக்கடியைத் தீர்ப்பதற்கு, அனைத்துக் கட்சி அல்லது ஐக்கிய அரசாங்கத்தை அமைக்க நாடாளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர்களை அழைப்பது உட்பட, சாத்தியமான அனைத்து நடவடிக்கைகளையும் நான் எடுத்தேன் என்பது எனது தனிப்பட்ட நம்பிக்கை\" என்று அந்தக் கடிதத்தில் கூறப்பட்டுள்ளது.",
        "ஜனாதிபதி பதவிக்கான வேட்புமனுக்களை ஏற்றுக்கொள்வதற்காக பாராளுமன்றம் அடுத்த செவ்வாய்க்கிழமை கூடவுள்ளது. நாட்டின் தலைவரை தீர்மானிக்கும் வாக்கெடுப்பு புதன்கிழமை நடைபெற உள்ளது.",
        "நாடாளுமன்றத்தில் ராஜபக்சேவின் ஏக பிரதிநிதியான ராஜபக்சேவின் கூட்டாளியான பிரதமர் ரணில் விக்ரமசிங்கே, அதுவரை செயல் அதிபராக பதவியேற்றார்.",
        "விக்கிரமசிங்க முழுநேரப் பொறுப்பை ஏற்கும் முக்கியப் போட்டியாளர்களில் ஒருவர், ஆனால் எதிர்ப்பாளர்களும் அவரைப் போக விரும்புகிறார்கள், இது அவர் தேர்ந்தெடுக்கப்பட்டால் மேலும் அமைதியின்மைக்கு வழிவகுக்கும்.",
        "எதிர்க்கட்சிகளின் ஜனாதிபதி வேட்பாளர் சஜித் பிரேமதாச. ஆளும் கட்சியின் மூத்த நாடாளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர் டலஸ் அழகப்பெருமதான் இருண்ட குதிரையாக இருப்பார்.",
        "பொருளாதார நிலைமை காரணமாக சிரமப்படும் இலங்கையர்களுக்கு எரிபொருள், எரிவாயு மற்றும் அத்தியாவசிய உணவுப் பொருட்களை வழங்குவதற்கான அவசர நிவாரணத் திட்டத்தை நடைமுறைப்படுத்தவுள்ளதாக விக்ரமசிங்க சனிக்கிழமை தெரிவித்தார். அரசாங்கத்தின் ஊழலைக் குறைப்பது குறித்து போராட்டக்காரர்களுடன் பேச்சுவார்த்தை நடத்துவதாகவும் அவர் உறுதியளித்தார்.",
        "அரசியல் ஸ்திரமின்மை மற்றும் சமூக அமைதியின்மை IMF உடனான நிதி நிவாரணம் பற்றிய விவாதங்களை பாதிக்கும் என்பதால், இலங்கையின் பொருளாதாரம் இந்த ஆண்டு 6% க்கும் அதிகமாக சுருங்கக்கூடும் என்று நாட்டின் மத்திய வங்கியின் ஆளுநர் The Wall Street Journal க்கு தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "சனிக்கிழமையன்று பாராளுமன்றத்தை அணுகும் சாலையில் 100 க்கும் மேற்பட்ட போலீசார் மற்றும் பாதுகாப்புப் பணியாளர்கள், எந்தவித அமைதியின்மையும் ஏற்படாமல் தடுக்க தடுப்புகள் மற்றும் தண்ணீர் பீரங்கிகளை ஏந்தியிருந்தனர். பாதுகாப்புப் படைகளின் நெடுவரிசைகள் பாராளுமன்றத்திற்கு செல்லும் மற்றொரு அணுகுமுறை சாலையில் ரோந்து சென்றன, இருப்பினும் எதிர்ப்பாளர்கள் எவரும் இருப்பதற்கான அறிகுறிகள் எதுவும் இல்லை.",
        "இலங்கையின் பொருளாதாரச் சரிவு தொடர்பான வீதிப் போராட்டங்கள் ஜூலை 9 அன்று கொதித்தெழுவதற்கு முன்பே பல மாதங்களாக கொதித்தெழுந்தன, எதிர்ப்பாளர்கள் பணவீக்கம், அடிப்படைப் பொருட்களின் பற்றாக்குறை மற்றும் ஊழலுக்கு ராஜபக்ச குடும்பத்தையும் கூட்டாளிகளையும் குற்றம் சாட்டினர்.",
        "ராஜபக்ச குடும்பம் பல ஆண்டுகளாக இலங்கையில் அரசியலில் ஆதிக்கம் செலுத்தியது மற்றும் கோத்தபய ராஜபக்சேவின் சகோதரர் பசில் ராஜபாஸ்கா, ஏப்ரல் மாதம் தெருப் போராட்டங்கள் அதிகரித்ததால் நிதியமைச்சர் பதவியை ராஜினாமா செய்தார் மற்றும் ஜூன் மாதம் பாராளுமன்றத்தில் இருந்து வெளியேறினார்.",
        "தீவு தேசத்தில் 22 மில்லியனுக்கும் அதிகமான எரிபொருள் வரிசைகள் வழக்கமாகிவிட்டன, அதே சமயம் அந்நியச் செலாவணி இருப்பு பூஜ்ஜியத்திற்கு அருகில் குறைந்துள்ளது மற்றும் கடந்த மாதம் பணவீக்கம் 54.6% ஐ எட்டியது.",
        "மூன்று எரிபொருள் ஏற்றுமதிகளில் முதலாவது இலங்கைக்கு சனிக்கிழமை கிடைத்ததாக எரிசக்தி அமைச்சர் காஞ்சன விஜேசேகர தெரிவித்துள்ளார். சுமார் மூன்று வாரங்களில் நாட்டை வந்தடையும் முதல் ஏற்றுமதி இவை.",
        "இரண்டாவது டீசல் சரக்கு சனிக்கிழமை வரும், செவ்வாய்க்கிழமைக்குள் பெட்ரோல் அனுப்பப்பட வேண்டும்.",
        "\"மூன்று பேருக்கும் பணம் செலுத்தப்பட்டது\" என்று அமைச்சர் ஒரு ட்வீட்டில் கூறினார்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "கோட்டாபய",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கையின்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்த வாரம்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்சவின்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "வெள்ளி",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சிங்கப்பூர்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "நூறாயிரக்கணக்கான",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "கொழும்பு",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஒரு வாரத்திற்கு முன்பு",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சனிக்கிழமை",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "தம்மிக்க தசநாயக்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கையின்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ராஜபக்சே",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ராஜபக்சே",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கையின்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆண்டுகள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கையின்",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "செவ்வாய்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "புதன்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ராஜபக்சே",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஒன்று",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "சஜித் பிரேமதாச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "டலஸ் அழகப்பெரும",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "சனிக்கிழமை",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கையர்கள்",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கையின்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "6%க்கு மேல்",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்த வருடம்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "IMF",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "தி வால் ஸ்ட்ரீட் ஜர்னல்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "சனிக்கிழமை",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "மாதங்கள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜூலை 9",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ராஜபக்சே",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ராஜபக்சே",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆண்டுகள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "பசில் ராஜபஸ்கா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஏப்ரல்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜூன்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "நாட்கள்-நீண்ட",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "22 மில்லியன்",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "பூஜ்ஜியத்திற்கு அருகில்",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "54.6%",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "கடந்த மாதம்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "முதலில்",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "மூன்று",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "சனிக்கிழமை",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆற்றல்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "காஞ்சனா விஜேசேகர",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "முதலில்",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "சுமார் மூன்று வாரங்கள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இரண்டாவது",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "சனிக்கிழமை",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "செவ்வாய்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "3",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}