{
  "newspaper_id": "ada-lk",
  "url": "https://www.ada.lk/breaking_news/යූරියා-පොහොර-බෙදාහැරීම-හෙටින්-ඇරඹේ/11-395330",
  "time_ut": 1657537255,
  "original_lang": "si",
  "original_title": "යූරියා පොහොර බෙදාහැරීම හෙටින් ඇරඹේ",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Urea fertilizer distribution will start from tomorrow",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "The Ministry of Agriculture states that the distribution of urea fertilizer will start from tomorrow (12th).",
        "The ministry says that the unloading of fertilizer from the port of Colombo will be done round the clock and the unloading will be completed within 10 days.",
        "The Ministry of Agriculture mentions that the Ceylon Commercial Fertilizer Company has used a formal program to distribute the fertilizer throughout the island and whether the fertilizer distribution to the farmers will be done in a formal manner will be done under the full supervision of the Minister of Agriculture, Mr. Mahinda Amaraweera."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "tomorrow",
          "label": "DATE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "The Ministry of Agriculture",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Colombo",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "10 days",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "The Ministry of Agriculture",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Mahinda Amaraweera",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "යූරියා පොහොර බෙදාහැරීම හෙටින් ඇරඹේ",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "යූරියා පොහොර බෙදාහැරීම් කටයුතු හෙට (12දා) සිට ආරම්භ කරන බව කෘෂිකර්ම අමාත්‍යාංශය සඳහන් කරයි.",
        "කොළඹ වරායෙන් පොහොර ගොඩබෑමේ කටයුතු පැය 24 පුරාම සිදු කෙරෙන බවද  දින 10ක් ඇතුළත ගොඩබෑමේ කටයුතු අවසන් කිරීමට නියමිත බවද එම අමාත්‍යාංශය පවසයි.",
        "ලංකා කොමර්ෂල් පොහොර සමාගම විසින් එම පොහොර තොගය දිවයින පුරා බෙදාහැරිම සඳහා  විධිමත් වැඩපිළිවෙලක් යොදා ඇතැයි ද ගොවීන්ට පොහොර බෙදාහැරිමේ කටයුතු විධිමත්ව සිදුවන්නේ ද යන්න කෘෂිකර්ම අමාත්‍ය මහින්ද අමරවීර මහතාගේ පූර්ණ අධික්ෂණය මත සිදු කෙරෙන බවත් කෘෂිකර්ම අමාත්‍යාංශය සඳහන් කරයි."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "හෙට",
          "label": "DATE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "කෘෂිකර්ම අමාත්‍යාංශය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "කොළඹ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "දින 10 යි",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "කෘෂිකර්ම අමාත්‍යාංශය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "මහින්ද අමරවීර",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "யூரியா உர விநியோகம் நாளை முதல் ஆரம்பமாகிறது",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "யூரியா உர விநியோகம் நாளை (12ஆம் திகதி) முதல் ஆரம்பிக்கப்படும் என விவசாய அமைச்சு தெரிவித்துள்ளது.",
        "கொழும்பு துறைமுகத்தில் இருந்து உரம் இறக்கும் பணி 24 மணி நேரமும் மேற்கொள்ளப்படும் என்றும், 10 நாட்களுக்குள் இறக்கும் பணிகள் நிறைவடையும் என்றும் அமைச்சு கூறுகிறது.",
        "இலங்கை வர்த்தக உர நிறுவனம் முறையான வேலைத்திட்டத்தின் மூலம் நாடளாவிய ரீதியில் உரங்களை விநியோகித்துள்ளதாகவும் விவசாயிகளுக்கான உர விநியோகம் முறையான முறையில் விவசாய அமைச்சரின் பூரண மேற்பார்வையின் கீழ் மேற்கொள்ளப்படுமெனவும் விவசாய அமைச்சு குறிப்பிடுகிறது. , திரு.மகிந்த அமரவீர."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "நாளை",
          "label": "DATE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "விவசாய அமைச்சகம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "கொழும்பு",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "10 நாட்கள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "விவசாய அமைச்சகம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "மஹிந்த அமரவீர",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}