{
  "newspaper_id": "lankadeepa-lk",
  "url": "https://www.lankadeepa.lk/latest_news/22-සංශෝධනයේ-ශ්‍රේෂ්ඨාධිකරණ-මතය-මේ-සතිය-අගදී/1-619114",
  "time_ut": 1662017647,
  "original_lang": "si",
  "original_title": "22 සංශෝධනයේ ශ්‍රේෂ්ඨාධිකරණ මතය මේ සතිය අගදී",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Supreme Court Opinion on Amendment 22 later this week",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "Minister of Justice Dr. Wijayadasa Rajapaksa said in Parliament today (1) that it is hoped that the Supreme Court's opinion on the twenty-second constitutional amendment will be received by the end of this week.",
        "He also expressed confidence that after receiving the opinion of the Supreme Court, the bill can be passed in a manner that suits the country.",
        "He thus expressed his confidence by joining the debate on the second reading of the Budget Appropriation Bill.",
        "The minister said that today corruption is happening not only in the public sector but also in the private sector and also stated that about fifteen bills have been submitted to the Parliament in the past for various purposes including prevention of corruption and fraud.",
        "He said that after the adoption of the Anti-Corruption Act, the Bribery Act as well as the Assets Liabilities Law will be changed.",
        "Mr. Wijedasa Rajapaksa also said that \"our country made a mistake in money management\".",
        "The minister said that the executive took individual decisions and the sale of Hambantota port also contributed to the creation of an economic crisis in the country."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Supreme Court Opinion on Amendment 22 later this week",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Justice",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Wijayadasa Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "1",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Supreme Court's",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the end of this week",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the Supreme Court",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "second",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Budget Appropriation Bill",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "about fifteen",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the Anti-Corruption Act",
            "label": "LAW"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Bribery Act",
            "label": "LAW"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Wijedasa Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Hambantota",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "22 සංශෝධනයේ ශ්‍රේෂ්ඨාධිකරණ මතය මේ සතිය අගදී",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "විසි දෙවෙනි ආණ්ඩු ක්‍රම ව්‍යවස්ථා සංශෝධනය පිළිබඳ ශ්‍රේෂ්ඨාධිකරණයේ මතය මේ සතිය අවසානයේදී ලැබෙනු ඇතැයි බලාපොරොත්තු වන බව අධිකරණ අමාත්‍ය ආචාර්ය විජයදාස රාජපක්ෂ මහතා පාර්ලිමේන්තුවේදී අද (1)  පැවසීය.",
        "ශ්‍රේෂ්ඨාධිකරණයේ  මතය ලැබුණු පසු එම පනත් කෙටුම්පත රටට ගැලපෙන විදියට  සම්මත කර ගැනීමට හැකි වෙතැයිද හෙතෙම විශ්වාසය පළ කළේය.",
        "ඔහු මෙලෙස  විශ්වාසය පළ කළේ අයවැය විසර්ජන පනත් කෙටුම්පත පිළිබඳ දෙවැනි වර කියවීමේ විවාදයට එක්වෙමිනි.",
        "අද රාජ්‍ය අංශයේ පමණක් නොව පෞද්ගලික  අංශයේද දූෂණ සිදුවන බව පැවසූ අමාත්‍යවරයා දූෂණ වංචා වැළැක්වීම ඇතුළු විවිධ අරමුණු වෙනුවෙන්  පනත් පහළොවක් පමණ පසුගිය කාලයේ දී පාර්ලිමේන්තුවට ඉදිරිපත් කෙරුණු බවද  ප්‍රකාශ කළේය.",
        "දූෂණ විරෝධී පනත සම්මත කර ගත් පසු අල්ලස් පනත මෙන්ම වත්කම් බැරකම් නීතියද වෙනස් කළ හැකි වනු ඇතැයි ඔහු පැවසුවේය.",
        "\"මුදල් කළමනාකරණයේදී  අපේ රටට වැරදුණා \" යැයිද  විජේදාස රාජපක්ෂ මහතා පැවසීය.",
        "විධායකය තනි තීන්දු ගැනීමද  රටේ ආර්ථික අර්බුදයක් නිර්මාණය වීමට බලපෑ පැවසූ අමාත්‍යවරයා හම්බන්තොට වරාය විකිණීමද ඊට ලොකු උත්තේජනයක් සැපයූ බව"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "22 සංශෝධනය පිළිබඳ ශ්‍රේෂ්ඨාධිකරණයේ මතය මේ සතිය අගදී",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "යුක්තිය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "විජයදාස රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "1",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රේෂ්ඨාධිකරණයේ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "මෙම සතියේ අවසානය",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රේෂ්ඨාධිකරණය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "දෙවැනි",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "අයවැය විසර්ජන පනත් කෙටුම්පත",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "පහළොවක් පමණ",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "දූෂණ විරෝධී පනත",
            "label": "LAW"
          },
          {
            "text": "අල්ලස් පනත",
            "label": "LAW"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "විජේදාස රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "හම්බන්තොට",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "இந்த வாரத்தின் பிற்பகுதியில் திருத்தம் 22 இல் உச்ச நீதிமன்றத்தின் கருத்து",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "இருபத்தி இரண்டாவது அரசியலமைப்புத் திருத்தம் தொடர்பான உச்ச நீதிமன்றத்தின் கருத்து இந்த வார இறுதிக்குள் கிடைக்கப்பெறும் என நம்புவதாக நீதி அமைச்சர் கலாநிதி விஜயதாச ராஜபக்ஷ இன்று (1) பாராளுமன்றத்தில் தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "உச்ச நீதிமன்றத்தின் கருத்தைப் பெற்ற பிறகு நாட்டுக்கு ஏற்ற வகையில் மசோதாவை நிறைவேற்ற முடியும் என்றும் அவர் நம்பிக்கை தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "வரவு செலவுத் திட்ட ஒதுக்கீட்டுச் சட்டமூலத்தின் இரண்டாம் வாசிப்பு மீதான விவாதத்தில் கலந்துகொண்டு அவர் இவ்வாறு நம்பிக்கை தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "இன்று அரச துறையில் மட்டுமன்றி தனியார் துறையிலும் ஊழல் இடம்பெற்று வருவதாக தெரிவித்த அமைச்சர், ஊழல் மோசடிகளை தடுப்பது உள்ளிட்ட பல்வேறு நோக்கங்களுக்காக கடந்த காலங்களில் சுமார் பதினைந்து சட்டமூலங்கள் பாராளுமன்றத்தில் சமர்ப்பிக்கப்பட்டுள்ளதாகவும் தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "ஊழல் தடுப்புச் சட்டம் அமலுக்கு வந்த பிறகு, லஞ்ச ஒழிப்புச் சட்டம் மற்றும் சொத்துப் பொறுப்புச் சட்டம் மாற்றப்படும் என்றார்.",
        "திரு.விஜேதாச ராஜபக்ஷவும் “எமது நாடு பண முகாமைத்துவத்தில் தவறிழைத்துவிட்டது” என்றார்.",
        "நிறைவேற்று அதிகாரம் தனிப்பட்ட தீர்மானங்களை எடுத்ததுடன், ஹம்பாந்தோட்டை துறைமுகத்தை விற்பனை செய்தமையும் நாட்டில் பொருளாதார நெருக்கடியை உருவாக்குவதற்கு பங்களித்துள்ளதாக அமைச்சர் கூறினார்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "இந்த வாரத்தின் பிற்பகுதியில் திருத்தம் 22 இல் உச்ச நீதிமன்றத்தின் கருத்து",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "நீதி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "விஜயதாச ராஜபக்ச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "1",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "உச்ச நீதிமன்றத்தின்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்த வார இறுதியில்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "உச்ச நீதிமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இரண்டாவது",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "பட்ஜெட் ஒதுக்கீட்டு மசோதா",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சுமார் பதினைந்து",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஊழல் தடுப்பு சட்டம்",
            "label": "LAW"
          },
          {
            "text": "லஞ்ச ஒழிப்பு சட்டம்",
            "label": "LAW"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "விஜேதாச ராஜபக்ஷ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஹம்பாந்தோட்டை",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}