{
  "newspaper_id": "lankadeepa-lk",
  "url": "https://www.lankadeepa.lk/latest_news/ලිට්‍රෝ-ගණන්-බහී/1-619278",
  "time_ut": 1662290106,
  "original_lang": "si",
  "original_title": "ලිට්‍රෝ ගණන් බහී",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Liter counting down",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "Litro Gas Company says that the price of a Litro domestic gas cylinder will be reduced by 100 to 200 rupees from midnight tomorrow (5).",
        "Mr. Muditha Peiris, the president of the company, said that this price reduction will be done according to the gas price formula introduced by Litro Gas Company, the Ministry of Finance and the Consumer Affairs Authority.",
        "The chairman said that this price reduction will be done according to the current gas prices in the world market and also mentioned that the price of gas cylinders of all sizes will be reduced.",
        "The chairman who said that Litro Gas Company has made a significant profit in the past two months, also said that the company has made a huge profit of 70 crore rupees in the last month of August alone."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Liter",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Litro Gas Company",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Litro",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "100 to 200",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "midnight tomorrow",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "5",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Muditha Peiris",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Litro Gas Company",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Ministry of Finance",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Consumer Affairs Authority",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "Litro Gas Company",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the past two months",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "70",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "the last month of August",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "ලිට්‍රෝ ගණන් බහී",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "ලිට්‍රෝ ගෘහස්ථ ගෑස් සිලින්ඩරයක මිල හෙට (5) මධ්‍යම රාත්‍රියේ සිට රුපියල් 100ත්, 200ත් අතර මිලකින් පහත හෙළන බව ලිට්‍රෝ ගෑස් සමාගම පවසයි.",
        "ලිට්‍රෝ ගෑස් සමාගම, මුදල් අමාත්‍යංශ සහ පාරිභෝගික කටයුතු අධිකාරිය සමඟ එකතුව හදුන්වාදුන් ගෑස් මිල සූත්‍රය අනුව මෙම මිල අඩුකිරීම සිදුවන බව සමාගමේ සභාපති මුදිත පීරිස් මහතා පැවසීය.",
        "ලෝක වෙළෙඳපොළේ වත්මන් ගෑස් මිල ගණන් අනුව මෙම මිල අඩුකිරීම සිදුවන බව කී සභාපතිවරයා සියලුම ප්‍රමාණයන්හි ගෑස් සිලින්ඩරවල මිල අඩු වන බව ද සඳහන් කළේය.",
        "ගතවූ මාස දෙකක කාලයේදී ලිට්‍රෝ ගැස් සමාගම සැලකිය යුතු ලාභයක් උපයා ඇතැයි කී සභාපතිවරයා ඉකුත් අගෝස්තු මාසයේ පමණක් සමාගම රුපියල් කෝටි 70 ක අධික ලාභයක් උපයා ඇතැයි ද කීවේය."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ලීටර්",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ලිට්‍රෝ ගෑස් සමාගම",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ලිට්රෝ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "100 සිට 200 දක්වා",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "හෙට මධ්‍යම රාත්‍රිය",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "5",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "මුදිත පීරිස්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ලිට්‍රෝ ගෑස් සමාගම",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "මුදල් අමාත්යාංශය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාරිභෝගික කටයුතු අධිකාරිය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "ලිට්‍රෝ ගෑස් සමාගම",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "පසුගිය මාස දෙක",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "70",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "අගෝස්තු අවසාන මාසය",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "லிட்டர் கணக்கிடப்படுகிறது",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "லிட்ரோ வீட்டு எரிவாயு சிலிண்டரின் விலை நாளை (5) நள்ளிரவு முதல் 100 முதல் 200 ரூபா வரை குறைக்கப்படும் என லிட்ரோ எரிவாயு நிறுவனம் தெரிவித்துள்ளது.",
        "லிட்ரோ எரிவாயு நிறுவனம், நிதியமைச்சு மற்றும் நுகர்வோர் விவகார அதிகார சபையினால் அறிமுகப்படுத்தப்பட்டுள்ள எரிவாயு விலை சூத்திரத்தின் பிரகாரம் இந்த விலை குறைப்பு மேற்கொள்ளப்படவுள்ளதாக நிறுவனத்தின் தலைவர் திரு.முதித பீரிஸ் தெரிவித்துள்ளார்.",
        "உலக சந்தையில் தற்போது நிலவும் எரிவாயு விலைக்கு ஏற்ப இந்த விலை குறைப்பு மேற்கொள்ளப்படும் என தெரிவித்த தலைவர், அனைத்து அளவிலான எரிவாயு சிலிண்டர்களின் விலையும் குறைக்கப்படும் எனவும் குறிப்பிட்டார்.",
        "கடந்த இரண்டு மாதங்களில் லிட்ரோ கேஸ் நிறுவனம் கணிசமான லாபத்தை ஈட்டியுள்ளதாக தெரிவித்த தலைவர், கடந்த ஆகஸ்ட் மாதத்தில் மட்டும் 70 கோடி ரூபா பாரிய லாபத்தை ஈட்டியுள்ளதாகவும் தெரிவித்தார்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "லிட்டர்",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "லிட்ரோ எரிவாயு நிறுவனம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "லிட்ரோ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "100 முதல் 200 வரை",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "நாளை நள்ளிரவு",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "5",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "முதித பீரிஸ்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "லிட்ரோ எரிவாயு நிறுவனம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "நிதி அமைச்சகம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "நுகர்வோர் விவகார ஆணையம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "லிட்ரோ எரிவாயு நிறுவனம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "கடந்த இரண்டு மாதங்கள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "70",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆகஸ்ட் கடைசி மாதம்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}