{
  "newspaper_id": "news-first-lk",
  "url": "https://www.newsfirst.lk/2022/07/17/vasudeva-pledges-support-to-dullas/",
  "time_ut": 1658054400,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Vasudeva pledges support to Dullas",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Vasudeva pledges support to Dullas",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); The Leader of the Democratic Left Front, Vasudeva Nanayakkara says that the party will be supporting SLPP MP Dallas Alahapperuma in electing a successor President.",
        "The Leader of Democratic Left Front stated that the decision was taken for the betterment of the public.",
        "He further stated that he hopes that the all-party Government made under the Presidency of candidate Alahapperuma would also be able to alleviate the current crisis plaguing the public, to some extent.",
        "Indian Govt calls for all-party meeting over Sri Lankan crisis",
        "Japan engages in high level talks with CBSL & Treasury officials"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Vasudeva",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "Dullas",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "News 1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Democratic",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Left Front",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Vasudeva Nanayakkara",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Dallas Alahapperuma",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Democratic",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Alahapperuma",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Indian",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lankan",
            "label": "LOC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Japan",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "CBSL & Treasury",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "වාසුදේව ඩලස්ට සහාය දෙන බවට පොරොන්දු වෙයි",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); ප්‍රජාතන්ත්‍රවාදී වාමාංශික පෙරමුණේ නායක වාසුදේව නානායක්කාර මහතා පැවසුවේ, අනුප්‍රාප්තික ජනාධිපතිවරයකු තෝරා පත් කර ගැනීම සඳහා ශ්‍රී ලංකා පොදුජන පෙරමුණේ පාර්ලිමේන්තු මන්ත්‍රී ඩලස් අලහප්පෙරුම මහතාට සහය පළ කරන බවයි.",
        "ප්‍රජාතන්ත්‍රවාදී වාමාංශික පෙරමුණේ නායකයා ප්‍රකාශ කළේ මහජනතාවගේ යහපත වෙනුවෙන් මෙම තීරණය ගත් බවයි.",
        "අපේක්‍ෂක අලහප්පෙරුම මහතාගේ ජනාධිපතිධුරය යටතේ පිහිටුවන ලද සර්ව පාක්ෂික ආණ්ඩුවට ද මේ වනවිට මහජනතාව පීඩාවට පත්වී ඇති අර්බුදය යම් තරමකට හෝ සමනය කිරීමට හැකිවනු ඇතැයි තමන් බලාපොරොත්තු වන බවද ඔහු වැඩිදුරටත් සඳහන් කළේය.",
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ අර්බුදය සම්බන්ධයෙන් ඉන්දීය රජය සර්ව පාක්ෂික හමුවක් කැඳවයි",
        "ජපානය CBSL සහ භාණ්ඩාගාර නිලධාරීන් සමඟ ඉහළ මට්ටමේ සාකච්ඡා පවත්වයි"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "වාසුදේව",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "ඩලස්",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "News 1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ප්‍රජාතන්ත්‍රවාදී",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "වම් පෙරමුණ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "වාසුදේව නානායක්කාර",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඩලස් අලහප්පෙරුම",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ප්‍රජාතන්ත්‍රවාදී",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Alahapperuma",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දීය",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලාංකික",
            "label": "LOC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ජපානය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "CBSL සහ භාණ්ඩාගාරය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "வாசுதேவா டல்லாஸுக்கு ஆதரவளிப்பதாக உறுதியளித்தார்",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); ஶ்ரீலங்கா பொதுஜன பெரமுனவின் பாராளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர் டலஸ் அழகப்பெருமவுக்கு அடுத்த ஜனாதிபதியை தெரிவு செய்வதற்கு ஜனநாயக இடதுசாரி முன்னணி ஆதரவளிக்கும் என அக்கட்சியின் தலைவர் வாசுதேவ நாணயக்கார தெரிவித்துள்ளார்.",
        "பொதுமக்களின் நலனுக்காக இந்த முடிவு எடுக்கப்பட்டதாக ஜனநாயக இடதுசாரி முன்னணியின் தலைவர் தெரிவித்துள்ளார்.",
        "வேட்பாளர் அழகப்பெருமவின் தலைமையில் உருவாக்கப்பட்ட சர்வகட்சி அரசாங்கமும் பொதுமக்களை வாட்டி வதைக்கும் தற்போதைய நெருக்கடியை ஓரளவுக்கு தணிக்க முடியும் என நம்புவதாக அவர் மேலும் தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "இலங்கை பிரச்சனை தொடர்பாக அனைத்து கட்சி கூட்டத்திற்கு இந்திய அரசு அழைப்பு விடுத்துள்ளது",
        "CBSL மற்றும் கருவூல அதிகாரிகளுடன் ஜப்பான் உயர்மட்ட பேச்சுவார்த்தையில் ஈடுபட்டுள்ளது"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "வாசுதேவா",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "டல்லாஸ்",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "News 1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜனநாயகம்",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "இடது முன்னணி",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "வாசுதேவ நாணயக்கார",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "டலஸ் அழகப்பெரும",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஜனநாயகம்",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Alahapperuma",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இந்தியன்",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "LOC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஜப்பான்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "CBSL & கருவூலம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}