{
  "newspaper_id": "daily-ft-lk",
  "url": "https://www.ft.lk/news/Julian-Bolling-summoned-to-CID-today/56-738780",
  "time_ut": 1660688508,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Julian Bolling summoned to CID today",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Julian Bolling summoned to CID today",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "CID seeks statements from Bolling and another on 9 July attack on President’s residence",
        "Bolling is a co-petitioner of an FR filed against the President and 12 others",
        "Former Sri Lankan Swimming Champion Julian Bolling and Businessman Jonathan Martenstyn have been summoned to appear before the Police Criminal Investigations Department (CID) today. The duo have been summoned over the protests held on 9 July.",
        "According to the CID Bolling and Martenstyn have been summoned to the CID in order to record statements from them for the purpose of future investigations into the arson attack on President Ranil Wickremesinghe’s residence on 9 July.",
        "Bolling is also a co-petitioner of a fundamental rights petition filed against persons responsible for the current economic crisis in Sri Lanka. President Ranil Wickremesinghe is among 13 respondents named in the petition filed by Bolling, the now popular Swim coach."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Julian Bolling",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "CID",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "today",
          "label": "DATE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "CID",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Bolling",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "9 July",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "FR",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "12",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Julian Bolling",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Jonathan Martenstyn",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Police Criminal Investigations Department",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "CID",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "9 July",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the CID Bolling and Martenstyn",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "CID",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "9 July",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "13",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Bolling",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "ජූලියන් බොලිං අද අපරාධ පරීක්ෂණ දෙපාර්තමේන්තුවට කැඳවා ඇත",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "ජුලි 9 වැනිදා ජනාධිපතිවරයාගේ නිවසට එල්ල වූ ප්‍රහාරයේ දී CID බොලින් සහ තවත් අයගෙන් ප්‍රකාශ ඉල්ලා සිටී",
        "බොලිං යනු ජනාධිපතිවරයාට සහ තවත් 12 දෙනෙකුට එරෙහිව ගොනු කර ඇති FR හි සම-පෙත්සම්කරුවෙකි",
        "හිටපු ශ්‍රී ලංකා පිහිනුම් ශූර ජූලියන් බෝලිං සහ ව්‍යාපාරික ජොනතන් මාර්ටෙන්ස්ටයින්ට අද පොලිස් අපරාධ පරීක්ෂණ දෙපාර්තමේන්තුව (සීඅයිඩී) හමුවේ පෙනී සිටින ලෙසට සිතාසි නිකුත් කර තිබේ. පසුගිය ජුලි 9 වනදා පැවති විරෝධතා හේතුවෙන් මොවුන් දෙදෙනාට මෙලෙස කැඳවා තිබේ.",
        "ජුලි 9 වැනිදා ජනාධිපති රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතාගේ නිවසට ගිනි තැබීමේ සිද්ධිය සම්බන්ධයෙන් ඉදිරි විමර්ශන කටයුතු සඳහා ඔවුන්ගෙන් ප්‍රකාශ සටහන් කර ගැනීම සඳහා ඔවුන්ගෙන් ප්‍රකාශ සටහන් කර ගැනීම සඳහා ඔවුන්ගෙන් ප්‍රකාශ සටහන් කර ගැනීම සඳහා අපරාධ පරීක්ෂණ දෙපාර්තමේන්තුවට කැඳවා ඇති බව රහස් පොලිසිය පවසයි.",
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ වත්මන් ආර්ථික අර්බුදයට වගකිව යුතු පුද්ගලයන්ට එරෙහිව ගොනු කර ඇති මූලික අයිතිවාසිකම් පෙත්සමක සම පෙත්සම්කරුවෙක් ද බොලිංය. වර්තමානයේ ජනප්‍රිය පිහිනුම් පුහුණුකරු වන බොලින් විසින් ගොනු කරන ලද පෙත්සමේ වගඋත්තරකරුවන් 13 දෙනා අතරට ජනාධිපති රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ ද ඇතුළත් වේ."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ජූලියන් බොලිං",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "CID",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "අද",
          "label": "DATE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "CID",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "බොලිං",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "9 ජූලි",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "එෆ්ආර්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "12",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ජූලියන් බොලිං",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජොනතන් මාර්ටෙන්ස්ටින්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "පොලිස් අපරාධ පරීක්ෂණ දෙපාර්තමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "CID",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "9 ජූලි",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "CID Bolling සහ Martenstyn",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "CID",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "9 ජූලි",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "13",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "බොලිං",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "ஜூலியன் பொலிங் இன்று சிஐடிக்கு சம்மன் அனுப்பியுள்ளார்",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "ஜூலை 9 ஆம் தேதி ஜனாதிபதியின் இல்லத்தின் மீது நடத்தப்பட்ட தாக்குதல் தொடர்பாக போலிங் மற்றும் மற்றொருவரிடமிருந்து சிஐடி வாக்குமூலம் பெறுகிறது",
        "போல்லிங் ஜனாதிபதி மற்றும் 12 பேருக்கு எதிராக தாக்கல் செய்யப்பட்ட FR இன் இணை மனுதாரர் ஆவார்",
        "இலங்கையின் முன்னாள் நீச்சல் சம்பியன் ஜூலியன் பொலிங் மற்றும் தொழிலதிபர் ஜொனாதன் மார்டென்ஸ்டின் ஆகியோரை பொலிஸ் குற்றப் புலனாய்வு திணைக்களத்தில் (CID) இன்று ஆஜராகுமாறு அழைப்பாணை விடுக்கப்பட்டுள்ளது. ஜூலை 9ஆம் தேதி நடைபெற்ற போராட்டங்கள் தொடர்பாக இருவருக்கும் சம்மன் அனுப்பப்பட்டுள்ளது.",
        "ஜூலை 9ஆம் திகதி ஜனாதிபதி ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்கவின் இல்லத்தில் தீவைக்கப்பட்ட சம்பவம் தொடர்பான எதிர்கால விசாரணைகளின் நோக்கத்திற்காக பொலிங் மற்றும் மார்டென்ஸ்டின் ஆகியோர் குற்றப் புலனாய்வுப் பிரிவிற்கு அழைக்கப்பட்டுள்ளனர்.",
        "இலங்கையின் தற்போதைய பொருளாதார நெருக்கடிக்கு காரணமான நபர்களுக்கு எதிராக தாக்கல் செய்யப்பட்ட அடிப்படை உரிமை மனுவின் இணை மனுதாரராகவும் போல்லிங் உள்ளார். தற்போது பிரபல நீச்சல் பயிற்சியாளரான பொலிங் தாக்கல் செய்த மனுவில் 13 பிரதிவாதிகளில் ஜனாதிபதி ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்கவும் அடங்குவார்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ஜூலியன் பொலிங்",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "சி.ஐ.டி",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "இன்று",
          "label": "DATE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "சி.ஐ.டி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "போல்லிங்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "9 ஜூலை",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "FR",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "12",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஜூலியன் பொலிங்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜொனாதன் மார்டென்ஸ்டைன்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "பொலிஸ் குற்றப் புலனாய்வு திணைக்களம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "சி.ஐ.டி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "9 ஜூலை",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "CID பொலிங் மற்றும் மார்டென்ஸ்டைன்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "சி.ஐ.டி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "9 ஜூலை",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "13",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "போல்லிங்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}