{
  "newspaper_id": "news-first-lk",
  "url": "https://www.newsfirst.lk/2022/08/01/indian-fishermen-rescued-by-sri-lankan-navy/",
  "time_ut": 1659332280,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Indian fishermen rescued by Sri Lankan Navy",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Indian fishermen rescued by Sri Lankan Navy",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); Sri Lanka Navy rescued 06 distressed Indian fishermen who drifted to the Sri Lankan waters north of Talaimannar, with their defunct trawler. The rescued Indian fishermen were provided humanitarian assistance and handed over to another Indian fishing trawler at the International Maritime Boundary Line (IMBL).",
        "The Indian trawler (Reg No. IND/TN/10/MM/ 1032) drifting in island waters north of Talaimannar, was spotted by SLNS Ranajaya patrolling in the sea area last morning (31st July 2022). Following a subsequent inspection, it was revealed that the Indian trawler had swept towards Sri Lankan waters as a result of a mechanical failure of its engine.",
        "Thus, the Navy promptly rescued the 06 distressed Indian fishermen aboard the defunct vessel and they were provided with food, drink, and other necessary humanitarian assistance.",
        "Further, SLNS Ranajaya escorted the distressed Indian fishing trawler and the 06 rescued Indian fishermen to the IMBL and handed over them to another Indian trawler, ensuring their safe return.",
        "Remaining committed to keep with obligations of the international conventions, the Sri Lanka Navy is constantly ready to provide necessary assistance to the naval and fishing communities in distress in Sri Lanka’s Search and Rescue Region.",
        "Colombo Chief Magistrate’s Court orders to produce Dhaniz Ali on Tuesday (2)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Indian",
          "label": "NORP"
        },
        {
          "text": "Sri Lankan Navy",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "News 1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka Navy",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "06",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Indian",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lankan",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "Talaimannar",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Indian",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Indian",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "the International Maritime Boundary Line",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "IMBL",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Indian",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Reg No. IND/TN/10/MM/",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "1032",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Talaimannar",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "SLNS Ranajaya",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the sea area",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "last morning",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "31st July 2022",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Indian",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lankan",
            "label": "LOC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Navy",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "06",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Indian",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "SLNS Ranajaya",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Indian",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "06",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Indian",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "IMBL",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Indian",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the Sri Lanka Navy",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka’s",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Magistrate",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Dhaniz Ali",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Tuesday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "2",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "ශ්‍රී ලංකා නාවික හමුදාව විසින් ඉන්දීය ධීවරයින් බේරා ගැනේ",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); ශ්‍රී ලංකා නාවික හමුදාව විසින් තලෙයිමන්නාරමට උතුරින් පිහිටි ශ්‍රී ලංකා මුහුදු ප්‍රදේශයට ගසාගෙන ගිය විපතට පත් ඉන්දීය ධීවරයින් 06 දෙනෙකු ඔවුන්ගේ අභාවප්‍රාප්ත ට්‍රෝලර් යාත්‍රාව සමඟ බේරා ගැනීමට සමත් විය. මුදාගත් ඉන්දීය ධීවරයින්ට මානුෂීය ආධාර ලබාදී ජාත්‍යන්තර සමුද්‍ර සීමාවේ (IMBL) තවත් ඉන්දීය ධීවර යාත්‍රාවකට භාර දෙන ලදී.",
        "තලෙයිමන්නාරමට උතුරින් පිහිටි දූපත් ජලයේ ගසාගෙන යන ඉන්දීය ට්‍රෝලර් යාත්‍රාව (Reg No. IND/TN/10/MM/ 1032) ඊයේ (2022 ජූලි 31) උදෑසන මුහුදු ප්‍රදේශයේ මුර සංචාරයේ යෙදී සිටි SLNS රණජය විසින් නිරීක්ෂණය කරන ලදී. ඉන් අනතුරුව සිදුකළ පරීක්ෂාවකදී අනාවරණ වී ඇත්තේ ඉන්දීය ට්‍රෝලර් යාත්‍රාව ශ්‍රී ලංකා මුහුදු තීරය දෙසට ගසාගෙන ගොස් ඇත්තේ එහි එන්ජිමේ යාන්ත්‍රික දෝෂයක් හේතුවෙන් බවයි.",
        "මේ අනුව, අභාවප්‍රාප්ත වූ යාත්‍රාවේ සිටි විපතට පත් ඉන්දීය ධීවරයින් 06 දෙනා නාවික හමුදාව විසින් කඩිනමින් බේරා ගත් අතර ඔවුන්ට අවශ්‍ය ආහාර පාන සහ අනෙකුත් මානුෂීය ආධාර ලබා දෙන ලදී.",
        "තවද, ශ්‍රී ලංකා නාවික නෞකා රණජය විසින් විපතට පත් ඉන්දීය ධීවර යාත්‍රාව සහ බේරාගත් ඉන්දීය ධීවරයින් 06 දෙනා IMBL වෙත රැගෙන ගොස් ඔවුන් ආරක්ෂිතව ආපසු පැමිණීම සහතික කරමින් වෙනත් ඉන්දීය ට්‍රෝලර් යාත්‍රාවකට භාර දෙන ලදී.",
        "ජාත්‍යන්තර සම්මුතිවලට අනුකූලව බැඳී සිටීමට කැපවී සිටින ශ්‍රී ලංකා නාවික හමුදාව ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ සෙවීම් සහ මුදාගැනීමේ කලාපයේ ආපදාවට ලක්ව සිටින නාවික සහ ධීවර ප්‍රජාවට අවශ්‍ය සහය ලබාදීමට නිරතුරුව සූදානමින් සිටී.",
        "ධනීස් අලි අඟහරුවාදා (2) ඉදිරිපත් කරන ලෙස කොළඹ ප්‍රධාන මහේස්ත්‍රාත් අධිකරණය නියෝග කරයි"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ඉන්දීය",
          "label": "NORP"
        },
        {
          "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකා නාවික හමුදාව",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "News 1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකා නාවික හමුදාව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "06",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දීය",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලාංකික",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "තලෙයිමන්නාරම",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දීය",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දීය",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජාත්‍යන්තර සමුද්‍ර මායිම් රේඛාව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "IMBL",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දීය",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ලියාපදිංචි අංකය IND/TN/10/MM/",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "1032",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "තලෙයිමන්නාරම",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකා නාවික නෞකා රණජය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "මුහුදු ප්රදේශය",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "පසුගිය උදෑසන",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "2022 ජූලි 31",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දීය",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලාංකික",
            "label": "LOC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "නාවික",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "06",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දීය",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකා නාවික නෞකා රණජය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දීය",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "06",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දීය",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "IMBL",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දීය",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකා නාවික හමුදාව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "මහේස්ත්රාත්වරයා",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ධනීස් අලි",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "අඟහරුවාදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "2",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "இலங்கை கடற்படையினரால் மீட்கப்பட்ட இந்திய மீனவர்கள்",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); தலைமன்னாருக்கு வடக்கே இலங்கை கடற்பரப்பிற்குச் சென்ற 06 இந்திய மீனவர்களை, செயலிழந்த இழுவை படகு மூலம் இலங்கை கடற்படையினர் மீட்டுள்ளனர். மீட்கப்பட்ட இந்திய மீனவர்களுக்கு மனிதாபிமான உதவிகள் வழங்கப்பட்டு, சர்வதேச கடல் எல்லைக் கோட்டில் (IMBL) மற்றொரு இந்திய மீன்பிடி இழுவை படகிடம் ஒப்படைக்கப்பட்டது.",
        "இந்திய இழுவை படகு (பதிவு எண். IND/TN/10/MM/ 1032) தலைமன்னாருக்கு வடக்கே தீவுக் கடற்பரப்பில் சென்றுகொண்டிருந்ததை, நேற்று காலை (31 ஜூலை 2022) கடல் பகுதியில் ரோந்து சென்ற SLNS ரணஜெயாவால் கண்டுபிடிக்கப்பட்டது. அதனைத் தொடர்ந்து மேற்கொள்ளப்பட்ட சோதனையில், இந்திய இழுவை படகு இயந்திரத்தில் ஏற்பட்ட இயந்திரக் கோளாறு காரணமாக இலங்கை கடற்பரப்பை நோக்கிச் சென்றமை தெரியவந்துள்ளது.",
        "இவ்வாறு, செயலிழந்த கப்பலில் இருந்த 06 இந்திய மீனவர்களை கடற்படையினர் உடனடியாக மீட்டதுடன், அவர்களுக்கு உணவு, பானம் மற்றும் தேவையான மனிதாபிமான உதவிகள் வழங்கப்பட்டன.",
        "மேலும், SLNS ரணஜய, பாதிக்கப்பட்ட இந்திய மீன்பிடி இழுவை படகு மற்றும் மீட்கப்பட்ட 06 இந்திய மீனவர்களை IMBL க்கு அழைத்துச் சென்று மற்றொரு இந்திய இழுவை படகிடம் ஒப்படைத்து, அவர்கள் பாதுகாப்பாக திரும்புவதை உறுதி செய்தது.",
        "சர்வதேச உடன்படிக்கைகளின் கடமைகளை கடைப்பிடிப்பதில் உறுதியாக இருக்கும் இலங்கை கடற்படை, இலங்கையின் தேடுதல் மற்றும் மீட்புப் பிராந்தியத்தில் ஆபத்தில் உள்ள கடற்படை மற்றும் மீனவ சமூகங்களுக்கு தேவையான உதவிகளை வழங்கத் தயாராக உள்ளது.",
        "தனிஸ் அலியை செவ்வாய்க்கிழமை (2) ஆஜர்படுத்துமாறு கொழும்பு பிரதான நீதவான் நீதிமன்றம் உத்தரவு"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "இந்தியன்",
          "label": "NORP"
        },
        {
          "text": "இலங்கை கடற்படை",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "News 1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை கடற்படை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "06",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்தியன்",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "தலைமன்னார்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்தியன்",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்தியன்",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "சர்வதேச கடல் எல்லைக் கோடு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "IMBL",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இந்தியன்",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "பதிவு எண். IND/TN/10/MM/",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "1032",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "தலைமன்னார்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "SLNS ரணஜய",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "கடல் பகுதி",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "கடைசி காலை",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "31 ஜூலை 2022",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்தியன்",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "LOC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "கடற்படை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "06",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்தியன்",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "SLNS ரணஜய",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்தியன்",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "06",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்தியன்",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "IMBL",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்தியன்",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை கடற்படை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கையின்",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "மாஜிஸ்திரேட்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "தனிஸ் அலி",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "செவ்வாய்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "2",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}