{
  "newspaper_id": "news-first-lk",
  "url": "https://www.newsfirst.lk/2022/07/19/sri-lanka-crisis-india-calls-all-party-meet-on-tuesday-19/",
  "time_ut": 1658221800,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Sri Lanka crisis: India calls all-party meet on Tuesday (19)",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Sri Lanka crisis: India calls all-party meet on Tuesday (19)",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); As Sri Lanka continues to reel under a political and economic crisis, the Indian government has decided to hold an all-party meeting Tuesday (19) to discuss the situation in the neighbouring country.",
        "Parliamentary Affairs Minister Pralhad Joshi Sunday said that Finance Minister Nirmala Sitharaman and External Affairs Minister S Jaishankar will, during the all-party meeting, brief leaders of various political parties on the Sri Lankan crisis.",
        "Meanwhile, at a meeting of various parties convened ahead of the monsoon session of Parliament, Tamil Nadu-based Dravida Munnetra Kazhagam (DMK) and All India Anna Dravida Munnetra Kazhagam (AIADMK) demanded that India intervene in the crisis plaguing Sri Lanka.",
        "Both DMK and AIADMK raised the Sri Lankan issue, especially the condition of the country’s Tamil population.",
        "Speaking to the media following the meeting, DMK leader T R Baalu and AIADMK leader M Thambidurai reiterated the demand of their respective parties.",
        "Citing an office memorandum dated July 16, a senior government official said that the briefing by the finance and external affairs ministries has been scheduled for the evening of July 19, the second day of the monsoon session of Parliament, news agency PTI reported.",
        "The briefing will be attended by the floor leaders of various political parties, the official added.",
        "India has assured Sri Lanka that it will continue to support democracy, stability and economic recovery in the country, which is at a crucial juncture, amid the unprecedented political crisis and economic turmoil.",
        "The assurance was given to Sri Lankan Parliament Speaker Mahinda Yapa Abeywardena by India’s High Commissioner Gopal Baglay when he called on the Sri Lankan leader on Saturday.",
        "The meeting took place a day after Speaker Abeywardena accepted the resignation of President Gotabaya Rajapaksa.",
        "Sri Lanka crisis: India calls all-party meet on Tuesday (19)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Sri Lanka",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "India",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "Tuesday",
          "label": "DATE"
        },
        {
          "text": "19",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "News 1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Indian",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Tuesday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "19",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Pralhad Joshi",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sunday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Finance",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Nirmala Sitharaman",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "S Jaishankar",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lankan",
            "label": "LOC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Tamil Nadu",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Dravida Munnetra Kazhagam",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "DMK",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "All India Anna Dravida Munnetra Kazhagam",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "AIADMK",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "India",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "DMK",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "AIADMK",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lankan",
            "label": "LOC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "DMK",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "AIADMK",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "M Thambidurai",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "July 16",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the evening of July 19",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "PTI",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "India",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lankan Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Mahinda Yapa Abeywardena",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "India",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Gopal Baglay",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lankan",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "Saturday",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "a day",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Abeywardena",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Gotabaya Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "India",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Tuesday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "19",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ අර්බුදය: ඉන්දියාව අඟහරුවාදා (19) සර්ව පාක්ෂික රැස්වීමක් කැඳවයි",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); ශ්‍රී ලංකාව දිගින් දිගටම දේශපාලන හා ආර්ථික අර්බුදයක ගිලී සිටින හෙයින් අසල්වැසි රටේ තත්ත්වය පිළිබඳව සාකච්ඡා කිරීම සඳහා අඟහරුවාදා (19) සර්ව පාක්ෂික රැස්වීමක් පැවැත්වීමට ඉන්දීය රජය තීරණය කර තිබේ.",
        "මුදල් අමාත්‍ය නිර්මලා සීතාරාමන් සහ විදේශ කටයුතු අමාත්‍ය එස් ජයශංකර් යන මහත්වරුන් සර්ව පාක්ෂික රැස්වීමේදී ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ අර්බුදය පිළිබඳව විවිධ දේශපාලන පක්ෂ නායකයින් දැනුවත් කරනු ඇති බව පාර්ලිමේන්තු කටයුතු අමාත්‍ය ප්‍රහද් ජෝෂි ඉරිදා ප්‍රකාශ කළේය.",
        "මේ අතර, පාර්ලිමේන්තුවේ මෝසම් සැසිවාරයට පෙර කැඳවා තිබූ විවිධ පක්ෂවල රැස්වීමකදී, තමිල්නාඩුව පදනම් කරගත් ද්‍රවිඩ මුන්නේත්‍ර කසාගම් (ඩීඑම්කේ) සහ සමස්ත ඉන්දීය අන්නා ද්‍රවිඩ මුන්නේත්‍ර කසාගම් (ඒඅයිඒඩීඑම්කේ) ශ්‍රී ලංකාව පීඩාවට පත් කර ඇති අර්බුදයට ඉන්දියාව මැදිහත් වන ලෙස ඉල්ලා සිටියේය.",
        "ඩීඑම්කේ සහ ඒඩීඑම්කේ යන දෙකම ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ ප්‍රශ්නය, විශේෂයෙන් රටේ දෙමළ ජනගහනයේ තත්වය මතු කළහ.",
        "රැස්වීමෙන් අනතුරුව මාධ්‍ය වෙත අදහස් දක්වමින් ඩීඑම්කේ නායක ටී ආර් බාලු සහ ඒඅයිඩීඑම්කේ නායක එම් තම්බිදුරෙයි තම පක්ෂවල ඉල්ලීම නැවත අවධාරණය කළහ.",
        "ජුලි 16 දිනැති කාර්යාල සංදේශයක් උපුටා දක්වමින් රජයේ ජ්‍යෙෂ්ඨ නිලධාරියෙකු පැවසුවේ මුදල් හා විදේශ කටයුතු අමාත්‍යාංශ විසින් දැනුවත් කිරීම පාර්ලිමේන්තුවේ මෝසම් සැසියේ දෙවන දිනය වන ජූලි 19 සවස පැවැත්වීමට සැලසුම් කර ඇති බවයි.",
        "මෙම දැනුවත් කිරීම සඳහා විවිධ දේශපාලන පක්ෂ නායකයින් සහභාගී වීමට නියමිත බව එම නිලධාරියා වැඩිදුරටත් පැවසීය.",
        "පෙර නොවූ විරූ දේශපාලන අර්බුද සහ ආර්ථික ව්‍යාකූලත්වය මධ්‍යයේ තීරණාත්මක සන්ධිස්ථානයකට පැමිණ සිටින ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ ප්‍රජාතන්ත්‍රවාදය, ස්ථාවරත්වය සහ ආර්ථික ප්‍රකෘතිය සඳහා අඛණ්ඩව සහාය දෙන බවට ඉන්දියාව සහතික වී තිබේ.",
        "ඉන්දීය මහ කොමසාරිස් ගෝපාල් බග්ලේ මහතා ශ්‍රී ලංකා පාර්ලිමේන්තුවේ කථානායක මහින්ද යාපා අබේවර්ධන මහතා සෙනසුරාදා ශ්‍රී ලංකා නායකයා හමුවූ අවස්ථාවේදී මෙම සහතිකය ලබා දුන්නේය.",
        "ජනාධිපති ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂගේ ඉල්ලා අස්වීම කථානායක අබේවර්ධන විසින් පිළිගෙන දිනකට පසුව මෙම හමුව සිදු විය.",
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ අර්බුදය: ඉන්දියාව අඟහරුවාදා (19) සර්ව පාක්ෂික රැස්වීමක් කැඳවයි"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "ඉන්දියාව",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "අඟහරුවාදා",
          "label": "DATE"
        },
        {
          "text": "19",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "News 1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දීය",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "අඟහරුවාදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "19",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ප්‍රහද් ජෝෂි",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉරිදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මූල්ය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "නිර්මලා සීතාරාමන්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "එස් ජයශංකර්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලාංකික",
            "label": "LOC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "තමිල්නාඩුව",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ද්‍රවිඩ මුන්නේත්‍ර කසාගම්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඩී.එම්.කේ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "සමස්ත ඉන්දීය අන්නා ද්‍රවිඩ මුන්නේත්‍ර කසාගම්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඒ.අයි.ඒ.ඩී.එම්.කේ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ඩී.එම්.කේ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඒ.අයි.ඒ.ඩී.එම්.කේ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලාංකික",
            "label": "LOC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ඩී.එම්.කේ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඒ.අයි.ඒ.ඩී.එම්.කේ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "එම් තම්බිදුරෙයි",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ජූලි 16",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජූලි 19 සවස",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "පී.ටී.අයි",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකා පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "මහින්ද යාපා අබේවර්ධන",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගෝපාල් බග්ලේ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලාංකික",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "සෙනසුරාදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "දවසක්",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "අබේවර්ධන ය",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "අඟහරුවාදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "19",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "இலங்கை நெருக்கடி: செவ்வாய்க்கிழமை (19) அனைத்துக் கட்சிக் கூட்டத்திற்கு இந்தியா அழைப்பு",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); இலங்கை தொடர்ந்து அரசியல் மற்றும் பொருளாதார நெருக்கடியில் சிக்கித் தவித்து வரும் நிலையில், அண்டை நாட்டின் நிலைமை குறித்து ஆலோசிக்க அனைத்துக் கட்சிக் கூட்டத்தை செவ்வாய்கிழமை (19) நடத்த இந்திய அரசு முடிவு செய்துள்ளது.",
        "அனைத்துக் கட்சிக் கூட்டத்தின் போது, ​​நிதியமைச்சர் நிர்மலா சீதாராமன் மற்றும் வெளியுறவுத் துறை அமைச்சர் ஜெய்சங்கர் ஆகியோர் இலங்கை நெருக்கடி குறித்து பல்வேறு அரசியல் கட்சித் தலைவர்களுக்கு விளக்கமளிப்பார்கள் என்று நாடாளுமன்ற விவகார அமைச்சர் பிரகலாத் ஜோஷி ஞாயிற்றுக்கிழமை தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "இதற்கிடையில், நாடாளுமன்ற மழைக்கால கூட்டத் தொடருக்கு முன்னதாக கூட்டப்பட்ட பல்வேறு கட்சிகளின் கூட்டத்தில், தமிழகத்தைச் சேர்ந்த திராவிட முன்னேற்றக் கழகமும், அனைத்திந்திய அண்ணா திராவிட முன்னேற்றக் கழகமும் (அதிமுக) இலங்கையில் நிலவும் நெருக்கடியில் இந்தியா தலையிட வேண்டும் என்று கோரின.",
        "திமுகவும், அதிமுகவும் இலங்கைப் பிரச்சினையை, குறிப்பாக நாட்டின் தமிழ் மக்களின் நிலைமையை எழுப்பின.",
        "இதனைத் தொடர்ந்து செய்தியாளர்களிடம் பேசிய திமுக தலைவர் டிஆர் பாலு, அதிமுக தலைவர் தம்பிதுரை ஆகியோர் தங்கள் கட்சிகளின் கோரிக்கையை வலியுறுத்தினர்.",
        "ஜூலை 16 தேதியிட்ட அலுவலக குறிப்பாணையை மேற்கோள் காட்டி, ஒரு மூத்த அரசாங்க அதிகாரி, நிதி மற்றும் வெளியுறவு அமைச்சகங்களின் விளக்கம், ஜூலை 19 மாலை, பாராளுமன்ற மழைக்கால கூட்டத் தொடரின் இரண்டாவது நாளுக்கு திட்டமிடப்பட்டுள்ளது என்று செய்தி நிறுவனம் PTI தெரிவித்துள்ளது.",
        "இந்த மாநாட்டில் பல்வேறு அரசியல் கட்சிகளின் தலைவர்கள் கலந்து கொள்வார்கள் என்று அந்த அதிகாரி மேலும் கூறினார்.",
        "முன்னெப்போதும் இல்லாத அரசியல் நெருக்கடி மற்றும் பொருளாதாரக் குழப்பங்களுக்கு மத்தியில், ஒரு முக்கியமான கட்டத்தில் இருக்கும் நாட்டில் ஜனநாயகம், ஸ்திரத்தன்மை மற்றும் பொருளாதார மீட்சிக்கு தொடர்ந்து ஆதரவளிப்பதாக இந்தியா உறுதியளித்துள்ளது.",
        "இலங்கை நாடாளுமன்ற சபாநாயகர் மகிந்த யாப்பா அபேவர்தனவை, இந்திய உயர்ஸ்தானிகர் கோபால் பாக்லே, இலங்கைத் தலைவரை சனிக்கிழமை சந்தித்தபோது, ​​இந்த உறுதிமொழியை வழங்கினார்.",
        "ஜனாதிபதி கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ஷவின் இராஜினாமாவை சபாநாயகர் அபேவர்தன ஏற்றுக்கொண்ட ஒரு நாளின் பின்னரே இந்த சந்திப்பு இடம்பெற்றுள்ளது.",
        "இலங்கை நெருக்கடி: செவ்வாய்க்கிழமை (19) அனைத்துக் கட்சிக் கூட்டத்திற்கு இந்தியா அழைப்பு"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "இலங்கை",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "இந்தியா",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "செவ்வாய்",
          "label": "DATE"
        },
        {
          "text": "19",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "News 1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்தியன்",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "செவ்வாய்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "19",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பிரகலாத் ஜோஷி",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஞாயிற்றுக்கிழமை",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "நிதி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "நிர்மலா சீதாராமன்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "எஸ் ஜெய்சங்கர்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "LOC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "தமிழ்நாடு",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "திராவிட முன்னேற்றக் கழகம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "தி.மு.க",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "அனைத்திந்திய அண்ணா திராவிட முன்னேற்றக் கழகம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "அதிமுக",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்தியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "தி.மு.க",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "அதிமுக",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "LOC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "தி.மு.க",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "அதிமுக",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "எம் தம்பிதுரை",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஜூலை 16",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜூலை 19 மாலை",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "PTI",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "இந்தியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "மஹிந்த யாப்பா அபேவர்தன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்தியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "கோபால் பாக்லே",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "சனிக்கிழமை",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஒரு நாள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "அபேவர்தன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்தியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "செவ்வாய்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "19",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}