{
  "newspaper_id": "ada-derana-lk",
  "url": "http://www.adaderana.lk/news/84762/bill-to-trim-presidents-powers-likely-to-become-law-soon-ali-sabry",
  "time_ut": 1662363660,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Bill to trim President’s powers likely to become law soon - Ali Sabry",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Bill to trim President’s powers likely to become law soon - Ali Sabry",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "(Reuters) - Sri Lanka’s Foreign Minister Ali Sabry said on Monday a constitutional amendment bill trimming presidential powers is expected to become law in a couple of weeks.",
        "“The new amendment will reduce presidential powers and bring back participatory governance. Sri Lanka is also in the process of drafting out a new anti-terror law that will be in line with international best practices,” Sabry told reporters at the foreign ministry.",
        "The bill is yet to be voted on in parliament. It requires a two-third majority in the house to become law."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Bill",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "Ali Sabry",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Reuters) -",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ali Sabry",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Monday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "a couple of weeks",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sabry",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "two-third",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "ජනාධිපතිගේ බලතල කප්පාදු කිරීමේ පනත් කෙටුම්පත ළඟදීම නීතියක් - අලි සබ්රි",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "(රොයිටර්) - ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ විදේශ අමාත්‍ය අලි සබ්රි සඳුදා ප්‍රකාශ කළේ ජනාධිපති බලතල කප්පාදු කරන ව්‍යවස්ථා සංශෝධන පනත් කෙටුම්පත සති දෙකකින් නීතියක් බවට පත්වනු ඇතැයි අපේක්ෂා කරන බවයි.",
        "“නව සංශෝධනය මගින් ජනාධිපති බලතල අඩු කර, සහභාගීත්ව පාලනය නැවත ගෙන එනු ඇත. ජාත්‍යන්තර හොඳම භාවිතයන්ට අනුකූල වන නව ත්‍රස්ත-විරෝධී නීතියක් කෙටුම්පත් කිරීමේ ක්‍රියාවලියක ශ්‍රී ලංකාව ද කටයුතු කරමින් සිටී, ”සබ්රි විදේශ අමාත්‍යාංශයේ වාර්තාකරුවන්ට පැවසීය.",
        "පනත් කෙටුම්පත තවමත් පාර්ලිමේන්තුවේ ඡන්ද විමසීමට නියමිතයි. නීතියක් බවට පත්වීමට නිවසේ තුනෙන් දෙකක බහුතරයක් අවශ්‍ය වේ."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "බිල්පත්",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "අලි සබ්රි",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "රොයිටර්) -",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "අලි සබ්රි",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "සඳුදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "සති කිහිපයක්",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "සබ්රි",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "තුනෙන් දෙකක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "ஜனாதிபதியின் அதிகாரங்களை குறைக்கும் மசோதா விரைவில் சட்டமாக மாறும் - அலி சப்ரி",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "(ராய்ட்டர்ஸ்) - இலங்கையின் வெளியுறவு அமைச்சர் அலி சப்ரி திங்களன்று ஜனாதிபதியின் அதிகாரங்களைக் குறைக்கும் அரசியலமைப்புத் திருத்தச் சட்டமூலம் ஓரிரு வாரங்களில் சட்டமாகும் என எதிர்பார்க்கப்படுகிறது.",
        "“புதிய திருத்தம் ஜனாதிபதியின் அதிகாரங்களைக் குறைத்து மீண்டும் பங்கேற்பு ஆட்சியைக் கொண்டுவரும். சர்வதேச சிறந்த நடைமுறைகளுக்கு இணங்க புதிய பயங்கரவாத எதிர்ப்புச் சட்டத்தை உருவாக்கும் பணியில் இலங்கையும் ஈடுபட்டுள்ளது,” என்று வெளியுறவு அமைச்சகத்தில் செய்தியாளர்களிடம் சப்ரி கூறினார்.",
        "இந்த மசோதா இன்னும் நாடாளுமன்றத்தில் வாக்கெடுப்பு நடத்தப்பட உள்ளது. அது சட்டமாக்குவதற்கு வீட்டில் மூன்றில் இரண்டு பங்கு பெரும்பான்மை தேவை."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ர சி து",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "அலி சப்ரி",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ராய்ட்டர்ஸ்) -",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "அலி சப்ரி",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "திங்கட்கிழமை",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இரண்டு வாரங்கள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சப்ரி",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "மூன்றில் இரண்டு பங்கு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}