{
  "newspaper_id": "lankadeepa-lk",
  "url": "https://www.lankadeepa.lk/news/‘‘රට-කරන්න-බැරි-නම්-ඉල්ලා-අස්-වෙන්න‘‘/101-591781",
  "time_ut": 1622730576,
  "original_lang": "si",
  "original_title": "‘‘රට කරන්න බැරි නම් ඉල්ලා අස් වෙන්න‘‘",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "\"Resign if you can't do it for the country\"",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "UNP General Secretary Palitha Range Bandara says that if it is not possible to control the epidemic without childish acts like \"Gazette\" to scare the health workers who know very well that saving people's lives is an essential service, they should resign.",
        "Mr. Range Bandara said that the people are being oppressed by Gotabaya during the Anuradhapura era and the current government is also oppressing the people.",
        "\"After King Sirisangabo, the most unlucky king in this country in the Anuradhapura period is King Gotabhaya. During the period of King Gotabhaya, there were famines and epidemics in the country. Injustice reigned. An era of unrighteous rule was born. Corruption spread. And people's minds were corrupted. The country was in a state of confusion. According to the order to bring the head of King Sirisangabo, many people started killing each other and bringing the heads. They tried to earn money by doing so. In the Gotabaya era of history, we also faced such a confused era,\" UNP General Secretary Palitha Range addressed the media through video technology. Mr. Bandara said."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "UNP",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Palitha Range",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Bandara",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Gazette",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Range Bandara",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Gotabaya",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "After King Sirisangabo",
            "label": "WORK_OF_ART"
          },
          {
            "text": "King Gotabhaya",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "King Gotabhaya",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "King Sirisangabo",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Gotabaya",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "UNP",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Palitha Range",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Bandara",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "‘‘රට කරන්න බැරි නම් ඉල්ලා අස් වෙන්න‘‘",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "ජනතාවගේ ජීවිත රැක ගැනීම අත්‍යවශ්‍ය සේවයක් බව හොඳින්ම දැන කටයුතු කරන සෞඛ්‍ය සේවකයන් බිය වැද්දීම සඳහා \"ගැසට්\" ගැසී⁣ම වැනි බොළඳ ක්‍රියා නොකර වසංගතය පාලනය කරන්නට බැරි නම් ඉල්ලා අස් වෙන්නැයි එක්සත් ජාතික පක්ෂ මහා ලේකම් පාලිත රංගේ බණ්ඩාර මහතා පවසයි.",
        "අනුරාධපුර යුගයේ ගෝඨාභය රජ කාලය මෙන්ම වර්තමාන පාලනය ද ජනතාව පීඩාවට පත් කරමින් සිටින බව කී රංගේ බණ්ඩාර මහතා මෙි අවස්ථාවේ රට ගොඩනගන්නට ලෝකය පිළිගත් පළපුරුදු නායකයා සිටින්නේ එක්සත් ජාතික පක්ෂයේ පමණක් බවද සඳහන් කළේය.",
        "\"සිරිසඟබෝ රජුගෙන් අනතුරුව අනුරාධපුර යුගයේ මේ රට පත් වූ අභාග්‍යසම්පන්නම රජු වන්නේ ගෝඨාභය රජතුමායි. මේ ගෝඨාභය රජුගේ කාලපරිච්ඡේදය තුළ රටේ දුර්භික්ෂ හා වසංගත ඇති වුණා. අසාධාරණය රජ වුණා. අධාර්මික පාලන යුගයක් ඇතිවුණා. දූෂණය ඉහවහා ගියා. එමෙන්ම මිනිසුන්ගේ සිත් දූෂණය වුණා. රටේ ව්‍යාකූල තත්ත්වයක් ඇති වුණා. සිරිසඟබෝ රජුගේ හිස ගෙනත් දෙන්නැයි කළ නියෝගය අනුව නොයෙක් අය එකිනෙකා මරා හිස් ගෙනෙන්නට පටන් ගත්තා. එමගින් මුදල් උපයන්න උත්සහ කළා. ඉතිහාසයේ ගෝඨාභය යුගයේ අපට මුහුණ දෙන්නට වූයේත් මෙවැනි ව්‍යාකූල යුගයකටයි\"යනුවෙන්ද වීඩියෝ තාක්ෂණය ඔස්සේ මාධ්‍ය ඇමතූ එක්සත් ජාතික පක්ෂ මහ ලේකම් පාලිත රංගේ බණ්ඩාර මහතා කීය."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "එජාප",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාලිත රංගේ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "බණ්ඩාර ය",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගැසට්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "රංගේ බණ්ඩාර",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගෝඨාභය",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "සිරිසඟබෝ රජුගෙන් පසු",
            "label": "WORK_OF_ART"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගෝඨාභය රජතුමා",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගෝඨාභය රජතුමා",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "සිරිසඟබෝ රජතුමා",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගෝඨාභය",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "එජාප",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාලිත රංගේ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "බණ්ඩාර ය",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "\"நாட்டிற்கு செய்ய முடியாவிட்டால் பதவி விலகுங்கள்\"",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "மக்களின் உயிரைக் காப்பது இன்றியமையாத சேவை என்பதை நன்கு அறிந்த சுகாதார ஊழியர்களை பயமுறுத்தும் வர்த்தமானி போன்ற சிறுபிள்ளைத்தனமான செயற்பாடுகள் இன்றி தொற்றுநோயைக் கட்டுப்படுத்த முடியாவிட்டால் அவர்கள் பதவி விலக வேண்டும் என ஐக்கிய தேசியக் கட்சியின் பொதுச் செயலாளர் பாலித ரங்கே பண்டார தெரிவித்துள்ளார்.",
        "அநுராதபுர காலத்தில் கோட்டாபயவினால் மக்கள் ஒடுக்கப்பட்டு வருவதாகவும் தற்போதைய அரசாங்கமும் மக்களை ஒடுக்குவதாகவும் திரு.ரங்கே பண்டார தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "“சிறிசங்கபோ மன்னருக்குப் பிறகு, அனுராதபுர காலத்தில் இந்த நாட்டில் மிகவும் துரதிஷ்டசாலியான மன்னன் கோத்தபாய மன்னன், கோத்தபாய மன்னன் காலத்தில் நாட்டில் பஞ்சம், தொற்றுநோய்கள் ஏற்பட்டன. அநீதி ஆட்சி செய்தது. அநீதியான ஆட்சி யுகம் பிறந்தது. ஊழல் பரவியது. மேலும் மக்களின் மனங்கள் சிதைக்கப்பட்டன.நாடு குழப்பத்தில் இருந்தது.மன்னர் சிறிசங்கபோவின் தலையை கொண்டு வர வேண்டும் என்ற உத்தரவின்படி பலர் ஒருவரையொருவர் கொன்று தலைகளை கொண்டு வர ஆரம்பித்தனர்.அதன் மூலம் பணம் சம்பாதிக்க முயன்றனர்.கோட்டாபயவில் வரலாற்றின் சகாப்தத்தில், அத்தகைய குழப்பமான யுகத்தை நாமும் எதிர்கொண்டோம்\" என ஐக்கிய தேசியக் கட்சியின் பொதுச் செயலாளர் பாலித ரங்கே காணொளி தொழில்நுட்பத்தின் ஊடாக ஊடகங்களுக்கு உரையாற்றினார். திரு. பண்டார தெரிவித்தார்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ஐ.தே.க",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாலித ரேஞ்ச்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "பண்டார",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "அரசிதழ்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ரங்கே பண்டார",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "கோட்டாபய",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "சிறிசங்கபோ மன்னருக்குப் பிறகு",
            "label": "WORK_OF_ART"
          },
          {
            "text": "மன்னன் கோத்தபாய",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "மன்னன் கோத்தபாய",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "மன்னர் சிரிசங்கபோ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "கோட்டாபய",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஐ.தே.க",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாலித ரேஞ்ச்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "பண்டார",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}