{
  "newspaper_id": "daily-ft-lk",
  "url": "https://www.ft.lk/news/Sri-Lanka-celebrates-55thASEAN-Day/56-738502",
  "time_ut": 1660088015,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Sri Lanka celebrates 55th ASEAN Day",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Sri Lanka celebrates 55th ASEAN Day",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "Secretary to the Ministry of Foreign Affairs Aruni Wijewardane was the Chief Guest at the 55th ASEAN Day on 8 August at the Indonesian Embassy in Colombo. The event was hosted by Ambassador of Indonesia Dewi Gustina Tobing and the Heads of Mission of the four other ASEAN Member States in Colombo, High Commissioner of Malaysia Tan Yang Thai, Ambassador of Myanmar Han Thu, Ambassador of Thailand Poj Harnpol, and Ambassador of Viet Nam Ho Thi Thanh Truc.",
        "Foreign Secretary Wijewardane in her remarks, recalled the strong ties between Sri Lanka and Southeast Asian countries which date back to ancient times when Sri Lanka was known worldwide as a major maritime economic hub. In continuing these connections which are centuries old, today there are many opportunities for Sri Lanka to partner with successful ASEAN economies.",
        "The Foreign Secretary highlighted the recent visit of Foreign Minister Ali Sabry to Cambodia to attend the ASEAN Regional Forum where he engaged constructively with ASEAN Members, Observers and Dialogue Partners. She also referred to the ASEAN ACT – ‘Addressing Challenges Together’ as an apt theme as ASEAN works towards a sustainable future of revitalising economic activity, ensuring food, energy and climate security and addressing the regional security environment.",
        "Chief of Protocol Senarath Dissanayake and South East Asia Division Director General Satya Rodrigo of the Ministry of Foreign Affairs also attended the event which was followed by a reception."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Sri Lanka",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "55th",
          "label": "ORDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "ASEAN",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "the Ministry of Foreign Affairs",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Aruni Wijewardane",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "55th",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "8 August",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Indonesian Embassy in Colombo",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Indonesia",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Heads of Mission",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "four",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ASEAN",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Colombo",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Malaysia",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Tan Yang Thai",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Myanmar Han Thu",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Thailand",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Poj Harnpol",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Viet Nam",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Wijewardane",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Southeast Asian",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "centuries",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ASEAN",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Ali Sabry",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Cambodia",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the ASEAN Regional Forum",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ASEAN",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Observers and Dialogue Partners",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the ASEAN ACT – ‘Addressing Challenges Together’",
            "label": "LAW"
          },
          {
            "text": "ASEAN",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Protocol Senarath Dissanayake",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "South East Asia Division",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "Satya Rodrigo",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Ministry of Foreign Affairs",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "ශ්‍රී ලංකාව 55 වැනි ආසියාන් දිනය සමරයි",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "විදේශ කටයුතු අමාත්‍යාංශයේ ලේකම් අරුණි විජේවර්ධන මහත්මිය අගෝස්තු 8 වැනි දින කොළඹ ඉන්දුනීසියානු තානාපති කාර්යාලයේ පැවති 55 වැනි ආසියාන් දින උත්සවයේ ප්‍රධාන ආරාධිත අමුත්තා වූවාය. මෙම අවස්ථාවට සත්කාරකත්වය සපයනු ලැබුවේ ඉන්දුනීසියාවේ තානාපති ඩිවි ගුස්ටිනා ටොබිං සහ කොළඹ අනෙකුත් ආසියාන් සාමාජික රටවල් හතරේ දූත මණ්ඩල ප්‍රධානීන්, මැලේසියාවේ මහ කොමසාරිස් ටැන් යැං තායි, මියන්මාර තානාපති හන් තු, තායිලන්ත තානාපති පොජ් හර්න්පෝල් සහ වියට් තානාපති විසිනි. Nam Ho Thi Thanh Truc.",
        "විදේශ ලේකම් විජේවර්ධන සිය ප්‍රකාශයේ දී ශ්‍රී ලංකාව සහ අග්නිදිග ආසියාතික රටවල් අතර ශ්‍රී ලංකාව ප්‍රධාන සමුද්‍රීය ආර්ථික මධ්‍යස්ථානයක් ලෙස ලොව පුරා ප්‍රචලිත වූ පුරාණ කාලයේ සිට පැවත එන ශක්තිමත් සබඳතා සිහිපත් කළාය. ශතවර්ෂ ගණනාවක් පැරණි මෙම සබඳතා අඛණ්ඩව පවත්වාගෙන යාමේදී අද ශ්‍රී ලංකාවට සාර්ථක ආසියාන් ආර්ථිකයන් සමඟ හවුල් වීමට බොහෝ අවස්ථාවන් තිබේ.",
        "ආසියාන් කලාපීය සංසදයට සහභාගී වීම සඳහා විදේශ අමාත්‍ය අලි සබ්රි මෑතකදී කාම්බෝජයට ගිය සංචාරය විදේශ ලේකම්වරයා අවධාරණය කළේය. ආර්ථික ක්‍රියාකාරකම් පුනර්ජීවනය කිරීම, ආහාර, බලශක්ති සහ දේශගුණික ආරක්ෂාව සහතික කිරීම සහ කලාපීය ආරක්ෂක පරිසරය ආමන්ත්‍රණය කිරීමේ තිරසාර අනාගතයක් සඳහා ASEAN ක්‍රියා කරන බැවින් ඇය ASEAN ACT - ‘එකට අභියෝග ආමන්ත්‍රණය කිරීම’ උචිත තේමාවක් ලෙස සඳහන් කළාය.",
        "ප්‍රොටෝකෝල් ප්‍රධානී සෙනරත් දිසානායක සහ විදේශ කටයුතු අමාත්‍යාංශයේ අග්නිදිග ආසියානු අංශයේ අධ්‍යක්ෂ ජනරාල් සත්‍ය රොද්‍රිගෝ යන මහත්වරු ද මෙම අවස්ථාවට සහභාගී වූ අතර අනතුරුව පිළිගැනීමේ උත්සවයක් ද පැවැත්විණි."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "55 වැනි",
          "label": "ORDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "ආසියාන්",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "විදේශ කටයුතු අමාත්යාංශය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "අරුණි විජේවර්ධන",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "55 වැනි",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "8 අගෝස්තු",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "කොළඹ ඉන්දුනීසියානු තානාපති කාර්යාලය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දුනීසියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "දූත මණ්ඩල ප්‍රධානීන්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "හතර",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ආසියාන්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "කොළඹ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මැලේසියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ටැන් යැං තායි",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "මියන්මාර හන් තු",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "තායිලන්තය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Poj Harnpol",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "වියට්නාමය",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "විජේවර්ධන ය",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "අග්නිදිග ආසියානු",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "සියවස්",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ආසියාන්",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "අලි සබ්රි",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "කාම්බෝජය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ASEAN කලාපීය සංසදය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ආසියාන්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "නිරීක්ෂකයින් සහ සංවාද හවුල්කරුවන්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ආසියාන් පනත - 'එකට අභියෝග ආමන්ත්‍රණය කිරීම'",
            "label": "LAW"
          },
          {
            "text": "ආසියාන්",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ප්රොටෝකෝලය සෙනරත් දිසානායක",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "අග්නිදිග ආසියානු අංශය",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "සත්‍ය රුද්‍රිගු",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "විදේශ කටයුතු අමාත්යාංශය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "இலங்கை 55வது ஆசியான் தினத்தைக் கொண்டாடுகிறது",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "கொழும்பில் உள்ள இந்தோனேசிய தூதரகத்தில் ஆகஸ்ட் 8ஆம் தேதி நடைபெற்ற 55வது ஆசியான் தினத்தில் பிரதம அதிதியாக வெளிவிவகார அமைச்சின் செயலாளர் அருணி விஜேவர்தன கலந்து கொண்டார். இந்தோனேசியாவின் தூதுவர் Dewi Gustina Tobing மற்றும் கொழும்பில் உள்ள மற்ற நான்கு ASEAN உறுப்பு நாடுகளின் தூது தலைவர்கள், மலேசியாவின் உயர் ஸ்தானிகர் Tan Yang Thai, மியான்மர் தூதுவர் Han Thu, தாய்லாந்து தூதர் Poj Harnpol மற்றும் Viet நாட்டின் தூதர் ஆகியோர் இந்நிகழ்வை தொகுத்து வழங்கினர். நாம் ஹோ தி தான் ட்ரூக்.",
        "வெளிவிவகாரச் செயலாளர் விஜேவர்தன தனது கருத்துக்களில், இலங்கை மற்றும் தென்கிழக்காசிய நாடுகளுக்கிடையிலான வலுவான உறவுகளை நினைவு கூர்ந்தார், இது பண்டைய காலத்தில் இலங்கை ஒரு முக்கிய கடல்சார் பொருளாதார மையமாக உலகளவில் அறியப்பட்டது. பல நூற்றாண்டுகள் பழமையான இந்த இணைப்புகளை தொடர்வதில், இன்று வெற்றிகரமான ஆசியான் பொருளாதாரங்களுடன் பங்காளியாக இலங்கைக்கு பல வாய்ப்புகள் உள்ளன.",
        "வெளிவிவகார அமைச்சர் அலி சப்ரி அண்மையில் கம்போடியாவிற்கு வருகை தந்திருந்த ஆசியான் பிராந்திய மன்றத்தில் கலந்துகொள்வதற்காக அவர் ஆசியான் உறுப்பினர்கள், பார்வையாளர்கள் மற்றும் உரையாடல் பங்காளிகளுடன் ஆக்கப்பூர்வமாக ஈடுபட்டதை வெளிவிவகார செயலாளர் எடுத்துரைத்தார். ஆசியான் சட்டம் - 'ஒன்றாக சவால்களை சமாளித்தல்' ஒரு பொருத்தமான கருப்பொருளாக அவர் குறிப்பிட்டார், ஏனெனில் ஆசியான் பொருளாதார நடவடிக்கைகளை புத்துயிர் பெறுதல், உணவு, ஆற்றல் மற்றும் காலநிலை பாதுகாப்பை உறுதி செய்தல் மற்றும் பிராந்திய பாதுகாப்பு சூழலை நிவர்த்தி செய்வதற்கான நிலையான எதிர்காலத்தை நோக்கி செயல்படுகிறது.",
        "நெறிமுறைகளின் பிரதானி செனரத் திசாநாயக்க மற்றும் வெளிவிவகார அமைச்சின் தென்கிழக்கு ஆசியப் பிரிவு பணிப்பாளர் நாயகம் சத்யா ரொட்ரிகோ ஆகியோரும் கலந்துகொண்ட இந்நிகழ்வில் வரவேற்பு நிகழ்வு இடம்பெற்றது."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "இலங்கை",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "55வது",
          "label": "ORDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "ஆசியான்",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "வெளியுறவு அமைச்சகம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "அருணி விஜேவர்தன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "55வது",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "8 ஆகஸ்ட்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "கொழும்பில் உள்ள இந்தோனேசிய தூதரகம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்தோனேசியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "மிஷன் தலைவர்கள்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "நான்கு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆசியான்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "கொழும்பு",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "மலேசியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "டான் யாங் தாய்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "மியான்மர் ஹன் து",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "தாய்லாந்து",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "போஜ் ஹர்ன்போல்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "வியட்நாம்",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "விஜேவர்தன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "தென்கிழக்கு ஆசியர்",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "நூற்றாண்டுகள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆசியான்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "அலி சப்ரி",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "கம்போடியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆசியான் பிராந்திய மன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆசியான்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "பார்வையாளர்கள் மற்றும் உரையாடல் கூட்டாளர்கள்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆசியான் சட்டம் - 'ஒன்றாக சவால்களை எதிர்கொள்வது'",
            "label": "LAW"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆசியான்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "நெறிமுறை செனரத் திசாநாயக்க",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "தென்கிழக்கு ஆசிய பிரிவு",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "சத்யா ரோட்ரிகோ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "வெளியுறவு அமைச்சகம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}