{
  "newspaper_id": "lankadeepa-lk",
  "url": "https://www.lankadeepa.lk/latest_news/ඕමානයෙනුත්-ජනපතිට-පොරොන්දුවක්/1-615714",
  "time_ut": 1656679116,
  "original_lang": "si",
  "original_title": "ඕමානයෙනුත් ජනපතිට පොරොන්දුවක්",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "A promise to the President from Oman too",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "Oman Ambassador Ahmed Ali Saeed Al Rashdi told President Gotabaya Gotabaya Rajapaksa that he will support the strengthening of bilateral relations between the two countries in terms of fuel, gas, energy, employment and investment opportunities.",
        "He said this when he met the President at the Colombo Fort Presidential Palace today (1) in the morning.",
        "The Ambassador of Oman is scheduled to leave the island after completing his service and met the President to inform him of this.",
        "About 25,000 Sri Lankans are currently employed in Oman.",
        "The President also requested the Ambassador to assist in increasing employment opportunities in the field of training.",
        "The President appreciated Saeed Al-Rashd's support to Sri Lanka during his eight years in office and discussed the vast opportunities for trade and investment in Sri Lanka.",
        "Mr. Rushd told the President that he was scheduled to report to the Foreign Ministry of Oman and that he would continue to work to strengthen relations between the two countries.",
        "Chief of Staff to the President Anura Dissanayake was also present on the occasion."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Oman",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Oman",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ahmed Ali Saeed Al Rashdi",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Gotabaya Gotabaya",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "two",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the Colombo Fort Presidential Palace",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "1",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Oman",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "About 25,000",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lankans",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Oman",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "Saeed Al-Rashd's",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "his eight years",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Rushd",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Foreign Ministry of Oman",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "two",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Anura Dissanayake",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "ඕමානයෙනුත් ජනපතිට පොරොන්දුවක්",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "ඉන්ධන, ගෑස්, බලශක්ති, රැකියා සහ ආයෝජන අවස්ථා සම්බන්ධයෙන් දෙරට අතර ද්විපාර්ශ්වීය සබඳතා ශක්තිමත් කර ගැනීමට සහාය වන බව ඕමාන තානාපති අහමඩ් අලි සයීඩ් අල් රෂ්ඩි (Ahmed Ali Saeed Al Rashdi) මහතා ජනාධිපති ගෝඨාභය ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ මහතා හමුවේ පැවසීය.",
        "ඔහු මෙසේ පැවසුවේ ජනාධිපතිවරයා කොළඹ කොටුව ජනාධිපති මන්දිරයේදී අද (1) පෙරවරුවේ හමු වූ අවස්ථාවේදීය.",
        "ඕමාන්  තානාපතිවරයා සේවය අවසන් කර දිවයිනෙන් පිටව යෑමට නියමිත අතර ජනාධිපති වරයා හමුවූයේ ඒ පිළිබඳව දැනුම් දීමටය.",
        "ශ්‍රී ලාංකිකයෝ  25,000ක පමණ පිරිසක් මේ වනවිට ඕමානයේ රැකියාවන්හි නිරතව සිටිති.",
        "පුහුණු ක්ෂේත්‍රයේ රැකියා අවස්ථා වැඩිකර ගැනීමටද  සහාය වන ලෙස ජනාධිපතිවරයා  තානාපතිවරයාගෙන් ඉල්ලා සිටියේය.",
        "සයීඩ් අල් රෂ්ඩ් මහතාගේ වසර 08ක සේවා කාලයේදී  ශ්‍රී ලංකාවට ලබාදුන් සහාය ඇගයීමට ලක් කළ ජනාධිපතිවරයා  මෙරට වෙළෙඳ සහ ආයේජන අවස්ථා සඳහා ඇති පුළුල් අවකාශය පිළිබඳවද සාකච්ඡා කළේය.",
        "තමා ඕමාන විදේශ අමාත්‍යාංශයේ සේවයට වාර්තා කිරීමට නියමිත බවත්   දෙරට අතර සබඳතා ශක්තිමත් කරගැනීමට එහි සිටද කටයුතු කරන බවත්  රෂ්ඩ් මහතා ජනාධිපතිවරයා  සමග සඳහන් කළේය.",
        "මේ අවස්ථාවට  ජනාධිපති කාර්ය මණ්ඩල ප්‍රධානි අනුර දිසානායක මහතාද සහභාගී විය."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ඕමානය",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ඕමානය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "අහමඩ් අලි සයීඩ් අල් රෂ්ඩි",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගෝඨාභය ගෝඨාභය",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "දෙක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "කොළඹ කොටුව ජනාධිපති මන්දිරය",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "1",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ඕමානය",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "25,000 ක් පමණ වේ",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලාංකිකයන්",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඕමානය",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "සයීඩ් අල්-රෂ්ඩ්ගේ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඔහුගේ අට වසර",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "රෂ්ඩ්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඕමාන් විදේශ අමාත්‍යාංශය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "දෙක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "අනුර දිසානායක",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "ஓமானில் இருந்தும் ஜனாதிபதிக்கு ஒரு வாக்குறுதி",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "எரிபொருள், எரிவாயு, எரிசக்தி, வேலைவாய்ப்பு மற்றும் முதலீட்டு வாய்ப்புகள் போன்றவற்றில் இருதரப்பு உறவுகளை வலுப்படுத்துவதற்கு இரு நாடுகளும் ஆதரவளிக்கும் என்று ஓமன் ஜனாதிபதி அஹமட் அலி சயீத் அல் ரஷ்தி, ஓமன் ஜனாதிபதி அஹமட் அலி சயீத் அல் ரஷ்தி ஜனாதிபதி கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ஷவிடம் தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "இன்று (1) காலை கொழும்பு கோட்டையிலுள்ள ஜனாதிபதி மாளிகையில் ஜனாதிபதியுடனான சந்திப்பின் போதே அவர் இவ்வாறு தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "ஓமான் தூதுவர் தனது சேவையை முடித்துக்கொண்டு தீவை விட்டு வெளியேறத் திட்டமிட்டுள்ளதுடன், ஜனாதிபதியை சந்தித்து இதனைத் தெரிவிக்கவுள்ளார்.",
        "ஓமானில் தற்போது சுமார் 25,000 இலங்கையர்கள் பணிபுரிகின்றனர்.",
        "பயிற்சித் துறையில் தொழில் வாய்ப்புகளை அதிகரிப்பதற்கு உதவுமாறு ஜனாதிபதி தூதுவரிடம் கேட்டுக்கொண்டார்.",
        "திரு. சையத் அல் ரஷ்த் தனது 08 வருட சேவையின் போது இலங்கைக்கு வழங்கிய ஆதரவைப் பாராட்டிய ஜனாதிபதி, நாட்டில் வர்த்தகம் மற்றும் முதலீட்டு வாய்ப்புகளுக்கான பரந்த வாய்ப்புகள் குறித்தும் கலந்துரையாடினார்.",
        "ஓமானின் வெளிவிவகார அமைச்சுக்கு அறிக்கை அளிக்கத் திட்டமிட்டுள்ளதாகவும், இரு நாடுகளுக்கு இடையேயான உறவுகளை வலுப்படுத்த தொடர்ந்து பாடுபடுவதாகவும் திரு.ருஷ்ட் ஜனாதிபதியிடம் தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "இந்நிகழ்வில் ஜனாதிபதியின் பணிப்பாளர் பிரதானி அனுர திஸாநாயக்கவும் கலந்துகொண்டார்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ஓமன்",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ஓமன்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "அகமது அலி சயீத் அல் ரஷ்தி",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "கோட்டாபய கோட்டாபய",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இரண்டு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "கொழும்பு கோட்டை ஜனாதிபதி மாளிகை",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "1",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஓமன்",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "சுமார் 25,000",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கையர்கள்",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஓமன்",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "சயீத் அல்-ரஷ்தின்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "அவரது எட்டு ஆண்டுகள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ரஷ்ட்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஓமன் வெளியுறவு அமைச்சகம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இரண்டு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "அனுர திஸாநாயக்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}