{
  "newspaper_id": "economy-next-com",
  "url": "https://economynext.com/sri-lankas-runaway-ex-president-to-return-on-aug-24-25-cousin-98700/",
  "time_ut": 1660731720,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Sri Lanka’s runaway ex president to return on Aug 24, 25: cousin",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Sri Lanka’s runaway ex president to return on Aug 24, 25: cousin",
      "author": "Chanka Jayasinghe",
      "body_lines": [
        "ECONOMYNEXT – Sri Lanka former President Gotabaya Rajapaksa who fled the country in early July following a wave of protests will be returning to Sri Lanka on August 24 or 25, a family member and former diplomat said.",
        "Ex-Ambassador to Russia Udayanga Weeratunga, who is a cousin of the former president, told EconomyNext on Wednesday August 17 that Rajapaksa will return to Sri Lanka next week.",
        "“It is confirmed that the former President will be returning to the island on 24 or 25th of this month. If nothing changes, he will be here.",
        "“According to the constitution, he will receive protection and other facilities. I assume a house will be prepared for him here as well,” said Weeratunga.",
        "Former President Rajapaksa, who fled the country after protestors stormed his official residence in Colombo, is currently in Bangkok, Thailand. He arrived there on August 12 after a brief stay in Singapore.",
        "Rajapaksa resigned from the presidency after mass protests against the worst currency crisis in the history of the island’s intermediate regime central bank."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Sri Lanka’s",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "24",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "25",
          "label": "DATE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Gotabaya Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "early July",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "August 24 or 25",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Russia Udayanga Weeratunga",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "EconomyNext",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Wednesday August 17",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Rajapaksa",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "next week",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "24 or 25th of this month",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Weeratunga",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Colombo",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Bangkok",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Thailand",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "August 12",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Singapore",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "පැනගිය ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ හිටපු ජනාධිපතිවරයා අගෝස්තු 24, 25 යන දිනවල නැවත එයි: ඥාති සහෝදරයා",
      "author": "චංක ජයසිංහ",
      "body_lines": [
        "ECONOMYNEXT - ශ්‍රී ලංකාව විරෝධතා රැල්ලක් හේතුවෙන් ජූලි මස මුලදී රටින් පලා ගිය හිටපු ජනාධිපති ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ අගෝස්තු 24 හෝ 25 දින නැවත ශ්‍රී ලංකාවට පැමිණෙන බව පවුලේ සාමාජිකයෙකු සහ හිටපු රාජ්‍ය තාන්ත්‍රිකයෙකු පැවසීය.",
        "හිටපු ජනාධිපතිවරයාගේ ඥාති සොහොයුරෙකු වන රුසියාවේ හිටපු තානාපති උදයංග වීරතුංග අගෝස්තු 17 බදාදා EconomyNext වෙත පැවසුවේ රාජපක්ෂ ලබන සතියේ නැවත ශ්‍රී ලංකාවට පැමිණෙන බවයි.",
        "“හිටපු ජනාධිපතිවරයා මේ මස 24 හෝ 25 යන දිනයන්හිදී යළි දිවයිනට පැමිණෙන බව ස්ථිරයි. කිසිවක් වෙනස් නොවේ නම්, ඔහු මෙහි සිටිනු ඇත.",
        "“ආණ්ඩුක්‍රම ව්‍යවස්ථාව අනුව ඔහුට ආරක්ෂාව සහ අනෙකුත් පහසුකම් ලැබෙනවා. එයාටත් මෙහෙ ගෙයක් ලෑස්ති ​​කරයි කියලා මම හිතනවා” වීරතුංග කීවේය.",
        "කොළඹ පිහිටි ඔහුගේ නිල නිවසට විරෝධතාකරුවන් කඩා වැදීමෙන් පසු රටින් පලා ගිය හිටපු ජනාධිපති රාජපක්ෂ මේ වන විට තායිලන්තයේ බැංකොක් නුවර රැඳී සිටියි. ඔහු සිංගප්පූරුවේ කෙටි නවාතැනකින් පසු අගෝස්තු 12 වැනිදා එහි පැමිණියේය.",
        "දිවයිනේ අතරමැදි පාලන තන්ත්‍රයේ මහ බැංකු ඉතිහාසයේ දරුණුතම මුදල් අර්බුදයට එරෙහිව මහජන විරෝධතාවලින් පසු රාජපක්ෂ ජනාධිපති ධුරයෙන් ඉල්ලා අස්විය."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "24",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "25",
          "label": "DATE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජූලි මුල",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "අගෝස්තු 24 හෝ 25",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "රුසියාව උදයංග වීරතුංග",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "EconomyNext",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "අගෝස්තු 17 බදාදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඊළඟ සතිය",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "මේ මස 24 හෝ 25",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "වීරතුංග ය",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "කොළඹ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "බැංකොක්",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "තායිලන්තය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "අගෝස්තු 12",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "සිංගප්පූරුව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "ஓடிப்போன இலங்கையின் முன்னாள் அதிபர் ஆகஸ்ட் 24, 25ல் திரும்புவார்: உறவினர்",
      "author": "சங்க ஜெயசிங்க",
      "body_lines": [
        "பொருளாதாரம் - இலங்கையின் முன்னாள் ஜனாதிபதி கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ச எதிர்ப்பு அலைகளைத் தொடர்ந்து ஜூலை தொடக்கத்தில் நாட்டை விட்டு வெளியேறிய ஆகஸ்ட் 24 அல்லது 25 ஆம் தேதிகளில் இலங்கை திரும்புவார் என்று குடும்ப உறுப்பினரும் முன்னாள் இராஜதந்திரியும் தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "முன்னாள் ஜனாதிபதியின் உறவினரான ரஷ்யாவுக்கான முன்னாள் தூதுவர் உதயங்க வீரதுங்க, ராஜபக்ச அடுத்த வாரம் இலங்கை திரும்புவார் என எகனாமிநெக்ஸ்ட் புதன்கிழமை ஆகஸ்ட் 17 அன்று தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "“முன்னாள் ஜனாதிபதி இம்மாதம் 24 அல்லது 25ஆம் திகதி நாடு திரும்புவார் என்பது உறுதிப்படுத்தப்பட்டுள்ளது. எதுவும் மாறவில்லை என்றால், அவர் இங்கே இருப்பார்.",
        "“அரசியலமைப்புச் சட்டத்தின்படி, அவர் பாதுகாப்பு மற்றும் பிற வசதிகளைப் பெறுவார். இங்கும் அவருக்கு வீடு தயாராகும் என நான் கருதுகிறேன்” என வீரதுங்க கூறினார்.",
        "கொழும்பில் உள்ள அவரது உத்தியோகபூர்வ இல்லத்தை போராட்டக்காரர்கள் முற்றுகையிட்டதையடுத்து நாட்டை விட்டு வெளியேறிய முன்னாள் அதிபர் ராஜபக்சே தற்போது தாய்லாந்தின் பாங்காக்கில் தங்கியுள்ளார். சிங்கப்பூரில் சிறிது காலம் தங்கியிருந்த அவர் ஆகஸ்ட் 12ஆம் தேதி அங்கு வந்தார்.",
        "தீவின் இடைநிலை ஆட்சி மத்திய வங்கியின் வரலாற்றில் மிக மோசமான நாணய நெருக்கடிக்கு எதிரான வெகுஜன எதிர்ப்புகளுக்குப் பிறகு ராஜபக்சே ஜனாதிபதி பதவியை ராஜினாமா செய்தார்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "இலங்கையின்",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "24",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "25",
          "label": "DATE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜூலை தொடக்கத்தில்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆகஸ்ட் 24 அல்லது 25",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ரஷ்யா உதயங்க வீரதுங்க",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "EconomyNext",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆகஸ்ட் 17 புதன்கிழமை",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ராஜபக்சே",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "அடுத்த வாரம்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இந்த மாதம் 24 அல்லது 25 ஆம் தேதி",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "வீரதுங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ராஜபக்சே",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "கொழும்பு",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாங்காக்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "தாய்லாந்து",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆகஸ்ட் 12",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சிங்கப்பூர்",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ராஜபக்சே",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}