{
  "newspaper_id": "ada-lk",
  "url": "https://www.ada.lk/breaking_news/ඉන්ධන-නැව්-එන-දින-ගැන-ඇමති-කියයි/11-395327",
  "time_ut": 1657537009,
  "original_lang": "si",
  "original_title": "ඉන්ධන නැව් එන දින ගැන ඇමති කියයි",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Minister tells about the date of arrival of fuel ships",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "Mr. Kanchana Wijesekera, Minister of Electricity and Energy, has announced on his Twitter account the dates of the arrival of the diesel and petrol ships that have paid cash and advance payments.",
        "Accordingly, the Central Bank and the Ministry of Finance jointly paid the I.O.C. owned by the company",
        "A petrol ship is scheduled to arrive in Sri Lanka on the 22nd-24th.",
        "A petrol ship is also scheduled to arrive in Lanka between 17-19.",
        "The Minister says that a Borale ship is scheduled to arrive in Sri Lanka between 15-17.",
        "The minister further said that the ship which was supposed to arrive on the 9th could not arrive due to bad weather and the supplier has informed that the ship has already left India."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Kanchana Wijesekera",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Electricity and Energy",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Twitter",
            "label": "PRODUCT"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the Central Bank",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Ministry of Finance",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "I.O.C.",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "between 17-19",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Borale",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "between 15-17",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "9th",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "India",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "ඉන්ධන නැව් එන දින ගැන ඇමති කියයි",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "මුදල් හා අත්තිකාරම් ගෙවීම් කළ ඩීසල්, පෙට්‍රල් නැව් පැමිණෙන දින වකවානු පිළිබඳව විදුලි බල හා බලශක්ති අමාත්‍ය කාංචන විජේසේකර මහතා සිය ට්විටර් ගිණුමෙන් ප්‍රකාශ කර තිබේ.",
        "ඒ අනුව මහ බැංකුව හා මුදල් අමාත්‍යාංශය එක්ව ගෙවීම් කළ අයි.ඕ.සී. සමාගමට අයත්",
        "පෙට්‍රල් නෞකාවක් එළැඹෙන 22-24 යන දිනයන් අතරත් ලංකාවට පැමිණීමට නියමිතය.",
        "‍පෙට්‍රල් නෞකාවක් 17-19 යන දිනයන් අතරත් ලංකවට පැමිණීමට නියමිතව තිබේ.",
        "බොරලේ නෞකාවක් 15-17 අතරත් ශ්‍රී ලංකාවට පැමිණිමට නියමිත බව අමාත්‍යවරයා පවසයි.",
        "9 වැනිදා පැමිණීමට නියමිතව තිබූ නෞකාව කාලගුණය අයහපත් වීම නිසා පැමිණීමට නොහැකි වූ බවත් එම නෞකාව මේ වන විට ඉන්දියාවෙන් පිටත්ව ඇති බවට සැපයුම්කරු විසින් දන්වා ඇති බවත් අමාත්‍යවරයා වැඩිදුරටත් පැවසයි."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "කාංචන විජේසේකර",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "විදුලිය සහ බලශක්තිය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ට්විටර්",
            "label": "PRODUCT"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "මහ බැංකුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "මුදල් අමාත්යාංශය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "I.O.C.",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ලංකා",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "17-19 අතර",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "බොරලේ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "15-17 අතර",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "9 වැනි",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "எரிபொருள் கப்பல்கள் வரும் தேதி பற்றி அமைச்சர் கூறுகிறார்",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "பணம் மற்றும் முன்பணம் செலுத்திய டீசல் மற்றும் பெற்றோல் கப்பல்கள் வரும் தேதிகளை மின்சாரம் மற்றும் எரிசக்தி அமைச்சர் திரு.காஞ்சன விஜேசேகர தனது டுவிட்டரில் அறிவித்துள்ளார்.",
        "இதன்படி, மத்திய வங்கியும் நிதி அமைச்சும் இணைந்து ஐ.ஓ.சி. நிறுவனத்திற்கு சொந்தமானது",
        "எதிர்வரும் 22-24 ஆம் திகதிகளில் பெற்றோல் கப்பல் ஒன்று இலங்கைக்கு வரவுள்ளது.",
        "17-19 க்கு இடையில் ஒரு பெற்றோல் கப்பல் இலங்கைக்கு வர உள்ளது.",
        "15-17 க்கு இடையில் பொரலே கப்பல் ஒன்று இலங்கைக்கு வரவுள்ளதாக அமைச்சர் கூறுகிறார்.",
        "கடந்த 9ஆம் திகதி வரவிருந்த கப்பல் மோசமான வானிலை காரணமாக வரமுடியவில்லை எனவும், கப்பல் ஏற்கனவே இந்தியாவை விட்டு வெளியேறிவிட்டதாக விநியோகஸ்தர் தெரிவித்துள்ளதாக அமைச்சர் மேலும் தெரிவித்தார்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "காஞ்சனா விஜேசேகர",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "மின்சாரம் மற்றும் ஆற்றல்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ட்விட்டர்",
            "label": "PRODUCT"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "மத்திய வங்கி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "நிதி அமைச்சகம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஐ.ஓ.சி.",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "17-19 இடையே",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "போரலே",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "15-17 இடையே",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "9வது",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்தியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}