{
  "newspaper_id": "news-first-lk",
  "url": "https://www.newsfirst.lk/2022/06/24/over-8000-dengue-cases-reported-in-june/",
  "time_ut": 1656052980,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Over 8,000 Dengue cases reported in June",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Over 8,000 Dengue cases reported in June",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); The National Dengue Control Unit says that 8,179 dengue patients have been reported during the past month.",
        "The Director Specialist of the National Dengue Control Unit Dr. Sudath Samaraweema said that this is the highest number of dengue patients reported in during a month.",
        "Dr. Sudath Samaraweera said that 32,385 dengue patients have been identified during this year.",
        "Dr. Samaraweera further said that a special dengue eradication program was launched in the Western Province last week.",
        "Moreover, Dr. Samaraweera said that 8,179 dengue patients were reported during June.",
        "5-year no-pay leave for Public Sector to work in Private Sector?",
        "Another group of 35 people detained for illegal migration attempt to Australia"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "June",
          "label": "DATE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "The National Dengue Control Unit",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "8,179",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "the past month",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Specialist",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the National Dengue Control Unit",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sudath Samaraweema",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "a month",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sudath Samaraweera",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "32,385",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "this year",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Samaraweera",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Western Province",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "last week",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Samaraweera",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "8,179",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "June",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "5-year",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Private Sector",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "35",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Australia",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "ජුනි මාසයේදී ඩෙංගු රෝගීන් 8,000 කට අධික සංඛ්‍යාවක් වාර්තා වී ඇත",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); ගත වූ මාසය තුළ ඩෙංගු රෝගීන් 8,179ක් වාර්තා වී ඇති බව ජාතික ඩෙංගු මර්දන ඒකකය පවසයි.",
        "ජාතික ඩෙංගු මර්දන ඒකකයේ අධ්‍යක්ෂ විශේෂඥ වෛද්‍ය සුදත් සමරවීම මහතා පැවසුවේ මාසයක කාලය තුළ වාර්තා වූ වැඩිම ඩෙංගු රෝගීන් සංඛ්‍යාව මෙය බවයි.",
        "මෙම වසර තුළ ඩෙංගු රෝගීන් 32,385 දෙනෙකු හඳුනාගෙන ඇති බව වෛද්‍ය සුදත් සමරවීර මහතා පැවසීය.",
        "පසුගිය සතියේ බස්නාහිර පළාත තුළ විශේෂ ඩෙංගු මර්දන වැඩසටහනක් ආරම්භ කළ බවද වෛද්‍ය සමරවීර මහතා වැඩිදුරටත් පැවසීය.",
        "තවද, ජුනි මාසය තුළ ඩෙංගු රෝගීන් 8,179ක් වාර්තා වී ඇති බව වෛද්‍ය සමරවීර මහතා පැවසීය.",
        "පෞද්ගලික අංශයේ වැඩ කිරීමට රාජ්‍ය අංශයට වසර 5ක වැටුප් රහිත නිවාඩු ද?",
        "නීතිවිරෝධී ලෙස ඕස්ට්‍රේලියාවට සංක්‍රමණය වීමට උත්සාහ කළ තවත් 35 දෙනෙකුගෙන් යුත් කණ්ඩායමක් අත්අඩංගුවට ගෙන තිබේ"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ජූනි",
          "label": "DATE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ජාතික ඩෙංගු මර්දන ඒකකය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "8,179 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "පසුගිය මාසය",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "විශේෂඥ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජාතික ඩෙංගු මර්දන ඒකකය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "සුදත් සමරවීම",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "මාසයක්",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "සුදත් සමරවීර",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "32,385 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "මේ වසරේ",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "සමරවීර",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "බස්නාහිර පළාත",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගිය සතිය",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "සමරවීර",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "8,179 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජූනි",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "අවුරුදු 5ක්",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "පෞද්ගලික අංශයේ",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "35",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඕස්ට්රේලියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "ஜூன் மாதத்தில் 8,000 டெங்கு வழக்குகள் பதிவாகியுள்ளன",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); கடந்த மாதத்தில் 8,179 டெங்கு நோயாளர்கள் பதிவாகியுள்ளதாக தேசிய டெங்கு கட்டுப்பாட்டு பிரிவு தெரிவித்துள்ளது.",
        "ஒரு மாதத்தில் பதிவான அதிகூடிய டெங்கு நோயாளர்களின் எண்ணிக்கை இதுவாகும் என தேசிய டெங்கு கட்டுப்பாட்டு பிரிவின் பணிப்பாளர் விசேட வைத்திய நிபுணர் டொக்டர் சுதத் சமரவீம தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "இந்த வருடத்தில் 32,385 டெங்கு நோயாளர்கள் இனங்காணப்பட்டுள்ளதாக வைத்தியர் சுதத் சமரவீர தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "கடந்த வாரம் மேல் மாகாணத்தில் விசேட டெங்கு ஒழிப்பு வேலைத்திட்டம் ஆரம்பிக்கப்பட்டதாக டொக்டர் சமரவீர மேலும் தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "மேலும், ஜூன் மாதத்தில் 8,179 டெங்கு நோயாளர்கள் பதிவாகியுள்ளதாக டாக்டர் சமரவீர தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "தனியார் துறையில் பணிபுரிய பொதுத்துறைக்கு 5 ஆண்டு ஊதியம் இல்லாத விடுப்பு?",
        "அவுஸ்திரேலியாவிற்கு சட்டவிரோதமாக குடியேற முயற்சித்த 35 பேர் கொண்ட மற்றொரு குழு கைது செய்யப்பட்டுள்ளனர்"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ஜூன்",
          "label": "DATE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "தேசிய டெங்கு கட்டுப்பாட்டு பிரிவு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "8,179",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "கடந்த மாதம்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "நிபுணர்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "தேசிய டெங்கு கட்டுப்பாட்டு பிரிவு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "சுதத் சமரவீம",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஒரு மாதம்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "சுதத் சமரவீர",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "32,385",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்த வருடம்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "சமரவீர",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "மேல் மாகாணம்",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "கடந்த வாரம்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "சமரவீர",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "8,179",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜூன்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "5-ஆண்டு",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "தனியார் துறை",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "35",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆஸ்திரேலியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  },
  "title": "Over 8,000 Dengue cases reported in June",
  "body_lines": [
    "COLOMBO (News 1st); The National Dengue Control Unit says that 8,179 dengue patients have been reported during the past month.",
    "The Director Specialist of the National Dengue Control Unit Dr. Sudath Samaraweema said that this is the highest number of dengue patients reported in during a month.",
    "Dr. Sudath Samaraweera said that 32,385 dengue patients have been identified during this year.",
    "Dr. Samaraweera further said that a special dengue eradication program was launched in the Western Province last week.",
    "Moreover, Dr. Samaraweera said that 8,179 dengue patients were reported during June.",
    "5-year no-pay leave for Public Sector to work in Private Sector?",
    "Another group of 35 people detained for illegal migration attempt to Australia"
  ],
  "translate": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Over 8,000 Dengue cases reported in June",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); The National Dengue Control Unit says that 8,179 dengue patients have been reported during the past month.",
        "The Director Specialist of the National Dengue Control Unit Dr. Sudath Samaraweema said that this is the highest number of dengue patients reported in during a month.",
        "Dr. Sudath Samaraweera said that 32,385 dengue patients have been identified during this year.",
        "Dr. Samaraweera further said that a special dengue eradication program was launched in the Western Province last week.",
        "Moreover, Dr. Samaraweera said that 8,179 dengue patients were reported during June.",
        "5-year no-pay leave for Public Sector to work in Private Sector?",
        "Another group of 35 people detained for illegal migration attempt to Australia"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "June",
          "label": "DATE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "The National Dengue Control Unit",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "8,179",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "the past month",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Specialist",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the National Dengue Control Unit",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sudath Samaraweema",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "a month",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sudath Samaraweera",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "32,385",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "this year",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Samaraweera",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Western Province",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "last week",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Samaraweera",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "8,179",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "June",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "5-year",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Private Sector",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "35",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Australia",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "ජුනි මාසයේදී ඩෙංගු රෝගීන් 8,000 කට අධික සංඛ්‍යාවක් වාර්තා වී ඇත",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); ගත වූ මාසය තුළ ඩෙංගු රෝගීන් 8,179ක් වාර්තා වී ඇති බව ජාතික ඩෙංගු මර්දන ඒකකය පවසයි.",
        "ජාතික ඩෙංගු මර්දන ඒකකයේ අධ්‍යක්ෂ විශේෂඥ වෛද්‍ය සුදත් සමරවීම මහතා පැවසුවේ මාසයක කාලය තුළ වාර්තා වූ වැඩිම ඩෙංගු රෝගීන් සංඛ්‍යාව මෙය බවයි.",
        "මෙම වසර තුළ ඩෙංගු රෝගීන් 32,385 දෙනෙකු හඳුනාගෙන ඇති බව වෛද්‍ය සුදත් සමරවීර මහතා පැවසීය.",
        "පසුගිය සතියේ බස්නාහිර පළාත තුළ විශේෂ ඩෙංගු මර්දන වැඩසටහනක් ආරම්භ කළ බවද වෛද්‍ය සමරවීර මහතා වැඩිදුරටත් පැවසීය.",
        "තවද, ජුනි මාසය තුළ ඩෙංගු රෝගීන් 8,179ක් වාර්තා වී ඇති බව වෛද්‍ය සමරවීර මහතා පැවසීය.",
        "පෞද්ගලික අංශයේ වැඩ කිරීමට රාජ්‍ය අංශයට වසර 5ක වැටුප් රහිත නිවාඩු ද?",
        "නීතිවිරෝධී ලෙස ඕස්ට්‍රේලියාවට සංක්‍රමණය වීමට උත්සාහ කළ තවත් 35 දෙනෙකුගෙන් යුත් කණ්ඩායමක් අත්අඩංගුවට ගෙන තිබේ"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ජූනි",
          "label": "DATE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ජාතික ඩෙංගු මර්දන ඒකකය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "8,179 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "පසුගිය මාසය",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "විශේෂඥ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජාතික ඩෙංගු මර්දන ඒකකය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "සුදත් සමරවීම",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "මාසයක්",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "සුදත් සමරවීර",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "32,385 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "මේ වසරේ",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "සමරවීර",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "බස්නාහිර පළාත",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගිය සතිය",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "සමරවීර",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "8,179 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජූනි",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "අවුරුදු 5ක්",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "පෞද්ගලික අංශයේ",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "35",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඕස්ට්රේලියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "ஜூன் மாதத்தில் 8,000 டெங்கு வழக்குகள் பதிவாகியுள்ளன",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); கடந்த மாதத்தில் 8,179 டெங்கு நோயாளர்கள் பதிவாகியுள்ளதாக தேசிய டெங்கு கட்டுப்பாட்டு பிரிவு தெரிவித்துள்ளது.",
        "ஒரு மாதத்தில் பதிவான அதிகூடிய டெங்கு நோயாளர்களின் எண்ணிக்கை இதுவாகும் என தேசிய டெங்கு கட்டுப்பாட்டு பிரிவின் பணிப்பாளர் விசேட வைத்திய நிபுணர் டொக்டர் சுதத் சமரவீம தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "இந்த வருடத்தில் 32,385 டெங்கு நோயாளர்கள் இனங்காணப்பட்டுள்ளதாக வைத்தியர் சுதத் சமரவீர தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "கடந்த வாரம் மேல் மாகாணத்தில் விசேட டெங்கு ஒழிப்பு வேலைத்திட்டம் ஆரம்பிக்கப்பட்டதாக டொக்டர் சமரவீர மேலும் தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "மேலும், ஜூன் மாதத்தில் 8,179 டெங்கு நோயாளர்கள் பதிவாகியுள்ளதாக டாக்டர் சமரவீர தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "தனியார் துறையில் பணிபுரிய பொதுத்துறைக்கு 5 ஆண்டு ஊதியம் இல்லாத விடுப்பு?",
        "அவுஸ்திரேலியாவிற்கு சட்டவிரோதமாக குடியேற முயற்சித்த 35 பேர் கொண்ட மற்றொரு குழு கைது செய்யப்பட்டுள்ளனர்"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ஜூன்",
          "label": "DATE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "தேசிய டெங்கு கட்டுப்பாட்டு பிரிவு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "8,179",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "கடந்த மாதம்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "நிபுணர்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "தேசிய டெங்கு கட்டுப்பாட்டு பிரிவு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "சுதத் சமரவீம",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஒரு மாதம்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "சுதத் சமரவீர",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "32,385",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்த வருடம்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "சமரவீர",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "மேல் மாகாணம்",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "கடந்த வாரம்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "சமரவீர",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "8,179",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜூன்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "5-ஆண்டு",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "தனியார் துறை",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "35",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆஸ்திரேலியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}