{
  "newspaper_id": "b-b-c-com-sinhala",
  "url": "https://www.bbc.com/sinhala/sri-lanka-62205966",
  "time_ut": 1658120081,
  "original_lang": "si",
  "original_title": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ:වැඩබලන ජනපතිට රට යථා තත්ත්වයට පත්කළ හැකිද?",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Ranil Wickramasinghe: Can the acting president restore the country?",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "Ranil Wickremesinghe, who was the Prime Minister of Sri Lanka, was suddenly promoted to the new Acting President. But it is not clear how long he will stay in that position.",
        "His predecessor Gotabaya Rajapaksa fled to Singapore due to public protests caused by the island's economic crisis.",
        "Ranil Wickremesinghe, a senior member of parliament from the opposition, has been prime minister six times, but has never served a full term.",
        "His most recent tenure as Prime Minister began last May, when Gotabhaya Rajapaksa was nominated to the post in a failed attempt to retain his position.",
        "Ranil's new role as Acting President got off to an inauspicious start after he announced a nationwide curfew. Despite that, thousands of protesters stormed his office in the capital city of Colombo to protest the decision.",
        "In a televised statement, he denounced the protesters as \"fascists\". But they see him as one of Gotabaya's closest friends and think that he should also step down. During the unrest, his private house was set on fire. He was not at home at that time.",
        "Acting President Ranil Wickremesinghe has issued a special gazette notice announcing a state of emergency in the country with effect from today (July 18) in accordance with the powers assigned to him under Article 40 (1) d of the Constitution.",
        "People have been suffering for months due to daily power outages and lack of basic necessities like fuel, food and medicine.",
        "The country's foreign currency reserves have dried up, which means that Sri Lanka does not have enough money to buy goods from other countries.",
        "At least nine people have lost their lives due to the hardships caused by the growing crisis.",
        "A lawyer by profession, Ranil Wickramasinghe comes from a family of politicians and businessmen.",
        "He was elected to Parliament for the first time in 1977 and immediately rose to the top of the party after Ranasinghe Premadasa became President in 1989. He served as Prime Minister for the first time from 1993 to 1994.",
        "In 1994, when Gamini Dissanayake was killed by a group of suspected rebels of the Liberation Tigers of Tamil Eelam, he became the leader of the United National Party.",
        "When he was addressing a meeting in Eppawala town, he escaped a bomb attack.",
        "Ranil Wickramasinghe improved the image of his party by appointing a disciplinary commission to remove corrupt party members.",
        "He tried different hairstyles to make his personal image more attractive and tried to expand the public support of the United National Party by visiting the villages.",
        "At the turn of the century, he also ran for the presidency, but his efforts failed.",
        "Ranil Wickremesinghe was also the Prime Minister at the time of the 2019 deadly Easter Sunday bombings that killed at least 250 people.",
        "He told the BBC that he had not received intelligence warnings before the attacks.",
        "In the last election, he was the only one who got into parliament from UNP. That too, through the only national list MP that the party got. This further fueled opposition criticism that he was unfit for the post of prime minister.",
        "One of the main reasons why people are angry with Ranil Wickremesinghe is that he is close to the Rajapaksa family. Many believe he helped protect them when they lost power in 2015.",
        "In a bid to bolster his authority, he has instructed a new committee of army and police chiefs to \"do what needs to be done\" to restore order.",
        "But now the problem is that it is not clear what are the things that should be done or whether Ranil Wickramasinghe is the right person to do it all."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Ranil Wickramasinghe",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Gotabaya Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Singapore",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "six",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "last May",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Gotabhaya Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Ranil",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "thousands",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Gotabaya",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "July 18",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Article 40",
            "label": "LAW"
          },
          {
            "text": "Constitution",
            "label": "LAW"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "months",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "daily",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "At least nine",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickramasinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "first",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "1977",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ranasinghe Premadasa",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "1989",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "first",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "1993 to 1994",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "1994",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Gamini Dissanayake",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Tamil Eelam",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the United National Party",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Eppawala",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickramasinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the United National Party",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the turn of the century",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "2019",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Easter Sunday",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "at least 250",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "BBC",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "UNP",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "One",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "2015",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickramasinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ:වැඩබලන ජනපතිට රට යථා තත්ත්වයට පත්කළ හැකිද?",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ අග්‍රාමාත්‍යධුරයේ සිටි රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ හදිසියේ නව වැඩබලන ජනාධිපතිවරයා දක්වා උසස්විය. නමුත් ඔහු එම තනතුරේ කොපමණ කාලයක් රැඳී සිටිනු ඇත්ද ද යන්න පැහැදිලි නැත.",
        "ඔහුගේ පූර්වගාමියා වූ ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ දිවයිනේ ආර්ථික අර්බුදය හේතුවෙන් ඇතිවූ මහජන විරෝධතා නිසාවෙන් සිංගප්පූරුවට පළා ගියේ ය.",
        "විපක්ෂයේ ජ්‍යේෂ්ඨ පාර්ලිමේන්තු මන්ත්‍රීවරයෙකු වන රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ සය වතාවක් අගමැති වී ඇතත්, කිසිදා සම්පූර්ණ ධුරකාලයක් ගතකර නැත.",
        "ඔහුගේ නවතම අග්‍රාමාත්‍යධුර කාලය ආරම්භ වූයේ පසුගිය මැයි මාසයේ දී, ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ තම තනතුර රැකගැනීමේ අසාර්ථක උත්සාහයක් ලෙස ඔහු තනතුරට නම් කරනු ලැබීමත් සමඟය .",
        "වැඩබලන ජනාධිපති ලෙස රනිල්ගේ නව භූමිකාව අශුභවාදී ආරම්භයක් වූයේ ඔහු රටපුරා ඇඳිරි  නීතිය ප්‍රකාශයට පත්කිරීමෙන් පසුව ය. එය නොතකා කොළඹ අගනුවර පිහිටි ඔහුගේ කාර්යාලයට කඩා වැදුණු දහස් සංඛ්‍යාත විරෝධතාකරුවෝ එම තීරණයට විරෝධය පෑහ.",
        "රූපවාහිනිය හරහා ප්‍රකාශයක් සිදුකළ ඔහු විරෝධතාකරුවන් \"ෆැසිස්ට්වාදීන්\" ලෙස හඳුන්වමින් හෙළා දුටුවේ ය. නමුත් ඔවුන් ඔහු ගෝඨාභයගේ අති සමීපතමයෙකු ලෙස දකින නිසා ඔහු ද ධුරයෙන් ඉවත්විය යුතුබව සිතයි.  ඇති වූ නොසන්සුන්තාවන්  අතරතුර ඔහුගේ පෞද්ගලික නිවසට ගිනි තබනු ලැබිණි. ඒවේලේ ඔහු නිවසේ  නොසිටියේ ය.",
        "මේ වන විට  වැඩබලන ජනාධිපති රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ විසින් ආණ්ඩුක්‍රම ව්‍යවස්ථාවේ 40 (1) ඈ ව්‍යවස්ථාව අනුව තමන් වෙත පැවරී ඇති බලතල ප්‍රකාරව අද (ජූලි 18) සිට ක්‍රියාත්මක වන පරිදි හදිසි අවස්ථා තත්ත්වයක් ද  රට තුළ ප්‍රකාශයට පත්කරමින් අති විශේෂ ගැසට් නිවේදනයක් නිකුත් කොට තිබේ.",
        "ජනතාව මාස ගණනාවක තිස්සේ දෛනික විදුලිය විසන්ධිකිරීම්, සහ ඉන්ධන, ආහාර, ඖෂධ වැනි මූලික අවශ්‍යතා හිඟකම හේතුවෙන් දුෂ්කරතාවට පත්ව සිටිති.",
        "රටේ විදේශ මුදල් සංචිත සිඳීගොස් ඇති අතර එයින් අදහස් වන්නේ වෙනත් රටවලින් භාණ්ඩ මිළ දී ගැනීමට ප්‍රමාණවත් මුදලක් ශ්‍රී ලංකාව සතුව නොමැති බව යි.",
        "ක්‍රමයෙන් වැඩෙන අර්බුදයෙන් ඇතිකළ දුෂ්කරතා හේතුවෙන් ජනතා කෝපය ඉතිරීගොස් ඇති මේ අවස්ථාවේ අවම වශයෙන් නව දෙනෙකුට ජීවිත අහිමිවී තිබේ.",
        "වෘත්තියෙන් නීතිඥයෙකු වන රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ දේශපාලනඥයින් සහ ව්‍යාපාරිකයන්ගෙන් සපිරි පවුලකින් පැවත එන අයෙකි.",
        "1977 දී ප්‍රථම වරට පාර්ලිමේන්තුවට තේරී පත්වූ ඔහු 1989 දී රණසිංහ ප්‍රේමදාස ජනාධිපතිධුරයට පත්වීමෙන් පසු ක්ෂණයෙන් පක්ෂයේ ඉහළට ගියේ ය. 1993 සිට 1994 දක්වා කාලයේ දී ඔහු ප්‍රථම වරට අගමැති ලෙස කටයුතු කළේ ය.",
        "1994 දී දෙමළ ඊළාම් විමුක්ති කොටි සංවිධානයේ කැරලිකරුවන්යැ යි සැක කරන පිරිසක් ගාමිණී දිසානායක ඝාතනය කළ විට ඔහු එක්සත් ජාතික පක්ෂයේ නායකත්වයට පත්විය.",
        "එප්පාවල නගරයේ රැස්වීමක් අමතමින් සිටිය දී ඔහු ඉලක්කකොට එල්ලවූ බෝම්බ ප්‍රහාරයකින් ඔහු නූලෙන් ගැලවුණේ ය.",
        "දූෂිත පාක්ෂිකයින් ඉවත්කිරීමට විනය කොමිසමක් පත් කිරීමෙන් රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ තම පක්ෂයේ ප්‍රතිරූපය වැඩි දියුණු කළේ ය.",
        "සිය පුද්ගල ප්‍රතිරූපය ද වඩාත් ආකර්ෂණීයකර ගැනීම සඳහා විවිධ කොණ්ඩා මෝස්තර අත්හදා බැලූ ඔහු ගම්වල සංචාරය කරමින් එක්සත් ජාතික පක්ෂයේ මහජන සහයෝගය පුළුල් කිරීමට උත්සාහ කළේ ය.",
        "ශතවර්ෂය ආරම්භයේ දී ඔහු ජනාධිපතිවරණයට ද තරග කළ නමුත් ඔහුගේ උත්සාහය ව්‍යවර්ථ විය.",
        "අවම වශයෙන් පුද්ගලයින් 250 දෙනෙකුට මරු කැඳවූ 2019 මාරාන්තික පාස්කු ඉරිදා බෝම්බ ප්‍රහාරය සිදුවූ සමයේ දී ද අගමැතිව සිටියේ රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ ය.",
        "ප්‍රහාරවලට පෙර බුද්ධි අංශ සිදුකර තිබූ අනතුරු ඇඟවීම් තමාට නොලැබුණු බව ඔහු BBCයට පැවසුවේ ය.",
        "පසුගිය මැතිවරණයේ දී එජාපයෙන් පාර්ලිමේන්තුවට පත්වූයේ ඔහු පමණකි. එය ද, එම පක්ෂය ලැබූ එකම ජාතික ලැයිස්තු මන්ත්‍රීධුරය හරහා ය. මෙය අගමැතිධුරයට ඔහු නුසුදුසු බව පෙන්වාදෙන විරුද්ධපාක්ෂික විවේචන වඩාත් අවුලුවයි.",
        "ජනතාව රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ කෙරෙහි කෝපයට පත්වීමට එක් ප්‍රධාන හේතුවක් වී ඇත්තේ ඔහු රාජපක්ෂ පවුලට සමීපව සිටීම යි. 2015 දී ඔවුනට බලය අහිමිවූ විට ඔහු ඔවුන් ආරක්ෂා කිරීමට උපකාර කළ බව බොහෝදෙනා විශ්වාස කරයි.",
        "ඔහුගේ අධිකාරී බලය ඉහළ නැංවීමේ උත්සාහයක් ලෙස, සාමය යථා තත්ත්වයට පත්කිරීම සඳහා \"කළ යුතු දේ කරන\" ලෙස ඔහු හමුදා සහ පොලිස් ප්‍රධානීන්ගෙන් යුත් නව කමිටුවකට උපදෙස් දී ඇත.",
        "නමුත් දැන් ගැටළුව වන්නේ එ‍සේ කළ යුතු දේවල් මොනවා ද යන්න හෝ, ඒ සියල්ල සිදු කිරීමට උචිත වන මිනිසා රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ ද යන්න අපැහැදිලිවීම යි."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "සිංගප්පූරුව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "හය",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "පසුගිය මැයි",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "රනිල්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "දහස්",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ගෝඨාභය",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජූලි 18",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "40 වැනි වගන්තිය",
            "label": "LAW"
          },
          {
            "text": "ආණ්ඩුක්රම ව්යවස්ථාව",
            "label": "LAW"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "මාස",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "දිනපතා",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "අවම වශයෙන් නවයක්",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "පළමුවන",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "1977",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "රණසිංහ ප්‍රේමදාස",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "1989",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "පළමුවන",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "1993 සිට 1994 දක්වා",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "1994",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගාමිණී දිසානායක",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "දෙමළ ඊළම",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "එක්සත් ජාතික පක්ෂය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Eppawala",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "එක්සත් ජාතික පක්ෂය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "සියවසේ හැරීම",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "2019",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාස්කු ඉරිදා",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "අවම වශයෙන් 250",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "බීබීසී",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "එජාප",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "එක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "2015",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க: ஜனாதிபதியால் நாட்டை மீட்டெடுக்க முடியுமா?",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "இலங்கையின் பிரதமராக இருந்த ரணில் விக்ரமசிங்கே திடீரென புதிய செயல் அதிபராக பதவி உயர்வு பெற்றார். ஆனால் அவர் எவ்வளவு காலம் அந்தப் பதவியில் இருப்பார் என்பது தெரியவில்லை.",
        "அவரது முன்னோடியாக இருந்த கோத்தபய ராஜபக்ச, தீவின் பொருளாதார நெருக்கடியால் ஏற்பட்ட மக்கள் எதிர்ப்பு காரணமாக சிங்கப்பூருக்கு தப்பிச் சென்றார்.",
        "எதிர்க்கட்சியைச் சேர்ந்த மூத்த நாடாளுமன்ற உறுப்பினரான ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க, 6 முறை பிரதமராக இருந்த போதிலும், ஒருமுறை கூட முழுப் பதவியில் இருந்ததில்லை.",
        "கடந்த மே மாதம் கோத்தபாய ராஜபக்ச தனது பதவியை தக்கவைத்துக்கொள்ளும் முயற்சியில் தோல்வியடைந்து அப்பதவிக்கு பரிந்துரைக்கப்பட்டபோது, ​​அவரது மிக சமீபத்திய பிரதமராக பதவிக்காலம் தொடங்கியது.",
        "நாடளாவிய ரீதியில் ஊரடங்குச் சட்டம் அமுல்படுத்தப்பட்டதையடுத்து, ஜனாதிபதியாக ரணிலின் புதிய பொறுப்பு ஒரு மோசமான ஆரம்பத்தை எட்டியது. இருந்த போதிலும், இந்த முடிவை எதிர்த்து ஆயிரக்கணக்கான போராட்டக்காரர்கள் தலைநகர் கொழும்பில் உள்ள அவரது அலுவலகத்தை முற்றுகையிட்டனர்.",
        "ஒரு தொலைக்காட்சி அறிக்கையில், எதிர்ப்பாளர்களை \"பாசிஸ்டுகள்\" என்று கண்டித்தார். ஆனால் கோத்தபாயவின் நெருங்கிய நண்பர்களில் ஒருவராக அவரைப் பார்க்கிறார்கள், அவரும் பதவி விலக வேண்டும் என்று நினைக்கிறார்கள். அமைதியின்மையின் போது, ​​அவரது தனிப்பட்ட வீடு தீக்கிரையாக்கப்பட்டது. அப்போது அவர் வீட்டில் இல்லை.",
        "அரசியலமைப்பின் 40 (1) d பிரிவின் கீழ் அவருக்கு வழங்கப்பட்டுள்ள அதிகாரங்களுக்கு அமைவாக இன்று (ஜூலை 18) முதல் அமுலுக்கு வரும் வகையில் நாட்டில் அவசரகால நிலை பிரகடனப்படுத்தப்படும் என பதில் ஜனாதிபதி ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க விசேட வர்த்தமானி அறிவித்தலை வெளியிட்டுள்ளார்.",
        "நாள்தோறும் மின்வெட்டு மற்றும் அத்தியாவசிய தேவைகளான எரிபொருள், உணவு, மருந்து கிடைக்காமல் பல மாதங்களாக மக்கள் அவதிப்பட்டு வருகின்றனர்.",
        "நாட்டின் வெளிநாட்டு நாணய கையிருப்பு வறண்டு போயுள்ளது, அதாவது மற்ற நாடுகளிடம் இருந்து பொருட்களை வாங்குவதற்கு இலங்கையிடம் போதிய பணம் இல்லை.",
        "வளர்ந்து வரும் நெருக்கடியால் ஏற்பட்ட கஷ்டங்களால் குறைந்தது ஒன்பது பேர் உயிரிழந்துள்ளனர்.",
        "தொழில் ரீதியாக ஒரு சட்டத்தரணி, ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க அரசியல்வாதிகள் மற்றும் வர்த்தகர்களின் குடும்பத்தில் இருந்து வந்தவர்.",
        "1977ஆம் ஆண்டு முதன்முறையாக நாடாளுமன்றத்துக்குத் தெரிவான அவர், 1989ஆம் ஆண்டு ரணசிங்க பிரேமதாச ஜனாதிபதியாக பதவியேற்ற பின்னர் கட்சியின் உயர்பீடத்திற்கு உடனடியாக உயர்ந்தார். 1993 முதல் 1994 வரை முதல் முறையாக பிரதமராக பதவி வகித்தார்.",
        "1994 ஆம் ஆண்டு தமிழீழ விடுதலைப் புலிகளின் கிளர்ச்சியாளர்கள் என சந்தேகிக்கப்படும் குழுவினால் காமினி திஸாநாயக்க கொல்லப்பட்ட போது, ​​அவர் ஐக்கிய தேசியக் கட்சியின் தலைவராக ஆனார்.",
        "எப்பாவல நகரில் நடைபெற்ற கூட்டமொன்றில் கலந்து கொண்டு உரையாற்றிய போது, ​​குண்டுத் தாக்குதலில் இருந்து தப்பினார்.",
        "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க ஊழல்வாதிகளை நீக்குவதற்கு ஒழுக்காற்று ஆணைக்குழுவை நியமித்து தனது கட்சியின் இமேஜை மேம்படுத்தினார்.",
        "அவர் தனது தனிப்பட்ட தோற்றத்தை மிகவும் கவர்ச்சிகரமானதாக மாற்ற பல்வேறு சிகை அலங்காரங்களை முயற்சித்தார் மற்றும் கிராமங்களுக்குச் சென்று ஐக்கிய தேசியக் கட்சியின் பொது ஆதரவை விரிவுபடுத்த முயன்றார்.",
        "நூற்றாண்டின் தொடக்கத்தில், அவர் ஜனாதிபதி பதவிக்கும் போட்டியிட்டார், ஆனால் அவரது முயற்சிகள் தோல்வியடைந்தன.",
        "2019 ஈஸ்டர் ஞாயிறு குண்டுவெடிப்பில் குறைந்தது 250 பேர் கொல்லப்பட்ட நேரத்தில் ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்கவும் பிரதமராக இருந்தார்.",
        "தாக்குதல்களுக்கு முன்னர் தனக்கு உளவுத்துறை எச்சரிக்கைகள் வரவில்லை என்று அவர் பிபிசியிடம் கூறினார்.",
        "கடந்த தேர்தலில் ஐக்கிய தேசியக் கட்சியில் இருந்து பாராளுமன்றத்திற்கு வந்தவர் இவர் மட்டுமே. அதுவும் அக்கட்சிக்கு கிடைத்த ஒரேயொரு தேசியப்பட்டியல் எம்.பி. இது அவர் பிரதமர் பதவிக்கு தகுதியற்றவர் என்ற எதிர்க்கட்சிகளின் விமர்சனத்தை மேலும் தூண்டியது.",
        "ரணில் விக்ரமசிங்கே மீது மக்கள் கோபமாக இருப்பதற்கு முக்கிய காரணம் அவர் ராஜபக்ச குடும்பத்துடன் நெருக்கமாக இருப்பதுதான். 2015 இல் அதிகாரத்தை இழந்தபோது அவர் அவர்களைப் பாதுகாக்க உதவினார் என்று பலர் நம்புகிறார்கள்.",
        "தனது அதிகாரத்தை வலுப்படுத்தும் முயற்சியில், ஒழுங்கை மீட்டெடுக்க \"செய்ய வேண்டியதைச் செய்ய\" இராணுவம் மற்றும் காவல்துறைத் தலைவர்களின் புதிய குழுவிற்கு அவர் அறிவுறுத்தியுள்ளார்.",
        "ஆனால் இப்போது பிரச்சனை என்னவென்றால், என்ன செய்ய வேண்டும் அல்லது ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க அதைச் செய்ய சரியான நபரா என்பது தெளிவாகத் தெரியவில்லை."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "சிங்கப்பூர்",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆறு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "கடந்த மே",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "கோத்தபாய ராஜபக்ச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ரணில்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆயிரக்கணக்கான",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "கோட்டாபய",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜூலை 18",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "கட்டுரை 40",
            "label": "LAW"
          },
          {
            "text": "அரசியலமைப்பு",
            "label": "LAW"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "மாதங்கள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "தினசரி",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "குறைந்தது ஒன்பது",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "முதலில்",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "1977",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரணசிங்க பிரேமதாச",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "1989",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "முதலில்",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "1993 முதல் 1994 வரை",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "1994",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "காமினி திசாநாயக்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "தமிழ் ஈழம்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஐக்கிய தேசிய கட்சி",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Eppawala",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஐக்கிய தேசிய கட்சி",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "நூற்றாண்டின் திருப்பம்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "2019",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஈஸ்டர் ஞாயிறு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "குறைந்தது 250",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பிபிசி",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஐ.தே.க",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஒன்று",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ராஜபக்சே",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "2015",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}