{
  "newspaper_id": "virakesari-lk",
  "url": "http://www.virakesari.lk/article/132321",
  "time_ut": 1658897675,
  "original_lang": "ta",
  "original_title": "சபை முதல்வராக சுசில் : ஆளும் கட்சியின் பிரதம கொறடாவாக பிரசன்ன ரணதுங்க",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Susil as Chief Minister: Prasanna Ranatunga as Chief Whip of the ruling party",
      "author": "",
      "body_lines": [
        "Also, Minister Prasanna Ranatunga has been re-appointed as the Chief Whip of the ruling party.",
        "The first parliamentary session will be held today after Ranil Wickremesinghe was sworn in as President.",
        "Minister Dines Gunawardena, who previously served as the Chief Minister, has been sworn in as the Prime Minister. Education Minister Sushil Premajayantha has been appointed to fill the vacant post of the council principal.",
        "Parliament will convene today, Wednesday at 10.00 am under the chairmanship of Speaker Mahinda Yappa Abeywardhana. The first event will be the swearing in of Vajira Abeyvarthana.",
        "While Ranil Wickramasinghe went to Parliament on the only National List seat available to the United National Party in the General Election, now that seat has become vacant as he has been elected to the post of President.",
        "According to the letter sent by the Election Commission to the Secretary of the United National Party, with the full approval of the Central Executive Committee and the Management Council of the United National Party, the name of the party's vice president Vajira Abeywardhana was submitted to the Election Commission by the party's secretary, Palitha Range Bandara.",
        "Based on that, the Election Commission had announced the name of Vajira Abeywardhana as a member of the National List of the United National Party for the vacant seat in the Parliament last week through the gazette.",
        "Based on that, when Parliament meets today, Vajira Abeywardhana will take oath as a Member of Parliament in the presence of the Speaker.",
        "During today's Parliament session, the state of emergency declared by the President under the Public Security Act will be debated till 4.30 pm.",
        "On the 17th, a state of emergency was declared during Ranil Wickramasinghe's tenure as Acting President through the announcement of Special Gazette No. 2288/30.",
        "According to the law, if the approval of the Parliament is not obtained within 14 days, the declaration of the state of emergency is null and void.",
        "This declaration was made in accordance with the power given to the President under the Public Security Ordinance to maintain the security of the people, the peace of the country, and the provision and services essential to public life."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Prasanna Ranatunga",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Prasanna Ranatunga",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "first",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Dines Gunawardena",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sushil Premajayantha",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "today, Wednesday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "10.00 am",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "Mahinda Yappa Abeywardhana",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "first",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Vajira Abeyvarthana",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickramasinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "National List",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the United National Party",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the General Election",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the Election Commission",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the United National Party",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Central Executive Committee",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Management Council of the United National Party",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Vajira Abeywardhana",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Election Commission",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Palitha",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Range Bandara",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the Election Commission",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Vajira Abeywardhana",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the National List of the United National Party",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "last week",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Vajira Abeywardhana",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Public Security Act",
            "label": "LAW"
          },
          {
            "text": "4.30 pm",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the 17th",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickramasinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "2288/30",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "14 days",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        []
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "සුසිල් මහ ඇමති ලෙස: ප්‍රසන්න රණතුංග ආණ්ඩු පක්ෂයේ ප්‍රධාන සංවිධායක",
      "author": "",
      "body_lines": [
        "එමෙන්ම ආණ්ඩු පක්ෂයේ ප්‍රධාන සංවිධායක ධූරයට අමාත්‍ය ප්‍රසන්න රණතුංග මහතා යළි පත් කර තිබෙනවා.",
        "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතා ජනාධිපතිවරයා ලෙස දිවුරුම් දීමෙන් පසු පළමු පාර්ලිමේන්තු සැසිවාරය අද පැවැත්වෙනවා.",
        "මීට පෙර ප්‍රධාන අමාත්‍යවරයා ලෙස කටයුතු කළ අමාත්‍ය දිනේස් ගුණවර්ධන මහතා අග්‍රාමාත්‍යවරයා ලෙස දිවුරුම් දී තිබේ. පුරප්පාඩු වූ සභාවේ විදුහල්පති තනතුර සඳහා අධ්‍යාපන අමාත්‍ය සුෂිල් ප්‍රේමජයන්ත පත් කර තිබේ.",
        "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව අද බදාදා පෙරවරු 10.00ට කථානායක මහින්ද යාප්පා අබේවර්ධන මහතාගේ ප්‍රධානත්වයෙන් රැස්වේ. පළමු උත්සවය වජිර අබේවර්ධන දිවුරුම් දීමයි.",
        "මහ මැතිවරණයේදී එක්සත් ජාතික පක්ෂයට තිබූ එකම ජාතික ලැයිස්තු මන්ත්‍රී ධුරයෙන් රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතා පාර්ලිමේන්තුවට ගිය අතර ඔහු ජනාධිපති ධුරයට පත්වීම නිසා දැන් එම මන්ත්‍රී ධුරය පුරප්පාඩු වී තිබේ.",
        "එක්සත් ජාතික පක්ෂයේ මධ්‍යම විධායක කමිටුවේ සහ කළමනාකරණ සභාවේ පූර්ණ අනුමැතිය ඇතිව මැතිවරණ කොමිෂන් සභාව එක්සත් ජාතික පක්ෂයේ ලේකම්වරයා වෙත යවන ලද ලිපියට අනුව පක්ෂයේ උප සභාපති වජිර අබේවර්ධනගේ නම පාර්ලිමේන්තු මන්ත්‍රීවරයා වෙත ඉදිරිපත් කර ඇත. මැතිවරණ කොමිසමේ ලේකම් පාලිත රංගේ බණ්ඩාර විසිනි.",
        "ඒ අනුව පුරප්පාඩු වූ පාර්ලිමේන්තු අසුන සඳහා එක්සත් ජාතික පක්ෂයේ ජාතික ලැයිස්තු මන්ත්‍රීවරයෙකු ලෙස වජිර අබේවර්ධනගේ නම මැතිවරණ කොමිසම විසින් ගැසට් මගින් පසුගිය සතියේ ප්‍රකාශයට පත් කර තිබුණා.",
        "ඒ අනුව අද පාර්ලිමේන්තුව රැස්වන අවස්ථාවේදී වජිර අබේවර්ධන මන්ත්‍රීවරයෙකු ලෙස කථානායකවරයා ඉදිරියේ දිවුරුම් දීමට නියමිතයි.",
        "අද පැවැත්වෙන පාර්ලිමේන්තු සැසියේදී මහජන ආරක්ෂක පනත යටතේ ජනාධිපතිවරයා විසින් ප්‍රකාශයට පත් කර ඇති හදිසි නීතිය පස්වරු 4.30 දක්වා විවාදයට ගැනීමට නියමිතයි.",
        "පසුගිය 17 වැනිදා අංක 2288/30 දරන අතිවිශේෂ ගැසට් පත්‍රය මගින් රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතා වැඩබලන ජනාධිපතිවරයා ලෙස කටයුතු කරන සමයේ හදිසි තත්ත්වයක් ප්‍රකාශයට පත් කළේය.",
        "නීතියට අනුව දින 14ක් ඇතුළත පාර්ලිමේන්තුවේ අනුමැතිය නොලැබුණහොත් හදිසි නීතිය ප්‍රකාශ කිරීම බල රහිත වේ.",
        "ජනතාවගේ ආරක්ෂාව, රටේ සාමය සහ ජන ජීවිතයට අත්‍යාවශ්‍ය ප්‍රතිපාදන හා සේවාවන් පවත්වාගෙන යාම සඳහා මහජන ආරක්ෂක ආඥාපනත යටතේ ජනාධිපතිවරයා වෙත ලබා දී ඇති බලයට අනුව මෙම ප්‍රකාශය සිදු කර ඇත."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ප්‍රසන්න රණතුංග",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ප්‍රසන්න රණතුංග",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "පළමුවන",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ඩයිනස් ගුණවර්ධන",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "සුෂිල් ප්‍රේමජයන්ත",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "අද, බදාදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "10.00 පෙ.ව",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "මහින්ද යාප්පා අබේවර්ධන",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "පළමුවන",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "වජිර අබේවර්ධන",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජාතික ලැයිස්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "එක්සත් ජාතික පක්ෂය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "මහ මැතිවරණය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "මැතිවරණ කොමිසම",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "එක්සත් ජාතික පක්ෂය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "මධ්යම විධායක කමිටුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "එක්සත් ජාතික පක්ෂයේ කළමනාකරණ මණ්ඩලය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "වජිර අබේවර්ධන",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "මැතිවරණ කොමිසම",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාලිත",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "රංගේ බණ්ඩාර",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "මැතිවරණ කොමිසම",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "වජිර අබේවර්ධන",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "එක්සත් ජාතික පක්ෂයේ ජාතික ලැයිස්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගිය සතිය",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "වජිර අබේවර්ධන",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "මහජන ආරක්ෂක පනත",
            "label": "LAW"
          },
          {
            "text": "4.30 ප.ව",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "17 වැනි",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "2288/30",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "දින 14 යි",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        []
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "சபை முதல்வராக சுசில் : ஆளும் கட்சியின் பிரதம கொறடாவாக பிரசன்ன ரணதுங்க",
      "author": "",
      "body_lines": [
        "அத்துடன் ஆளும் கட்சியின் பிரதம கொறடாவாக அமைச்சர் பிரசன்ன ரணதுங்க மீண்டும் நியமிக்கப்பட்டுள்ளார்.",
        "ஜனாதிபதியாக ரணில் விக்ரமசிங்க பதவியேற்றதன் பின்னர் முதலாவது பாராளுமன்ற அமர்வு இன்று இடம்பெறவுள்ளது.",
        "முன்னதாக சபை முதல்வராக செயற்பட்ட அமைச்சர் தினேஸ் குணவர்தன பிரதமராக பதவியேற்றுள்ளார். இதனால் ஏற்பட்ட சபை முதல்வர் பதவி வெற்றிடத்திற்காக கல்வியமைச்சர் சுசில் பிரேமஜயந்த நியமிக்கப்பட்டுள்ளார்.",
        "பாராளுமன்றம் இன்று புதன்கிழமை காலை 10.00 மணிக்கு சபாநாயகர் மஹிந்த யாப்பா அபேவர்த்தன தலைமையில் கூடுகின்றது. இதன்போது ஆரம்ப நிகழ்வாக வஜிர அபேவர்த்தனவின் சத்தியப்பிரமாணம் இடம்பெறும்.",
        "பொதுத் தேர்தலில் ஐக்கிய தேசிய கட்சிக்கு கிடைக்கப்பெற்ற ஒரே ஒரு தேசியப்பட்டியல் ஆசனத்தில் ரணில் விக்ரமசிங்க பாராளுமன்றத்துக்கு சென்ற நிலையில் தற்போது அவர் ஜனாதிபதி பதவிக்கு தெரிவுசெய்யப்பட்டதால், குறித்த ஆசனம் வெற்றிடமாகி இருந்தது..",
        "அதன் பிரகாரம் தேர்தல் ஆணைக்குழு ஐக்கிய தேசிய கட்சியின் செயலாளருக்கு அனுப்பி இருந்த கடிதத்தின் பிரகாரம், ஐக்கிய தேசிய கட்சியின் மத்திய செயற்குழு மற்றும் முகாமைத்துவ சபையின் பூரண அனுமதியுடன் கட்சியின் தவிசாளர் வஜிர அபேவர்த்தனவின் பெயரை கட்சியின் செயலாளர் பாலித்த ரங்கே பண்டார தேர்தல் ஆணைக்குழுவுக்கு சமர்ப்பித்திருந்தார்.",
        "அதனடிப்படையில் பாராளுமன்றத்தில் வெற்றிடமாகி இருந்த ஆசனத்துக்கு ஐக்கிய தேசிய கட்சியின் தேசியப்பட்டியல் உறுப்பினராக வஜிர அபேவர்த்தனவின் பெயரை தேர்தல் ஆணைக்குழு கடந்த வாரம் வர்த்தமானி மூலம் அறிவிப்பு செய்திருந்தது.",
        "அதனடிப்படையில் இன்று பாராளுமன்றம் கூடும்போது வஜிர அபேவர்த்தன பாராளுமன்ற உறுப்பினராக சபாநாயகர் முன்னிலையில் சத்தியப்பிரமாணம் செய்துகொள்வார்.",
        "இன்றைய பாராளுமன்ற அமர்வின் போது, பொதுமக்கள் பாதுகாப்புச் சட்டத்தின் கீழ், பதில் ஜனாதிபதியினால் பிரகடனப்படுத்தப்பட்ட அவசரகால நிலை தொடர்பில் பிற்பகல் 4.30 வரை விவாதிக்கப்பட்டவுள்ளது.",
        "கடந்த 17 ஆம் திகதி, 2288/30 ஆம் இலக்க அதிவிசேட வர்த்தமானி அறிவித்தல் மூலம், ரணில் விக்ரமசிங்க பதில் ஜனாதிபதியாக செயற்பட்ட காலத்தில் அவசரகால நிலை பிரகடனப்படுத்தப்பட்டிருந்தது.",
        "சட்ட விதிகளுக்கு அமைய, 14 நாட்களுக்குள் பாராளுமன்றத்தின் அனுமதி பெறப்படாவிட்டால், அவசரகால நிலைமைப் பிரகடனம் இரத்தாகிவிடும்.",
        "மக்களின் பாதுகாப்பு, நாட்டின் அமைதியைப் பாதுகாத்தல், பொதுமக்கள் வாழ்வுக்கு அத்தியாவசியமான வழங்கல்கள் மற்றும் சேவைகள் என்பவற்றைப் பேணுவதற்கு, பொதுமக்கள் பாதுகாப்பு கட்டளை சட்டத்தின்கீழ் ஜனாதிபதிக்கு வழங்கப்பட்டுள்ள அதிகாரத்துக்கு அமைய இந்தப் பிரகடனம் செய்யப்பட்டது."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "பிரசன்ன ரணதுங்க",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "பிரசன்ன ரணதுங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "முதலில்",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "டைன்ஸ் குணவர்தன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "சுசில் பிரேமஜயந்த",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று, புதன்கிழமை",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "காலை 10.00 மணி",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "மஹிந்த யாப்பா அபேவர்தன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "முதலில்",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "வஜிர அபேவர்தன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "தேசிய பட்டியல்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஐக்கிய தேசிய கட்சி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "பொது தேர்தல்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "தேர்தல் ஆணையம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஐக்கிய தேசிய கட்சி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "மத்திய செயற்குழு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஐக்கிய தேசியக் கட்சியின் நிர்வாக சபை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "வஜிர அபேவர்தன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "தேர்தல் ஆணையம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாலித",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரங்கே பண்டார",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "தேர்தல் ஆணையம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "வஜிர அபேவர்தன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஐக்கிய தேசியக் கட்சியின் தேசியப் பட்டியல்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "கடந்த வாரம்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "வஜிர அபேவர்தன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "பொது பாதுகாப்பு சட்டம்",
            "label": "LAW"
          },
          {
            "text": "மாலை 4.30 மணி",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "17வது",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "2288/30",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "14 நாட்கள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        []
      ]
    }
  }
}