{
  "newspaper_id": "daily-mirror-lk",
  "url": "https://www.dailymirror.lk/top_story/GR-confirms-to-resign-on-Wednesday-Presidential-Polls-before-March/155-240783",
  "time_ut": 1657510607,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "GR confirms to resign on Wednesday; Presidential Polls before March",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "GR confirms to resign on Wednesday; Presidential Polls before March",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "President Gotabaya Rajapaksa will end his presidency on Wednesday after handing in his resignation to the Parliament Speaker after which a decision has been taken to hold a presidential and parliamentary election before March next year, senior political sources told Daily Mirror last evening.",
        "Despite the Speaker announcing on Saturday night that the President would resign on Wednesday, there was uncertainty if he would actually step down from his post. However, in a discussion held with Prime Minister Ranil Wickremesinghe following the nationwide protest on Saturday, Rajapaksa had confirmed he would end his presidency on July 13, thereby allowing Wickremesinghe or a new leader to be sworn in. The whereabouts of President Rajapaksa is still unknown.",
        "Following discussions held within the political parties till last evening, Wickremesinghe held a majority of nearly 115 seats in Parliament. Several MPs have also requested him to continue and take over the Presidency and not leave the economic crisis halfways especially since talks with the IMF were ongoing.",
        "Opposition Leader Sajith Premadasa also held separate discussions after Saturday's riots and even hinted to his inner circle that if he is elected as the President then his likely candidate for the Prime Minister would be Dullas Allahapperuma. However, as of last evening, Sajith was yet to secure the majority support of Parliament.",
        "If Wickremesinghe continues in office, he will be sworn in as the President on Wednesday following Rajapaksa's resignation and till a Presidential election is held, he will concentrate on finalizing a deal with the IMF and restoring some kind of economic normalcy. It is still unsure who will be Wickremesinghe's Prime Ministerial candidate but he is likely to allow Parliament to nominate a suitable candidate.",
        "If Wickremesinghe resigns, then Speaker of Parliament Mahinda Yapa Abeywardena will be temporarily sworn in as the President on Wednesday for a period of 30 days during which Parliament will select a new President - any candidate who has majority support.",
        "Today the Prime Minister will call for a cabinet meeting in the evening and discuss the fuel shipments and foreign delegations which are due to arrive in the country this week. President Rajapaksa is likely to join the cabinet meeting via conference.",
        "Political sources said that those ministers who submitted their resignations will continue in their portfolios as none of the resignations has been accepted by the President.",
        "Harin Fernando, Manusha Nanayakkara, Dhammika Perera and Bandula Gunawardena were those who resigned from their ministerial portfolios over the weekend but they have been informed to attend the cabinet meeting today as their resignations have been rejected.",
        "Following the cabinet meeting, the Prime Minister has called for an All Party Leaders meeting to discuss the ongoing crisis and seek a solution soon. (JAMILA HUSAIN)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Wednesday",
          "label": "DATE"
        },
        {
          "text": "Presidential Polls",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "March",
          "label": "DATE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Gotabaya Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Wednesday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "March next year",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Daily Mirror",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "last evening",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Saturday night",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "Wednesday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Saturday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "July 13",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "last evening",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "nearly 115",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "IMF",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sajith Premadasa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Saturday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Dullas Allahapperuma",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "last evening",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sajith",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Wednesday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Rajapaksa",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "IMF",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Yapa Abeywardena",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Wednesday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "a period of",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "30 days",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Today",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "this week",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "Harin Fernando",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Manusha Nanayakkara",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Dhammika Perera",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Bandula Gunawardena",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the weekend",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        []
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "GR බදාදා ඉල්ලා අස්වන බව තහවුරු කරයි; මාර්තු වලට කලින් ජනාධිපතිවරණය",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "ජනාධිපති ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ මහතා සිය ඉල්ලා අස්වීමේ ලිපිය කථානායකවරයාට භාරදීමෙන් පසු බදාදා සිය ජනාධිපති ධුර කාලය අවසන් කරන බවත් ඉන් අනතුරුව ලබන වසරේ මාර්තු මාසයට පෙර ජනාධිපතිවරණයක් සහ පාර්ලිමේන්තු මැතිවරණයක් පැවැත්වීමට තීරණය කර ඇති බවත් ජ්‍යෙෂ්ඨ දේශපාලන ආරංචි මාර්ග ඊයේ සවස ඩේලි මිරර් වෙත පැවසීය.",
        "ජනාධිපතිවරයා බදාදා ඉල්ලා අස්වන බව කථානායකවරයා සෙනසුරාදා රාත්‍රියේ ප්‍රකාශ කළද ඔහු සැබවින්ම සිය ධුරයෙන් ඉවත් වන්නේද යන්න අවිනිශ්චිතතාවක් විය. කෙසේ වෙතත්, සෙනසුරාදා රටපුරා ඇති වූ විරෝධතාවයෙන් පසු අගමැති රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ සමඟ පැවති සාකච්ඡාවකදී රාජපක්ෂ ජූලි 13 වනදා සිය ජනාධිපති ධූරය අවසන් කරන බව තහවුරු කර ඇති අතර එමඟින් වික්‍රමසිංහට හෝ නව නායකයෙකු දිවුරුම් දීමට ඉඩ ලබා දී ඇත. .",
        "ඊයේ සවස් වනතුරු දේශපාලන පක්ෂ තුළ පැවති සාකච්ඡාවලින් අනතුරුව පාර්ලිමේන්තුවේ ආසන 115කට ආසන්න බහුතර බලයක් වික‍්‍රමසිංහ මහතා සතු විය. විශේෂයෙන්ම ජාත්‍යන්තර මූල්‍ය අරමුදල සමඟ සාකච්ඡා පැවැත්වෙන බැවින් ආර්ථික අර්බුදය අතරමග අත් නොහරින ලෙසත්, තවදුරටත් ජනාධිපති ධුරය භාර ගන්නා ලෙසත් මන්ත්‍රීවරුන් කිහිප දෙනෙකු ඔහුගෙන් ඉල්ලා තිබේ.",
        "විපක්ෂ නායක සජිත් ප්‍රේමදාස මහතා ද සෙනසුරාදා ඇති වූ කලහකාරී තත්ත්වයෙන් පසු වෙනම සාකච්ඡා පැවැත්වූ අතර තමන් ජනාධිපතිවරයා ලෙස තේරී පත් වුවහොත් තමාගේ අගමැති අපේක්ෂකයා ඩලස් අලහප්පෙරුම බව ඔහුගේ අභ්‍යන්තර කවයට පවා ඉඟි කළේය. කෙසේ වෙතත්, ඊයේ සවස් වන විටත් සජිත්ට පාර්ලිමේන්තුවේ බහුතර සහාය හිමිව නොතිබුණි.",
        "වික්‍රමසිංහ දිගටම ධූරයේ කටයුතු කරන්නේ නම්, රාජපක්ෂගේ ඉල්ලා අස්වීමෙන් පසු බදාදා ඔහු ජනාධිපතිවරයා ලෙස දිවුරුම් දෙනු ඇති අතර ජනාධිපතිවරණයක් පැවැත්වෙන තෙක් ඔහු අවධානය යොමු කරන්නේ IMF සමඟ ගනුදෙනුවක් අවසන් කර යම් ආකාරයක ආර්ථික සාමාන්‍ය තත්වයක් ඇති කර ගැනීම කෙරෙහි ය. වික්‍රමසිංහගේ අගමැති අපේක්ෂකයා කවුරුන්ද යන්න තවමත් අවිනිශ්චිත නමුත් සුදුසු අපේක්ෂකයෙකු නම් කිරීමට ඔහු පාර්ලිමේන්තුවට ඉඩ දෙනු ඇත.",
        "වික්‍රමසිංහ ඉල්ලා අස් වුවහොත්, පාර්ලිමේන්තුවේ කථානායක මහින්ද යාපා අබේවර්ධන බදාදා දින 30ක කාලයක් සඳහා ජනාධිපතිවරයා ලෙස තාවකාලිකව දිවුරුම් දෙනු ඇති අතර එම කාලය තුළ බහුතර සහාය ඇති ඕනෑම අපේක්ෂකයෙකු පාර්ලිමේන්තුව විසින් නව ජනාධිපතිවරයකු තෝරා ගනු ඇත.",
        "අද පස්වරුවේ අග්‍රාමාත්‍යවරයා කැබිනට් රැස්වීමක් කැඳවා මේ සතියේ මෙරටට පැමිණීමට නියමිත ඉන්ධන ප්‍රවාහනය සහ විදේශ නියෝජිතයින් පිළිබඳව සාකච්ඡා කිරීමට නියමිතයි. ජනාධිපතිවරයා කැබිනට් රැස්වීමට සම්මන්ත්‍රණයක් හරහා එක්වීමට බොහෝ දුරට ඉඩ තිබේ.",
        "දේශපාලන ආරංචි මාර්ග සඳහන් කළේ ඉල්ලා අස්වීම් කිසිවක් ජනාධිපතිවරයා විසින් පිළිගෙන නොමැති බැවින් ඉල්ලා අස්වීම් භාරදුන් අමාත්‍යවරුන් තවදුරටත් සිය අමාත්‍ය ධුරවල රැඳී සිටින බවයි.",
        "හරීන් ප්‍රනාන්දු, මනූෂ නානායක්කාර, ධම්මික පෙරේරා සහ බන්දුල ගුණවර්ධන සති අන්තයේ සිය අමාත්‍ය ධූරවලින් ඉල්ලා අස්වූ නමුත් ඔවුන්ගේ ඉල්ලා අස්වීම් ප්‍රතික්ෂේප වී ඇති බැවින් අද පැවැත්වෙන කැබිනට් රැස්වීමට පැමිණෙන ලෙස ඔවුන්ට දැනුම් දී තිබේ.",
        "අමාත්‍ය මණ්ඩල රැස්වීමෙන් අනතුරුව අග්‍රාමාත්‍යවරයා විසින් සර්ව පාක්ෂික නායක රැස්වීමක් කැඳවා ඇත්තේ පවතින අර්බුදය පිළිබඳව සාකච්ඡා කර කඩිනමින් විසඳුම් සෙවීම සඳහාය. (ජමිලා හුසේන්)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "බදාදා",
          "label": "DATE"
        },
        {
          "text": "ජනාධිපතිවරණ ඡන්ද",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "මාර්තු",
          "label": "DATE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "බදාදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ලබන වසරේ මාර්තු",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඩේලි මිරර්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඊයේ සවස",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "සෙනසුරාදා රෑ",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "බදාදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "සෙනසුරාදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජූලි 13",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ඊයේ සවස",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "115ට ආසන්නයි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "IMF",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "සජිත් ප්‍රේමදාස",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "සෙනසුරාදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඩලස් අලහප්පෙරුම",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඊයේ සවස",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "සජිත්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "බදාදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "IMF",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "යාපා අබේවර්ධන",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "බදාදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "කාල සීමාවක්",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "දින 30",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මෙම සතිය",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "හරීන් ප්‍රනාන්දු",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "මනූෂ නානායක්කාර",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ධම්මික පෙරේරා",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "බන්දුල ගුණවර්ධන",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "සති අන්තය",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        []
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "ஜி.ஆர் புதன்கிழமை ராஜினாமா செய்வதை உறுதிப்படுத்துகிறார்; மார்ச்சுக்கு முன் ஜனாதிபதி தேர்தல்",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "ஜனாதிபதி கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ஷ தனது இராஜினாமா கடிதத்தை பாராளுமன்ற சபாநாயகரிடம் கையளித்ததன் பின்னர் ஜனாதிபதி மற்றும் பாராளுமன்ற தேர்தலை அடுத்த வருடம் மார்ச் மாதத்திற்கு முன்னர் நடத்துவதற்கு தீர்மானிக்கப்பட்டுள்ளதாக சிரேஷ்ட அரசியல் வட்டாரங்கள் நேற்று மாலை டெய்லி மிரருக்கு தெரிவித்தன.",
        "ஜனாதிபதி புதன்கிழமை இராஜினாமா செய்வார் என்று சபாநாயகர் சனிக்கிழமை இரவு அறிவித்த போதிலும், அவர் உண்மையில் தனது பதவியில் இருந்து விலகுவாரா என்பது நிச்சயமற்றது. எவ்வாறாயினும், சனிக்கிழமையன்று நாடு தழுவிய போராட்டத்தைத் தொடர்ந்து பிரதமர் ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்கவுடன் நடத்திய கலந்துரையாடலில், ராஜபக்சே தனது ஜனாதிபதி பதவியை ஜூலை 13 ஆம் தேதி முடித்துக்கொள்வதை உறுதிசெய்தார், அதன் மூலம் விக்ரமசிங்கே அல்லது புதிய தலைவரை பதவியேற்க அனுமதித்தார். ஜனாதிபதி ராஜபக்சேவின் இருப்பிடம் இன்னும் தெரியவில்லை. .",
        "நேற்று மாலை வரை அரசியல் கட்சிகளுக்குள் நடைபெற்ற விவாதங்களைத் தொடர்ந்து, விக்ரமசிங்கே நாடாளுமன்றத்தில் கிட்டத்தட்ட 115 ஆசனங்களைக் கைப்பற்றினார். IMF உடனான பேச்சுவார்த்தை நடந்து கொண்டிருப்பதால், பொருளாதார நெருக்கடியை பாதியிலேயே விட்டுவிட வேண்டாம் என்றும், தொடர்ந்து அதிபர் பதவியை ஏற்குமாறும் பல எம்பிக்கள் அவரிடம் கோரிக்கை விடுத்துள்ளனர்.",
        "எதிர்க்கட்சித் தலைவர் சஜித் பிரேமதாசவும் சனிக்கிழமை கலவரத்தின் பின்னர் தனித்தனியாக கலந்துரையாடினார், மேலும் அவர் ஜனாதிபதியாகத் தேர்ந்தெடுக்கப்பட்டால், பிரதமர் வேட்பாளராக டலஸ் அலகப்பெருமதான் இருப்பார் என்று அவரது நெருங்கிய வட்டாரங்களுக்கு சூசகமாகத் தெரிவித்தார். எவ்வாறாயினும், நேற்று மாலை வரை, சஜித் இன்னும் பாராளுமன்றத்தின் பெரும்பான்மை ஆதரவைப் பெறவில்லை.",
        "விக்ரமசிங்கே பதவியில் தொடர்ந்தால், ராஜபக்சேவின் ராஜினாமாவைத் தொடர்ந்து அவர் புதன்கிழமை அதிபராகப் பதவியேற்பார் மற்றும் ஜனாதிபதித் தேர்தல் நடைபெறும் வரை, அவர் சர்வதேச நாணய நிதியத்துடன் ஒரு ஒப்பந்தத்தை இறுதி செய்து சில வகையான பொருளாதார இயல்புகளை மீட்டெடுப்பதில் கவனம் செலுத்துவார். விக்கிரமசிங்கவின் பிரதமர் வேட்பாளர் யார் என்பது இன்னும் உறுதியாகத் தெரியவில்லை, ஆனால் அவர் பொருத்தமான வேட்பாளரை பரிந்துரைக்க பாராளுமன்றத்தை அனுமதிப்பார்.",
        "விக்ரமசிங்க பதவி விலகினால், பாராளுமன்ற சபாநாயகர் மஹிந்த யாப்பா அபேவர்தன 30 நாட்களுக்கு தற்காலிகமாக ஜனாதிபதியாக பதவியேற்பார், இதன் போது பாராளுமன்றம் புதிய ஜனாதிபதியை தெரிவு செய்யும் - பெரும்பான்மை ஆதரவைப் பெற்ற எந்தவொரு வேட்பாளரையும் பாராளுமன்றம் தெரிவு செய்யும்.",
        "இன்று மாலை அமைச்சரவை கூட்டத்திற்கு அழைப்பு விடுக்கும் பிரதமர், இந்த வாரம் நாட்டிற்கு வரவுள்ள எரிபொருள் ஏற்றுமதி மற்றும் வெளிநாட்டு பிரதிநிதிகள் குறித்து கலந்துரையாடவுள்ளார். ஜனாதிபதி ராஜபக்ஷ மாநாடு மூலம் அமைச்சரவை கூட்டத்தில் சேர வாய்ப்புள்ளது.",
        "ராஜினாமா கடிதங்கள் எதுவும் ஜனாதிபதியால் ஏற்றுக்கொள்ளப்படாததால், ராஜினாமாவை சமர்ப்பித்த அமைச்சர்கள் தங்கள் இலாகாக்களில் நீடிப்பார்கள் என்று அரசியல் வட்டாரங்கள் தெரிவித்தன.",
        "ஹரீன் பெர்னாண்டோ, மனுஷ நாணயக்கார, தம்மிக்க பெரேரா மற்றும் பந்துல குணவர்தன ஆகியோர் தமது அமைச்சுப் பதவிகளை வார இறுதியில் இராஜினாமா செய்திருந்த போதிலும், அவர்களது இராஜினாமா நிராகரிக்கப்பட்டதால் இன்றைய அமைச்சரவைக் கூட்டத்தில் பங்கேற்குமாறு அவர்களுக்கு அறிவிக்கப்பட்டுள்ளது.",
        "அமைச்சரவைக் கூட்டத்தைத் தொடர்ந்து, தற்போது நிலவும் நெருக்கடி குறித்து விவாதித்து விரைவில் தீர்வு காண அனைத்துக் கட்சித் தலைவர்கள் கூட்டத்துக்கு பிரதமர் அழைப்பு விடுத்துள்ளார். (ஜமிலா ஹுசைன்)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "புதன்",
          "label": "DATE"
        },
        {
          "text": "ஜனாதிபதி தேர்தல்",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "மார்ச்",
          "label": "DATE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "புதன்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "அடுத்த ஆண்டு மார்ச்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "டெய்லி மிரர்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "நேற்று மாலை",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "சனிக்கிழமை இரவு",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "புதன்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "சனிக்கிழமை",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ராஜபக்சே",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜூலை 13",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ராஜபக்சே",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "நேற்று மாலை",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "கிட்டத்தட்ட 115",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "IMF",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "சஜித் பிரேமதாச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "சனிக்கிழமை",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "டலஸ் அலகப்பெரும",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "நேற்று மாலை",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "சஜித்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "புதன்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ராஜபக்சே",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "IMF",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "யாப்பா அபேவர்தன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "புதன்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஒரு காலம்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "30 நாட்கள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்த வாரம்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ராஜபக்சே",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஹரின் பெர்னாண்டோ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "மனுஷ நாணயக்கார",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "தம்மிக்க பெரேரா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "பந்துல குணவர்தன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "வார இறுதி",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        []
      ]
    }
  }
}