{
  "newspaper_id": "economy-next-com",
  "url": "https://economynext.com/sri-lankas-state-run-litro-raises-gas-prices-distribution-to-begin-july-11-97237/",
  "time_ut": 1657521000,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Sri Lanka’s state-run Litro raises gas prices, distribution to begin July 11",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Sri Lanka’s state-run Litro raises gas prices, distribution to begin July 11",
      "author": "Dulya de Silva",
      "body_lines": [
        "ECONOMYNEXT – Sri Lanka’s state run cooking gas provider Litro Gas Lanka Ltd will commence distribution to Colombo at 12.00 pm Monday July 11 after a price hike. The company requests the public to produce their electricity bill for the month of May as proof of residence in order to reduce stockpiling.",
        "The new price of a 12.5kg canister of liquid petroleum (LP) gas will be so sold at 4,910 rupees in the Colombo and Gampaha districts, while in Mullativu it is to be retailed at 5,220.",
        "Litro said in a statement that distribution will continue for Colombo and other highly populated areas on Monday  and Tuesday. Island-wide distribution will commence on Wednesday.",
        "Of the 3,725 metric-ton shipment that arrived on Sunday July 10, 70 percent is to be distributed within the Colombo district.",
        "The company said Sri Lanka Police and its paramilitary arm the Special Task Force (STF) will assist distribution. Litro has also requested public support in the matter. (Colombo/Jul11/2022)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Sri Lanka’s",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "July 11",
          "label": "DATE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Litro Gas Lanka Ltd",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "12.00 pm",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "Monday July 11",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the month of May",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "12.5kg",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "4,910",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Gampaha",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Mullativu",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "5,220",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Monday  and Tuesday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Wednesday",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "3,725 metric-ton",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sunday July 10",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "70 percent",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka Police",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Special Task Force",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "STF",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Litro",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Colombo/Jul11/2022",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ රාජ්‍ය පාලනය වන ලිට්‍රෝ සමාගම ගෑස් මිල ඉහළ නංවන අතර බෙදාහැරීම ජූලි 11 වැනිදා ආරම්භ වේ",
      "author": "දුල්යා ද සිල්වා",
      "body_lines": [
        "ECONOMYNEXT - ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ රාජ්‍ය ඉවුම් පිහුම් ගෑස් සපයන්නා වන ලිට්‍රෝ ගෑස් ලංකා ලිමිටඩ් මිල ඉහළ දැමීමකින් පසු ජූලි 11 සඳුදා දහවල් 12.00 ට කොළඹට බෙදා හැරීම ආරම්භ කරයි. තොග ගබඩා කිරීම අවම කිරීම සඳහා පදිංචිය පිළිබඳ සාක්ෂියක් ලෙස මැයි මාසය සඳහා වන විදුලි බිල්පත් ඉදිරිපත් කරන ලෙස සමාගම මහජනතාවගෙන් ඉල්ලා සිටී.",
        "කොළඹ සහ ගම්පහ දිස්ත්‍රික්කවල කිලෝග්‍රෑම් 12.5ක දියර පෙට්‍රෝලියම් (LP) ගෑස් කැනිස්ටරයක නව මිල රුපියල් 4,910කට අලෙවි කෙරෙන අතර මුලතිව්හි එය රුපියල් 5,220කට අලෙවි කිරීමට නියමිතය.",
        "ලිට්‍රෝ නිවේදනයක් නිකුත් කරමින් කියා සිටියේ සඳුදා සහ අඟහරුවාදා කොළඹ සහ අනෙකුත් ඉහළ ජනාකීර්ණ ප්‍රදේශ සඳහා බෙදා හැරීම අඛණ්ඩව සිදු කරන බවයි. දිවයින පුරා බෙදා හැරීම බදාදා ආරම්භ වේ.",
        "ජුලි 10 ඉරිදා පැමිණි මෙට්‍රික් ටොන් 3,725ක තොගයෙන් සියයට 70ක් කොළඹ දිස්ත්‍රික්කය තුළ බෙදා හැරීමට නියමිතය.",
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකා පොලිසිය සහ එහි පැරාමිලිටරි අංශය විශේෂ කාර්ය බළකාය (STF) බෙදා හැරීමට සහාය වන බව සමාගම පවසයි. මේ සම්බන්ධයෙන් ලිට්‍රෝ මහජන සහයෝගය ද ඉල්ලා ඇත. (කොළඹ/ජූලි11/2022)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "ජූලි 11",
          "label": "DATE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ලිට්‍රෝ ගෑස් ලංකා ලිමිටඩ්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "12.00 ප.ව",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජූලි 11 සඳුදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මැයි මාසය",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "12.5kg",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "4,910 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගම්පහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "මුලතිව්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "5,220 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "සඳුදා  සහ අඟහරුවාදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "බදාදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "මෙට්‍රික් ටොන් 3,725 කි",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජූලි 10 ඉරිදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "සියයට 70 කි",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකා පොලිසිය",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "විශේෂ කාර්ය බලකාය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "එස්.ටී.එෆ්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ලිට්රෝ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "කොළඹ/ජූලි11/2022",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "இலங்கையின் அரச நிறுவனமான லிட்ரோ எரிவாயு விலையை உயர்த்தியுள்ளது, விநியோகம் ஜூலை 11 முதல் தொடங்கும்",
      "author": "துல்யா டி சில்வா",
      "body_lines": [
        "ECONOMYNEXT - இலங்கையின் அரசால் நடத்தப்படும் சமையல் எரிவாயு வழங்குனரான Litro Gas Lanka Ltd, விலையேற்றத்தின் பின்னர் ஜூலை 11 திங்கட்கிழமை மதியம் 12.00 மணிக்கு கொழும்புக்கு விநியோகிக்கத் தொடங்கும். கையிருப்பைக் குறைப்பதற்காக, மே மாதத்திற்கான மின்சாரக் கட்டணத்தை வசிப்பிடச் சான்றாக சமர்ப்பிக்குமாறு நிறுவனம் பொதுமக்களைக் கேட்டுக்கொள்கிறது.",
        "கொழும்பு மற்றும் கம்பஹா மாவட்டங்களில் 12.5 கிலோகிராம் எடையுள்ள திரவ பெற்றோலிய வாயுவின் (LP) கேனிஸ்டரின் புதிய விலை 4,910 ரூபாவாகவும், முல்லைத்தீவில் 5,220 ரூபாவாகவும் விற்பனை செய்யப்படவுள்ளது.",
        "திங்கள் மற்றும் செவ்வாய் கிழமைகளில் கொழும்பு மற்றும் அதிக மக்கள் தொகை கொண்ட பிற பகுதிகளுக்கு விநியோகம் தொடரும் என்று லிட்ரோ ஒரு அறிக்கையில் தெரிவித்துள்ளது. நாடளாவிய ரீதியில் விநியோகம் புதன்கிழமை ஆரம்பிக்கப்படும்.",
        "ஜூலை 10 ஞாயிற்றுக்கிழமை வந்த 3,725 மெட்ரிக் தொன் ஏற்றுமதியில், 70 சதவீதம் கொழும்பு மாவட்டத்திற்குள் விநியோகிக்கப்பட உள்ளது.",
        "இலங்கை பொலிஸ் மற்றும் அதன் துணை இராணுவப் பிரிவான விசேட அதிரடிப்படை (STF) விநியோகத்திற்கு உதவுவதாக நிறுவனம் தெரிவித்துள்ளது. லிட்ரோ இந்த விவகாரத்தில் பொதுமக்களின் ஆதரவையும் கோரியுள்ளது. (கொழும்பு/ஜூலை11/2022)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "இலங்கையின்",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "ஜூலை 11",
          "label": "DATE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "லிட்ரோ கேஸ் லங்கா லிமிடெட்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "மதியம் 12.00 மணி",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜூலை 11 திங்கட்கிழமை",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "மே மாதம்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "12.5 கிலோ",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "4,910",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "கம்பஹா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "முல்லைத்தீவு",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "5,220",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "திங்கள் மற்றும் செவ்வாய்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "புதன்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "3,725 மெட்ரிக் டன்",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜூலை 10 ஞாயிறு",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "70 சதவீதம்",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை காவல்துறை",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "சிறப்பு அதிரடிப்படை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "எஸ்.டி.எஃப்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "லிட்ரோ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "கொழும்பு/ஜூலை11/2022",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}