{
  "newspaper_id": "daily-ft-lk",
  "url": "https://www.ft.lk/news/SLPP-violations-exacerbated-crisis-Kiriella/56-738737",
  "time_ut": 1660595792,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "SLPP violations exacerbated crisis: Kiriella",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "SLPP violations exacerbated crisis: Kiriella",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "SJB MP Lakshman Kiriella yesterday said the party will support all commendable efforts of the Government through the working Committees in Parliament. This has been communicated by the party leader to the President, Kiriella added.",
        "Over two years ago, the party had requested the then-Government to present the Chairmanship of the Finance Committee to the Opposition as per standing orders in Parliament, Kiriella said. But the Speaker and the then-Leader of the House suspended standing orders and presented the post to the ruling party.",
        "The SJB’s nominee then was Dr. Harsha De Silva, he added, and had he been Chairman of the Committee, his comments would have been received with greater credence in the house, and Sri Lanka may have approached the IMF earlier, Kiriella stated.",
        "Developed countries like the UK and Japan are ruled by governments, but working committees are often headed by Opposition members, as they are committed to point out mistakes of Government. This creates good balance, Kiriella added.",
        "Accordingly, with the Speaker and the Leader of the House not affording the Chairmanship of the Finance Committee to Dr. De Silva, they hastened the moves that plunged the country into bankruptcy, Kiriella stated. (DA)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Kiriella",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "yesterday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kiriella",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "two years ago",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Finance Committee",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Opposition",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kiriella",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "House",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "SJB",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Harsha De Silva",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kiriella",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "UK",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Japan",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Opposition",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kiriella",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "House",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "De Silva",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kiriella",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "ශ්‍රී ලංකා පොදුජන පෙරමුණ උල්ලංඝනය කිරීම් අර්බුදය උග්‍ර කළේය: කිරිඇල්ල",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "SJB පාර්ලිමේන්තු මන්ත්‍රී ලක්ෂ්මන් කිරිඇල්ල මහතා ඊයේ ප්‍රකාශ කළේ පාර්ලිමේන්තුවේ කෘත්‍යාධිකාරී මණ්ඩල හරහා ආණ්ඩුවේ සියලු ප්‍රශංසනීය ප්‍රයත්නයන්ට පක්ෂය සහාය දෙන බවයි. මේ බව පක්‍ෂ නායකයා විසින් ජනාධිපතිවරයා වෙත දන්වා ඇති බවද කිරිඇල්ල වැඩිදුරටත් පැවසීය.",
        "පාර්ලිමේන්තුවේ ස්ථාවර නියෝගවලට අනුව මුදල් කාරක සභාවේ සභාපතිත්වය විපක්ෂයට ලබාදෙන ලෙසට පක්ෂය විසින් වසර දෙකකට ඉහතදී එවකට පැවැති රජයෙන් ඉල්ලීමක් කළ බවද කිරිඇල්ල පැවසීය. එහෙත් කථානායකවරයා සහ එවකට සිටි සභානායකවරයා ස්ථාවර නියෝග අත්හිටුවා ආණ්ඩු පක්ෂයට තනතුර පිරිනැමීය.",
        "එවකට SJB හි නාමිකයා වූයේ ආචාර්ය හර්ෂ ද සිල්වා බවත්, ඔහු කමිටුවේ සභාපතිවරයා වූයේ නම්, ඔහුගේ අදහස් සභාව තුළ වඩාත් විශ්වාසදායක ලෙස ලැබෙනු ඇති බවත්, ශ්‍රී ලංකාව මීට පෙර IMF වෙත යාමට ඉඩ ඇති බවත්, කිරිඇල්ල ප්‍රකාශ කළේය.",
        "එක්සත් රාජධානිය සහ ජපානය වැනි සංවර්ධිත රටවල් ආණ්ඩු විසින් පාලනය කරනු ලැබේ, නමුත් කෘත්‍යාධිකාරී මණ්ඩල බොහෝ විට ප්‍රධානත්වය දරනු ලබන්නේ විපක්ෂයේ සාමාජිකයින් විසිනි, මන්ද ඔවුන් රජයේ වැරදි පෙන්වා දීමට කැපවී සිටින බැවිනි. මෙය හොඳ සමබරතාවයක් ඇති කරන බව කිරිඇල්ල වැඩිදුරටත් පැවසීය.",
        "ඒ අනුව කථානායකවරයා සහ සභානායකවරයා මුදල් කාරක සභාවේ සභාපතිත්වය ආචාර්ය ද සිල්වා මහතාට ලබා නොදීමත් සමඟ රට බංකොලොත් භාවයට ඇද දැමීමේ වැඩපිළිවෙළ කඩිනම් කළ බවද කිරිඇල්ල ප්‍රකාශ කළේය. (ඩීඒ)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "කිරිඇල්ල",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඊයේ",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "කිරිඇල්ල",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "අවුරුදු දෙකකට පෙර",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මූල්ය කමිටුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "විපක්ෂ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "කිරිඇල්ල",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "නිවස",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "එස්.ජේ.බී",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "හර්ෂ ද සිල්වා",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "කිරිඇල්ල",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "එක්සත් රාජධානිය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජපානය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "විපක්ෂ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "කිරිඇල්ල",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "නිවස",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ද සිල්වා",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "කිරිඇල්ල",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "SLPP மீறல்கள் நெருக்கடியை அதிகரிக்கச் செய்தன: கிரியெல்ல",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "பாராளுமன்றத்தில் செயற்குழுக்கள் ஊடாக அரசாங்கத்தின் அனைத்து பாராட்டத்தக்க முயற்சிகளுக்கும் கட்சி ஆதரவளிக்கும் என SJB பாராளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர் லக்ஷ்மன் கிரியெல்ல தெரிவித்துள்ளார். இது தொடர்பில் கட்சியின் தலைவர் ஜனாதிபதிக்கு அறிவித்துள்ளதாக கிரியெல்ல மேலும் தெரிவித்துள்ளார்.",
        "இரண்டு வருடங்களுக்கு முன்னர், பாராளுமன்ற நிலையியற் கட்டளையின் பிரகாரம் நிதிக்குழுவின் தலைவர் பதவியை எதிர்க்கட்சிக்கு வழங்குமாறு அக்கட்சி அப்போதைய அரசாங்கத்திடம் கோரியிருந்ததாக கிரியெல்ல தெரிவித்தார். ஆனால் சபாநாயகரும் அப்போதைய அவைத்தலைவரும் நிலையியற் கட்டளைகளை இடைநிறுத்தி ஆளுங்கட்சிக்கு பதவியை வழங்கினர்.",
        "அப்போது SJB யின் பரிந்துரைக்கப்பட்டவர் கலாநிதி ஹர்ஷ டி சில்வா, அவர் குழுவின் தலைவராக இருந்திருந்தால், அவரது கருத்துக்கள் சபையில் அதிக நம்பகத்தன்மையுடன் பெறப்பட்டிருக்கும், மேலும் இலங்கை இதற்கு முன்னர் IMF ஐ அணுகியிருக்கலாம் என்று கிரியெல்ல கூறினார்.",
        "இங்கிலாந்து மற்றும் ஜப்பான் போன்ற வளர்ந்த நாடுகள் அரசாங்கங்களால் ஆளப்படுகின்றன, ஆனால் செயற்குழுக்கள் பெரும்பாலும் எதிர்க்கட்சி உறுப்பினர்களால் வழிநடத்தப்படுகின்றன, ஏனெனில் அவை அரசாங்கத்தின் தவறுகளை சுட்டிக்காட்ட உறுதிபூண்டுள்ளன. இது நல்ல சமநிலையை உருவாக்குகிறது, கிரியெல்ல மேலும் கூறினார்.",
        "இதன்படி, சபாநாயகரும் சபைத் தலைவரும் கலாநிதி டி சில்வாவுக்கு நிதிக் குழுவின் தலைவர் பதவியை வழங்காத நிலையில், நாட்டை திவாலான நிலைக்கு தள்ளும் நகர்வுகளை துரிதப்படுத்தியதாக கிரியெல்ல குறிப்பிட்டார். (டிஏ)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "கிரியெல்ல",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "நேற்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "கிரியெல்ல",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இரண்டு ஆண்டுகளுக்கு முன்பு",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "நிதிக் குழு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "எதிர்ப்பு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "கிரியெல்ல",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "வீடு",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "எஸ்.ஜே.பி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஹர்ஷ டி சில்வா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "கிரியெல்ல",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "யுகே",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜப்பான்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "எதிர்ப்பு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "கிரியெல்ல",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "வீடு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "டி சில்வா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "கிரியெல்ல",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}