{
  "newspaper_id": "lankadeepa-lk",
  "url": "https://www.lankadeepa.lk/news/රජයේ-සේවක-විශ්‍රාම-වැටුපටත්-තට්ටු--කරන්න-හදනවා/101-619175",
  "time_ut": 1662098900,
  "original_lang": "si",
  "original_title": "රජයේ සේවක විශ්‍රාම වැටුපටත් තට්ටු  කරන්න හදනවා",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "They are also trying to tap the government employee pension",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "Mr. Ranjith Maddumabandara, appointed member of Samagi Janabalawega, said in Parliament that they are trying to tap the pension of government employees by adopting a contributory pension system.",
        "Mr. Maddumabandara said that pension is the right of public servants and now they are trying to work on it too.",
        "Joining the debate on the last day of the budget, Mr. Maddumabandara said that the former Prime Minister and his colleagues are giving advice to the President today."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Ranjith Maddumabandara",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Samagi Janabalawega",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Maddumabandara",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the last day",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Maddumabandara",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "රජයේ සේවක විශ්‍රාම වැටුපටත් තට්ටු  කරන්න හදනවා",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "දායකත්ව විශ්‍රාම වැටුප් ක්‍රමයක් හදා රජයේ සේවකයන්ගේ විශ්‍රාම වැටුපටත් තට්ටු කරන්න හදන බව සමගි ජනබලවේගයේ පත් කළ මන්ත්‍රී රංජිත් මද්දුමබණ්ඩාර මහතා පාර්ලිමේන්තුවේ දී පැවසීය.",
        "විශ්‍රාම වැටුප රාජ්‍ය සේවකයන්ගේ අයිතියක් බවද  දැන් එයටත් වැඩේ දෙන්න හදනවා යැයිද මද්දුමබණ්ඩාර මහතා කීය.",
        "අද ජනාධිපතිට උපදෙස් දෙන්නේ රට ප්‍රතික්ෂේප කර හිටපු අගමැති සහ ඔහුගේ සගයන් බව ද අයවැය  අවසන් දින විවාදයට එක්වෙමින් මද්දුමබණ්ඩාර මහතා කීය."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "රංජිත් මද්දුමබණ්ඩාර",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "සමගි ජනබලවේග",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "මද්දුමබණ්ඩාර",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "අවසාන දිනය",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මද්දුමබණ්ඩාර",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "அரசு ஊழியர் ஓய்வூதியத்தையும் தட்டிக் கேட்கின்றனர்",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "பங்களிப்பு ஓய்வூதிய முறையை கடைப்பிடித்து அரச ஊழியர்களின் ஓய்வூதியத்தை தட்டிக்கழிக்க முயற்சிப்பதாக சமகி ஜனபலவேகவின் நியமன உறுப்பினர் திரு.ரஞ்சித் மத்துமபண்டார பாராளுமன்றத்தில் தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "ஓய்வூதியம் என்பது அரச உத்தியோகத்தர்களின் உரிமை எனவும் தற்போது அதனையும் செயற்படுத்த முயற்சிப்பதாகவும் திரு.மத்துமபண்டார தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "வரவு செலவுத்திட்டத்தின் இறுதிநாள் விவாதத்தில் கலந்து கொண்டு உரையாற்றிய மத்துமபண்டார, முன்னாள் பிரதமர் மற்றும் அவரது சகாக்கள் இன்று ஜனாதிபதிக்கு ஆலோசனை வழங்குவதாக தெரிவித்தார்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ரஞ்சித் மத்துமபண்டார",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "சமகி ஜனபாலவேகா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "மத்துமபண்டார",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "கடைசி நாள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "மத்துமபண்டார",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}