{
  "newspaper_id": "daily-mirror-lk",
  "url": "https://www.dailymirror.lk/latest_news/President-Wickremasinghe-should-be-discharged-from-FR-petitions-filed-over-Easter-Sunday-attacks-Counsel/342-241825",
  "time_ut": 1658844456,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "President Wickremasinghe should be discharged from FR petitions filed over Easter Sunday attacks: Counsel",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "President Wickremasinghe should be discharged from FR petitions filed over Easter Sunday attacks: Counsel",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "Counsel Suren Fernando appearing for President Ranil Wickremasinghe today moved Supreme Court that his client should  be discharged from the Fundamental Rights petitions filed over Easter Sunday attacks, owing to the presidential immunity.",
        "Suren Ferndando, Counsel for the former Prime Minister and incumbent President Ranil Wickremasinghe submitted to Supreme Court that in terms of the Constitutional provisions, even the Attorney General cannot be named  to represent  his client.",
        "Fernando maintained that his Client should  be discharged from these Fundamental Rights Applications forthwith.",
        "Twelve Fundamental Rights petitions pertaining to the Easter Sunday Attacks were taken up yesterday before a fuller bench of the Supreme Court in order to enable the petitioners and relevant parties to mention their stance in respect of these Fundamental Rights applications pertaining to the maintaining of these Applications against President Ranil Wickramasinghe upon his assuming office as the President of Sri Lanka.",
        "Meanwhile, Additional Solicitor General Priyantha Navana appearing for the Attorney General stated that Immunity  does apply, in relation to former Prime Minister and incumbent President Ranil Wickremasinghe.",
        "Several Counsel appearing for the petitioners including Manohara de Silva PC, Saliya Peiris PC and Sanjeewa Jayawardena PC raised objections and stated that the provisions with regard to Immunity under Article 35 of the Constitution does not apply to the former Prime Minister and now President Ranil Wickramasinghe.",
        "Shammil Perera PC, appearing on behalf of the Archbishop of Colombo, made his submissions in concurrence with the position taken by the President's Counsel appeared for the petitioners and stated that Immunity of President under Article 35 of the Constitution, does not apply to the former Prime Minister Ranil Wickramasinghe in these Fundamental Rights  Applications.",
        "Since the issue  involved is a pure question of law, the Supreme Court directed all  parties to make submissions in this regard.",
        "Thereby, these petitions were refixed for today (27) for Faiszer Musthapha PC, the Counsel for the Former President Maithripala Sirisena to make his submissions in this regard, and for 02nd August 2022 for the other Counsel to make their submissions.",
        "Through these petitions, petitioners including Sri Lanka Bar Association are pleading an order to prosecute those who directly or indirectly responsible for terrorist attacks.  They are also claiming compensations for the victims of the terrorist attacks.",
        "The Supreme Court seven-judge-bench compromised Chief Justice Jayantha Jayasuriya, justices Buwaneka Aluvihare, L.T.B. Dehideniya, Murdu Fernando, S. Thurairajah, A.H.M.D. Nawaz and Shiran Gooneratne.",
        "Sanjeewa Jayawardena PC appeared for the Bar Association of Sri Lanka (BASL). Saliya Saliya Peiris PC, Manohara De Silva PC appeared for other Petitioners.",
        "Shammil Perera PC with counsel Varuna Senadhira and Duthika Perera appeared for the Archbishop of Colombo. (Lakmal Sooriyagoda)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Wickremasinghe",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "FR",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "Easter Sunday",
          "label": "FAC"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Suren Fernando",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickremasinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Supreme Court",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Easter Sunday",
            "label": "FAC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Suren Ferndando",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Counsel",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickremasinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Supreme Court",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Constitutional",
            "label": "FAC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Fernando",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "these Fundamental Rights Applications",
            "label": "LAW"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Twelve",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Easter Sunday Attacks",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "yesterday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Supreme Court",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickramasinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Additional Solicitor",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Priyantha Navana",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Immunity",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickremasinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Manohara de Silva",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Saliya Peiris",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sanjeewa Jayawardena",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Immunity under Article 35 of the Constitution",
            "label": "LAW"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickramasinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Shammil Perera",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Counsel",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Article 35 of the Constitution",
            "label": "LAW"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickramasinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "these Fundamental Rights  Applications",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the Supreme Court",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "27",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Faiszer Musthapha",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Maithripala Sirisena",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "August 2022",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Counsel",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka Bar Association",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "The Supreme Court",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "seven",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Jayantha Jayasuriya",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Buwaneka Aluvihare",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "L.T.B. Dehideniya",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Murdu Fernando",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "S. Thurairajah",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Shiran Gooneratne",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sanjeewa Jayawardena",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Bar Association of Sri Lanka",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Saliya Saliya Peiris",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Manohara De Silva",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Petitioners",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Varuna Senadhira",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Perera",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Lakmal Sooriyagoda",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "පාස්කු ඉරිදා ප්‍රහාරයට අදාළව ගොනු කර ඇති FR පෙත්සම්වලින් ජනාධිපති වික්‍රමසිංහ නිදහස් කළ යුතුයි - නීතිඥ",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "පාස්කු ඉරිදා ප්‍රහාරය සම්බන්ධයෙන් ගොනු කර ඇති මූලික අයිතිවාසිකම් පෙත්සම්වලින් ජනාධිපති මුක්තිය හේතුවෙන් තම සේවාදායකයා නිදහස් කරන ලෙස ඉල්ලා ජනාධිපති රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතා වෙනුවෙන් පෙනී සිටින නීතීඥ සුරේන් ප්‍රනාන්දු මහතා අද ශ්‍රේෂ්ඨාධිකරණය හමුවේ පෙත්සමක් ඉදිරිපත් කළේය.",
        "ආණ්ඩුක්‍රම ව්‍යවස්ථාවේ ප්‍රතිපාදන අනුව තම සේවාදායකයා වෙනුවෙන් පෙනී සිටීමට නීතිපතිවරයාට පවා නම් කළ නොහැකි බව හිටපු අග්‍රාමාත්‍ය සහ වත්මන් ජනාධිපති රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතාගේ නීතීඥ සුරේන් ප්‍රනාන්දු මහතා ශ්‍රේෂ්ඨාධිකරණයට කරුණු ඉදිරිපත් කළේය.",
        "ප්‍රනාන්දු කියා සිටියේ තම සේවාදායකයා මෙම මූලික අයිතිවාසිකම් අයදුම්පත්වලින් වහාම නිදහස් කළ යුතු බවයි.",
        "පාස්කු ඉරිදා ප්‍රහාරයට අදාළ මූලික අයිතිවාසිකම් පෙත්සම් 12ක් ශ්‍රේෂ්ඨාධිකරණයේ පූර්ණ විනිසුරු මඩුල්ලක් හමුවේ ඊයේ කැඳවනු ලැබුවේ මෙම මූලික අයිතිවාසිකම් අයදුම්පත් සම්බන්ධයෙන් තම ස්ථාවරය සඳහන් කිරීමට පෙත්සම්කරුවන්ට සහ අදාළ පාර්ශ්වයන්ට හැකිවන පරිදිය. ජනාධිපති රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතා ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ ජනාධිපතිවරයා ලෙස වැඩ භාරගැනීමෙන් අනතුරුව.",
        "මේ අතර නීතිපතිවරයා වෙනුවෙන් පෙනී සිටි අතිරේක සොලිසිටර් ජනරාල් ප්‍රියන්ත නාවාන ප්‍රකාශ කළේ හිටපු අග්‍රාමාත්‍ය සහ වත්මන් ජනාධිපති රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතා සම්බන්ධයෙන් මුක්තියක් අදාළ වන බවයි.",
        "පෙත්සම්කරුවන් වෙනුවෙන් පෙනී සිටි නීතිඥවරුන් වන ජනාධිපති නීතිඥ මනෝහර ද සිල්වා, සාලිය පීරිස් සහ ජනාධිපති නීතිඥ සංජීව ජයවර්ධන ඇතුළු නීතීඥවරුන් කිහිප දෙනෙකු විරෝධතා මතු කරමින් කියා සිටියේ ආණ්ඩුක්‍රම ව්‍යවස්ථාවේ 35 වැනි වගන්තිය යටතේ පවතින මුක්තිය සම්බන්ධයෙන් වන විධිවිධාන හිටපු අගමැති සහ දැන් ජනාධිපති රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහට අදාළ නොවන බවයි.",
        "පෙත්සම්කරුවන් වෙනුවෙන් පෙනී සිටි ජනාධිපති නීතීඥවරයාගේ ස්ථාවරයට එකඟ වෙමින් කොළඹ අගරදගුරුවරයා වෙනුවෙන් පෙනී සිටි ජනාධිපති නීතිඥ ෂම්මිල් පෙරේරා මහතා කරුණු දක්වමින් කියා සිටියේ ආණ්ඩුක්‍රම ව්‍යවස්ථාවේ 35 වැනි වගන්තිය යටතේ ජනාධිපතිවරයාගේ මුක්තිය හිටපු අගමැතිවරයාට අදාළ නොවන බවයි. මෙම මූලික අයිතිවාසිකම් අයදුම්පත්‍රයේදී අමාත්‍ය රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ.",
        "අදාළ ප්‍රශ්නය නීතිය පිළිබඳ පිරිසිදු ප්‍රශ්නයක් බැවින් ඒ සම්බන්ධයෙන් කරුණු ඉදිරිපත් කරන ලෙස ශ්‍රේෂ්ඨාධිකරණය සියලු පාර්ශ්වවලට නියම කළේය.",
        "මේ අනුව, හිටපු ජනාධිපති මෛත්‍රීපාල සිරිසේන මහතාගේ නීතීඥ ජනාධිපති නීතිඥ ෆයිසර් මුස්තාපා මහතාට මේ සම්බන්ධයෙන් කරුණු දැක්වීමට සහ 2022 අගෝස්තු 02 වැනි දින සෙසු නීතිඥවරයාට කරුණු දැක්වීම සඳහා මෙම පෙත්සම් අද (27) යළි කැඳවන ලදී.",
        "මෙම පෙත්සම් මගින් ශ්‍රී ලංකා නීතීඥ සංගමය ඇතුළු පෙත්සම්කරුවන් ඉල්ලා සිටින්නේ ත්‍රස්තවාදී ප්‍රහාරවලට සෘජුව හෝ වක්‍රව වගකිව යුතු පුද්ගලයින්ට එරෙහිව නඩු පවරන ලෙස නියෝගයක් නිකුත් කරන ලෙසයි. ත්‍රස්ත ප්‍රහාරයෙන් විපතට පත්වූවන්ට වන්දි ලබාදෙන ලෙසද ඔවුහු ඉල්ලා සිටිති.",
        "ශ්‍රේෂ්ඨාධිකරණ සත් පුද්ගල විනිසුරු මඩුල්ල විසින් අගවිනිසුරු ජයන්ත ජයසූරිය, බුවනෙක අලුවිහාරේ, එල්.ටී.බී. දෙහිදෙණිය, මුර්දු ප්‍රනාන්දු, එස්.තුරෙයිරාජා, ඒ.එච්.එම්.ඩී. නවාස් සහ ශිරාන් ගුණරත්න.",
        "ජනාධිපති නීතිඥ සංජීව ජයවර්ධන මහතා ශ්‍රී ලංකා නීතිඥ සංගමය (BASL) වෙනුවෙන් පෙනී සිටියේය. සෙසු පෙත්සම්කරුවන් වෙනුවෙන් ජනාධිපති නීතිඥ සාලිය සාලිය පීරිස්, ජනාධිපති නීතිඥ මනෝහර ද සිල්වා පෙනී සිටියහ.",
        "කොළඹ අගරදගුරු වෙනුවෙන් නීතීඥ වරුණ සේනාධිර සහ දුතික පෙරේරා සමඟ ජනාධිපති නීතිඥ ෂම්මිල් පෙරේරා පෙනී සිටියේය. (ලක්මාල් සූරියගොඩ)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "වික්‍රමසිංහ",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "එෆ්ආර්",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "පාස්කු ඉරිදා",
          "label": "FAC"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "සුරේන් ප්‍රනාන්දු",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රේෂ්ඨාධිකරණය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාස්කු ඉරිදා",
            "label": "FAC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Suren Ferndando",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "උපදේශක",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රේෂ්ඨාධිකරණය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ව්යවස්ථානුකූලයි",
            "label": "FAC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ප්‍රනාන්දු",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "මෙම මූලික අයිතිවාසිකම් අයදුම්පත්",
            "label": "LAW"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "දොළහයි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාස්කු ඉරිදා ප්‍රහාරය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඊයේ",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රේෂ්ඨාධිකරණය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "අතිරේක සොලිසිටර්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ප්‍රියන්ත නවනා",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ප්රතිශක්තිය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "මනෝහර ද සිල්වා",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "සාලිය පීරිස්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "සංජීව ජයවර්ධන",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ආණ්ඩුක්‍රම ව්‍යවස්ථාවේ 35 වැනි වගන්තිය යටතේ මුක්තිය",
            "label": "LAW"
          },
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ෂම්මිල් පෙරේරා",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "උපදේශක",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ආණ්ඩුක්රම ව්යවස්ථාවේ 35 වැනි වගන්තිය",
            "label": "LAW"
          },
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "මෙම මූලික අයිතිවාසිකම් අයදුම්පත්",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රේෂ්ඨාධිකරණය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "27",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ෆයිසර් මුස්තාපා",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "මෛත්‍රීපාල සිරිසේන",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "2022 අගෝස්තු",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "උපදේශක",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකා නීතිඥ සංගමය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රේෂ්ඨාධිකරණය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "හත",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජයන්ත ජයසූරිය",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "බුවනෙක අලුවිහාරේ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "එල්.ටී.බී. දෙහිදෙණිය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "මුර්දු ප්‍රනාන්දු",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "එස්.තුරෙයිරාජා",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශිරාන් ගුණරත්න",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "සංජීව ජයවර්ධන",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකා නීතිඥ සංගමය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "සාලිය සාලිය පීරිස්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "මනෝහර ද සිල්වා",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "පෙත්සම්කරුවන්",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "වරුණ සේනාධිර",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "පෙරේරා",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ලක්මාල් සූරියගොඩ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "ஈஸ்டர் ஞாயிறு தாக்குதல்கள் தொடர்பாக தாக்கல் செய்யப்பட்ட FR மனுக்களில் இருந்து ஜனாதிபதி விக்கிரமசிங்க விடுவிக்கப்பட வேண்டும்: சட்டத்தரணி",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "ஈஸ்டர் ஞாயிறு தாக்குதல்கள் தொடர்பாக தாக்கல் செய்யப்பட்டுள்ள அடிப்படை உரிமை மீறல் மனுக்களில் இருந்து ஜனாதிபதியின் விதிவிலக்கு காரணமாக தனது கட்சிக்காரரை விடுவிக்குமாறு ஜனாதிபதி ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க சார்பில் ஆஜரான சட்டத்தரணி சுரேன் பெர்னாண்டோ இன்று உச்ச நீதிமன்றத்தில் மனுத்தாக்கல் செய்துள்ளார்.",
        "அரசியலமைப்பு விதிகளின் பிரகாரம் சட்டமா அதிபரின் பெயரைக் கூட தனது கட்சிக்காரரை பிரதிநிதித்துவப்படுத்த முடியாது என முன்னாள் பிரதமரும் தற்போதைய ஜனாதிபதியுமான ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்கவின் சட்டத்தரணி சுரேன் பெர்னாண்டோ உச்ச நீதிமன்றில் சமர்ப்பித்தார்.",
        "பெர்னாண்டோ தனது வாடிக்கையாளர் இந்த அடிப்படை உரிமைகள் விண்ணப்பங்களில் இருந்து உடனடியாக விடுவிக்கப்பட வேண்டும் என்று கூறினார்.",
        "ஈஸ்டர் ஞாயிறு தாக்குதல்கள் தொடர்பான 12 அடிப்படை உரிமை மனுக்கள் நேற்று உச்ச நீதிமன்றத்தின் முழு அமர்வு முன்னிலையில் விசாரணைக்கு எடுத்துக்கொள்ளப்பட்டது. ஜனாதிபதி ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க இலங்கை அதிபராக பதவியேற்றதும்.",
        "இதேவேளை, சட்டமா அதிபர் சார்பில் ஆஜரான மேலதிக சொலிசிட்டர் ஜெனரல் பிரியந்த நாவன, முன்னாள் பிரதமரும் தற்போதைய ஜனாதிபதியுமான ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்கவுக்கு எதிராக இம்யூனிட்டி பொருந்தும் எனத் தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "மனுதாரர்கள் சார்பில் ஆஜரான சட்டத்தரணிகளான மனோகர டி சில்வா, சாலிய பீரிஸ், சஞ்சீவ ஜயவர்தன உள்ளிட்ட சட்டத்தரணிகள் ஆட்சேபனைகளை எழுப்பியதுடன், அரசியலமைப்பின் 35 ஆவது சரத்தின் கீழ் உள்ள விதிவிலக்குகள் முன்னாள் பிரதமரும் தற்போதைய ஜனாதிபதியுமான ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்கவுக்குப் பொருந்தாது எனத் தெரிவித்தனர்.",
        "மனுதாரர்கள் சார்பில் ஆஜரான ஜனாதிபதி சட்டத்தரணியின் நிலைப்பாட்டிற்கு இணங்க கொழும்பு பேராயர் சார்பில் ஆஜரான சட்டத்தரணி ஷம்மில் பெரேரா, அரசியலமைப்பின் 35ஆவது சரத்தின் கீழ் ஜனாதிபதிக்கு விதிக்கப்பட்டுள்ள விலக்குரிமை முன்னாள் பிரதமருக்குப் பொருந்தாது எனத் தெரிவித்தார். இந்த அடிப்படை உரிமை விண்ணப்பங்களில் அமைச்சர் ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க.",
        "சம்பந்தப்பட்ட பிரச்சினை சட்டத்தின் தூய்மையான கேள்வி என்பதால், இது தொடர்பாக அனைத்து தரப்பினரும் சமர்பிக்குமாறு உச்ச நீதிமன்றம் உத்தரவிட்டது.",
        "இதன்படி, இந்த மனுக்கள் இன்று (27) முன்னாள் ஜனாதிபதி மைத்திரிபால சிறிசேனவின் சட்டத்தரணியான பைசர் முஸ்தபாவுக்கும், ஏனைய சட்டத்தரணிகள் தமது சமர்ப்பணங்களை சமர்ப்பிப்பதற்கும் 2022 ஆம் ஆண்டு ஆகஸ்ட் மாதம் 02 ஆம் திகதி வரை மறுசீரமைக்கப்பட்டன.",
        "இந்த மனுக்கள் மூலம், இலங்கை சட்டத்தரணிகள் சங்கம் உள்ளிட்ட மனுதாரர்கள், பயங்கரவாதத் தாக்குதல்களுக்கு நேரடியாகவோ அல்லது மறைமுகமாகவோ காரணமானவர்களுக்கு எதிராக வழக்குத் தொடர உத்தரவிடுமாறு கோரியுள்ளனர். தீவிரவாத தாக்குதலில் உயிரிழந்தவர்களுக்கு இழப்பீடு வழங்க வேண்டும் என்றும் கோரிக்கை விடுத்துள்ளனர்.",
        "பிரதம நீதியரசர் ஜயந்த ஜயசூரிய, நீதியரசர்களான புவனேக அலுவிஹாரே, எல்.டி.பி. தெஹிதெனிய, முர்து பெர்னாண்டோ, எஸ்.துரைராஜா, ஏ.எச்.எம்.டி. நவாஸ் மற்றும் ஷிரான் குணரத்ன.",
        "சஞ்சீவ ஜயவர்தன பிசி இலங்கை சட்டத்தரணிகள் சங்கத்திற்காக (BASL) ஆஜரானார். சாலிய சாலிய பீரிஸ், பிசி மனோகர டி சில்வா ஆகியோர் மனுதாரர்களுக்காக ஆஜராகியிருந்தனர்.",
        "கொழும்பு பேராயர் சார்பாக சட்டத்தரணி வருண சேனாதிர மற்றும் துத்திகா பெரேராவுடன் சம்மில் பெரேரா ஆஜரானார். (லக்மால் சூரியகொட)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "விக்கிரமசிங்க",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "FR",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "ஈஸ்டர் ஞாயிறு",
          "label": "FAC"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "சுரேன் பெர்னாண்டோ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "உச்ச நீதிமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஈஸ்டர் ஞாயிறு",
            "label": "FAC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Suren Ferndando",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆலோசகர்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "உச்ச நீதிமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "அரசியலமைப்பு",
            "label": "FAC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பெர்னாண்டோ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்த அடிப்படை உரிமைகள் விண்ணப்பங்கள்",
            "label": "LAW"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பன்னிரண்டு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஈஸ்டர் ஞாயிறு தாக்குதல்கள்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "நேற்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "உச்ச நீதிமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "கூடுதல் வழக்கறிஞர்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "பிரியந்த நவன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "நோய் எதிர்ப்பு சக்தி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "மனோகர டி சில்வா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "சாலிய பீரிஸ்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "சஞ்சீவ ஜயவர்தன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "அரசியலமைப்பின் 35 வது பிரிவின் கீழ் நோய் எதிர்ப்பு சக்தி",
            "label": "LAW"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஷம்மில் பெரேரா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆலோசகர்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "அரசியலமைப்பின் பிரிவு 35",
            "label": "LAW"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்த அடிப்படை உரிமைகள் விண்ணப்பங்கள்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "உச்ச நீதிமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "27",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "பைசர் முஸ்தபா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "மைத்திரிபால சிறிசேன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆகஸ்ட் 2022",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆலோசகர்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை சட்டத்தரணிகள் சங்கம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "உச்ச நீதிமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஏழு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜயந்த ஜயசூரிய",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "புவனேக அலுவிஹாரே",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "எல்.டி.பி. தெஹிதெனிய",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "முர்து பெர்னாண்டோ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "எஸ்.துரைராஜா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஷிரான் குணரத்ன",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "சஞ்சீவ ஜயவர்தன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை சட்டத்தரணிகள் சங்கம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "சாலிய சாலிய பீரிஸ்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "மனோகர டி சில்வா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "மனுதாரர்கள்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "வருண சேனாதிர",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "பெரேரா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "லக்மால் சூரியகொட",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}