{
  "newspaper_id": "ada-derana-lk",
  "url": "http://www.adaderana.lk/news/83737/india-to-invest-more-in-sri-lanka-after-crisis-support-of-38-bn",
  "time_ut": 1658217180,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "India to invest more in Sri Lanka after crisis support of $3.8 Bn",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "India to invest more in Sri Lanka after crisis support of $3.8 Bn",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "India is willing to make more investments in neighbouring Sri Lanka after supporting it with $3.8 billion this year, New Delhi’s envoy in Colombo told the Indian Express newspaper.",
        "“The idea is to respond to Sri Lanka’s requests for enabling them to meet their foreign exchange crisis,” said Gopal Baglay, India’s high commissioner in Sri Lanka.",
        "“We would like to continue to bring more investment into Sri Lanka because that will help create medium- and long-term capacity to respond within the Sri Lankan economy.”"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "India",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "Sri Lanka",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "$3.8 Bn",
          "label": "MONEY"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "India",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "$3.8 billion",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "this year",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "New Delhi’s",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Colombo",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Indian Express",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka’s",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Gopal Baglay",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "India",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lankan",
            "label": "LOC"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "ඩොලර් බිලියන 3.8 ක අර්බුදකාරී ආධාරයකින් පසු ඉන්දියාව ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ තවත් ආයෝජනය කරයි",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "මේ වසරේ ඩොලර් බිලියන 3.8 ක ආධාර ලබා දීමෙන් පසු අසල්වැසි ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ තවත් ආයෝජන සිදු කිරීමට ඉන්දියාව කැමැත්තෙන් සිටින බව කොළඹ නවදිල්ලියේ නියෝජිතයෙකු ඉන්දියන් එක්ස්ප්‍රස් පුවත්පතට පැවසීය.",
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ ඉන්දීය මහ කොමසාරිස් ගෝපාල් බග්ලේ පැවසුවේ “ඔවුන්ගේ විදේශ විනිමය අර්බුදයට මුහුණ දීම සඳහා ශ්‍රී ලංකාව කරන ඉල්ලීම්වලට ප්‍රතිචාර දැක්වීමයි.",
        "\"අපි ශ්‍රී ලංකාවට තව තවත් ආයෝජන ගෙන ඒමට කැමැත්තෙමු, මන්ද එය ශ්‍රී ලංකා ආර්ථිකය තුළ ප්‍රතිචාර දැක්වීම සඳහා මධ්‍යම හා දිගුකාලීන ධාරිතාවක් ඇති කිරීමට උපකාරී වනු ඇත.\""
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ඉන්දියාව",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "ඩොලර් බිලියන 3.8",
          "label": "MONEY"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඩොලර් බිලියන 3.8 කි",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "මේ වසරේ",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "නවදිල්ලියේ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "කොළඹ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දියන් එක්ස්ප්‍රස්",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගෝපාල් බග්ලේ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලාංකික",
            "label": "LOC"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "3.8 பில்லியன் டாலர் நெருக்கடி ஆதரவுக்குப் பிறகு இந்தியா இலங்கையில் அதிக முதலீடு செய்ய உள்ளது",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "இந்த ஆண்டு 3.8 பில்லியன் டாலர்களை ஆதரித்த பிறகு, அண்டை நாடான இலங்கையில் அதிக முதலீடுகளைச் செய்ய இந்தியா தயாராக உள்ளது என்று கொழும்பில் உள்ள புது டெல்லியின் தூதர் இந்தியன் எக்ஸ்பிரஸ் செய்தித்தாளிடம் தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "\"அந்நியச் செலாவணி நெருக்கடியைச் சந்திக்க இலங்கையின் கோரிக்கைகளுக்குப் பதிலளிப்பதே யோசனை\" என்று இலங்கைக்கான இந்திய உயர்ஸ்தானிகர் கோபால் பாக்லே தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "\"இலங்கையில் அதிக முதலீட்டை நாங்கள் தொடர்ந்து கொண்டு வர விரும்புகிறோம், ஏனெனில் இது இலங்கையின் பொருளாதாரத்திற்குள் பதிலளிக்கும் நடுத்தர மற்றும் நீண்ட கால திறனை உருவாக்க உதவும்.\""
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "இந்தியா",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "இலங்கை",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "$3.8 பில்லியன்",
          "label": "MONEY"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "இந்தியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "$3.8 பில்லியன்",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்த வருடம்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "புது டெல்லியின்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "கொழும்பு",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்தியன் எக்ஸ்பிரஸ்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கையின்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "கோபால் பாக்லே",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்தியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "LOC"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}