{
  "newspaper_id": "lankadeepa-lk",
  "url": "https://www.lankadeepa.lk/news/මෝල්කාරයෝ-අපායේ-දොර-දැක-කෑ-ගහනවා/101-615685",
  "time_ut": 1656654899,
  "original_lang": "si",
  "original_title": "මෝල්කාරයෝ අපායේ දොර දැක කෑ ගහනවා",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "The millers saw the door of hell and screamed",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "The main organizer of the opposition, Samagi Jana Balawega, Kandy District Member of Parliament, lawyer Mr. Lakshman Kiriella, said, \"Maybe the millers are shouting lies today because they see the suffering of the people and see the suffering of the people.\"",
        "He also stated that what has been done so far is to exploit the innocent people of the country.",
        "He said that under the current circumstances, the date for leaving the country was unthinkable and as far as he knew, the loan from the International Monetary Fund would be around next December."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Samagi Jana Balawega",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kandy District",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Lakshman Kiriella",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "the International Monetary Fund",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "next December",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "මෝල්කාරයෝ අපායේ දොර දැක කෑ ගහනවා",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "සමහර වී මෝල් කාරයන් මිනිසුන්ගේ දුක දැක අද බොරුවට කෑ ගහන්නේ ඔවුනට අපාය පෙනෙන නිසා යැයි විපක්ෂයේ ප්‍රධාන සංවිධායක සමගි ජන බලවේගයේ මහනුවර දිස්ත්‍රික් පාර්ලිමේන්තු මන්ත්‍රී නීතිඥ ලක්ෂ්මන් කිරිඇල්ල මහතා පැවසීය.",
        "මේ දක්වා කළේ රටේ අහිංසක ජනතාව සූරාගෙන කෑම බවද ඔහු සඳහන් කළේය.",
        "පවතින තත්ව යටතේ රට ගොඩ යන දිනය සිතාගත නොහැකි බවත් තමාට දැනගන්නට ඇති ආකාරයට ජාත්‍යන්තර මූල්‍ය අරමුදලේ ණය මුදල ලැබීම ලබන දෙසැම්බර් මාසය පමණ වනු ඇති බවත් මන්ත්‍රීවරයා කීවේය."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "සමගි ජන බලවේගය",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "මහනුවර දිස්ත්‍රික්කය",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ලක්ෂ්මන් කිරිඇල්ල",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "ජාත්‍යන්තර මුල්‍ය අරමුදල",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ලබන දෙසැම්බර්",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "மில்லர்கள் நரகத்தின் கதவைப் பார்த்து அலறுகிறார்கள்",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "மக்கள் படும் துன்பங்களை கண்டு மில்லர்கள் இன்று பொய் கூச்சலிடலாம் என எதிர்கட்சியின் பிரதான அமைப்பாளர் சமகி ஜன பலவேக கண்டி மாவட்ட பாராளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர் சட்டத்தரணி லக்ஷ்மன் கிரியெல்ல தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "நாட்டில் உள்ள அப்பாவி மக்களை சுரண்டுவதுதான் இதுவரை மேற்கொள்ளப்பட்டு வருவதாகவும் அவர் குறிப்பிட்டுள்ளார்.",
        "தற்போதைய சூழ்நிலையில், நாட்டை விட்டு வெளியேறும் தேதி நினைத்துப் பார்க்க முடியாதது என்றும், தனக்கு தெரிந்தவரை, சர்வதேச நாணய நிதியத்திடம் இருந்து கடனுதவி வரும் டிசம்பரில் இருக்கும் என்றும் அவர் கூறினார்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "சமகி ஜன பலவேகா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "கண்டி மாவட்டம்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "லக்ஷ்மன் கிரியெல்ல",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "சர்வதேச நாணய நிதியம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "அடுத்த டிசம்பர்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}