{
  "newspaper_id": "daily-ft-lk",
  "url": "https://www.ft.lk/news/President-appoints-committee-to-probe-bribery-allegation-on-Japan-funded-BIA-expansion/56-737869",
  "time_ut": 1658689410,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "President appoints committee to probe bribery allegation on Japan funded BIA expansion",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "President appoints committee to probe bribery allegation on Japan funded BIA expansion",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "President Ranil Wickramasinghe has appointed a three-member committee for an investigation focusing on a request made by former Minister Nimal Siripala de Silva with immediate effect.",
        "Former Minister Nimal Siripala de Silva has requested the President to conduct an impartial investigation into the matter raised by the Leader of the Opposition in the Parliament based on the news published in electronic and print media including social media networks that a Cabinet Minister had asked for a bribe from Japan’s Taisei Corporation. The committee will be chaired by the retired High Court Judge and President’s Counsel Kusala Sarojani Weerawardena while retired Senior Deputy Inspector General of Police S.M. Wickramasinghe and retired special grade officer of the Sri Lanka Administrative Service S.M.G.K. Perera will serve as the other members of the Committee.",
        "The President has also informed that the report of the investigation should be submitted to him before 31 July."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Japan",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickramasinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "three",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Nimal Siripala de Silva",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Nimal Siripala de Silva",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Cabinet",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Japan",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Taisei Corporation",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "S.M. Wickramasinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Sri Lanka Administrative Service S.M.G.K.",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Committee",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "31 July",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "ජපානයේ අරමුදල් සහිත BIA ව්‍යාප්තිය පිළිබඳ අල්ලස් චෝදනාව විමර්ශනය කිරීමට ජනපති කමිටුවක් පත් කරයි",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "හිටපු අමාත්‍ය නිමල් සිරිපාල ද සිල්වා මහතා කළ ඉල්ලීමක් සම්බන්ධයෙන් වහාම ක්‍රියාත්මක වන පරිදි විමර්ශනයක් සඳහා ත්‍රිපුද්ගල කමිටුවක් පත් කිරීමට ජනාධිපති රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතා පියවර ගෙන තිබේ.",
        "කැබිනට් අමාත්‍යවරයෙකු ඉල්ලා සිටි බවට සමාජ මාධ්‍ය ජාල ඇතුළු විද්‍යුත් සහ මුද්‍රිත මාධ්‍යවල පළ වූ පුවත් පදනම් කර ගනිමින් විපක්ෂ නායකවරයා පාර්ලිමේන්තුවේදී මතු කළ කරුණු සම්බන්ධයෙන් අපක්ෂපාතී පරීක්ෂණයක් පවත්වන ලෙස හිටපු අමාත්‍ය නිමල් සිරිපාල ද සිල්වා ජනාධිපතිවරයාගෙන් ඉල්ලීමක් කළා. ජපානයේ Taisei සංස්ථාවෙන් අල්ලස්. විශ්‍රාමලත් මහාධිකරණ විනිසුරු සහ ජනාධිපති නීතිඥ කුසලා සරෝජනී වීරවර්ධන මහත්මියගේ ප්‍රධානත්වයෙන් කමිටුව කටයුතු කරන අතර විශ්‍රාමික ජ්‍යෙෂ්ඨ නියෝජ්‍ය පොලිස්පති එස්.එම්. වික්‍රමසිංහ සහ ශ්‍රී ලංකා පරිපාලන සේවයේ විශ්‍රාමලත් විශේෂ ශ්‍රේණියේ නිලධාරි එස්.එම්.ජී.කේ. පෙරේරා කමිටුවේ සෙසු සාමාජිකයන් ලෙස කටයුතු කරනු ඇත.",
        "එම විමර්ශන වාර්තාව ජූලි 31 වැනිදාට පෙර තමා වෙත ලබා දෙන ලෙස ද ජනාධිපතිවරයා දැනුම් දී ඇත."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ජපානය",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "තුන්",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "නිමල් සිරිපාල ද සිල්වා",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "නිමල් සිරිපාල ද සිල්වා",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "මණ්ඩල",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජපානය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Taisei සංස්ථාව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "එස්.එම්. වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකා පරිපාලන සේවය S.M.G.K.",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "කමිටුවක්",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "31 ජූලි",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "ஜப்பானின் நிதியுதவி BIA விரிவாக்கம் மீதான லஞ்ச குற்றச்சாட்டு குறித்து விசாரணை நடத்த ஜனாதிபதி குழுவை நியமித்தார்",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "முன்னாள் அமைச்சர் நிமல் சிறிபால டி சில்வா விடுத்த கோரிக்கைக்கு அமைய ஜனாதிபதி ரணில் விக்ரமசிங்க விசாரணைகளை மேற்கொள்ள மூவரடங்கிய குழுவொன்றை உடனடியாக அமுலுக்கு வரும் வகையில் நியமித்துள்ளார்.",
        "நாடாளுமன்றத்தில் எதிர்க்கட்சித் தலைவர் எழுப்பிய விவகாரம் தொடர்பில், சமூக ஊடகங்கள் உள்ளிட்ட இலத்திரனியல் மற்றும் அச்சு ஊடகங்களில் வெளியாகியுள்ள செய்திகளின் அடிப்படையில், அமைச்சரவை அமைச்சர் ஒருவரால் அது தொடர்பில் பக்கச்சார்பற்ற விசாரணை நடத்துமாறு, முன்னாள் அமைச்சர் நிமல் சிறிபால டி சில்வா, ஜனாதிபதியிடம் கோரிக்கை விடுத்துள்ளார். ஜப்பானின் Taisei கார்ப்பரேஷனிடம் இருந்து லஞ்சம். இந்தக் குழுவின் தலைவராக ஓய்வுபெற்ற உயர் நீதிமன்ற நீதிபதியும் ஜனாதிபதி சட்டத்தரணியுமான குசலா சரோஜனி வீரவர்தன செயற்படவுள்ளதுடன், ஓய்வுபெற்ற சிரேஷ்ட பிரதிப் பொலிஸ் மா அதிபர் எஸ்.எம். விக்கிரமசிங்க மற்றும் இலங்கை நிர்வாக சேவையின் ஓய்வுபெற்ற விசேட தர அதிகாரி எஸ்.எம்.ஜி.கே. பெரேரா குழுவின் மற்ற உறுப்பினர்களாக பணியாற்றுவார்.",
        "விசாரணை அறிக்கையை ஜூலை 31 ஆம் திகதிக்கு முன்னர் தம்மிடம் சமர்ப்பிக்க வேண்டும் என்றும் ஜனாதிபதி அறிவித்துள்ளார்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ஜப்பான்",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "மூன்று",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "நிமல் சிறிபால டி சில்வா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "நிமல் சிறிபால டி சில்வா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "மந்திரி சபை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜப்பான்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Taisei கார்ப்பரேஷன்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "எஸ்.எம். விக்கிரமாதித்தன்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை நிர்வாக சேவை எஸ்.எம்.ஜி.கே.",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "குழு",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "31 ஜூலை",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}