{
  "newspaper_id": "tamil-mirror-lk",
  "url": "https://www.tamilmirror.lk/செய்திகள்/கோட்டாவுக்கு-24-மணி-நேரம்-காலக்கெடு/175-300083",
  "time_ut": 1657374117,
  "original_lang": "ta",
  "original_title": "கோட்டாவுக்கு 24 மணி நேரம் காலக்கெடு",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Quota has a 24 hour deadline",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "Former President Maithripala Sirisena has said that it is the decision of the Sri Lanka Freedom Party that the Prime Minister and the President should submit to the people's vote and resign.",
        "The president of the Sri Lanka Freedom Party has stated in a statement that the president should resign within 24 hours, the prime minister should also resign, and after that all parties should be invited to form an all-party government.",
        "Today the President's Office and the Presidential Palace are occupied by people fighting for justice.",
        "The former President has said that his only demand is that President Gotabaya Rajapaksa should step down and Prime Minister Ranil Wickremesinghe should do the same as he has no mandate to hold that position.",
        "Therefore, he states that the Sri Lanka Freedom Party's view is that the President and the Prime Minister should immediately resign from their positions and an all-party government should act immediately to solve the country's problems. . (R)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Quota",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "24 hour",
          "label": "TIME"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Maithripala Sirisena",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Sri Lanka Freedom Party",
            "label": "FAC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the Sri Lanka Freedom Party",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "24 hours",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Today",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the President's Office",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Presidential Palace",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Gotabaya Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the Sri Lanka Freedom Party's",
            "label": "FAC"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "කෝටාවට පැය 24ක කාල සීමාවක් ඇත",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "අගමැතිවරයා සහ ජනාධිපතිවරයා ජනතාවගේ ඡන්දයට යටත් වී ඉල්ලා අස්විය යුතු බව ශ්‍රී ලංකා නිදහස් පක්ෂයේ තීරණය බව හිටපු ජනාධිපති මෛත්‍රීපාල සිරිසේන මහතා පැවසීය.",
        "පැය 24ක් ඇතුළත ජනාධිපතිවරයා ඉල්ලා අස්විය යුතු බවත්, අගමැතිවරයාද ඉල්ලා අස්විය යුතු බවත්, ඉන් පසු සර්ව පාක්ෂික ආණ්ඩුවක් පිහිටුවීමට සියලු පක්ෂවලට ආරාධනා කළ යුතු බවත් ශ්‍රී ලංකා නිදහස් පක්ෂයේ සභාපතිවරයා නිවේදනයක් නිකුත් කරමින් සඳහන් කර ඇත.",
        "අද ජනාධිපති කාර්යාලය සහ ජනාධිපති මන්දිරය යුක්තිය වෙනුවෙන් සටන් කරන මිනිසුන් විසින් අල්ලාගෙන සිටිති.",
        "තමාගේ එකම ඉල්ලීම ජනාධිපති ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ මහතාට එම ධුරය දැරීමට ජනවරමක් නොමැති බැවින් අග්‍රාමාත්‍ය රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතාද එම ධුරයෙන් ඉවත් විය යුතු බව හිටපු ජනාධිපතිවරයා පවසයි.",
        "එබැවින් ජනාධිපතිවරයා සහ අග්‍රාමාත්‍යවරයා වහාම සිය ධුරවලින් ඉල්ලා අස්විය යුතු බවත්, රටේ ප්‍රශ්න විසඳීමට සර්ව පාක්ෂික රජයක් වහා ක්‍රියා කළ යුතු බවත් ශ්‍රී ලංකා නිදහස් පක්ෂයේ අදහස බව ඔහු සඳහන් කරයි. . (ආ)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "කෝටාව",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "පැය 24 යි",
          "label": "TIME"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "මෛත්‍රීපාල සිරිසේන",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකා නිදහස් පක්ෂය",
            "label": "FAC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකා නිදහස් පක්ෂය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "පැය 24",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජනාධිපති කාර්යාලය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජනාධිපති මන්දිරය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකා නිදහස් පක්ෂයේ",
            "label": "FAC"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "கோட்டாவுக்கு 24 மணி நேரம் காலக்கெடு",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "மக்களின் வாக்கெடுப்புக்கு பணிந்து பிரதமரும் ஜனாதிபதியும் பதவி விலக வேண்டும் என்பது ஸ்ரீலங்கா சுதந்திரக் கட்சியின் தீர்மானம் என முன்னாள் ஜனாதிபதி மைத்திரிபால சிறிசேன தெரிவித்துள்ளார்.",
        "24 மணித்தியாலங்களுக்குள் ஜனாதிபதி பதவி விலக வேண்டும் எனவும், பிரதமரும் பதவி விலக வேண்டும் எனவும், அதன் பின்னர் சர்வகட்சி அரசாங்கத்தை அமைக்க அனைத்துக் கட்சிகளையும் அழைக்க வேண்டும் எனவும் ஸ்ரீலங்கா சுதந்திரக் கட்சியின் தலைவர் விடுத்துள்ள அறிக்கையில் குறிப்பிட்டுள்ளார்.",
        "இன்று ஜனாதிபதி அலுவலகம் மற்றும் ஜனாதிபதி மாளிகையை நீதிக்காக போராடும் மக்களே ஆக்கிரமித்துள்ளனர்.",
        "ஜனாதிபதி கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ஷ பதவி விலக வேண்டும் என்பதே தமது ஒரே கோரிக்கை எனவும், பிரதமர் ரணில் விக்ரமசிங்கவும் அந்த பதவியை வகிக்க ஆணை இல்லாததால் அதனை செய்ய வேண்டும் எனவும் முன்னாள் ஜனாதிபதி தெரிவித்துள்ளார்.",
        "எனவே, ஜனாதிபதியும் பிரதமரும் உடனடியாக தமது பதவிகளை இராஜினாமா செய்வதன் மூலம் நாட்டின் பிரச்சினைகளுக்கு தீர்வு காண்பதற்கு அனைவரும் ஏற்றுக்கொள்ளும் சர்வகட்சி அரசாங்கம் உடனடியாக செயற்பட வேண்டும் என்பதே ஸ்ரீலங்கா சுதந்திரக் கட்சியின் கருத்தாகும் என அவர் குறிப்பிடுகின்றார். . (R)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ஒதுக்கீடு",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "24 மணி நேரம்",
          "label": "TIME"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "மைத்திரிபால சிறிசேன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஸ்ரீலங்கா சுதந்திரக் கட்சி",
            "label": "FAC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஸ்ரீலங்கா சுதந்திரக் கட்சி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "24 மணி நேரம்",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜனாதிபதி அலுவலகம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜனாதிபதி மாளிகை",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஸ்ரீலங்கா சுதந்திரக் கட்சியின்",
            "label": "FAC"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}