{
  "newspaper_id": "lankadeepa-lk",
  "url": "https://www.lankadeepa.lk/news/ඉන්ධන-බෙදාහැරීම-හෙට-සිට-ඇරඹේ/101-616745",
  "time_ut": 1658309419,
  "original_lang": "si",
  "original_title": "ඉන්ධන බෙදාහැරීම හෙට සිට ඇරඹේ",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Fuel delivery will start from tomorrow",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "According to the last digit of the vehicle's registration number and the relevant date, fuel distribution will start tomorrow (21) across the country, Mr. Kumara Rajapaksa, the president of the Petrol Station Owners Association, said today (20) afternoon.",
        "Mr. Kumara Rajapaksa said that the 'National Fuel Licence' is not relevant for the distribution of that fuel and only vehicles with the last digit 3, 4 and 5 of the vehicle registration number should come to get fuel today.",
        "Ceylon Petroleum Private Tanker Association Joint Secretary D. V. In the inquiry made to Mr. Shanta Silva yesterday afternoon, he said that the tankers have not been called to report for fuel transportation until the afternoon.",
        "A senior official of the Ministry of Energy said that the Petroleum Corporation currently has a stock of nearly 80,000 metric tons of diesel and 35,000 metric tons of gasoline."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "tomorrow",
          "label": "DATE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "tomorrow",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "21",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kumara Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Petrol Station Owners Association",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "20) afternoon",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Kumara Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "3",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "5",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Petroleum Private Tanker Association",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "D. V.",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Shanta Silva",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "yesterday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "afternoon",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "the afternoon",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the Ministry of Energy",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Petroleum Corporation",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "nearly 80,000 metric tons",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "35,000 metric tons",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "ඉන්ධන බෙදාහැරීම හෙට සිට ඇරඹේ",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "වාහනයේ ලියාපදිංචි අංකයේ අවසන් ඉලක්කම සහ ඊට අදාල දිනය අනුව රටපුරා ඉන්ධන බෙදාහැරීම හෙට (21) ආරම්භ කරන බව ඉන්ධන පිරවුම්හල් හිමියන්ගේ සංගමයේ සභාපති කුමාර රාජපක්ෂ මහතා අද (20) පස්වරුවේ පැවසීය.",
        "එම ඉන්ධන බෙදාහැරීමට ‘ජාතික ඉන්ධන බලපත්‍රය’ අදාල නොවන බවත් වාහන ලියාපදිංචි අංකයේ අවසන් ඉලක්කම 3, 4 සහ 5 වන වාහන පමණක් අද දිනයේ ඉන්ධන ලබාගැනීමට පැමිණිය යුතු බවත් කුමාර රාජපක්ෂ මහතා කීය.",
        "ලංකා ඛනිජ තෙල් පෞද්ගලික ටැංකි රථ හිමියන්ගේ සංගමයේ සම ලේකම් ඩී. වී. ශාන්ත සිල්වා මහතාගෙන් ඊයේ පස්වරුවේ කළ විමසුමේදී පැවසුවේ ඉන්ධන ප්‍රවාහන සඳහා වාර්තා කරන ලෙස ටැංකි රථවලට පස්වරුව දක්වා කැඳවීමක් කර නොමැති බවය.",
        "ඛනිජ තෙල් සංස්ථාව සතුව මේ වන විට ඩීසල් මෙටි්‍රක්ටොන් 80,000 කට ආසන්න සහ පෙට්‍රල් මෙටි්‍රක්ටොන් 35,000 කට ආසන්න තොගයක් ඇති බව ද බලශක්ති අමාත්‍යංශයේ උසස් නිලධාරියකු පැවසීය."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "හෙට",
          "label": "DATE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "හෙට",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "21",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "කුමාර රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්ධන පිරවුම්හල් හිමියන්ගේ සංගමය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "20) සවස",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "කුමාර රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "3",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "5",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ඛනිජ තෙල් පෞද්ගලික ටැංකි සංගමය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඩී.වී.",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශාන්ත සිල්වා",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඊයේ",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "දහවල්",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "පස්වරුව",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "බලශක්ති අමාත්යාංශය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඛනිජ තෙල් සංස්ථාව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "මෙට්‍රික් ටොන් 80,000කට ආසන්නයි",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "මෙට්‍රික් ටොන් 35,000 කි",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "நாளை முதல் எரிபொருள் விநியோகம் தொடங்கும்",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "வாகனத்தின் பதிவு இலக்கத்தின் கடைசி இலக்கம் மற்றும் உரிய திகதியின் பிரகாரம், நாடு முழுவதும் எரிபொருள் விநியோகம் நாளை (21) ஆரம்பமாகும் என, எரிபொருள் நிரப்பு நிலைய உரிமையாளர்கள் சங்கத்தின் தலைவர் திரு.குமார ராஜபக்ஷ இன்று (20) பிற்பகல் தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "அந்த எரிபொருளை விநியோகிப்பதற்கு 'தேசிய எரிபொருள் அனுமதிப்பத்திரம்' பொருத்தமற்றது எனவும், வாகனப் பதிவு இலக்கத்தின் கடைசி இலக்கமான 3, 4 மற்றும் 5 ஆகிய இலக்கங்களைக் கொண்ட வாகனங்கள் மாத்திரம் இன்று எரிபொருளைப் பெற்றுக்கொள்ள வருமாறும் திரு.குமார ராஜபக்ஷ தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "இலங்கை பெற்றோலியம் தனியார் டேங்கர் சங்கத்தின் இணைச் செயலாளர் டி. வி. சாந்த சில்வாவிடம் நேற்று பிற்பகல் மேற்கொண்ட விசாரணையில், பிற்பகல் வரை எரிபொருள் போக்குவரத்திற்காக டேங்கர்கள் அழைக்கப்படவில்லை எனத் தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "பெற்றோலியக் கூட்டுத்தாபனத்தில் தற்போது 80,000 மெற்றிக் தொன் டீசல் மற்றும் 35,000 மெற்றிக் தொன் பெற்றோல் இருப்பு உள்ளதாக எரிசக்தி அமைச்சின் உயர் அதிகாரி ஒருவர் தெரிவித்தார்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "நாளை",
          "label": "DATE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "நாளை",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "21",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "குமார ராஜபக்ஷ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "பெட்ரோல் நிலைய உரிமையாளர்கள் சங்கம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "20) பிற்பகல்",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "குமார ராஜபக்ஷ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "3",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "5",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பெட்ரோலிய தனியார் டேங்கர் சங்கம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "டி.வி.",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "சாந்த சில்வா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "நேற்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "பிற்பகல்",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "மதியம்",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "எரிசக்தி அமைச்சகம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "பெட்ரோலியம் கூட்டுத்தாபனம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "கிட்டத்தட்ட 80,000 மெட்ரிக் டன்",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "35,000 மெட்ரிக் டன்",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}