{
  "newspaper_id": "lankadeepa-lk",
  "url": "https://www.lankadeepa.lk/latest_news/ප්‍රදේශ-රැසකට-ගිගුරුම්-සහිත-වැසි/1-619037",
  "time_ut": 1661911839,
  "original_lang": "si",
  "original_title": "ප්‍රදේශ රැසකට ගිගුරුම් සහිත වැසි",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Thunderstorms at many places",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "The Department of Meteorology says that due to the development of a lower atmospheric disturbance in Sri Lanka, there will be occasional rain or thundershowers in many areas.",
        "Accordingly, on today (31), some places in the Western, Southern, Sabaragamuwa, Central and Uva provinces will experience very heavy rains of more than 150 millimeters and some places in other provinces will experience heavy rains of more than 100 millimeters, said a spokesperson of the department.",
        "The spokesman also mentioned that the sky in the southern half of the island is heavy with clouds.",
        "The Department of Meteorology advises people to take action to avoid accidents as lightning accidents and temporary strong winds are also possible along with thunderstorms.",
        "(Diana Udayangani) The Department of Meteorology says that due to the development of a lower atmospheric disturbance over Sri Lanka, there will be occasional rain or thundershowers in many areas. Accordingly, on today (31), some places in the Western, Southern, Sabaragamuwa, Central and Uva provinces will experience very heavy rains of more than 150 millimeters and some places in other provinces will experience heavy rains of more than 100 millimeters, said a spokesperson of the department. The spokesman also mentioned that the sky in the southern half of the island is heavy with clouds. The Department of Meteorology advises people to take action to avoid accidents as lightning accidents and temporary strong winds are also possible along with thunderstorms."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "The Department of Meteorology",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Western",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Uva",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "more than 150",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "more than 100",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "half",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "The Department of Meteorology",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Diana Udayangani",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "The Department of Meteorology",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Western",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Uva",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "more than 150",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "more than 100",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "half",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "The Department of Meteorology",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "ප්‍රදේශ රැසකට ගිගුරුම් සහිත වැසි",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකාව ආශ්‍රිත පහළ වායුගෝලීය කැළඹිලි තත්වයක් වර්ධනයවීම හේතුවෙන් බොහෝ ප්‍රදේශවලට විටින් විට වැසි හෝ ගිගුරුම් සහිත වැනි ඇතිවන බව කාලගුණ විද්‍යා දෙපාර්තමේන්තුව පවසයි.",
        "ඒ අනුව අද (31) දිනයේදී බස්නාහිර, දකුණ, සබරගමුව, මධ්‍යම සහ ඌව පළාත්වල ඇතැම් ස්ථානවලට මිලිමීටර 150 ට වැඩි ඉතා තද වැසි ඇතිවන අතර සෙසු පළාත්වල ඇතැම් ස්ථානවලට මිලිමීටර 100 ට වැඩි තද වැසි ඇතිවන බව එම දෙපාර්තමේන්තුවේ ප්‍රකාශකයෙක් පැවසීය.",
        "දිවයිනේ දකුණු අර්ධයේ අහස වළාකුලින් බරව පවතින බව ද එම ප්‍රකාශකයා සඳහන් කළේය.",
        "ගිගුරුම් සහිත වැසි සමඟ අකුණු අනතුරු සහ තාවකාලික තද සුළං ද ඇතිවිය හැකි බැවින් අනතුරු වළක්වාගැනීමට ක්‍රියා කරන්නැයි කාලගුණ විද්‍යා දෙපාර්තමේන්තුව ජනතාවට දැනුම්දීමක් කරයි.",
        "(ඩයනා උදයංගනී) ශ්‍රී ලංකාව ආශ්‍රිත පහළ වායුගෝලීය කැළඹිලි තත්වයක් වර්ධනයවීම හේතුවෙන් බොහෝ ප්‍රදේශවලට විටින් විට වැසි හෝ ගිගුරුම් සහිත වැනි ඇතිවන බව කාලගුණ විද්‍යා දෙපාර්තමේන්තුව පවසයි. ඒ අනුව අද (31) දිනයේදී බස්නාහිර, දකුණ, සබරගමුව, මධ්‍යම සහ ඌව පළාත්වල ඇතැම් ස්ථානවලට මිලිමීටර 150 ට වැඩි ඉතා තද වැසි ඇතිවන අතර සෙසු පළාත්වල ඇතැම් ස්ථානවලට මිලිමීටර 100 ට වැඩි තද වැසි ඇතිවන බව එම දෙපාර්තමේන්තුවේ ප්‍රකාශකයෙක් පැවසීය. දිවයිනේ දකුණු අර්ධයේ අහස වළාකුලින් බරව පවතින බව ද එම ප්‍රකාශකයා සඳහන් කළේය. ගිගුරුම් සහිත වැසි සමඟ අකුණු අනතුරු සහ තාවකාලික තද සුළං ද ඇතිවිය හැකි බැවින් අනතුරු වළක්වාගැනීමට ක්‍රියා කරන්නැයි කාලගුණ විද්‍යා දෙපාර්තමේන්තුව ජනතාවට දැනුම්දීමක් කරයි."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "කාලගුණ විද්‍යා දෙපාර්තමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "බටහිර",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඌව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "150 ට වැඩි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "100 ට වැඩි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "අඩක්",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "කාලගුණ විද්‍යා දෙපාර්තමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ඩයනා උදයංගනී",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "කාලගුණ විද්‍යා දෙපාර්තමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "බටහිර",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඌව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "150 ට වැඩි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "100 ට වැඩි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "අඩක්",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "කාලගුණ විද්‍යා දෙපාර්තමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "பல இடங்களில் இடியுடன் கூடிய மழை",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "வளிமண்டலவியல் திணைக்களத்தின் கருத்துப்படி, இலங்கையில் குறைந்த வளிமண்டல குழப்ப நிலை உருவாகி வருவதால், பல பகுதிகளில் அவ்வப்போது மழை அல்லது இடியுடன் கூடிய மழை பெய்யும்.",
        "அதன்படி, இன்று (31) மேற்கு, தெற்கு, சப்ரகமுவ, மத்திய மற்றும் ஊவா மாகாணங்களில் சில இடங்களில் 150 மில்லிமீற்றருக்கும் அதிகமான மிக பலத்த மழை பெய்யக்கூடும், ஏனைய மாகாணங்களில் சில இடங்களில் 100 மில்லிமீற்றருக்கும் அதிகமான பலத்த மழை பெய்யக்கூடும். , திணைக்களத்தின் பேச்சாளர் கூறினார்.",
        "தீவின் தெற்குப் பகுதியில் வானம் மேக மூட்டத்துடன் காணப்படுவதாகவும் பேச்சாளர் குறிப்பிட்டுள்ளார்.",
        "இடியுடன் கூடிய மழையுடன் கூடிய மின்னல் விபத்துக்கள் மற்றும் தற்காலிக பலத்த காற்றும் வீசக்கூடும் என்பதால், விபத்துக்களை தவிர்ப்பதற்கு நடவடிக்கை எடுக்குமாறு வளிமண்டலவியல் திணைக்களம் மக்களுக்கு அறிவுறுத்தியுள்ளது.",
        "(டயானா உதயங்கனி) இலங்கைக்கு மேல் வளிமண்டலத்தில் ஏற்பட்டுள்ள தாழமுக்கம் காரணமாக அவ்வப்போது மழையோ அல்லது இடியுடன் கூடிய மழையோ பெய்யக்கூடும் என வளிமண்டலவியல் திணைக்களம் தெரிவித்துள்ளது. அதன்படி, இன்று (31) மேற்கு, தெற்கு, சப்ரகமுவ, மத்திய மற்றும் ஊவா மாகாணங்களில் சில இடங்களில் 150 மில்லிமீற்றருக்கும் அதிகமான மிக பலத்த மழை பெய்யக்கூடும், ஏனைய மாகாணங்களில் சில இடங்களில் 100 மில்லிமீற்றருக்கும் அதிகமான பலத்த மழை பெய்யக்கூடும். , திணைக்களத்தின் பேச்சாளர் கூறினார். தீவின் தெற்குப் பகுதியில் வானம் மேக மூட்டத்துடன் காணப்படுவதாகவும் பேச்சாளர் குறிப்பிட்டுள்ளார். இடியுடன் கூடிய மழையுடன் கூடிய மின்னல் விபத்துக்கள் மற்றும் தற்காலிக பலத்த காற்றும் வீசக்கூடும் என்பதால், விபத்துக்களை தவிர்ப்பதற்கு நடவடிக்கை எடுக்குமாறு வளிமண்டலவியல் திணைக்களம் மக்களுக்கு அறிவுறுத்தியுள்ளது."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "வளிமண்டலவியல் திணைக்களம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "மேற்கு",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஊவா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "150க்கு மேல்",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "100க்கு மேல்",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பாதி",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "வளிமண்டலவியல் திணைக்களம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "டயானா உதயங்கனி",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "வளிமண்டலவியல் திணைக்களம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "மேற்கு",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஊவா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "150க்கு மேல்",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "100க்கு மேல்",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாதி",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "வளிமண்டலவியல் திணைக்களம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}