{
  "newspaper_id": "virakesari-lk",
  "url": "http://www.virakesari.lk/article/132169",
  "time_ut": 1658662174,
  "original_lang": "ta",
  "original_title": "அரசியல் கைதிகளின் விபரம் கையளிப்பு !",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Hand over the details of political prisoners!",
      "author": "Digital Desk 5",
      "body_lines": [
        "The Voice of the Voiceless organization handed over the details of Tamil political prisoners who have been detained in jails for a long time to Vigneswaran, President of the Tamil People's Alliance and Member of Parliament.",
        "Voice of the Voiceless organizations met and discussed with Member of Parliament Wigneswaran at the residence of Member of Parliament Wigneswaran in Nallur and also provided details of political prisoners.",
        "It is noteworthy that Wigneswaran supported Ranil Wickramasinghe with certain conditions including the release of political prisoners while electing the President.",
        "Member of Parliament Wigneswaran promised that he would give the details of the political prisoners to the President and press for their release when he met and discussed with President Ranil Wickramasinghe."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "The Voice of the Voiceless",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Tamil",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Vigneswaran",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Tamil People's Alliance",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Nallur",
            "label": "LOC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Wigneswaran",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickramasinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Wigneswaran",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickramasinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "දේශපාලන සිරකරුවන්ගේ විස්තර බාර දෙන්න!",
      "author": "ඩිජිටල් මේසය 5",
      "body_lines": [
        "දීර්ඝ කාලයක් බන්ධනාගාරවල රඳවා සිටින දෙමළ දේශපාලන සිරකරුවන්ගේ තොරතුරු දෙමළ ජනතා සන්ධානයේ සභාපති පාර්ලිමේන්තු මන්ත්‍රී විග්නේෂ්වරන් මහතා වෙත ලබාදුන් හඬක් නැති හඬ සංවිධානයයි.",
        "Voice of Voiceless සංවිධාන විසින් විග්නේෂ්වරන් මන්ත්‍රීවරයාගේ නල්ලූර් හි පිහිටි නිවසේදී විග්නේෂ්වරන් මන්ත්‍රීවරයා හමුවී සාකච්ඡා කළ අතර දේශපාලන සිරකරුවන්ගේ විස්තර ද ලබා දුන්නේය.",
        "විග්නේෂ්වරන් ජනාධිපතිවරයා තෝරා පත් කර ගැනීමේදී දේශපාලන සිරකරුවන් නිදහස් කිරීම ඇතුළු කොන්දේසි කිහිපයක් සහිතව රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතාට සහය පළ කිරීම විශේෂත්වයකි.",
        "තමන් ජනාධිපති රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ හමුවී සාකච්ඡා කළ අවස්ථාවේදී දේශපාලන සිරකරුවන්ගේ තොරතුරු ජනාධිපතිවරයාට ලබාදී ඔවුන් නිදහස් කිරීමට බලපෑම් කරන බවට විග්නේෂ්වරන් මන්ත්‍රීවරයා පොරොන්දු විය."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "හඬක් නැති අයගේ හඬ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "දෙමළ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "විග්නේෂ්වරන්",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "දෙමළ ජනතා සන්ධානය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "නල්ලුර්",
            "label": "LOC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "විග්නේෂ්වරන්",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "විග්නේෂ්වරන්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "அரசியல் கைதிகளின் விபரம் கையளிப்பு !",
      "author": "Digital Desk 5",
      "body_lines": [
        "நீண்ட காலமாக  சிறைச்சாலைகளில் தடுத்து வைக்கப்பட்டுள்ள தமிழ் அரசியல் கைதிகளின் விபரங்களை குரலற்றவர்களின் குரல் அமைப்பு, தமிழ் மக்கள் கூட்டணியின் தலைவரும்நாடாளுமன்ற உறுப்பினருமான விக்னேஸ்வரனிடம் கையளித்தது.",
        "நல்லூரில் அமைந்துள்ள நாடாளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர் விக்னேஸ்வரனின் வாசஸ்தலத்தில் இன்றைய தினம் ஞாயிற்றுக்கிழமை  குரலற்றவர்களின் குரல் அமைப்பினர் நாடாளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர் விக்னேஸ்வரனை சந்தித்து கலந்துரையாடியதுடன் அரசியல் கைதிகளினுடைய விபரங்களையும் வழங்கினர்.",
        "ஜனாதிபதியை தெரிவு செய்யும்போது அரசியல் கைதி விடுதலை உள்ளிட்ட சில நிபந்தனைகளுடன் ரணில் விக்ரமசிங்கவிற்கு விக்னேஸ்வரன் ஆதரவளித்தமை குறிப்பிடத்தக்கது.",
        "ஜனாதிபதி ரணில் விக்ரமசிங்கவை சந்தித்து கலந்துரையாடும் போது அரசியல் கைதிகளின் விபரங்களை ஜனாதிபதியிடம் கொடுத்து அவர்களின் விடுதலைக்காக வலியுறுத்துவேன் என நாடாளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர் விக்னேஸ்வரன் உறுதியளித்தார்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "குரலற்றவர்களின் குரல்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "தமிழ்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "விக்னேஸ்வரன்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "தமிழ் மக்கள் கூட்டமைப்பு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "நல்லூர்",
            "label": "LOC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "விக்னேஸ்வரன்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "விக்னேஸ்வரன்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}