{
  "newspaper_id": "ada-lk",
  "url": "https://www.ada.lk/breaking_news/අනුරගේ-වාහනයට-තෙල්-එන-හැටි-අනුර-හෙළිකරයි/11-395078",
  "time_ut": 1656921507,
  "original_lang": "si",
  "original_title": "අනුරගේ වාහනයට තෙල් එන හැටි අනුර හෙළිකරයි",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Anura reveals how oil gets into Anura's vehicle",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "Janata Vimukthi Peramuna leader Mr. Anura Kumara Dissanayake stated that the party members get fuel from queues in the petrol stations for the vehicles of their party and they have never used the privileges of MPs to get fuel.",
        "He mentioned this in a press conference held today in Colombo. In a press conference held yesterday, Minister of Power and Energy Mr. Kanchana Wijesekera questioned how Mr. Anura Kumara Dissanayake will get oil when there is no oil in the country.",
        "He also said that when oil was given to parliamentarians from Narahenpitin, he refused both the occasions when he was asked to give oil from the parliament a few days ago.",
        "However, he said that in the last few days luxury vehicles had taken fuel from Kolonnawa Terminal.",
        "He also mentioned that Minister Kanchana Wijesekera should pay attention to those matters."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Anura",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "Anura",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Janata Vimukthi Peramuna",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Anura Kumara Dissanayake",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "yesterday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kanchana Wijesekera",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Anura Kumara Dissanayake",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Narahenpitin",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "a few days ago",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the last few days",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kolonnawa Terminal",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Kanchana Wijesekera",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "අනුරගේ වාහනයට තෙල් එන හැටි අනුර හෙළිකරයි",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "තම පක්ෂයෙ ඇති වාහන වෙනුවෙන් පක්ෂ සාමාජිකයන් ඉන්ධන හල් තුළ පෝලිම්වල සිට ඉන්ධන ලබා ගන්නා බවත් කිසිම අවස්ථාවක මන්ත්‍රී වරප්‍රසාද භාවිත කරමින් ඉන්ධන ලබාගෙන නොමැති බවත් ජනතා විමුක්ති පෙරමුණේ නායක අනුර කුමාර දිසානායක මහතා පැවැසිය.",
        "කොළඹදී අද පැවැති මාධ්‍ය හමුවකදි ඔහු මේ බව සඳහන් කළේය. ඊයේ පැවැති මාධ්‍ය හමුවකදී විදුලි බල හා බලශක්ති අමාත්‍ය කාංචන විජේසේකර මහතා ප්‍රශ්න කළේ රටේම තෙල් නොමැති අවස්ථාවක අනුර කුමාර දිසානායක මහතාට තෙල් ලැබෙන්නේ කොහොමද යනුවෙනි.",
        "පාර්ලිමේන්තු මනත්‍රීවරුන්ට නාරාහේන්පිටින් තෙල් ලබාදුන් අවස්තාවේදී මීට දින කිහිපයකට පෙර පාර්ලිමේන්තුවෙන් තෙල් ලබාදීමට කථා කළ අවස්ථාවේදීත් තමන් එම අවස්ථා දෙකම ප්‍රතික්ෂේප කළ බවද ඔහු පැවැසීය.",
        "කෙසේ වෙතත් පසුගිය දින කිහිපයේදී කොලොන්නාව පර්යන්තයෙන් සුඛෝපභෝගි වාහන ඉන්ධන ලබාගෙන තිබුණ බවත් ඔහු පැවැසීය.",
        "අමාත්‍ය කංචන විජේසේකර මහතා එම කරුණු පිළිබඳව අවධානය යොමුකළ යුතුව ඇතැයිද ඔහු සඳහන් කළේය."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "අනුර",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "අනුර",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ජනතා විමුක්ති පෙරමුණ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "අනුර කුමාර දිසානායක",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඊයේ",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "කාංචන විජේසේකර",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "අනුර කුමාර දිසානායක",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "නාරාහේන්පිටින්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "දින කිහිපයකට පෙර",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "පසුගිය දින කිහිපය",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "කොළොන්නාව පර්යන්තය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "කාංචන විජේසේකර",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "அநுரவின் வாகனத்தில் எண்ணெய் எவ்வாறு நுழைகிறது என்பதை அனுர வெளிப்படுத்துகிறார்",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "ஜனதா விமுக்தி பெரமுனவின் தலைவர் திரு அனுரகுமார திஸாநாயக்க, கட்சியினர் தமது கட்சியின் வாகனங்களுக்கு எரிபொருள் நிரப்பு நிலையங்களில் வரிசையில் நின்று எரிபொருளை பெற்றுக் கொள்வதாகவும், பாராளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர்களின் சிறப்புரிமையை அவர்கள் ஒருபோதும் எரிபொருள் பெற பயன்படுத்தவில்லை எனவும் தெரிவித்துள்ளார்.",
        "கொழும்பில் இன்று நடைபெற்ற ஊடகவியலாளர் சந்திப்பில் அவர் இதனைக் குறிப்பிட்டுள்ளார். நேற்று நடைபெற்ற ஊடகவியலாளர் சந்திப்பில் மின்வலு மற்றும் எரிசக்தி அமைச்சர் திரு.காஞ்சன விஜேசேகர, நாட்டில் எண்ணெய் இல்லாத போது திரு.அனுரகுமார திஸாநாயக்கவுக்கு எவ்வாறு எண்ணெய் கிடைக்கும் என கேள்வி எழுப்பினார்.",
        "நாரஹேன்பிட்டியில் இருந்து பாராளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர்களுக்கு எண்ணெய் வழங்கப்பட்ட போது, ​​சில நாட்களுக்கு முன்னர் பாராளுமன்றத்தில் இருந்து எண்ணெய் வழங்குமாறு கேட்ட போது இரண்டு சந்தர்ப்பங்களிலும் தாம் மறுத்ததாகவும் அவர் கூறினார்.",
        "எவ்வாறாயினும், கடந்த சில நாட்களாக கொலன்னாவ முனையத்தில் இருந்து சொகுசு வாகனங்கள் எரிபொருளை எடுத்துச் சென்றதாக அவர் கூறினார்.",
        "அந்த விடயங்கள் தொடர்பில் அமைச்சர் காஞ்சன விஜேசேகர கவனம் செலுத்த வேண்டும் எனவும் அவர் குறிப்பிட்டுள்ளார்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "அனுர",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "அனுர",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ஜனதா விமுக்தி பெரமுனா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "அனுரகுமார திஸாநாயக்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "நேற்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "காஞ்சனா விஜேசேகர",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "அனுரகுமார திஸாநாயக்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "நாராஹென்பிடின்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஒரு சில நாட்களுக்கு முன்பு",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "கடந்த சில நாட்களாக",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "கொலன்னாவ முனையம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "காஞ்சனா விஜேசேகர",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}