{
  "newspaper_id": "lankadeepa-lk",
  "url": "https://www.lankadeepa.lk/news/කන්කසන්තුරේ-සිට-මුරුක්කන්ඩි-දක්වා-නව-දුම්රියක්/101-616253",
  "time_ut": 1657539269,
  "original_lang": "si",
  "original_title": "කන්කසන්තුරේ සිට මුරුක්කන්ඩි දක්වා නව දුම්රියක්",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "A new train from Kankasanthure to Murukkandi",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "Focusing on the demand for trains, a new train from Kankasanthure to Kilinochchi Murukkandi started running yesterday (11).",
        "This slow train will start its journey from Kankasanthure station at 6.00 am and reach Kilinochchiya station at 7.50 am and Murukkandi station at 8.11 am.",
        "The train departs from Murukkandi railway station at 8.30 am and reaches Kankasanthure station at 10.41 am.",
        "The train departs from Kankasanthure station at 2.00 pm and reaches Murukkandi station at 4.10 pm and departs from Murukkandi station at 4.40 pm to reach Kankasanthure station by 7.00 pm.",
        "According to the request of Fisheries Minister Douglas Devananda, the Railway Department deployed this train on the instructions of Transport and Highways Minister Dr. Bandula Gunawardena.",
        "Dr. Bandula Gunawardena, Minister of Transport and Highways, said that the new train was added for the convenience of the passengers in the Northern Province in order to maintain their daily activities without interruption due to the fuel crisis that people are currently facing and due to the fact that bus fares are very high."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Murukkandi",
          "label": "NORP"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Kankasanthure",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kilinochchi Murukkandi",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "yesterday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "11",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Kankasanthure",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "6.00 am",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kilinochchiya",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "7.50 am",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "Murukkandi",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "8.11 am",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Murukkandi",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "8.30 am",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "10.41 am",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Kankasanthure",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "2.00 pm",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "Murukkandi",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "4.10 pm",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "Murukkandi",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "4.40 pm",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kankasanthure",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "7.00 pm",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Fisheries",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Douglas Devananda",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Railway Department",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Bandula Gunawardena",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Bandula Gunawardena",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Northern Province",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "daily",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "කන්කසන්තුරේ සිට මුරුක්කන්ඩි දක්වා නව දුම්රියක්",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "දුම්රිය සඳහා ඇති ඉල්ලුම පිළිබඳව අවධානය යොමුකරමින් කන්කසන්තුරේ සිට කිලිනොච්චිය මුරුක්කන්ඩි දක්වා නව දුම්රියක් ඊයේ (11) ධාවනය ආරම්භ කළේය.",
        "මෙම මන්දගාමී දුම්රිය කන්කසන්තුරේ දුම්රිය ස්ථානයෙන් පෙරවරු 6.00 ට ගමන් ආරම්භ කර පෙරවරු 7.50 ට කිලිනොච්චිය දුම්රිය ස්ථානයටත් පෙරවරු 8.11 ට මුරුක්කන්ඩි දුම්රිය ස්ථානයට ළගා වීමට නියමිතය.",
        "නැවත පෙරවරු 8.30 ට මුරුක්කන්ඩි දුම්රිය ස්ථානයෙන් කන්කසන්තුරේ බලා පිටත් වන එම දුම්රිය පෙරවරු 10.41 වන විට කන්කසන්තුරේ දුම්රිය ස්ථානයට ලඟාවේ.",
        "එම දුම්රිය නැවත පස්වරු 2.00 ට කන්කසන්තුරේ දුම්රිය ස්ථානයෙන් ගමන් ආරම්භ කර පස්වරු 4.10 ට මුරුක්කන්ඩි දුම්රිය ස්ථානය වෙත පැමිණ නැවත පස්වරු 4.40 ට මුරුක්කන්ඩි දුම්රිය ස්ථානයෙන් කන්කසන්තුරේ බලා පිටත් වන එම දුම්රිය පස්වරු 7.00 වන විට කන්කසන්තුරේ දුම්රිය ස්ථානයට ලඟාවීමට නියමිතය",
        "ධීවර අමාත්‍ය ඩග්ලස් දේවානන්ද මහතාගේ ඉල්ලීමකට අනුව ප්‍රවාහන හා මහාමාර්ග අමාත්‍ය ආචාර්ය බන්දුල ගුණවර්ධන මහතාගේ උපදෙස් පරිදි දුම්රිය දෙපාර්තමේන්තුව මෙම දුම්රිය යෙදවීය.",
        "ජනතාව මේ වන විට මුහුණු දෙන ඉන්ධන අර්බුදය හේතුවෙන් ඔවුන්ගේ දෛනික කටයුතු බාධාවකින් තොරව පවත්වා ගැනීමටත්, බස් ගාස්තු ඉතා ඉහළ අගයක පැවතීම හේතුවෙන් උතුරු පළාතේ මඟී ජනතාවගේ පහසුව උදෙසා මෙම නව දුම්රිය ධාවනයට එක් කළ බව ප්‍රවාහන හා මහාමාර්ග අමාත්‍ය ආචාර්ය බන්දුල ගුණවර්ධන මහතා පැවසීය."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "මුරුක්කන්ඩි",
          "label": "NORP"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "කන්කසන්තුරේ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "කිලිනොච්චි මුරුක්කන්ඩි",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඊයේ",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "11",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "කන්කසන්තුරේ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "6.00 පෙ.ව",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "කිලිනොච්චිය",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "7.50 ට",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "මුරුක්කන්ඩි",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "8.11 පෙ.ව",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "මුරුක්කන්ඩි",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "8.30 ට",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "10.41 පෙ.ව",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "කන්කසන්තුරේ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "2.00 ප.ව",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "මුරුක්කන්ඩි",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "4.10 ප.ව",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "මුරුක්කන්ඩි",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "4.40 ප.ව",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "කන්කසන්තුරේ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "7.00 ප.ව",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ධීවර",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඩග්ලස් දේවානන්ද",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "දුම්රිය දෙපාර්තමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "බන්දුල ගුණවර්ධන",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "බන්දුල ගුණවර්ධන",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "උතුරු පළාත",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "දිනපතා",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "காங்கசந்தூரிலிருந்து முருக்கண்டிக்கு புதிய ரயில்",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "புகையிரத தேவையை மையமாக வைத்து காங்கேசன்துறையில் இருந்து கிளிநொச்சி முறுக்கண்டி வரையிலான புதிய புகையிரதமொன்று நேற்று (11) ஆரம்பமாகியது.",
        "இந்த மெதுவான ரயில் காலை 6.00 மணிக்கு காங்கசந்துறை நிலையத்திலிருந்து தனது பயணத்தை ஆரம்பித்து 7.50 மணிக்கு கிளிநொச்சி நிலையத்தையும் 8.11 மணிக்கு முருக்கண்டி நிலையத்தையும் சென்றடையும்.",
        "முருக்கண்டி ரயில் நிலையத்தில் இருந்து காலை 8.30 மணிக்கு புறப்படும் ரயில் 10.41 மணிக்கு காங்கசந்தூர் நிலையத்தை சென்றடைகிறது.",
        "காங்கசந்துறை நிலையத்திலிருந்து பிற்பகல் 2.00 மணிக்குப் புறப்பட்டு 4.10 மணிக்கு முறுக்கண்டி நிலையத்தை அடைந்து 4.40 மணிக்கு முருக்கண்டி நிலையத்திலிருந்து புறப்பட்டு இரவு 7.00 மணிக்கு காங்கசந்துறை நிலையத்தைச் சென்றடையும்.",
        "கடற்றொழில் அமைச்சர் டக்ளஸ் தேவானந்தாவின் வேண்டுகோளுக்கு இணங்க, போக்குவரத்து மற்றும் நெடுஞ்சாலைகள் அமைச்சர் கலாநிதி பந்துல குணவர்தனவின் பணிப்புரைக்கு அமைய புகையிரத திணைக்களம் இந்த புகையிரதத்தை சேவையில் ஈடுபடுத்தியுள்ளது.",
        "வடமாகாண மக்கள் தற்போது எதிர்நோக்கி வரும் எரிபொருள் நெருக்கடி காரணமாக அவர்களின் அன்றாட நடவடிக்கைகளை இடையூறுகள் இன்றி மேற்கொள்ளும் வகையில் அவர்களின் வசதிக்காகவே புதிய ரயில் சேர்க்கப்பட்டுள்ளதாக போக்குவரத்து மற்றும் நெடுஞ்சாலைகள் அமைச்சர் கலாநிதி பந்துல குணவர்தன தெரிவித்தார். அதிக பஸ் கட்டணத்திற்கு."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "முறுக்கண்டி",
          "label": "NORP"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "காங்கசந்துரே",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "கிளிநொச்சி முறுக்கண்டி",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "நேற்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "11",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "காங்கசந்துரே",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "காலை 6.00 மணி",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "கிளிநொச்சியா",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "காலை 7.50 மணி",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "முறுக்கண்டி",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "காலை 8.11 மணி",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "முறுக்கண்டி",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "காலை 8.30 மணி",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "காலை 10.41 மணி",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "காங்கசந்துரே",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "மதியம் 2.00 மணி",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "முறுக்கண்டி",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "மாலை 4.10 மணி",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "முறுக்கண்டி",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "மாலை 4.40 மணி",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "காங்கசந்துரே",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "மாலை 7.00 மணி",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "மீன்வளம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "டக்ளஸ் தேவானந்தா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரயில்வே துறை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "பந்துல குணவர்தன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பந்துல குணவர்தன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "வடக்கு மாகாணம்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "தினசரி",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}