{
  "newspaper_id": "economy-next-com",
  "url": "https://economynext.com/sri-lankas-party-leaders-to-hold-meeting-to-find-solutions-as-july-9th-protest-continues-97176/",
  "time_ut": 1657362720,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Sri Lanka’s party leaders to hold meeting to find solutions as July 9th protest continues",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Sri Lanka’s party leaders to hold meeting to find solutions as July 9th protest continues",
      "author": "",
      "body_lines": [
        "ECONOMYNEXT – Following a meeting held by Prime Minister Ranil Wickremesinghe, Sri Lanka’s party leaders are said to hold a meeting to discuss the subsequent steps to resolve the situation in the country as protesters take over the President’s official residence.",
        "Prime Minister Ranil Wickremesinghe held discussions with several party leaders on July 09th afternoon as protesters continued to break into President Gotabaya Rajapaksa’s official residence demanding his resignation.",
        "“All party leaders are scheduled to meet shortly at a meeting organised by the Speaker of the Parliament to decide on the next steps to be taken to resolve the situation in the country,” his office said.",
        "Protestors have also invaded the Presidential Secretariat, located nearby by the Galle Face Green, where protests have been held for months for the same cause.  (Colombo/Jul09/2022)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Sri Lanka’s",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "July 9th",
          "label": "DATE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka’s",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "July 09th",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Gotabaya Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the Galle Face Green",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "months",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "ජුලි 9 විරෝධතා අඛණ්ඩව පවතින බැවින් විසඳුම් සෙවීම සඳහා ශ්‍රී ලංකා පක්ෂ නායක රැස්වීමක්",
      "author": "",
      "body_lines": [
        "ECONOMYNEXT - අග්‍රාමාත්‍ය රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතා විසින් පවත්වන ලද සාකච්ඡාවකින් අනතුරුව විරෝධතාකරුවන් ජනාධිපති නිල නිවස අත්පත් කර ගැනීමත් සමඟ රටේ උද්ගතව ඇති තත්ත්වය සමථයකට පත් කිරීම සඳහා ඉදිරි ක්‍රියාමාර්ග පිළිබඳව සාකච්ඡා කිරීමට ශ්‍රී ලංකා පක්ෂ නායක රැස්වීමක් පැවැත්වීමට නියමිත බව පැවසේ.",
        "ජනාධිපති ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ මහතාට ඉල්ලා අස්වන ලෙස බලකරමින් විරෝධතාකරුවන් දිගින් දිගටම ජනාධිපති ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ මහතාගේ නිල නිවසට කඩා වැදීම හේතුවෙන් අග්‍රාමාත්‍ය රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතා පක්ෂ නායකයින් කිහිප දෙනෙකු සමඟ ජුලි 09 පස්වරුවේ සාකච්ඡා පැවැත්වීය.",
        "“රටේ උද්ගතව ඇති තත්ත්වය විසඳීම සඳහා ගත යුතු ඉදිරි ක්‍රියාමාර්ග පිළිබඳව තීරණය කිරීම සඳහා පාර්ලිමේන්තුවේ කථානායකවරයා විසින් සංවිධානය කරන ලද රැස්වීමකදී සියලුම පක්ෂ නායකයින් නුදුරේදීම රැස්වීමට නියමිතය,” ඔහුගේ කාර්යාලය පවසයි.",
        "එම හේතුව මුල්කර ගනිමින් මාස ගණනාවක් තිස්සේ විරෝධතා පවත්වනු ලබන ගාලුමුවදොර පිටිය අසල පිහිටි ජනාධිපති ලේකම් කාර්යාලයටද විරෝධතාකරුවන් කඩා වැදී ඇත. (කොළඹ/ජූලි 09/2022)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "ජූලි 9",
          "label": "DATE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජූලි 09",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ගාලු මුවදොර පිටිය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "මාස",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "ஜூலை 9 ஆம் திகதி போராட்டம் தொடரும் நிலையில், தீர்வு காணும் நோக்கில் இலங்கையின் கட்சித் தலைவர்கள் கூட்டம் நடத்தப்படவுள்ளது",
      "author": "",
      "body_lines": [
        "பொருளாதாரம் - பிரதமர் ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க நடத்திய சந்திப்பைத் தொடர்ந்து, ஜனாதிபதியின் உத்தியோகபூர்வ இல்லத்தை போராட்டக்காரர்கள் கைப்பற்றியதையடுத்து, நாட்டில் நிலவும் நிலைமையைத் தீர்ப்பதற்கான அடுத்தடுத்த நடவடிக்கைகள் குறித்து விவாதிக்க இலங்கையின் கட்சித் தலைவர்கள் கூட்டமொன்றை நடத்தவுள்ளதாக கூறப்படுகிறது.",
        "ஜனாதிபதி கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்சவை பதவி விலகுமாறு கோரி அவரது உத்தியோகபூர்வ இல்லத்துக்குள் ஆர்ப்பாட்டக்காரர்கள் தொடர்ந்து அத்துமீறி நுழைந்த நிலையில், பிரதமர் ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க, ஜூலை 09 ஆம் திகதி பிற்பகல் பல கட்சித் தலைவர்களுடன் கலந்துரையாடினார்.",
        "“நாட்டில் நிலவும் நிலைமையைத் தீர்ப்பதற்கு எடுக்கப்பட வேண்டிய அடுத்தகட்ட நடவடிக்கைகள் குறித்து முடிவெடுப்பதற்காக நாடாளுமன்ற சபாநாயகரால் ஏற்பாடு செய்யப்பட்ட கூட்டத்தில் அனைத்துக் கட்சித் தலைவர்களும் விரைவில் கூடவுள்ளனர்” என்று அவரது அலுவலகம் தெரிவித்துள்ளது.",
        "இதே காரணத்திற்காக பல மாதங்களாக போராட்டங்கள் நடத்தப்பட்டு வரும் காலி முகத்திடல் மைதானத்திற்கு அருகில் அமைந்துள்ள ஜனாதிபதி செயலகத்திற்கும் எதிர்ப்பாளர்கள் படையெடுத்துள்ளனர். (கொழும்பு/ஜூலை09/2022)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "இலங்கையின்",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "ஜூலை 9",
          "label": "DATE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கையின்",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜூலை 09",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Galle Face Green",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "மாதங்கள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}