{
  "newspaper_id": "ada-derana-lk",
  "url": "http://www.adaderana.lk/news/83523/police-curfew-orders-to-be-lifted",
  "time_ut": 1657332300,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Police curfew orders to be lifted",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Police curfew orders to be lifted",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "Police curfew imposed in parts of the Western Province last night (July 08) will be lifted at 8.00 a.m. today (July 09), Sri Lanka Police says.",
        "Ahead of the mass protests planned for today, the Inspector-General of Police (IGP) announced last night that Negombo, Kelaniya, Nugegoda, Mount Lavinia, Colombo North, Colombo South and Colombo Central police areas will be under police curfew orders from 9.00 p.m. yesterday until further notice.",
        "He also urged the residents of these areas to remain indoors while the curfew is effective and stressed law will be enforced strictly against those who violate the order.",
        "However, the move came under criticism of various parties including the Bar Association of Sri Lanka (BASL) and the Opposition. Calling the imposition of police curfew illegal, they pointed out that it is also a violation of the fundamental rights of the people of the country who are protesting against the incumbent President and the government.",
        "In a statement, the BASL questioned the police chief as to under what authority he declared the curfew order.",
        "Noting that the declaration of curfew is clearly intended to stifle the freedom of expression and dissent, the association said the move is “totally unacceptable and undemocratic”."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "the Western Province",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "last night",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "July 08",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "8.00 a.m.",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "July 09",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka Police",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "IGP",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "last night",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "Negombo",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kelaniya",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Nugegoda",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Mount Lavinia",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Colombo North, Colombo South and Colombo Central",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "9.00 p.m.",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "yesterday",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "the Bar Association of Sri Lanka",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Opposition",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "BASL",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        []
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "පොලිස් ඇඳිරි නීතිය ඉවත් කිරීමට නියෝග",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "බස්නාහිර පළාතේ ප්‍රදේශ කිහිපයකට ඊයේ (ජුලි 08) රාත්‍රියේ පනවා තිබූ පොලිස් ඇඳිරි නීතිය අද (ජුලි 09) පෙරවරු 8.00ට ඉවත් කරන බව ශ්‍රී ලංකා පොලිසිය පවසයි.",
        "අද පැවැත්වීමට නියමිත ජනතා විරෝධතා ව්‍යාපාරයට පෙරාතුව, මීගමුව, කැලණිය, නුගේගොඩ, ගල්කිස්ස, කොළඹ උතුර, කොළඹ දකුණ සහ කොළඹ මධ්‍යම යන පොලිස් බල ප්‍රදේශවලට රාත්‍රී 9.00 සිට පොලිස් ඇඳිරි නීතිය ක්‍රියාත්මක කරන බව පොලිස්පතිවරයා ඊයේ රාත්‍රියේ නිවේදනය කළේය. ඊයේ නැවත දැනුම් දෙන තුරු.",
        "ඇඳිරි නීතිය ක්‍රියාත්මක වනතුරු නිවෙස් තුළටම වී සිටින ලෙසත් එම නියෝගය කඩකරන්නන්ට එරෙහිව දැඩිව නීතිය ක්‍රියාත්මක කරන ලෙසත් ඔහු මෙම ප්‍රදේශවල වැසියන්ගෙන් ඉල්ලා සිටියේය.",
        "කෙසේ වෙතත්, මෙම පියවර ශ්‍රී ලංකා නීතීඥ සංගමය (BASL) සහ විපක්ෂය ඇතුළු විවිධ පාර්ශවයන්ගේ විවේචනයට ලක් විය. පොලිස් ඇඳිරි නීතිය පැනවීම නීතිවිරෝධී ක්‍රියාවක් ලෙස හඳුන්වමින් ඔවුන් පෙන්වා දුන්නේ එය වත්මන් ජනාධිපතිවරයාට සහ රජයට එරෙහිව විරෝධතාවයේ නිරත වන රටේ ජනතාවගේ මූලික අයිතිවාසිකම්ද කඩ කිරීමක් බවයි.",
        "නිවේදනයක් නිකුත් කරමින් BASL ආයතනය පොලිස් ප්‍රධානියාගෙන් ප්‍රශ්න කළේ කුමන අධිකාරියක් යටතේ ඇඳිරි නීතිය ප්‍රකාශ කළේද යන්නයි.",
        "ඇඳිරි නීතිය ප්‍රකාශයට පත් කිරීම පැහැදිලිවම අදහස් ප්‍රකාශ කිරීමේ සහ විසම්මුතියේ නිදහස යටපත් කිරීමට අදහස් කරන බව සඳහන් කළ සංගමය, මෙම පියවර “සම්පූර්ණයෙන්ම පිළිගත නොහැකි සහ ප්‍රජාතන්ත්‍ර විරෝධී” බව පැවසීය."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "බස්නාහිර පළාත",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "අවසන් රාත්රිය",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජූලි 08",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "8.00 පෙ.ව.",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජූලි 09",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකා පොලිසිය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "පොලිස්පති",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "අවසන් රාත්රිය",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "මීගමුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kelaniya",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "නුගේගොඩ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගල්කිස්ස",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "කොළඹ උතුර, කොළඹ දකුණ සහ මැද කොළඹ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "9.00 ප.ව.",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඊයේ",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකා නීතිඥ සංගමය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "විපක්ෂ",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "BASL",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        []
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "பொலிஸ் ஊரடங்கு உத்தரவு நீக்கப்பட வேண்டும்",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "மேல் மாகாணத்தின் சில பகுதிகளில் நேற்றிரவு (ஜூலை 08) அமுல்படுத்தப்பட்ட பொலிஸ் ஊரடங்குச் சட்டம் இன்று (ஜூலை 09) காலை 8.00 மணிக்கு தளர்த்தப்படும் என சிறிலங்கா காவல்துறை தெரிவித்துள்ளது.",
        "இன்று திட்டமிடப்பட்டுள்ள பாரிய ஆர்ப்பாட்டங்களுக்கு முன்னதாக, நீர்கொழும்பு, களனி, நுகேகொட, கல்கிசை, கொழும்பு வடக்கு, கொழும்பு தெற்கு மற்றும் கொழும்பு மத்திய பொலிஸ் பகுதிகள் இரவு 9.00 மணி முதல் பொலிஸ் ஊரடங்கு உத்தரவின் கீழ் இருக்கும் என பொலிஸ் மா அதிபர் (IGP) நேற்று இரவு அறிவித்தார். நேற்று மறு அறிவித்தல் வரை.",
        "ஊரடங்குச் சட்டம் அமுலில் இருக்கும் போது இந்த பகுதிகளில் வசிப்பவர்கள் வீட்டுக்குள்ளேயே இருக்க வேண்டும் என்றும் உத்தரவை மீறுபவர்களுக்கு எதிராக சட்டம் கடுமையாக அமுல்படுத்தப்படும் என்றும் அவர் வலியுறுத்தினார்.",
        "எவ்வாறாயினும், இந்த நடவடிக்கை இலங்கை சட்டத்தரணிகள் சங்கம் (BASL) மற்றும் எதிர்க்கட்சிகள் உட்பட பல்வேறு தரப்பினரின் விமர்சனத்திற்கு உட்பட்டது. பொலிஸ் ஊரடங்குச் சட்டம் அமுல்படுத்தப்பட்டமை சட்டவிரோதமானது எனத் தெரிவித்த அவர்கள், தற்போதைய ஜனாதிபதி மற்றும் அரசாங்கத்திற்கு எதிராக ஆர்ப்பாட்டத்தில் ஈடுபட்டுள்ள நாட்டு மக்களின் அடிப்படை உரிமைகளை மீறுவதாகவும் சுட்டிக்காட்டியுள்ளனர்.",
        "எந்த அதிகாரத்தின் கீழ் ஊரடங்கு உத்தரவை பிரகடனம் செய்தார் என BASL பொலிஸ்மா அதிபரிடம் கேள்வி எழுப்பியுள்ளது.",
        "ஊரடங்கு உத்தரவு பிரகடனம் என்பது கருத்துச் சுதந்திரம் மற்றும் கருத்து வேறுபாடுகளை நசுக்குவதைத் தெளிவாகக் குறிக்கும் என்று குறிப்பிட்ட சங்கம், இந்த நடவடிக்கை \"முற்றிலும் ஏற்றுக்கொள்ள முடியாதது மற்றும் ஜனநாயகமற்றது\" என்று கூறியது."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "மேல் மாகாணம்",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "நேற்று இரவு",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜூலை 08",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "காலை 8.00 மணி",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜூலை 09",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை காவல்துறை",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஐ.ஜி.பி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "நேற்று இரவு",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "நீர்கொழும்பு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kelaniya",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "நுகேகொட",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "கல்கிசை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "கொழும்பு வடக்கு, கொழும்பு தெற்கு மற்றும் கொழும்பு மத்திய",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "காலை 9.00 மணி.",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "நேற்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை சட்டத்தரணிகள் சங்கம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "எதிர்ப்பு",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "BASL",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        []
      ]
    }
  }
}