{
  "newspaper_id": "ada-derana-lk",
  "url": "http://www.adaderana.lk/news/84467/sc-adjourns-hearing-of-petitions-against-22nd-amendment",
  "time_ut": 1661171460,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "SC adjourns hearing of petitions against 22nd Amendment",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "SC adjourns hearing of petitions against 22nd Amendment",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "The hearing of the petitions which were filed challenging the 22nd Amendment to the constitution has been adjourned until tomorrow (23).",
        "The Supreme Court today (Aug 22) commenced hearing of the nine petitions before the three-judge bench consisting of Chief Justice Jayantha Jayasuriya, Justices Buwaneka Aluvihare and Arjuna Obeysekera.",
        "The petitions were filed by nine citizens including the Secretary of the ‘Vinivinda Peramuna’ attoney-at-law Nagananda Kodituwakku, Dr. Gunadasa Amarasekara, attorney-at-law Nuwan Ballantudawa, Tissa Bandara Ratnayake, H.D.J. Kulatunga and B.P. Dahanayake.",
        "The Attorney General has been named as the respondent in the petitions.",
        "The petitions have alleged that the fundamental human rights guaranteed by the Constitution are being violated through the 22nd Amendment to the constitution.",
        "Therefore, the petitions have further requested the Supreme Court to give a decision that if it is necessary to pass the clauses included in the relevant bill, it should be passed by a two-thirds majority vote of the Parliament and a referendum."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "22nd",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "tomorrow",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "23",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "The Supreme Court",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "22",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "nine",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "three",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Jayantha Jayasuriya",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Arjuna Obeysekera",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "nine",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "the ‘Vinivinda Peramuna’",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "Nagananda Kodituwakku",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Gunadasa Amarasekara",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Nuwan Ballantudawa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Tissa Bandara Ratnayake",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "H.D.J. Kulatunga",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "B.P. Dahanayake",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "Constitution",
            "label": "LAW"
          },
          {
            "text": "22nd",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the Supreme Court",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "a two-thirds",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "22 වැනි සංශෝධනයට එරෙහි පෙත්සම් විභාගය ශ්‍රේෂ්ඨාධිකරණය කල් තබයි",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "22 වන ආණ්ඩුක්‍රම ව්‍යවස්ථා සංශෝධනය අභියෝගයට ලක්කරමින් ගොනු කර ඇති පෙත්සම් විභාගය හෙට (23) දක්වා කල් තැබුණා.",
        "අගවිනිසුරු ජයන්ත ජයසූරිය, බුවනෙක අලුවිහාරේ සහ අර්ජුන ඔබේසේකර යන ත්‍රිපුද්ගල විනිසුරු මඩුල්ල හමුවේ ශ්‍රේෂ්ඨාධිකරණය අද (අගෝස්තු 22) පෙත්සම් නවය සලකා බැලීම ආරම්භ කළේය.",
        "විනිවින්ද පෙරමුණේ ලේකම් නීතිඥ නාගානන්ද කොඩිතුවක්කු, ආචාර්ය ගුණදාස අමරසේකර, නීතිඥ නුවන් බැල්ලන්තුඩාව, තිස්ස බණ්ඩාර රත්නායක, එච්.ඩී.ජේ. කුලතුංග සහ බී.පී. දහනායක.",
        "එම පෙත්සම්වල වගඋත්තරකරු ලෙස නීතිපතිවරයා නම් කර ඇත.",
        "ආණ්ඩුක්‍රම ව්‍යවස්ථාවේ 22 වැනි සංශෝධනය හරහා ආණ්ඩුක්‍රම ව්‍යවස්ථාවෙන් සහතික කර ඇති මූලික මානව හිමිකම් උල්ලංඝනය වන බවට පෙත්සම් මගින් චෝදනා කර ඇත.",
        "එබැවින් අදාළ පනත් කෙටුම්පතේ ඇතුළත් වගන්ති සම්මත කර ගැනීමට අවශ්‍ය නම් එය පාර්ලිමේන්තුවේ තුනෙන් දෙකක බහුතර ඡන්දයෙන් සහ ජනමත විචාරණයකින් සම්මත කළ යුතු බවට තීන්දුවක් ලබාදෙන ලෙස එම පෙත්සම් මඟින් ශ්‍රේෂ්ඨාධිකරණයෙන් වැඩිදුරටත් ඉල්ලා තිබේ."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "22 වැනි",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "හෙට",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "23",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රේෂ්ඨාධිකරණය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "22",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "නවය",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "තුන්",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජයන්ත ජයසූරිය",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "අර්ජුන ඔබේසේකර",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "නවය",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "'විනිවින්ද පෙරමුණ'",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "Nagananda Kodituwakku",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Gunadasa Amarasekara",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "නුවන් බැල්ලන්තුඩාව",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "තිස්ස බණ්ඩාර රත්නායක",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "එච්.ඩී.ජේ. කුලතුංග ය",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "බී.පී. දහනායක",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "ආණ්ඩුක්රම ව්යවස්ථාව",
            "label": "LAW"
          },
          {
            "text": "22 වැනි",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රේෂ්ඨාධිකරණය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "තුනෙන් දෙකක්",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "22வது திருத்தத்திற்கு எதிரான மனுக்கள் மீதான விசாரணையை உச்சநீதிமன்றம் ஒத்திவைத்தது",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "அரசியலமைப்பின் 22 ஆவது திருத்தத்தை சவாலுக்கு உட்படுத்தி தாக்கல் செய்யப்பட்ட மனுக்கள் மீதான விசாரணை நாளை (23) வரை ஒத்திவைக்கப்பட்டுள்ளது.",
        "பிரதம நீதியரசர் ஜயந்த ஜயசூரிய, நீதியரசர்களான புவனேகா அலுவிஹாரே மற்றும் அர்ஜுன ஒபேசேகர ஆகிய மூவரடங்கிய நீதியரசர்கள் குழாம் முன்னிலையில் 9 மனுக்கள் மீதான விசாரணை இன்று (ஆகஸ்ட் 22) உச்ச நீதிமன்றத்தில் ஆரம்பமானது.",
        "வினிவிந்த பெரமுனவின் செயலாளர் சட்டத்தரணி நாகாநந்த கொடிதுவாக்கு, கலாநிதி குணதாச அமரசேகர, சட்டத்தரணி நுவான் பல்லந்துடாவ, திஸ்ஸ பண்டார ரத்நாயக்க, எச்.டி.ஜே உட்பட ஒன்பது பிரஜைகளால் இந்த மனுக்கள் தாக்கல் செய்யப்பட்டுள்ளன. குலதுங்க மற்றும் பி.பி. தஹநாயக்க.",
        "இந்த மனுக்களில் பிரதிவாதியாக சட்டமா அதிபர் குறிப்பிடப்பட்டுள்ளார்.",
        "அரசியலமைப்பின் 22 ஆவது திருத்தத்தின் மூலம் அரசியலமைப்பின் அடிப்படை மனித உரிமைகள் மீறப்படுவதாக மனுக்களில் கூறப்பட்டுள்ளது.",
        "எனவே, குறித்த சட்டமூலத்தில் உள்ளடக்கப்பட்டுள்ள சரத்துக்களை நிறைவேற்றுவது அவசியமானால், அதனை நாடாளுமன்றத்தின் மூன்றில் இரண்டு பெரும்பான்மை வாக்குகளாலும், வாக்கெடுப்பு மூலமாகவும் நிறைவேற்ற வேண்டும் என உச்ச நீதிமன்றத்திடம் மனுக்கள் மேலும் கோரியுள்ளன."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "22வது",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "நாளை",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "23",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "உச்ச நீதிமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "22",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஒன்பது",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "மூன்று",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜயந்த ஜயசூரிய",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "அர்ஜுன ஒபேசேகர",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஒன்பது",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "'வினிவிந்த பெரமுன'",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "Nagananda Kodituwakku",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Gunadasa Amarasekara",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "நுவன் பலந்துடாவ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "திஸ்ஸ பண்டார ரத்நாயக்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "எச்.டி.ஜே. குலதுங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "பி.பி. தஹநாயக்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "அரசியலமைப்பு",
            "label": "LAW"
          },
          {
            "text": "22வது",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "உச்ச நீதிமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "மூன்றில் இரண்டு பங்கு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}