{
  "newspaper_id": "news-first-lk",
  "url": "https://www.newsfirst.lk/2022/09/03/india-advocating-assistance-for-sri-lanka/",
  "time_ut": 1662184500,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "India advocating assistance for Sri Lanka",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "India advocating assistance for Sri Lanka",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st): Shri Arindam Bagchi, Official Spokesperson for the Indian Foreign Ministry said that  India has been advocating for assistance to Sri Lanka.",
        "Commenting on the IMF Staff-Level Agreement he said \"let's see how it progresses.\"",
        "He noted that the issues of creditor equitability and transparency are important for the island nation.",
        "\"We have extended assistance 3.8 billion, I think it's nearly now 4 billion in assistance in various forms. We have been talking about it for quite some time. We have also made our comments on the other issues,\" he added.",
        "The Indian Foreign Ministry Spokesperson commenting on the recent visit of a Pakistan Warship to Colombo said if there are developments that affect India's security, India will keep a close watch on them and take necessary measures to safeguard that.",
        "\"But I think that is a separate element from what our relationship with Sri Lanka is and what all we have done and what we can do, including the conversation we just had, how the IMF staff-level talks as well as the debt restructuring that can happen ahead so that Sri Lankans can improve, you know, get away from this economic difficulty and turmoil that they're facing right now,\" he added."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "India",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "Sri Lanka",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "News 1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Shri Arindam Bagchi",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Indian Foreign Ministry",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "India",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "3.8 billion",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "4 billion",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "The Indian Foreign Ministry Spokesperson",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "India",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "India",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "IMF",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lankans",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "ඉන්දියාව ශ්‍රී ලංකාවට සහාය පළ කරයි",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st): ඉන්දීය විදේශ අමාත්‍යාංශයේ නිල ප්‍රකාශක ශ්‍රී අරින්දම් බග්චි පැවසුවේ  ඉන්දියාව ශ්‍රී ලංකාවට ආධාර ඉල්ලා සිටින බවයි.",
        "ජාත්‍යන්තර මූල්‍ය අරමුදලේ කාර්ය මණ්ඩල මට්ටමේ ගිවිසුම පිළිබඳව අදහස් දක්වමින් ඔහු කියා සිටියේ \"එය ප්‍රගතිය කෙසේ වේද බලමු\" යනුවෙනි.",
        "ණය හිමියන්ගේ සමානාත්මතාවය සහ විනිවිදභාවය පිළිබඳ ගැටළු දිවයින ජාතියට වැදගත් වන බව ඔහු සඳහන් කළේය.",
        "\"අපි බිලියන 3.8 ක ආධාර ලබා දී තිබෙනවා, මම හිතන්නේ එය විවිධ ආකාරවලින් බිලියන 4 කට ආසන්නයි. අපි ඒ ගැන සෑහෙන වෙලාවක් කතා කරනවා. අපි අනෙක් කාරණා ගැනත් අපේ අදහස් ඉදිරිපත් කළා,\" ඔහු වැඩිදුරටත් පැවසීය.",
        "පසුගියදා පාකිස්ථාන යුද නෞකාවක් කොළඹට පැමිණීම සම්බන්ධයෙන් අදහස් දැක්වූ ඉන්දීය විදේශ අමාත්‍යාංශ ප්‍රකාශකවරයා කියා සිටියේ ඉන්දියාවේ ආරක්ෂාවට බලපාන ආකාරයේ වර්ධනයක් සිදුවුවහොත් ඉන්දියාව ඒවා පිළිබඳව දැඩි අවධානයෙන් පසුවන අතර එය ආරක්ෂා කිරීමට අවශ්‍ය පියවර ගන්නා බවයි.",
        "“නමුත් මම හිතන්නේ එය ශ්‍රී ලංකාව සමඟ අපගේ සබඳතාව කුමක්ද සහ අප කළ සියල්ල සහ අපට කළ හැකි දේ, අප කළ සංවාදය ඇතුළුව, ජාත්‍යන්තර මූල්‍ය අරමුදලේ කාර්ය මණ්ඩල මට්ටමේ කතා කරන ආකාරය මෙන්ම ණය ප්‍රතිව්‍යුහගත කිරීමත් සමඟ එය වෙනම අංගයකි. ශ්‍රී ලංකිකයින්ට ඔවුන් දැන් මුහුණ දී සිටින මෙම ආර්ථික දුෂ්කරතාවයෙන් සහ කැලඹිලිවලින් මිදීමට හැකි වන පරිදි ඉදිරියට යා හැකිය,\" ඔහු වැඩිදුරටත් පැවසීය."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ඉන්දියාව",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "News 1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී අරින්දම් බග්චි",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දීය විදේශ අමාත්‍යාංශය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "බිලියන 3.8 කි",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "බිලියන 4 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දීය විදේශ අමාත්‍යාංශයේ ප්‍රකාශක",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "IMF",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලාංකිකයන්",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "இந்தியா இலங்கைக்கு உதவ வேண்டும்",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st): இந்திய வெளியுறவு அமைச்சகத்தின் அதிகாரப்பூர்வ செய்தித் தொடர்பாளர் ஸ்ரீ அரிந்தம் பாக்சி கூறுகையில்,  இலங்கைக்கு உதவ இந்தியா வாதிட்டு வருகிறது.",
        "IMF பணியாளர் நிலை ஒப்பந்தம் குறித்து கருத்து தெரிவித்த அவர், \"அது எப்படி முன்னேறுகிறது என்பதைப் பார்ப்போம்\" என்றார்.",
        "கடனாளிகளின் சமத்துவம் மற்றும் வெளிப்படைத்தன்மை ஆகிய பிரச்சினைகள் தீவு தேசத்திற்கு முக்கியமானவை என்று அவர் குறிப்பிட்டார்.",
        "\"நாங்கள் 3.8 பில்லியன் உதவிகளை நீட்டித்துள்ளோம், இது பல்வேறு வடிவங்களில் இப்போது 4 பில்லியன் உதவியாக உள்ளது என்று நான் நினைக்கிறேன். நாங்கள் சில காலமாக அதைப் பற்றி பேசி வருகிறோம். மற்ற விஷயங்களிலும் நாங்கள் எங்கள் கருத்துக்களை தெரிவித்துள்ளோம்,\" என்று அவர் மேலும் கூறினார்.",
        "அண்மையில் பாகிஸ்தான் போர்க்கப்பல் ஒன்று கொழும்புக்கு விஜயம் செய்தமை தொடர்பில் கருத்து தெரிவித்த இந்திய வெளிவிவகார அமைச்சின் பேச்சாளர், இந்தியாவின் பாதுகாப்பை பாதிக்கும் வகையில் முன்னேற்றங்கள் ஏற்பட்டால், அவற்றை இந்தியா உன்னிப்பாக அவதானித்து அதனை பாதுகாக்க தேவையான நடவடிக்கைகளை மேற்கொள்ளும் என்றார்.",
        "\"ஆனால், இது இலங்கையுடனான எங்கள் உறவு என்ன, நாங்கள் என்ன செய்தோம், என்ன செய்ய முடியும் என்பதில் இருந்து இது ஒரு தனி அம்சம் என்று நான் நினைக்கிறேன், நாங்கள் இப்போது நடத்திய உரையாடல் உட்பட, IMF ஊழியர்கள் மட்ட பேச்சுக்கள் மற்றும் கடன் மறுசீரமைப்பு உட்பட. இலங்கையர்கள் தற்போது எதிர்கொள்ளும் இந்த பொருளாதார சிரமம் மற்றும் கொந்தளிப்பில் இருந்து விடுபட, முன்னேற்றம் அடைய முடியும்,\" என்று அவர் மேலும் கூறினார்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "இந்தியா",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "இலங்கை",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "News 1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஸ்ரீ அரிந்தம் பாக்சி",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்திய வெளியுறவு அமைச்சகம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்தியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "3.8 பில்லியன்",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "4 பில்லியன்",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இந்திய வெளியுறவு அமைச்சக செய்தித் தொடர்பாளர்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்தியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்தியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "IMF",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கையர்கள்",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}