{
  "newspaper_id": "ada-lk",
  "url": "https://www.ada.lk/breaking_news/පාසල්-දිවා-ආහාරයේ-පෝෂණ-මට්ටම-ඉහළ-නැංවීමට-ඇමරිකාවෙන්-අතහිත/11-396630",
  "time_ut": 1661510153,
  "original_lang": "si",
  "original_title": "පාසල් දිවා ආහාරයේ පෝෂණ මට්ටම ඉහළ නැංවීමට ඇමරිකාවෙන් අතහිත",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "America has failed to raise the nutritional level of school lunches",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "The American government has donated a stock of dry food to this country with the aim of increasing the nutritional level of school lunches. The delivery of this food stock to the Minister of Education Dr. Susil Premajayantha was officially done today (26) at the 'Spectra' warehouse complex in Wattala, Muthurajawela by the American Ambassador to Sri Lanka, Mrs. Julie Chang.",
        "Under this grant, Sri Lanka has received 890 metric tons of pink salmon and 2,000 metric tons of valuable lentils. These dry foods are to be added to the lunch of school students.",
        "With the direct intervention of the 'Save the Children' Institute, this nutrition program, launched jointly by that institute and the three Ministries of Education, Finance and Health, is expected to encourage students to attend school, increase learning focus, maintain the nutritional level of the food, and thereby improve the learning skills of the students. Improvement has been the main objective.",
        "On this occasion, Mr. Mariano Beillard, Regional Representative of the United States Department of Agriculture and Mr. Julian Chellappah, National Director of 'Save the Children' Institute, were present."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "America",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "American",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Susil Premajayantha",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "26",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Spectra",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Wattala",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Muthurajawela",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "American",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Julie Chang",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "890 metric tons",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "2,000 metric tons",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the 'Save the Children' Institute",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "three",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Finance",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Health",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Mariano Beillard",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the United States Department of Agriculture",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Julian Chellappah",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "'Save the Children' Institute",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "පාසල් දිවා ආහාරයේ පෝෂණ මට්ටම ඉහළ නැංවීමට ඇමරිකාවෙන් අතහිත",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "පාසල් දිවා ආහාර වේලෙහි පෝෂණීය මට්ටම ඉහළ නැංවීමේ අරමුණින් වියළි ආහාර තොගයක් ඇමරිකානු රජය විසින් මෙරට ට ප්‍රදානය කර ඇත. අධ්‍යාපන අමාත්‍ය ආචාර්ය සුසිල් ප්‍රේමජයන්ත මහතා වෙත මෙම ආහාර තොගය භාරදීම, මෙරට ඇමරිකානු තානාපති, ජූලි චං මහත්මිය අතින් වත්තල, මුතුරාජවෙල පිහිටි ‘ස්පෙක්ට්‍රා‘ ගබඩා සංකීර්ණයේ දී අද (26) දින,  නිල වශයෙන්  සිදු විය.",
        "පෝෂණීය ගුණයෙන් ඉහළ රෝස සැමන් මෙටි්‍රක් ටොන් 890ක් සහ වටිනා පරිප්පු මෙටි්‍රක් ටොන් 2,000ක් මෙම ප්‍රදානය යටතේ මෙරටට ලැබී ඇත. පාසල් සිසුන්ගේ දිවා ආහාරය සඳහා මෙම වියළි ආහාර එක් කිරිමට නියමිත ය.",
        "‘සේව් ද චිල්ඩ්රන්‘ ආයතනයේ සෘජු මැදිහත්වීම මත එම ආයතනය හා   අධ්‍යාපන, මුදල්, සෞඛ්‍ය යන අමාත්‍යාංශ තුන ම ඒකාබද්ධ ව දියත් කෙරෙන මෙම පෝෂණ වැඩසටහන මගින් සිසුන්ගේ පාසල් පැමිණීම දිරි ගැන්වීමටත් ඉගෙනුම් අවධානය වැඩි කිරීමටත් ආහාරයේ සමබල පෝෂණීය මට්ටම රඳවා ගැනීමටත්     අපේක්ෂිත අතර එමගින් සිසුන්ගේ  ඉගෙනුම් නිපුණතා වැඩිදියුණු කිරීම මුඛ්‍ය අරමුණ වී ඇත.",
        "මේ අවස්ථාවට ඇමරිකා එක්සත් ජනපද කෘෂිකර්ම දෙපාර්තමේන්තුවේ කලාපීය නියෝජිත මරියානෝ බෙලාඩ් (Mariano Beillard) හා ‘සේව් ද චිල්ඩ්රන්‘ ආයතනයේ  ජාතික අධ්‍යක්ෂ ජූලියන් සෙල්ලප්පා (Julian Chellappah) යන මහත්වරුන් ඇතුළු පිරිසක් එක් ව සිටියහ."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ඇමරිකාව",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ඇමෙරිකානු",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "සුසිල් ප්‍රේමජයන්ත",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "26",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "වර්ණාවලි",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "වත්තල",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මුතුරාජවෙල",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඇමෙරිකානු",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජූලි චෑන්ග්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මෙට්‍රික් ටොන් 890 කි",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "මෙට්‍රික් ටොන් 2000 කි",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "'ළමා සුරකින්න' ආයතනය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "තුන්",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "මූල්ය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "සෞඛ්යය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "මරියානෝ බෙයිලාඩ්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "එක්සත් ජනපද කෘෂිකර්ම දෙපාර්තමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජූලියන් චෙල්ලප්පා",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "'ළමා සුරකින්න' ආයතනය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "பள்ளி மதிய உணவின் ஊட்டச்சத்து அளவை உயர்த்த அமெரிக்கா தவறிவிட்டது",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "பள்ளி மதிய உணவின் ஊட்டச்சத்தை அதிகரிக்கும் நோக்கில் அமெரிக்க அரசாங்கம் உலர் உணவுகளை இந்நாட்டிற்கு நன்கொடையாக வழங்கியுள்ளது. இலங்கைக்கான அமெரிக்கத் தூதுவர் திருமதி ஜூலி சாங் அவர்களினால் வத்தளை, முத்துராஜவெலயிலுள்ள 'ஸ்பெக்ட்ரா' களஞ்சியசாலை வளாகத்தில் இன்று (26) கல்வி அமைச்சர் கலாநிதி சுசில் பிரேமஜயந்தவிடம் இந்த உணவுப் பங்குகள் உத்தியோகபூர்வமாக வழங்கப்பட்டது.",
        "இந்த மானியத்தின் கீழ், இலங்கைக்கு 890 மெட்ரிக் தொன் இளஞ்சிவப்பு சால்மன் மற்றும் 2,000 மெட்ரிக் தொன் மதிப்புமிக்க பருப்பு வகைகள் கிடைத்துள்ளன. பள்ளி மாணவர்களின் மதிய உணவில் இந்த உலர் உணவுகள் சேர்க்கப்பட உள்ளன.",
        "'சேவ் தி சில்ட்ரன்' நிறுவனத்தின் நேரடித் தலையீட்டுடன், அந்த நிறுவனம் மற்றும் கல்வி, நிதி மற்றும் சுகாதாரம் ஆகிய மூன்று அமைச்சகங்கள் இணைந்து தொடங்கியுள்ள இந்த ஊட்டச்சத்து திட்டம், மாணவர்களை பள்ளிக்குச் செல்வதற்கும், கற்றலில் கவனம் செலுத்துவதற்கும், ஊட்டச்சத்து அளவைப் பராமரிப்பதற்கும் ஊக்கமளிக்கும் என எதிர்பார்க்கப்படுகிறது. உணவு மற்றும் அதன் மூலம் மாணவர்களின் கற்றல் திறனை மேம்படுத்துதல், மேம்பாடு முக்கிய நோக்கமாக உள்ளது.",
        "இந்நிகழ்வில், அமெரிக்காவின் விவசாயத் திணைக்களத்தின் பிராந்தியப் பிரதிநிதி திரு.மரியானோ பெய்லார்ட் மற்றும் 'சேவ் தி சில்ட்ரன்' நிறுவனத்தின் தேசிய இயக்குநர் திரு.ஜூலியன் செல்லப்பா ஆகியோர் கலந்துகொண்டனர்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "அமெரிக்கா",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "அமெரிக்கன்",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "சுசில் பிரேமஜயந்த",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "26",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "நிறமாலை",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "வத்தளை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "முத்துராஜவெல",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "அமெரிக்கன்",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜூலி சாங்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "890 மெட்ரிக் டன்",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "2,000 மெட்ரிக் டன்",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "'குழந்தைகளை காப்பாற்றுங்கள்' நிறுவனம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "மூன்று",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "நிதி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆரோக்கியம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "மரியானோ பெய்லார்ட்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "அமெரிக்காவின் விவசாயத் துறை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜூலியன் செல்லப்பா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "'குழந்தைகளைக் காப்பாற்றுங்கள்' நிறுவனம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}