{
  "newspaper_id": "lankadeepa-lk",
  "url": "https://www.lankadeepa.lk/latest_news/රැජින-පීලිපනී---ප්‍රධාන-මාර්ගයේ-දුම්රිය-ධාවනවට-බාධා/1-619169",
  "time_ut": 1662096748,
  "original_lang": "si",
  "original_title": "රැජින පීලිපනී - ප්‍රධාන මාර්ගයේ දුම්රිය ධාවනවට බාධා",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Rajina Pilipani - Disruption to train running on the main line",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "It is reported that the Rajarata Rajina Express Gami train running from Anuradhapura to Beliatta has derailed at the Polgahawela station and the train running on the main route has been disrupted and the passengers have been greatly inconvenienced.",
        "It is reported that the express train running from Kandy to Colombo Fort at 6.20 in the morning is also running with a delay of 1 hour 30 minutes with high passenger capacity and the train is being stopped midway.",
        "When Lankadeepa made a telephone call to the 1971 hotline regarding the derailment and train delay of the Rajarata Queen train, its officials directed us to Mr. Seneviratne, Deputy General Manager (Traffic), and since Mr. Seneviratne was not in the office, the office again called the 1971 hotline. We were directed.",
        "We were again referred to the General Manager's office, where an official who did not want to mention the name of the Railway General Manager's office said that although there may be a train delay at Polgahawela station, it will not affect the train running."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Rajina Pilipani - Disruption",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Rajina Express Gami",
            "label": "PRODUCT"
          },
          {
            "text": "Anuradhapura",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Beliatta",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Polgahawela",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Kandy to Colombo Fort",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "6.20 in the morning",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "1 hour 30 minutes",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "1971",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Rajarata Queen",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Seneviratne",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Traffic",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Seneviratne",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "1971",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the Railway General Manager's",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Polgahawela",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "රැජින පීලිපනී - ප්‍රධාන මාර්ගයේ දුම්රිය ධාවනවට බාධා",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "අනුරාධපුර සිට බෙලිඅත්ත බලා ධාවනය වන රජරට රැජින සීඝ්‍ර ගාමි දුම්රිය පොල්ගහවෙල දුම්රිය ස්ථානයේදී පීලි පැනීමට ලක්වීම හේතුවෙන් ප්‍රධාන මාර්ගයේ දුම්රිය ධාවනයට බාධා එල්ල වී ඇති බවත් මගීන් දැඩි ලෙස අපහසුතාවයට පත්ව ඇති බවත් වාර්තා වේ.",
        "මේ වනවිට උදෑසන 6.20 ට මහනුවර සිට කොළඹ කොටුව බලා ධාවනය වන සීඝ්‍රගාමි දුම්රිය ද අධික මගීන් ධාරිතාවක් සහිතව පැය 1 මිනිත්තු 30 ක ප්‍රමාදයකින් යුක්තව ධාවනය වෙමින් පවතින බවත්, දුම්රිය අතරමග නවත්වමින් ධාවන වෙමින් පවතින බවත් වාර්තා වේ.",
        "රජරට රැජින දුම්රියේ පීලි පැනීම සහ දුම්රිය ප්‍රමාදය පිළිබද 1971 ක්ෂණික ඇමතුම් අංකයට ලංකාදීපය දුරකතන ඇමතුමක් ලබා ගත් විට එහි නිලධාරීන් අපව නියෝජ්‍ය සාමාන්‍යාධිකාරී (ගමනා ගමන) සෙනෙවිරත්න මහතා වෙත යොමුකළ අතර,ඉන් පසු සෙනවිරත්න මහතා කාර්යාලයේ නොසිටි බැවින් එම කාර්යාලය නැවතත් 1971 ක්ෂණික දුරකථන ඇමතුම් අංකය වෙත අප යොමු කරන ලදි.",
        "නැවතත් අප සාමාන්‍යාධිකාරී කාර්යාලය වෙත යොමු කෙරුණු අතර එහිදී කළ විමසීමකදී පොල්ගහවෙල දුම්රිය ස්ථානයේදී දුම්රිය ප්‍රමාදයක් සිදුවිය හැකි වුවත් දුම්රිය ධාවනයට එයින්  විශාල බලපෑමක් එල්ල නොවන බව දුම්රිය සාමාන්‍යාධිකාරි කාර්යාලයේ නම සඳහන් කිරීමට අකමැති නිලධාරියෙක් පැවසීය."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "රැජින පිලිපානි - බාධා",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "රැජින එක්ස්ප්‍රස් ගැමි",
            "label": "PRODUCT"
          },
          {
            "text": "අනුරාධපුර",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "බෙලිඅත්ත",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "පොල්ගහවෙල",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "මහනුවර සිට කොළඹ කොටුව දක්වා",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "උදේ 6.20 ට",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "පැය 1 විනාඩි 30 යි",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "1971",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "රජරට රැජින",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "සෙනෙවිරත්න",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "රථවාහන",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "සෙනෙවිරත්න",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "1971",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "දුම්රිය සාමාන්‍යාධිකාරීවරයාගේ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "පොල්ගහවෙල",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "ரஜினா பிலிபானி - மெயின் லைனில் ஓடும் ரயிலுக்கு இடையூறு",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "அநுராதபுரத்தில் இருந்து பெலியத்த நோக்கிச் செல்லும் ரஜரட்ட ரஜின எக்ஸ்பிரஸ் கமி ரயில் பொல்கஹவெல நிலையத்தில் தடம் புரண்டதால் பிரதான பாதையில் செல்லும் ரயில் தடைப்பட்டு பயணிகள் பெரும் அசௌகரியங்களுக்கு உள்ளாகியுள்ளதாக தெரிவிக்கப்படுகின்றது.",
        "காலை 6.20 மணிக்கு கண்டியில் இருந்து கொழும்பு கோட்டை நோக்கி இயக்கப்படும் விரைவு ரயிலும் அதிக பயணிகளை ஏற்றிக்கொண்டு 1 மணி 30 நிமிடம் தாமதமாக இயக்கப்படுவதாகவும், ரயில் நடுவழியில் நிறுத்தப்படுவதாகவும் தெரிவிக்கப்படுகிறது.",
        "ரஜரட்ட குயின் ரயில் தடம் புரண்டது மற்றும் ரயில் தாமதம் தொடர்பாக லங்காதீப 1971 தொலைபேசி இலக்கத்திற்கு தொலைபேசி அழைப்பு விடுத்தபோது, ​​அதன் அதிகாரிகள் எங்களை பிரதிப் பொது முகாமையாளர் (போக்குவரத்து) திரு செனவிரத்னவிடம் அழைத்துச் சென்றனர், மேலும் திரு. அலுவலகம் மீண்டும் 1971 ஹாட்லைனுக்கு அழைப்பு விடுத்தது.",
        "நாங்கள் மீண்டும் பொது முகாமையாளர் அலுவலகத்திற்கு பரிந்துரைக்கப்பட்டோம், அங்கு ரயில்வே பொது முகாமையாளர் அலுவலகத்தின் பெயரைக் குறிப்பிட விரும்பாத அதிகாரி ஒருவர், பொல்கஹவெல நிலையத்தில் ரயில் தாமதம் ஏற்பட்டாலும், அது ரயில் ஓட்டத்திற்கு பாதிப்பில்லை என்று கூறினார்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ரஜினா பிலிபானி - இடையூறு",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ரஜினா எக்ஸ்பிரஸ் காமி",
            "label": "PRODUCT"
          },
          {
            "text": "அனுராதபுரம்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "பெலியட்டா",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "பொல்கஹவெல",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "கண்டி முதல் கொழும்பு கோட்டை வரை",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "காலை 6.20",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "1 மணி 30 நிமிடங்கள்",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "1971",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரஜரட்ட ராணி",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "செனவிரத்ன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "போக்குவரத்து",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "செனவிரத்ன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "1971",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ரயில்வே பொது மேலாளர்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "பொல்கஹவெல",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}