{
  "newspaper_id": "ada-derana-lk",
  "url": "http://www.adaderana.lk/news/84588/teenage-school-girl-killed-in-wild-elephant-attack",
  "time_ut": 1661680980,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Teenage school girl killed in wild elephant attack",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Teenage school girl killed in wild elephant attack",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "A sixteen-year-old school girl has died this morning (28) following a wild elephant attack at Pahe-Ela in Gangeyaya, Hasalaka.",
        "Pahe-Ela is a village that reportedly sees frequent wild elephant attacks while the animals are said to be damaging crops as well as posing a threat to the lives of the villagers.",
        "According to reports, the girl in question was on her way to the temple along with her parents to take alms on behalf of her brother who had died 14 days ago when she was attacked by an elephant.",
        "Later, she was admitted to Hasalaka Hospital but had succumbed to injuries then.",
        "The deceased was a student named Anuttara Indunil, a resident of Pahe-Ela area in Gangeyaya, Hasalaka.",
        "She was reportedly preparing to face the practical tests of this year’s G.C.E. Ordinary Level examination tomorrow (29).",
        "The villagers say that if a proper solution is not given by authorities to the threat of wild elephants, it will not be possible to prevent the loss of more precious lives."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "sixteen-year-old",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "this morning",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "28",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Pahe-Ela",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Gangeyaya",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Hasalaka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Pahe-Ela",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "14 days ago",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Hasalaka Hospital",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Anuttara Indunil",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Pahe-Ela",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Gangeyaya",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Hasalaka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "year",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "tomorrow",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "29",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        []
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "වන අලි ප්‍රහාරයකින් පාසල් සිසුවියක් මරුට",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "හසලක, ගංගේයාය, පහේ ඇල ප්‍රදේශයේදී වන අලි ප්‍රහාරයකින් දහසය හැවිරිදි පාසල් සිසුවියක් අද (28) උදෑසන ජීවිතක්ෂයට පත්ව තිබෙනවා.",
        "පහේ-ඇල යනු නිරන්තරයෙන් වන අලි ප්‍රහාරවලට ලක්වන ගම්මානයක් වන අතර එම සතුන් වගා හානි මෙන්ම ගම්වාසීන්ගේ ජීවිතවලට තර්ජනයක් වන බව පැවසේ.",
        "වාර්තා වන අන්දමට අදාළ දැරිය මීට දින 14කට පෙර අලි ප්‍රහාරයකට ලක්ව මියගිය තම සොහොයුරා වෙනුවෙන් දානයක් ගැනීමට දෙමාපියන් සමඟ විහාරස්ථානයට යමින් සිට ඇත.",
        "පසුව ඇය හසලක රෝහලට ඇතුළත් කළත් ඒ වනවිටත් ඇය ජීවිතක්ෂයට පත්ව තිබුණා.",
        "මෙලෙස මියගොස් ඇත්තේ හසලක ගංගේයාය පහේ ඇල ප්‍රදේශයේ පදිංචිව සිටි අනුත්තරා ඉඳුනිල් නමැති සිසුවෙකි.",
        "ඇය මේ වසරේ අ.පො.ස. ප්‍රායෝගික පරීක්ෂණවලට මුහුණ දීමට සූදානම් වෙමින් සිටි බව වාර්තා වේ. සාමාන්‍ය පෙළ විභාගය හෙට (29)",
        "වන අලි තර්ජනයට බලධාරීන් නිසි විසඳුමක් ලබා නොදෙන්නේ නම් මීට වඩා වටිනා ජීවිත විනාශ වීම වැළැක්විය නොහැකි බව ගම්වාසීහු පවසති."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "දහසය හැවිරිදිය",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මේ උදෑසන",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "28",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "පහේ-ඇල",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගඟේයාය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "හසලක",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "පහේ-ඇල",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "දින 14 කට පෙර",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "හසලක රෝහල",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "අනුත්තරා ඉඳුනිල්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "පහේ-ඇල",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගඟේයාය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "හසලක",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "වර්ෂය",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "හෙට",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "29",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        []
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "காட்டு யானை தாக்கியதில் பள்ளி மாணவி பலி",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "ஹசலக்க, கங்கேயாய, பஹே-எல பகுதியில் காட்டு யானை தாக்கியதில் பதினாறு வயதுடைய பாடசாலை மாணவி ஒருவர் இன்று (28) காலை உயிரிழந்துள்ளார்.",
        "பஹே-எல என்பது காட்டு யானைகளின் தாக்குதல்களை அடிக்கடி காணக்கூடிய ஒரு கிராமமாகும், அதே நேரத்தில் விலங்குகள் பயிர்களை சேதப்படுத்துவதோடு கிராம மக்களின் உயிருக்கு அச்சுறுத்தலாக இருப்பதாக கூறப்படுகிறது.",
        "குறித்த சிறுமி 14 நாட்களுக்கு முன்னர் யானை தாக்கி உயிரிழந்த தனது சகோதரரின் சார்பாக பிச்சை எடுப்பதற்காக பெற்றோருடன் கோவிலுக்குச் சென்று கொண்டிருந்ததாக தகவல்கள் தெரிவிக்கின்றன.",
        "பின்னர், அவர் ஹசலக்க வைத்தியசாலையில் அனுமதிக்கப்பட்ட போதிலும் சிகிச்சை பலனின்றி உயிரிழந்துள்ளார்.",
        "ஹசலக்க, கங்கேயாய, பஹே-எல பகுதியைச் சேர்ந்த அனுத்தரா இந்துனில் என்ற மாணவியே உயிரிழந்துள்ளார்.",
        "இந்த ஆண்டு ஜி.சி.இ.யின் நடைமுறை சோதனைகளை எதிர்கொள்ள அவர் தயாராகி வருவதாக கூறப்படுகிறது. சாதாரண தரப் பரீட்சை நாளை (29)",
        "காட்டு யானைகளின் அட்டகாசத்திற்கு உரிய தீர்வை அதிகாரிகள் வழங்காவிடின் மேலும் விலைமதிப்பற்ற உயிர்கள் பலியாவதை தடுக்க முடியாது என கிராம மக்கள் தெரிவிக்கின்றனர்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "பதினாறு வயது",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று காலை",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "28",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "பஹே-எலா",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "கங்கேயாய",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஹசலக",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பஹே-எலா",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "14 நாட்களுக்கு முன்பு",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஹசலக வைத்தியசாலை",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "அனுத்தர இந்துனில்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "பஹே-எலா",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "கங்கேயாய",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஹசலக",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஆண்டு",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "நாளை",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "29",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        []
      ]
    }
  }
}