{
  "newspaper_id": "daily-ft-lk",
  "url": "https://www.ft.lk/news/Indian-Govt-convenes-all-party-meeting-tomorrow-on-Sri-Lanka/56-737604",
  "time_ut": 1658088206,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Indian Govt. convenes all-party meeting tomorrow on Sri Lanka",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Indian Govt. convenes all-party meeting tomorrow on Sri Lanka",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "The Indian Government has called an all-party meeting to discuss the current crisis situation in Sri Lanka after a request from the Tamil Nadu political parties.",
        "Indian media reported that after a request from the Dravida Munnetra Kazhagam (DMK) and the All India Anna Dravdia Munnetra Kazhagam (AIADMK), the Centre Government has decided to convene an all-party meeting on the situation in Sri Lanka tomorrow.",
        "Indian Finance Minister Nirmala Sitharaman and External Affairs Minister S. Jaishankar will brief leaders of all political parties in both the Houses of Parliament, on the “present situation in Sri Lanka” tomorrow, Parliamentary Affairs Minister Pralhad Joshi said in an invitation sent to the party leaders.",
        "According to The Hindu, DMK chief and Tamil Nadu Chief Minister M.K. Stalin had met Prime Minister Narendra Modi and written letters on the issue of humanitarian assistance to the economic crisis-hit island nation.",
        "Yesterday, the DMK and AIADMK urged the Centre to intervene in the crisis to help the neighbouring country, The Hindu reported.",
        "DMK leader in the Lok Sabha T. R. Baalu said India should intervene to address the situation. Senior AIADMK leader, Rajya Sabha MP and Lok Sabha former Deputy Speaker M. Thambidurai also demanded that the country should intervene to resolve the crisis in Sri Lanka.",
        "Recently, Modi had said in Chennai that India is providing all possible support to Sri Lanka, a close friend and neighbour. “This includes financial support, fuel, food, medicine and other essential items,” the PM said.",
        "During his meeting with Modi, Stalin had submitted a detailed memorandum on the economic crisis in Sri Lanka and the measures his Government had taken to help migrants. Many Opposition parties and economists had also asked the Centre to learn from the situation in Sri Lanka and address the economic problems in the country."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Indian",
          "label": "NORP"
        },
        {
          "text": "tomorrow",
          "label": "DATE"
        },
        {
          "text": "Sri Lanka",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "The Indian Government",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Tamil Nadu",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Indian",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Dravida Munnetra Kazhagam",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "DMK",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the All India Anna Dravdia Munnetra Kazhagam",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "AIADMK",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Centre Government",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "tomorrow",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Indian",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Nirmala Sitharaman",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "S. Jaishankar",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Houses",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "tomorrow",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Pralhad Joshi",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Hindu",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "DMK",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Tamil Nadu",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "M.K. Stalin",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Narendra Modi",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Yesterday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "DMK",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "AIADMK",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Centre",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Hindu",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "DMK",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Lok Sabha T. R. Baalu",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "India",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "AIADMK",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Rajya Sabha MP",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Lok Sabha",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "M. Thambidurai",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Modi",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "India",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Modi",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Stalin",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Centre",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "ඉන්දීය රජය ශ්‍රී ලංකාව සම්බන්ධයෙන් සර්ව පාක්ෂික රැස්වීමක් හෙට කැඳවයි",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "තමිල්නාඩු දේශපාලන පක්ෂවල ඉල්ලීමකට අනුව ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ වත්මන් අර්බුදකාරී තත්ත්වය පිළිබඳව සාකච්ඡා කිරීම සඳහා ඉන්දීය රජය සර්ව පාක්ෂික හමුවක් කැඳවා තිබේ.",
        "ද්‍රවිඩ මුන්නේත්‍ර කසාගම් (ඩීඑම්කේ) සහ සමස්ත ඉන්දීය අන්නා ද්‍රව්‍ය මුන්නේත්‍ර කසාගම් (ඒඅයිඒඩීඑම්කේ) විසින් කරන ලද ඉල්ලීමකට අනුව මධ්‍යම රජය විසින් ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ තත්ත්වය පිළිබඳව හෙට සර්ව පාක්ෂික රැස්වීමක් කැඳවීමට තීරණය කර ඇති බව ඉන්දීය මාධ්‍ය වාර්තා කළේය.",
        "ඉන්දීය මුදල් අමාත්‍ය නිර්මලා සීතාරාමන් සහ විදේශ කටයුතු අමාත්‍ය S. Jaishankar විසින් “ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ වත්මන් තත්ත්වය” පිළිබඳව හෙට පාර්ලිමේන්තු සභා දෙකෙහි සියලුම දේශපාලන පක්ෂ නායකයින් දැනුවත් කරන බව පාර්ලිමේන්තු කටයුතු අමාත්‍ය ප්‍රහද් ජෝෂි සාදයට යවන ලද ආරාධනයක සඳහන් කළේය. නායකයන්.",
        "ද හින්දු පුවත්පතට අනුව, DMK ප්‍රධානියා සහ තමිල්නාඩු මහ ඇමති එම්.කේ. ස්ටාලින් අග්‍රාමාත්‍ය නරේන්ද්‍ර මෝදි හමුවී ආර්ථික අර්බුදකාරී දූපත් ජාතියට මානුෂීය ආධාර ලබා දීම සම්බන්ධයෙන් ලිපි ලියා ඇත.",
        "අසල්වැසි රටට උපකාර කිරීම සඳහා අර්බුදයට මැදිහත් වන ලෙස ඩීඑම්කේ සහ ඒඩීඑම්කේය ඊයේ මධ්‍යස්ථානයෙන් ඉල්ලා සිටි බව ද හින්දු වාර්තා කරයි.",
        "ලෝක් සභාවේ ඩීඑම්කේ නායක ටී ආර් බාලු පැවසුවේ තත්ත්වය විසඳීමට ඉන්දියාව මැදිහත් විය යුතු බවයි. ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ අර්බුදය විසඳීමට රට මැදිහත් විය යුතු බව ජ්‍යෙෂ්ඨ ඒඩීඑම්කේ නායක, රාජ්‍ය සභා මන්ත්‍රී සහ ලෝක් සභාවේ හිටපු නියෝජ්‍ය කථානායක එම්.තම්බිදුරෙයි ද ඉල්ලා සිටියේය.",
        "සමීප මිතුරෙකු සහ අසල්වැසියෙකු වන ශ්‍රී ලංකාවට ඉන්දියාව හැකි සෑම සහයෝගයක්ම ලබා දෙන බව මෝදි පසුගියදා චෙන්නායිහිදී ප්‍රකාශ කර තිබුණා. \"මෙයට මූල්‍ය ආධාර, ඉන්ධන, ආහාර, ඖෂධ සහ අනෙකුත් අත්‍යාවශ්‍ය ද්‍රව්‍ය ඇතුළත් වේ\" යැයි අගමැතිවරයා පැවසීය.",
        "මෝදි සමඟ පැවති සාකච්ඡාවේදී ස්ටාලින් ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ ආර්ථික අර්බුදය සහ සංක්‍රමණිකයන්ට උපකාර කිරීම සඳහා තම රජය ගෙන ඇති ක්‍රියාමාර්ග පිළිබඳ සවිස්තරාත්මක සංදේශයක් ඉදිරිපත් කර ඇත. බොහෝ විරුද්ධ පක්ෂ සහ ආර්ථික විද්‍යාඥයන් ද ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ තත්ත්වයෙන් පාඩම් ඉගෙන ගෙන රටේ ආර්ථික ගැටලුවලට විසඳුම් ලබා දෙන ලෙස මධ්‍යස්ථානයෙන් ඉල්ලා තිබුණි."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ඉන්දීය",
          "label": "NORP"
        },
        {
          "text": "හෙට",
          "label": "DATE"
        },
        {
          "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දීය රජය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "තමිල්නාඩුව",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දීය",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ද්‍රවිඩ මුන්නේත්‍ර කසාගම්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඩී.එම්.කේ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "සමස්ත ඉන්දීය අන්නා ද්‍රව්‍ය මුන්නේත්‍ර කසාගම්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඒ.අයි.ඒ.ඩී.එම්.කේ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "මධ්යම රජය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "හෙට",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දීය",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "නිර්මලා සීතාරාමන්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "එස්. ජයශංකර්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "නිවාස",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "හෙට",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ප්‍රහද් ජෝෂි",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "හින්දු",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඩී.එම්.කේ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "තමිල්නාඩුව",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "එම්.කේ. ස්ටාලින්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "නරේන්ද්‍ර මෝදි",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ඊයේ",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඩී.එම්.කේ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඒ.අයි.ඒ.ඩී.එම්.කේ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "මධ්යස්ථානය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "හින්දු",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ඩී.එම්.කේ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ලෝක් සභාව T. R. Baalu",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඒ.අයි.ඒ.ඩී.එම්.කේ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "රාජ්‍ය සභා මන්ත්‍රී",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ලෝක් සභාව",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "එම් තම්බිදුරෙයි",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "මෝඩි",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "මෝඩි",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ස්ටාලින්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මධ්යස්ථානය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "இந்திய அரசு இலங்கை தொடர்பாக நாளை அனைத்து கட்சி கூட்டத்தை கூட்டுகிறது",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "தமிழக அரசியல் கட்சிகளின் கோரிக்கையை ஏற்று, இலங்கையின் தற்போதைய நெருக்கடி நிலை குறித்து ஆலோசிக்க இந்திய அரசு அனைத்துக் கட்சிக் கூட்டத்துக்கு அழைப்பு விடுத்துள்ளது.",
        "திராவிட முன்னேற்றக் கழகம் (திமுக) மற்றும் அனைத்திந்திய அண்ணா திராவிட முன்னேற்றக் கழகம் (அதிமுக) விடுத்த கோரிக்கையை அடுத்து, இலங்கையின் நிலைமை குறித்து நாளை அனைத்துக் கட்சிக் கூட்டத்தைக் கூட்ட மத்திய அரசு முடிவு செய்துள்ளதாக இந்திய ஊடகங்கள் செய்தி வெளியிட்டுள்ளன.",
        "இந்திய நிதியமைச்சர் நிர்மலா சீதாராமன் மற்றும் வெளிவிவகார அமைச்சர் எஸ். ஜெய்சங்கர் ஆகியோர், நாடாளுமன்றத்தின் இரு அவைகளிலும் உள்ள அனைத்து அரசியல் கட்சித் தலைவர்களுக்கும், \"இலங்கையின் தற்போதைய நிலைமை\" குறித்து நாளை விளக்குவார்கள் என்று, பார்லிமென்ட் விவகார அமைச்சர் பிரகலாத் ஜோஷி, கட்சிக்கு அனுப்பிய அழைப்பில் தெரிவித்துள்ளார். தலைவர்கள்.",
        "தி இந்து, திமுக தலைவரும், தமிழக முதல்வருமான மு.க. ஸ்டாலின், பிரதமர் நரேந்திர மோடியை சந்தித்து, பொருளாதார நெருக்கடியில் சிக்கித் தவிக்கும் தீவு நாட்டிற்கு மனிதாபிமான உதவி வழங்குவது குறித்து கடிதம் எழுதியுள்ளார்.",
        "இந்த நெருக்கடியில் மத்திய அரசு தலையிட்டு அண்டை நாட்டிற்கு உதவ வேண்டும் என்று திமுக மற்றும் அதிமுக நேற்று வலியுறுத்தியதாக தி ஹிந்து செய்தி வெளியிட்டுள்ளது.",
        "இந்த நிலையில் இந்தியா தலையிட வேண்டும் என்று மக்களவையில் திமுக தலைவர் டி.ஆர்.பாலு கூறினார். அதிமுக மூத்த தலைவரும், ராஜ்யசபா எம்.பி.யும், லோக்சபா முன்னாள் துணை சபாநாயகருமான மு. தம்பிதுரையும், இலங்கையில் நிலவும் நெருக்கடிக்கு தீர்வு காண, நாடு தலையிட வேண்டும் என கோரிக்கை விடுத்துள்ளார்.",
        "நெருங்கிய நண்பனும் அண்டை நாடான இலங்கைக்கு இந்தியா அனைத்து விதமான ஆதரவையும் வழங்கி வருவதாக சமீபத்தில் மோடி சென்னையில் கூறியிருந்தார். \"நிதி உதவி, எரிபொருள், உணவு, மருந்து மற்றும் பிற அத்தியாவசிய பொருட்கள் இதில் அடங்கும்\" என்று பிரதமர் கூறினார்.",
        "மோடியுடனான சந்திப்பின் போது, ​​இலங்கையில் ஏற்பட்டுள்ள பொருளாதார நெருக்கடி மற்றும் புலம்பெயர்ந்தோருக்கு உதவ தனது அரசு எடுத்துள்ள நடவடிக்கைகள் குறித்த விரிவான குறிப்பாணையை ஸ்டாலின் சமர்ப்பித்துள்ளார். பல எதிர்க்கட்சிகளும் பொருளாதார நிபுணர்களும் இலங்கையின் நிலைமையிலிருந்து பாடம் கற்று, நாட்டின் பொருளாதாரப் பிரச்சினைகளுக்கு தீர்வு காணுமாறு மத்திய அரசை கேட்டுக் கொண்டனர்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "இந்தியன்",
          "label": "NORP"
        },
        {
          "text": "நாளை",
          "label": "DATE"
        },
        {
          "text": "இலங்கை",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "இந்திய அரசு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "தமிழ்நாடு",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இந்தியன்",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "திராவிட முன்னேற்றக் கழகம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "தி.மு.க",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "அனைத்திந்திய அண்ணா திராவிட முன்னேற்றக் கழகம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "அதிமுக",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "மத்திய அரசு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "நாளை",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இந்தியன்",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "நிர்மலா சீதாராமன்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "எஸ். ஜெய்சங்கர்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "வீடுகள்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "நாளை",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "பிரகலாத் ஜோஷி",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இந்து",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "தி.மு.க",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "தமிழ்நாடு",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "எம்.கே. ஸ்டாலின்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "நரேந்திர மோடி",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "நேற்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "தி.மு.க",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "அதிமுக",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "மையம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்து",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "தி.மு.க",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "மக்களவை டி.ஆர்.பாலு",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்தியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "அதிமுக",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ராஜ்யசபா எம்.பி",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "மக்களவை",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "மு. தம்பிதுரை",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "மோடி",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்தியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "மோடி",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஸ்டாலின்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "மையம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}