{
  "newspaper_id": "economy-next-com",
  "url": "https://economynext.com/who-pledges-medical-aid-worth-40mn-dollars-to-crisis-hit-sri-lanka-99015/",
  "time_ut": 1661423460,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "WHO pledges medical aid worth 40mn dollars to crisis-hit Sri Lanka",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "WHO pledges medical aid worth 40mn dollars to crisis-hit Sri Lanka",
      "author": "Mahadiya Hamza",
      "body_lines": [
        "ECONOMYNEXT – The World Health Organisation (WHO) has promised crisis-hit Sri Lanka four million US dollars worth of essential medical supplies and other support to meet the immediate health needs of the country.",
        "WHO Director General Dr Tedros Adhanom Ghebreyesus has directed the WHO Health Emergencies Programme to take immediate action to meet the most urgent health needs of the people of Sri Lanka, a statement from the president’s office said on Thursday August 25.",
        "The WHO chief was quoted as saying that the organisation recognises the ongoing economic pressure Sri Lanka is facing in addition to COVID-19-related pressure on the health system.",
        "“To this end, I am pleased to inform you that I have tasked the WHO Health Emergencies Programme to take immediate action to meet the most urgent health needs of the people of Sri Lanka,” he said.",
        "WHO is in the process of procuring medical supplies in collaboration with WHO’s Regional and Country Offices, as well as the Sri Lanka’s ministry of health and other relevant ministries.",
        "Tedros said WHO will closely monitor the health risks to the population including the functionality and resilience of the health system and provide necessary technical assistance to strengthen provincial health services. (Colombo/Aug25/2022)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Sri Lanka",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "The World Health Organisation",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "four million US dollars",
            "label": "MONEY"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the WHO Health Emergencies Programme",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Thursday August 25",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "WHO",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "WHO’s Regional and Country Offices",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Sri Lanka’s",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "ministry of health",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Tedros",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "WHO",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "ලෝක සෞඛ්‍ය සංවිධානය අර්බුදකාරී ශ්‍රී ලංකාවට ඩොලර් මිලියන 40ක වෛද්‍ය ආධාර ලබා දීමට පොරොන්දු වෙයි",
      "author": "මහදිය හම්සා",
      "body_lines": [
        "ECONOMYNEXT - ලෝක සෞඛ්‍ය සංවිධානය (WHO) අර්බුදකාරී ශ්‍රී ලංකාවට ඇමරිකානු ඩොලර් මිලියන හතරක් වටිනා අත්‍යවශ්‍ය වෛද්‍ය සැපයුම් සහ රටේ ක්ෂණික සෞඛ්‍ය අවශ්‍යතා සපුරාලීම සඳහා වෙනත් ආධාර ලබා දෙන බවට පොරොන්දු වී තිබේ.",
        "ලෝක සෞඛ්‍ය සංවිධානයේ අධ්‍යක්ෂ ජනරාල් වෛද්‍ය ටෙඩ්‍රොස් අද්නාම් ගෙබ්‍රෙයිසස් විසින් ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ ජනතාවගේ වඩාත් හදිසි සෞඛ්‍ය අවශ්‍යතා සපුරාලීම සඳහා කඩිනම් පියවර ගන්නා ලෙස ලෝක සෞඛ්‍ය සංවිධානයේ සෞඛ්‍ය හදිසි අවස්ථා වැඩසටහනට නියෝග කර ඇති බව ජනාධිපති කාර්යාලයේ ප්‍රකාශයක් අගෝස්තු 25 බ්‍රහස්පතින්දා ප්‍රකාශ කළේය.",
        "සෞඛ්‍ය පද්ධතියට COVID-19 ආශ්‍රිත පීඩනයට අමතරව ශ්‍රී ලංකාව මුහුණ දෙන අඛණ්ඩ ආර්ථික පීඩනය සංවිධානය පිළිගන්නා බව ලෝක සෞඛ්‍ය සංවිධානයේ ප්‍රධානියා උපුටා දැක්වීය.",
        "\"මේ සඳහා, ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ ජනතාවගේ අත්‍යවශ්‍ය සෞඛ්‍ය අවශ්‍යතා සපුරාලීම සඳහා කඩිනම් ක්‍රියාමාර්ග ගැනීමට ලෝක සෞඛ්‍ය සංවිධානයේ සෞඛ්‍ය හදිසි අවස්ථා වැඩසටහනට මා භාර දී ඇති බව ඔබට දන්වා සිටීමට කැමැත්තෙමි,\" ඔහු පැවසීය.",
        "ලෝක සෞඛ්‍ය සංවිධානය ලෝක සෞඛ්‍ය සංවිධානයේ ප්‍රාදේශීය සහ රට කාර්යාල මෙන්ම ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ සෞඛ්‍ය අමාත්‍යාංශය සහ අනෙකුත් අදාළ අමාත්‍යාංශ සමඟ සහයෝගයෙන් වෛද්‍ය සැපයුම් ලබා ගැනීමේ ක්‍රියාවලියක යෙදී සිටී.",
        "සෞඛ්‍ය පද්ධතියේ ක්‍රියාකාරීත්වය සහ ඔරොත්තු දීමේ හැකියාව ඇතුළුව ජනගහනයට ඇති සෞඛ්‍ය අවදානම් පිළිබඳව ලෝක සෞඛ්‍ය සංවිධානය සමීපව නිරීක්ෂණය කරන අතර පළාත් සෞඛ්‍ය සේවාවන් ශක්තිමත් කිරීම සඳහා අවශ්‍ය තාක්ෂණික සහාය ලබා දෙන බව ටෙඩ්‍රොස් පැවසීය. (කොළඹ/අගෝස්තු 25/2022)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ලෝක සෞඛ්‍ය සංවිධානය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඩොලර් මිලියන හතරක්",
            "label": "MONEY"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "WHO සෞඛ්‍ය හදිසි අවස්ථා වැඩසටහන",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "අගෝස්තු 25 බ්රහස්පතින්දා",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "කවුද",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ලෝක සෞඛ්‍ය සංවිධානයේ ප්‍රාදේශීය සහ රට කාර්යාල",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "සෞඛ්ය අමාත්යාංශය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ටෙඩ්රොස්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "කවුද",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "நெருக்கடியால் பாதிக்கப்பட்டுள்ள இலங்கைக்கு 40 மில்லியன் டொலர்கள் பெறுமதியான மருத்துவ உதவிகளை வழங்குவதாக WHO உறுதியளித்துள்ளது",
      "author": "மஹதியா ஹம்சா",
      "body_lines": [
        "ECONOMYNEXT - உலக சுகாதார அமைப்பு (WHO) நெருக்கடியால் பாதிக்கப்பட்டுள்ள இலங்கைக்கு நான்கு மில்லியன் அமெரிக்க டொலர்கள் பெறுமதியான அத்தியாவசிய மருத்துவ பொருட்கள் மற்றும் நாட்டின் உடனடி சுகாதாரத் தேவைகளைப் பூர்த்தி செய்வதற்கு ஏனைய உதவிகளை வழங்குவதாக உறுதியளித்துள்ளது.",
        "உலக சுகாதார அமைப்பின் பணிப்பாளர் நாயகம் Dr Tedros Adhanom Ghebreyesus இலங்கை மக்களின் மிக அவசரமான சுகாதாரத் தேவைகளைப் பூர்த்தி செய்ய உடனடி நடவடிக்கை எடுக்குமாறு WHO சுகாதார அவசரகாலத் திட்டத்திற்கு உத்தரவிட்டுள்ளதாக ஜனாதிபதி அலுவலகம் வியாழன் ஆகஸ்ட் 25 அன்று தெரிவித்துள்ளது.",
        "சுகாதார அமைப்பில் COVID-19 தொடர்பான அழுத்தங்களுக்கு மேலதிகமாக இலங்கை எதிர்கொள்ளும் தற்போதைய பொருளாதார அழுத்தத்தை அமைப்பு அங்கீகரிக்கிறது என்று WHO தலைவர் மேற்கோள் காட்டினார்.",
        "\"இதற்காக, இலங்கை மக்களின் மிக அவசரமான சுகாதாரத் தேவைகளைப் பூர்த்தி செய்ய உடனடி நடவடிக்கை எடுக்க உலக சுகாதார அமைப்பின் அவசரகாலத் திட்டத்தை நான் பணித்துள்ளேன் என்பதை உங்களுக்குத் தெரிவித்துக் கொள்வதில் மகிழ்ச்சி அடைகிறேன்,\" என்று அவர் கூறினார்.",
        "WHO வின் பிராந்திய மற்றும் நாட்டு அலுவலகங்கள், அத்துடன் இலங்கையின் சுகாதார அமைச்சு மற்றும் ஏனைய தொடர்புடைய அமைச்சுகளுடன் இணைந்து மருத்துவப் பொருட்களை கொள்வனவு செய்யும் பணியில் WHO ஈடுபட்டுள்ளது.",
        "சுகாதார அமைப்பின் செயல்பாடு மற்றும் பின்னடைவு உட்பட மக்களுக்கு ஏற்படும் உடல்நல அபாயங்களை WHO உன்னிப்பாகக் கண்காணிக்கும் மற்றும் மாகாண சுகாதார சேவைகளை வலுப்படுத்த தேவையான தொழில்நுட்ப உதவிகளை வழங்கும் என்று டெட்ரோஸ் கூறினார். (கொழும்பு/ஆகஸ்ட்25/2022)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "இலங்கை",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "உலக சுகாதார நிறுவனம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "நான்கு மில்லியன் அமெரிக்க டாலர்கள்",
            "label": "MONEY"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "WHO சுகாதார அவசரநிலை திட்டம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆகஸ்ட் 25 வியாழன்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "WHO",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "WHO இன் பிராந்திய மற்றும் நாட்டு அலுவலகங்கள்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கையின்",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "சுகாதார அமைச்சகம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "டெட்ரோஸ்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "WHO",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}