{
  "newspaper_id": "daily-mirror-lk",
  "url": "https://www.dailymirror.lk/breaking_news/AG-requests-to-dismiss-the-case-against-Russian-Aeroflot-flight/108-239958",
  "time_ut": 1656407725,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "AG requests to dismiss the case against Russian Aeroflot flight",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "AG requests to dismiss the case against Russian Aeroflot flight",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "The Airport and Aviation Services Ltd through the Attorney General's Department today filed a motion before Colombo Commercial High Court urging to dismiss the case filed against Russian Aeroflot flight.",
        "On June 6, the Colombo Commercial High Court issued an order suspending the operation of Enjoining Order issued against Russian Aeroflot flight, after taking into consideration facts presented by parties including the Attorney General to effect that the Enjoining Order had been obtained by misleading the court and misrepresentation of facts.",
        "Additional Solicitor General Sumathi Dharmawardena PC appearing for the Airport and Aviation Services Ltd (second defendant) moved court to reject this plaint since the Russian Aeroflot flight has left the territorial jurisdiction of the court. He moved Court to dismiss the plaint in terms of section 56 of the Civil Procedure Code.",
        "\"There is no cause of action to proceed with the plaint since there is no flight in Sri Lanka.",
        "An order made by Court should be within the framework of the public policy of Sri Lanka,\" Dharmawardena said.",
        "Dr. Lasantha Hettiarachchi, appearing for the Russian Airlines sought the earliest possible date for the matter to be taken up for inquiry since the Aeroflot flights have suspended operations to Sri Lanka.",
        "Taking into consideration facts, Colombo Commercial High Court Judge Harsha Sethunge fixed the matter for inquiry on July 5.",
        "On June 2, the Colombo Commercial High Court issued an Enjoining Order preventing a Russian Aeroflot flight from taking off within the territorial jurisdiction of Sri Lanka pursuant to a request made by Celestial Aviation Trading Limited in Ireland.",
        "Celestial Aviation Trading Limited in Ireland obtained this Enjoining Order against Aeroflot Russian Airlines for its failure to comply with the terms of a Lease Agreement between two parties.",
        "In this application, the plaintiff company had named the Public Joint Stock Company-Aeroflot Russian Airlines and N.C. Abeywardena Acting Head of Air Navigation Services as the defendants of the petition.",
        "Avindra Rodrigo PC appeared for the plaintiff. Additional Solicitor General Sumathi Dharmawardena PC with SDSG Mahen Gopallawa and DSG Rajiv Gunatilleke appeared for the second defendant. (Lakmal Sooriyagoda)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "AG",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "Russian",
          "label": "NORP"
        },
        {
          "text": "Aeroflot",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "The Airport and Aviation Services Ltd",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Russian",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Aeroflot",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "June 6",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Enjoining Order",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Russian",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Aeroflot",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Enjoining Order",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the Airport and Aviation Services Ltd",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "second",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Russian Aeroflot",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Court",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "section 56",
            "label": "LAW"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Civil Procedure Code",
            "label": "EVENT"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Court",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Dharmawardena",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Lasantha Hettiarachchi",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Russian Airlines",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Aeroflot",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Harsha Sethunge",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "July 5",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "June 2",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Russian",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Aeroflot",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Celestial Aviation Trading Limited",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ireland",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Celestial Aviation Trading Limited",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ireland",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Aeroflot Russian Airlines",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "two",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the Public Joint Stock Company-Aeroflot Russian Airlines",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Air Navigation Services",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Avindra Rodrigo PC",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Mahen Gopallawa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "second",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Lakmal Sooriyagoda",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "රුසියානු Aeroflot ගුවන් යානයට එරෙහි නඩුව ඉවත් කරන ලෙස AG ඉල්ලා සිටී",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "රුසියානු Aeroflot ගුවන් යානයට එරෙහිව පවරා ඇති නඩුව නිෂ්ප්‍රභ කරන ලෙස බලකරමින් සීමාසහිත ගුවන් තොටුපළ සහ ගුවන් සේවා සමාගම නීතිපති දෙපාර්තමේන්තුව හරහා අද කොළඹ වාණිජ මහාධිකරණය හමුවේ මෝසමක් ගොනු කළේය.",
        "අධිකරණය නොමග යවමින් මෙම වාරණ නියෝගය ලබාගෙන ඇති බවට නීතිපතිවරයා ඇතුළු පාර්ශ්ව ඉදිරිපත් කළ කරුණු සැලකිල්ලට ගනිමින් රුසියානු Aeroflot ගුවන් යානයට එරෙහිව නිකුත් කර ඇති වාරණ නියෝගය ක්‍රියාත්මක කිරීම අත්හිටුවමින් කොළඹ වාණිජ මහාධිකරණය ජුනි 6 වැනිදා නියෝගයක් නිකුත් කළේය. කරුණු වැරදි ලෙස නිරූපණය කිරීම.",
        "සීමාසහිත Airport and Aviation Services Ltd (දෙවන විත්තිකරු) වෙනුවෙන් පෙනී සිටි අතිරේක සොලිසිටර් ජනරාල් සුමති ධර්මවර්ධන මහත්මිය මෙම පැමිණිල්ල ප්‍රතික්ෂේප කරන ලෙස අධිකරණයට ඉදිරිපත් කළේ රුසියානු Aeroflot යානය අධිකරණයේ භෞමික බල සීමාවෙන් ඉවත්ව ගොස් ඇති බැවිනි. සිවිල් නඩු විධාන සංග්‍රහයේ 56 වැනි වගන්තිය ප්‍රකාරව පැමිණිල්ල නිෂ්ප්‍රභ කිරීමට ඔහු අධිකරණයට ඉදිරිපත් විය.",
        "“ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ ගුවන් ගමනක් නොමැති බැවින් පැමිණිල්ල ඉදිරියට ගෙන යාමට ක්‍රියාමාර්ගයක් නොමැත.",
        "අධිකරණය විසින් කරන ලද නියෝගයක් ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ රාජ්‍ය ප්‍රතිපත්තියේ රාමුව තුළ තිබිය යුතුය,\" ධර්මවර්ධන පැවසීය.",
        "රුසියානු ගුවන් සේවය වෙනුවෙන් පෙනී සිටි වෛද්‍ය ලසන්ත හෙට්ටිආරච්චි මහතා, Aeroflot ගුවන් යානා ශ්‍රී ලංකාව වෙත මෙහෙයුම් අත්හිටුවා ඇති බැවින් ඒ සම්බන්ධයෙන් විමර්ශනය කිරීමට හැකි ඉක්මනින් දිනය ඉල්ලා සිටියේය.",
        "කරුණු සැලකිල්ලට ගත් කොළඹ වාණිජ මහාධිකරණ විනිසුරු හර්ෂ සේතුංග මහතා අදාළ නඩුව ජූලි 5 වැනිදා විභාගයට ගැනීමට නියම කළේය.",
        "අයර්ලන්තයේ Celestial Aviation Trading Limited විසින් කරන ලද ඉල්ලීමකට අනුව ජූනි 2 වන දින කොළඹ වාණිජ මහාධිකරණය විසින් රුසියානු Aeroflot ගුවන් යානයක් ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ භෞමික බල ප්‍රදේශය තුළ ගුවන් ගත වීම වළක්වමින් වාරණ නියෝගයක් නිකුත් කරන ලදී.",
        "අයර්ලන්තයේ Celestial Aviation Trading Limited සමාගම Aeroflot රුසියානු ගුවන් සමාගමට එරෙහිව මෙම වාරණ නියෝගය ලබා ගත්තේ පාර්ශව දෙකක් අතර බදු ගිවිසුමේ නියමයන්ට අනුකූලව කටයුතු නොකිරීම හේතුවෙන්.",
        "මෙම අයදුම්පත්‍රයේ පැමිණිල්ලේ විත්තිකරුවන් ලෙස පැමිණිලිකාර සමාගම මහජන ඒකාබද්ධ කොටස් සමාගම-Aeroflot Russian Airlines සහ වැඩබලන ගුවන් නාවික සේවා ප්‍රධානී N.C. අබේවර්ධන නම් කර තිබුණි.",
        "පැමිණිල්ල වෙනුවෙන් ජනාධිපති නීතිඥ අවින්ද්‍ර රුද්‍රිගු මහතා පෙනී සිටියේය. දෙවැනි විත්තිකරු වෙනුවෙන් අතිරේක සොලිසිටර් ජනරාල් ජනාධිපති නීතිඥ සුමති ධර්මවර්ධන, එස්.ඩී.එස්.ජී මහේන් ගොපල්ලව සහ ඩී.එස්.ජී. රජීව් ගුණතිලක සමඟ පෙනී සිටියා. (ලක්මාල් සූරියගොඩ)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "AG",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "රුසියානු",
          "label": "NORP"
        },
        {
          "text": "Aeroflot",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "සීමාසහිත ගුවන් තොටුපල සහ ගුවන් සේවා",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "රුසියානු",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Aeroflot",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ජූනි 6",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "වාරණ නියෝගය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "රුසියානු",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Aeroflot",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "වාරණ නියෝගය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "සීමාසහිත ගුවන් තොටුපළ සහ ගුවන් සේවා",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "දෙවැනි",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "රුසියානු Aeroflot",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "අධිකරණය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "56 වගන්තිය",
            "label": "LAW"
          },
          {
            "text": "සිවිල් නඩු විධාන සංග්රහය",
            "label": "EVENT"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "අධිකරණය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ධර්මවර්ධන ය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ලසන්ත හෙට්ටිආරච්චි",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "රුසියානු ගුවන් සේවය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Aeroflot",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "හර්ෂ සේතුංග",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජූලි 5",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ජූනි 2",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "රුසියානු",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Aeroflot",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Celestial Aviation Trading Limited",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "අයර්ලන්තය",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Celestial Aviation Trading Limited",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "අයර්ලන්තය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Aeroflot රුසියානු ගුවන් සේවය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "දෙක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "මහජන ඒකාබද්ධ කොටස් සමාගම - Aeroflot රුසියානු ගුවන් සේවය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගුවන් නාවික සේවා",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "අවින්ද්‍ර රුද්‍රිගු පී.සී",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "මහේන් ගොපල්ලව",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "දෙවැනි",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ලක්මාල් සූරියගොඩ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "ரஷ்ய ஏரோஃப்ளோட் விமானத்திற்கு எதிரான வழக்கை தள்ளுபடி செய்ய ஏஜி கோருகிறது",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "ரஷ்ய ஏரோஃப்ளோட் விமானத்திற்கு எதிராக தாக்கல் செய்யப்பட்ட வழக்கை தள்ளுபடி செய்யுமாறு கோரி ஏர்போர்ட் அன்ட் ஏவியேஷன் சர்வீசஸ் லிமிடெட் சட்டமா அதிபர் திணைக்களத்தின் ஊடாக கொழும்பு வர்த்தக மேல் நீதிமன்றில் இன்று மனுவொன்றை தாக்கல் செய்துள்ளது.",
        "நீதிமன்றத்தை தவறாக வழிநடத்தி இந்த தடை உத்தரவு பெறப்பட்டதாக அட்டர்னி ஜெனரல் உள்ளிட்ட தரப்பினர் முன்வைத்த உண்மைகளை கருத்தில் கொண்டு, ரஷ்ய ஏரோஃப்ளோட் விமானத்திற்கு எதிராக பிறப்பிக்கப்பட்ட தடை உத்தரவின் செயல்பாட்டை இடைநிறுத்தி ஜூன் 6 ஆம் தேதி கொழும்பு வணிக உயர் நீதிமன்றம் உத்தரவு பிறப்பித்தது. உண்மைகளை தவறாக சித்தரித்தல்.",
        "ஏர்போர்ட் அன்ட் ஏவியேஷன் சர்வீசஸ் லிமிடெட் (இரண்டாம் பிரதிவாதி) சார்பில் ஆஜரான கூடுதல் சொலிசிட்டர் ஜெனரல் சுமதி தர்மவர்தன பிசி, ரஷ்ய ஏரோஃப்ளோட் விமானம் நீதிமன்றத்தின் எல்லையை விட்டு வெளியேறியதால் இந்த வழக்கை நிராகரிக்குமாறு நீதிமன்றத்தை நாடினார். சிவில் நடைமுறைச் சட்டத்தின் 56-வது பிரிவின்படி அவர் மனுவைத் தள்ளுபடி செய்ய நீதிமன்றத்தை நாடினார்.",
        "\"இலங்கையில் விமானம் இல்லாததால், வழக்கை தொடர எந்த நடவடிக்கையும் இல்லை.",
        "நீதிமன்றத்தால் வழங்கப்படும் உத்தரவு இலங்கையின் பொதுக் கொள்கையின் கட்டமைப்பிற்குள் இருக்க வேண்டும்\" என்று தர்மவர்தன கூறினார்.",
        "ரஷ்ய விமான சேவைக்காக ஆஜரான கலாநிதி லசந்த ஹெட்டியாராச்சி, ஏரோஃப்ளோட் விமானங்கள் இலங்கைக்கான நடவடிக்கைகளை இடைநிறுத்தியுள்ளதால், இந்த விவகாரம் விசாரணைக்கு எடுத்துக்கொள்ளப்படுவதற்கான சாத்தியமான விரைவான தேதியைக் கோரினார்.",
        "உண்மைகளை கருத்திற்கொண்ட கொழும்பு வர்த்தக மேல் நீதிமன்ற நீதிபதி ஹர்ஷ சேதுங்க இந்த வழக்கை ஜூலை 5 ஆம் திகதி விசாரணைக்கு ஒத்திவைத்தார்.",
        "அயர்லாந்தில் உள்ள செலஸ்டியல் ஏவியேஷன் டிரேடிங் லிமிடெட் விடுத்த கோரிக்கைக்கு இணங்க, இலங்கையின் எல்லைக்குள் ரஷ்ய ஏரோஃப்ளோட் விமானம் புறப்படுவதைத் தடுக்கும் தடை உத்தரவை ஜூன் 2 அன்று கொழும்பு வணிக உயர் நீதிமன்றம் பிறப்பித்தது.",
        "அயர்லாந்தில் உள்ள செலஸ்டியல் ஏவியேஷன் டிரேடிங் லிமிடெட், ஏரோஃப்ளோட் ரஷியன் ஏர்லைன்ஸுக்கு எதிராக இந்த தடை உத்தரவைப் பெற்றுள்ளது.",
        "இந்த விண்ணப்பத்தில், வாதி நிறுவனம், பொது கூட்டுப் பங்கு நிறுவனம்-ஏரோஃப்ளோட் ரஷியன் ஏர்லைன்ஸ் மற்றும் ஏர் நேவிகேஷன் சர்வீசஸின் செயல் தலைவர் என்.சி. அபேவர்தன ஆகியோர் மனுவின் பிரதிவாதிகளாகக் குறிப்பிடப்பட்டுள்ளனர்",
        "மனுதாரர் சார்பில் அவிந்திர ரோட்ரிகோ ஆஜரானார். இரண்டாம் பிரதிவாதி சார்பாக மேலதிக சொலிசிட்டர் ஜெனரல் சுமதி தர்மவர்தன, எஸ்.டி.எஸ்.ஜி மகேன் கோபல்லவ மற்றும் டி.எஸ்.ஜி ராஜீவ் குணதிலக்க ஆகியோர் முன்னிலையாகினர். (லக்மால் சூரியகொட)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ஏஜி",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "ரஷ்யன்",
          "label": "NORP"
        },
        {
          "text": "ஏரோஃப்ளோட்",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "விமான நிலையம் மற்றும் விமான சேவைகள் லிமிடெட்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரஷ்யன்",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஏரோஃப்ளோட்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஜூன் 6",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "உத்தரவு உத்தரவு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரஷ்யன்",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஏரோஃப்ளோட்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "தடை உத்தரவு",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "விமான நிலையம் மற்றும் விமான சேவைகள் லிமிடெட்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இரண்டாவது",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரஷ்ய ஏரோஃப்ளோட்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "நீதிமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "பிரிவு 56",
            "label": "LAW"
          },
          {
            "text": "சிவில் நடைமுறைக் குறியீடு",
            "label": "EVENT"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "நீதிமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "தர்மவர்தன",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "லசந்த ஹெட்டியாராச்சி",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரஷ்ய ஏர்லைன்ஸ்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஏரோஃப்ளோட்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஹர்ஷா சேதுங்கே",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜூலை 5",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஜூன் 2",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரஷ்யன்",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஏரோஃப்ளோட்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Celestial Aviation Trading Limited",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "அயர்லாந்து",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Celestial Aviation Trading Limited",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "அயர்லாந்து",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஏரோஃப்ளோட் ரஷ்ய ஏர்லைன்ஸ்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இரண்டு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பொது கூட்டு பங்கு நிறுவனம் - ஏரோஃப்ளோட் ரஷ்ய ஏர்லைன்ஸ்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "விமான வழிசெலுத்தல் சேவைகள்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "அவிந்த்ரா ரோட்ரிகோ பிசி",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "மகேன் கோபல்லவ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இரண்டாவது",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "லக்மால் சூரியகொட",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}