{
  "newspaper_id": "lankadeepa-lk",
  "url": "https://www.lankadeepa.lk/latest_news/අලුතින්-බාරගත්-සභාපතිකම-ගැන-හර්ෂගෙන්-සහතිකයක්/1-618919",
  "time_ut": 1661750145,
  "original_lang": "si",
  "original_title": "අලුතින් බාරගත් සභාපතිකම ගැන හර්ෂගෙන් සහතිකයක්",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "An assurance from Harsha about the newly assumed chairmanship",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "Dr. Harsha De Silva, Colombo District Member of Samagi Jana Balawega said that he accepts the position of Chairman of the Finance Committee and fulfills its responsibilities to the best of his ability.",
        "Mr. Anura Priyadarshana Yapa, the former chairman of the said committee, also managed the position of chairman of the said committee well with his best efforts and for that he thanked him as the new chairman.",
        "Mr. Kanchana Wijesekera said to look into the procurement of fuel and coal and Mr. Harsha de Silva said that the Finance Committee has full powers and will act immediately to fulfill the minister's request.",
        "Investigate and appoint a separate committee for this purpose. Make procurement from the committee."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Harsha De Silva",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Samagi",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Jana Balawega",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Finance Committee",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Anura Priyadarshana Yapa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Kanchana Wijesekera",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Harsha de Silva",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Finance Committee",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        []
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "අලුතින් බාරගත් සභාපතිකම ගැන හර්ෂගෙන් සහතිකයක්",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "මුදල්  කාරක සභාවේ සභාපති ධුරය පිළිගන්නා අතර එහි වගකීම්  උපරිමයෙන් එය ඉටුකරන බව සමගි ජන බලවේගයේ කොළඹ දිස්ත්‍රික් මන්ත්‍රී ආචාර්ය හර්ෂ ද සිල්වා මහතා පැවසීය.",
        "එම කාරක සභාවේ හිටපු සභාපති අනුර ප්‍රියදර්ශන යාපා මහතා ද උපරිම උත්සාහයෙන් එම සභාවේ සභාපති ධුරය හොඳන් මෙහෙයවනු ලැබු අතර ඒ වෙනුවෙන් නව සභාපති ලෙස එතුමාට ස්තුතිය  පුදකරන බවද කීය.",
        "ඉන්ධන හා ගල් අඟුරු ප්‍රසම්පාදනය පිළිබඳ සොයා බලන ලෙස කංචන විජේසේකර මහතා පැවසු අතර ඊට සම්පූර්ණ බලතල මුදල් කාරක සභාවට තිබෙන බවත් අමාත්‍යවරයාගේ ඉල්ලීම ඉටුකරන්නට  වහාම ක්‍රියාත්මක වෙන බවත්  හර්ෂ ද සිල්වා මහතා කීය.",
        "සොයා බලන අතර මේ වෙනුවෙන් වෙනමම කාරක සභාවක් පත්කරන්න.කාරක සභාවෙන් ප්‍රසම්පාදනයත් කරන්න."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "හර්ෂ ද සිල්වා",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "සමගි",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජන බලවේගය",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "මුදල් කාරක සභාව",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "අනුර ප්‍රියදර්ශන යාපා",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "කාංචන විජේසේකර",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "හර්ෂ ද සිල්වා",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "මුදල් කාරක සභාව",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        []
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "புதிதாக பொறுப்பேற்றுள்ள தலைவர் பதவி குறித்து ஹர்ஷாவிடம் இருந்து ஒரு உறுதி",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "நிதிக் குழுவின் தலைவர் பதவியை ஏற்று தன்னால் இயன்றவரை பொறுப்புகளை நிறைவேற்றுவதாக சமகி ஜன பலவேகவின் கொழும்பு மாவட்ட உறுப்பினர் கலாநிதி ஹர்ஷ டி சில்வா தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "மேற்படி குழுவின் முன்னாள் தலைவர் திரு.அனுர பிரியதர்ஷன யாப்பாவும் தனது சிறந்த முயற்சியால் மேற்படி குழுவின் தலைவர் பதவியை சிறப்பாக நிர்வகித்து அதற்கு புதிய தலைவராக அவருக்கு நன்றி தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "எரிபொருள் மற்றும் நிலக்கரி கொள்வனவுகள் தொடர்பில் ஆராயுமாறு திரு.காஞ்சன விஜேசேகர தெரிவித்ததுடன், நிதிக் குழுவிற்கு முழு அதிகாரம் உள்ளதாகவும் அமைச்சரின் கோரிக்கையை நிறைவேற்றுவதற்கு உடனடியாக நடவடிக்கை எடுப்பதாகவும் திரு.ஹர்ஷ டி சில்வா தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "இதற்காக தனி குழுவை விசாரித்து நியமித்து, கமிட்டியில் இருந்து கொள்முதல் செய்ய வேண்டும்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ஹர்ஷ டி சில்வா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "சமகி",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜன பலவேகா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "நிதிக் குழு",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "அனுர பிரியதர்ஷன யாப்பா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "காஞ்சனா விஜேசேகர",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஹர்ஷ டி சில்வா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "நிதிக் குழு",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        []
      ]
    }
  }
}