{
  "newspaper_id": "d-b-s-jeyaraj-com",
  "url": "https://dbsjeyaraj.com/dbsj/archives/79077",
  "time_ut": 1660849020,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "SLPP Delegation led by National Organizer Basil Rajapaksa Meets President Wickremesinghe and Requests him to Facilitate Former President Gotabaya Rajapaksa’s safe Return to Sri Lanka :assures party’s fullest support to Ranil’s  endeavours to ensure the recovery of Sri Lanka’s economy.",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "SLPP Delegation led by National Organizer Basil Rajapaksa Meets President Wickremesinghe and Requests him to Facilitate Former President Gotabaya Rajapaksa’s safe Return to Sri Lanka :assures party’s fullest support to Ranil’s  endeavours to ensure the recovery of Sri Lanka’s economy.",
      "author": "Administrator",
      "body_lines": [
        "The Sri Lanka Podujana Peramuna says it has requested President Ranil Wickremesinghe to facilitate the safe return of former President Gotabaya Rajapaksa back to Sri Lanka.",
        "The SLPP said the request was made during a meeting between representatives of the SLPP and the President held on Thursday at the Presidential Secretariat.",
        "According to the SLPP, the party’s national organiser former Minister Basil Rajapaksa had assured the President of their fullest support in his endeavours to ensure the recovery of Sri Lanka’s economy. In a release, the SLPP said Rajapaksa had stressed to the President that this was the party’s main request.",
        "At the meeting, the SLPP was represented by Prasanna Ranatunga, Sagara Kariyawasam, Rohitha Abeygunawardena, Johnston Fernando, and Pavitra Wanniarachchi, Namal Rajapaksa and Sanjeeva Edirimanna while Sagala Ratnayake, Vajira Abeywardena, Ruwan Wijaywardena and Shamal Senarath were also in attendance.",
        "Former Ambassador of Sri Lanka to Russia Udayanga Weeratunga, this week told the media that former President Gotabaya Rajapaksa is set to return on 24 August. Gotabaya Rajapaksa is currently in Thailand after moving there from Singapore on 11 August."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "National Organizer Basil Rajapaksa Meets",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "Wickremesinghe",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "Facilitate",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "Gotabaya Rajapaksa",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "Sri Lanka",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "Ranil’s",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "Sri Lanka’s",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "Podujana Peramuna",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Gotabaya Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Thursday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Presidential Secretariat",
            "label": "FAC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Basil Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka’s",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "SLPP",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Prasanna Ranatunga",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sagara Kariyawasam",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Rohitha Abeygunawardena",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Johnston Fernando",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Wanniarachchi",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Namal Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sanjeeva Edirimanna",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sagala Ratnayake",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Vajira Abeywardena",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ruwan Wijaywardena",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Russia Udayanga Weeratunga",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "this week",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Gotabaya Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "24 August",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Gotabaya Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Thailand",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Singapore",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "11 August",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "ශ්‍රී ලංකා පොදුජන පෙරමුණේ ජාතික සංවිධායක බැසිල් රාජපක්ෂ මහතා ප්‍රමුඛ ශ්‍රී ලංකා පොදුජන පෙරමුණේ දූත පිරිස ජනාධිපති වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතා හමුවී හිටපු ජනාධිපති ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ මහතාට නිරුපද්‍රිතව යළි ශ්‍රී ලංකාවට පැමිණීමට පහසුකම් සලසන ලෙස ඉල්ලා සිටිති: ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ ආර්ථිකය යථා තත්ත්වයට පත් කිරීම සඳහා රනිල් ගෙන යන ප්‍රයත්නයට පක්ෂයේ පූර්ණ සහාය ලබා දෙන බවට සහතික වෙයි.",
      "author": "පරිපාලක",
      "body_lines": [
        "හිටපු ජනාධිපති ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ මහතා ආරක්ෂිතව ශ්‍රී ලංකාවට පැමිණීමට පහසුකම් සලසන ලෙස තමන් ජනාධිපති රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතාගෙන් ඉල්ලීමක් කළ බව ශ්‍රී ලංකා පොදුජන පෙරමුණ පවසයි.",
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකා පොදුජන පෙරමුණේ නියෝජිතයින් සහ ජනාධිපතිවරයා අතර බ්‍රහස්පතින්දා ජනාධිපති ලේකම් කාර්යාලයේ පැවති හමුවකදී මෙම ඉල්ලීම සිදු කළ බව ශ්‍රී ලංකා පොදුජන පෙරමුණ පවසයි.",
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකා පොදුජන පෙරමුණට අනුව, ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ ආර්ථිකය යථා තත්ත්වයට පත් කිරීම සහතික කිරීම සඳහා දරන ප්‍රයත්නයන් සඳහා ඔවුන්ගේ උපරිම සහයෝගය ලබා දෙන බවට එම පක්ෂයේ ජාතික සංවිධායක හිටපු අමාත්‍ය බැසිල් රාජපක්ෂ මහතා ජනාධිපතිවරයාට සහතික විය. නිවේදනයක් නිකුත් කරමින් ශ්‍රී ලංකා පොදුජන පෙරමුණ කියා සිටියේ එය පක්ෂයේ ප්‍රධාන ඉල්ලීම බව රාජපක්ෂ ජනාධිපතිවරයාට අවධාරණය කළ බවයි.",
        "මෙම රැස්වීමට ශ්‍රී ලංකා පොදුජන පෙරමුණ නියෝජනය කරමින් ප්‍රසන්න රණතුංග, සාගර කාරියවසම්, රෝහිත අබේගුණවර්ධන, ජොන්ස්ටන් ප්‍රනාන්දු, සහ පවිත්‍රා වන්නිආරච්චි, නාමල් රාජපක්ෂ, සංජීව එදිරිමාන්න යන මහත්ම මහත්මීන් එක්ව සිටි අතර සාගල රත්නායක, වජිර අබේවර්ධන, රුවන් විජයවර්ධන සහ ශාමල් සෙනරත් යන මහත්වරුද සහභාගි වූහ.",
        "රුසියාවේ හිටපු ශ්‍රී ලංකා තානාපති උදයංග වීරතුංග මහතා මේ සතියේ මාධ්‍ය වෙත ප්‍රකාශ කළේ හිටපු ජනාධිපති ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ මහතා අගෝස්තු 24 වැනිදා යළි පැමිණීමට නියමිත බවයි. අගෝස්තු 11 වන දින සිංගප්පූරුවේ සිට එහි ගිය ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ මේ වන විට තායිලන්තයේ සිටී."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ජාතික සංවිධායක බැසිල් රාජපක්ෂ මහතා හමුවෙයි",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "වික්‍රමසිංහ",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "පහසුකම් සලසන්න",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "රනිල්ගේ",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "පොදුජන පෙරමුණ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "බ්රහස්පතින්දා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජනාධිපති ලේකම් කාර්යාලය",
            "label": "FAC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "බැසිල් රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "SLPP",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ප්‍රසන්න රණතුංග",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "සාගර කාරියවසම්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "රෝහිත අබේගුණවර්ධන",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජොන්ස්ටන් ප්‍රනාන්දු",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "වන්නිආරච්චි",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "නාමල් රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "සංජීව එදිරිමාන්න",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "සාගල රත්නායක",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "වජිර අබේවර්ධන",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "රුවන් විජයවර්ධන",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "රුසියාව උදයංග වීරතුංග",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "මෙම සතිය",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "අගෝස්තු 24",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "තායිලන්තය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "සිංගප්පූරුව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "අගෝස්තු 11",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "ஸ்ரீலங்கா பொதுஜன பெரமுனவின் தேசிய அமைப்பாளர் பசில் ராஜபக்ச தலைமையிலான குழுவினர் ஜனாதிபதி விக்ரமசிங்கவை சந்தித்து, முன்னாள் ஜனாதிபதி கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்சவின் பாதுகாப்பாக இலங்கை திரும்புவதற்கு வசதி செய்து தருமாறு வேண்டுகோள் விடுத்துள்ளனர்: இலங்கையின் பொருளாதாரத்தை மீட்டெடுப்பதற்கான ரணிலின் முயற்சிகளுக்கு கட்சியின் பூரண ஆதரவை உறுதியளிக்கிறது.",
      "author": "நிர்வாகி",
      "body_lines": [
        "முன்னாள் ஜனாதிபதி கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ச பாதுகாப்பாக இலங்கைக்கு திரும்புவதற்கு வசதி செய்து தருமாறு ஜனாதிபதி ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்கவிடம் கோரிக்கை விடுத்துள்ளதாக ஸ்ரீலங்கா பொதுஜன பெரமுன தெரிவித்துள்ளது.",
        "ஸ்ரீலங்கா பொதுஜன பெரமுனவின் பிரதிநிதிகளுக்கும் ஜனாதிபதிக்கும் இடையில் நேற்று வியாழக்கிழமை ஜனாதிபதி செயலகத்தில் இடம்பெற்ற சந்திப்பின் போதே இந்த கோரிக்கை விடுக்கப்பட்டுள்ளதாக ஸ்ரீலங்கா பொதுஜன பெரமுன தெரிவித்துள்ளது.",
        "ஸ்ரீலங்கா பொதுஜன பெரமுனவின் படி, கட்சியின் தேசிய அமைப்பாளரான முன்னாள் அமைச்சர் பசில் ராஜபக்ஷ, இலங்கையின் பொருளாதாரத்தை மீட்டெடுப்பதற்கான தனது முயற்சிகளுக்கு ஜனாதிபதி அவர்களின் பூரண ஆதரவை வழங்குவதாக உறுதியளித்துள்ளார். இதுவே கட்சியின் முக்கிய கோரிக்கை என ராஜபக்ச ஜனாதிபதியிடம் வலியுறுத்தியதாக SLPP தெரிவித்துள்ளது.",
        "இக்கூட்டத்தில் ஸ்ரீலங்கா பொதுஜன பெரமுனவின் சார்பில் பிரசன்ன ரணதுங்க, சாகர காரியவசம், ரோஹித அபேகுணவர்தன, ஜோன்ஸ்டன் பெர்னாண்டோ, பவித்ரா வன்னியாராச்சி, நாமல் ராஜபக்ஷ, சஞ்சீவ எதிரிமான்ன ஆகியோர் கலந்து கொண்டதுடன் சாகல ரத்நாயக்க, வஜிர அபேவர்தன, ருவான் விஜயவர்தன, ஷமல் செனரத் ஆகியோரும் கலந்துகொண்டனர்.",
        "முன்னாள் ஜனாதிபதி கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ச எதிர்வரும் ஆகஸ்ட் மாதம் 24ஆம் திகதி நாடு திரும்பவுள்ளதாக ரஷ்யாவுக்கான இலங்கையின் முன்னாள் தூதுவர் உதயங்க வீரதுங்க ஊடகங்களுக்கு தெரிவித்துள்ளார். ஆகஸ்ட் 11 ஆம் தேதி சிங்கப்பூரில் இருந்து தாய்லாந்திற்குச் சென்ற கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ச தற்போது தாய்லாந்தில் இருக்கிறார்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "தேசிய அமைப்பாளர் பசில் ராஜபக்ச சந்திப்பு",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "விக்கிரமசிங்க",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "வசதி செய்",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ச",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "இலங்கை",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "ரணிலின்",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "இலங்கையின்",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "பொதுஜன பெரமுன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "வியாழன்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜனாதிபதி செயலகம்",
            "label": "FAC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பசில் ராஜபக்ச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கையின்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "எஸ்.எல்.பி.பி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ராஜபக்சே",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பிரசன்ன ரணதுங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "சாகர காரியவசம்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரோஹித அபேகுணவர்தன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜோன்ஸ்டன் பெர்னாண்டோ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "வன்னியாராச்சி",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "நாமல் ராஜபக்ச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "சஞ்சீவ எதிரிமான்ன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "சாகல ரத்நாயக்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "வஜிர அபேவர்தன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ருவான் விஜயவர்தன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரஷ்யா உதயங்க வீரதுங்க",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்த வாரம்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "24 ஆகஸ்ட்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "தாய்லாந்து",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சிங்கப்பூர்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "11 ஆகஸ்ட்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}