{
  "newspaper_id": "lankadeepa-lk",
  "url": "https://www.lankadeepa.lk/news/කටාර්වලින්-ණයට-ඉන්ධන---ගෑස්-ගන්න-සාකච්ඡා/101-615567",
  "time_ut": 1656431495,
  "original_lang": "si",
  "original_title": "කටාර්වලින් ණයට ඉන්ධන - ගෑස් ගන්න සාකච්ඡා",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Negotiations to buy fuel and gas on loan from Qatar",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "Minister of Power and Energy Kanchana Wijesekera, who is on an official visit to the State of Qatar, held discussions with the Deputy Director General of the Qatar Fund for Development and discussed obtaining fuel and gas on loan to Sri Lanka.",
        "The Deputy Director General of the Qatar Fund for Development has informed the Minister that funds have been allocated for medical supplies and that the International Monetary Fund's request for credit facilities will be considered."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Qatar",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "the State of Qatar",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Qatar Fund for Development",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the Qatar Fund for Development",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the International Monetary Fund's",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "කටාර්වලින් ණයට ඉන්ධන - ගෑස් ගන්න සාකච්ඡා",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "කටාර් රාජ්‍යයේ නිල සංචාරයක නිතරව සිටින විදුලිබල හා බලශක්ති අමාත්‍ය කංචන විජේසේකර මහතා සංවර්ධනය සඳහා වන කටාර් අරමුදලේ නියෝජ්‍ය අධ්‍යක්‍ෂ ජනරාල්වරා සමඟ සාකච්ඡා කළ අතර ශ්‍රී ලංකාවට ණය පදනමින් ඉන්ධන සහ ගෑස් ලබාගැනීමට සාකච්ඡා කළේය.",
        "වෛද්‍ය සැපයුම් සඳහා අරමුදල් වෙන් කර ඇති බවත් ජාත්‍යන්තර මූල්‍ය අරමුදලේ ණය පහසුකම් සඳහා වන ඉල්ලීම සලකා බලන බවත් එහිදී සංවර්ධනය සඳහා කටාර් අරමුදලේ නියෝජ්‍ය අධ්‍යක්‍ෂ ජනරාල්වරා අමාත්‍යවරයාට දැනුම්දී තිබේ."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "කටාර්",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "කටාර් රාජ්‍යය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "සංවර්ධනය සඳහා කටාර් අරමුදල",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "සංවර්ධනය සඳහා කටාර් අරමුදල",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජාත්‍යන්තර මුල්‍ය අරමුදලේ",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "கத்தாரிடம் இருந்து கடனாக எரிபொருள் மற்றும் எரிவாயு வாங்குவதற்கான பேச்சுவார்த்தை",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "கட்டார் நாட்டிற்கு உத்தியோகபூர்வ விஜயம் மேற்கொண்டுள்ள மின்வலு மற்றும் எரிசக்தி அமைச்சர் காஞ்சன விஜேசேகர அபிவிருத்திக்கான கட்டார் நிதியத்தின் பிரதிப் பணிப்பாளர் நாயகத்துடன் கலந்துரையாடியதுடன் இலங்கைக்கு கடனாக எரிபொருள் மற்றும் எரிவாயுவைப் பெற்றுக் கொள்வது தொடர்பில் கலந்துரையாடினார்.",
        "மருத்துவப் பொருட்களுக்கு நிதி ஒதுக்கப்பட்டுள்ளதாகவும் சர்வதேச நாணய நிதியத்தின் கடன் வசதிக்கான கோரிக்கை பரிசீலிக்கப்படும் எனவும் கத்தார் அபிவிருத்திக்கான நிதியத்தின் பிரதிப் பணிப்பாளர் அமைச்சரிடம் தெரிவித்துள்ளார்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "கத்தார்",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "கத்தார் மாநிலம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "வளர்ச்சிக்கான கத்தார் நிதி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "வளர்ச்சிக்கான கத்தார் நிதி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "சர்வதேச நாணய நிதியம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}