{
  "newspaper_id": "daily-mirror-lk",
  "url": "https://www.dailymirror.lk/latest_news/GOTABAYA-RAJAPAKSA-RESIGNS/342-241125",
  "time_ut": 1657857412,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "GOTABAYA RAJAPAKSA RESIGNS",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "GOTABAYA RAJAPAKSA RESIGNS",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "Gotabaya Rajapaksa has resigned as the President of Sri Lanka, Speaker of Parliament announced a short while ago.",
        "Ranil Wickremesinghe will be sworn in as the President later today as an interim President till the conclusion of electing a new President by Parliament, the Speaker added.",
        "Under the section 38.1 (b) of the Constitution of the Democratic Socialist Republic of Sri Lanka I have received the resignation letter of His Excellency the President Gotabaya Rajapaksa . Accordingly,  effective from 14 July 2022 , from this point forth the President has legally resigned from his legal duties and responsibilities. Under these circumstances, the constitutional procedure of appointing a new President will now be activated. Until this constitutional procedure is over, according to the constitution the Prime Minister will function in the capacity of the President overseeing functions, duties, and powers of the office of the President.",
        "As informed by me at the Party Leaders meeting convened on the subject of selecting the President, the President will be selected according to the provisions of the Special Provisions Act No. 2 of 1981 and the Article 40 of the Constitution. It is my intention to complete this procedure successfully and speedily. As the oldest democracy in the South Asian region holding Democratic traditions sacred, completing this process in a transparent and Democratic manner would be a milestone not only in the history of Sri Lanka, but also of the Democratic history of the world.",
        "Therefore, I would like to request maximum cooperation for this Democratic process from all party leaders, state officials, and security forces. My special appeal to our respected and dear citizens of Sri Lanka is to create the peaceful environment that will allow all members of Parliament to attend Parliament freely and act according to their conscience. Under such an environment, with the help of all responsible, I intend to conclude the above process within a short period of seven days. Accordingly, the notice is hereby given that the Parliament will convene of the 16th of this month (16.07.2022) and all members are requested to attend on that day."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Gotabaya Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "later today",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "38.1",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Democratic",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Gotabaya Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "14 July 2022",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Party Leaders",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "2",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Article 40 of the Constitution",
            "label": "LAW"
          },
          {
            "text": "South Asian",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Democratic",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Democratic",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Democratic",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Democratic",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "seven days",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the 16th of this month",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "16.07.2022",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "that day",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ ඉල්ලා අස්වෙයි",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ මහතා ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ ජනාධිපති ධුරයෙන් ඉල්ලා අස් වූ බව කථානායකවරයා මීට සුළු මොහොතකට පෙර නිවේදනය කළේය.",
        "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව විසින් නව ජනාධිපතිවරයෙකු තෝරා පත් කර ගැනීම අවසන් වන තුරු අන්තර්වාර ජනාධිපතිවරයෙකු ලෙස රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතා අද පස්වරුවේ ජනාධිපතිවරයා ලෙස දිවුරුම් දීමට නියමිත බව කථානායකවරයා වැඩිදුරටත් පැවසීය.",
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකා ප්‍රජාතාන්ත්‍රික සමාජවාදී ජනරජයේ ආණ්ඩුක්‍රම ව්‍යවස්ථාවේ 38.1 (ආ) වගන්තිය යටතේ අතිගරු ජනාධිපති ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ මැතිතුමාගේ ඉල්ලා අස්වීමේ ලිපිය මා වෙත ලැබී ඇත. ඒ අනුව,  2022 ජූලි 14 දින සිට බලපැවැත්වෙන පරිදි, මෙතැන් සිට ජනාධිපතිවරයා නීත්‍යානුකූලව සිය නීතිමය රාජකාරි සහ වගකීම්වලින් ඉල්ලා අස්වී ඇත. මේ තත්ත්වය යටතේ නව ජනාධිපතිවරයකු පත්කිරීමේ ව්‍යවස්ථාපිත ක්‍රියා පටිපාටිය දැන් ක්‍රියාත්මක වනු ඇත. මෙම ව්‍යවස්ථාපිත ක්‍රියාපටිපාටිය අවසන් වනතුරු ආණ්ඩුක්‍රම ව්‍යවස්ථාව අනුව ජනාධිපතිවරයාගේ තනතුරේ කටයුතු, රාජකාරි සහ බලතල අධීක්‍ෂණය කරමින් අගමැතිවරයා කටයුතු කරනු ඇත.",
        "ජනාධිපතිවරයා තෝරා ගැනීම සම්බන්ධයෙන් කැදවා ඇති පක්ෂ නායක රැස්වීමේදී මා දන්වා ඇති පරිදි 1981 අංක 2 දරන විශේෂ විධිවිධාන පනතේ සහ ආණ්ඩුක්‍රම ව්‍යවස්ථාවේ 40 වැනි වගන්තියේ විධිවිධාන අනුව ජනාධිපතිවරයා තෝරා ගනු ඇත. මෙම ක්‍රියාපටිපාටිය සාර්ථකව හා ඉක්මනින් අවසන් කිරීම මගේ අරමුණයි. ප‍්‍රජාතන්ත‍්‍රවාදී සම්ප‍්‍රදායන් පූජනීයත්වයට පත් කරන දකුණු ආසියාතික කලාපයේ පැරණිතම ප‍්‍රජාතන්ත‍්‍රවාදී රාජ්‍යයක් ලෙස මෙම කි‍්‍රයාවලිය විනිවිදභාවයෙන් හා ප‍්‍රජාතන්ත‍්‍රවාදීව නිම කිරීම ශ‍්‍රී ලංකා ඉතිහාසයේ පමණක් නොව ලෝක ප‍්‍රජාතන්ත‍්‍රවාදී ඉතිහාසයේ සන්ධිස්ථානයක් වනු ඇත.",
        "එබැවින්, මෙම ප්‍රජාතන්ත්‍රවාදී ක්‍රියාවලිය සඳහා සියලු පක්ෂ නායකයින්, රාජ්‍ය නිලධාරීන් සහ ආරක්ෂක අංශවලින් උපරිම සහයෝගය ඉල්ලා සිටීමට කැමැත්තෙමි. ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ අපගේ ගෞරවනීය සහ ආදරණීය පුරවැසියන් වෙත මගේ විශේෂ ආයාචනය වන්නේ සියලුම පාර්ලිමේන්තු මන්ත්‍රීවරුන්ට නිදහසේ පාර්ලිමේන්තුවට පැමිණීමට සහ ඔවුන්ගේ හෘද සාක්ෂියට අනුව කටයුතු කිරීමට හැකි සාමකාමී පරිසරයක් නිර්මාණය කරන ලෙසයි. එවන් වටපිටාවක් යටතේ වගකිව යුතු සියලු දෙනාගේම සහාය ඇතිව දින හතක් වැනි කෙටි කාලයක් තුළ ඉහත ක්‍රියාවලිය අවසන් කිරීමට අදහස් කරමි. ඒ අනුව පාර්ලිමේන්තුව මේ මස 16 වැනි දින (2022.07.16) රැස්වන බවත් එදිනට සියලු මන්ත්‍රීවරුන් සහභාගි වන ලෙසත් මෙම දැනුම්දීම දන්වා සිටී."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "අද පසුව",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "38.1",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ප්‍රජාතන්ත්‍රවාදී",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "2022 ජූලි 14",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "පක්ෂ නායකයන්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "2",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ආණ්ඩුක්‍රම ව්‍යවස්ථාවේ 40 වැනි වගන්තිය",
            "label": "LAW"
          },
          {
            "text": "දකුණු ආසියානු",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ප්‍රජාතන්ත්‍රවාදී",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ප්‍රජාතන්ත්‍රවාදී",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ප්‍රජාතන්ත්‍රවාදී",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ප්‍රජාතන්ත්‍රවාදී",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "දින හතක්",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "මේ මස 16 වැනිදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "2022.07.16",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "එදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ச ராஜினாமா",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "இலங்கை அதிபர் கோத்தபய ராஜபக்சே தனது பதவியை ராஜினாமா செய்ததாக சபாநாயகர் சற்றுமுன் அறிவித்தார்.",
        "பாராளுமன்றத்தினால் புதிய ஜனாதிபதியை தெரிவு செய்யும் வரை இடைக்கால ஜனாதிபதியாக ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க இன்று ஜனாதிபதியாக பதவிப் பிரமாணம் செய்து கொள்வார் என சபாநாயகர் மேலும் தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "இலங்கை ஜனநாயக சோசலிச குடியரசின் அரசியலமைப்பின் 38.1 (b) பிரிவின் கீழ், அதிமேதகு ஜனாதிபதி கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ஷவின் இராஜினாமா கடிதம் எனக்கு கிடைத்துள்ளது. அதன்படி,  14 ஜூலை 2022 முதல் நடைமுறைக்கு வரும், இதுமுதல் ஜனாதிபதி சட்டப்பூர்வமாக தனது சட்டப்பூர்வ கடமைகள் மற்றும் பொறுப்புகளில் இருந்து ராஜினாமா செய்துள்ளார். இந்நிலையில், புதிய ஜனாதிபதியை நியமிப்பதற்கான அரசியலமைப்பு நடைமுறை தற்போது செயல்படுத்தப்படும். இந்த அரசியலமைப்பு நடைமுறை முடிவடையும் வரை, அரசியலமைப்பின் படி, ஜனாதிபதியின் அலுவலகத்தின் செயல்பாடுகள், கடமைகள் மற்றும் அதிகாரங்களை மேற்பார்வையிடும் ஜனாதிபதியின் தகுதியில் பிரதமர் செயல்படுவார்.",
        "ஜனாதிபதியை தெரிவு செய்யும் விடயத்தில் கூட்டப்பட்ட கட்சித் தலைவர்கள் கூட்டத்தில் நான் தெரிவித்தபடி, 1981 ஆம் ஆண்டின் 2 ஆம் இலக்க விசேட ஏற்பாடுகள் சட்டம் மற்றும் அரசியலமைப்பின் 40 ஆவது சரத்தின் படி ஜனாதிபதி தெரிவு செய்யப்படுவார். இந்த நடைமுறையை வெற்றிகரமாகவும் விரைவாகவும் முடிக்க வேண்டும் என்பதே எனது நோக்கம். தெற்காசியப் பிராந்தியத்தில் ஜனநாயக மரபுகளை புனிதமாக வைத்திருக்கும் பழமையான ஜனநாயகம் என்ற வகையில், இந்த செயல்முறையை வெளிப்படையான மற்றும் ஜனநாயக முறையில் நிறைவு செய்வது இலங்கையின் வரலாற்றில் மட்டுமல்ல, உலக ஜனநாயக வரலாற்றிலும் ஒரு மைல்கல்லாக இருக்கும்.",
        "எனவே, அனைத்துக் கட்சித் தலைவர்கள், மாநில அதிகாரிகள் மற்றும் பாதுகாப்புப் படையினரிடம் இருந்து இந்த ஜனநாயக செயல்முறைக்கு அதிகபட்ச ஒத்துழைப்பைக் கோர விரும்புகிறேன். இலங்கையின் மதிப்பிற்குரிய மற்றும் அன்பான குடிமக்களுக்கு எனது விசேஷ வேண்டுகோள் என்னவென்றால், அனைத்து நாடாளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர்களும் சுதந்திரமாக பாராளுமன்றத்திற்கு வருவதற்கும் அவர்களின் மனசாட்சிப்படி செயல்படுவதற்கும் அமைதியான சூழலை உருவாக்க வேண்டும். இவ்வாறான சூழலில், பொறுப்புள்ள அனைவரின் உதவியோடு, மேற்கூறிய செயல்முறையை ஏழு நாட்களுக்குள் குறுகிய காலத்திற்குள் முடிக்க உத்தேசித்துள்ளேன். இதன்படி, நாடாளுமன்றம் இம்மாதம் 16ஆம் திகதி (16.07.2022) கூடும் எனவும், அன்றைய தினம் அனைத்து உறுப்பினர்களும் கலந்துகொள்ளுமாறும் இதன் மூலம் அறிவித்தல் விடுக்கப்பட்டுள்ளது."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "பின்னர் இன்று",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "38.1",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜனநாயகம்",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "14 ஜூலை 2022",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "கட்சித் தலைவர்கள்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "2",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "அரசியலமைப்பின் பிரிவு 40",
            "label": "LAW"
          },
          {
            "text": "தெற்காசிய",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜனநாயகம்",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜனநாயகம்",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜனநாயகம்",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஜனநாயகம்",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஏழு நாட்கள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்த மாதம் 16 ஆம் தேதி",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "16.07.2022",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "அந்த நாள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}