{
  "newspaper_id": "b-b-c-com-sinhala",
  "url": "https://www.bbc.com/sinhala/sri-lanka-62222493",
  "time_ut": 1658206911,
  "original_lang": "si",
  "original_title": "සජිත් අගමැති කරන්න සුදානම් බව පොහොට්ටුවේ සභාපති ජී.එල්.පීරිස් කියයි",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "GL Peiris, Chairman of Pohottuwa, says that he is ready to make Sajith the Prime Minister",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "Sri Lanka Podujana Peramuna President Professor GL Peiris told the BBC that he is committed to making opposition leader Sajith Premadasa the Prime Minister.",
        "When the nominations related to the selection of the successor president were called in Parliament today (July 19), the name of Dallas Alahaperuma MP was proposed by Sajith Premadasa. Professor G. L. Peiris seconded the motion.",
        "Many people are wondering whether a plan to make Dallas Alahaperuma the President and Sajith Premadasa the Prime Minister will be implemented by now.",
        "Also, a group including Sagara Kariyawasam, Secretary of the Sri Lanka Podujana Peramuna chaired by Professor G.L. Peiris, is working for Ranil Wickramasinghe's victory.",
        "However, many MPs refrained from commenting on this matter to the media."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "GL Peiris",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "Pohottuwa",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "Sajith",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Podujana Peramuna",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "GL Peiris",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "BBC",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sajith Premadasa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "July 19",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Dallas",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sajith Premadasa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "G. L. Peiris",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Dallas",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sagara Kariyawasam",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "Podujana Peramuna",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "G.L. Peiris",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickramasinghe's",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        []
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "සජිත් අගමැති කරන්න සුදානම් බව පොහොට්ටුවේ සභාපති ජී.එල්.පීරිස් කියයි",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "විපක්ෂ නායක සජිත් ප්‍රේමදාස අගමැතිවරයා කිරීමට කැපවෙන බව ශ්‍රී ලංකා පොදුජන පෙරමුණේ සභාපති මහාචාර්ය ජී.එල් පීරිස් බීබීසීයට පැවසුවේය.",
        "අනුප්‍රාප්තික ජනාධිපතිවරයා තෝරා ගැනීමට අදාළ නාමයෝජනා අද (ජූලි 19) පාර්ලිමේන්තුවේදී කැඳවූ අවස්ථාවේදී ඒ සඳහා ඩලස් අලහපෙරුම මන්ත්‍රීවරයාගේ නම යෝජනා කරන ලද්දේ සජිත් ප්‍රේමදාස විසිනි. මහාචාර්ය ජී.එල් පීරිස් එම යෝජනාව ස්ථිර කළේය.",
        "ඩලස් අලහපෙරුම ජනාධිපති කර සජිත් ප්‍රේමදාස අගමැති කිරීමේ සැලැස්මක් මේ වනවිට ක්‍රියාත්මක වේ දැයි යන්න බොහෝ දෙනාගේ ද කුකුසයි.",
        "එමෙන්ම මහාචාර්ය ජී.එල් පීරිස්  සභාපතීත්වය දරණ ශ්‍රී ලංකා පොදුජන පෙරමුණේ ලේකම් සාගර කාරියවසම් ඇතුළු කණ්ඩායමක් රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ ජයග්‍රහණය කිරීම සඳහාද  ක්‍රියා කරමින් සිටී.",
        "කෙසේ වෙතත් මේ සම්බන්ධයෙන් මාධ්‍යට අදහස් පළ කිරීමෙන් බොහෝ මන්ත්‍රීවරු වැළකී සිටියහ."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ජී එල් පීරිස්",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "පොහොට්ටුව",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "සජිත්",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "පොදුජන පෙරමුණ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජී එල් පීරිස්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "බීබීසී",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "සජිත් ප්‍රේමදාස",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජූලි 19",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඩලස්",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "සජිත් ප්‍රේමදාස",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජී.එල්. පීරිස්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ඩලස්",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "සාගර කාරියවසම්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "පොදුජන පෙරමුණ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජී.එල් පීරිස්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහගේ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        []
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "சஜித்தை பிரதமராக்க தயார் என பொஹொட்டுவ தலைவர் ஜீ.எல்.பீரிஸ் தெரிவித்துள்ளார்",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "எதிர்க்கட்சித் தலைவர் சஜித் பிரேமதாசவை பிரதமராக்குவதில் உறுதியாக இருப்பதாக ஸ்ரீலங்கா பொதுஜன பெரமுனவின் தலைவர் பேராசிரியர் ஜீ.எல்.பீரிஸ் பிபிசியிடம் தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "வாரிசான ஜனாதிபதியை தெரிவு செய்வது தொடர்பான வேட்புமனுக்கள் இன்று (ஜூலை 19) பாராளுமன்றத்தில் கோரப்பட்ட போது, ​​சஜித் பிரேமதாசவினால் டலஸ் அழகப்பெரும எம்.பியின் பெயர் முன்மொழியப்பட்டது. பேராசிரியர் ஜி.எல்.பீரிஸ் பிரேரணையை உறுதிப்படுத்தினார்.",
        "டலஸ் அழகப்பெருமவை ஜனாதிபதியாக்கும் திட்டம், சஜித் பிரேமதாசவை பிரதமராக்கும் திட்டம் இந்நேரத்தில் அமுல்படுத்தப்படுமா என பலரும் கேள்வி எழுப்புகின்றனர்.",
        "அத்துடன், பேராசிரியர் ஜீ.எல்.பீரிஸ் தலைமையில் ஸ்ரீலங்கா பொதுஜன பெரமுனவின் செயலாளர் சாகர காரியவசம் உள்ளிட்ட குழுவினர் ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்கவின் வெற்றிக்காக செயற்பட்டு வருகின்றனர்.",
        "எவ்வாறாயினும், பல எம்.பி.க்கள் இந்த விடயம் தொடர்பில் ஊடகங்களுக்கு கருத்து தெரிவிக்கவில்லை."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ஜி.எல்.பீரிஸ்",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "பொஹொட்டுவ",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "சஜித்",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "பொதுஜன பெரமுன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜி.எல்.பீரிஸ்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "பிபிசி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "சஜித் பிரேமதாச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜூலை 19",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "டல்லாஸ்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சஜித் பிரேமதாச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜி.எல்.பீரிஸ்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "டல்லாஸ்",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "சாகர காரியவசம்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "பொதுஜன பெரமுன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜி.எல்.பீரிஸ்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்கவின்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        []
      ]
    }
  }
}