{
  "newspaper_id": "news-first-lk",
  "url": "https://www.newsfirst.lk/2022/08/22/sajith-meets-ranil-says-no-to-positions/",
  "time_ut": 1661179140,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Sajith meets Ranil, says NO to positions",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Sajith meets Ranil, says NO to positions",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); Opposition Leader Sajith Premadasa met with President Ranil Wickremesinghe for talks on Monday (22).",
        "The Samagi Jana Balavegaya said the President and the Opposition Leader exchanges views on an All-Party Government.",
        "The SJB said that the President had once again requested the Opposotion Leader to join with the Government with ministerial positions awarded to SJB MPs.",
        "The Opposition Leader had turned down the offer, and stressed to the President that the SJB will NOT obtain ministerial positions, and will support an All-Party Government program.",
        "The Opposition Leader had noted that rather than adding more burden to the public coffers by obtaining ministerial positions, the SJB will remain in opposition and support the positive steps taken by the government, and criticize the anti-people programs proposed by the government.",
        "Had a forthright amicable discussion with Pres @RW_UNP on the challenges faced by the country.",
        "Re-emphasized @sjbsrilanka's commitment to support all progressive initiatives via parliamentary committee system & stressed our grave reservations on the use of PTA as state policy.",
        "Assault on Deshabandu: Eight suspects plead guilty, and released on bail",
        "Sri Lankan Apparel exporters at Sourcing at Magic in Las Vegas",
        "MTV goes to HRCSL against intimidation tactics used to harass the Senior Management of Capital Maharaja Group"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Ranil",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "News 1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sajith Premadasa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Monday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "22",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Samagi",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Jana Balavegaya",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "All-Party Government",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "SJB",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "SJB",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "All-Party Government",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "SJB",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "PTA",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Eight",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lankan Apparel",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Magic",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "Las Vegas",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "MTV",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Senior Management of Capital Maharaja Group",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "සජිත් රනිල් හමුවෙයි, තනතුරු එපා කියයි",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); විපක්ෂ නායක සජිත් ප්‍රේමදාස මහතා සඳුදා (22) ජනාධිපති රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතා හමුවී සාකච්ඡා කළේය.",
        "සර්ව පාක්ෂික ආණ්ඩුවක් සම්බන්ධයෙන් ජනාධිපතිවරයා සහ විපක්ෂ නායකවරයා අදහස් හුවමාරු කර ගන්නා බව සමගි ජන බලවේගය පවසයි.",
        "SJB මන්ත්‍රීවරුන්ට පිරිනමන අමාත්‍ය ධූර සමඟ රජය සමඟ එක්වන ලෙස ජනාධිපතිවරයා නැවත වරක් විපක්ෂ නායකවරයාගෙන් ඉල්ලීමක් කළ බව SJB පවසයි.",
        "විපක්ෂ නායකවරයා එම යෝජනාව ප්‍රතික්ෂේප කර ඇති අතර, SJB අමාත්‍ය ධූර ලබා නොගන්නා බවත්, සර්ව පාක්ෂික රජයේ වැඩපිළිවෙලකට සහය දෙන බවත් ජනාධිපතිවරයාට අවධාරණය කර ඇත.",
        "අමාත්‍ය ධුර ලබාගෙන රාජ්‍ය භාණ්ඩාගාරයට තවත් බරක් එකතු කරනවාට වඩා SJB විපක්ෂයේ රැඳී සිටිමින් රජය ගන්නා සාධනීය ක්‍රියාමාර්ගවලට සහය පළ කරන බවත් රජය යෝජනා කරන ජනතා විරෝධී වැඩපිළිවෙළ විවේචනය කරන බවත් විපක්ෂ නායකවරයා සඳහන් කර තිබුණා.",
        "රට මුහුණ දෙන අභියෝග පිළිබඳව Pres @RW_UNP සමඟ සෘජු සුහද සාකච්ඡාවක් පැවැත්වීය.",
        "පාර්ලිමේන්තු කාරක සභා ක්‍රමය හරහා සියලුම ප්‍රගතිශීලී මුලපිරීම් සඳහා සහාය වීමට @sjbsrilanka හි කැපවීම නැවත අවධාරණය කළ අතර රාජ්‍ය ප්‍රතිපත්තියක් ලෙස ත්‍රස්තවාදය වැළැක්වීමේ පනත භාවිතා කිරීම පිළිබඳ අපගේ බරපතල වෙන් කිරීම් අවධාරණය කළේය.",
        "දේශබන්දුට පහරදීම: සැකකරුවන් අට දෙනෙකු වරද පිළිගෙන ඇප මත මුදා හැරේ",
        "ලාස් වේගාස් හි මැජික් හි සෝර්සිං හි ශ්‍රී ලංකා ඇඟලුම් අපනයනකරුවන්",
        "කැපිටල් මහරාජා සමූහ ව්‍යාපාරයේ ජ්‍යෙෂ්ඨ කළමනාකාරීත්වයට හිරිහැර කිරීමට යොදාගත් බිය ගැන්වීමේ උපක්‍රමවලට එරෙහිව MTV HRCSL වෙත යයි"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "රනිල්",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "News 1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "සජිත් ප්‍රේමදාස",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "සඳුදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "22",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "සමගි",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජන බලවේගය",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "සර්ව පාක්ෂික ආණ්ඩුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "එස්.ජේ.බී",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "එස්.ජේ.බී",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "සර්ව පාක්ෂික ආණ්ඩුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "එස්.ජේ.බී",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "PTA",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "අට",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකා ඇඟලුම්",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "මැජික්",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "ලාස් වේගාස්",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "MTV",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "කැපිටල් මහරාජා සමූහයේ ජ්‍යෙෂ්ඨ කළමනාකාරීත්වය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "பதவிகள் வேண்டாம் என்று ரணிலை சந்தித்த சஜித்",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); எதிர்க்கட்சித் தலைவர் சஜித் பிரேமதாச, ஜனாதிபதி ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்கவை திங்கட்கிழமை (22) சந்தித்துப் பேச்சு நடத்தினார்.",
        "ஜனாதிபதியும் எதிர்க்கட்சித் தலைவரும் சர்வகட்சி அரசாங்கம் தொடர்பில் கருத்துக்களை பரிமாறிக் கொள்வதாக சமகி ஜன பலவேகய தெரிவித்துள்ளது.",
        "SJB பாராளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர்களுக்கு வழங்கப்படும் அமைச்சுப் பதவிகளுடன் அரசாங்கத்துடன் இணைந்து கொள்ளுமாறு ஜனாதிபதி மீண்டும் எதிர்க்கட்சித் தலைவரிடம் கோரிக்கை விடுத்துள்ளதாக SJB தெரிவித்துள்ளது.",
        "எதிர்க்கட்சித் தலைவர் இந்த வாய்ப்பை நிராகரித்தார், மேலும் SJB அமைச்சர் பதவிகளைப் பெறாது, மேலும் சர்வகட்சி அரசாங்க வேலைத்திட்டத்திற்கு ஆதரவளிக்கும் என்று ஜனாதிபதியிடம் வலியுறுத்தினார்.",
        "அமைச்சுப் பதவிகளைப் பெற்று பொது நிதிக்கு மேலும் சுமையைச் சேர்ப்பதற்குப் பதிலாக, SJB எதிர்க்கட்சியில் இருந்துகொண்டு அரசாங்கத்தின் சாதகமான நடவடிக்கைகளுக்கு ஆதரவளிப்பதாகவும், அரசாங்கம் முன்வைக்கும் மக்கள் விரோத திட்டங்களை விமர்சிப்பதாகவும் எதிர்க்கட்சித் தலைவர் குறிப்பிட்டுள்ளார்.",
        "நாடு எதிர்கொள்ளும் சவால்கள் குறித்து @RW_UNP பிரஸ் உடன் நேரடியான இணக்கமான விவாதம் நடைபெற்றது.",
        "பாராளுமன்றக் குழு அமைப்பு மூலம் அனைத்து முற்போக்கான முயற்சிகளுக்கும் ஆதரவளிக்கும் @sjbsrilanka இன் உறுதிப்பாட்டை மீண்டும் வலியுறுத்தியது மற்றும் பயங்கரவாத தடைச் சட்டத்தை மாநிலக் கொள்கையாகப் பயன்படுத்துவதில் எங்களின் கடுமையான இட ஒதுக்கீடுகளை வலியுறுத்தியது.",
        "தேசாபாண்டுவில் தாக்குதல்: எட்டு சந்தேக நபர்கள் குற்றத்தை ஒப்புக்கொள்கிறார்கள், ஜாமீனில் விடுவிக்கப்பட்டனர்",
        "லாஸ் வேகாஸில் உள்ள மேஜிக் அட் சோர்ஸிங்கில் இலங்கை ஆடை ஏற்றுமதியாளர்கள்",
        "கேபிட்டல் மஹாராஜா குழுமத்தின் மூத்த நிர்வாகத்தை துன்புறுத்த பயன்படுத்தப்படும் மிரட்டல் தந்திரங்களுக்கு எதிராக எம்டிவி HRCSL க்கு செல்கிறது"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ரணில்",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "News 1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சஜித் பிரேமதாச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "திங்கட்கிழமை",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "22",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "சமகி",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜன பலவேகயா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "அனைத்து கட்சி அரசு",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "எஸ்.ஜே.பி",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "எஸ்.ஜே.பி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "அனைத்து கட்சி அரசு",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "எஸ்.ஜே.பி",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "PTA",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "எட்டு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை ஆடை",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "மந்திரம்",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "லாஸ் வேகஸ்",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "எம்டிவி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "கேபிடல் மகாராஜா குழுமத்தின் மூத்த நிர்வாகம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}