{
  "newspaper_id": "d-b-s-jeyaraj-com",
  "url": "https://dbsjeyaraj.com/dbsj/archives/79019",
  "time_ut": 1660589280,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Immigration Dept  Grants Scottish National Kayleigh Fraser  a  Grace Period to Leave Sri Lanka Following  the Dismissal  of het Writ Application Against her Deportation Order by the Court of Appeal",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Immigration Dept  Grants Scottish National Kayleigh Fraser  a  Grace Period to Leave Sri Lanka Following  the Dismissal  of het Writ Application Against her Deportation Order by the Court of Appeal",
      "author": "Administrator",
      "body_lines": [
        "Scottish national Kayleigh Fraser, who participated in the “aragalaya” (struggle) in Sri Lanka, will be given time to leave the country, said the Department of Immigration and Emigration, following yesterday’s (16) dismissal by the Court of Appeal of her writ petition filed challenging her deportation by the Department over alleged visa violations.",
        "The Media Spokesperson of the Department, speaking to The Morning yesterday, noted that the court had dismissed the petition on the grounds that the individual lacked the authority to file such action against the decision taken by the Department, in which she had named the Controller General of Immigration and Emigration as a respondent to the petition.",
        "“The petition filed by Fraser was dismissed today by the court, as she lacked the authority to file such a petition against the decision taken by the Department.”",
        "Following this dismissal of the case, Fraser has been instructed to depart from Sri Lanka as soon as possible, but it was informed that the Department has allowed her a grace period to leave the country.",
        "The petition was filed on 12 August by the Scottish national requesting the court to issue an order preventing her deportation to her country and seeking the revocation of the cancellation of her visa period.",
        "Fraser, who was granted resident visa for medical purposes, had, it was revealed, also engaged in business activities, in addition to her anti-Government activism on social media."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Kayleigh Fraser",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "Grace Period",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "Dismissal",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Scottish",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kayleigh Fraser",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Department of Immigration and Emigration",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "yesterday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "16",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Court of Appeal",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Department",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "The Media Spokesperson of the Department",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "The Morning",
            "label": "WORK_OF_ART"
          },
          {
            "text": "yesterday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Department",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Controller General of Immigration and Emigration",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Fraser",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Department",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Fraser",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Department",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "12 August",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Scottish",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Fraser",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "ආගමන විගමන දෙපාර්තමේන්තුව විසින් ස්කොට්ලන්ත ජාතික කේලී ෆ්‍රේසර්ට ශ්‍රී ලංකාව හැර යාමට සහන කාලයක් ලබා දෙයි, අභියාචනාධිකරණය විසින් පිටුවහල් කිරීමේ නියෝගයට එරෙහි හෙට් රිට් අයදුම්පත ප්‍රතික්ෂේප කිරීමෙන් පසුව",
      "author": "පරිපාලක",
      "body_lines": [
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ අරගලයට (අරගලයට) සහභාගී වූ ස්කොට්ලන්ත ජාතික කයිලී ෆ්‍රේසර්ට රට හැර යාමට කාලය ලබා දෙන බව ආගමන හා විගමන දෙපාර්තමේන්තුව ඊයේ (16) අභියාචනාධිකරණය විසින් අභියාචනාධිකරණය විසින් ප්‍රකාශ කළේය. වීසා උල්ලංඝනය කිරීම් සම්බන්ධයෙන් දෙපාර්තමේන්තුව විසින් ඇය පිටුවහල් කිරීම අභියෝගයට ලක් කරමින් ගොනු කරන ලද පෙත්සම.",
        "දෙපාර්තමේන්තුවේ මාධ්‍ය ප්‍රකාශක, ඊයේ උදෑසන කළ විමසීමකදී කියා සිටියේ තමන් පාලක ජනරාල්වරයා නම් කර තිබූ දෙපාර්තමේන්තුව විසින් ගනු ලැබූ තීරණයට එරෙහිව එවැනි ක්‍රියාමාර්ගයක් ගොනු කිරීමට පුද්ගලයාට බලයක් නොමැති බව පවසමින් අධිකරණය විසින් මෙම පෙත්සම නිෂ්ප්‍රභ කළ බවයි. පෙත්සමේ වගඋත්තරකරුවෙකු ලෙස ආගමන හා විගමන.",
        "\"දෙපාර්තමේන්තු ගත් තීරණයට එරෙහිව එවැනි පෙත්සමක් ගොනු කිරීමට ඇයට බලයක් නොමැති බැවින් ෆ්‍රේසර් විසින් ගොනු කරන ලද පෙත්සම අධිකරණය විසින් අද ප්‍රතික්ෂේප කරන ලදී.\"",
        "මෙම නඩුව නිෂ්ප්‍රභ කිරීමත් සමඟ ෆ්‍රේසර්ට හැකි ඉක්මනින් ශ්‍රී ලංකාවෙන් පිටව යන ලෙස දන්වා ඇතත් ඇයට රට හැර යාමට දෙපාර්තමේන්තුව සහන කාලයක් ලබා දී ඇති බව දන්වා ඇත.",
        "ඇය සිය රටට පිටුවහල් කිරීම වළක්වන නියෝගයක් නිකුත් කරන ලෙසත්, වීසා කාලය අවලංගු කිරීම අවලංගු කරන ලෙසත් ඉල්ලා ස්කොට්ලන්ත ජාතිකයා විසින් අගෝස්තු 12 වැනි දින මෙම පෙත්සම ගොනු කර තිබුණි.",
        "වෛද්‍ය කටයුතු සඳහා නේවාසික වීසා ලබාදී ඇති ෆ්‍රේසර්, සමාජ මාධ්‍ය තුළ රාජ්‍ය විරෝධී ක්‍රියාකාරකම්වලට අමතරව ව්‍යාපාරික කටයුතුවල ද නිරත වී ඇති බව අනාවරණය විය."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Kayleigh Fraser",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "සහන කාලය",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "සේවයෙන් පහ කිරීම",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ස්කොට්ලන්ත",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kayleigh Fraser",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ආගමන හා විගමන දෙපාර්තමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඊයේ",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "16",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "අභියාචනාධිකරණය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ෙදපාර්තෙම්න්තුෙව්",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "දෙපාර්තමේන්තුවේ මාධ්‍ය ප්‍රකාශක",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "උදෑසන",
            "label": "WORK_OF_ART"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඊයේ",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "දෙපාර්තමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ආගමන හා විගමන පාලක ජනරාල්",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ෆ්රේසර්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ෙදපාර්තෙම්න්තුෙව්",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ෆ්රේසර්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ෙදපාර්තෙම්න්තුෙව්",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "අගෝස්තු 12",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ස්කොට්ලන්ත",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ෆ්රේසර්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "மேன்முறையீட்டு நீதிமன்றத்தால் நாடுகடத்தப்பட்ட உத்தரவுக்கு எதிரான ஹெட் ரிட் விண்ணப்பம் நிராகரிக்கப்பட்டதைத் தொடர்ந்து, ஸ்காட்டிஷ் நேஷனல் கெய்லி ஃப்ரேசருக்கு இலங்கையை விட்டு வெளியேறுவதற்கான கால அவகாசத்தை குடிவரவுத் திணைக்களம் வழங்குகிறது.",
      "author": "நிர்வாகி",
      "body_lines": [
        "இலங்கையில் நடைபெற்ற “அறகலய” (போராட்டம்) யில் கலந்து கொண்ட ஸ்கொட்லாந்து நாட்டைச் சேர்ந்த கெய்லி பிரேசர், மேன்முறையீட்டு நீதிமன்றத்தினால் நேற்று (16) நிராகரிக்கப்பட்டதைத் தொடர்ந்து, அவர் நாட்டை விட்டு வெளியேற கால அவகாசம் வழங்கப்படும் என குடிவரவு மற்றும் குடியகல்வு திணைக்களம் தெரிவித்துள்ளது. விசா மீறல் குற்றச்சாட்டில் திணைக்களம் அவரை நாடு கடத்தியதை எதிர்த்து தாக்கல் செய்யப்பட்ட மனு.",
        "திணைக்களத்தின் ஊடகப் பேச்சாளர், திணைக்களத்தின் ஊடகப் பேச்சாளர், திணைக்களத்தினால் எடுக்கப்பட்ட தீர்மானத்திற்கு எதிராக, கட்டுப்பாட்டாளர் ஜெனரலைக் குறிப்பிட்டு, அத்தகைய நடவடிக்கையை தாக்கல் செய்ய தனிநபருக்கு அதிகாரம் இல்லை என்ற அடிப்படையில், இந்த மனுவை நீதிமன்றம் தள்ளுபடி செய்ததாக நேற்று காலை குறிப்பிட்டார். மனுவின் பிரதிவாதியாக குடிவரவு மற்றும் குடியகல்வு.",
        "\"திணைக்களம் எடுத்த முடிவுக்கு எதிராக அத்தகைய மனுவை தாக்கல் செய்ய அவருக்கு அதிகாரம் இல்லாததால், பிரேசர் தாக்கல் செய்த மனு நீதிமன்றத்தால் இன்று தள்ளுபடி செய்யப்பட்டது.\"",
        "இந்த வழக்கு தள்ளுபடி செய்யப்பட்டதைத் தொடர்ந்து, பிரேசர் விரைவில் இலங்கையை விட்டு வெளியேறுமாறு அறிவுறுத்தப்பட்டுள்ளார், ஆனால் அவர் நாட்டை விட்டு வெளியேறுவதற்கு திணைக்களம் அவகாசம் வழங்கியுள்ளதாக தெரிவிக்கப்பட்டுள்ளது.",
        "ஆகஸ்ட் 12 ஆம் தேதி ஸ்காட்லாந்து நாட்டவரால் தனது நாட்டுக்கு நாடு கடத்தப்படுவதைத் தடுக்கும் உத்தரவைப் பிறப்பிக்குமாறு கோரியும் அவரது விசா காலத்தை ரத்து செய்யக் கோரியும் மனு தாக்கல் செய்யப்பட்டது.",
        "மருத்துவ நோக்கங்களுக்காக குடியுரிமை விசா வழங்கப்பட்ட ஃப்ரேசர், சமூக ஊடகங்களில் அரசாங்கத்திற்கு எதிரான தனது செயல்பாட்டிற்கு மேலதிகமாக வணிக நடவடிக்கைகளிலும் ஈடுபட்டது தெரியவந்தது."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "கெய்லீ ஃப்ரேசர்",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "கருணை காலம்",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "பதவி நீக்கம்",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ஸ்காட்டிஷ்",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "கெய்லீ ஃப்ரேசர்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "குடிவரவு மற்றும் குடியகல்வு திணைக்களம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "நேற்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "16",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "மேல்முறையீட்டு நீதிமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "துறை",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "திணைக்களத்தின் ஊடகப் பேச்சாளர்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "தி மார்னிங்",
            "label": "WORK_OF_ART"
          },
          {
            "text": "நேற்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "துறை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "குடிவரவு மற்றும் குடியகல்வு கட்டுப்பாட்டாளர் ஜெனரல்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஃப்ரேசர்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "துறை",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஃப்ரேசர்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "துறை",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "12 ஆகஸ்ட்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஸ்காட்டிஷ்",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஃப்ரேசர்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}