{
  "newspaper_id": "d-b-s-jeyaraj-com",
  "url": "https://dbsjeyaraj.com/dbsj/archives/78505",
  "time_ut": 1657393020,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Chandrika Kumaratunga Condemns Torching of Premier Wickremesinghe’s Home; “The ‘struggle’ does not need violence to achieve its goal of ousting a government that is highly disliked by the people”  says Former President",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Chandrika Kumaratunga Condemns Torching of Premier Wickremesinghe’s Home; “The ‘struggle’ does not need violence to achieve its goal of ousting a government that is highly disliked by the people”  says Former President",
      "author": "Administrator",
      "body_lines": [
        "While condemning the torching of the private residence of Prime Minister Ranil Wickremesinghe on Saturday (9), former President Chandrika Bandaranaike Kumaratunga said that there is no need for violence to oust a government that lacks the support of the people.",
        "Making a special statement regarding the prevailing situation in the country, she said: “Violence will only cause chaos and you (those engaged in the struggle) will be seen as using the same methods and practices as the Government that you wish to change. The people have had enough of the violence, lies, and robbery of the Rajapaksa regime. That is why the people support this struggle and they do not wish them to be repeated.”",
        "Commenting on the incident of Wickremesinghe’s private residence having been set on fire, she said that she strongly condemns the incident, and added: “The ‘struggle’ does not need violence to achieve its goal of ousting a government that is highly disliked by the people and establishing a viable, people’s Government.”",
        "During the massive protest that took place last Saturday (9) demanding the resignations of President Gotabaya Rajapaksa, Premier Wickremesinghe and the Government, a group of people had gathered outside Wickremesinghe’s private residence at Fifth Lane in Colombo 3 and staged a protest demanding his resignation. During the protest, a group of journalists were brutally assaulted by the Police and Police Special Task Force (STF) officers who were at the scene. Shortly after the attacks on journalists, a group had broken into Wickremesinghe’s residence and set the place on fire."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Wickremesinghe",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Saturday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "9",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Chandrika Bandaranaike",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kumaratunga",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "last Saturday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "9",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Gotabaya Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Fifth Lane",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Police and Police Special Task Force",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "STF",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "අගමැති වික්‍රමසිංහගේ නිවසට ගිනි තැබීම චන්ද්‍රිකා කුමාරතුංග හෙළා දකියි; ජනතා අප්‍රසාදයට ලක්වන ආණ්ඩුවක් එළවා දැමීමේ අරමුණ ඉටුකර ගැනීමට ‘අරගලයට’ ප්‍රචණ්ඩත්වය අවශ්‍ය නැතැයි හිටපු ජනපති කියයි",
      "author": "පරිපාලක",
      "body_lines": [
        "සෙනසුරාදා (9) අග්‍රාමාත්‍ය රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතාගේ පෞද්ගලික නිවසට ගිනි තැබීම හෙළා දකිමින් හිටපු ජනාධිපතිනි චන්ද්‍රිකා බණ්ඩාරනායක කුමාරතුංග මහත්මිය ප්‍රකාශ කළේ ජනතා සහය නොමැති ආණ්ඩුවක් පළවා හැරීමට ප්‍රචණ්ඩත්වය අවශ්‍ය නොවන බවයි.",
        "රටේ පවතින තත්ත්වය සම්බන්ධයෙන් විශේෂ ප්‍රකාශයක් කරමින් ඇය මෙසේ පැවසුවාය: “ප්‍රචණ්ඩත්වය අවුල් ජාලාවක් පමණක් ඇති කරන අතර ඔබ (අරගලයේ නියැලෙන්නන්) ඔබ වෙනස් කිරීමට බලාපොරොත්තු වන රජය භාවිතා කරන ක්‍රම සහ භාවිතයන් භාවිතා කරන බව සලකනු ඇත. රාජපක්ෂ රෙජීමයේ ප්‍රචණ්ඩත්වය, බොරුව, මංකොල්ලකෑම් ජනතාවට ඕනෑ තරම් තිබේ. ඒ නිසා තමයි ජනතාව මේ අරගලයට සහය දෙන්නේ.",
        "වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතාගේ පෞද්ගලික නිවසට ගිනි තැබීමේ සිද්ධිය සම්බන්ධයෙන් අදහස් දක්වමින් ඇය එම සිද්ධිය තරයේ හෙළා දකින බවත්, “ජනතාවගේ අප්‍රසාදයට ලක් වූ රජයක් එළවා දැමීමේ අරමුණ ඉටුකර ගැනීමට ‘අරගලයට’ ප්‍රචණ්ඩත්වය අවශ්‍ය නොවන බවත් ඇය පැවසුවාය. සහ ශක්‍ය, ජනතාවාදී රජයක් ස්ථාපිත කිරීම.”",
        "ජනාධිපති ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ, අගමැති වික්‍රමසිංහ ඇතුළු රජයට ඉල්ලා අස්වන ලෙස බලකරමින් පසුගිය සෙනසුරාදා (9) පැවති දැවැන්ත විරෝධතාවයේදී කොළඹ 3 පස්වන පටුමගේ පිහිටි වික්‍රමසිංහගේ පෞද්ගලික නිවස ඉදිරිපිට පිරිසක් රැස්ව ඔහුට ඉල්ලා අස්වන ලෙස බලකරමින් විරෝධතාවයක නිරත වුණා. විරෝධතාව අතරතුර මාධ්‍යවේදීන් පිරිසකට එම ස්ථානයේ සිටි පොලිස් සහ පොලිස් විශේෂ කාර්ය බළකායේ (STF) නිලධාරීන් විසින් අමානුෂික ලෙස පහර දී ඇත. මාධ්‍යවේදීන්ට පහරදීමෙන් ටික වේලාවකට පසු කිසියම් පිරිසක් වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතාගේ නිවසට කඩා වැදී එම ස්ථානයට ගිනි තබා ඇත."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "වික්‍රමසිංහ",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "සෙනසුරාදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "9",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "චන්ද්‍රිකා බණ්ඩාරනායක",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "කුමාරතුංග ය",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ගිය සෙනසුරාදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "9",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "පස්වන පටුමග",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "පොලිසිය සහ පොලිස් විශේෂ කාර්ය බලකාය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "එස්.ටී.එෆ්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "பிரதமர் விக்கிரமசிங்கவின் வீட்டிற்கு தீவைக்கப்பட்டமைக்கு சந்திரிகா குமாரதுங்க கண்டனம்; மக்களால் பெரிதும் விரும்பப்படாத அரசாங்கத்தை பதவியில் இருந்து அகற்றும் இலக்கை அடைய ‘போராட்டத்திற்கு’ வன்முறை தேவையில்லை” என முன்னாள் ஜனாதிபதி தெரிவித்துள்ளார்.",
      "author": "நிர்வாகி",
      "body_lines": [
        "பிரதமர் ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்கவின் தனிப்பட்ட இல்லம் சனிக்கிழமை (9) எரிக்கப்பட்டதைக் கண்டித்த முன்னாள் ஜனாதிபதி சந்திரிக்கா பண்டாரநாயக்க குமாரதுங்க, மக்களின் ஆதரவற்ற அரசாங்கத்தை பதவியில் இருந்து அகற்றுவதற்கு வன்முறைகள் தேவையில்லை என தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "நாட்டில் நிலவும் சூழ்நிலை குறித்து சிறப்பு அறிக்கை வெளியிட்ட அவர், “வன்முறையால் குழப்பம்தான் ஏற்படும், நீங்கள் மாற்ற விரும்பும் அரசாங்கத்தின் அதே வழிமுறைகளையும் நடைமுறைகளையும் நீங்கள் (போராட்டத்தில் ஈடுபட்டுள்ளவர்கள்) பயன்படுத்தியவர்களாகவே பார்க்கப்படுவீர்கள். ராஜபக்ச ஆட்சியின் வன்முறைகள், பொய்கள், கொள்ளைகள் மக்களுக்கு போதுமானதாக உள்ளது. அதனால்தான் இந்த போராட்டத்தை மக்கள் ஆதரிக்கிறார்கள், மேலும் இது மீண்டும் நடைபெறுவதை அவர்கள் விரும்பவில்லை.",
        "விக்கிரமசிங்கவின் தனிப்பட்ட இல்லம் தீக்கிரையாக்கப்பட்ட சம்பவம் தொடர்பில் கருத்து தெரிவித்த அவர், இந்த சம்பவத்தை தாம் வன்மையாகக் கண்டிப்பதாகவும் மேலும் மேலும் தெரிவிக்கையில், “மக்களால் பெரிதும் விரும்பப்படாத அரசாங்கத்தை அகற்றும் இலக்கை அடைய ‘போராட்டத்திற்கு’ வன்முறை தேவையில்லை. மற்றும் ஒரு சாத்தியமான, மக்கள் அரசாங்கத்தை நிறுவுதல்.",
        "ஜனாதிபதி கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ஷ, பிரதமர் விக்ரமசிங்க மற்றும் அரசாங்கம் பதவி விலகக் கோரி கடந்த சனிக்கிழமை (9) இடம்பெற்ற பாரிய ஆர்ப்பாட்டத்தின் போது, ​​கொழும்பு 3 இல் உள்ள ஐந்தாவது பாதையில் உள்ள விக்கிரமசிங்கவின் தனிப்பட்ட இல்லத்திற்கு வெளியே ஒரு குழுவினர் ஒன்று திரண்டு அவரை பதவி விலகுமாறு கோரி ஆர்ப்பாட்டத்தில் ஈடுபட்டனர். ஆர்ப்பாட்டத்தின் போது, ​​சம்பவ இடத்தில் இருந்த பொலிஸ் மற்றும் பொலிஸ் விசேட அதிரடிப்படை (STF) அதிகாரிகளால் ஊடகவியலாளர்கள் குழுவொன்று கொடூரமான முறையில் தாக்கப்பட்டது. ஊடகவியலாளர்கள் மீது தாக்குதல் நடத்தப்பட்ட சிறிது நேரத்திலேயே, ஒரு குழுவினர் விக்கிரமசிங்கவின் வீட்டிற்குள் புகுந்து அந்த இடத்திற்கு தீ வைத்துள்ளனர்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "விக்கிரமசிங்க",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "சனிக்கிழமை",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "9",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "சந்திரிகா பண்டாரநாயக்கா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "குமாரதுங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ராஜபக்சே",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "கடந்த சனிக்கிழமை",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "9",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஐந்தாவது பாதை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "பொலிஸ் மற்றும் பொலிஸ் விசேட அதிரடிப்படை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "எஸ்.டி.எஃப்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}