{
  "newspaper_id": "ada-derana-lk",
  "url": "http://www.adaderana.lk/news/83948/stf-arrests-two-accomplices-of-kimbula-ele-guna",
  "time_ut": 1659086400,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "STF arrests two accomplices of “Kimbula Ele Guna”",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "STF arrests two accomplices of “Kimbula Ele Guna”",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "The Police Special Task Force has arrested two persons who have been operating the drug syndicate of the organized criminal gang leader “Kibula Ale Guna”.",
        "The relevant suspects were arrested based on information received by the STF Intelligence Division.",
        "The STF officers seized 6kg and 440g of Kerala cannabis, 5g and 300mg of heroin and one M67 live grenade manufactured in a foreign country in possession of the suspects.",
        "One of the arrestees is a 45-year-old resident of Madampitiya Road of Colombo 15 who is named Angamuththu Raja alias “High Coat Raja” and the other is named Nagaraja Robin Nicolas who is aged 32.",
        "The arrested suspects were handed over to the Wattala Police for further inquiries."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "STF",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "two",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "two",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kibula Ale Guna",
            "label": "WORK_OF_ART"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the STF Intelligence Division",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "STF",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "6kg",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "440",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kerala",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "5",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "300mg",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "one",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "M67",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "One",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "45-year-old",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Madampitiya Road of Colombo",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Angamuththu Raja",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Nagaraja Robin Nicolas",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "32",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the Wattala Police",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "කිඹුල ඇලේ ගුණාගේ ගෝලයන් දෙදෙනෙකු STF අත්අඩංගුවට",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "සංවිධානාත්මක අපරාධ කල්ලි නායක කිබුල ඇලේ ගුණාගේ මත්ද්‍රව්‍ය ජාවාරම මෙහෙයවූ පුද්ගලයින් දෙදෙනෙකු පොලිස් විශේෂ කාර්ය බලකාය විසින් අත්අඩංගුවට ගෙන තිබෙනවා.",
        "විශේෂ කාර්ය බළකායේ බුද්ධි අංශයට ලැබුණු තොරතුරකට අනුවයි අදාළ සැකකරුවන් අත්අඩංගුවට ගෙන ඇත්තේ.",
        "සැකකරුවන් සන්තකයේ තිබී විදේශීය රටක නිෂ්පාදිත කේරළ ගංජා කිලෝග්‍රෑම් 6යි ග්‍රෑම් 440ක්, හෙරොයින් ග්‍රෑම් 5යි මිලිග්‍රෑම් 300ක් සහ M67 වර්ගයේ ජීව අත්බෝම්බයක් පොලිස් විශේෂ කාර්ය බලකාය භාරයට ගෙන ඇත.",
        "අත්අඩංගුවට ගත් එක් අයෙක් කොළඹ 15 මාදම්පිටිය පාරේ පදිංචි 45 හැවිරිදි අංගමුත්තු රාජා නොහොත් “හයි කෝට් රාජා” නැමැත්තා වන අතර අනෙක් පුද්ගලයා නාගරාජා රොබින් නිකලස් නැමති 32 හැවිරිදි වියේ පසුවේ.",
        "අත්අඩංගුවට ගත් සැකකරුවන් වැඩිදුර විමර්ශන සඳහා වත්තල පොලිසියට භාරදී ඇත."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "එස්.ටී.එෆ්",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "දෙක",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "දෙක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "කිබුල අලේ ගුණා",
            "label": "WORK_OF_ART"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "STF බුද්ධි අංශය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "එස්.ටී.එෆ්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "6kg",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "440",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "කේරල",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "5",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "300mg",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "එක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "M67",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "එක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "45 හැවිරිදිය",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "කොළඹ මාදම්පිටිය පාර",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "අංගමුත්තු රාජා",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "නාගරාජා රොබින් නිකොලස්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "32",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "වත්තල පොලිසිය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "கிம்புலா எலே குணாவின் இரண்டு கூட்டாளிகளை STF கைது செய்துள்ளது.",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "ஒழுங்கமைக்கப்பட்ட கிரிமினல் கும்பல் தலைவன் “கிபுலா அலே குணா”வின் போதைப்பொருள் கும்பலைச் செயல்படுத்தி வந்த இருவரை பொலிஸ் விசேட அதிரடிப்படையினர் கைது செய்துள்ளனர்.",
        "பொலிஸ் விசேட அதிரடிப்படையின் புலனாய்வுப் பிரிவினருக்கு கிடைத்த தகவலின் அடிப்படையில் குறித்த சந்தேகநபர்கள் கைது செய்யப்பட்டுள்ளனர்.",
        "சந்தேகநபர்களிடம் இருந்து 6kg 440g கேரள கஞ்சா, 5g மற்றும் 300mg ஹெரோயின் மற்றும் வெளிநாட்டில் தயாரிக்கப்பட்ட M67 கைக்குண்டு ஒன்றையும் STF அதிகாரிகள் கைப்பற்றியுள்ளனர்.",
        "கைது செய்யப்பட்டவர்களில் ஒருவர் கொழும்பு 15, மாதம்பிட்டி வீதியில் வசிக்கும் 45 வயதான “ஹை கோட் ராஜா” என அழைக்கப்படும் அங்கமுத்து ராஜா எனவும் மற்றையவரின் பெயர் 32 வயதுடைய நாகராஜா ரொபின் நிக்கோலஸ் எனவும் தெரியவந்துள்ளது.",
        "கைது செய்யப்பட்ட சந்தேக நபர்கள் மேலதிக விசாரணைகளுக்காக வத்தளை பொலிஸாரிடம் ஒப்படைக்கப்பட்டனர்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "எஸ்.டி.எஃப்",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "இரண்டு",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "இரண்டு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "கிபுலா அலே குணா",
            "label": "WORK_OF_ART"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "STF புலனாய்வுப் பிரிவு",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "எஸ்.டி.எஃப்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "6 கிலோ",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "440",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "கேரளா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "5",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "300மி.கி",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஒன்று",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "M67",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஒன்று",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "45 வயது",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "கொழும்பு மாதம்பிட்டிய வீதி",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "அங்கமுத்து ராஜா",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "நாகராஜா ராபின் நிக்கோலஸ்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "32",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "வத்தளை பொலிஸ்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}