{
  "newspaper_id": "economy-next-com",
  "url": "https://economynext.com/sri-lanka-warned-of-floods-rough-seas-if-heavy-rains-continue-99471/",
  "time_ut": 1662375420,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Sri Lanka warned of floods, rough seas if heavy rains continue",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Sri Lanka warned of floods, rough seas if heavy rains continue",
      "author": "Neshella Perera",
      "body_lines": [
        "ECONOMYNEXT – Sri Lanka’s Irrigation Department has issued a flood warning to areas around the Attanagalu, Kalu, Kelani, Ging and Nilwala rivers as the river basins are already saturated with water posing a threat of floods if rain continues.",
        "The Department of Meteorology issued a red notice on the country’s prevailing weather situation on Monday September 05, valid for 24 hours.",
        "Very heavy showers above 150mm may occur in parts of the Western and Sabaragamuwa provinces and Kandy, Nuwara-Eliya, Galle and Matara districts, the notice said.",
        "Hanwella in the Colombo district has reported rainfall of 150.5mm, Waharaka in Kegalle district 133mm and Awissawella 114mm.",
        "A red notice was also issued warning of rough sea and strong winds gusting up to (60-70) kmph along the coast extending from Puttalam to Pottuvil via Colombo, Galle and Hambantota due to active Southwest Monsoon conditions.",
        "There is a possibility of an increase in swell waves (about 2.5 – 3.0 m high). It is advised not to venture out to sea for  fishing or naval activities in the aforementioned areas in the next 24 hours, the notice said.",
        "The general public has been advised to be vigilant with regard to weather conditions and take adequate precautions to minimise damages caused by lightning activity. The public is also advised to pay close attention to Met Department notices. (Colombo/Sep05/2022)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Sri Lanka",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka’s",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Irrigation Department",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Attanagalu",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kelani",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ging",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Nilwala",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "The Department of Meteorology",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Monday September 05",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "24 hours",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "150mm",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "Western",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sabaragamuwa",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kandy",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Galle",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Matara",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Hanwella",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Colombo",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "150.5mm",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "Waharaka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kegalle",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "133mm",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "Awissawella",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "114mm",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "60-70",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Puttalam",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Galle",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Hambantota",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Southwest Monsoon",
            "label": "LOC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "about 2.5",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "3.0",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "the next 24 hours",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Met Department",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "අධික වර්ෂාව දිගටම පැවතුනහොත් ගංවතුර, මුහුද රළු විය හැකි බවට ශ්‍රී ලංකාව අනතුරු ඇඟවීය",
      "author": "නෙෂෙල්ලා පෙරේරා",
      "body_lines": [
        "ECONOMYNEXT - ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ වාරිමාර්ග දෙපාර්තමේන්තුව අත්තනගලු, කළු, කැලණි, ගිං සහ නිල්වලා යන ගංගා ආශ්‍රිත ප්‍රදේශවලට ගංවතුර අනතුරු ඇඟවීමක් නිකුත් කර ඇති අතර, වර්ෂාව දිගටම පැවතුනහොත් ගංවතුර තර්ජනයක් විය හැකි පරිදි ගංගා ද්‍රෝණි දැනටමත් ජලයෙන් සංතෘප්ත වී ඇත.",
        "කාලගුණ විද්‍යා දෙපාර්තමේන්තුව සැප්තැම්බර් 05 වැනි සඳුදා පැය 24 සඳහා වලංගු වන පරිදි රටේ පවතින කාලගුණ තත්ත්වය පිළිබඳ රතු නිවේදනයක් නිකුත් කළේය.",
        "බස්නාහිර සහ සබරගමුව පළාත්වලත් මහනුවර, නුවරඑළිය, ගාල්ල සහ මාතර දිස්ත්‍රික්කවලත් ඇතැම් ස්ථානවලට මිලිමීටර් 150 ට වැඩි ඉතා තද වැසි ඇති විය හැකි බව එම නිවේදනයේ දැක්වේ.",
        "කොළඹ දිස්ත්‍රික්කයේ හංවැල්ලට මිලිමීටර් 150.5ක වර්ෂාපතනයක් ද, කෑගල්ල දිස්ත්‍රික්කයේ වහරකට මිලිමීටර් 133ක් සහ අවිස්සාවේල්ලෙන් මිලිමීටර් 114ක වර්ෂාපතනයක් ද වාර්තා වී තිබේ.",
        "සක්‍රීය නිරිතදිග මෝසම් තත්ත්වය හේතුවෙන් පුත්තලම සිට කොළඹ, ගාල්ල සහ හම්බන්තොට හරහා පොතුවිල් දක්වා වෙරළට ඔබ්බෙන් වන මුහුදු ප්‍රදේශවල පැයට කිලෝමීටර් (60-70) දක්වා තද සුළං ඇති විය හැකි බවට රතු නිවේදනයක් ද නිකුත් කර ඇත.",
        "ඉදිමුණු තරංග (මීටර් 2.5 - 3.0 පමණ උස) වැඩිවීමේ හැකියාවක් පවතී. ඉදිරි පැය 24 තුළ ඉහත ප්‍රදේශවල ධීවර හෝ නාවික කටයුතු සඳහා මුහුදට නොයන ලෙසට උපදෙස් දෙනු ලැබේ.",
        "කාලගුණික තත්ත්වයන් පිළිබඳව විමසිලිමත් වන ලෙසත් අකුණු මඟින් සිදුවන අනතුරු අවම කර ගැනීමට අවශ්‍ය පියවර ගන්නා ලෙසත් සාමාන්‍ය ජනතාවට දන්වා ඇත. කාලගුණ දෙපාර්තමේන්තු නිවේදන කෙරෙහි දැඩි අවධානයක් යොමු කරන ලෙස ද මහජනතාවට දැනුම් දෙනවා. (කොළඹ/සැප්.05/2022)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "වාරිමාර්ග දෙපාර්තමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "අත්තනගලු",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kelani",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ging",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "නිල්වලා",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "කාලගුණ විද්‍යා දෙපාර්තමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "සැප්තැම්බර් 05 සඳුදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "පැය 24",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "150 මි.මී",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "බටහිර",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "සබරගමුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "මහනුවර",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගාල්ල",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මාතර",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "හංවැල්ල",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "කොළඹ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "150.5 මි.මී",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "වහරක",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "කෑගල්ල",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "133 මි.මී",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "අවිස්සාවේල්ල",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "114 මි.මී",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "60-70",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "පුත්තලම",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගාල්ල",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "හම්බන්තොට",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "නිරිතදිග මෝසම්",
            "label": "LOC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "2.5 ක් පමණ",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "3.0",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඊළඟ පැය 24",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "කාලගුණ දෙපාර්තමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "தொடர்ந்து கனமழை பெய்தால் வெள்ளம், கடல் சீற்றம் ஏற்படும் என இலங்கை எச்சரிக்கை விடுத்துள்ளது",
      "author": "நெஷெல்லா பெரேரா",
      "body_lines": [
        "பொருளாதாரம் - இலங்கையின் நீர்ப்பாசனத் திணைக்களம் அத்தனகலு, களு, களனி, கிங் மற்றும் நில்வலா ஆகிய ஆறுகளை சுற்றியுள்ள பகுதிகளுக்கு வெள்ள அபாய எச்சரிக்கையை விடுத்துள்ளது, ஏனெனில் ஆற்றுப் படுகைகள் ஏற்கனவே நீரினால் நிரம்பியுள்ளன, மழை தொடர்ந்தால் வெள்ள அபாயத்தை ஏற்படுத்துகிறது.",
        "வளிமண்டலவியல் திணைக்களம் செப்டம்பர் 05 திங்கட்கிழமை 24 மணிநேரத்திற்கு செல்லுபடியாகும் நாட்டில் நிலவும் காலநிலை நிலைமை குறித்து சிவப்பு அறிவிப்பை வெளியிட்டது.",
        "மேல் மற்றும் சப்ரகமுவ மாகாணங்களிலும் கண்டி, நுவரெலியா, காலி மற்றும் மாத்தறை மாவட்டங்களிலும் 150 மில்லிமீற்றருக்கும் அதிகமான பலத்த மழை பெய்யக்கூடும் என அந்த அறிக்கையில் தெரிவிக்கப்பட்டுள்ளது.",
        "கொழும்பு மாவட்டத்தின் ஹன்வெல்லயில் 150.5 மில்லிமீற்றர் மழைவீழ்ச்சியும், கேகாலை மாவட்டத்தில் வஹரகாவில் 133 மில்லிமீற்றர் மழைவீழ்ச்சியும், அவிசாவளையில் 114 மில்லிமீற்றர் மழையும் பதிவாகியுள்ளது.",
        "சுறுசுறுப்பான தென்மேற்கு பருவக்காற்று நிலைமைகள் காரணமாக புத்தளத்திலிருந்து கொழும்பு, காலி மற்றும் ஹம்பாந்தோட்டை ஊடாக பொத்துவில் வரையான கடற்கரையோரங்களில் மணிக்கு (60-70) கிலோமீற்றர் வேகத்தில் பலத்த காற்று வீசுவதுடன் கடல் கொந்தளிப்பாகவும் வீசக்கூடும் எனவும் சிவப்பு அறிவித்தல் விடுக்கப்பட்டுள்ளது.",
        "வீக்க அலைகள் (சுமார் 2.5 - 3.0 மீ உயரம்) அதிகரிக்கும் வாய்ப்பு உள்ளது. அடுத்த 24 மணி நேரத்தில் மேற்கூறிய பகுதிகளில் மீன்பிடி அல்லது கடற்படை நடவடிக்கைகளுக்காக கடலுக்குச் செல்ல வேண்டாம் என அறிவுறுத்தப்பட்டுள்ளது.",
        "பொதுமக்கள் காலநிலை தொடர்பில் அவதானமாக இருக்குமாறும் மின்னல் தாக்கங்களினால் ஏற்படக்கூடிய பாதிப்புகளை குறைத்துக்கொள்ள போதிய முன்னெச்சரிக்கை நடவடிக்கைகளை எடுக்குமாறும் அறிவுறுத்தப்பட்டுள்ளனர். மேலும் வானிலை ஆய்வு மைய அறிவிப்புகளை பொதுமக்கள் உன்னிப்பாக கவனிக்க வேண்டும் என அறிவுறுத்தப்பட்டுள்ளது. (கொழும்பு/செப்05/2022)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "இலங்கை",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கையின்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "நீர்ப்பாசன திணைக்களம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "அத்தனகலு",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kelani",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜிங்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "நில்வாலா",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "வளிமண்டலவியல் திணைக்களம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "செப்டம்பர் 05 திங்கட்கிழமை",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "24 மணி நேரம்",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "150மிமீ",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "மேற்கு",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "சப்ரகமுவ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "கண்டி",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "காலி",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "மாத்தறை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஹன்வெல்ல",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "கொழும்பு",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "150.5மிமீ",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "வஹரக",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "கேகாலை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "133மிமீ",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "அவிசாவளை",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "114மிமீ",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "60-70",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "புத்தளம்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "காலி",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஹம்பாந்தோட்டை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "தென்மேற்கு பருவக்காற்று",
            "label": "LOC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "சுமார் 2.5",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "3.0",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "அடுத்த 24 மணி நேரம்",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "வானிலை துறை",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}