{
  "newspaper_id": "lankadeepa-lk",
  "url": "https://www.lankadeepa.lk/news/ධානිශ්-අලී-රිමාන්ඩ්/101-617162",
  "time_ut": 1658973424,
  "original_lang": "si",
  "original_title": "ධානිශ් අලී රිමාන්ඩ්",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Dhanish Ali remanded",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "Colombo Fort Magistrate Thilina Gamage ordered today (27) to remand Dhanish Ali, who was arrested by the Criminal Investigation Department in relation to a warrant issued by the Fort Court while he was on a flight preparing to go abroad.",
        "31-year-old Dhanish Ali, a resident of Kurunegala Webada area, was remanded.",
        "The Magistrate also ordered the prison to present the suspect under cover to the Colombo Chief Magistrate's Court on the 1st for an identification parade in a case related to a complaint filed by the Kurunduwatta Police regarding the alleged entry into the television corporation by force."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Dhanish Ali",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "27",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Dhanish Ali",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Criminal Investigation Department",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Fort Court",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "31-year-old",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Dhanish Ali",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kurunegala",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Magistrate",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Magistrate",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the 1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "ධානිශ් අලී රිමාන්ඩ්",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "විදෙස් ගත වීමට සූදානමින් ගුවන්යානයක රැඳී සිටියදී කොටුව අධිකරණය නිකුත් කළ වරෙන්තුවකට අදාළව අපරාධ පරීක්ෂණ දෙපාර්තමේන්තුව අත්අඩංගුවට ධානිශ් අලී නැමැත්තා ලබන 05 වැනිදා තෙක් රක්ෂිත බන්ධනාගාර ගත කිරීමට කොළඹ කොටුව මහේස්ත්‍රාත් තිළිණ ගමගේ මහතා අද (27) නියෝග කළේය .",
        "මෙලෙස රක්ෂිත බන්ධනාගාර ගත කරනු ලැබුවේ කුරුණෑගල වෑබඩ ප්‍රදේශයේ පදිංචි 31 හැවිරිදි ධානිශ් අලී නැමැත්තාය.",
        "රූපවාහිනී සංස්ථාවට අයුතු ලෙස ඇතුළු වී බලහත්කාරයෙන් කටයුතු කලැයි කියන සිද්ධියට අදාළව කුරුඳුවත්ත පොලිසිය මගින් කළ පැමිණිල්ලක් සම්බන්ධයෙන් වන නඩුවක හදුනාගැනීමේ පෙරට්ටුවක් සඳහා කොළඹ ප්‍රධාන මහේස්ත්‍රාත් අධිකරණයට ලබන 01 වැනිදා ආවරණය සහිතව මෙම සැකකරු ඉදිරිපත් කරන ලෙසට ද මහෙස්ත්‍රාත්වරයා බන්ධනාගාරයට නියෝග කළේය."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ධනිෂ් අලි",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "27",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ධනිෂ් අලි",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "අපරාධ පරීක්ෂණ දෙපාර්තමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "කොටුව උසාවිය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "31 හැවිරිදිය",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ධනිෂ් අලි",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "කුරුණෑගල",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "මහේස්ත්රාත්වරයා",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "මහේස්ත්රාත්වරයා",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "1 වන",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "தனிஷ் அலி ரிமாண்ட் செய்யப்பட்டார்",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "வெளிநாடு செல்வதற்காக விமானத்தில் பயணித்த போது, ​​கோட்டை நீதிமன்றத்தினால் பிறப்பிக்கப்பட்ட பிடியாணைக்கு அமைய குற்றப் புலனாய்வுப் பிரிவினரால் கைது செய்யப்பட்ட தனிஷ் அலியை விளக்கமறியலில் வைக்குமாறு கொழும்பு கோட்டை நீதவான் திலின கமகே இன்று (27) உத்தரவிட்டுள்ளார்.",
        "குருநாகல் வெபட பிரதேசத்தைச் சேர்ந்த 31 வயதான தனிஷ் அலி என்பவரே இவ்வாறு விளக்கமறியலில் வைக்கப்பட்டுள்ளார்.",
        "தொலைக்காட்சி கூட்டுத்தாபனத்திற்குள் பலவந்தமாக பிரவேசித்தமை தொடர்பில் குருந்துவத்தை பொலிஸாரால் தாக்கல் செய்யப்பட்ட முறைப்பாடு தொடர்பான வழக்கின் அடையாள அணிவகுப்பிற்காக சந்தேக நபரை எதிர்வரும் முதலாம் திகதி கொழும்பு பிரதான நீதவான் நீதிமன்றில் முன்னிலைப்படுத்துமாறு நீதவான் சிறைச்சாலைக்கு உத்தரவிட்டுள்ளார்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "தனிஷ் அலி",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "27",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "தனிஷ் அலி",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "குற்றப் புலனாய்வுத் துறை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "கோட்டை நீதிமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "31 வயது",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "தனிஷ் அலி",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "குருநாகல்",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "மாஜிஸ்திரேட்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "மாஜிஸ்திரேட்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "1வது",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}