{
  "newspaper_id": "island-lk",
  "url": "http://island.lk/huawei-signs-mou-with-university-of-sri-jayewardenepura-to-strengthen-digital-talent-building-and-setup-joint-innovation-lab/",
  "time_ut": 1661713080,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Huawei signs MoU with University of Sri Jayewardenepura to strengthen digital talent building and setup Joint Innovation Lab",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Huawei signs MoU with University of Sri Jayewardenepura to strengthen digital talent building and setup Joint Innovation Lab",
      "author": "Thilina Walpola",
      "body_lines": [
        "Huawei, a leading global provider of information and communications technology (ICT) infrastructure and smart devices, recently announced the signing of a Memorandum of Understanding (MoU) with the University of Sri Jayewardenepura to build, and nurture local ICT talents through several training programs including certifications, internships, field trainings, and establishing the Huawei ICT Academy and Joint Innovation Lab at the university premises. The agreement will contribute towards building a talent ecosystem and boosting the development of the ICT industry in Sri Lanka.",
        "The proposed joint innovation lab with the University of Sri Jayewardenepura will further facilitate undergraduate and graduate research, and provide a platform to develop solutions and products for industrial needs and to organize certification courses on advanced ICT technologies.",
        "Senior Prof. Sudantha Liyanage, Vice Chancellor of University of Sri Jayewardenepura said, “As one of the largest and most diverse Universities in Sri Lanka, University of Sri Jayewardenepura is an ideal institution to collaborate with Huawei to empower the Sri Lankan youth and talent with the latest ICT industry skills and knowledge. Such ICT skills will prepare them for the future where digitization and digital transformation will play an increasingly crucial role. As we collaborate with a world leading technology company such as Huawei, we will be able to provide Sri Lankan University students with the necessary exposure to the best technology practices and global experiences in line with the fast-changing technologies.”",
        "Tao Guangyao, CEO of Huawei Sri Lanka said, “We are glad and delighted to be collaborating with a prestigious national university of Sri Lanka, the University of Sri Jayewardenepura, as part of our ongoing efforts to empower local ICT talent and support Sri Lanka in its economic transformation efforts, including developing world-class talent for key industries and digital transformation. Through this partnership, we will provide world-class capabilities and advanced technologies to enable future generations to lead the digital transformation journey and advance the economic growth in Sri Lanka.”",
        "S-lon relocates its Jaffna re-distribution centre to provide better service",
        "Princess Diana’s 1985 Ford Escort tops $850,000 at auction sale",
        "Leave a Reply Cancel replyYour email address will not be published. Required fields are marked *Comment Name *",
        "Save my name, email, and website in this browser for the next time I comment."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Huawei",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "University of Sri Jayewardenepura",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "Joint Innovation Lab",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Huawei",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ICT",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the University of Sri Jayewardenepura",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ICT",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Huawei ICT Academy",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ICT",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the University of Sri Jayewardenepura",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ICT",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sudantha Liyanage",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "University of Sri Jayewardenepura",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "one",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "University of Sri Jayewardenepura",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Huawei",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ICT",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ICT",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Huawei",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lankan University",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Tao Guangyao",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Huawei Sri Lanka",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "national university of Sri Lanka",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the University of Sri Jayewardenepura",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ICT",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Jaffna",
            "label": "PRODUCT"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Diana",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "1985",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ford",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Escort",
            "label": "PRODUCT"
          },
          {
            "text": "850,000",
            "label": "MONEY"
          }
        ],
        [],
        []
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "ඩිජිටල් කුසලතා ගොඩනැගීම සහ ඒකාබද්ධ නවෝත්පාදන විද්‍යාගාරය පිහිටුවීම සඳහා Huawei ශ්‍රී ජයවර්ධනපුර විශ්වවිද්‍යාලය සමඟ අවබෝධතා ගිවිසුමක් අත්සන් කරයි",
      "author": "තිළිණ වල්පොල",
      "body_lines": [
        "තොරතුරු සහ සන්නිවේදන තාක්ෂණ (ICT) යටිතල පහසුකම් සහ ස්මාර්ට් උපාංග සපයන ප්‍රමුඛ පෙළේ ගෝලීය සැපයුම්කරුවෙකු වන Huawei, පුහුණු වැඩසටහන් කිහිපයක් හරහා දේශීය තොරතුරු හා සන්නිවේදන තාක්ෂණ කුසලතා ගොඩනැගීමට සහ පෝෂණය කිරීමට ශ්‍රී ජයවර්ධනපුර විශ්ව විද්‍යාලය සමඟ අවබෝධතා ගිවිසුමක් (MoU) අත්සන් කරන බව මෑතකදී නිවේදනය කළේය. සහතික කිරීම්, සීමාවාසික පුහුණුව, ක්ෂේත්‍ර පුහුණු කිරීම් සහ විශ්වවිද්‍යාල පරිශ්‍රයේ Huawei ICT ඇකඩමිය සහ ඒකාබද්ධ නවෝත්පාදන විද්‍යාගාරය පිහිටුවීම. මෙම ගිවිසුම මගින් කුසලතා පරිසර පද්ධතියක් ගොඩනැගීමට සහ ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ තොරතුරු හා සන්නිවේදන තාක්ෂණ කර්මාන්තයේ දියුණුව සඳහා දායක වනු ඇත.",
        "ශ්‍රී ජයවර්ධනපුර විශ්වවිද්‍යාලය සමඟ යෝජිත ඒකාබද්ධ නවෝත්පාදන විද්‍යාගාරය උපාධි හා උපාධි පර්යේෂණ සඳහා තවදුරටත් පහසුකම් සපයන අතර කාර්මික අවශ්‍යතා සඳහා විසඳුම් සහ නිෂ්පාදන සංවර්ධනය කිරීමට සහ උසස් තොරතුරු හා සන්නිවේදන තාක්ෂණ තාක්ෂණ පිළිබඳ සහතික කිරීමේ පාඨමාලා සංවිධානය කිරීමට වේදිකාවක් සපයයි.",
        "ශ්‍රී ජයවර්ධනපුර විශ්වවිද්‍යාලයේ උපකුලපති ජ්‍යෙෂ්ඨ මහාචාර්ය සුදන්ත ලියනගේ මහතා පැවසුවේ, “ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ විශාලතම හා විවිධත්වයෙන් යුත් විශ්වවිද්‍යාලවලින් එකක් ලෙස ශ්‍රී ජයවර්ධනපුර විශ්වවිද්‍යාලය Huawei සමඟ එක්ව ශ්‍රී ලාංකීය තරුණයන් සහ දක්ෂතා සවිබල ගැන්වීම සඳහා කදිම ආයතනයකි. නවතම ICT කර්මාන්ත කුසලතා සහ දැනුම. ඩිජිටල්කරණය සහ ඩිජිටල් පරිවර්තනය වැඩි වැඩියෙන් තීරණාත්මක කාර්යභාරයක් ඉටු කරන අනාගතය සඳහා එවැනි තොරතුරු සන්නිවේදන තාක්ෂණ කුසලතා ඔවුන් සූදානම් කරනු ඇත. අපි Huawei වැනි ලොව ප්‍රමුඛ පෙළේ තාක්‍ෂණ සමාගමක් සමඟ සහයෝගයෙන් කටයුතු කරන බැවින්, වේගයෙන් වෙනස් වන තාක්‍ෂණයන්ට අනුකූලව ශ්‍රී ලාංකේය විශ්වවිද්‍යාල සිසුන්ට හොඳම තාක්‍ෂණ භාවිතයන් සහ ගෝලීය අත්දැකීම් සඳහා අවශ්‍ය නිරාවරණය ලබා දීමට අපට හැකි වනු ඇත.",
        "Huawei Sri Lanka හි ප්‍රධාන විධායක නිලධාරී Tao Guangyao මහතා පැවසුවේ, “දේශීය තොරතුරු හා සන්නිවේදන තාක්‍ෂණ කුසලතා සවිබල ගැන්වීමට සහ ශ්‍රී ලංකාවට සහය දැක්වීමේ අපගේ අඛණ්ඩ උත්සාහයේ කොටසක් ලෙස ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ කීර්තිමත් ජාතික විශ්ව විද්‍යාලයක් වන ශ්‍රී ජයවර්ධනපුර විශ්ව විද්‍යාලය සමඟ සහයෝගයෙන් කටයුතු කිරීමට ලැබීම පිළිබඳව අපි සතුටට හා සතුටට පත්වෙනවා. එහි ආර්ථික පරිවර්තන ප්‍රයත්න, ප්‍රධාන කර්මාන්ත සඳහා ලෝක මට්ටමේ දක්ෂතා වර්ධනය කිරීම සහ ඩිජිටල් පරිවර්තනය ඇතුළුව. මෙම හවුල්කාරිත්වය තුළින් අනාගත පරම්පරාවන්ට ඩිජිටල් පරිවර්තන ගමනට නායකත්වය දීමට සහ ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ ආර්ථික වර්ධනය ඉදිරියට ගෙන යාමට හැකි වන පරිදි අපි ලෝක මට්ටමේ හැකියාවන් සහ උසස් තාක්ෂණයන් ලබා දෙන්නෙමු.",
        "S-lon වඩා හොඳ සේවාවක් සැපයීම සඳහා යාපනය නැවත බෙදාහැරීමේ මධ්‍යස්ථානය වෙනත් ස්ථානයකට ගෙන යයි",
        "ඩයනා කුමරියගේ 1985 Ford Escort වෙන්දේසියේ දී ඩොලර් 850,000 ඉහළට",
        "පිළිතුරක් දෙන්න පිළිතුර අවලංගු කරන්න ඔබගේ විද්‍යුත් තැපැල් ලිපිනය ප්‍රකාශයට පත් නොකෙරේ. අවශ්‍ය ක්ෂේත්‍ර සලකුණු කර ඇත *අදහස් නම *",
        "මම ඊළඟ වතාවේ අදහස් දැක්වීම සඳහා මගේ නම, විද්‍යුත් තැපෑල සහ වෙබ් අඩවිය මෙම බ්‍රවුසරයේ සුරකින්න."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Huawei",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "ශ්‍රී ජයවර්ධනපුර විශ්වවිද්‍යාලය",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "ඒකාබද්ධ නවෝත්පාදන විද්යාගාරය",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Huawei",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "සන්නිවේදන තාක්ෂණ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ජයවර්ධනපුර විශ්වවිද්‍යාලය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "සන්නිවේදන තාක්ෂණ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Huawei ICT ඇකඩමිය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "සන්නිවේදන තාක්ෂණ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ජයවර්ධනපුර විශ්වවිද්‍යාලය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "සන්නිවේදන තාක්ෂණ",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "සුදන්ත ලියනගේ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ජයවර්ධනපුර විශ්වවිද්‍යාලය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "එක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ජයවර්ධනපුර විශ්වවිද්‍යාලය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Huawei",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "සන්නිවේදන තාක්ෂණ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "සන්නිවේදන තාක්ෂණ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Huawei",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකා විශ්වවිද්‍යාලය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Tao Guangyao",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Huawei Sri Lanka",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ ජාතික විශ්ව විද්‍යාලය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ජයවර්ධනපුර විශ්වවිද්‍යාලය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "සන්නිවේදන තාක්ෂණ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "යාපනය",
            "label": "PRODUCT"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ඩයනා",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "1985",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ෆෝඩ්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "පරිවාර",
            "label": "PRODUCT"
          },
          {
            "text": "850,000 කි",
            "label": "MONEY"
          }
        ],
        [],
        []
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "டிஜிட்டல் திறமைகளை வலுப்படுத்தவும், கூட்டு கண்டுபிடிப்பு ஆய்வகத்தை அமைக்கவும் ஸ்ரீ ஜெயவர்தனபுர பல்கலைக்கழகத்துடன் Huawei புரிந்துணர்வு ஒப்பந்தத்தில் கையெழுத்திட்டுள்ளது.",
      "author": "திலின வல்பொல",
      "body_lines": [
        "தகவல் மற்றும் தொடர்பாடல் தொழிநுட்பம் (ICT) உள்கட்டமைப்பு மற்றும் ஸ்மார்ட் சாதனங்களை வழங்கும் முன்னணி உலகளாவிய வழங்குநரான Huawei, ஸ்ரீ ஜயவர்தனபுர பல்கலைக்கழகத்துடன் பல பயிற்சித் திட்டங்கள் மூலம் உள்ளூர் ICT திறமைகளை கட்டியெழுப்புவதற்கும் வளர்ப்பதற்கும் புரிந்துணர்வு ஒப்பந்தம் (MoU) ஒன்றை அண்மையில் கைச்சாத்திடுவதாக அறிவித்தது. சான்றிதழ்கள், பயிற்சிகள், களப் பயிற்சிகள் மற்றும் பல்கலைக்கழக வளாகத்தில் Huawei ICT அகாடமி மற்றும் கூட்டு கண்டுபிடிப்பு ஆய்வகத்தை நிறுவுதல். இந்த ஒப்பந்தம் திறமையான சுற்றுச்சூழல் அமைப்பை உருவாக்குவதற்கும், இலங்கையில் ICT துறையின் வளர்ச்சியை மேம்படுத்துவதற்கும் பங்களிக்கும்.",
        "ஸ்ரீ ஜயவர்தனபுர பல்கலைக்கழகத்துடன் முன்மொழியப்பட்ட கூட்டு கண்டுபிடிப்பு ஆய்வகம் இளங்கலை மற்றும் பட்டதாரி ஆராய்ச்சியை மேலும் எளிதாக்கும், மேலும் தொழில்துறை தேவைகளுக்கான தீர்வுகள் மற்றும் தயாரிப்புகளை உருவாக்குவதற்கும் மேம்பட்ட ICT தொழில்நுட்பங்கள் குறித்த சான்றிதழ் படிப்புகளை ஒழுங்கமைப்பதற்கும் ஒரு தளத்தை வழங்கும்.",
        "ஸ்ரீ ஜயவர்தனபுர பல்கலைக்கழகத்தின் துணைவேந்தரான சிரேஷ்ட பேராசிரியர் சுதந்த லியனகே, “இலங்கையில் உள்ள மிகப் பெரிய மற்றும் பன்முகத்தன்மை வாய்ந்த பல்கலைக்கழகங்களில் ஒன்றாக, ஸ்ரீ ஜயவர்தனபுர பல்கலைக்கழகம் இலங்கை இளைஞர்கள் மற்றும் திறமைகளை வலுப்படுத்த Huawei உடன் இணைந்து பணியாற்றுவதற்கான சிறந்த நிறுவனமாகும். சமீபத்திய ICT தொழில் திறன்கள் மற்றும் அறிவு. இத்தகைய ICT திறன்கள், டிஜிட்டல் மயமாக்கல் மற்றும் டிஜிட்டல் மாற்றம் பெருகிய முறையில் முக்கிய பங்கு வகிக்கும் எதிர்காலத்திற்கு அவர்களை தயார்படுத்தும். Huawei போன்ற உலகின் முன்னணி தொழில்நுட்ப நிறுவனத்துடன் நாம் ஒத்துழைப்பதன் மூலம், இலங்கைப் பல்கலைக்கழக மாணவர்களுக்குத் தேவையான சிறந்த தொழில்நுட்ப நடைமுறைகள் மற்றும் உலகளாவிய அனுபவங்களை வேகமாக மாறிவரும் தொழில்நுட்பங்களுக்கு ஏற்ப வெளிப்படுத்துவதை எங்களால் வழங்க முடியும்.",
        "Huawei Sri Lanka இன் பிரதம நிறைவேற்று அதிகாரி Tao Guangyao கூறுகையில், “உள்ளூர் ICT திறமைகளை வலுப்படுத்துவதற்கும் இலங்கைக்கு ஆதரவளிப்பதற்கும் எமது தொடர்ச்சியான முயற்சிகளின் ஒரு பகுதியாக இலங்கையின் புகழ்பெற்ற தேசிய பல்கலைக்கழகமான ஸ்ரீ ஜயவர்தனபுர பல்கலைக்கழகத்துடன் இணைந்து பணியாற்றுவதில் நாங்கள் மகிழ்ச்சியும் மகிழ்ச்சியும் அடைகிறோம். அதன் பொருளாதார மாற்ற முயற்சிகள், முக்கிய தொழில்கள் மற்றும் டிஜிட்டல் மாற்றத்திற்கான உலகத் தரத்திலான திறமைகளை வளர்ப்பது உட்பட. இந்த பங்காளித்துவத்தின் மூலம், எதிர்கால சந்ததியினருக்கு டிஜிட்டல் உருமாற்ற பயணத்தை முன்னெடுப்பதற்கும் இலங்கையின் பொருளாதார வளர்ச்சியை முன்னேற்றுவதற்கும் உலகத்தரம் வாய்ந்த திறன்களையும் மேம்பட்ட தொழில்நுட்பங்களையும் வழங்குவோம்.",
        "S-lon சிறந்த சேவையை வழங்குவதற்காக அதன் யாழ்ப்பாண மறு விநியோக மையத்தை இடமாற்றம் செய்கிறது",
        "இளவரசி டயானாவின் 1985 ஃபோர்டு எஸ்கார்ட் ஏல விற்பனையில் $850,000 முதலிடம் பிடித்தது",
        "ஒரு பதிலை விடுங்கள் பதிலை ரத்துசெய் உங்கள் மின்னஞ்சல் முகவரி வெளியிடப்படாது. தேவையான புலங்கள் குறிக்கப்பட்டுள்ளன *கருத்து பெயர் *",
        "அடுத்த முறை நான் கருத்து தெரிவிக்க, எனது பெயர், மின்னஞ்சல் மற்றும் இணையதளத்தை இந்த உலாவியில் சேமிக்கவும்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ஹூவாய்",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "ஸ்ரீ ஜயவர்தனபுர பல்கலைக்கழகம்",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "கூட்டு கண்டுபிடிப்பு ஆய்வகம்",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ஹூவாய்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஐ.சி.டி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஸ்ரீ ஜயவர்தனபுர பல்கலைக்கழகம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஐ.சி.டி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Huawei ICT அகாடமி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஐ.சி.டி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஸ்ரீ ஜயவர்தனபுர பல்கலைக்கழகம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஐ.சி.டி",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "சுதந்த லியனகே",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஸ்ரீ ஜயவர்தனபுர பல்கலைக்கழகம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஒன்று",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஸ்ரீ ஜயவர்தனபுர பல்கலைக்கழகம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஹூவாய்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஐ.சி.டி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஐ.சி.டி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஹூவாய்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கைப் பல்கலைக்கழகம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Tao Guangyao",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Huawei Sri Lanka",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை தேசிய பல்கலைக்கழகம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஸ்ரீ ஜயவர்தனபுர பல்கலைக்கழகம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஐ.சி.டி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "யாழ்",
            "label": "PRODUCT"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "டயானா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "1985",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஃபோர்டு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "எஸ்கார்ட்",
            "label": "PRODUCT"
          },
          {
            "text": "850,000",
            "label": "MONEY"
          }
        ],
        [],
        []
      ]
    }
  }
}