{
  "newspaper_id": "lankadeepa-lk",
  "url": "https://www.lankadeepa.lk/latest_news/නාමල්ගේ-යෝජනාවට-හවුල්-පක්ෂ-පයින්-ගසයි/1-615765",
  "time_ut": 1656820578,
  "original_lang": "si",
  "original_title": "නාමල්ගේ යෝජනාවට හවුල් පක්ෂ පයින් ගසයි",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "The coalition parties kick Namal's proposal",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "It is reported that the group of nine joint parties has rejected a proposal made by Sri Lanka Podujana Peramuna Member of Parliament Mr. Namal Rajapaksa that the government should be changed and a new government should be formed together.",
        "MP Namal Rajapakse informed this proposal in a separate meeting with MP Vasudeva Nanayakkara yesterday, and Mr. Vasudeva Nanayakkara is reported to have announced Namala's proposal to the party leaders during the discussion of the leaders of the nine joint parties held at the Communist Party headquarters last Tuesday.",
        "Political sources say that the proposal was strongly rejected by all the party leaders.",
        "The leaders of the joint parties have commented on this matter and stated that since the Rajapaksas are responsible for this crisis, they are no longer able to govern with them.",
        "Therefore, political sources state that the leaders of the joint parties have decided not to hold any discussion with the MP Namal Rajapaksa in this regard."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Namal",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "nine",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Podujana Peramuna",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Namal Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Namal Rajapakse",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Vasudeva Nanayakkara",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "yesterday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Vasudeva Nanayakkara",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Namala",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "nine",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Communist Party",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "last Tuesday",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "Rajapaksas",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Namal Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "නාමල්ගේ යෝජනාවට හවුල් පක්ෂ පයින් ගසයි",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "ආණ්ඩුව වෙනස් කර, සියලු දෙනා එක්ව නව ආණ්ඩුවක් පිහිටුවිය යුතු බවට ශ්‍රී ලංකා පොදුජන පෙරමුණේ පාර්ලිමේන්තු මන්ත්‍රී නාමල් රාජපක්ෂ මහතා විසින් කරන ලදැයි කියන යෝජනාවක් හවුල් පක්ෂ නවයේ කණ්ඩායම ප්‍රතික්ෂේප කර ඇතැයි වාර්තා වේ.",
        "නාමල් රාජපක්ෂ මන්ත්‍රීවරයා මෙම යෝජනාව වාසුදේව නානයක්කාර මන්ත්‍රීවරයා ඉකුත්දා වෙනම හමුවී දැනුම් දී ඇති අතර, වාසුදේව නානායක්කාර මහතා ඉකුත් අඟහරුවාදා කොමියුනිස්ට් පක්ෂ මූලස්ථානයේ පැවැති හවුල් පක්ෂ නවයේ නායකයන්ගේ සාකච්ඡාවේදී නාමලගේ යෝජනාව පක්ෂ නායකයන් හමුවේ ප්‍රකාශ කර ඇතැයි වාර්තා වේ.",
        "එහිදී පක්ෂ නායකයින් සියලු දෙනා විසින් එම යෝජනාව දැඩිව ප්‍රතික්ෂේප කරනු ලැබූ බවද දේශපාලන ආරංචි මාර්ග සඳහන් කරයි.",
        "එහිදී හවුල් පක්ෂවල නායකයන් මේ සම්බන්ධයෙන් අදහස් දක්වමින් ප්‍රකාශ කර ඇත්තේ,මෙම අර්බුදයට රාජපක්ෂලා වගකිවයුතු බැවින් ,ඔවුන් සමග තවදුරටත් ආණ්ඩු කිරීමේ හැකියාවක් නොමැති බවය.",
        "එබැවින් නාමල් රාජපක්ෂ මන්ත්‍රීවරයා සමඟ මේ සම්බන්ධයෙන් කිසිදු සාකච්ඡාවක් නොකිරීමට ද හවුල් පක්ෂවල නායකයන් තීරණය කර ඇතැයි දේශපාලන ආරංචි මාර්ග සඳහන් කරයි."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "නාමල්",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "නවය",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "පොදුජන පෙරමුණ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "නාමල් රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "නාමල් රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "වාසුදේව නානායක්කාර",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඊයේ",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "වාසුදේව නානායක්කාර",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "නාමල",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "නවය",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "කොමියුනිස්ට් පක්ෂය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගිය අඟහරුවාදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "රාජපක්ෂලා",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "නාමල් රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "நாமலின் பிரேரணையை கூட்டமைப்பு கட்சிகள் உதைத்தன",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "அரசாங்கத்தை மாற்றி புதிய அரசாங்கத்தை உருவாக்க வேண்டும் என ஸ்ரீலங்கா பொதுஜன பெரமுனவின் நாடாளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர் திரு நாமல் ராஜபக்ஷ முன்வைத்த யோசனையை ஒன்பது கூட்டுக் கட்சிகள் நிராகரித்துள்ளதாக தெரிவிக்கப்படுகிறது.",
        "பாராளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர் நாமல் ராஜபக்ஷ நேற்று பாராளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர் வாசுதேவ நாணயக்காரவுடன் நடத்திய தனியான சந்திப்பில் இந்த பிரேரணையை தெரிவித்ததுடன், கடந்த கம்யூனிஸ்ட் கட்சியின் தலைமையகத்தில் நடைபெற்ற ஒன்பது கூட்டு கட்சிகளின் தலைவர்களின் கலந்துரையாடலின் போதே திரு வாசுதேவ நாணயக்கார கட்சித் தலைவர்களுக்கு நாமலாவின் யோசனையை அறிவித்ததாகத் தெரிவிக்கப்படுகிறது. செவ்வாய்.",
        "இந்த பிரேரணையை அனைத்து கட்சி தலைவர்களும் கடுமையாக நிராகரித்துள்ளதாக அரசியல் வட்டாரங்கள் தெரிவிக்கின்றன.",
        "இது தொடர்பில் கருத்துத் தெரிவித்த கூட்டுக் கட்சிகளின் தலைவர்கள், இந்த நெருக்கடிக்கு ராஜபக்சக்களே காரணம் என்பதால், அவர்களுடன் இணைந்து ஆட்சியமைக்க முடியாது எனத் தெரிவித்துள்ளனர்.",
        "எனவே, இது தொடர்பில் பாராளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர் நாமல் ராஜபக்ஷவுடன் எவ்வித கலந்துரையாடலும் நடத்துவதில்லை என கூட்டுக் கட்சிகளின் தலைவர்கள் தீர்மானித்துள்ளதாக அரசியல் வட்டாரங்கள் தெரிவிக்கின்றன."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "நாமல்",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ஒன்பது",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "பொதுஜன பெரமுன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "நாமல் ராஜபக்ச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "நாமல் ராஜபக்ஷ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "வாசுதேவ நாணயக்கார",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "நேற்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "வாசுதேவ நாணயக்கார",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "நமல",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஒன்பது",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "பொதுவுடைமைக்கட்சி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "கடந்த செவ்வாய்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "ராஜபக்சேக்கள்",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "நாமல் ராஜபக்ச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}