{
  "newspaper_id": "ada-lk",
  "url": "https://www.ada.lk/business/Asia-Pacific-Seeds-for-the-Future-2022-දියත්-වේ/7-396753",
  "time_ut": 1661882146,
  "original_lang": "si",
  "original_title": "Asia Pacific Seeds for the Future 2022 දියත් වේ",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Asia Pacific Seeds for the Future will launch in 2022",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "There has been a hole recently to mark the start of the Seeds for the Future 2022 program representing the Asia Pacific region, which is implemented in cooperation with the Ministry of Education.",
        "The official launch ceremony was held recently at the Ministry of Education office, and the Minister of Education Dr. Susil Premajayantha, the representative of UNESCO Sri Lanka Office, Himali Jinadasa, the CEO of Huawei Sri Lanka, Mr. Tao Guangyo, its representatives and students have participated.",
        "Through the Huawei Asia-Pacific Seeds for the Future 2022 program, a group of exceptionally talented university students were given the opportunity to participate in an IT training in Thailand.",
        "Seeds for the Future, a global program aimed at developing ICT skills. Through this, various opportunities will be provided to the students to share their technical knowledge as well as develop their technical skills. The initiative also encourages the building of regional collaborations and communication between countries and cultures."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Asia Pacific Seeds",
          "label": "LOC"
        },
        {
          "text": "Future",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "2022",
          "label": "DATE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "2022",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Asia Pacific",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Ministry of Education",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the Ministry of Education",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Susil Premajayantha",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "UNESCO Sri Lanka Office",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Himali Jinadasa",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Huawei Sri Lanka",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "Tao Guangyo",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the Huawei Asia-Pacific Seeds",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "2022",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Thailand",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Future",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ICT",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "Asia Pacific Seeds for the Future 2022 දියත් වේ",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "අධ්‍යාපන අමාත්‍යංශය සහයෝගයෙන් ක්‍රියාත්මක කරන ආසියානු පැසිෆික් කලාපය නියෝජනය කරන Seeds for the Future 2022 වැඩසටහනේ ආරම්භය සනිටුවහන් කිරීම පසුගියදා සිදුරක තිබේ.",
        "මෙහි නිල දියත් කිරීමේ උත්සව පසුගියදා අධ්‍යාපන අමාත්‍යංශ කාර්යාලයේදී පැවැත්වුණු අතර, මේ සඳහා අධ්‍යාපන අමාත්‍ය ආචාර්ය සුසිල් ප්‍රේමජයන්ත මහතා, යුනෙස්කෝ ශ්‍රී ලංකා කාර්යාලයේ මෙරට නියෝජිත හිමාලි ජිනදාස මහමත්මිය, Huawei ශ්‍රී ලංකා ප්‍රධාන විධායක නිලධාරී ටාඕ ගුවන්ග්යෝ මහතා, එහි නියෝජිතයින් සහ ශිෂ්‍ය ශිෂ්‍යාවන් සහභාගී වී ඇත.",
        "Huawei Asia-Pacific Seeds for the Future 2022 වැඩසටහන හරහා සුවිශේෂී දක්ෂතා දක්වන විශ්ව විද්‍යාල සිසුන් කණ්ඩායමක් සඳහා තායිලන්තයේ පැවැත්වෙන තොරතුරු තාක්ෂණ පුහුණුවක් සඳහා සහභාගී වීමට අවස්ථාව හිමිවූ බවද දැනුම් දෙයි.",
        "Seeds for the Future, තොරතුරු හා සන්නිවේදන තාක්ෂණ කුසලතා වර්ධනය කිරීම අරමුණු කරගත් ගෝලීය වැඩසටහනකි.  මේ හරහා සිසුන්ට සිය තාක්ෂණික දැනුම හුවමාරු කර ගැනීමට මෙන්ම ඔවුන්ගේ තාක්ෂණික කුසලතා සංවර්ධනය කර ගැනීමට විවිධ අවස්ථා රැසක් සපයනු ඇත. තවද මෙම මුලපිරීම කලාපීය සහයෝගීතාවයන් ගොඩනැගීම සහ රටවල් සහ සංස්කෘතීන් අතර සන්නිවේදනය කිරීම දිරිමත් කරයි."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ආසියා පැසිෆික් බීජ",
          "label": "LOC"
        },
        {
          "text": "අනාගතය",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "2022",
          "label": "DATE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "2022",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ආසියා පැසිෆික්",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "අධ්යාපන අමාත්යාංශය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "අධ්යාපන අමාත්යාංශය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "සුසිල් ප්‍රේමජයන්ත",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "යුනෙස්කෝ ශ්‍රී ලංකා කාර්යාලය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "හිමාලි ජිනදාස",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Huawei Sri Lanka",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "Tao Guangyo",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Huawei ආසියා පැසිෆික් බීජ",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "2022",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "තායිලන්තය",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "අනාගතය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "සන්නිවේදන තාක්ෂණ",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "எதிர்காலத்திற்கான ஆசிய பசிபிக் விதைகள் 2022 இல் தொடங்கப்படும்",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "ஆசிய பசிபிக் பிராந்தியத்தை பிரதிநிதித்துவப்படுத்தும் எதிர்காலத்திற்கான விதைகள் 2022 திட்டத்தின் தொடக்கத்தைக் குறிக்கும் வகையில் சமீபத்தில் ஒரு ஓட்டை ஏற்பட்டுள்ளது, இது கல்வி அமைச்சகத்துடன் இணைந்து செயல்படுத்தப்படுகிறது.",
        "உத்தியோகபூர்வ வெளியீட்டு விழா அண்மையில் கல்வி அமைச்சின் அலுவலகத்தில் இடம்பெற்றதுடன், கல்வி அமைச்சர் கலாநிதி சுசில் பிரேமஜயந்த, யுனெஸ்கோ அலுவலகத்தின் பிரதிநிதி ஹிமாலி ஜினதாச, Huawei Sri Lanka இன் பிரதம நிறைவேற்று அதிகாரி திரு. Tao Guangyo மற்றும் அதன் பிரதிநிதிகள் மற்றும் மாணவர்கள் கலந்து கொண்டனர்.",
        "எதிர்காலத்திற்கான Huawei Asia-Pacific Seeds for the Future 2022 திட்டத்தின் மூலம், தாய்லாந்தில் ஒரு IT பயிற்சியில் பங்கேற்கும் வாய்ப்பு மிகவும் திறமையான பல்கலைக்கழக மாணவர்கள் குழுவிற்கு வழங்கப்பட்டது.",
        "எதிர்காலத்திற்கான விதைகள், ICT திறன்களை மேம்படுத்துவதை நோக்கமாகக் கொண்ட உலகளாவிய திட்டமாகும். இதன் மூலம் மாணவர்கள் தங்களின் தொழில்நுட்ப அறிவைப் பகிர்ந்து கொள்வதோடு, அவர்களின் தொழில்நுட்பத் திறனையும் வளர்த்துக் கொள்ள பல்வேறு வாய்ப்புகள் வழங்கப்படும். இந்த முயற்சியானது பிராந்திய ஒத்துழைப்பை உருவாக்குதல் மற்றும் நாடுகள் மற்றும் கலாச்சாரங்களுக்கிடையேயான தொடர்பை ஊக்குவிக்கிறது."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ஆசிய பசிபிக் விதைகள்",
          "label": "LOC"
        },
        {
          "text": "எதிர்காலம்",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "2022",
          "label": "DATE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "2022",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆசிய பசிபிக்",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "கல்வி அமைச்சு",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "கல்வி அமைச்சு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "சுசில் பிரேமஜயந்த",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "யுனெஸ்கோ இலங்கை அலுவலகம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஹிமாலி ஜினதாச",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Huawei Sri Lanka",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "Tao Guangyo",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Huawei ஆசிய-பசிபிக் விதைகள்",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "2022",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "தாய்லாந்து",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "எதிர்காலம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஐ.சி.டி",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}