{
  "newspaper_id": "news-first-lk",
  "url": "https://www.newsfirst.lk/2022/06/25/fishermen-protest-against-rising-costs/",
  "time_ut": 1656159660,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Fishermen protest against rising costs",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Fishermen protest against rising costs",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); Fishermen have requested the Government to not to hike prices of fuel.",
        "A group of fishermen also engaged in a protest in Matara demanding for fuel.",
        "The protest was organized by the All Ceylon Fisheries Federation at the Kiralawella fishing port in Devinuwara, Matara.",
        "The protest was held demanding a solution to the problems faced by the fishing community including exemption of fishing gear from taxes and reduction of fuel prices.",
        "Ratna Gamage, the National Organizer of the All Ceylon Common Fisheries Federation pointed out that in some areas, kerosene has not been sold for months.",
        "Emphasizing that the ocean resource is one which can earn dollars to the country, Gamage said that fuel prices have increased 5 times within the last year, in addition to the prices of fishing gear.",
        "Fuel shipments further delayed & CPC cannot confirm next shipment arrival date"
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "Matara",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the All Ceylon Fisheries Federation",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kiralawella",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Devinuwara",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Matara",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "Ratna Gamage",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the National Organizer of the All Ceylon Common Fisheries Federation",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "months",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Gamage",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "5",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "the last year",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "& CPC",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "මිල වැඩිවීමට එරෙහිව ධීවරයෝ විරෝධතාවයක",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); ඉන්ධන මිල වැඩි නොකරන ලෙස ධීවරයෝ රජයෙන් ඉල්ලීමක් කරති.",
        "ඉන්ධන ඉල්ලා ධීවරයින් පිරිසක් මාතරදී විරෝධතාවක ද නිරත වුණා.",
        "සමස්ත ලංකා ධීවර සම්මේලනය විසින් මාතර දෙවිනුවර කිරලවැල්ල ධීවර වරාය පරිශ්‍රයේදී මෙම විරෝධතාව සංවිධානය කර තිබුණි.",
        "ධීවර ආම්පන්න බදුවලින් නිදහස් කිරීම, ඉන්ධන මිල අඩු කිරීම ඇතුළු ධීවර ප්‍රජාව මුහුණ දෙන ගැටලුවලට විසඳුම් ඉල්ලා මෙම විරෝධතාව පැවැත්විණි.",
        "සමස්ත ලංකා පොදු ධීවර සම්මේලනයේ ජාතික සංවිධායක රත්න ගමගේ පෙන්වා දුන්නේ ඇතැම් ප්‍රදේශවල මාස ගණනක සිට භූමිතෙල් අලෙවි කර නොමැති බවයි.",
        "සාගර සම්පත රටට ඩොලර් ඉපයිය හැකි සම්පතක් බව අවධාරණය කළ ගමගේ මහතා පසුගිය වසර තුළ ධීවර ආම්පන්න මිලට අමතරව ඉන්ධන මිල 5 ගුණයකින් ඉහළ ගොස් ඇති බව පැවසීය.",
        "ඉන්ධන නැව්ගත කිරීම් තවදුරටත් ප්‍රමාද වී ඇති අතර CPC හට ඊළඟ නැව්ගත කිරීමේ දිනය තහවුරු කළ නොහැක"
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "මාතර",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "සමස්ත ලංකා ධීවර සම්මේලනය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "කිරලවැල්ල",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "දෙවිනුවර",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මාතර",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "රත්න ගමගේ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "සමස්ත ලංකා පොදු ධීවර සම්මේලනයේ ජාතික සංවිධායක",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "මාස",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ගමගේ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "5",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "පසුගිය වසරේ",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "සහ CPC",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "விலைவாசி உயர்வை கண்டித்து மீனவர்கள் போராட்டம்",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); எரிபொருள் விலையை உயர்த்த வேண்டாம் என மீனவர்கள் அரசுக்கு கோரிக்கை விடுத்துள்ளனர்.",
        "மாத்தறையில் எரிபொருளைக் கோரி மீனவர்கள் குழுவொன்று ஆர்ப்பாட்டத்தில் ஈடுபட்டுள்ளனர்.",
        "மாத்தறை தெவிநுவர கிரளவெல்ல மீன்பிடி துறைமுகத்தில் அகில இலங்கை கடற்றொழில் சம்மேளனத்தின் ஏற்பாட்டில் இந்த போராட்டம் முன்னெடுக்கப்பட்டது.",
        "மீன்பிடி உபகரணங்களுக்கு வரி விலக்கு, எரிபொருள் விலை குறைப்பு உள்ளிட்ட மீனவ சமூகம் எதிர்நோக்கும் பிரச்சினைகளுக்கு தீர்வு காணுமாறு கோரியே இந்த போராட்டம் நடத்தப்பட்டது.",
        "சில பகுதிகளில் பல மாதங்களாக மண்ணெண்ணெய் விற்பனை செய்யப்படுவதில்லை என அகில இலங்கை பொது கடற்றொழில் சம்மேளனத்தின் தேசிய அமைப்பாளர் ரத்ன கமகே சுட்டிக்காட்டினார்.",
        "கடல் வளம் நாட்டுக்கு டொலர்களை ஈட்டக்கூடிய ஒன்றாகும் என வலியுறுத்திய கமகே, கடந்த வருடத்தில் மீன்பிடி உபகரணங்களின் விலைகளுக்கு மேலதிகமாக எரிபொருள் விலை 5 தடவைகள் அதிகரித்துள்ளதாகவும் தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "எரிபொருள் ஏற்றுமதி மேலும் தாமதமானது & CPC அடுத்த ஷிப்மெண்ட் வருகை தேதியை உறுதிப்படுத்த முடியாது"
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "மாத்தறை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "அகில இலங்கை மீனவ கூட்டமைப்பு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "கிரலவெல்ல",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "தெவிநுவர",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "மாத்தறை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "ரத்ன கமகே",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "அகில இலங்கை பொது மீன்பிடி சம்மேளனத்தின் தேசிய அமைப்பாளர்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "மாதங்கள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "கமகே",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "5",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "கடந்த ஆண்டு",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "& CPC",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}