{
  "newspaper_id": "d-b-s-jeyaraj-com",
  "url": "https://dbsjeyaraj.com/dbsj/archives/78373",
  "time_ut": 1656875160,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Leader of the Opposition Sajith Premadasa and Ex-President Maithripala  Sirisena Meet with several Opposition political party leaders and  civil rights activists for discussions on the theme “National Reforms and Progress” and moot a collective program to get the country out of the current crisis.",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Leader of the Opposition Sajith Premadasa and Ex-President Maithripala  Sirisena Meet with several Opposition political party leaders and  civil rights activists for discussions on the theme “National Reforms and Progress” and moot a collective program to get the country out of the current crisis.",
      "author": "Administrator",
      "body_lines": [
        "Samagi Jana Balawegaya Leader Sajith Premadasa and Sri Lanka Freedom Party Leader and former President Maithripala Sirisena met with several Opposition political party leaders as well as civil rights activists yesterday in a fresh effort to moot a collective program to get the country out of the current crisis.",
        "The meeting was organised on the theme “National Reforms and Progress” and is aimed at finding common ground on several issues to salvage the country and bring about long-term reforms.",
        "Premadasa who addressed the meeting said that whatever form a Government takes, the economic issues of the people have to be addressed urgently and a solution acceptable to all people must be found first. “We are faced with a dollar and cents problem today. The basic human needs can only be met with the increase in our foreign reserves,” he said.",
        "Premadasa said that the country can be built through social reforms that take a wide variety of opinions on board. “We must listen to the proposals and ideas of all progressive parties. The aim of the opposition is to rebuild the country through a common national agenda that can bring together diverse ideas,” Premadasa said.",
        "Former President Sirisena said that the country’s foreign policy is in a mess and during the past three years Sri Lanka has lost her traditional allies including Russia and Japan.",
        "“We are fully supportive of a common plan of action to put the country on the proper track. We need to form a Government unlike any we have had in the past so that the aspirations of the youth can be addressed,” he said.",
        "He added that the issue of corruption must also be addressed urgently. “Over 100 state institutions are involved in large scale corruption. Today we know that when a bowser leaves Kolonnawa, they inform the petrol shed owner and demand a certain sum to bring the bowser there. Although there is no petrol in the sheds, plenty can be bought in the black market,” he said.",
        "Sirisena added that the Government has failed to put in place a proper distribution system for essential goods till today.",
        "The meeting was convened by SJB MPs Rajitha Senaratne and Buddhika Pathirana.",
        "Those who attended the meeting included Samagi Jana Balavega General Secretary Ranjith Maddumabandara, President Sarath Fonseka, Mano Ganesan, Rauf Hakeem, C. Wigneswaran, P. Digambaram, many political leaders and a large number of civil activists including Victor Ivan, Janaranjana, Gamini Viyangoda, Prof. Rohan Samarajeeva, Upul Jayasuriya PC and business leaders such as Kulathunga Rajapaksa and Ariyaseela Wickramanayake."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "the Opposition Sajith Premadasa",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "Maithripala",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "National Reforms and Progress",
          "label": "WORK_OF_ART"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Samagi Jana Balawegaya",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sajith Premadasa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka Freedom Party",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Maithripala Sirisena",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "yesterday",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "National Reforms and Progress",
            "label": "WORK_OF_ART"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "first",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "a dollar and cents",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Premadasa",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Premadasa",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sirisena",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the past three years",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Russia",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Japan",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "100",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Today",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kolonnawa",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "SJB MPs",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Rajitha Senaratne",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Buddhika Pathirana",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Samagi Jana Balavega",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ranjith Maddumabandara",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sarath Fonseka",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Mano Ganesan",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Rauf Hakeem",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "C. Wigneswaran",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "P. Digambaram",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Victor Ivan",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Janaranjana",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Gamini Viyangoda",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Rohan Samarajeeva",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Upul Jayasuriya",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kulathunga Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ariyaseela Wickramanayake",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "විපක්ෂ නායක සජිත් ප්‍රේමදාස මහතා සහ හිටපු ජනාධිපති මෛත්‍රීපාල සිරිසේන මහතා විපක්ෂයේ දේශපාලන පක්ෂ නායකයින් සහ සිවිල් අයිතිවාසිකම් ක්‍රියාකාරීන් කිහිප දෙනෙකු හමුවී \"ජාතික ප්‍රතිසංස්කරණ සහ ප්‍රගතිය\" යන තේමාව යටතේ සාකච්ඡා කර පවතින අර්බුදයෙන් රට ගොඩගැනීම සඳහා සාමූහික වැඩපිළිවෙලක් සකස් කර ඇත.",
      "author": "පරිපාලක",
      "body_lines": [
        "පවතින අර්බුදයෙන් රට ගොඩගැනීම සඳහා සාමූහික වැඩපිළිවෙලක් සැකසීමේ නව ප්‍රයත්නයක් ලෙස සමගි ජන බලවේගයේ නායක සජිත් ප්‍රේමදාස සහ ශ්‍රී ලංකා නිදහස් පක්ෂ නායක හිටපු ජනාධිපති මෛත්‍රීපාල සිරිසේන ඊයේ විපක්ෂ දේශපාලන පක්ෂ නායකයින් සහ සිවිල් අයිතිවාසිකම් ක්‍රියාකාරීන් කිහිප දෙනෙකු හමුවුණා.",
        "“ජාතික ප්‍රතිසංස්කරණ සහ ප්‍රගතිය” යන තේමාව යටතේ මෙම රැස්වීම සංවිධානය කර ඇති අතර රට බේරා ගැනීමට සහ දිගුකාලීන ප්‍රතිසංස්කරණ ඇති කිරීමට කරුණු කිහිපයක් සම්බන්ධයෙන් පොදු පදනමක් සොයා ගැනීම මෙහි අරමුණයි.",
        "මෙම රැස්වීම ඇමතූ ප්‍රේමදාස කියා සිටියේ කුමන ආකාරයක ආණ්ඩුවක් ආවත් ජනතාවගේ ආර්ථික ප්‍රශ්නවලට කඩිනමින් විසඳුම් ලබාදිය යුතු බවත් ඊට ප්‍රථමයෙන් සියලු ජනතාවට පිළිගත හැකි විසඳුමක් ලබාදිය යුතු බවත්ය. “අපි අද මුහුණ දී සිටින්නේ ඩොලර් සහ ශත ප්‍රශ්නයකටයි. මූලික මිනිස් අවශ්‍යතා සපුරා ගත හැක්කේ අපේ විදේශ සංචිත ඉහළ යාමෙන් පමණයි,” ඔහු පැවසීය.",
        "ප්‍රේමදාස කියා සිටියේ විවිධ මත දරන සමාජ ප්‍රතිසංස්කරණ තුළින් රට ගොඩනැගිය හැකි බවයි. “සියලු ප්‍රගතිශීලී පක්ෂවල යෝජනා සහ අදහස්වලට අපි සවන් දිය යුතුයි. විවිධ අදහස් එක්කාසු කළ හැකි පොදු ජාතික න්‍යාය පත්‍රයක් හරහා රට ගොඩගැනීම විපක්ෂයේ අරමුණයි.” ප්‍රේමදාස පැවසීය.",
        "රටේ විදේශ ප්‍රතිපත්තිය අවුල් සහගත තත්ත්වයක පවතින බවත්, ගතවූ වසර තුන තුළ ශ්‍රී ලංකාවට රුසියාව, ජපානය ඇතුළු සාම්ප්‍රදායික මිත්‍ර රටවල් අහිමි වූ බවත් හිටපු ජනාධිපති සිරිසේන ප්‍රකාශ කළා.",
        "“රට නිසි මගට ගෙන ඒම සඳහා වන පොදු ක්‍රියාකාරී සැලැස්මකට අපි පූර්ණ සහයෝගය දෙනවා. තරුණයන්ගේ අභිලාෂයන් විසඳා ගැනීමට හැකිවන පරිදි අතීතයේ තිබූ ආණ්ඩුවක් මෙන් නොව අපි ආණ්ඩුවක් පිහිටුවිය යුතුයි.",
        "දූෂණ ප්‍රශ්නයටද කඩිනමින් පිළියම් යෙදිය යුතු බවද ඔහු පැවසීය. “රාජ්‍ය ආයතන 100කට අධික ප්‍රමාණයක් මහා පරිමාණ දූෂණවලට සම්බන්ධයි. අද අපි දන්නවා බවුසරයක් කොළොන්නාවෙන් යනකොට පෙට්‍රල් ෂෙඩ් අයිතිකරුට දන්වලා බවුසරය එතනට ගේන්න යම් මුදලක් ඉල්ලනවා. ෂෙඩ්වල පෙට්‍රල් නැති වුණාට කළු කඩෙන් ප්ලේන්ටියක් ගන්න පුළුවන්” යැයි පැවසීය.",
        "අත්‍යාවශ්‍ය භාණ්ඩ බෙදාහැරීමේ විධිමත් ක්‍රමවේදයක් අද දක්වා ක්‍රියාත්මක කිරීමට රජය අපොහොසත් වී ඇති බවද සිරිසේන මහතා පැවසීය.",
        "මෙම රැස්වීම කැඳවා තිබුණේ SJB පාර්ලිමේන්තු මන්ත්‍රීවරුන් වන රාජිත සේනාරත්න සහ බුද්ධික පතිරණ විසිනි.",
        "මෙම හමුවට සමගි ජන බලවේගයේ ප්‍රධාන ලේකම් රංජිත් මද්දුමබණ්ඩාර, සභාපති සරත් ෆොන්සේකා, මනෝ ගනේෂන්, රවුෆ් හකීම්, සී.විග්නේෂ්වරන්, පී.දිගම්බරම්, දේශපාලන නායකයින් රැසක් සහ වික්ටර් අයිවන්, ජනරංජන, ගාමිණී වියන්ගොඩ ඇතුළු සිවිල් ක්‍රියාකාරීන් විශාල පිරිසක් එක්ව සිටියහ. , මහාචාර්ය රොහාන් සමරජීව, ජනාධිපති නීතිඥ උපුල් ජයසූරිය සහ කුලතුංග රාජපක්ෂ, ආරියසීල වික්‍රමනායක වැනි ව්‍යාපාරික නායකයින්."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "විපක්ෂය සජිත් ප්‍රේමදාස",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "මෛත්‍රීපාල",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "ජාතික ප්‍රතිසංස්කරණ සහ ප්‍රගතිය",
          "label": "WORK_OF_ART"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "සමගි ජන බලවේගය",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "සජිත් ප්‍රේමදාස",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකා නිදහස් පක්ෂය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "මෛත්‍රීපාල සිරිසේන",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඊයේ",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ජාතික ප්‍රතිසංස්කරණ සහ ප්‍රගතිය",
            "label": "WORK_OF_ART"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "පළමුවන",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඩොලර් සහ ශත",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ප්‍රේමදාස ය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ප්‍රේමදාස ය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "සිරිසේන",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "පසුගිය වසර තුන",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "රුසියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජපානය",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "100",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "කොලොන්නාව",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "SJB මන්ත්‍රීවරු",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "රාජිත සේනාරත්න",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "බුද්ධික පතිරණ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "සමගි ජන බලවේගය",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "රංජිත් මද්දුමබණ්ඩාර",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "සරත් ෆොන්සේකා",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Mano Ganesan",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "රවුෆ් හකීම්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "සී විග්නේෂ්වරන්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "පී.දිගම්බරම්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "වික්ටර් අයිවන්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජනරංජන",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගාමිණී වියන්ගොඩ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "රොහාන් සමරජීව",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "උපුල් ජයසූරිය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "කුලතුංග රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ආරියසීල වික්‍රමනායක",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "எதிர்க்கட்சித் தலைவர் சஜித் பிரேமதாச மற்றும் முன்னாள் ஜனாதிபதி மைத்திரிபால சிறிசேன ஆகியோர் பல எதிர்க்கட்சி அரசியல் கட்சித் தலைவர்கள் மற்றும் சிவில் உரிமை ஆர்வலர்களை சந்தித்து \"தேசிய சீர்திருத்தம் மற்றும் முன்னேற்றம்\" என்ற தொனிப்பொருளில் கலந்துரையாடல் மற்றும் தற்போதைய நெருக்கடியிலிருந்து நாட்டை மீட்டெடுப்பதற்கான கூட்டு வேலைத்திட்டத்தை முன்வைத்தனர்.",
      "author": "நிர்வாகி",
      "body_lines": [
        "சமகி ஜன பலவேகய தலைவர் சஜித் பிரேமதாச மற்றும் ஸ்ரீலங்கா சுதந்திரக் கட்சியின் தலைவரும் முன்னாள் ஜனாதிபதியுமான மைத்திரிபால சிறிசேன ஆகியோர் எதிர்க்கட்சி அரசியல் கட்சித் தலைவர்கள் மற்றும் சிவில் உரிமை செயற்பாட்டாளர்களை நேற்று சந்தித்தனர்.",
        "\"தேசிய சீர்திருத்தங்கள் மற்றும் முன்னேற்றம்\" என்ற கருப்பொருளில் இந்த கூட்டம் ஏற்பாடு செய்யப்பட்டுள்ளது மற்றும் நாட்டைக் காப்பாற்றுவதற்கும் நீண்ட கால சீர்திருத்தங்களைக் கொண்டுவருவதற்கும் பல பிரச்சினைகளில் பொதுவான அடிப்படையைக் கண்டறிவதை நோக்கமாகக் கொண்டுள்ளது.",
        "கூட்டத்தில் உரையாற்றிய பிரேமதாச, அரசாங்கம் எந்த வடிவத்தை எடுத்தாலும், மக்களின் பொருளாதாரப் பிரச்சினைகளுக்கு அவசரமாகத் தீர்வு காண வேண்டும், முதலில் அனைத்து மக்களும் ஏற்றுக்கொள்ளக்கூடிய தீர்வு காணப்பட வேண்டும். \"நாங்கள் இன்று டாலர் மற்றும் சென்ட் பிரச்சனையை எதிர்கொள்கிறோம். நமது வெளிநாட்டு கையிருப்பு அதிகரிப்பால் மட்டுமே மனிதனின் அடிப்படைத் தேவைகளை பூர்த்தி செய்ய முடியும்,'' என்றார்.",
        "பலதரப்பட்ட கருத்துக்களை உள்வாங்கும் சமூக சீர்திருத்தங்கள் மூலம் நாட்டை கட்டியெழுப்ப முடியும் என பிரேமதாச தெரிவித்துள்ளார். “அனைத்து முற்போக்குக் கட்சிகளின் முன்மொழிவுகளையும் யோசனைகளையும் நாம் கேட்க வேண்டும். பலதரப்பட்ட யோசனைகளை ஒன்றிணைக்கக்கூடிய பொதுவான தேசிய நிகழ்ச்சி நிரலின் மூலம் நாட்டை மீளக் கட்டியெழுப்புவதே எதிர்க்கட்சிகளின் நோக்கமாகும்” என்று பிரேமதாச கூறினார்.",
        "நாட்டின் வெளியுறவுக் கொள்கை குழப்பத்தில் இருப்பதாகவும், கடந்த மூன்று வருடங்களில் ரஷ்யா, ஜப்பான் உள்ளிட்ட தனது பாரம்பரிய நட்பு நாடுகளை இலங்கை இழந்துள்ளதாகவும் முன்னாள் ஜனாதிபதி சிறிசேன தெரிவித்துள்ளார்.",
        "“நாட்டை சரியான பாதையில் கொண்டு செல்வதற்கான பொதுவான செயல்திட்டத்திற்கு நாங்கள் முழு ஆதரவளிக்கிறோம். இளைஞர்களின் அபிலாஷைகளை நிவர்த்தி செய்யும் வகையில், கடந்த காலத்தில் இருந்ததைப் போலல்லாமல், நாங்கள் ஒரு அரசாங்கத்தை அமைக்க வேண்டும், ”என்று அவர் கூறினார்.",
        "ஊழல் பிரச்சினைக்கு உடனடி தீர்வு காண வேண்டும் என்றும் அவர் கூறினார். “100க்கும் மேற்பட்ட அரச நிறுவனங்கள் பாரிய ஊழலில் ஈடுபட்டுள்ளன. கொலன்னாவையில் இருந்து ஒரு பவுசர் வெளியேறும் போது, ​​அவர்கள் பெற்றோல் கொட்டகை உரிமையாளருக்கு அறிவித்து, அந்த பவுசரை அங்கு கொண்டு வருவதற்கு குறிப்பிட்ட தொகையை கோருவதை இன்று நாம் அறிவோம். ஷெட்களில் பெட்ரோல் இல்லை என்றாலும், கறுப்புச் சந்தையில் ஏராளமாக வாங்கலாம்,'' என்றார்.",
        "அத்தியாவசியப் பொருட்களுக்கான முறையான விநியோக முறையை இன்று வரை ஏற்படுத்த அரசாங்கம் தவறிவிட்டதாக சிறிசேனா மேலும் தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "எஸ்.ஜே.பி பாராளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர்களான ராஜித சேனாரத்ன மற்றும் புத்திக பத்திரன ஆகியோரால் இந்த கூட்டம் கூட்டப்பட்டது.",
        "சமகி ஜன பலவேகவின் பொதுச் செயலாளர் ரஞ்சித் மத்துமபண்டார, தலைவர் சரத் பொன்சேகா, மனோ கணேசன், ரவூப் ஹக்கீம், சி.விக்னேஸ்வரன், பி.திகாம்பரம், பல அரசியல் தலைவர்கள், விக்டர் ஐவன், ஜனரஞ்சன, காமினி வியங்கொட உட்பட பெருந்தொகையான சிவில் ஆர்வலர்கள் இந்தக் கூட்டத்தில் கலந்துகொண்டனர். , பேராசிரியர் ரொஹான் சமரஜீவ, உபுல் ஜயசூரிய பி.சி. மற்றும் வணிகத் தலைவர்களான குலதுங்க ராஜபக்ஷ மற்றும் ஆரியசீல விக்கிரமநாயக்க."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "எதிர்க்கட்சியான சஜித் பிரேமதாச",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "மைத்திரிபால",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "தேசிய சீர்திருத்தங்கள் மற்றும் முன்னேற்றம்",
          "label": "WORK_OF_ART"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "சமகி ஜன பலவேகயா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "சஜித் பிரேமதாச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஸ்ரீலங்கா சுதந்திரக் கட்சி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "மைத்திரிபால சிறிசேன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "நேற்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "தேசிய சீர்திருத்தங்கள் மற்றும் முன்னேற்றம்",
            "label": "WORK_OF_ART"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "முதலில்",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஒரு டாலர் மற்றும் சென்ட்",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பிரேமதாச",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "பிரேமதாச",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "சிறிசேன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "கடந்த மூன்று வருடங்கள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரஷ்யா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜப்பான்",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "100",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "கொலன்னாவ",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "SJB பாராளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர்கள்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ராஜித சேனாரத்ன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "புத்திக பத்திரன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "சமகி ஜன பலவேகா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரஞ்சித் மத்துமபண்டார",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "சரத் ​​பொன்சேகா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Mano Ganesan",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரவூப் ஹக்கீம்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "சி.விக்னேஸ்வரன்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "பி.திகாம்பரம்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "விக்டர் இவான்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜனரஞ்சனா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "காமினி வியங்கொட",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரொஹான் சமரஜீவ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "உபுல் ஜயசூரிய",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "குலதுங்க ராஜபக்ச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆரியசீல விக்கிரமநாயக்க",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}