{
  "newspaper_id": "lankadeepa-lk",
  "url": "https://www.lankadeepa.lk/latest_news/දුම්රිය-ධාවනය-අඛණ්ඩව/1-616339",
  "time_ut": 1657695410,
  "original_lang": "si",
  "original_title": "දුම්රිය ධාවනය අඛණ්ඩව",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Train continues",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "Deputy General Superintendent of Railways Mr. Gamini Senaviratne said that due to the imposition of curfew in the Western Province, the trains have not been suspended so far.",
        "The Deputy General Superintendent of Railways said that the decision about the train should be taken by the General Manager of Railways Dhammika Jayasundara."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Gamini Senaviratne",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Western Province",
            "label": "LOC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Dhammika Jayasundara",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "දුම්රිය ධාවනය අඛණ්ඩව",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "බස්නාහිර පළාතට ක්‍රියාත්මක වන පරිදි ඇඳිරි නීතිය පැනවීම හේතුවෙන් මේ දක්වා දුම්රිය ධාවනය අත්හිටුවා නොමැති බව දුම්රිය නියෝජ්‍ය සාමාන්‍ය අධිකාරී ගාමිණී සෙනවිරත්න මහතා පැවසීය.",
        "දුම්රිය නියෝජ්‍ය සාමාන්‍ය අධිකාරීවරයා පැවසුවේ දුම්රිය පිළිබඳ තීරණය දුම්රිය සාමාන්‍යධිකාරී ධම්මික ජයසුන්දර මහතා විසින් ගත යුතු බවයි."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ගාමිණී සෙනවිරත්න",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "බස්නාහිර පළාත",
            "label": "LOC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ධම්මික ජයසුන්දර",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "ரயில் தொடர்கிறது",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "மேல் மாகாணத்தில் ஊரடங்குச் சட்டம் அமுல்படுத்தப்பட்டுள்ளமையினால் இதுவரை ரயில் சேவைகள் இடைநிறுத்தப்படவில்லை என ரயில்வே பிரதி பொது அத்தியட்சகர் திரு.காமினி சேனவிரத்ன தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "புகையிரதம் தொடர்பான தீர்மானத்தை புகையிரத பொது முகாமையாளர் தம்மிக்க ஜயசுந்தர மேற்கொள்ள வேண்டும் என ரயில்வே பிரதி பொது அத்தியட்சகர் தெரிவித்துள்ளார்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "காமினி சேனவிரத்ன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "மேல் மாகாணம்",
            "label": "LOC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "தம்மிக்க ஜயசுந்தர",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}