{
  "newspaper_id": "ada-lk",
  "url": "https://www.ada.lk/breaking_news/සර්ව-පාක්ෂික-රජයක්-පිළිබඳ-ජනතාව-දැඩි-විශ්වාසයකින්--බලා-සිටිනවා/11-395973",
  "time_ut": 1659452575,
  "original_lang": "si",
  "original_title": "සර්ව පාක්ෂික රජයක් පිළිබඳ ජනතාව දැඩි විශ්වාසයකින්  බලා සිටිනවා",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "People are waiting for an all-party government with great confidence",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "President Ranil Wickramasinghe said that religious leaders led by the Maha Sangharatna, civil organizations, youth groups and the entire people have strong confidence and expectation about an all-party government.",
        "Mr. Ranil Wickramasinghe mentioned this in the discussion held today (02) with the political parties regarding the establishment of an all-party government.",
        "Several rounds of negotiations with political parties were held today at the President's Office.",
        "Party leaders and members representing the ruling party including the Sri Lanka Podujana Peramuna participated in the first round of discussions and the second discussion was held with the Ceylon Labor Congress. Ceylon Labor Congress Leader Sendhil Thondaman and Secretary General Member of Parliament Jeevan Thondaman and other representatives participated in it.",
        "The third discussion was held with the National Congress and its leader Member of Parliament A.L.M. A delegation including Ataullah participated in it.",
        "The President is going to discuss the formation of an all-party government tomorrow (03) with several parties and many parties including the Samagi Jana Balawegaya, Sri Lanka Freedom Party, Tamil National Alliance have expressed their agreement to join the future discussions.",
        "Prime Minister Dinesh Gunawardena, President's Secretary Saman Ekanayake, President's Additional Secretary Lawyer Chaminda Kularatne and others participated in this discussion."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickramasinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Maha Sangharatna",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickramasinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "Podujana Peramuna",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "first",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "second",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sendhil Thondaman",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Jeevan Thondaman",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "third",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "the National Congress",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ataullah",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "tomorrow",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "03",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Samagi",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka Freedom Party",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Tamil National Alliance",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Dinesh Gunawardena",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Saman Ekanayake",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Lawyer Chaminda Kularatne",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "සර්ව පාක්ෂික රජයක් පිළිබඳ ජනතාව දැඩි විශ්වාසයකින්  බලා සිටිනවා",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "සර්ව පාක්ෂික රජයක් පිළිබඳව මහා සංඝරත්නය ප්‍රමුඛ ආගමික නායකයින්, සිවිල් සංවිධාන, තරුණ කණ්ඩායම් ඇතුළු සමස්ත ජනතාව දැඩි විශ්වාසයකින් හා අපේක්ෂාවෙන් පසුවන බව ජනාධිපති රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතා පැවසීය.",
        "සර්ව පාක්ෂික රජයක් පිහිටුවීම සම්බන්ධව දේශපාලන පක්ෂ සමග අද (02) පැවති සාකච්ඡාවේ දී රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතා මේ බව සඳහන් කළේය.",
        "දේශපාලන පක්ෂ සමග සාකච්ඡා වට කිහිපයක් අද දිනයේ ජනාධිපති කාර්යාලයේ දී පැවැත්විණ.",
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකා පොදුජන පෙරමුණ ඇතුළු ආණ්ඩු පක්ෂය නියෝජනය කරන පක්ෂ නායකයින් සහ සාමාජිකයෝ  පළමු සාකච්ඡා වටයට එක්ව සිටි අතර දෙවන සාකච්ඡාව ලංකා කම්කරු කොංග්‍රසය සමග පැවැත්විණි. ලංකා කම්කරු කොංග්‍රසයේ නායක සෙන්දිල් තොණ්ඩමන් සහ මහලේකම් පාර්ලිමේන්තු මන්ත්‍රී ජීවන් තොණ්ඩමන් යන මහත්වරු ඇතුළු නියෝජිතයෝ ඊට සහභාගී වූහ.",
        "තෙවන සාකච්ඡාව ජාතික කොංග්‍රසය සමග පැවැත්වුණ අතර එහි නායක පාර්ලිමේන්තු මන්ත්‍රී ඒ.එල්.එම්. අතාවුල්ලා ඇතුළු නියෝජිත පිරිසක් ඊට සහභාගී වූහ.",
        "සර්ව පාක්ෂික රජයක් පිහිටුවීම පිළිබඳ හෙට (03) දිනයේ ද පාර්ශ්ව කිහිපයක් සමග ජනාධිපතිවරයා  සාකච්ඡා කිරීමට නියමිත අතර සමගි ජන බලවේගය, ශ්‍රී ලංකා නිදහස් පක්ෂය, දෙමළ ජාතික සන්ධානය ඇතුළු පක්ෂ රැසක් ඉදිරි සාකච්ඡාවලට එක්වීමට එකඟතාව පළ කර තිබේ.",
        "අග්‍රාමාත්‍ය දිනේෂ් ගුණවර්ධන, ජනාධිපති ලේකම් සමන් ඒකනායක, ජනාධිපති අතිරේක ලේකම් නීතිඥ චමින්ද කුලරත්න යන මහත්වරු ඇතුළු පිරිසක් මෙම සාකච්ඡාවට එක්ව සිටියහ."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "මහා සංඝරත්නය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "පොදුජන පෙරමුණ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "පළමුවන",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "දෙවැනි",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "සෙන්දිල් තොණ්ඩමන්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජීවන් තොණ්ඩමන්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "තෙවන",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජාතික කොංග්රසය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "අතාවුල්ලාය",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "හෙට",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "03",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "සමගි",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකා නිදහස් පක්ෂය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "දෙමළ ජාතික සන්ධානය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "දිනේෂ් ගුණවර්ධන",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "සමන් ඒකනායක",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "නීතිඥ චමින්ද කුලරත්න",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "அனைத்துக் கட்சி ஆட்சி அமையும் என மக்கள் மிகுந்த நம்பிக்கையுடன் காத்திருக்கின்றனர்",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "மகாசங்கரத்னா தலைமையிலான மதத் தலைவர்கள், சிவில் அமைப்புக்கள், இளைஞர் குழுக்கள் மற்றும் ஒட்டுமொத்த மக்களும் சர்வகட்சி அரசாங்கம் தொடர்பில் பலமான நம்பிக்கையும் எதிர்பார்ப்பும் கொண்டுள்ளனர் என ஜனாதிபதி ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "சர்வகட்சி அரசாங்கத்தை அமைப்பது தொடர்பில் அரசியல் கட்சிகளுடன் இன்று (02) இடம்பெற்ற கலந்துரையாடலில் ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க இதனைக் குறிப்பிட்டுள்ளார்.",
        "அரசியல் கட்சிகளுடன் பல சுற்று பேச்சுவார்த்தை இன்று ஜனாதிபதி அலுவலகத்தில் இடம்பெற்றது.",
        "ஶ்ரீலங்கா பொதுஜன பெரமுன உட்பட ஆளும் கட்சியை பிரதிநிதித்துவப்படுத்தும் கட்சித் தலைவர்கள் மற்றும் உறுப்பினர்கள் முதல் சுற்று கலந்துரையாடலில் கலந்து கொண்டதுடன் இரண்டாவது கலந்துரையாடல் இலங்கை தொழிலாளர் காங்கிரஸுடன் இடம்பெற்றது. இதில் இலங்கை தொழிலாளர் காங்கிரஸின் தலைவர் செந்தில் தொண்டமான், செயலாளர் நாயகம் ஜீவன் தொண்டமான் உள்ளிட்டோர் கலந்துகொண்டனர்.",
        "மூன்றாவது கலந்துரையாடல் தேசிய காங்கிரஸ் மற்றும் அதன் தலைவர் பாராளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர் ஏ.எல்.எம். அதாவுல்லா உள்ளிட்ட குழுவினர் இதில் கலந்துகொண்டனர்.",
        "சர்வகட்சி அரசாங்கத்தை அமைப்பது தொடர்பில் ஜனாதிபதி நாளை (03) பல கட்சிகளுடன் கலந்துரையாடவுள்ளதோடு, எதிர்கால பேச்சுவார்த்தையில் இணைந்து கொள்வதற்கு சமகி ஜன பலவேகய, ஸ்ரீலங்கா சுதந்திரக் கட்சி, தமிழ்த் தேசியக் கூட்டமைப்பு உள்ளிட்ட பல கட்சிகள் இணக்கம் தெரிவித்துள்ளன.",
        "இந்த கலந்துரையாடலில் பிரதமர் தினேஷ் குணவர்தன, ஜனாதிபதியின் செயலாளர் சமன் ஏக்கநாயக்க, ஜனாதிபதியின் மேலதிக செயலாளர் சட்டத்தரணி சமிந்த குலரத்ன மற்றும் பலர் கலந்துகொண்டனர்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "மகா சங்கரத்னா",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "பொதுஜன பெரமுன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "முதலில்",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "இரண்டாவது",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "செந்தில் தொண்டமான்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜீவன் தொண்டமான்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "மூன்றாவது",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "தேசிய காங்கிரஸ்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "அதாவுல்லா",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "நாளை",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "03",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "சமகி",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஸ்ரீலங்கா சுதந்திரக் கட்சி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "தமிழ் தேசிய கூட்டமைப்பு",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "தினேஷ் குணவர்தன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "சமன் ஏக்கநாயக்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "சட்டத்தரணி சமிந்த குலரத்ன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}