{
  "newspaper_id": "ada-lk",
  "url": "https://www.ada.lk/breaking_news/ගෝඨා-සෙනසුරාදා-එයි/11-396820",
  "time_ut": 1662030250,
  "original_lang": "si",
  "original_title": "ගෝඨා සෙනසුරාදා එයි",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Gota will come on Saturday",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "It is reported that former President Gotabhaya Rajapaksa is scheduled to return to the island next Saturday. In view of the strong public protest against the President on July 9, the former President first left for the Maldives and then for Singapore.",
        "While in Singapore, the President announced his resignation from office and due to exceeding the time he could stay there, he left Singapore for Thailand.",
        "According to the Sri Lanka Podujana Peramuna's request to the President to provide the necessary facilities for the former President to return to Sri Lanka, the necessary facilities have been provided for him to return to Sri Lanka."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Saturday",
          "label": "DATE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Gotabhaya Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "next Saturday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "July 9",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Maldives",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Singapore",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Singapore",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Singapore",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Thailand",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "Podujana Peramuna's",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "ගෝඨා සෙනසුරාදා එයි",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "හිටපු ජනාධිපති ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ මහතා ලබන සෙනසුරාදා යළි දිවයිනට පැමිණීමට නියමිත බව වාර්තා වෙයි. ජනපතිවරයාට එරෙහිව ජුලි 9 දා එල්ල වූ දැඩි ජනතා විරෝධය හමුවේ හිටපු ජනපතිවරයා මුලින්ම මාලදිවයිනටත් ඉන් අනතුරුව සිංගප්පූරුවටත් පිටත්ව ගියේය.",
        "සිංගප්පූරුවේ සිටිමින් ජනපතිවරයා සිය ධුරයෙන් ඉල්ලා අස්වීම ප්‍රකාශයට පත්කළ අතර එහි රැදී සිටිය හැකි කාලය ඉක්මවා යාම හේතුවෙන් ඔහු සිංගප්පූරුවෙන් තායිලන්තය බලා පිටත්ව ගියේය.",
        "හිටපු ජනපතිවරයාට නැවත ලංකාවට පැමිණීම සඳහා අවශ්‍ය පහසුකම් සලසන ලෙස ශ්‍රී ලංකා පොදුජන පෙරමුණ ජනපතිවරයාගෙන් කළ ඉල්ලිමට අනුව මෙසේ ඔහුට නැවත ලංකාවට පැමිණීමට අවශ්‍ය පහසුකම් සලසා දී තිබේ."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "සෙනසුරාදා",
          "label": "DATE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "එන සෙනසුරාදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජූලි 9",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මාලදිවයින",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "සිංගප්පූරුව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "සිංගප්පූරුව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "සිංගප්පූරුව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "තායිලන්තය",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "පොදුජන පෙරමුණේ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "கோதா சனிக்கிழமை வருவார்",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "முன்னாள் ஜனாதிபதி கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ஷ எதிர்வரும் சனிக்கிழமை நாடு திரும்பவுள்ளதாக தெரிவிக்கப்படுகின்றது. கடந்த ஜூலை மாதம் 9ஆம் திகதி ஜனாதிபதிக்கு எதிராக மக்கள் மத்தியில் பலத்த எதிர்ப்பு கிளம்பியதையடுத்து, முன்னாள் ஜனாதிபதி முதலில் மாலைதீவுக்கும் பின்னர் சிங்கப்பூருக்கும் சென்றுள்ளார்.",
        "சிங்கப்பூரில் இருந்தபோது, ​​ஜனாதிபதி தனது பதவியை ராஜினாமா செய்வதாக அறிவித்தார், மேலும் அவர் அங்கு தங்கியிருக்கும் நேரத்தை மீறியதால், அவர் சிங்கப்பூரிலிருந்து தாய்லாந்துக்கு சென்றார்.",
        "முன்னாள் ஜனாதிபதி இலங்கைக்கு திரும்புவதற்கு தேவையான வசதிகளை செய்து தருமாறு ஸ்ரீலங்கா பொதுஜன பெரமுன ஜனாதிபதியிடம் விடுத்த கோரிக்கைக்கு அமைய, அவர் இலங்கை திரும்புவதற்கு தேவையான வசதிகள் செய்யப்பட்டுள்ளன."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "சனிக்கிழமை",
          "label": "DATE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "கோத்தபாய ராஜபக்ச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "அடுத்த சனிக்கிழமை",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜூலை 9",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "மாலத்தீவுகள்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "சிங்கப்பூர்",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "சிங்கப்பூர்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சிங்கப்பூர்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "தாய்லாந்து",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "பொதுஜன பெரமுனவின்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}