{
  "newspaper_id": "daily-ft-lk",
  "url": "https://www.ft.lk/business/Exterminators-achieves-best-1Q-since-inception/34-738778",
  "time_ut": 1660688434,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Exterminators achieves best 1Q since inception",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Exterminators achieves best 1Q since inception",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "Pest management and environmental technology specialists Exterminators Plc., said yesterday it has achieved the best first quarter during 1 April to 30 June 2022 since the company’s inception.",
        "It said revenue increased by 26% to Rs. 30 million, gross profit by 20% to Rs. 22.5 million, operating profit by 13% to Rs. 4.8 million, profit before tax by 84% to Rs. 6.7 million with the support of Rs. 2.2 million as finance income, net profit by 49% to Rs. 4.9 million and the comprehensive income by 991% to Rs. 36 million in the 1Q of the financial year 2023.",
        "The earnings per share increased by 12% and the net assets per share increased by 27% in the 1Q of the financial year 2023 even during the prevailing crisis. The total dividend payout for FY22 was Rs. 0.16 per share, which is 29.7% of the PAT, the company will issue the final dividend payment of Rs. 0.07 per share in early September.",
        "Exterminators currently operates with three branches in Colombo, Kandy and Dambulla. The company aims to expand its network by setting up branches in Hambantota, Galle and Jaffna to capture opportunities within these areas of potential future development while setting up a premier Customer Centre in the heart of Colombo. The company will also franchise its business to the Northern and Eastern Provinces. The company has identified opportunities in Maldives with many leisure sector establishments requiring pest control services.",
        "“We carved a unique niche within the industry as an environmental management company which extends its services beyond the realms of pest control. As a growth oriented business we hope to explore market development strategies by venturing across borders with global expansion,” Chairman Chaaminda Ratnayake said.",
        "“As a proactive company with an entrepreneurial mindset, we reacted to the unfolding events in a positive and proactive manner, always bearing in mind that crises create opportunities to challenge and change the status quo for a better future,” added Managing Director Marlon Ferreira."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "1Q",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Pest",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Exterminators Plc",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "yesterday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the best first quarter",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "1 April to 30 June 2022",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "26%",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "30 million",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "20%",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "22.5 million",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "13%",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "4.8 million",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "84%",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "6.7 million",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Rs",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "2.2 million",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "49%",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "4.9 million",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "991%",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "36 million",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "12%",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "27%",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "the 1Q of the financial year 2023",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "0.16",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "29.7%",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "PAT",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Rs",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "0.07",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "early September",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "three",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Colombo",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kandy",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Dambulla",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Hambantota",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Galle",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Jaffna",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Colombo",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Northern",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "Eastern Provinces",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "Maldives",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "pest",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "pest",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Chaaminda Ratnayake",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Marlon Ferreira",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "Exterminators ආරම්භයේ සිට හොඳම 1Q ලබා ගනී",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "පළිබෝධ කළමනාකරණය සහ පාරිසරික තාක්ෂණ විශේෂඥයින් වන Exterminators Plc., සමාගම ආරම්භයේ සිට 2022 අප්‍රේල් 1 සිට ජූනි 30 දක්වා කාලය තුළ හොඳම පළමු කාර්තුව අත්පත් කර ගෙන ඇති බව ඊයේ පැවසීය.",
        "ආදායම 26% කින් රු. මිලියන 30, දළ ලාභය 20% සිට රු. මිලියන 22.5 ක්, මෙහෙයුම් ලාභය 13% කින් රු. මිලියන 4.8 ක්, බදු පෙර ලාභය 84% කින් රු. මිලියන 6.7 ක සහය ඇතිව රු. මිලියන 2.2ක් මුල්‍ය ආදායම ලෙසත්, ශුද්ධ ලාභය 49% කින් රු. මිලියන 4.9 ක් වූ අතර විස්තීරණ ආදායම 991% කින් රු. 2023 මුල්‍ය වර්ෂයේ පළමු කාර්තුවේදී රුපියල් මිලියන 36 කි.",
        "පවතින අර්බුදය තුළ පවා 2023 මූල්‍ය වර්ෂයේ පළමු කාර්තුවේදී කොටසක ඉපැයීම් 12% කින් සහ කොටසක ශුද්ධ වත්කම් 27% කින් වැඩි විය. FY22 සඳහා මුළු ලාභාංශ ගෙවීම රු. කොටසකට 0.16, එනම් PAT හි 29.7% වන අතර, සමාගම විසින් අවසාන ලාභාංශ ගෙවීම රු. සැප්තැම්බර් මුල කොටසකට 0.07.",
        "Exterminators දැනට කොළඹ, මහනුවර සහ දඹුල්ල යන ප්‍රදේශවල ශාඛා තුනක් සමඟ ක්‍රියාත්මක වේ. කොළඹ නගර මධ්‍යයේ ප්‍රමුඛතම පාරිභෝගික මධ්‍යස්ථානයක් පිහිටුවන අතරම අනාගත සංවර්ධනයේ විභව ක්ෂේත්‍ර තුළ අවස්ථා ග්‍රහණය කර ගැනීම සඳහා හම්බන්තොට, ගාල්ල සහ යාපනය යන ප්‍රදේශවල ශාඛා පිහිටුවීමෙන් සිය ජාලය පුළුල් කිරීමට සමාගම අපේක්ෂා කරයි. සමාගම උතුරු හා නැඟෙනහිර පළාත්වලට ද සිය ව්‍යාපාර බලය පැවරීමට නියමිතය. සමාගම මාලදිවයිනේ පළිබෝධ පාලන සේවා අවශ්‍ය බොහෝ විවේක අංශයේ ආයතන සමඟ අවස්ථා හඳුනාගෙන ඇත.",
        "“පළිබෝධ පාලන ක්ෂේත්‍රවලින් ඔබ්බට සිය සේවාවන් පුළුල් කරන පාරිසරික කළමනාකරණ සමාගමක් ලෙස අපි කර්මාන්තය තුළ අද්විතීය ස්ථානයක් කැටයම් කළෙමු. වර්ධනය ඉලක්ක කරගත් ව්‍යාපාරයක් ලෙස ගෝලීය ව්‍යාප්තියත් සමඟ දේශසීමා හරහා ගමන් කරමින් වෙළෙඳපොළ සංවර්ධන උපාය මාර්ග ගවේෂණය කිරීමට අපි බලාපොරොත්තු වෙනවා,” සභාපති චමින්ද රත්නායක මහතා පැවසීය.",
        "\"ව්‍යවසායකත්ව මානසිකත්වයකින් යුත් ක්‍රියාශීලී සමාගමක් ලෙස, අපි දිග හැරෙන සිදුවීම් වලට ධනාත්මක සහ ක්‍රියාශීලී ආකාරයකින් ප්‍රතිචාර දැක්වූවෙමු, අර්බුද වඩා හොඳ අනාගතයක් සඳහා පවතින තත්ත්වයට අභියෝග කිරීමට සහ වෙනස් කිරීමට අවස්ථාවන් නිර්මාණය කරන බව සැමවිටම මතක තබා ගනිමින්,\" කළමනාකාර අධ්‍යක්ෂ මාලන් ෆෙරේරා වැඩිදුරටත් පැවසීය."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "1Q",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "පළිබෝධ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Exterminators Plc",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඊයේ",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "හොඳම පළමු කාර්තුව",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "2022 අප්‍රේල් 1 සිට ජූනි 30 දක්වා",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "26%",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "මිලියන 30 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "20%",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "මිලියන 22.5 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "13%",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "මිලියන 4.8 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "84%",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "මිලියන 6.7 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "රුපියල්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "මිලියන 2.2 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "49%",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "මිලියන 4.9 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "991%",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "මිලියන 36 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "12%",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "27%",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "2023 මුදල් වර්ෂයේ 1Q",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "0.16",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "29.7%",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "PAT",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "රුපියල්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "0.07",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "සැප්තැම්බර් මුල",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "තුන්",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "කොළඹ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මහනුවර",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "දඹුල්ල",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "හම්බන්තොට",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගාල්ල",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "යාපනය",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "කොළඹ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "උතුරු",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "නැගෙනහිර පළාත්",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "මාලදිවයින",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "පලිබෝධ",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "පලිබෝධ",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "චාමින්ද රත්නායක",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "මාලන් ෆෙරේරා",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "Exterminators தொடக்கத்தில் இருந்து சிறந்த 1Q அடையும்",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "பூச்சி மேலாண்மை மற்றும் சுற்றுச்சூழல் தொழில்நுட்ப வல்லுநர்கள் எக்ஸ்டெர்மினேட்டர்ஸ் பிஎல்சி., நிறுவனம் தொடங்கப்பட்டதில் இருந்து 2022 ஏப்ரல் 1 முதல் ஜூன் 30 வரையிலான காலாண்டில் சிறந்த முதல் காலாண்டை எட்டியுள்ளதாக நேற்று தெரிவித்தனர்.",
        "வருவாய் 26% அதிகரித்து ரூ. 30 மில்லியன், மொத்த லாபம் 20% முதல் ரூ. 22.5 மில்லியன், இயக்க லாபம் 13% அதிகரித்து ரூ. 4.8 மில்லியன், வரிக்கு முந்தைய லாபம் 84% அதிகரித்து ரூ. 6.7 மில்லியன் ஆதரவுடன் ரூ. 2.2 மில்லியன் நிதி வருமானம், நிகர லாபம் 49% அதிகரித்து ரூ. 4.9 மில்லியன் மற்றும் விரிவான வருமானம் 991% ஆக ரூ. 2023 நிதியாண்டின் முதல் காலாண்டில் 36 மில்லியன்.",
        "2023 நிதியாண்டின் 1 காலாண்டில், நிலவும் நெருக்கடியின் போதும் ஒரு பங்கின் வருவாய் 12% அதிகரித்துள்ளது மற்றும் ஒரு பங்கின் நிகர சொத்துக்கள் 27% அதிகரித்துள்ளது. FY22க்கான மொத்த ஈவுத்தொகை ரூ. ஒரு பங்கிற்கு 0.16, இது PAT இன் 29.7% ஆகும், நிறுவனம் இறுதி டிவிடெண்ட் செலுத்தும் ரூ. செப்டம்பர் தொடக்கத்தில் ஒரு பங்குக்கு 0.07.",
        "Exterminators தற்போது கொழும்பு, கண்டி மற்றும் தம்புள்ளையில் மூன்று கிளைகளுடன் செயல்படுகிறது. கொழும்பின் மையத்தில் முதன்மையான வாடிக்கையாளர் மையத்தை அமைக்கும் அதே வேளையில், எதிர்கால வளர்ச்சிக்கான வாய்ப்புகளைப் பெறுவதற்கு ஹம்பாந்தோட்டை, காலி மற்றும் யாழ்ப்பாணத்தில் கிளைகளை அமைப்பதன் மூலம் நிறுவனம் தனது வலையமைப்பை விரிவுபடுத்துவதை நோக்கமாகக் கொண்டுள்ளது. நிறுவனம் தனது வர்த்தகத்தை வடக்கு மற்றும் கிழக்கு மாகாணங்களுக்கும் உரிமையாக்கும். நிறுவனம் மாலத்தீவில் பூச்சி கட்டுப்பாடு சேவைகள் தேவைப்படும் பல ஓய்வு துறை நிறுவனங்களுடன் வாய்ப்புகளை அடையாளம் கண்டுள்ளது.",
        "\"சுற்றுச்சூழல் மேலாண்மை நிறுவனமாக தொழில்துறையில் ஒரு தனித்துவமான இடத்தை நாங்கள் செதுக்கினோம், இது பூச்சி கட்டுப்பாடு பகுதிகளுக்கு அப்பால் அதன் சேவைகளை விரிவுபடுத்துகிறது. ஒரு வளர்ச்சி சார்ந்த வணிகமாக, உலகளாவிய விரிவாக்கத்துடன் எல்லைகளைத் தாண்டிச் செல்வதன் மூலம் சந்தை மேம்பாட்டு உத்திகளை ஆராய்வோம் என்று நாங்கள் நம்புகிறோம், ”என்று தலைவர் சமிந்த ரத்நாயக்க கூறினார்.",
        "\"தொழில் முனைவோர் மனப்பான்மை கொண்ட ஒரு செயலூக்கமுள்ள நிறுவனமாக, வெளிவரும் நிகழ்வுகளுக்கு நேர்மறையான மற்றும் செயலூக்கமான முறையில் நாங்கள் எதிர்வினையாற்றினோம், நெருக்கடிகள் ஒரு சிறந்த எதிர்காலத்திற்கான நிலைமையை சவால் செய்வதற்கும் மாற்றுவதற்கும் வாய்ப்புகளை உருவாக்குகின்றன என்பதை எப்போதும் நினைவில் கொள்கிறோம்,\" என்று நிர்வாக இயக்குனர் மார்லன் ஃபெரீரா கூறினார்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "1Q",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "பூச்சி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Exterminators Plc",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "நேற்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சிறந்த முதல் காலாண்டு",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "1 ஏப்ரல் முதல் 30 ஜூன் 2022 வரை",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "26%",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "30 மில்லியன்",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "20%",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "22.5 மில்லியன்",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "13%",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "4.8 மில்லியன்",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "84%",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "6.7 மில்லியன்",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரூ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "2.2 மில்லியன்",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "49%",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "4.9 மில்லியன்",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "991%",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "36 மில்லியன்",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "12%",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "27%",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "2023 நிதியாண்டின் 1Q",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "0.16",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "29.7%",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "PAT",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரூ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "0.07",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "செப்டம்பர் தொடக்கத்தில்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "மூன்று",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "கொழும்பு",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "கண்டி",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "தம்புள்ளை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஹம்பாந்தோட்டை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "காலி",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "யாழ்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "கொழும்பு",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "வடக்கு",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "கிழக்கு மாகாணங்கள்",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "மாலத்தீவுகள்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "பூச்சி",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பூச்சி",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "சமிந்த ரத்நாயக்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "மார்லன் ஃபெரீரா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}