{
  "newspaper_id": "economy-next-com",
  "url": "https://economynext.com/sri-lanka-kerosene-price-hike-finmin-to-identify-recipients-of-cash-transfer-proposed-by-president-98864/",
  "time_ut": 1661158080,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Sri Lanka kerosene price hike: FinMin to identify recipients of cash transfer proposed by president",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Sri Lanka kerosene price hike: FinMin to identify recipients of cash transfer proposed by president",
      "author": "",
      "body_lines": [
        "ECONOMYNEXT – A government decision proposed by President Ranil Wickremesinghe to make direct cash transfers to vulnerable groups affected by Sri Lanka’s record kerosene price hike will see line ministries working with the Ministry of Finance to identify deserving recipients, according to Power & Energy Minister Kanchana Wijesekara.",
        "In a response to a request raised by opposition MP Mano Gansena, Wijesekara tweeted Monday August 22 afternoon that the proposal to pay direct cash subsidies to low income families, fisherfolk and plantation workers was made by President Wickremesinghe when price revisions were discussed.",
        "Hon MP, it was not my decision to grant direct cash allowances. It was proposed by the President when the pricing revisions was discussed. The line ministries will have to work with the Finance ministry to identify the low income families & sectors that will need the cash grant.",
        "The minister made the cash transfer announcement Monday morning, following an overnight price hike of kerosene by a record 290 percent, with the price going up from  87 rupees per litre to 340 rupees per litre.",
        "Sri Lanka to make cash transfers to the those hit hard by record kerosene price hike",
        "Kerosene was out of stock in the market as Sri Lanka’s sole oil refinery that produced kerosene remained shut due to a shortage of crude oil shipments.",
        "The ministry announced on Saturday that the refinery will be run for at least 40 days as it has purchased two consignments of Russian crude oil.",
        "Fishermen in many coastal areas have been protesting for some days  demanding a solution to the fuel crisis despite the island having managed its fuel queues via a QR code ration system. (Colombo/Aug22/2022)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Sri Lanka",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka’s",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Ministry of Finance",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Power & Energy",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kanchana Wijesekara",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Mano Gansena",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Wijesekara",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Monday August 22 afternoon",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the Finance ministry",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Monday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "morning",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "290 percent",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "87",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "340",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Saturday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "at least 40 days",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "two",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Russian",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "some days",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ භූමිතෙල් මිල ඉහළ නැංවීම: ජනාධිපතිවරයා විසින් යෝජනා කරන ලද මුදල් හුවමාරු ලබන්නන් හඳුනා ගැනීමට FinMin",
      "author": "",
      "body_lines": [
        "ECONOMYNEXT - ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ වාර්තාගත භූමිතෙල් මිල ඉහළ යාමෙන් පීඩාවට පත් වූ අවදානම් කණ්ඩායම් වෙත සෘජු මුදල් හුවමාරු කිරීමට ජනාධිපති රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතා විසින් යෝජනා කරන ලද රජයේ තීරණයකට අනුව සුදුසුකම් ලත් ප්‍රතිලාභීන් හඳුනා ගැනීම සඳහා රේඛීය අමාත්‍යාංශ මුදල් අමාත්‍යාංශය සමඟ කටයුතු කරන බව විදුලිබල හා බලශක්ති අමාත්‍ය කංචන විජේසේකර පවසයි.",
        "විපක්ෂයේ පාර්ලිමේන්තු මන්ත්‍රී මනෝ ගන්සේන විසින් මතු කරන ලද ඉල්ලීමකට ප්‍රතිචාර වශයෙන් විජේසේකර අගෝස්තු 22 සඳුදා පස්වරුවේ ට්විටර් පණිවුඩයක් නිකුත් කරමින් කියා සිටියේ අඩු ආදායම්ලාභී පවුල්, ධීවරයින් සහ වතු කම්කරුවන් සඳහා සෘජු මුදල් සහනාධාරය ලබාදීමේ යෝජනාව මිල සංශෝධන සාකච්ඡා කළ අවස්ථාවේ දී ජනාධිපති වික්‍රමසිංහ විසින් කරන ලද බවයි.",
        "ගරු මන්ත්‍රීතුමනි, සෘජු මුදල් දීමනා ලබාදීම මගේ තීරණයක් නොවේ. මිල සංශෝධන සම්බන්ධයෙන් සාකච්ඡා කළ අවස්ථාවේදී ජනාධිපතිවරයා එය යෝජනා කළා. මුදල් ප්‍රදානය අවශ්‍ය අඩු ආදායම්ලාභී පවුල් සහ අංශ හඳුනා ගැනීමට රේඛීය අමාත්‍යාංශවලට මුදල් අමාත්‍යාංශය සමඟ කටයුතු කිරීමට සිදුවේ.",
        "අමාත්‍යවරයා සඳුදා උදෑසන භූමිතෙල් මිල වාර්තාගත සියයට 290 කින් ඉහළ දැමීමෙන් අනතුරුව, සඳුදා උදෑසන මුදල් හුවමාරු කිරීමේ නිවේදනය සිදු කළේ, ලීටරයක මිල රුපියල් 87 සිට රුපියල් 340 දක්වා ඉහළ යාමත් සමඟ ය.",
        "වාර්තාගත භූමිතෙල් මිල ඉහළ යාමෙන් දැඩි ලෙස පීඩාවට පත් වූවන්ට මුදල් හුවමාරු කිරීමට ශ්‍රී ලංකාව",
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ භූමිතෙල් නිෂ්පාදනය කරන එකම තෙල් පිරිපහදුව බොරතෙල් නැව්ගත කිරීම් හිඟයක් හේතුවෙන් වසා දමා තිබීම නිසා භූමිතෙල් වෙළඳපොලේ තොග අවසන් විය.",
        "රුසියානු බොරතෙල් තොග දෙකක් මිලදී ගෙන ඇති බැවින් පිරිපහදුව අවම වශයෙන් දින 40 ක කාලයක් පවත්වාගෙන යන බව අමාත්‍යාංශය සෙනසුරාදා නිවේදනය කළේය.",
        "QR කේත සලාක ක්‍රමයක් හරහා දිවයිනේ ඉන්ධන පෝලිම් කළමනාකරණය කර තිබියදීත් ඉන්ධන අර්බුදයට විසඳුම් ඉල්ලා බොහෝ වෙරළබඩ ප්‍රදේශවල ධීවරයින් දින කිහිපයක් තිස්සේ විරෝධතා පවත්වයි. (කොළඹ/අගෝස්තු 22/2022)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මුදල් අමාත්යාංශය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "බලය සහ බලශක්තිය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "කාංචන විජේසේකර",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Mano Gansena",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "විජේසේකර",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "අගෝස්තු 22 සඳුදා සවස",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "මුදල් අමාත්යාංශය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "සඳුදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "උදෑසන",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "සියයට 290 කි",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "87",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "340",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "සෙනසුරාදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "අවම වශයෙන් දින 40 ක්",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "දෙක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "රුසියානු",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "සමහර දවස්",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "இலங்கை மண்ணெண்ணெய் விலை உயர்வு: ஜனாதிபதியால் முன்மொழியப்பட்ட பணப் பரிமாற்றத்தைப் பெறுபவர்களை அடையாளம் காண FinMin",
      "author": "",
      "body_lines": [
        "பொருளாதாரம் - இலங்கையின் மண்ணெண்ணெய் விலை உயர்வால் பாதிக்கப்பட்டுள்ள பாதிப்புக்குள்ளான குழுக்களுக்கு நேரடி பணப்பரிமாற்றம் செய்ய ஜனாதிபதி ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க முன்மொழிந்த அரசாங்கத் தீர்மானம், நிதியமைச்சுடன் இணைந்து நிதியமைச்சுடன் இணைந்து செயற்படும் என மின்சக்தி மற்றும் எரிசக்தி அமைச்சர் காஞ்சனா விஜேசேகர தெரிவித்துள்ளார்.",
        "எதிர்க்கட்சி பாராளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர் மனோ கன்சேன எழுப்பிய கோரிக்கைக்கு பதிலளிக்கும் வகையில், ஆகஸ்ட் 22 திங்கட்கிழமை பிற்பகல் விஜேசேகர ட்வீட் செய்துள்ளார், குறைந்த வருமானம் பெறும் குடும்பங்கள், மீனவர்கள் மற்றும் தோட்டத் தொழிலாளர்களுக்கு நேரடி பண மானியங்களை வழங்குவதற்கான முன்மொழிவு விலை திருத்தங்கள் விவாதிக்கப்பட்டபோது ஜனாதிபதி விக்கிரமசிங்கவினால் முன்வைக்கப்பட்டது.",
        "மாண்புமிகு எம்.பி அவர்களே, நேரடி பணப் படிகள் வழங்குவது எனது முடிவு அல்ல. விலை நிர்ணயம் தொடர்பில் கலந்துரையாடப்பட்ட போது ஜனாதிபதியினால் இது முன்மொழியப்பட்டது. குறைந்த வருமானம் கொண்ட குடும்பங்கள் மற்றும் ரொக்க மானியம் தேவைப்படும் துறைகளை அடையாளம் காண மத்திய அமைச்சகங்கள் நிதி அமைச்சகத்துடன் இணைந்து செயல்பட வேண்டும்.",
        "ஒரே இரவில் மண்ணெண்ணெய் விலை 290 சதவீதம் உயர்ந்ததைத் தொடர்ந்து, திங்கள்கிழமை காலை அமைச்சர் பணப் பரிமாற்ற அறிவிப்பை வெளியிட்டார்.",
        "இலங்கை மண்ணெண்ணெய் விலை உயர்வால் கடுமையாக பாதிக்கப்பட்டவர்களுக்கு பணப்பரிமாற்றம் செய்ய வேண்டும்",
        "மண்ணெண்ணெய் உற்பத்தி செய்யும் இலங்கையின் ஒரேயொரு எண்ணெய் சுத்திகரிப்பு நிலையம் கச்சா எண்ணெய் ஏற்றுமதியின் பற்றாக்குறை காரணமாக மூடப்பட்டிருந்ததால் சந்தையில் மண்ணெண்ணெய் இருப்பு இல்லை.",
        "ரஷ்ய கச்சா எண்ணெய் இரண்டு சரக்குகளை வாங்கியதால், சுத்திகரிப்பு நிலையம் குறைந்தது 40 நாட்களுக்கு இயக்கப்படும் என்று அமைச்சகம் சனிக்கிழமை அறிவித்தது.",
        "தீவு தனது எரிபொருள் வரிசையை QR குறியீடு ரேஷன் முறை மூலம் நிர்வகித்த போதிலும், பல கடலோரப் பகுதிகளில் உள்ள மீனவர்கள் எரிபொருள் நெருக்கடிக்குத் தீர்வு காணக் கோரி சில நாட்களாகப் போராட்டம் நடத்தி வருகின்றனர். (கொழும்பு/ஆகஸ்ட்22/2022)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "இலங்கை",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கையின்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "நிதி அமைச்சகம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "சக்தி மற்றும் ஆற்றல்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "காஞ்சனா விஜேசேகர",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Mano Gansena",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "விஜேசேகர",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆகஸ்ட் 22 திங்கள் மதியம்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "நிதி அமைச்சகம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "திங்கட்கிழமை",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "காலை",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "290 சதவீதம்",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "87",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "340",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "சனிக்கிழமை",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "குறைந்தது 40 நாட்கள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இரண்டு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரஷ்யன்",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "சில நாட்கள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}