{
  "newspaper_id": "ada-derana-lk",
  "url": "http://www.adaderana.lk/news/84343/undco-regional-director-for-asia-pacific-arrives-in-sri-lanka",
  "time_ut": 1660658520,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "UNDCO Regional Director for Asia-Pacific arrives in Sri Lanka",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "UNDCO Regional Director for Asia-Pacific arrives in Sri Lanka",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "Regional Director for Asia-Pacific from the United Nations Development Coordination Office (UNDCO) David McLachlan-Karr arrived in Sri Lanka today (16 August).",
        "McLachlan-Karr is scheduled to meet with Government, the Opposition, civil society, the diplomatic community and others. He will also travel to Jaffna to meet with government and civil society groups there.",
        "His discussions with officials in Sri Lanka will focus on the launch of the United Nations Sustainable Development Cooperation Framework (UNSDCF) 2023-2027 which will guide the work of all UN Agencies in Sri Lanka over the next five years.",
        "The Development Coordination Office’s objective is to support the capacity, effectiveness and efficiency of Resident Coordinators and the UN development system as a whole in support of national efforts for sustainable development.",
        "The UN in Sri Lanka said Mr. McLachlan-Karr will meet with government, opposition, civil society and others in Colombo and Jaffna to discuss how the UN can support all Sri Lankans to recover from the Economic Crisis through a joint programme of work over the next 5 years."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Asia-Pacific",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "Sri Lanka",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Asia-Pacific",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the United Nations Development Coordination Office",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "David McLachlan-Karr",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "16 August",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "McLachlan-Karr",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Opposition",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Jaffna",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the United Nations Sustainable Development Cooperation Framework",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "UNSDCF",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "2023-2027",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "all UN Agencies in Sri Lanka",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the next five years",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "The Development Coordination Office’s",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Resident Coordinators",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "UN",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "UN",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "McLachlan-Karr",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Colombo",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Jaffna",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "UN",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lankans",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Economic Crisis",
            "label": "EVENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "the next 5 years",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "UNDCO ආසියා පැසිෆික් කලාපීය අධ්‍යක්ෂ ශ්‍රී ලංකාවට පැමිණේ",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "එක්සත් ජාතීන්ගේ සංවර්ධන සම්බන්ධීකරණ කාර්යාලයේ (UNDCO) ආසියා-පැසිෆික් කලාපීය අධ්‍යක්ෂ ඩේවිඩ් මැක්ලච්ලන්-කාර් මහතා අද (අගෝස්තු 16) ශ්‍රී ලංකාවට පැමිණියේය.",
        "McLachlan-Karr රජය, විපක්ෂය, සිවිල් සමාජය, රාජ්‍යතාන්ත්‍රික ප්‍රජාව සහ වෙනත් අය හමුවීමට නියමිතය. ඔහු යාපනයට ගොස් රජයේ සහ සිවිල් සමාජ කණ්ඩායම් හමුවීමට ද නියමිතය.",
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ නිලධාරීන් සමඟ ඔහුගේ සාකච්ඡා ඉදිරි වසර පහ තුළ ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ සියලුම එක්සත් ජාතීන්ගේ නියෝජිතායතනවල කටයුතු මෙහෙයවනු ලබන එක්සත් ජාතීන්ගේ තිරසාර සංවර්ධන සහයෝගීතා රාමුව (UNSDCF) 2023-2027 දියත් කිරීම කෙරෙහි අවධානය යොමු කරනු ඇත.",
        "සංවර්ධන සම්බන්ධීකරණ කාර්යාලයේ පරමාර්ථය වන්නේ තිරසාර සංවර්ධනය සඳහා වන ජාතික ප්‍රයත්නයන්ට සහාය වීම සඳහා නේවාසික සම්බන්ධීකාරකවරුන්ගේ සහ සමස්තයක් ලෙස එක්සත් ජාතීන්ගේ සංවර්ධන පද්ධතියෙහි ධාරිතාව, කාර්යක්ෂමතාව සහ කාර්යක්ෂමතාවයට සහාය වීමයි.",
        "McLachlan-Karr මහතා රජය, විපක්ෂය, සිවිල් සමාජය සහ අනෙකුත් අය සමඟ කොළඹ සහ යාපනයේදී හමුවී ඒකාබද්ධ වැඩපිළිවෙලක් හරහා ආර්ථික අර්බුදයෙන් ගොඩ ඒමට එක්සත් ජාතීන්ගේ සංවිධානයට සහාය විය හැකි ආකාරය පිළිබඳව සාකච්ඡා කරන බව ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ එක්සත් ජාතීන්ගේ සංවිධානය පවසයි. ඉදිරි වසර 5."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ආසියා-පැසිෆික්",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ආසියා-පැසිෆික්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "එක්සත් ජාතීන්ගේ සංවර්ධන සම්බන්ධීකරණ කාර්යාලය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඩේවිඩ් මැක්ලච්ලන්-කාර්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "අගෝස්තු 16",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "මැක්ලච්ලන්-කාර්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "විපක්ෂ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "යාපනය",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "එක්සත් ජාතීන්ගේ තිරසාර සංවර්ධන සහයෝගීතා රාමුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "UNSDCF",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "2023-2027",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ සියලුම එක්සත් ජාතීන්ගේ නියෝජිතායතන",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉදිරි වසර පහ",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "සංවර්ධන සම්බන්ධීකරණ කාර්යාලය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "නේවාසික සම්බන්ධීකාරකවරුන්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "එක්සත් ජාතීන්ගේ සංවිධානය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "එක්සත් ජාතීන්ගේ සංවිධානය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මැක්ලච්ලන්-කාර්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "කොළඹ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "යාපනය",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "එක්සත් ජාතීන්ගේ සංවිධානය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලාංකිකයන්",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ආර්ථික අර්බුදය",
            "label": "EVENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉදිරි වසර 5",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "UNDCO ஆசிய பசுபிக் பிராந்திய பணிப்பாளர் இலங்கை வந்தடைந்தார்",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "ஐக்கிய நாடுகளின் அபிவிருத்தி ஒருங்கிணைப்பு அலுவலகத்தின் (UNDCO) ஆசிய-பசிபிக் பிராந்தியப் பணிப்பாளர் டேவிட் மெக்லாக்லன்-கார் இன்று (ஆகஸ்ட் 16) இலங்கை வந்தடைந்தார்.",
        "McLachlan-Karr, அரசாங்கம், எதிர்க்கட்சி, சிவில் சமூகம், இராஜதந்திர சமூகம் மற்றும் பிறரை சந்திக்க திட்டமிடப்பட்டுள்ளது. மேலும் அவர் யாழ்ப்பாணம் சென்று அங்குள்ள அரசு மற்றும் சிவில் சமூக குழுக்களை சந்திப்பார்.",
        "இலங்கையில் உள்ள அதிகாரிகளுடனான அவரது கலந்துரையாடல் ஐக்கிய நாடுகளின் நிலையான அபிவிருத்தி ஒத்துழைப்பு கட்டமைப்பை (UNSDCF) 2023-2027 தொடக்கத்தில் கவனம் செலுத்தும், இது அடுத்த ஐந்து ஆண்டுகளில் இலங்கையில் உள்ள அனைத்து ஐ.நா முகவர் நிறுவனங்களின் பணிகளையும் வழிநடத்தும்.",
        "நிலையான வளர்ச்சிக்கான தேசிய முயற்சிகளுக்கு ஆதரவாக வதிவிட ஒருங்கிணைப்பாளர்கள் மற்றும் ஒட்டுமொத்த ஐ.நா. வளர்ச்சி அமைப்புகளின் திறன், செயல்திறன் மற்றும் செயல்திறனை ஆதரிப்பதே மேம்பாட்டு ஒருங்கிணைப்பு அலுவலகத்தின் நோக்கமாகும்.",
        "இலங்கையில் உள்ள ஐ.நா., அரசாங்கம், எதிர்க்கட்சி, சிவில் சமூகம் மற்றும் பிறரை கொழும்பு மற்றும் யாழ்ப்பாணத்தில் சந்தித்து, பொருளாதார நெருக்கடியில் இருந்து மீள்வதற்கு ஐ.நா. அனைத்து இலங்கையர்களுக்கும் ஒரு கூட்டு வேலைத்திட்டத்தின் மூலம் எவ்வாறு ஆதரவளிக்க முடியும் என்பது குறித்து விவாதிக்கவுள்ளதாக இலங்கையில் உள்ள ஐ.நா. அடுத்த 5 ஆண்டுகள்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ஆசிய பசிபிக்",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "இலங்கை",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ஆசிய பசிபிக்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஐக்கிய நாடுகளின் வளர்ச்சி ஒருங்கிணைப்பு அலுவலகம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "டேவிட் மெக்லாக்லன்-கார்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "16 ஆகஸ்ட்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "மெக்லாக்லன்-கார்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "எதிர்ப்பு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "யாழ்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஐக்கிய நாடுகளின் நிலையான வளர்ச்சி ஒத்துழைப்பு கட்டமைப்பு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "UNSDCF",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "2023-2027",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கையில் உள்ள அனைத்து ஐ.நா",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "அடுத்த ஐந்து ஆண்டுகள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "அபிவிருத்தி ஒருங்கிணைப்பு அலுவலகம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "குடியுரிமை ஒருங்கிணைப்பாளர்கள்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஐ.நா",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஐ.நா",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "மெக்லாக்லன்-கார்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "கொழும்பு",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "யாழ்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஐ.நா",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கையர்கள்",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "பொருளாதார நெருக்கடி",
            "label": "EVENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "அடுத்த 5 ஆண்டுகள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}