{
  "newspaper_id": "lankadeepa-lk",
  "url": "https://www.lankadeepa.lk/news/සනත්-අධිකරණයට-අපහාස-කළැයි-නිතීඥ-ප්‍රියලාල්ගෙන්-පෙත්සමක්/101-618960",
  "time_ut": 1661774479,
  "original_lang": "si",
  "original_title": "සනත් අධිකරණයට අපහාස කළැයි නිතීඥ ප්‍රියලාල්ගෙන් පෙත්සමක්",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Petition from lawyer Priyalal that Sanath insulted the court",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "Lawyer Priyalal Sirisena has filed a petition in the Supreme Court today (29) requesting that a hearing be held and appropriate steps be taken regarding the statement that MP Sanath Nishantha insulted the court during a news conference held at the Sri Lanka Podujana Peramuna party headquarters.",
        "The respondents in this petition are the Member of Parliament Sanath Nishantha, the Sri Lanka Bar Association and the Governor.",
        "The first respondent of this petition is a suspect in the case pending in the Fort Magistrate's Court regarding the attack on the Galle Mudoora protest site on May 9th, and the petitioner has also stated in his petition that he has been accused of criminal incidents before.",
        "In his petition, the first respondent MP, who participated in a press conference held at the Sri Lanka Podujana Peramuna party office on the 23rd, made statements in a way that insulted the court and the entire judicial system was insulted by this."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Priyalal",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "the Supreme Court",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "29",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sanath Nishantha",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "Podujana Peramuna",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Parliament Sanath Nishantha",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Sri Lanka Bar Association",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "first",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Fort Magistrate's",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Court",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Galle Mudoora",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "May 9th",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "first",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "Podujana Peramuna",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the 23rd",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "සනත් අධිකරණයට අපහාස කළැයි නිතීඥ ප්‍රියලාල්ගෙන් පෙත්සමක්",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකා පොදු ජන පෙරමුණු පක්ෂ මූලස්ථානයේ පැවැති ප්‍රවෘත්ති සාකච්ඡාවකදී පාර්ලිමේන්තු මන්ත්‍රී සනත් නිශාන්ත මහතා අධිකරණයට අපහාස වන අයුරින් සිදුකළායැයි කියන ප්‍රකාශය සම්බන්ධයෙන් විභාගයක් පවත්වා සුදුසු පියවරක් ගන්නා ලෙසට ඉල්ලා ඉල්ලමින් නිතීඥ ප්‍රියලාල් සිරිසේන මහතා ශ්‍රේෂ්ඨාධිකරණයට අද (29) පෙත්සමක් ගොනුකරනු ලැබ ඇත.",
        "මෙම පෙත්සමේ වගඋත්තරකරුවන් ලෙස නම්කර ඇත්තේ පාර්ලිමේන්තු මන්ත්‍රී සනත් නිශාන්ත, ශ්‍රී ලංකා නිතීඥ සංගමය සහ නිතිපතිවරයා ය.",
        "මෙම පෙත්සමේ පළමු වගඋත්තරකරු ඉකුත් මැයි මස 09 වන දින ගාලු මුවදොර අරගල භූමියට පහරදීමේ සිද්ධිය සම්බන්ධයෙන් කොටුව මහේස්ත්‍රාත් අධිකරණයේ විභාග වන නඩුවේ සැකකරුවකු වන අතර, මීට පෙරද අපරාධ සිද්ධීන් සම්බන්ධයෙන් චෝදනා එල්ලවී ඇති අයකු බව ද පෙත්සම්කරු සිය පෙත්සමේ සදහන් කර ඇත.",
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකා පොදු ජන පෙරමුණු පක්ෂ කාර්යාලයේදී ඉකුත් 23 වැනිදා පැවැත්වූ මාධ්‍ය සාකච්ඡාවකට සහභාගී වූ මෙහි පළමු වගඋත්තර පාර්ලිමේන්තු මන්ත්‍රිවරයා අධිකරණයට අපහාස වන අයුරින් කරුණු දක්වනු ලැබූ බවත් මෙමගින් සමස්ථ අධිකරණ පද්ධතියටම අපහාසයක් සිදුව ඇති බවත් පැමිණීලිකාර නිතීඥවරයා සිය පෙත්සමෙන් කරුණු ඉදිරිපත් කර තිබේ."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ප්‍රියලාල්",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රේෂ්ඨාධිකරණය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "29",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "සනත් නිශාන්ත",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "පොදුජන පෙරමුණ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තු සනත් නිශාන්ත",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකා නීතිඥ සංගමය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "පළමුවන",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "කොටුව මහේස්ත්‍රාත්වරයාගේ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "අධිකරණය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගාල්ල මුදූර",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "මැයි 9 වැනිදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "පළමුවන",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "පොදුජන පෙරමුණ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "23 වැනි",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "சனத் நீதிமன்றத்தை அவமதித்ததாக வழக்கறிஞர் பிரியலால் மனு",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "ஸ்ரீலங்கா பொதுஜன பெரமுன கட்சியின் தலைமையகத்தில் நடைபெற்ற செய்தியாளர் சந்திப்பின் போது நாடாளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர் சனத் நிஷாந்த நீதிமன்றத்தை அவமதித்ததாக தெரிவித்த கருத்து தொடர்பில் விசாரணை நடத்தி உரிய நடவடிக்கை எடுக்குமாறு கோரி சட்டத்தரணி பிரியலால் சிறிசேன இன்று (29) உச்ச நீதிமன்றத்தில் மனுவொன்றை தாக்கல் செய்துள்ளார்.",
        "இந்த மனுவில் பிரதிவாதிகளாக பாராளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர் சனத் நிஷாந்த, இலங்கை சட்டத்தரணிகள் சங்கம் மற்றும் ஆளுநர் ஆகியோர் ஆவர்.",
        "இந்த மனுவின் முதலாவது பிரதிவாதியானது கடந்த மே மாதம் 9ஆம் திகதி காலி மூதூர போராட்டத் தளத்தின் மீதான தாக்குதல் தொடர்பில் கோட்டை நீதவான் நீதிமன்றத்தில் நிலுவையில் உள்ள வழக்கின் சந்தேக நபர் எனவும், இதற்கு முன்னரும் குற்றச் சம்பவங்களில் ஈடுபட்டதாக மனுதாரர் தனது மனுவில் குறிப்பிட்டுள்ளார்.",
        "ஶ்ரீலங்கா பொதுஜன பெரமுன கட்சி அலுவலகத்தில் கடந்த 23ஆம் திகதி நடைபெற்ற ஊடகவியலாளர் சந்திப்பில் கலந்து கொண்ட முதலாவது பிரதிவாதி எம்.பி., தனது மனுவில் நீதிமன்றத்தை அவமதிக்கும் வகையிலும், இதன் மூலம் ஒட்டுமொத்த நீதித்துறை அமைப்புக்கும் அவமானம் ஏற்படும் வகையிலும் கருத்து வெளியிட்டார்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ப்ரியாலால்",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "உச்ச நீதிமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "29",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "சனத் நிஷாந்த",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "பொதுஜன பெரமுன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம் சனத் நிஷாந்த",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை சட்டத்தரணிகள் சங்கம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "முதலில்",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "கோட்டை மாஜிஸ்திரேட்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "நீதிமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "காலி முதூரா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "மே 9 ஆம் தேதி",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "முதலில்",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "பொதுஜன பெரமுன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "23 ஆம் தேதி",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}