{
  "newspaper_id": "economy-next-com",
  "url": "https://economynext.com/sri-lanka-main-opposition-ready-to-take-presidency-premiership-sjb-leader-sajith-premadasa-97247/",
  "time_ut": 1657531860,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Sri Lanka main opposition ready to take presidency, premiership: SJB leader Sajith Premadasa",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Sri Lanka main opposition ready to take presidency, premiership: SJB leader Sajith Premadasa",
      "author": "",
      "body_lines": [
        "ECONOMYNEXT – Sri Lanka’s main opposition the Samagi Jana Balavegaya (SJB) is ready to lead the country at the presidential and prime ministerial level and develop the economy, opposition and SJB leader Sajith Premadasa said.",
        "In a video statement released on the SJB’s social media channels Monday July 11 afternoon, Premadasa said his party is ready to lead a programme aimed at bringing stability to the country.",
        "“We will appoint a government headed by a president and a prime minister. There is no other alternative. If anyone opposes this or tries to sabotage it in parliament we will see it as a treacherous act,” he said.",
        "“We’re ready to protect the motherland, to give leadership to the motherland, to build the economy,” he added.",
        "In his statement, Premadasa also recognised the people’s protests, known as the ‘aragalaya’ (struggle), that has all but seen ouster of President Gotabaya Rajapaksa.",
        "“Victory to the motherland, victory to the people, victory to the aragalaya,” he said.",
        "ආණ්ඩුවේ ජනවරම අවසන්! අලුත් ආණ්ඩුව හදන්න සමගි ජන බලවේගය සූදානම්. pic.twitter.com/0bdvnviRav",
        "President Rajapaksa has yet to formally resign. According to the prime minister’s office, Rajapaksa has officially communicated to Prime Minister Ranil Wickremesinghe that he will resign on Wednesday July 13 as previously announced. However, a statement from the president’s office later said that only the Speaker of Parliament can release statements from the president. (Colombo/Jul11/2022)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Sri Lanka",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "SJB",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "Sajith Premadasa",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "the Samagi Jana Balavegaya",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "SJB",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sajith Premadasa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Monday July 11",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Premadasa",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "Premadasa",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the ‘aragalaya",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Gotabaya Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "ආණ්ඩුවේ",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Wednesday July 13",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Colombo/Jul11/2022",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ ප්‍රධාන විපක්ෂය ජනාධිපතිකම, අගමැතිකම ගන්න සූදානම්: SJB නායක සජිත් ප්‍රේමදාස",
      "author": "",
      "body_lines": [
        "ECONOMYNEXT - ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ ප්‍රධාන විපක්ෂය වන සමගි ජන බලවේගය (SJB) ජනාධිපති සහ අගමැති මට්ටමින් රට මෙහෙයවීමට සහ ආර්ථිකය, විපක්ෂය සහ SJB නායක සජිත් ප්‍රේමදාස මහතා රට සංවර්ධනය කිරීමට සූදානම් බව පැවසීය.",
        "ජුලි 11 සඳුදා පස්වරුවේ SJB සමාජ මාධ්‍ය නාලිකා ඔස්සේ වීඩියෝ ප්‍රකාශයක් නිකුත් කරමින් ප්‍රේමදාස කියා සිටියේ රට ස්ථාවරභාවයක් ගෙන ඒම ඉලක්ක කරගත් වැඩසටහනකට නායකත්වය දීමට තම පක්ෂය සූදානම් බවයි.",
        "“අපි ජනාධිපතිවරයෙකුගේ සහ අගමැතිවරයෙකුගේ ප්‍රධානත්වයෙන් ආණ්ඩුවක් පත් කරනවා. වෙනත් විකල්පයක් නැත. කවුරුහරි මේකට විරුද්ධ වුණොත් හෝ පාර්ලිමේන්තුව තුළ කඩාකප්පල් කරන්න හදනවා නම් අපි එය දකින්නේ ද්‍රෝහී ක්‍රියාවක් ලෙසයි.",
        "\"මව්බිම සුරැකීමට, මාතෘභූමියට නායකත්වය දීමට, ආර්ථිකය ගොඩනැගීමට අපි සූදානම්,\" ඔහු වැඩිදුරටත් පැවසීය.",
        "ප්‍රේමදාස සිය ප්‍රකාශයේ දී, ජනාධිපති ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ බලයෙන් පහ කිරීම හැර අන් සියල්ලටම වඩා දැක ඇති ‘අරගලය’ (අරගලය) නමින් හැඳින්වෙන ජනතා විරෝධතා ද හඳුනා ගත්තේය.",
        "\"මව්බිමට ජය, ජනතාවට ජය, අරගලයට ජය\" ඔහු පැවසීය.",
        "ආණ්ඩුවේ ජනවරම අවසන්! අලුත් ආණ්ඩුව හදන්න සමග ජන බලවේගය සූදානම්. pic.twitter.com/0bdvnviRav",
        "ජනාධිපති රාජපක්ෂ තවමත් නිල වශයෙන් ඉල්ලා අස්වී නැත. අග්‍රාමාත්‍ය කාර්යාලයට අනුව රාජපක්ෂ මහතා කලින් ප්‍රකාශ කළ පරිදි ජූලි 13 බදාදා ඉල්ලා අස්වන බව අගමැති රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතාට නිල වශයෙන් දැනුම් දී තිබේ. කෙසේ වෙතත්, ජනාධිපතිවරයාගේ ප්‍රකාශ නිකුත් කළ හැක්කේ පාර්ලිමේන්තුවේ කථානායකවරයාට පමණක් බව ජනාධිපති කාර්යාලයෙන් පසුව නිවේදනයක් නිකුත් කර තිබේ. (කොළඹ/ජූලි11/2022)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "එස්.ජේ.බී",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "සජිත් ප්‍රේමදාස",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "සමගි ජන බලවේගය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "එස්.ජේ.බී",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "සජිත් ප්‍රේමදාස",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ජූලි 11 සඳුදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ප්‍රේමදාස ය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "ප්‍රේමදාස ය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "අරගලය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "ආණ්ඩුවේ",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජූලි 13 බදාදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "කොළඹ/ජූලි11/2022",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "இலங்கையின் பிரதான எதிர்க்கட்சி ஜனாதிபதி மற்றும் பிரதமர் பதவியை ஏற்க தயார்: SJB தலைவர் சஜித் பிரேமதாச",
      "author": "",
      "body_lines": [
        "பொருளாதாரம் - இலங்கையின் பிரதான எதிர்க்கட்சியான சமகி ஜன பலவேகய (SJB) ஜனாதிபதி மற்றும் பிரதமர் மட்டத்தில் நாட்டை வழிநடத்தவும், பொருளாதாரம், எதிர்க்கட்சி மற்றும் SJB தலைவர் சஜித் பிரேமதாசவை மேம்படுத்தவும் தயாராக உள்ளது.",
        "ஜூலை 11 திங்கட்கிழமை பிற்பகல் SJB இன் சமூக ஊடக சேனல்களில் வெளியிடப்பட்ட வீடியோ அறிக்கையில், நாட்டில் ஸ்திரத்தன்மையைக் கொண்டுவருவதை நோக்கமாகக் கொண்ட ஒரு வேலைத்திட்டத்தை வழிநடத்த தனது கட்சி தயாராக இருப்பதாக பிரேமதாச கூறினார்.",
        "“நாங்கள் ஜனாதிபதி மற்றும் பிரதமர் தலைமையில் அரசாங்கத்தை நியமிப்போம். வேறு மாற்று இல்லை. இதை யாராவது எதிர்த்தாலோ அல்லது நாடாளுமன்றத்தில் நாசவேலை செய்ய முயற்சித்தாலோ அதை துரோகச் செயலாகவே பார்க்கிறோம்,'' என்றார்.",
        "தாய்நாட்டைப் பாதுகாக்கவும், தாய்நாட்டிற்கு தலைமைத்துவத்தை வழங்கவும், பொருளாதாரத்தை கட்டியெழுப்பவும் நாங்கள் தயாராக உள்ளோம் என அவர் மேலும் தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "பிரேமதாச தனது அறிக்கையில், ஜனாதிபதி கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ஷவை வெளியேற்றுவதைத் தவிர, ‘அரகலயா’ (போராட்டம்) எனப்படும் மக்கள் போராட்டங்களையும் அங்கீகரித்தார்.",
        "\"தாய்நாட்டிற்கு வெற்றி, மக்களுக்கு வெற்றி, அரகலயத்திற்கு வெற்றி\" என்று அவர் கூறினார்.",
        "அரசாங்கே ஜனவரம இறுதி! புதிய அரசாங்கத்துடன் இணைந்து ஜன சக்தி தயார். pic.twitter.com/0bdvnviRav",
        "அதிபர் ராஜபக்சே இன்னும் முறையாக ராஜினாமா செய்யவில்லை. பிரதமர் அலுவலகத்தின்படி, ராஜபக்சே, பிரதமர் ரணில் விக்ரமசிங்கேவிடம், முன்னதாக அறிவித்தபடி ஜூலை 13 புதன்கிழமை பதவி விலகப் போவதாக அதிகாரப்பூர்வமாகத் தெரிவித்தார். எவ்வாறாயினும், ஜனாதிபதியின் அறிக்கையை பாராளுமன்ற சபாநாயகர் மட்டுமே வெளியிட முடியும் என்று ஜனாதிபதி அலுவலகம் பின்னர் வெளியிட்டுள்ள அறிக்கையில் தெரிவிக்கப்பட்டுள்ளது. (கொழும்பு/ஜூலை11/2022)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "இலங்கை",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "எஸ்.ஜே.பி",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "சஜித் பிரேமதாச",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "சமகி ஜன பலவேகயா",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "எஸ்.ஜே.பி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "சஜித் பிரேமதாச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஜூலை 11 திங்கட்கிழமை",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "பிரேமதாச",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "பிரேமதாச",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "அரகலய",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "அரசாங்கே",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ராஜபக்சே",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ராஜபக்சே",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜூலை 13 புதன்கிழமை",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "கொழும்பு/ஜூலை11/2022",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}