{
  "newspaper_id": "virakesari-lk",
  "url": "http://www.virakesari.lk/article/130162",
  "time_ut": 1656139604,
  "original_lang": "ta",
  "original_title": "திருச்சி முகாமில் இலங்கை தமிழர் தீக்குளிப்பு : உயிரை மாய்த்துக்கொள்ள முயன்ற 30 இலங்கைத் தமிழர்கள் வைத்தியசாலையில் அனுமதி",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Sri Lankan Tamils ​​set on fire in Trichy camp: 30 Sri Lankan Tamils ​​who tried to commit suicide admitted to hospital",
      "author": "T. Saranya",
      "body_lines": [
        "A Sri Lankan Tamil has caught fire at the Trichy Central Jail Special Camp and is being treated at the Trichy Government Hospital.",
        "Refugees from Sri Lanka, Bangladesh, Russia and Bulgaria are being held in special camps at the Trichy Central Jail.",
        "As a result, some Sri Lankan Tamils ​​have been on a hunger strike since May 20, demanding their release after more than three years in prison.",
        "As a result, 21 Sri Lankan Tamils ​​in the camp have been on a series of hunger strikes demanding their release.",
        "Thirty Sri Lankan Tamils ​​in a special camp tried to commit suicide by taking pills.",
        "Police rescued 30 people and admitted them to the hospital for treatment. There they are being treated. The incident has caused a great stir in the Trichy refugee camp.",
        "The Sri Lankan Tamils ​​there said that we were serving more than 3 years in prison and that the Tamil Nadu government and the district administration should release them.",
        "But there was no agreement on that. Meanwhile 4 Sri Lankan Tamils ​​suddenly climbed a tree and engaged in a struggle. They sat in the tree for a while chanting, then went downstairs."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Sri Lankan Tamils ​​set",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "Trichy",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "30",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "Sri Lankan Tamils ​​who",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lankan Tamil",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Trichy Central Jail Special Camp",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Trichy Government Hospital",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Bangladesh",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Russia",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Bulgaria",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Trichy Central Jail",
            "label": "FAC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lankan Tamils",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "May 20",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "more than three years",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "21",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lankan Tamils ​​in",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Thirty",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "30",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Trichy",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "The Sri Lankan Tamils ​​there",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "more than 3 years",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Tamil Nadu",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "4",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lankan Tamils",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "ට්‍රිචි කඳවුරේදී ශ්‍රී ලාංකික ද්‍රවිඩ ජාතිකයන් ගිනි තබයි: සියදිවි නසා ගැනීමට තැත් කළ ශ්‍රී ලාංකික දෙමළ ජාතිකයන් 30ක් රෝහලට",
      "author": "T. Saranya",
      "body_lines": [
        "ටි‍්‍රචි මධ්‍යම බන්ධනාගාර විශේෂ කඳවුරේදී ශ‍්‍රී ලාංකික දෙමළ ජාතිකයෙකු ගිනිගෙන ති‍්‍රච්චි රජයේ රෝහලේ ප‍්‍රතිකාර ලබයි.",
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකාව, බංග්ලාදේශය, රුසියාව සහ බල්ගේරියාව යන රටවල සරණාගතයින් ට්‍රිචි මධ්‍යම බන්ධනාගාරයේ විශේෂ කඳවුරුවල රඳවා සිටිති.",
        "එහි ප්‍රතිඵලයක් ලෙස වසර තුනකට අධික සිරදඬුවම් විඳීමෙන් පසු තමන් නිදහස් කරන ලෙස බලකරමින් ඇතැම් ශ්‍රී ලාංකික දෙමළ ජනතාව මැයි 20 වැනිදා සිට උපවාසයක නිරත වූහ.",
        "එහි ප්‍රතිඵලයක් ලෙස කඳවුරේ සිටින ශ්‍රී ලාංකික දෙමළ ජාතිකයන් 21 දෙනෙකු තමන් නිදහස් කරන ලෙස බලකරමින් උපවාස මාලාවක නිරතව සිටිති.",
        "විශේෂ කඳවුරක සිටි ශ්‍රී ලාංකික දෙමළ ජාතිකයන් 30 දෙනෙකු පෙති පානය කර සියදිවි නසා ගැනීමට තැත් කළහ.",
        "පොලිසිය 30 දෙනෙකු බේරාගෙන ප්‍රතිකාර සඳහා රෝහල් ගත කර ඇත. එහිදී ඔවුන්ට ප්‍රතිකාර කරනවා. මෙම සිද්ධිය ට්‍රිචි සරණාගත කඳවුරේ දැඩි ආන්දෝලනයකට තුඩු දී තිබේ.",
        "එහි සිටි ශ්‍රී ලාංකික දෙමළ ජනතාව කියා සිටියේ අප වසර 3කට වැඩි කාලයක් සිරගතව සිටින බවත් තමිල්නාඩු රජය සහ දිස්ත්‍රික් පරිපාලනය ඔවුන් නිදහස් කළ යුතු බවත්ය.",
        "නමුත් ඒ ගැන එකඟතාවක් තිබුණේ නැහැ. මේ අතර ශ්‍රී ලාංකික දෙමළ ජාතිකයන් 4 දෙනෙකු එක්වරම ගසකට නැග අරගලයක නිරත වුණා. ඔවුන් ටික වේලාවක් ගසේ වාඩි වී ගායනා කර, පසුව පහළට ගියහ."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ලංකාවේ දෙමළ සෙට් එක",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "ට්‍රිචි",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "30",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "ශ්‍රී ලාංකික දෙමළ ජාතිකයන්",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලාංකික දෙමළ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ට්‍රිචි මධ්‍යම බන්ධනාගාරයේ විශේෂ කඳවුර",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "ට්‍රිචි රජයේ රෝහල",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "බංග්ලාදේශය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "රුසියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "බල්ගේරියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ට්‍රිචි මධ්‍යම බන්ධනාගාරය",
            "label": "FAC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලාංකික දෙමළ ජනතාව",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "මැයි 20",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "අවුරුදු තුනකට වඩා වැඩි",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "21",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලාංකික දෙමළ ජනතාව තුළ",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "තිස්",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "30",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ට්‍රිචි",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "එහි සිටින ශ්‍රී ලාංකික දෙමළ ජනතාවයි",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "වසර 3 කට වඩා වැඩි කාලයක්",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "තමිල්නාඩුව",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "4",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලාංකික දෙමළ ජනතාව",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "திருச்சி முகாமில் இலங்கை தமிழர் தீக்குளிப்பு : உயிரை மாய்த்துக்கொள்ள முயன்ற 30 இலங்கைத் தமிழர்கள் வைத்தியசாலையில் அனுமதி",
      "author": "T. Saranya",
      "body_lines": [
        "திருச்சி மத்திய சிறை சிறப்பு முகாமில் இலங்கை தமிழர் ஒருவர் தீக்குளித்த நிலையில், அவருக்கு திருச்சி அரச வைத்தியசாலையில் தீவிர சிகிச்சை அளிக்கப்பட்டு வருகிறது.",
        "திருச்சி மத்திய சிறை வளாகத்தில் உள்ள சிறப்பு முகாமில் குற்ற வழக்குகளில் தொடர்பு உடைய இலங்கை, பங்களாதேஷ், ரஷ்யா, பல்கேரியா உள்ளிட்ட நாடுகளை சேர்ந்த அகதிகள் சிறை வைக்கப்பட்டுள்ளனர்.",
        "இந்நிலையில் இலங்கை தமிழர்கள் சிலர் சிறையில் அடைக்கப்பட்டு தண்டனை காலம் முடிந்து 3 ஆண்டுகளுக்கு மேல் ஆவதால், தங்களை விடுதலை செய்யக்கோரி கடந்த மே மாதம் 20 ஆம் திகதி முதல் உண்ணாவிரத போராட்டத்தில் ஈடுபட்டு வருகின்றனர்.",
        "இந்நிலையில் முகாமில் உள்ள இலங்கைத் தமிழர்கள் 21 பேர் தங்களை விடுதலை செய்ய வேண்டும் என்ற கோரிக்கையை வலியுறுத்தி தொடர்ந்து தொடர் உண்ணாவிரதப் போராட்டத்தில் ஈடுபட்டு வருகின்றனர்.",
        "சிறப்பு முகாமில் உள்ள இலங்கை தமிழர்கள் 30 பேர் மாத்திரை உட்கொண்டு தற்கொலை முயற்சியில் ஈடுபட்டனர்.",
        "30 பேரையும் மீட்டு வைத்தியசாலையில் சிகிச்சைக்காக பொலிஸார் அனுமதித்தனர். அங்கு அவர்களுக்கு சிகிச்சை அளிக்கப்பட்டு வருகிறது. இந்த சம்பவம் திருச்சி அகதிகள் முகாமில் பெரும் பரபரப்பை ஏற்படுத்தியுள்ளது.",
        "அங்குள்ள இலங்கை தமிழர்கள், நாங்கள் 3 ஆண்டுகளுக்கு மேலாக தண்டனை அனுபவித்து வருவதாகவும் தங்களை தமிழக அரசும், மாவட்ட நிர்வாகமும் விடுதலை செய்ய வேண்டும் எனவும் தெரிவித்தனர்.",
        "ஆனால் அதில் உடன்பாடு ஏற்படவில்லை. இதனிடையே இலங்கை தமிழர்கள் 4 பேர் திடீரென மரத்தில் ஏறி போராட்டத்தில் ஈடுபட்டனர். கோஷமிட்டபடி சிறிதுநேரம் மரத்தில் அமர்ந்திருந்த அவர்கள், பின்னர் கீழே இறங்கினார்கள்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "இலங்கைத் தமிழர்கள் தொகுப்பு",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "திருச்சி",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "30",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "இலங்கைத் தமிழர்கள் யார்",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கைத் தமிழர்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "திருச்சி மத்திய சிறை சிறப்பு முகாம்",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "திருச்சி அரசு மருத்துவமனை",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "பங்களாதேஷ்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரஷ்யா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "பல்கேரியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "திருச்சி மத்திய சிறை",
            "label": "FAC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கைத் தமிழர்கள்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "மே 20",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "மூன்று ஆண்டுகளுக்கு மேல்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "21",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கைத் தமிழர்கள்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "முப்பது",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "30",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "திருச்சி",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "அங்குள்ள இலங்கைத் தமிழர்கள்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "3 ஆண்டுகளுக்கு மேல்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "தமிழ்நாடு",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "4",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கைத் தமிழர்கள்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}