{
  "newspaper_id": "news-first-lk",
  "url": "https://www.newsfirst.lk/2022/08/22/indian-coast-guard-rescues-sri-lankan-refugees-stranded-at-sea/",
  "time_ut": 1661154900,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Indian Coast Guard rescues Sri Lankan refugees stranded at sea",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Indian Coast Guard rescues Sri Lankan refugees stranded at sea",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "Tamil Nadu: Amid the ongoing economic crisis in Sri Lanka, the Indian Coast Guard (ICG) rescued eight refugees from the island nation who were stranded for three days in the middle of the sea near Dhanushkodi in Tamil Nadu. The Sri Lankan refugees include 3 children and an infant.",
        "When personnel from the Indian Coast Guard spotted the refugees stranded at Arichalmunai, they intercepted and brought them to the shores in a hovercraft on Sunday.",
        "Sources told that the refugees were brought to the Mandapam marine police station. They were identified as 36-year-old Chandrakumar and his wife Delchithiram with their seven-year-old son and two-month-old infant from Kilinochchi district in Sri Lanka.",
        "Moreover, 30-year-old Kirubakaran and his wife Nishanthi with their two daughters aged nine and four from Jaffna were also rescued by the ICG. Marine Police officials said the refugees would be handed over to the officials at the Mandapam Rehabilitation Centre.",
        "Indian Coast Guard rescues Sri Lankan refugees stranded at sea"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Indian Coast Guard",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "Sri Lankan",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Tamil Nadu",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Indian Coast Guard",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "eight",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "three days",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Dhanushkodi",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Tamil Nadu",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "3",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the Indian Coast Guard",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sunday",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Mandapam marine police",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "36-year-old",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Chandrakumar",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Delchithiram",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "seven-year-old",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "two-month-old",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kilinochchi",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "30-year-old",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kirubakaran",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Nishanthi",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "two",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Jaffna",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ICG",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Marine Police",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Mandapam Rehabilitation Centre",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Indian Coast Guard",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lankan",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "ඉන්දීය වෙරළාරක්ෂක බලකාය මුහුදේ අතරමං වූ ශ්‍රී ලාංකික සරණාගතයින් බේරා ගනී",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "තමිල්නාඩුව: ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ පවතින ආර්ථික අර්බුදය මධ්‍යයේ, තමිල්නාඩුවේ ධනුෂ්කොඩි අසල මුහුද මැද දින තුනක් අතරමංව සිටි දූපත් ජාතියේ සරණාගතයින් අට දෙනෙකු ඉන්දීය වෙරළාරක්ෂක බලකාය (අයිසීජී) විසින් බේරා ගනු ලැබීය. ශ්‍රී ලාංකික සරණාගතයින් අතර කුඩා දරුවන් තිදෙනෙකු සහ බිළිඳෙකු ද වේ.",
        "ඉන්දීය වෙරළාරක්ෂක බළකායේ නිලධාරීන් අරිචල්මුණේ අතරමංව සිටින සරණාගතයින් දුටු විට, ඔවුන් අල්ලාගෙන ඉරිදා හොවර්ක්‍රාෆ්ට් එකකින් වෙරළට ගෙන එන ලදී.",
        "එම සරණාගතයින් මණ්ඩපම් සමුද්‍ර පොලිස් ස්ථානය වෙත රැගෙන ආ බවයි ආරංචි මාර්ග සඳහන් කළේ. ඔවුන් ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ කිලිනොච්චි දිස්ත්‍රික්කයේ පදිංචි 36 හැවිරිදි චන්ද්‍රකුමාර් සහ ඔහුගේ බිරිඳ ඩෙල්චිතිරම් ඔවුන්ගේ හත් හැවිරිදි පුතා සහ මාස දෙකක ළදරුවන් ලෙස හඳුනාගෙන ඇත.",
        "එපමණක් නොව, යාපනයේ පදිංචිව සිටි 30 හැවිරිදි කිරුබාකරන් සහ ඔහුගේ බිරිඳ නිශාන්ති ඔවුන්ගේ වයස අවුරුදු නවයේ සහ හතරේ දියණියන් දෙදෙනා ද අයි.සී.ජී. මෙම සරණාගතයින් මණ්ඩපම් පුනරුත්ථාපන මධ්‍යස්ථානයේ නිලධාරීන් වෙත භාරදීමට නියමිත බව සමුද්‍ර පොලිස් නිලධාරීහු ප්‍රකාශ කළහ.",
        "ඉන්දීය වෙරළාරක්ෂක බලකාය මුහුදේ අතරමං වූ ශ්‍රී ලාංකික සරණාගතයින් බේරා ගනී"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ඉන්දියානු වෙරළාරක්ෂක බලකාය",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "ශ්‍රී ලාංකික",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "තමිල්නාඩුව",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දියානු වෙරළාරක්ෂක බලකාය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "අට",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "දවස් තුනක්",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ධනුෂ්කොඩි",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "තමිල්නාඩුව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "3",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දියානු වෙරළාරක්ෂක බලකාය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉරිදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "මණ්ඩපම් සමුද්‍ර පොලිසිය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "36 හැවිරිදිය",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "චන්ද්‍රකුමාර් ය",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "දෙල්චිතිරම්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "අවුරුදු හතක් වයසැති",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මාස දෙකක් වයසැති",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "කිලිනොච්චි",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "30 හැවිරිදිය",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kirubakaran",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "නිශාන්ති",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "දෙක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "යාපනය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "අයි.සී.ජී",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "මැරීන් පොලිසිය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "මණ්ඩපම් පුනරුත්ථාපන මධ්යස්ථානය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දියානු වෙරළාරක්ෂක බලකාය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලාංකික",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "கடலில் தத்தளித்த இலங்கை அகதிகளை இந்திய கடலோர காவல்படையினர் மீட்டனர்",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "தமிழகம்: இலங்கையில் நிலவும் பொருளாதார நெருக்கடிக்கு மத்தியில், தமிழகத்தின் தனுஷ்கோடி அருகே நடுக்கடலில் மூன்று நாட்களாக தத்தளித்த தீவு தேசத்தைச் சேர்ந்த 8 அகதிகளை இந்திய கடலோர காவல்படையினர் மீட்டனர். இலங்கை அகதிகளில் 3 குழந்தைகளும் ஒரு கைக்குழந்தையும் அடங்குவர்.",
        "இந்திய கடலோர காவல்படையினர் அரிச்சல்முனையில் சிக்கித் தவித்த அகதிகளைக் கண்டதும், ஞாயிற்றுக்கிழமை ஹோவர் கிராஃப்ட் மூலம் அவர்களைக் கரைக்குக் கொண்டு வந்தனர்.",
        "அகதிகள் மண்டபம் கடல் காவல் நிலையத்திற்கு அழைத்து வரப்பட்டதாக வட்டாரங்கள் தெரிவித்தன. அவர்கள் இலங்கையில் கிளிநொச்சி மாவட்டத்தைச் சேர்ந்த 36 வயதான சந்திரகுமார் மற்றும் அவரது மனைவி டெல்சித்திரம் அவர்களின் ஏழு வயது மகன் மற்றும் இரண்டு மாத கைக்குழந்தையுடன் அடையாளம் காணப்பட்டனர்.",
        "மேலும், யாழ்ப்பாணத்தைச் சேர்ந்த 30 வயதான கிருபாகரன் மற்றும் அவரது மனைவி நிஷாந்தி மற்றும் ஒன்பது மற்றும் நான்கு வயதுடைய இரண்டு மகள்களுடன் ஐ.சி.ஜி. அகதிகள் மண்டபம் புனர்வாழ்வு மைய அதிகாரிகளிடம் ஒப்படைக்கப்படவுள்ளதாக மரைன் பொலிஸ் அதிகாரிகள் தெரிவித்தனர்.",
        "கடலில் தத்தளித்த இலங்கை அகதிகளை இந்திய கடலோர காவல்படையினர் மீட்டனர்"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "இந்திய கடலோர காவல்படை",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "இலங்கை",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "தமிழ்நாடு",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்திய கடலோர காவல்படை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "எட்டு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "மூன்று நாட்கள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "தனுஷ்கோடி",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "தமிழ்நாடு",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "3",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இந்திய கடலோர காவல்படை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஞாயிற்றுக்கிழமை",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "மண்டபம் மரைன் போலீஸ்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "36 வயது",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சந்திரகுமார்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "டெல்சித்திரம்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஏழு வயது",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இரண்டு மாத வயது",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "கிளிநொச்சி",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "30 வயது",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kirubakaran",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "நிஷாந்தி",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இரண்டு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "யாழ்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஐ.சி.ஜி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "மரைன் போலீஸ்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "மண்டபம் மறுவாழ்வு மையம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இந்திய கடலோர காவல்படை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}