{
  "newspaper_id": "daily-mirror-lk",
  "url": "https://www.dailymirror.lk/breaking_news/Court-recalls-arrest-warrant-against-Pathum-Kerner/108-243641",
  "time_ut": 1661323935,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Court recalls arrest warrant against Pathum Kerner",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Court recalls arrest warrant against Pathum Kerner",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "The Colombo Chief Magistrate's Court today recalled the arrest warrant issued against Social media activist Dr. Pathum Kerner, after he surrendered to court.",
        "On August 23, Colombo Additional Magistrate Harshana Kekunawala had issued warrants for the arrest of Pathum Kerner for not being present in Court in connection with a case filed against him by Colombo Crimes Division.",
        "Pathum Kerner surrendered to court alone with President’s Counsel Rienzie Arseculeratne and Counsel Udara Muhandiramge through a motion application.",
        "Defence counsel submitted to court that their counsel was unable to attend court on Tuesday (23) due to misunderstanding regarding the next date of hearing. Kerner apologised to court and gave an undertaking to appear in court on a regular basis. Additional Magistrate Harshana Kekunawala advised the suspect not to evade court and further magisterial inquiry fixed for November 29.",
        "Pathum Kerner was arrested for committing offences under Public Property Act during a violent protest held near Polduwa junction on July 13. He is currently out on bail.(Lakmal Sooriyagoda)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Pathum Kerner",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Magistrate",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Pathum Kerner",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "August 23",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Colombo Additional Magistrate",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Harshana Kekunawala",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Pathum Kerner",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Court",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Colombo Crimes Division",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Pathum Kerner",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Counsel Rienzie Arseculeratne",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Counsel Udara Muhandiramge",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Tuesday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "23",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Magistrate",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Harshana Kekunawala",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "November 29",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Pathum Kerner",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Public Property Act",
            "label": "LAW"
          },
          {
            "text": "Polduwa",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "July 13",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sooriyagoda",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "පැතුම් කර්නර් අත්අඩංගුවට ගැනීමේ වරෙන්තුව අධිකරණය යළි කැඳවයි",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "සමාජ මාධ්‍ය ක්‍රියාකාරිකයෙකු වන වෛද්‍ය පැතුම් කර්නර් මහතා අධිකරණයට භාරවීමෙන් පසු ඔහුට එරෙහිව නිකුත් කර තිබූ වරෙන්තුව කොළඹ ප්‍රධාන මහේස්ත්‍රාත් අධිකරණය අද යළි කැඳවා තිබේ.",
        "පැතුම් කර්නර්ට එරෙහිව කොළඹ අපරාධ කොට්ඨාශය විසින් පවරා ඇති නඩුවකට අදාළව අධිකරණයේ පෙනී නොසිටීම හේතුවෙන් කොළඹ අතිරේක මහේස්ත්‍රාත් හර්ෂණ කැකුණවල මහතා අගෝස්තු 23 වැනිදා ඔහු අත්අඩංගුවට ගන්නා ලෙස වරෙන්තු නිකුත් කර තිබුණි.",
        "පැතුම් කර්නර් ජනාධිපති නීතීඥ රියන්සි අර්සකුලරත්න සහ නීතීඥ උදාර මුහන්දිරම්ගේ සමග තනිව අධිකරණයට භාර වූයේ මෝසමක් මගින් ය.",
        "විත්තියේ නීතිඥවරයා අධිකරණයට ඉදිරිපත් කළේ මීළඟ නඩු දිනය සම්බන්ධයෙන් ඇති වූ වැරදි අවබෝධයක් හේතුවෙන් තම නීතිඥවරයාට අඟහරුවාදා (23) අධිකරණයට පැමිණීමට නොහැකි වූ බවයි. කර්නර් උසාවියෙන් සමාව අයැද සිටි අතර නිතිපතා අධිකරණයේ පෙනී සිටීමට පොරොන්දු විය. අධිකරණය මගහැර නොයන ලෙස අතිරේක මහේස්ත්‍රාත් හර්ෂණ කැකුණවල සැකකරුට උපදෙස් දුන් අතර වැඩිදුර මහේස්ත්‍රාත් පරීක්ෂණය නොවැම්බර් 29 දිනට නියම කළේය.",
        "ජුලි 13 වැනිදා පොල්දූව හන්දිය අසල පැවති ප්‍රචණ්ඩ විරෝධතාවකදී පොදු දේපළ පනත යටතේ වැරදි සිදුකිරීම සම්බන්ධයෙන් පැතුම් කර්නර් අත්අඩංගුවට ගෙන ඇති අතර ඔහු දැනට ඇප මත නිදහස්ව සිටියි.(ලක්මාල් සූරියගොඩ)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "පැතුම් කර්නර්",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "මහේස්ත්රාත්වරයා",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "පැතුම් කර්නර්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "අගෝස්තු 23",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "කොළඹ අතිරේක මහේස්ත්‍රාත්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "හර්ෂණ කැකුණවල",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "පැතුම් කර්නර්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "අධිකරණය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "කොළඹ අපරාධ කොට්ඨාශය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "පැතුම් කර්නර්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "නීතිඥ රියන්සි අර්සකුලරත්න",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "නීතිඥ උදාර මුහන්දිරම්ගේ",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "අඟහරුවාදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "23",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "මහේස්ත්රාත්වරයා",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "හර්ෂණ කැකුණවල",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "නොවැම්බර් 29",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "පැතුම් කර්නර්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "පොදු දේපල පනත",
            "label": "LAW"
          },
          {
            "text": "පොල්දූව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජූලි 13",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "සූරියගොඩ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "பாத்தும் கெர்னருக்கு எதிரான கைது வாரண்டை நீதிமன்றம் திரும்பப் பெறுகிறது",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "சமூக ஊடக செயற்பாட்டாளர் கலாநிதி பதும் கெர்னருக்கு எதிராக பிறப்பிக்கப்பட்ட பிடியாணையை கொழும்பு பிரதான நீதவான் நீதிமன்றம் இன்று நீதிமன்றத்தில் சரணடைந்ததையடுத்து மீளப்பெற்றுள்ளது.",
        "ஆகஸ்ட் 23ஆம் திகதி கொழும்பு குற்றத்தடுப்புப் பிரிவினால் தாக்கல் செய்யப்பட்ட வழக்கு தொடர்பில் நீதிமன்றில் முன்னிலையாகாத காரணத்தினால் பாத்தும் கெர்னரை கைது செய்யுமாறு கொழும்பு மேலதிக நீதவான் ஹர்ஷன கெகுனாவல பிடியாணை பிறப்பித்திருந்தார்.",
        "ஜனாதிபதி சட்டத்தரணி ரியன்சி அர்செகுலேரத்ன மற்றும் சட்டத்தரணி உதார முஹந்திரம்கே ஆகியோருடன் பாதம் கெர்னர் நீதிமன்றில் தனியாக சரணடைந்தார்.",
        "அடுத்த விசாரணைத் திகதி தொடர்பில் தவறான புரிதல் காரணமாக தமது சட்டத்தரணி செவ்வாய்க்கிழமை (23) நீதிமன்றில் ஆஜராக இயலவில்லை என பிரதிவாதி சட்டத்தரணி நீதிமன்றில் சமர்ப்பித்தார். கெர்னர் நீதிமன்றத்தில் மன்னிப்புக் கேட்டு, தொடர்ந்து நீதிமன்றத்தில் ஆஜராக உறுதி அளித்தார். மேலதிக நீதவான் ஹர்ஷன கெகுனாவல, சந்தேகநபரை நீதிமன்றத்தை தப்ப வேண்டாம் என அறிவுறுத்தி மேலதிக நீதவான் விசாரணையை நவம்பர் 29ஆம் திகதிக்கு ஒத்திவைத்தார்.",
        "ஜூலை 13 அன்று பொல்துவ சந்திக்கு அருகில் இடம்பெற்ற வன்முறைப் போராட்டத்தின் போது பொதுச் சொத்து சட்டத்தின் கீழ் குற்றங்களைச் செய்ததற்காக பாதம் கெர்னர் கைது செய்யப்பட்டார். அவர் தற்போது பிணையில் உள்ளார்.(லக்மால் சூரியகொட)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "பாத்தும் கெர்னர்",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "மாஜிஸ்திரேட்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாத்தும் கெர்னர்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஆகஸ்ட் 23",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "கொழும்பு மேலதிக நீதவான்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஹர்ஷன கெகுனாவல",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாத்தும் கெர்னர்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "நீதிமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "கொழும்பு குற்றப்பிரிவு",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பாத்தும் கெர்னர்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆலோசகர் ரியன்சி அர்செகுலேரத்ன",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆலோசகர் உதாரா முஹந்திரம்கே",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "செவ்வாய்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "23",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "மாஜிஸ்திரேட்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஹர்ஷன கெகுனாவல",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "நவம்பர் 29",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பாத்தும் கெர்னர்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "பொது சொத்து சட்டம்",
            "label": "LAW"
          },
          {
            "text": "பொல்துவா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜூலை 13",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சூரியகொட",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}