{
  "newspaper_id": "economy-next-com",
  "url": "https://economynext.com/sri-lanka-and-bangladesh-biz-chambers-hold-dicussion-to-enchance-bilateral-trade-98045/",
  "time_ut": 1659247440,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Sri Lanka and Bangladesh biz chambers hold dicussion to enchance bilateral trade",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Sri Lanka and Bangladesh biz chambers hold dicussion to enchance bilateral trade",
      "author": "",
      "body_lines": [
        "ECONOMYNEXT – Sri Lanka holds a discussion with Bangladesh’s business association to increase trade between the two countries in tourism, investment and shipping.",
        "On July 27, The High Commission of Sri Lanka in Dhaka organized a webinar with the National Chamber of Exporters (NCE) in Sri Lanka and the Dhaka Chamber of Commerce and Industry (DCCI).",
        "The participants discussed avenues for increasing bilateral trade and economic cooperation between the chambers.",
        "“This kind of timely initiative would pave the way to increase the bilateral trade volume between the two countries as well as cooperation in other sectors which include investment, tourism, and shipping,” High Commissioner Professor Sudharshan Seneviratne has said.",
        "Secretary General of NCE Shiham Marikkar and Secretary General of DCCI Afsarul Arifeen had worked out a plan to identify potential business opportunities between Bangladesh and Sri Lanka.",
        "Participants of both the business chambers had proposed several activities and agreed to conduct a follow-up webinar."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Sri Lanka",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "Bangladesh",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Bangladesh’s business association",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "two",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "July 27",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "The High Commission of Sri Lanka",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Dhaka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the National Chamber of Exporters",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Dhaka Chamber of Commerce and Industry",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "two",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sudharshan Seneviratne",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Shiham Marikkar",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Afsarul Arifeen",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Bangladesh",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        []
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "ශ්‍රී ලංකාව සහ බංග්ලාදේශය අතර ද්විපාර්ශ්වික වෙළෙඳාම ප්‍රවර්ධනය කිරීමට සාකච්ඡා පවත්වයි",
      "author": "",
      "body_lines": [
        "ECONOMYNEXT - සංචාරක, ආයෝජන සහ නාවික කටයුතු සම්බන්ධයෙන් දෙරට අතර වෙළඳාම වැඩි කිරීම සඳහා ශ්‍රී ලංකාව බංග්ලාදේශයේ ව්‍යාපාරික සංගමය සමඟ සාකච්ඡාවක් පවත්වයි.",
        "ජුලි 27 වන දින ඩකා හි ශ්‍රී ලංකා මහ කොමසාරිස් කාර්යාලය ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ ජාතික අපනයනකරුවන්ගේ මණ්ඩලය (NCE) සහ ඩකා වාණිජ හා කර්මාන්ත මණ්ඩලය (DCCI) සමඟ webinar සංවිධානය කළේය.",
        "කුටි අතර ද්විපාර්ශ්වික වෙළෙඳාම සහ ආර්ථික සහයෝගීතාව ඉහළ නැංවීමේ මාර්ග පිළිබඳව සහභාගිවන්නන් සාකච්ඡා කළහ.",
        "\"මෙවැනි කාලෝචිත මුලපිරීමක් දෙරට අතර ද්විපාර්ශ්වික වෙළඳ පරිමාව මෙන්ම ආයෝජන, සංචාරක සහ නාවික ඇතුළු අනෙකුත් අංශවල සහයෝගිතාව ඉහළ නැංවීමට මග සලසනු ඇත\" යනුවෙන් මහ කොමසාරිස් මහාචාර්ය සුදර්ශන් සෙනෙවිරත්න මහතා පැවසීය.",
        "NCE හි මහලේකම් ශිහාම් මරික්කාර් සහ DCCI හි මහලේකම් අෆ්සරුල් අරිෆීන් බංග්ලාදේශය සහ ශ්‍රී ලංකාව අතර ඇති විය හැකි ව්‍යාපාරික අවස්ථා හඳුනා ගැනීමට සැලැස්මක් සකස් කර තිබුණි.",
        "ව්‍යාපාරික කුටි දෙකෙහිම සහභාගිවන්නන් ක්‍රියාකාරකම් කිහිපයක් යෝජනා කර පසු විපරම් වෙබ් නාලිකාවක් පැවැත්වීමට එකඟ විය."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "බංග්ලාදේශය",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "බංග්ලාදේශයේ ව්යාපාරික සංගමය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "දෙක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ජූලි 27",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකා මහ කොමසාරිස් කාර්යාලය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඩකා",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "අපනයනකරුවන්ගේ ජාතික මණ්ඩලය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඩකා වාණිජ හා කර්මාන්ත මණ්ඩලය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "දෙක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "සුදර්ශන් සෙනෙවිරත්න",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශිහාම් මරික්කාර්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "අෆ්සාරුල් අරිෆීන්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "බංග්ලාදේශය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        []
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "இலங்கை மற்றும் பங்களாதேஷ் வர்த்தக சபைகள் இருதரப்பு வர்த்தகத்தை மேம்படுத்துவதற்கான கலந்துரையாடலை நடத்துகின்றன",
      "author": "",
      "body_lines": [
        "பொருளாதாரம் - சுற்றுலா, முதலீடு மற்றும் கப்பல் போக்குவரத்து ஆகியவற்றில் இரு நாடுகளுக்கும் இடையிலான வர்த்தகத்தை அதிகரிக்க பங்களாதேஷின் வர்த்தக சங்கத்துடன் இலங்கை கலந்துரையாடல் ஒன்றை நடத்துகிறது.",
        "ஜூலை 27 அன்று, டாக்காவில் உள்ள இலங்கை உயர் ஸ்தானிகராலயம், இலங்கையில் உள்ள தேசிய ஏற்றுமதியாளர்கள் சம்மேளனம் (NCE) மற்றும் டாக்கா வர்த்தகம் மற்றும் தொழில்துறை (DCCI) ஆகியவற்றுடன் ஒரு வெபினாரை ஏற்பாடு செய்தது.",
        "இருதரப்பு வர்த்தகம் மற்றும் அறைகளுக்கு இடையே பொருளாதார ஒத்துழைப்பை அதிகரிப்பதற்கான வழிகள் குறித்து பங்கேற்பாளர்கள் விவாதித்தனர்.",
        "\"இவ்வகையான சரியான நேரத்தில் முன்முயற்சியானது இரு நாடுகளுக்குமிடையிலான இருதரப்பு வர்த்தக அளவை அதிகரிப்பதற்கும் முதலீடு, சுற்றுலா மற்றும் கப்பல் போக்குவரத்து உள்ளிட்ட ஏனைய துறைகளில் ஒத்துழைப்பை அதிகரிப்பதற்கும் வழி வகுக்கும்\" என உயர்ஸ்தானிகர் பேராசிரியர் சுதர்சன் செனவிரத்ன தெரிவித்துள்ளார்.",
        "NCE இன் செயலாளர் நாயகம் ஷிஹாம் மரிக்கார் மற்றும் DCCI இன் செயலாளர் நாயகம் அஃப்சருல் ஆரிஃபீன் ஆகியோர் பங்களாதேஷ் மற்றும் இலங்கைக்கு இடையில் சாத்தியமான வர்த்தக வாய்ப்புகளை அடையாளம் காணும் திட்டத்தை வகுத்துள்ளனர்.",
        "இரு வணிக அறைகளின் பங்கேற்பாளர்களும் பல செயல்பாடுகளை முன்மொழிந்தனர் மற்றும் பின்தொடர் வலையரங்கை நடத்த ஒப்புக்கொண்டனர்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "இலங்கை",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "பங்களாதேஷ்",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "பங்களாதேஷின் வர்த்தக சங்கம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இரண்டு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஜூலை 27",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை உயர்ஸ்தானிகராலயம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "டாக்கா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஏற்றுமதியாளர்களின் தேசிய சபை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "டாக்கா சேம்பர் ஆஃப் காமர்ஸ் அண்ட் இன்டஸ்ட்ரி",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "இரண்டு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "சுதர்சன் செனவிரத்ன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஷிஹாம் மரிக்கார்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "அஃப்சருல் ஆரிபீன்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "பங்களாதேஷ்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        []
      ]
    }
  }
}