{
  "newspaper_id": "economy-next-com",
  "url": "https://economynext.com/rajapaksas-party-is-key-to-deciding-sri-lankas-new-president-97297/",
  "time_ut": 1657718460,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Rajapaksa’s party is key to deciding Sri Lanka’s new president",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Rajapaksa’s party is key to deciding Sri Lanka’s new president",
      "author": "Shihar Aneez",
      "body_lines": [
        "ECONOMYNEXT – Despite no member of the Rajapaksa family being in real power at present, former prime minister Mahinda Rajapaksa-led Sri Lanka Podujana Peramuna (SLPP) will be the key in electing a new president due to the parliament majority it has, analysts say.",
        "Despite breakaways and defections, the SLPP still holds the majority in the 225-member legislature.",
        "The party was established in 2016 to bring back Mahinda Rajapaksa to power after his defeat in 2015. Former President Maithripala Sirisena unseated his own party leader after defecting in what later transpired was an internationally backed democratic coup.",
        "Political analysts see a tricky situation come July 20 when parliament is supposed to elect a president from among its membership.",
        "The SLPP, even after all the defections, has 116 seat in parliament excluding the speaker while the opposition which includes many parties collectively has 108 members including all breakaway members from the SLPP.",
        "The SLPP is divided on the next leadership though many lawmakers and party stalwarts are rallying around former Media Minister Dullas Alahapperuma, party loyalists have told EconomyNext.",
        "Since the SLPP has the majority, it has final say on electing the 8th executive president of Sri Lanka, if all of its members vote for the same person.",
        "“Greatest threat to Sri Lanka’s stability, at this time, is SLPP asserting its parliament majority to become a proxy for the rejected leaders of the country,” Nishan de Mel, an economist and Executive Director at Colombo-based Verite Research, tweeted.",
        "“After 2015 and 2019 elections, parliament majority of the defeated presidential candidate, stood down. SLPP should do the same now.”",
        "Greatest threat to #SriLanka stability, at this time, is SLPP asserting its parliament majority to become a proxy for the rejected leaders of the country.",
        "After 2015&19 elections, parliament majority of the defeated presidential candidate, stood down. SLPP shld do the same now.",
        "In 2015, though Mahinda Rajapaksa had a majority in parliament, his party chose to sit in the opposition while in 2019, Wickremeisnghe’s party did the same after defeat at the November presidential poll.",
        "Opposition leader Sajith Premadasa in a tweet said Gotabaya Rajapaksa, Wickremesinghe, and the SLPP government have all “lost its legitimacy”.",
        "“In the past 2½ years your incompetence has destroyed our country. We will form a new government with a new President & a new PM. All those who oppose this process will be responsible for the ensuing anarchy.”",
        ".@GotabayaR, @RW_UNP & the Pohottuwa government has lost its legitimacy. In the past 2½ years your incompetence has destroyed our country. We will form a new government with a new President & a new PM. All those who oppose this process will be responsible for the ensuing anarchy.",
        "But this time, it is not after any national election. It is after an unprecedented resignation of a sitting president.",
        "Gotabaya Rajaoaksa has promised to resign on Wednesday. He has already fled the country, international media reports say, but the speaker has yet to officially announce the resignation.",
        "It will be the SLPP who will decide if the next president is going to be current prime minister and acting president Ranil Wickremesinghe or Janatha Vimukthi Peremuna leader Anura Kumara Dissanayake or former Media Minister Dullas Alahapperuma or opposition leader Premadasa unless it decides to go independent and ask its legislators to vote according to their consciousness.",
        "The Rajapaksas who have been trying to flee the country could still be the crucial decision makers on who the party should support.",
        "“If the SLPP wants to punish the people for forcing Rajapaksas to resign, they can vote to choose an incapable leader or a leader who does not have any support in the parliament.  By doing that, the SLPP can drag the suffering of the people,” a political analyst said asking not to be named.",
        "There are still three more Rajapaksas as legislators in the parliament apart from former Prime Minister Mahinda Rajapaksa.",
        "Though they’re no longer in power, a significant number of SLPP lawmakers still have respect for the Rajapaksas, especially for Mahinda Rajapaksa, who gave the political leadership to winning a 26-year war against Tamil Tiger rebels who fought for an independent state in the island nation’s North and East.",
        "Once the president resigns, the standing prime minister will become the caretaker president for 30 days. In the event the prime minister also resigns, the parliament speaker will become the caretaker president. Within the 30 days, the acting president must elect an interim president to run the country for the rest of the tenure of the resigned president.",
        "In the latest Sri Lankan crisis, President Gotabaya Rajapaksa has agreed to resign on Wednesday July 13. Speaker Mahinda Yapa Abeywardena has already scheduled the voting on July 20.",
        "The nominations are expected to called by the Parliament Secretary General on Friday (15) and nominations should be submitted by July 19.",
        "When it comes to the next president, all but former president Mahinda Rajapaksa will be eligible to be nominated. Mahinda Rajapaksa cannot be president as the constitution bars him from becoming the president for a third term.",
        "The nomination is done through the usual process of proposing and seconding the nominee in parliament and only current parliament members can be nominated. (Colombo/July 13/2022)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Rajapaksa",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "Sri Lanka’s",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Mahinda Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Podujana Peramuna",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "225",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "2016",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Mahinda Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "2015",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Maithripala Sirisena",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "July 20",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "116",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "108",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Media",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Dullas Alahapperuma",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "EconomyNext",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "8th",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka’s",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Nishan de Mel",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Verite Research",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "2015",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "2019",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "SriLanka",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "2015&19",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "2015",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Mahinda Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "2019",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Wickremeisnghe",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "November",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sajith Premadasa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Gotabaya Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the past 2½ years",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": ".@GotabayaR",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "@RW_UNP & the Pohottuwa",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the past 2½ years",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "Gotabaya Rajaoaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Wednesday",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Janatha Vimukthi Peremuna",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Anura Kumara Dissanayake",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Media",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Dullas Alahapperuma",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Premadasa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "three",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Rajapaksas",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Mahinda Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Rajapaksas",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Mahinda Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "26-year",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "North and East",
            "label": "LOC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "30 days",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the 30 days",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lankan",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Gotabaya Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Wednesday July 13",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Mahinda Yapa Abeywardena",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "July 20",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Friday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "15",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "July 19",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Mahinda Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "third",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Colombo",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ නව ජනාධිපතිවරයා තීරණය කිරීමේදී රාජපක්ෂගේ පක්ෂය ප්‍රධාන වේ",
      "author": "ශිහාර් අනීස්",
      "body_lines": [
        "ECONOMYNEXT - දැනට සැබෑ බලයේ සිටින රාජපක්ෂ පවුලේ කිසිවකු නොමැති වුවද, හිටපු අගමැති මහින්ද රාජපක්ෂ ප්‍රමුඛ ශ්‍රී ලංකා පොදුජන පෙරමුණ (SLPP) නව ජනාධිපතිවරයෙකු තෝරා ගැනීමේ ප්‍රධානතම පුද්ගලයා වනු ඇත්තේ ඔවුන්ට ඇති පාර්ලිමේන්තු බහුතරය නිසා බව විශ්ලේෂකයෝ පවසති.",
        "කැඩී බිඳී යාම සහ පලායෑම් තිබියදීත්, මන්ත්‍රීවරුන් 225කින් යුත් ව්‍යවස්ථාදායකයේ බහුතරය තවමත් ශ්‍රී ලංකා පොදුජන පෙරමුණට හිමිය.",
        "2015 පරාජයෙන් පසු මහින්ද රාජපක්ෂ නැවත බලයට ගෙන ඒම සඳහා 2016 දී පක්ෂය පිහිටුවන ලදී. හිටපු ජනාධිපති මෛත්‍රීපාල සිරිසේන පසුව සිදුවූයේ ජාත්‍යන්තරව පිටුබලය ලත් ප්‍රජාතන්ත්‍රවාදී කුමන්ත්‍රණයකින් පැන ගොස් ඔහුගේම පක්ෂ නායකයා ඉවත් කරමිනි.",
        "දේශපාලන විශ්ලේෂකයින් දකින්නේ ජුලි 20 වනදා පාර්ලිමේන්තුව එහි සාමාජිකත්වය අතරින් ජනාධිපතිවරයෙකු තෝරා පත් කර ගැනීමට නියමිත උපක්‍රමශීලී තත්වයක් ඇති වන බවයි.",
        "සියලු පලායෑම්වලින් පසුව වුවද ශ්‍රී ලංකා පොදුජන පෙරමුණට කථානායකවරයා හැර පාර්ලිමේන්තුවේ ආසන 116ක් හිමිව ඇති අතර පක්ෂ රැසක් ඇතුළත් විපක්ෂයට ශ්‍රී ලංකා පොදුජන පෙරමුණෙන් බිඳී ගිය සියලුම මන්ත්‍රීවරුන් ඇතුළුව මන්ත්‍රීවරු 108ක් සිටිති.",
        "හිටපු ජනමාධ්‍ය අමාත්‍ය ඩලස් අලහප්පෙරුම වටා බොහෝ නීති සම්පාදකයින් සහ පක්ෂ නායකයින් රොක් වෙමින් සිටියද මීළඟ නායකත්වය සම්බන්ධයෙන් ශ්‍රී ලංකා පොදුජන පෙරමුණ දෙකඩ වී ඇති බව පක්ෂ හිතවාදීන් EconomyNext වෙත පවසා තිබේ.",
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකා පොදුජන පෙරමුණට බහුතර බලය ඇති බැවින්, එහි සියලුම සාමාජිකයන් එකම පුද්ගලයාට ඡන්දය දෙන්නේ නම්, ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ 8 වැනි විධායක ජනාධිපතිවරයා තෝරා පත් කර ගැනීම පිළිබඳ අවසාන ප්‍රකාශය එය සතු වේ.",
        "“මේ අවස්ථාවේ ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ ස්ථාවරත්වයට ඇති ලොකුම තර්ජනය ශ්‍රී ලංකා පොදුජන පෙරමුණ රටේ ප්‍රතික්ෂේප කරන ලද නායකයින්ගේ ප්‍රොක්සියක් බවට පත්වීම සඳහා ශ්‍රී ලංකා පොදුජන පෙරමුණ සිය පාර්ලිමේන්තු බහුතරය තහවුරු කර ගැනීමයි,” යනුවෙන් ආර්ථික විද්‍යාඥයෙකු සහ කොළඹ පදනම් වූ Verite Research හි විධායක අධ්‍යක්ෂ නිශාන් ද මෙල් ට්වීට් කළේය.",
        "“2015 සහ 2019 මැතිවරණවලින් පසු පරාජිත ජනාධිපති අපේක්ෂකයාගේ පාර්ලිමේන්තුවේ බහුතරය ඉල්ලා අස්විය. ශ්‍රී ලංකා පොදුජන පෙරමුණත් දැන් කළ යුත්තේ එයමයි.”",
        "#ශ්‍රී ලංකා ස්ථාවරත්වයට ඇති ලොකුම තර්ජනය මේ මොහොතේ රටේ ප්‍රතික්ෂේප කරන ලද නායකයින්ගේ ප්‍රොක්සියක් වීමට ශ්‍රී ලංකා පොදුජන පෙරමුණ සිය පාර්ලිමේන්තු බහුතරය තහවුරු කර ගැනීමයි.",
        "2015 සහ 19 මැතිවරණවලින් පසු පරාජිත ජනාධිපති අපේක්ෂකයාගේ පාර්ලිමේන්තුවේ බහුතරය ඉල්ලා අස්විය. ශ්‍රී ලංකා පොදුජන පෙරමුණත් දැන් එයම කළ යුතුයි.",
        "2015 දී මහින්ද රාජපක්ෂට පාර්ලිමේන්තුවේ බහුතර බලය තිබුණද, ඔහුගේ පක්ෂය විපක්ෂයේ අසුන් ගැනීමට තෝරා ගත් අතර, 2019 නොවැම්බර් ජනාධිපතිවරණයෙන් පරාජයෙන් පසු වික්‍රමසිංහගේ පක්ෂය එයම කළේය.",
        "විපක්ෂ නායක සජිත් ප්‍රේමදාස මහතා ට්විටර් පණිවුඩයක් නිකුත් කරමින් කියා සිටියේ ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ, වික්‍රමසිංහ සහ ශ්‍රී ලංකා පොදුජන පෙරමුණේ ආණ්ඩුව සියල්ලෝම “නීත්‍යානුකූලභාවය නැති කර ගෙන ඇති” බවයි.",
        "“පසුගිය වසර දෙකහමාරක කාලය තුළ ඔබේ නොහැකියාව අපේ රට විනාශ කළා. අපි අලුත් ජනාධිපතිවරයෙක් සහ අලුත් අගමැතිවරයෙක් සමඟ අලුත් ආණ්ඩුවක් පිහිටුවනවා. මේ ක්‍රියාවලියට විරුද්ධ වන සියලු දෙනාම ඊළඟ අරාජිකත්වයට වගකිව යුතුයි.”",
        ".@GotabayaR, @RW_UNP & Pohottuwa ආණ්ඩුවේ සුජාතභාවය නැතිවෙලා. පසුගිය වසර දෙකහමාරක කාලය තුළ ඔබේ නොහැකියාව අපේ රට විනාශ කළා. අපි අලුත් ජනාධිපතිවරයෙක් සහ අලුත් අගමැතිවරයෙක් සමඟ අලුත් ආණ්ඩුවක් පිහිටුවනවා. මේ ක්‍රියාවලියට විරුද්ධ වන සියලු දෙනාම ඊළඟ අරාජිකත්වයට වගකිව යුතුයි.",
        "නමුත් මෙවර එය ජාතික මැතිවරණයකින් පසුව නොවේ. ඒ හිටපු ජනාධිපතිවරයකු පෙර නොවූ විරූ ලෙස ඉල්ලා අස්වීමෙන් පසුවය.",
        "ගෝඨාභය රාජඔක්ස බදාදා ඉල්ලා අස්වීමට පොරොන්දු වී ඇත. ඔහු මේ වන විටත් රටින් පලා ගොස් ඇති බව ජාත්‍යන්තර මාධ්‍ය වාර්තා කරන නමුත් කථානායකවරයා ඉල්ලා අස්වීම නිල වශයෙන් ප්‍රකාශ කර නොමැත.",
        "මීළඟ ජනාධිපතිවරයා වත්මන් අගමැති සහ වැඩබලන ජනාධිපති රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ හෝ ජනතා විමුක්ති පෙරමුණේ නායක අනුර කුමාර දිසානායක හෝ හිටපු ජනමාධ්‍ය අමාත්‍ය ඩලස් අලහප්පෙරුම හෝ විපක්ෂ නායක ප්‍රේමදාස මහතා ස්වාධීනව කටයුතු කිරීමට තීරණය නොකළහොත් ශ්‍රී ලංකා පොදුජන පෙරමුණ තීරණය කරනු ඇත. එහි නීති සම්පාදකයින් ඔවුන්ගේ විඥානය අනුව ඡන්දය ප්‍රකාශ කළ යුතුය.",
        "පක්ෂය සහය දිය යුත්තේ කාටද යන්න පිළිබඳ තීරණාත්මක තීරණ ගන්නන් තවමත් රටින් පැන යාමට උත්සාහ කරන රාජපක්ෂලා විය හැකිය.",
        "“රාජපක්‍ෂලාට ඉල්ලා අස්වීමට බල කිරීම සම්බන්ධයෙන් ජනතාවට දඬුවම් කිරීමට ශ්‍රී ලංකා පොදුජන පෙරමුණට අවශ්‍ය නම්, පාර්ලිමේන්තුවේ කිසිදු සහයෝගයක් නොමැති අදක්ෂ නායකයෙකු හෝ නායකයෙකු තෝරා ගැනීමට ඡන්දය දිය හැකිය. එසේ කිරීමෙන් ශ්‍රී ලංකා පොදුජන පෙරමුණට ජනතාවගේ දුක ඇදගෙන යා හැකියි,” දේශපාලන විශ්ලේෂකයෙකු සඳහන් කළේ නම් සඳහන් නොකරන ලෙසයි.",
        "හිටපු අගමැති මහින්ද රාජපක්ෂ මහතා හැර තවත් රාජපක්ෂවරු තිදෙනෙක් තවමත් පාර්ලිමේන්තුවේ ව්‍යවස්ථාදායකයන් ලෙස සිටිති.",
        "ඔවුන් තවදුරටත් බලයේ නොසිටින නමුත්, ශ්‍රී ලංකා පොදුජන පෙරමුණේ මන්ත්‍රීවරුන්ගෙන් සැලකිය යුතු ප්‍රමාණයක් තවමත් රාජපක්ෂලාට, විශේෂයෙන්ම ස්වාධීන රාජ්‍යයක් සඳහා සටන් කළ දෙමළ කොටි කැරලිකරුවන්ට එරෙහිව වසර 26ක යුද්ධයක් ජයග්‍රහණය කිරීමට දේශපාලන නායකත්වය දුන් මහින්ද රාජපක්ෂට ගෞරවයක් ඇත. දිවයින ජාතියේ උතුරු හා නැගෙනහිර.",
        "ජනාධිපතිවරයා ඉල්ලා අස්වීමෙන් පසු, ස්ථාවර අගමැති දින 30 ක් සඳහා භාරකාර ජනාධිපති වනු ඇත. අග්‍රාමාත්‍යවරයාද ඉල්ලා අස් වුවහොත් පාර්ලිමේන්තු කථානායකවරයා භාරකාර ජනාධිපතිවරයා බවට පත්වනු ඇත. දින 30 ඇතුළත, ඉල්ලා අස් වූ ජනාධිපතිවරයාගේ ඉතිරි කාලය සඳහා රට පාලනය කිරීම සඳහා වැඩබලන ජනාධිපතිවරයා අන්තර්වාර ජනාධිපතිවරයකු තෝරා පත් කර ගත යුතුය.",
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ අලුත්ම අර්බුදය තුළ ජනාධිපති ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ මහතා ජූලි 13 බදාදා ඉල්ලා අස්වීමට එකඟ වී ඇත. කථානායක මහින්ද යාපා අබේවර්ධන මහතා විසින් ඡන්දය ප්‍රකාශ කිරීම ජූලි 20 වැනි දිනට දැනටමත් සැලසුම් කර ඇත.",
        "සිකුරාදා (15) පාර්ලිමේන්තු මහලේකම්වරයා විසින් නාමයෝජනා කැඳවීමට අපේක්ෂා කරන අතර ජූලි 19 වනදා වන විට නාමයෝජනා භාරදිය යුතුය.",
        "මීළඟ ජනාධිපතිවරයා සම්බන්ධයෙන් ගත් කල, හිටපු ජනාධිපති මහින්ද රාජපක්ෂ හැර අන් සියල්ලන්ම නාමයෝජනා කිරීමට සුදුසුකම් ලබයි. ආණ්ඩුක්‍රම ව්‍යවස්ථාවෙන් මහින්ද රාජපක්ෂ මහතාට තුන්වන වරටත් ජනාධිපති වීමට බාධාවක් ඇති බැවින් ඔහුට ජනාධිපති විය නොහැක.",
        "නාමයෝජනා කිරීම සාමාන්‍ය පරිදි පාර්ලිමේන්තුවේ නාමයෝජනා යෝජනා කිරීම සහ ස්ථිර කිරීමේ ක්‍රියාවලිය හරහා සිදු කෙරෙන අතර වත්මන් පාර්ලිමේන්තු මන්ත්‍රීවරුන් පමණක් නම් කළ හැකිය. (කොළඹ/ජූලි 13/2022)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "රාජපක්ෂ",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "මහින්ද රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "පොදුජන පෙරමුණ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "225",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "2016",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මහින්ද රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "2015",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මෛත්‍රීපාල සිරිසේන",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ජූලි 20",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "116",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "108",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "මාධ්ය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඩලස් අලහප්පෙරුම",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "EconomyNext",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "8 වැනි",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "නිශාන් ද මෙල්",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "සත්‍ය පර්යේෂණ",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "2015",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "2019",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "2015 සහ 19",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "2015",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මහින්ද රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "2019",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "නොවැම්බර්",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "සජිත් ප්‍රේමදාස",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "පසුගිය වසර 2½",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": ".@ගෝඨාභය ආර්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "@RW_UNP සහ පොහොට්ටුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "පසුගිය වසර 2½",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "බදාදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජනතා විමුක්ති පෙරමුණ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "අනුර කුමාර දිසානායක",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "මාධ්ය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඩලස් අලහප්පෙරුම",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ප්‍රේමදාස ය",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "තුන්",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "රාජපක්ෂලා",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මහින්ද රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "රාජපක්ෂලා",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මහින්ද රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "අවුරුදු 26",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "උතුරු නැගෙනහිර",
            "label": "LOC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "දින 30",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "දින 30",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලාංකික",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජූලි 13 බදාදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මහින්ද යාපා අබේවර්ධන",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජූලි 20",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "සිකුරාදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "15",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජූලි 19",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "මහින්ද රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "තෙවන",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "කොළඹ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "இலங்கையின் புதிய அதிபரை தீர்மானிப்பதில் ராஜபக்சேவின் கட்சி முக்கியமானது",
      "author": "ஷிஹார் அனீஸ்",
      "body_lines": [
        "பொருளாதாரம் - தற்போது உண்மையான அதிகாரத்தில் ராஜபக்ச குடும்ப உறுப்பினர்கள் எவரும் இல்லாவிட்டாலும், முன்னாள் பிரதமர் மஹிந்த ராஜபக்ஷ தலைமையிலான ஸ்ரீலங்கா பொதுஜன பெரமுன (SLPP) பாராளுமன்ற பெரும்பான்மையின் காரணமாக புதிய ஜனாதிபதியைத் தேர்ந்தெடுப்பதில் முக்கிய பங்கு வகிக்கும் என்று ஆய்வாளர்கள் கூறுகின்றனர்.",
        "பிரிந்து சென்றாலும், கட்சி விலகினாலும், 225 உறுப்பினர்களைக் கொண்ட சட்டமன்றத்தில் SLPP இன்னும் பெரும்பான்மையைக் கொண்டுள்ளது.",
        "2015 இல் மஹிந்த ராஜபக்ஷ தோல்வியடைந்த பின்னர் மீண்டும் ஆட்சிக்கு வருவதற்காக 2016 இல் கட்சி ஸ்தாபிக்கப்பட்டது. முன்னாள் ஜனாதிபதி மைத்திரிபால சிறிசேன தனது சொந்தக் கட்சித் தலைவரை பதவியில் இருந்து நீக்கினார்.",
        "அரசியல் ஆய்வாளர்கள் ஜூலை 20 அன்று பாராளுமன்றம் அதன் உறுப்பினர்களில் இருந்து ஒரு ஜனாதிபதியைத் தேர்ந்தெடுக்கும் போது ஒரு தந்திரமான சூழ்நிலை வருவதைக் காண்கிறது.",
        "SLPP, அனைத்து விலகல்களுக்குப் பின்னரும் கூட, சபாநாயகரைத் தவிர்த்து பாராளுமன்றத்தில் 116 ஆசனங்களைக் கொண்டுள்ளது, பல கட்சிகளை உள்ளடக்கிய எதிர்க்கட்சியானது SLPP யில் இருந்து பிரிந்த அனைத்து உறுப்பினர்களையும் சேர்த்து 108 உறுப்பினர்களைக் கொண்டுள்ளது.",
        "ஸ்ரீலங்கா பொதுஜன பெரமுனவின் அடுத்த தலைமை குறித்து பிளவு ஏற்பட்டுள்ள போதிலும், முன்னாள் ஊடகத்துறை அமைச்சர் டலஸ் அழகப்பெருமவை சுற்றி பல பாராளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர்கள் மற்றும் கட்சியின் முக்கியஸ்தர்கள் அணி திரண்டுள்ளதாக கட்சியின் விசுவாசிகள் எகனாமிநெக்ஸ்டுக்கு தெரிவித்துள்ளனர்.",
        "ஸ்ரீலங்கா பொதுஜன பெரமுனவிற்கு பெரும்பான்மை இருப்பதால், அதன் உறுப்பினர்கள் அனைவரும் ஒரே நபருக்கு வாக்களித்தால், இலங்கையின் 8வது நிறைவேற்று ஜனாதிபதியை தெரிவு செய்வதில் அது இறுதியான முடிவாகும்.",
        "\"இலங்கையின் ஸ்திரத்தன்மைக்கு மிகப்பெரிய அச்சுறுத்தல், இந்த நேரத்தில், நாட்டின் நிராகரிக்கப்பட்ட தலைவர்களின் பினாமியாக SLPP தனது பாராளுமன்ற பெரும்பான்மையை உறுதிப்படுத்துகிறது\" என்று கொழும்பை தளமாகக் கொண்ட Verite Research இன் பொருளாதார நிபுணரும் நிர்வாக இயக்குநருமான நிஷான் டி மெல் ட்வீட் செய்துள்ளார்.",
        "“2015 மற்றும் 2019 தேர்தல்களுக்குப் பிறகு, தோற்கடிக்கப்பட்ட ஜனாதிபதி வேட்பாளரின் நாடாளுமன்ற பெரும்பான்மை வேட்பாளர் பதவியில் இருந்து விலகினார். SLPP இப்போது அதையே செய்ய வேண்டும்.",
        "இலங்கையின் ஸ்திரத்தன்மைக்கு மிகப்பெரிய அச்சுறுத்தல், இந்த நேரத்தில், நாட்டின் நிராகரிக்கப்பட்ட தலைவர்களின் பினாமியாக மாறுவதற்கு SLPP தனது பாராளுமன்ற பெரும்பான்மையை உறுதிப்படுத்துவதுதான்.",
        "2015 & 19 தேர்தல்களுக்குப் பிறகு, தோற்கடிக்கப்பட்ட ஜனாதிபதி வேட்பாளரின் பாராளுமன்ற பெரும்பான்மை வேட்பாளர் நிறுத்தப்பட்டார். SLPP இப்போது அதையே செய்ய வேண்டும்.",
        "2015 இல், மகிந்த ராஜபக்சவுக்கு நாடாளுமன்றத்தில் பெரும்பான்மை இருந்தபோதிலும், அவரது கட்சி எதிர்க்கட்சியில் அமரத் தேர்ந்தெடுத்தது, 2019 இல், விக்கிரமசிங்கவின் கட்சி நவம்பர் ஜனாதிபதித் தேர்தலில் தோல்வியடைந்த பின்னர் அதையே செய்தது.",
        "எதிர்க்கட்சித் தலைவர் சஜித் பிரேமதாச தனது டுவிட்டர் பதிவில், கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ச, விக்கிரமசிங்க மற்றும் ஸ்ரீலங்கா பொதுஜன பெரமுனவின் அரசாங்கம் \"அதன் நியாயத்தன்மையை இழந்துவிட்டன\" என்று தெரிவித்துள்ளார்.",
        "“கடந்த 2½ வருடங்களில் உங்கள் திறமையின்மை எங்கள் நாட்டை அழித்துவிட்டது. புதிய ஜனாதிபதி மற்றும் புதிய பிரதமருடன் புதிய அரசாங்கத்தை அமைப்போம். இந்தச் செயலியை எதிர்க்கும் அனைவரும் அடுத்தடுத்த அராஜகங்களுக்குப் பொறுப்பாவார்கள்” என்றார்.",
        ".@கோட்டாபயஆர், @RW_UNP & பொஹொட்டுவ அரசாங்கம் அதன் நியாயத்தன்மையை இழந்துவிட்டது. கடந்த 2½ வருடங்களில் உங்கள் திறமையின்மை எங்கள் நாட்டை அழித்துவிட்டது. புதிய ஜனாதிபதி மற்றும் புதிய பிரதமருடன் புதிய அரசாங்கத்தை அமைப்போம். இந்தச் செயலை எதிர்க்கும் அனைவரும் அடுத்தடுத்த அராஜகங்களுக்குப் பொறுப்பாவார்கள்.",
        "ஆனால் இந்த முறை, அது எந்த தேசிய தேர்தலுக்கும் பிறகு இல்லை. இது முன்னெப்போதும் இல்லாத வகையில் பதவியில் இருக்கும் ஜனாதிபதியின் ராஜினாமாவுக்குப் பிறகு.",
        "கோட்டாபய ராஜவோக்ச புதன்கிழமை பதவி விலகுவதாக உறுதியளித்துள்ளார். அவர் ஏற்கனவே நாட்டை விட்டு வெளியேறிவிட்டார் என சர்வதேச ஊடகங்கள் தெரிவிக்கின்றன, ஆனால் சபாநாயகர் இன்னும் உத்தியோகபூர்வமாக ராஜினாமாவை அறிவிக்கவில்லை.",
        "ஶ்ரீலங்கா பொதுஜன பெரமுனவின் அடுத்த ஜனாதிபதி தற்போதைய பிரதமரும், செயற்பாட்டு ஜனாதிபதியுமான ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்கவா அல்லது ஜனதா விமுக்தி பெரமுனவின் தலைவர் அனுரகுமார திஸாநாயக்கா அல்லது முன்னாள் ஊடகத்துறை அமைச்சர் டலஸ் அழகப்பெரும அல்லது எதிர்க்கட்சித் தலைவர் பிரேமதாசவை சுயேட்சையாகச் செல்வதா என தீர்மானிக்கும். அதன் சட்டமன்ற உறுப்பினர்கள் தங்கள் உணர்வுக்கு ஏற்ப வாக்களிக்க வேண்டும்.",
        "நாட்டை விட்டு தப்பிச் செல்ல முயற்சிக்கும் ராஜபக்சக்கள் கட்சி யாரை ஆதரிக்க வேண்டும் என்பதில் இன்னும் முக்கியமான முடிவெடுப்பவர்களாக இருக்க முடியும்.",
        "“ராஜபக்சேக்களை ராஜினாமா செய்ய வற்புறுத்தியதற்காக SLPP மக்களை தண்டிக்க விரும்பினால், அவர்கள் ஒரு திறமையற்ற தலைவரை அல்லது பாராளுமன்றத்தில் எந்த ஆதரவும் இல்லாத ஒரு தலைவரை தேர்ந்தெடுக்க வாக்களிக்கலாம். அதைச் செய்வதன் மூலம், SLPP மக்களின் துன்பத்தை இழுக்க முடியும், ”என்று ஒரு அரசியல் ஆய்வாளர் பெயர் குறிப்பிட வேண்டாம் என்று கேட்டார்.",
        "முன்னாள் பிரதமர் மகிந்த ராஜபக்சவைத் தவிர இன்னும் மூன்று ராஜபக்சக்கள் நாடாளுமன்றத்தில் சட்டமன்ற உறுப்பினர்களாக உள்ளனர்.",
        "அவர்கள் இப்போது ஆட்சியில் இல்லை என்றாலும், கணிசமான எண்ணிக்கையிலான SLPP சட்டமன்ற உறுப்பினர்கள் ராஜபக்சேக்கள் மீது, குறிப்பாக மகிந்த ராஜபக்ச மீது மரியாதை வைத்துள்ளனர். தீவு நாட்டின் வடக்கு மற்றும் கிழக்கு.",
        "ஜனாதிபதி ராஜினாமா செய்தவுடன், தற்போதைய பிரதமர் 30 நாட்களுக்கு தற்காலிக ஜனாதிபதியாக இருப்பார். பிரதமரும் பதவி விலகும் பட்சத்தில், நாடாளுமன்ற சபாநாயகர் தற்காலிக ஜனாதிபதியாக வருவார். 30 நாட்களுக்குள், பதவி விலகும் ஜனாதிபதியின் எஞ்சிய காலத்திற்கு நாட்டை நடத்துவதற்கு இடைக்கால ஜனாதிபதியை தற்காலிக ஜனாதிபதி தேர்ந்தெடுக்க வேண்டும்.",
        "சமீபத்திய இலங்கை நெருக்கடியில், ஜனாதிபதி கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ச, புதன்கிழமை ஜூலை 13 அன்று பதவி விலக ஒப்புக்கொண்டார். சபாநாயகர் மஹிந்த யாப்பா அபேவர்தன ஏற்கனவே ஜூலை 20 ஆம் தேதி வாக்கெடுப்பு நடத்த திட்டமிட்டுள்ளார்.",
        "வேட்புமனுக்கள் வெள்ளிக்கிழமை (15) பாராளுமன்ற செயலாளர் நாயகத்தால் அழைக்கப்படும் என்று எதிர்பார்க்கப்படுகிறது மற்றும் வேட்புமனுக்கள் ஜூலை 19 க்குள் சமர்ப்பிக்கப்பட வேண்டும்.",
        "அடுத்த ஜனாதிபதி என்று வரும்போது, ​​முன்னாள் ஜனாதிபதி மஹிந்த ராஜபக்ஷவைத் தவிர மற்ற அனைவரும் வேட்புமனு தாக்கல் செய்ய தகுதியுடையவர்கள். மகிந்த ராஜபக்ச மூன்றாவது தடவையாக ஜனாதிபதியாக பதவியேற்பதற்கு அரசியலமைப்பு தடையாக இருப்பதால் ஜனாதிபதியாக முடியாது.",
        "பாராளுமன்றத்தில் வேட்பாளரை முன்மொழிதல் மற்றும் இரண்டாம்ப்படுத்துதல் போன்ற வழக்கமான செயல்முறையின் மூலம் நியமனம் செய்யப்படுகிறது மற்றும் தற்போதைய நாடாளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர்களை மட்டுமே பரிந்துரைக்க முடியும். (கொழும்பு/ஜூலை 13/2022)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ராஜபக்சே",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "இலங்கையின்",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ராஜபக்சே",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "மஹிந்த ராஜபக்ஷ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "பொதுஜன பெரமுன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "225",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "2016",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "மஹிந்த ராஜபக்ஷ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "2015",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "மைத்திரிபால சிறிசேன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஜூலை 20",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "116",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "108",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஊடகம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "டலஸ் அழகப்பெரும",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "EconomyNext",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "8வது",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கையின்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "நிஷான் டி மெல்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "உண்மை ஆராய்ச்சி",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "2015",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "2019",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "2015&19",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "2015",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "மஹிந்த ராஜபக்ஷ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "2019",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "விக்கிரமசிங்கே",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "நவம்பர்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "சஜித் பிரேமதாச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "கடந்த 2½ ஆண்டுகள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": ".@கோட்டாபயஆர்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "@RW_UNP & பொஹொட்டுவா",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "கடந்த 2½ ஆண்டுகள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "கோட்டாபய ராஜஒக்ச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "புதன்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜனதா விமுக்தி பெரமுன",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "அனுரகுமார திஸாநாயக்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஊடகம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "டலஸ் அழகப்பெரும",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "பிரேமதாச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "மூன்று",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ராஜபக்சேக்கள்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "மஹிந்த ராஜபக்ஷ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ராஜபக்சேக்கள்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "மஹிந்த ராஜபக்ஷ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "26-ஆண்டு",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "வடக்கு மற்றும் கிழக்கு",
            "label": "LOC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "30 நாட்கள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "30 நாட்கள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜூலை 13 புதன்கிழமை",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "மஹிந்த யாப்பா அபேவர்தன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜூலை 20",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "வெள்ளி",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "15",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜூலை 19",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "மஹிந்த ராஜபக்ஷ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ராஜபக்சே",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "மூன்றாவது",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "கொழும்பு",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}