{
  "newspaper_id": "news-first-lk",
  "url": "https://www.newsfirst.lk/2022/06/28/kanchana-off-to-qatar-to-discuss-fuel-needs/",
  "time_ut": 1656389640,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Kanchana off to Qatar to discuss fuel needs",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Kanchana off to Qatar to discuss fuel needs",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); Minister of Power & Energy Kanchana Wijesekara and Minister of Environment Naseer Ahamed left for Qatar on Monday (27) to discuss matters relating to obtaining fuel for the country.",
        "The Duty Manager of the Katunayake International Airport said that the two Ministers left for Qatar at around 8.15 PM on Monday (27).",
        "The Ministers are scheduled to hold talks with Qatari authorities on the possibility of obtaining fuel for a certain period."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Kanchana",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "Qatar",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Power & Energy Kanchana Wijesekara",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Qatar",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Monday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "27",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the Katunayake International Airport",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "two",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Qatar",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "8.15 PM",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "Monday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "27",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Qatari",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "ඉන්ධන අවශ්‍යතා ගැන සාකච්ඡා කිරීමට කාංචනා කටාර් බලා පිටත් වෙයි",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); විදුලිබල හා බලශක්ති අමාත්‍ය කාංචන විජේසේකර සහ පරිසර අමාත්‍ය නසීර් අහමඩ් සඳුදා (27) කටාර් රාජ්‍යය බලා පිටත්ව ගියේ මෙරටට ඉන්ධන ලබා ගැනීම සම්බන්ධයෙන් සාකච්ඡා කිරීමටයි.",
        "කටුනායක ජාත්‍යන්තර ගුවන්තොටුපළේ රාජකාරි කළමණාකාරවරයා පැවසුවේ සඳුදා (27) රාත්‍රී 8.15 ට පමණ අමාත්‍යවරුන් දෙදෙනා කටාර් බලා පිටත්ව ගිය බවයි.",
        "නිශ්චිත කාලයක් සඳහා ඉන්ධන ලබාගැනීමේ හැකියාව පිළිබඳව අමාත්‍යවරුන් කටාර් බලධාරීන් සමඟ සාකච්ඡා කිරීමට නියමිතයි."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "කාංචනා",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "කටාර්",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "බලය සහ බලශක්ති කාංචන විජේසේකර",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "කටාර්",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "සඳුදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "27",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "කටුනායක ජාත්‍යන්තර ගුවන්තොටුපළ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "දෙක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "කටාර්",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "8.15 ප.ව",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "සඳුදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "27",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "කටාර්",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "எரிபொருள் தேவை குறித்து விவாதிக்க காஞ்சனா கத்தாருக்கு புறப்பட்டார்",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); மின்சக்தி மற்றும் எரிசக்தி அமைச்சர் காஞ்சன விஜேசேகர மற்றும் சுற்றாடல் அமைச்சர் நசீர் அஹமட் ஆகியோர் நாட்டிற்கான எரிபொருளை பெற்றுக்கொள்வது தொடர்பிலான விடயங்களை கலந்துரையாடுவதற்காக திங்கட்கிழமை (27) கட்டார் சென்றுள்ளனர்.",
        "இரண்டு அமைச்சர்களும் திங்கட்கிழமை (27) இரவு 8.15 மணியளவில் கட்டார் நோக்கிச் சென்றதாக கட்டுநாயக்க சர்வதேச விமான நிலையத்தின் கடமை முகாமையாளர் தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "குறிப்பிட்ட காலத்திற்கு எரிபொருளைப் பெறுவதற்கான சாத்தியக்கூறுகள் குறித்து கத்தார் அதிகாரிகளுடன் அமைச்சர்கள் பேச்சுவார்த்தை நடத்த உள்ளனர்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "காஞ்சனா",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "கத்தார்",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "பவர் & எனர்ஜி காஞ்சனா விஜேசேகர",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "கத்தார்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "திங்கட்கிழமை",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "27",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "கட்டுநாயக்க சர்வதேச விமான நிலையம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இரண்டு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "கத்தார்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "8.15 PM",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "திங்கட்கிழமை",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "27",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "கத்தார்",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}