{
  "newspaper_id": "daily-ft-lk",
  "url": "https://www.ft.lk/news/Marikkar-welcomes-release-of-Ranjan-calls-on-President-to-investigate-SLPP-MP-for-contempt/56-739167",
  "time_ut": 1661539685,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Marikkar welcomes release of Ranjan; calls on President to investigate SLPP MP for contempt",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Marikkar welcomes release of Ranjan; calls on President to investigate SLPP MP for contempt",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "SJB MP Kavinda Jayawardena calls on Harin to resign and make way for Ramanayake",
        "SJB MP S.M. Marikkar yesterday welcomed the conditional Presidential pardon granted to former MP Ranjan Ramanayake, who was released from prison.",
        "Marikkar stated that Ramanayake was found in contempt of court for comments he had made in passing to the press, and subsequently jailed. Ramanayake had not convened a media briefing and made a planned attack on the Judiciary, the SJB’s media spokesperson said.",
        "Marikkar said it places the spotlight on the recent comments made by SLPP MP Sanath Nishantha, who allegedly made disparaging comments on the Judiciary during a media briefing held at the party headquarters.",
        "“Many SLPP members have issues with the Judiciary, as many of them have been charged with various acts of violence and corruption. When a media briefing is convened by a party at its headquarters, and a party member criticises court it could be assumed that this is the position of the party. So this is not just an action by MP Sanath Nishantha, it becomes an action by the party and this should be investigated,” Marikkar said.",
        "He called on the President to conduct an inquiry into the matter as “part of his pledge” to uphold democracy and defeat fascist elements.",
        "During the media briefing yesterday, SJB MP Kavinda Jayawardena called on Minister Harin Fernando to resign from his National List seat in Parliament and make way for Ramanayake to return to the house. Fernando in 2021 made an offer to step down from his seat and make way for Ramanayake if he were freed from jail."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Marikkar",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "Ranjan",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Kavinda Jayawardena",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Harin",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ramanayake",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "SJB",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "S.M. Marikkar",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "yesterday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ranjan Ramanayake",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Marikkar",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ramanayake",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ramanayake",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Judiciary",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "SJB",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Marikkar",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sanath Nishantha",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sanath Nishantha",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Marikkar",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "yesterday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "SJB",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kavinda Jayawardena",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Harin Fernando",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "National List",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ramanayake",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Fernando",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "2021",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ramanayake",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "මරික්කාර් රන්ජන් නිදහස් කිරීම පිළිගනී; ශ්‍රී ලංකා පොදුජන පෙරමුණේ මන්ත්‍රීවරයාට අපහාස කිරීම සම්බන්ධයෙන් විමර්ශනයක් කරන ලෙස ජනාධිපතිවරයාගෙන් ඉල්ලා සිටියි",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "SJB පාර්ලිමේන්තු මන්ත්‍රී කාවින්ද ජයවර්ධන හරීන්ට ඉල්ලා අස්වී රාමනායකට මග සලසන ලෙස ඉල්ලා සිටී",
        "SJB පාර්ලිමේන්තු මන්ත්‍රී එස්.එම්. බන්ධනාගාරයෙන් නිදහස් වූ හිටපු පාර්ලිමේන්තු මන්ත්‍රී රන්ජන් රාමනායක මහතාට කොන්දේසි සහිත ජනාධිපති සමාව ලබා දීම පිළිබඳව මරික්කාර් ඊයේ සිය ප්‍රසාදය පළ කළේය.",
        "මරික්කාර් ප්‍රකාශ කළේ රාමනායක මහතා මාධ්‍ය වෙත ප්‍රකාශ කිරීම සම්බන්ධයෙන් අධිකරණයට අපහාස කළ බවට ඔප්පු වූ බවත්, පසුව ඔහු සිරගත කළ බවත්ය. රාමනායක මහතා මාධ්‍ය හමුවක් කැදවා අධිකරණයට සැලසුම් සහගත ප්‍රහාරයක් සිදු කර නොමැති බව SJB මාධ්‍ය ප්‍රකාශකවරයා පැවසීය.",
        "මරික්කාර් කියා සිටියේ පක්ෂ මූලස්ථානයේ පැවති මාධ්‍ය හමුවකදී අධිකරණයට අපහාස වන අයුරින් ප්‍රකාශ කළ බව කියන ශ්‍රී ලංකා පොදුජන පෙරමුණේ පාර්ලිමේන්තු මන්ත්‍රී සනත් නිශාන්ත විසින් පසුගියදා සිදුකළ ප්‍රකාශය පිළිබඳව අවධානය යොමු කරන බවයි.",
        "“ශ්‍රී ලංකා පොදුජන පෙරමුණේ බොහෝ සාමාජිකයින්ට අධිකරණය සමඟ ගැටලු තිබේ, ඔවුන්ගෙන් බොහෝ දෙනෙකුට විවිධ ප්‍රචණ්ඩ ක්‍රියා සහ දූෂණ චෝදනා එල්ල වී ඇත. පක්ෂ මූලස්ථානයේ මාධ්‍ය හමුවක් කැඳවා පාක්ෂිකයෙකු අධිකරණය විවේචනය කරන විට එය පක්ෂයේ ස්ථාවරය යැයි උපකල්පනය කළ හැකිය. ඉතින් මේක සනත් නිශාන්ත මන්ත්‍රීවරයාගේ ක්‍රියාවක් විතරක් නෙවෙයි, ඒක පක්ෂයේ ක්‍රියාවක් බවට පත්වෙනවා, මේ ගැන සොයා බැලිය යුතුයි” මරික්කාර් පැවසීය.",
        "ප‍්‍රජාතන්ත‍්‍රවාදය තහවුරු කිරීමට සහ ෆැසිස්ට්වාදී කොටස් පරාජය කිරීමට ඔහුගේ ප‍්‍රතිඥාවේ කොටසක් ලෙස මේ සම්බන්ධයෙන් පරීක්ෂණයක් පවත්වන ලෙස ඔහු ජනාධිපතිවරයාගෙන් ඉල්ලා සිටියේය.",
        "ඊයේ පැවති මාධ්‍ය හමුවේදී SJB පාර්ලිමේන්තු මන්ත්‍රී කාවින්ද ජයවර්ධන අමාත්‍ය හරීන් ප්‍රනාන්දු මහතාගෙන් ඉල්ලා සිටියේ තම ජාතික ලැයිස්තු මන්ත්‍රී ධුරයෙන් ඉල්ලා අස්වී රාමනායක මහතාට නිවසට පැමිණීමට ඉඩ සලසන ලෙසයි. ප්‍රනාන්දු 2021 දී ඔහුව හිරෙන් නිදහස් කළහොත් ඔහුගේ අසුනෙන් බැස රාමනායකට ඉඩ සලසන ලෙස යෝජනාවක් ඉදිරිපත් කළේය."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "මරික්කාර් ය",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "රන්ජන්",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "කාවින්ද ජයවර්ධන",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "හරීන්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "රාමනායක",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "එස්.ජේ.බී",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "එස්.එම්. මරික්කාර් ය",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඊයේ",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "රන්ජන් රාමනායක",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "මරික්කාර් ය",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "රාමනායක",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "රාමනායක",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "අධිකරණය",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "එස්.ජේ.බී",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "මරික්කාර් ය",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "සනත් නිශාන්ත",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "සනත් නිශාන්ත",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "මරික්කාර් ය",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "ඊයේ",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "එස්.ජේ.බී",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "කාවින්ද ජයවර්ධන",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "හරීන් ප්‍රනාන්දු",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජාතික ලැයිස්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "රාමනායක",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ප්‍රනාන්දු",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "2021",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "රාමනායක",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "ரஞ்சன் விடுதலையை மரிக்கார் வரவேற்றார்; ஸ்ரீலங்கா பொதுஜன பெரமுனவின் பாராளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர் அவமதிப்பு தொடர்பில் விசாரணை நடத்துமாறு ஜனாதிபதிக்கு அழைப்பு விடுக்கப்பட்டுள்ளது",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "SJB பாராளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர் காவிந்த ஜயவர்தன, ஹரினை இராஜினாமா செய்து ராமநாயக்கவுக்கு வழிவிடுமாறு அழைப்பு விடுத்துள்ளார்",
        "SJB பாராளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர் எஸ்.எம். சிறையிலிருந்து விடுவிக்கப்பட்ட முன்னாள் பாராளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர் ரஞ்சன் ராமநாயக்கவுக்கு நிபந்தனையுடன் கூடிய ஜனாதிபதி மன்னிப்பு வழங்கப்பட்டுள்ளதை மரிக்கார் நேற்று வரவேற்றுள்ளார்.",
        "ராமநாயக்க, ஊடகங்களுக்கு வழங்கிய கருத்துக்களுக்காக நீதிமன்றத்தை அவமதித்ததாகக் காணப்பட்டதாகவும், பின்னர் அவர் சிறையில் அடைக்கப்பட்டதாகவும் மரிக்கார் குறிப்பிட்டார். ராமநாயக்க ஊடகவியலாளர் சந்திப்பொன்றைக் கூட்டவில்லை மற்றும் நீதித்துறை மீது திட்டமிட்ட தாக்குதலை நடத்தவில்லை என SJB இன் ஊடகப் பேச்சாளர் தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "கட்சியின் தலைமையகத்தில் நடைபெற்ற ஊடகவியலாளர் சந்திப்பின் போது நீதித்துறையை இழிவுபடுத்தும் வகையில் கருத்து தெரிவித்ததாக கூறப்படும் ஸ்ரீலங்கா பொதுஜன பெரமுனவின் பாராளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர் சனத் நிஷாந்தவின் அண்மைய கருத்துக்கள் தொடர்பில் கவனம் செலுத்துவதாக மரிக்கார் கூறினார்.",
        "“பல SLPP உறுப்பினர்களுக்கு நீதித்துறையுடன் பிரச்சினைகள் உள்ளன, ஏனெனில் அவர்களில் பலர் பல்வேறு வன்முறை மற்றும் ஊழல் குற்றச்சாட்டுகள் சுமத்தப்பட்டுள்ளனர். கட்சியொன்று அதன் தலைமையகத்தில் ஊடகவியலாளர் சந்திப்பொன்றைக் கூட்டி, கட்சி உறுப்பினர் நீதிமன்றத்தை விமர்சிக்கும் போது, ​​கட்சியின் நிலைப்பாடு இதுதான் என்று கருதலாம். எனவே இது பாராளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர் சனத் நிஷாந்தவின் நடவடிக்கையல்ல, இது கட்சியின் நடவடிக்கையாக மாறுகிறது, இது குறித்து விசாரணை நடத்தப்பட வேண்டும்” என மரிக்கார் கூறினார்.",
        "ஜனநாயகத்தை நிலைநிறுத்துவதற்கும் பாசிச சக்திகளை தோற்கடிப்பதற்கும் \"அவரது உறுதிமொழியின் ஒரு பகுதியாக\" இந்த விவகாரம் குறித்து விசாரணை நடத்துமாறு ஜனாதிபதிக்கு அவர் அழைப்பு விடுத்தார்.",
        "நேற்றைய ஊடகவியலாளர் சந்திப்பின் போது, ​​SJB பாராளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர் காவிந்த ஜயவர்தன, அமைச்சர் ஹரீன் பெர்னாண்டோவை பாராளுமன்றத்தில் தனது தேசியப்பட்டியல் ஆசனத்தை இராஜினாமா செய்து ராமநாயக்கவை வீட்டிற்கு வர வழிவகை செய்யுமாறு அழைப்பு விடுத்தார். பெர்னாண்டோ 2021 இல் ராமநாயக்க சிறையிலிருந்து விடுவிக்கப்பட்டால், தனது இருக்கையில் இருந்து கீழே இறங்குவதாகவும், அவருக்கு வழிவகை செய்வதாகவும் கூறினார்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "மரிக்கார்",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "ரஞ்சன்",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "காவிந்த ஜெயவர்தன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஹரின்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ராமநாயக்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "எஸ்.ஜே.பி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "எஸ்.எம். மரிக்கார்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "நேற்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரஞ்சன் ராமநாயக்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "மரிக்கார்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ராமநாயக்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ராமநாயக்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "நீதித்துறை",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "எஸ்.ஜே.பி",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "மரிக்கார்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "சனத் நிஷாந்த",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "சனத் நிஷாந்த",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "மரிக்கார்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "நேற்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "எஸ்.ஜே.பி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "காவிந்த ஜெயவர்தன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஹரின் பெர்னாண்டோ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "தேசிய பட்டியல்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ராமநாயக்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "பெர்னாண்டோ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "2021",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ராமநாயக்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}