{
  "newspaper_id": "news-first-lk",
  "url": "https://www.newsfirst.lk/2022/08/31/sri-lanka-invites-saudi-arabia-to-set-up-oil-refinery-report/",
  "time_ut": 1661942820,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Sri Lanka invites Saudi Arabia to set up oil refinery – Report",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Sri Lanka invites Saudi Arabia to set up oil refinery – Report",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "Sri Lanka is seeking to boost energy cooperation with Saudi Arabia and has invited the Kingdom to set up a refinery in the South Asian nation, a special envoy of President Ranil Wickremesinghe said on Tuesday (30).",
        "Environment Minister Naseer Ahamed arrived in Riyadh on Sunday (28) as special envoy of the Sri Lankan president and has since held meetings with officials from the Kingdom, including Saudi Deputy Minister of Foreign Affairs Waleed Al-Khuraiji and CEO of the Saudi Fund for Development Sultan Al-Marshad.",
        "Ahamed, who assumed his ministerial duties in late May and also oversees Middle Eastern affairs, told Arab News that improving cooperation with Saudi Arabia would be helpful in “easing the current economic crisis” in Sri Lanka.",
        "The nation of 22 million people is facing its worst economic crisis since independence. For months people have suffered severe shortages of essentials, such as food, medicines and fuel, as the inflation rate surged to a record 60.8 percent in July.",
        "“We are offering Saudi Arabia to have its own refinery in Sri Lanka,” Ahamed said in a phone interview with Arab News. “We can also provide enough storage facilities on the island which could cover the region.”",
        "Colombo is seeking to “form long-term relations” with Saudi Arabia in the energy and fuel sectors, including for the supply of gas and crude oil.",
        "Sri Lanka has been struggling to find critical funding to finance essential imports, with its existing stock of petrol and diesel all but dry. The crisis had seen long queues of drivers at gas pumps across the country earlier this year, when people waited for days to fill their vehicles.",
        "Ahamed said that Saudi’s 2030 Vision, a reform plan designed to diversify the Kingdom’s economy, could also benefit Sri Lanka.",
        "“As you know, Saudi Arabia is one of the major economic powers in the region, especially in the field of energy sector. The 2030 Vision of the Crown Prince Mohammed bin Salman has attracted the whole world including Sri Lanka,” Ahamed said.",
        "“Our president wants to make use of this Vision by cooperating with the Kingdom to develop its goals and also to benefit from such developments, which would improve the Saudi-Lanka energy security cooperation.”",
        "Ahamed is optimistic that stronger energy cooperation will boost bilateral trade to billions of dollars from the current $300 million, and “enable Sri Lanka to buy oil with long-term conditions.”",
        "Sri Lanka is also seeking to tap Saudi investors for the country’s mining industry, he said.",
        "As his Saudi trip was set to conclude on Wednesday, Ahamed was optimistic about the outcome of his visit.",
        "“We are positive that Saudi Arabia will help Sri Lanka in granting some relief by supporting our projects and open up new areas of cooperation to strengthen the bilateral relations,” he said.",
        "One-month-old infant abandoned at a motor garage with a letter",
        "Are you a victim of Cyber Crime? Police Unit ready to crackdown crime in the cyberspace"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Sri Lanka",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "Saudi Arabia",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Saudi Arabia",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kingdom",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "South Asian",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Tuesday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "30",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Naseer Ahamed",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Riyadh",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sunday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "28",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lankan",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kingdom",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Saudi",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Waleed Al-Khuraiji",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Saudi Fund for Development",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sultan Al-Marshad",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "late May",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Middle Eastern",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Arab News",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Saudi Arabia",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "22 million",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "months",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "60.8 percent",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "July",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Saudi Arabia",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Arab News",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Saudi Arabia",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "earlier this year",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "days",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Saudi’s 2030 Vision",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kingdom",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Saudi Arabia",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "one",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "The 2030 Vision of",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Mohammed bin Salman",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Kingdom",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Saudi",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "billions of dollars",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "$300 million",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Saudi",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Saudi",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Wednesday",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Saudi Arabia",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "One-month-old",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Cyber Crime",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "තෙල් පිරිපහදුවක් පිහිටුවීමට ශ්‍රී ලංකාව සෞදි අරාබියට ආරාධනා කරයි – වාර්තාව",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "සෞදි අරාබිය සමඟ බලශක්ති සහයෝගීතාව ඉහළ නැංවීමට ශ්‍රී ලංකාව අපේක්ෂා කරන අතර දකුණු ආසියානු ජාතිය තුළ පිරිපහදුවක් පිහිටුවීමට රාජධානියට ආරාධනා කර ඇති බව ජනාධිපති රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහගේ විශේෂ නියෝජිත අඟහරුවාදා (30) පැවසීය.",
        "පරිසර අමාත්‍ය නසීර් අහමඩ් ශ්‍රී ලංකා ජනාධිපතිවරයාගේ විශේෂ නියෝජිතයා ලෙස ඉරිදා (28) රියාද් වෙත පැමිණි අතර එතැන් සිට සෞදි විදේශ කටයුතු නියෝජ්‍ය අමාත්‍ය Waleed Al-Khuraiji සහ Saudi Fund for Development හි ප්‍රධාන විධායක නිලධාරී ඇතුළු රාජධානියේ නිලධාරීන් සමඟ සාකච්ඡා පවත්වා තිබේ. සුල්තාන් අල්-මර්ෂාඩ්.",
        "මැයි මස අගදී සිය අමාත්‍ය ධුර භාරගත් අතර මැද පෙරදිග කටයුතු ද අධීක්‍ෂණය කරන අහමඩ් Arab News වෙත පැවසුවේ සෞදි අරාබිය සමඟ සහයෝගීතාව වැඩිදියුණු කිරීම ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ “වර්තමාන ආර්ථික අර්බුදය ලිහිල් කිරීමට” උපකාරී වනු ඇති බවයි.",
        "මිලියන 22 ක ජනතාවක් සිටින ජාතිය නිදහසින් පසු එහි දරුණුතම ආර්ථික අර්බුදයට මුහුණ දී සිටී. උද්ධමන අනුපාතිකය ජූලි මාසයේදී වාර්තාගත සියයට 60.8ක් දක්වා ඉහළ ගිය හෙයින් මාස ගනනාවක් තිස්සේ ජනතාව ආහාර, ඖෂධ සහ ඉන්ධන වැනි අත්‍යවශ්‍ය ද්‍රව්‍යවල උග්‍ර හිඟයකට ගොදුරු වී ඇත.",
        "\"අපි සෞදි අරාබියට ශ්‍රී ලංකාව තුළ තමන්ගේම පිරිපහදුවක් ඇති කර ගැනීමට ඉදිරිපත් වෙමු,\" Arab News සමඟ දුරකථන සම්මුඛ සාකච්ඡාවකදී අහමඩ් පැවසීය. කලාපය ආවරණය කළ හැකි ප්‍රමාණවත් ගබඩා පහසුකම් දිවයිනේ අපට සැපයිය හැකිය.",
        "ගෑස් සහ බොරතෙල් සැපයීම ඇතුළු බලශක්ති හා ඉන්ධන අංශයන්හි සෞදි අරාබිය සමග “දිගුකාලීන සබඳතා ඇති කර ගැනීමට” කොළඹ උත්සාහ කරයි.",
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකාව දැනට පවතින පෙට්‍රල් සහ ඩීසල් තොග වියළි හැරුණු විට අත්‍යවශ්‍ය ආනයන සඳහා මූල්‍යමය වශයෙන් තීරණාත්මක අරමුදල් සොයා ගැනීමට අරගල කරමින් සිටී. මෙම අර්බුදය නිසා මේ වසර මුලදී රට පුරා ගෑස් පොම්පවල රියදුරන්ගේ දිගු පෝලිම් දක්නට ලැබුණි, මිනිසුන් තම වාහන පුරවා ගැනීමට දින ගණන් බලා සිටි විට.",
        "සෞදි අරාබියේ 2030 දැක්ම, රාජධානියේ ආර්ථිකය විවිධාංගීකරණය කිරීම සඳහා නිර්මාණය කර ඇති ප්‍රතිසංස්කරණ සැලැස්ම ශ්‍රී ලංකාවට ද ප්‍රතිලාභ ලැබිය හැකි බව අහමඩ් පැවසීය.",
        "“ඔබ දන්නා පරිදි, සෞදි අරාබිය කලාපයේ ප්‍රධාන ආර්ථික බලවතුන්ගෙන් එකකි, විශේෂයෙන් බලශක්ති ක්ෂේත්‍රයේ. ඔටුන්න හිමි මොහොමඩ් බින් සල්මාන් කුමරුගේ 2030 දැක්ම ශ්‍රී ලංකාව ඇතුළු මුළු ලෝකයම ආකර්ෂණය කර ගෙන ඇත,” අහමඩ් පැවසීය.",
        "\"අපේ ජනාධිපතිවරයාට අවශ්‍ය වන්නේ සෞදි-ලංකා බලශක්ති ආරක්ෂණ සහයෝගීතාව වැඩිදියුණු කරන එවැනි වර්ධනයන්ගෙන් ප්‍රතිලාභ ලබා ගැනීමට සහ එහි අරමුණු වර්ධනය කර ගැනීම සඳහා රාජධානිය සමඟ සහයෝගයෙන් මෙම දැක්ම ප්‍රයෝජනයට ගැනීමටයි.\"",
        "ශක්තිමත් බලශක්ති සහයෝගීතාවය ද්විපාර්ශ්වික වෙළඳාම වත්මන් ඩොලර් මිලියන 300 සිට ඩොලර් බිලියන ගනනක් දක්වා ඉහළ නංවනු ඇති බවටත්, \"දිගුකාලීන කොන්දේසි සහිතව ශ්‍රී ලංකාවට තෙල් මිලදී ගැනීමට හැකි වනු ඇති\" බවත් අහමඩ් ශුභවාදී ය.",
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකාව ද රටේ පතල් කර්මාන්තය සඳහා සෞදි ආයෝජකයින් ගෙන්වා ගැනීමට උත්සාහ කරන බව ඔහු පැවසීය.",
        "ඔහුගේ සෞදි සංචාරය බදාදා අවසන් වීමට නියමිතව තිබූ බැවින්, අහමඩ් ඔහුගේ සංචාරයේ ප්‍රතිඵලය ගැන ශුභවාදී විය.",
        "“අපගේ ව්‍යාපෘති සඳහා සහය දැක්වීමෙන් සහ ද්විපාර්ශ්වික සබඳතා ශක්තිමත් කිරීම සඳහා සහයෝගීතාවයේ නව ක්ෂේත්‍ර විවෘත කිරීමෙන් යම් සහනයක් ලබා දීමට සෞදි අරාබිය ශ්‍රී ලංකාවට උපකාර කරනු ඇතැයි අපි ධනාත්මකව සිටිමු,” ඔහු පැවසීය.",
        "ලිපියක් සමඟ මෝටර් රථ ගරාජයක දමා ගිය මාසයක් වයසැති ළදරුවා",
        "ඔබ සයිබර් අපරාධයට ගොදුරු වූවෙක්ද? සයිබර් අවකාශයේ සිදුවන අපරාධ මර්දනයට පොලිස් ඒකකය සූදානම්"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "සවුදි අරාබිය",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "සවුදි අරාබිය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "රාජධානිය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "දකුණු ආසියානු",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "අඟහරුවාදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "30",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "නසීර් අහමඩ්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "රියාද්",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉරිදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "28",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලාංකික",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "රාජධානිය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "සෞදි",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "වලීඩ් අල්-කුරයිජි",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "සංවර්ධනය සඳහා සෞදි අරමුදල",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "සුල්තාන් අල්-මර්ෂාඩ්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "මැයි අග",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මැද පෙරදිග",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "අරාබි පුවත්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "සවුදි අරාබිය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "මිලියන 22 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "මාස",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "සියයට 60.8 කි",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජුලි",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "සවුදි අරාබිය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "අරාබි පුවත්",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "සවුදි අරාබිය",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මීට පෙර මෙම වසරේ",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "දින",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "සෞදියේ 2030 දැක්ම",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "රාජධානිය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "සවුදි අරාබිය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "එක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "2030 දැක්ම",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "මොහොමඩ් බින් සල්මාන්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "රාජධානිය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "සෞදි",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ඩොලර් බිලියන ගණනක්",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඩොලර් මිලියන 300 කි",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "සෞදි",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "සෞදි",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "බදාදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "සවුදි අරාබිය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "මාසයක් වයසැති",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "සයිබර් අපරාධ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "எண்ணெய் சுத்திகரிப்பு நிலையத்தை அமைக்க சவூதி அரேபியாவுக்கு இலங்கை அழைப்பு – அறிக்கை",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "சவூதி அரேபியாவுடன் எரிசக்தி ஒத்துழைப்பை அதிகரிக்க இலங்கை முயன்று வருவதாகவும் தெற்காசிய நாட்டில் ஒரு சுத்திகரிப்பு நிலையத்தை அமைப்பதற்கு இராச்சியத்தை அழைத்துள்ளதாக ஜனாதிபதி ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்கவின் விசேட தூதுவர் செவ்வாய்கிழமை (30) தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "சுற்றாடல் அமைச்சர் நசீர் அஹமட், ஞாயிற்றுக்கிழமை (28) இலங்கை ஜனாதிபதியின் விசேட தூதுவராக ரியாத்துக்கு வருகை தந்ததுடன், சவுதி அரேபிய பிரதி வெளிவிவகார அமைச்சர் வலீத் அல் குரைஜி மற்றும் அபிவிருத்திக்கான சவூதி நிதியத்தின் பிரதம நிறைவேற்று அதிகாரி உட்பட இராச்சியத்தின் அதிகாரிகளை சந்தித்து கலந்துரையாடியுள்ளார். சுல்தான் அல்-மர்ஷத்.",
        "மே மாத இறுதியில் தனது அமைச்சுக் கடமைகளை பொறுப்பேற்றுக் கொண்ட அஹமட், மத்திய கிழக்கு விவகாரங்களை மேற்பார்வையிடும் Arab News இடம், சவூதி அரேபியாவுடனான ஒத்துழைப்பை மேம்படுத்துவது இலங்கையின் \"தற்போதைய பொருளாதார நெருக்கடியைத் தணிக்க\" உதவியாக இருக்கும் என்று கூறினார்.",
        "22 மில்லியன் மக்கள் வாழும் நாடு சுதந்திரத்திற்குப் பிறகு மிக மோசமான பொருளாதார நெருக்கடியை எதிர்கொண்டுள்ளது. ஜூலை மாதத்தில் பணவீக்க விகிதம் 60.8 சதவீதமாக உயர்ந்ததால், பல மாதங்களாக உணவு, மருந்துகள் மற்றும் எரிபொருள் போன்ற அத்தியாவசியப் பொருட்களுக்கு மக்கள் கடுமையான பற்றாக்குறையை எதிர்கொண்டுள்ளனர்.",
        "\"சௌதி அரேபியாவிற்கு இலங்கையில் சொந்த சுத்திகரிப்பு ஆலையை அமைக்க நாங்கள் முன்வருகிறோம்\" என்று அஹமட் அரபு நியூஸ் உடனான தொலைபேசி பேட்டியில் கூறினார். \"நாங்கள் தீவில் போதுமான சேமிப்பு வசதிகளை வழங்க முடியும், இது பிராந்தியத்தை உள்ளடக்கியது.\"",
        "எரிவாயு மற்றும் கச்சா எண்ணெய் விநியோகம் உட்பட எரிசக்தி மற்றும் எரிபொருள் துறைகளில் சவூதி அரேபியாவுடன் \"நீண்ட கால உறவுகளை\" உருவாக்க கொழும்பு முயல்கிறது.",
        "அத்தியாவசிய இறக்குமதிகளுக்கு நிதியளிப்பதற்கான முக்கியமான நிதியைக் கண்டுபிடிக்க இலங்கை போராடி வருகிறது, தற்போதுள்ள பெட்ரோல் மற்றும் டீசல் அனைத்தும் வறண்ட நிலையில் உள்ளது. நெருக்கடி இந்த ஆண்டின் தொடக்கத்தில் நாடு முழுவதும் எரிவாயு பம்புகளில் ஓட்டுநர்களின் நீண்ட வரிசைகளைக் கண்டது, மக்கள் தங்கள் வாகனங்களை நிரப்ப பல நாட்கள் காத்திருந்தனர்.",
        "சவூதியின் 2030 தொலைநோக்கு, இராச்சியத்தின் பொருளாதாரத்தை பன்முகப்படுத்த வடிவமைக்கப்பட்ட சீர்திருத்தத் திட்டம், இலங்கைக்கும் பயனளிக்கக்கூடும் என்று அஹமட் கூறினார்.",
        "“உங்களுக்குத் தெரியும், சவுதி அரேபியா பிராந்தியத்தின் முக்கிய பொருளாதார சக்திகளில் ஒன்றாகும், குறிப்பாக எரிசக்தி துறையில். பட்டத்து இளவரசர் முகமது பின் சல்மானின் 2030 தொலைநோக்கு இலங்கை உட்பட முழு உலகையும் ஈர்த்துள்ளது” என்று அஹமட் கூறினார்.",
        "சவூதி-இலங்கை எரிசக்தி பாதுகாப்பு ஒத்துழைப்பை மேம்படுத்தும் இத்தகைய அபிவிருத்திகளில் இருந்து பயனடைவதற்கும் அதன் இலக்குகளை அபிவிருத்தி செய்வதற்கும் இராச்சியத்துடன் ஒத்துழைப்பதன் மூலம் எமது ஜனாதிபதி இந்த தொலைநோக்குப் பார்வையைப் பயன்படுத்த விரும்புகின்றார்.",
        "வலுவான எரிசக்தி ஒத்துழைப்பு இருதரப்பு வர்த்தகத்தை தற்போதைய $300 மில்லியனில் இருந்து பில்லியன் டாலர்களாக உயர்த்தும் என்றும், \"நீண்ட கால நிபந்தனைகளுடன் இலங்கைக்கு எண்ணெய் வாங்க உதவும்\" என்றும் அஹமட் நம்பிக்கை தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "நாட்டின் சுரங்கத் தொழிலுக்கு சவூதி முதலீட்டாளர்களைத் தட்டியெழுப்ப இலங்கையும் முயற்சிக்கிறது, என்றார்.",
        "தனது சவூதி பயணம் புதன்கிழமை முடிவடைய இருந்த நிலையில், அஹமட் தனது விஜயத்தின் முடிவைப் பற்றி நம்பிக்கையுடன் இருந்தார்.",
        "\"எமது திட்டங்களுக்கு ஆதரவளிப்பதன் மூலமும், இருதரப்பு உறவுகளை வலுப்படுத்த புதிய ஒத்துழைப்பைத் திறப்பதன் மூலமும் இலங்கைக்கு சில நிவாரணங்களை வழங்க சவூதி அரேபியா உதவும் என்பதில் நாங்கள் சாதகமாக உள்ளோம்\" என்று அவர் கூறினார்.",
        "கடிதத்துடன் மோட்டார் கேரேஜில் கைவிடப்பட்ட ஒரு மாத கைக்குழந்தை",
        "நீங்கள் சைபர் கிரைம் பாதிக்கப்பட்டவரா? சைபர்ஸ்பேஸ் குற்றங்களை ஒடுக்க போலீஸ் பிரிவு தயார்"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "இலங்கை",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "சவூதி அரேபியா",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சவூதி அரேபியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இராச்சியம்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "தெற்காசிய",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "செவ்வாய்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "30",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "நசீர் அகமது",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரியாத்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஞாயிற்றுக்கிழமை",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "28",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "இராச்சியம்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சவுதி",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "வலீத் அல் குரைஜி",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "வளர்ச்சிக்கான சவுதி நிதி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "சுல்தான் அல்-மர்ஷத்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "மே மாத இறுதியில்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "மத்திய கிழக்கு",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "அரபு செய்திகள்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "சவூதி அரேபியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "22 மில்லியன்",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "மாதங்கள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "60.8 சதவீதம்",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜூலை",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "சவூதி அரேபியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "அரபு செய்திகள்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "சவூதி அரேபியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்த ஆண்டின் தொடக்கத்தில்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "நாட்களில்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "சவுதியின் 2030 பார்வை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இராச்சியம்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "சவூதி அரேபியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஒன்று",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "2030 இன் பார்வை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "முகமது பின் சல்மான்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இராச்சியம்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சவுதி",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பில்லியன் டாலர்கள்",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "$300 மில்லியன்",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சவுதி",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "சவுதி",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "புதன்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "சவூதி அரேபியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஒரு மாத வயது",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "சைபர்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}