{
  "newspaper_id": "ada-lk",
  "url": "https://www.ada.lk/breaking_news/උසස්පෙළ-හපන්න්නු-මෙන්න/11-396677",
  "time_ut": 1661714217,
  "original_lang": "si",
  "original_title": "උසස්පෙළ හපන්න්නු මෙන්න",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "High school is here",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "Ishara Lakmal Heenkenda, who studied at Badulla Candagolla Maha Vidyalaya, managed to record the most outstanding result among the students who secured the top positions in the island in the 2021 General Certificate of Advanced Level Examination. Recorded the first place in the island in the art section.",
        "Neranda Dilhara Kumarasinghe student of Naramla Mayurapara Central High School has won the first place in the engineering technology section.",
        "Tamilvanan Tuvarakesh, student of St. Michael's College, Batticaloa, stood first in the biology section.",
        "Ishini Neha Amararatne, a student of Gampaha Ratnawali Girls' College, managed to get the first place in the island in the commercial section."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Ishara Lakmal Heenkenda",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Badulla Candagolla Maha Vidyalaya",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "2021",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "first",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Neranda",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kumarasinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Naramla Mayurapara Central High School",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "first",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Tamilvanan Tuvarakesh",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "St. Michael's College, Batticaloa",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "first",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Ishini Neha Amararatne",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Gampaha Ratnawali Girls'",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "first",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "උසස්පෙළ හපන්න්නු මෙන්න",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "2021 අධ්‍යයන පොදු සහතික පත්‍ර උසස් පෙළ විභාගයේ දිවයිනේ මුල් ස්ථාන ලබාගත් සිසුන් අතරින් මෙවර කැපී පෙනෙනම ප්‍රථිඵලය වාර්තා කිරීමට බදුල්ල කැන්දගොල්ල මහා විද්‍යාලයේ ඉගෙනුම ලැබු ඉෂාර ලක්මාල් හීන්කෙන්ද සිසුවා සමත්විය. ඒ කලා අංශයෙන් දිවයිනේම පළමු ස්ථානය වාර්තා කරමිනි.",
        "ඉංජිනේරු තාක්ෂණවේද අංශයේ දිවයිනේ ප්‍රථමස්ථානය  නාරාම්ල මයුරපාර මධ්‍යම මහා විද්‍යාලයේනෙරන්ද දිල්හාර කුමාරසිංහ සිසුවාට හිමිකරගෙන තිබේ.",
        "ජීව විද්‍යා අංශයේ ප්‍රථම ස්ථානය මඩකලපුව ශාන්ත මයිකල් විද්‍යාලයේ තමිල්වානන් තුවාරකේෂ් සිසුවායි.",
        "වානිජ අංශයෙන් දිවයිනෙන් ප්‍රථම ස්ථානය ලබා ගැනීමට  ගම්පහ රත්නාවලී බාලිකා විද්‍යාලයේ ඉෂිනි නේහා අමරරත්න සිසුවිය සමත් වූවාය."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ඉෂාර ලක්මාල් හීන්කෙන්ද",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "බදුල්ල කඳගොල්ල මහා විද්‍යාලය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "2021",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "පළමුවන",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "නෙරන්ඩ",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "කුමාරසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "නාරම්ල මයුරපාර මධ්‍ය මහා විද්‍යාලය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "පළමුවන",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "තමිල්වානන් තුවාරකේෂ්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "මඩකලපුව ශාන්ත මයිකල් විද්‍යාලය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "පළමුවන",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ඉෂිනි නේහා අමරරත්න",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගම්පහ රත්නාවලී බාලිකා'",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "පළමුවන",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "உயர்நிலைப் பள்ளி இங்கே உள்ளது",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "பதுளை கந்தகொல்ல மகா வித்தியாலயத்தில் கல்வி பயின்ற இஷார லக்மால் ஹீன்கெந்த, 2021 ஆம் ஆண்டுக்கான உயர்தரப் பரீட்சையின் பொதுச் சான்றிதழில் நாட்டில் உயர் பதவிகளைப் பெற்ற மாணவர்களில் மிகச் சிறந்த பெறுபேற்றைப் பதிவு செய்ய முடிந்தது. கலைப் பிரிவில் தீவுத்திடலில் முதலிடத்தைப் பதிவு செய்தார்.",
        "பொறியியல் தொழில்நுட்பப் பிரிவில் நரம்ல மயூரபர மத்திய மகா வித்தியாலயத்தைச் சேர்ந்த நெரந்த தில்ஹார குமாரசிங்க முதலாம் இடத்தைப் பெற்றுள்ளார்.",
        "உயிரியல் பிரிவில் மட்டக்களப்பு புனித மிக்கேல் கல்லூரி மாணவன் தமிழ்வாணன் துவரகேஷ் முதலிடத்தைப் பெற்றுக் கொண்டார்.",
        "கம்பஹா ரத்னாவலி மகளிர் கல்லூரி மாணவி இஷினி நேஹா அமரரத்ன வர்த்தகப் பிரிவில் நாடளாவிய ரீதியில் முதலாம் இடத்தைப் பெற முடிந்தது."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "இஷார லக்மால் ஹீன்கெந்த",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "பதுளை கந்தகொல்ல மகா வித்தியாலயம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "2021",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "முதலில்",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "நெராண்டா",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "குமாரசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "நாரம்லா மயூரபாரா மத்திய உயர்நிலைப்பள்ளி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "முதலில்",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "தமிழ்வாணன் துவாரகேஷ்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "புனித மைக்கேல் கல்லூரி, மட்டக்களப்பு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "முதலில்",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இஷினி நேஹா அமரரத்ன",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "கம்பஹா ரத்னாவலி பெண்கள்'",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "முதலில்",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}