{
  "newspaper_id": "daily-mirror-lk",
  "url": "https://www.dailymirror.lk/breaking_news/Gotabaya-Rajapaksa-advised-to-remain-indoors-for-security-reasons-at-Bangkok-hotel/108-242937",
  "time_ut": 1660312319,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Gotabaya Rajapaksa advised to remain indoors for security reasons at Bangkok hotel",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Gotabaya Rajapaksa advised to remain indoors for security reasons at Bangkok hotel",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "Former President Gotabaya Rajapaksa is staying at a hotel in Bangkok in the heart of Thailand's capital, where police have advised the ousted Sri Lankan president to remain indoors for security reasons, according to a media report on Friday.",
        "Rajapaksa arrived in Thailand with three other people on a chartered flight from Singapore at Wing 6 of the military airport adjacent to Don Mueang International Airport around 8 pm local time on Thursday.",
        "The group had planned to land in Phuket but concerns about a possible information leak resulted in the flight being redirected to the military airport in Bangkok, the Bangkok Post newspaper reported, citing a source.",
        "At the hotel, the location of which was not disclosed, plainclothes police officers from the Special Branch Bureau have been deployed to ensure safety of Rajapaksa. Officials have asked the embattled former Sri Lankan president to remain within the hotel during his stay in the country, the report said.",
        "Rajapaksa arrived in Bangkok on the same day that his visa in Singapore expired. He arrived here for a temporary stay before seeking permanent asylum in another country.",
        "Prime Minister Prayut Chan-o-cha on Wednesday confirmed a temporary visit to Thailand by the 73-year-old Sri Lankan leader for humanitarian reasons, and said he promised not to conduct political activities in the kingdom during his search for permanent asylum in another country.",
        "After fleeing to the Maldives on July 13, Rajapaksa then flew to Singapore, where he announced his resignation a day later after months of protests over Sri Lanka's unprecedented economic crisis.(PTI)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Gotabaya Rajapaksa",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "Bangkok",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Gotabaya Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Bangkok",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Thailand",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lankan",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Friday",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Rajapaksa",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Thailand",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "three",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Singapore",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "6",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Don Mueang International Airport",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "around 8 pm",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "Thursday",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Phuket",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Bangkok",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Bangkok Post",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the Special Branch Bureau",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Rajapaksa",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lankan",
            "label": "LOC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Bangkok",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Singapore",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Prayut Chan",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Wednesday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Thailand",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "73-year-old",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lankan",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Maldives",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "July 13",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Singapore",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "a day later after months",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka's",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "බැංකොක් හෝටලයේ ආරක්ෂක හේතූන් මත නිවසේ රැඳී සිටින ලෙස ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ උපදෙස් දුන්නේය",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "හිටපු ජනාධිපති ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ තායිලන්තයේ අගනුවර මැද පිහිටි බැංකොක් හි හෝටලයක නවාතැන් ගෙන සිටින අතර, බලයෙන් පහ කරන ලද ශ්‍රී ලංකා ජනාධිපතිවරයාට ආරක්ෂක හේතූන් මත නිවෙස් තුළම සිටින ලෙස පොලිසිය උපදෙස් දී ඇතැයි සිකුරාදා මාධ්‍ය වාර්තාවක දැක්වේ.",
        "රාජපක්ෂ තවත් පුද්ගලයින් තිදෙනෙකු සමඟ සිංගප්පූරුවේ සිට වරලත් ගුවන් යානයකින් තායිලන්තයට පැමිණියේ බ්‍රහස්පතින්දා දේශීය වේලාවෙන් රාත්‍රී 8 ට පමණ දොන් මුවැන්ග් ජාත්‍යන්තර ගුවන්තොටුපළට යාබද හමුදා ගුවන් තොටුපළේ වින්ග් 6 හි ය.",
        "කණ්ඩායම ෆුකෙට් වෙත ගොඩ බැසීමට සැලසුම් කර ඇති නමුත් තොරතුරු කාන්දු වීම පිළිබඳ කනස්සල්ල හේතුවෙන් ගුවන් යානය බැංකොක්හි හමුදා ගුවන් තොටුපළ වෙත හරවා යැවීමට හේතු වූ බව බැංකොක් පෝස්ට් පුවත්පත වාර්තා කළේය.",
        "එම හෝටලයේ ස්ථානය හෙළි නොකළ අතර රාජපක්ෂගේ ආරක්ෂාව සඳහා විශේෂ ශාඛා කාර්යාංශයේ සිවිල් ඇඳුමින් සැරසුණු පොලිස් නිලධාරීන් යොදවා ඇත. පැටලී සිටින හිටපු ශ්‍රී ලංකා ජනාධිපතිවරයාට රට තුළ රැඳී සිටින කාලය තුළ හෝටලය තුළම රැඳී සිටින ලෙස නිලධාරීන් ඉල්ලා ඇතැයි වාර්තාවේ.",
        "රාජපක්ෂ බැංකොක් වෙත පැමිණියේ සිංගප්පූරුවේ වීසා කාලය අවසන් වූ දිනයේමය. ඔහු වෙනත් රටක ස්ථීර සරණාගතභාවය ලබා ගැනීමට පෙර තාවකාලික රැඳී සිටීම සඳහා මෙහි පැමිණියේය.",
        "මානුෂීය හේතූන් මත 73 හැවිරිදි ශ්‍රී ලංකා නායකයාගේ තාවකාලික සංචාරයක් අගමැති ප්‍රයුත් චාන්-ඕ-චා බදාදා තහවුරු කළ අතර, වෙනත් රටක ස්ථිර රැකවරණ සෙවීමේදී රාජධානියේ දේශපාලන කටයුතු සිදු නොකරන බවට තමා පොරොන්දු වූ බව පැවසීය. රට.",
        "ජූලි 13 වන දින මාලදිවයිනට පලා යාමෙන් පසු රාජපක්ෂ පසුව සිංගප්පූරුවට පියාසර කළ අතර, ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ පෙර නොවූ විරූ ආර්ථික අර්බුදය සම්බන්ධයෙන් මාස ගණනාවක විරෝධතා වලින් පසුව දිනකට පසුව ඔහු ඉල්ලා අස්වන බව නිවේදනය කළේය.(PTI)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "බැංකොක්",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "බැංකොක්",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "තායිලන්තය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලාංකික",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "සිකුරාදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "තායිලන්තය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "තුන්",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "සිංගප්පූරුව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "6",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Don Mueang ජාත්‍යන්තර ගුවන් තොටුපළ",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "රාත්‍රී 8ට පමණ",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "බ්රහස්පතින්දා",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ෆුකෙට්",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "බැංකොක්",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "බැංකොක් පෝස්ට්",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "විශේෂ ශාඛා කාර්යාංශය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලාංකික",
            "label": "LOC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "බැංකොක්",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "සිංගප්පූරුව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ප්‍රයුත් චාන්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "බදාදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "තායිලන්තය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "73 හැවිරිදිය",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලාංකික",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "මාලදිවයින",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජූලි 13",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "සිංගප්පූරුව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මාසයකට පසු දිනකට පසුව",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "பாங்கொக் ஹோட்டலில் பாதுகாப்பு காரணங்களுக்காக வீட்டுக்குள்ளேயே இருக்குமாறு கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ச அறிவுறுத்தியுள்ளார்",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "முன்னாள் ஜனாதிபதி கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ச தாய்லாந்தின் தலைநகரின் மையப்பகுதியில் உள்ள பாங்காக்கில் உள்ள ஹோட்டலில் தங்கியுள்ளார், அங்கு பாதுகாப்பு காரணங்களுக்காக வீட்டிற்குள்ளேயே இருக்குமாறு இலங்கை ஜனாதிபதியை பொலிசார் அறிவுறுத்தியுள்ளதாக வெள்ளிக்கிழமை ஊடக அறிக்கை தெரிவித்துள்ளது.",
        "வியாழன் அன்று உள்ளூர் நேரப்படி இரவு 8 மணியளவில் டான் மியூயாங் சர்வதேச விமான நிலையத்தை ஒட்டிய இராணுவ விமான நிலையத்தின் 6வது பிரிவில் சிங்கப்பூரில் இருந்து ஒரு பட்டய விமானத்தில் ராஜபக்சே மேலும் மூன்று பேருடன் தாய்லாந்து வந்தடைந்தார்.",
        "குழு ஃபூகெட்டில் தரையிறங்க திட்டமிட்டிருந்தது, ஆனால் சாத்தியமான தகவல் கசிவு குறித்த கவலைகள் விமானம் பாங்காக்கில் உள்ள இராணுவ விமான நிலையத்திற்கு திருப்பி விடப்பட்டது என்று ஒரு ஆதாரத்தை மேற்கோள் காட்டி பாங்காக் போஸ்ட் செய்தித்தாள் தெரிவித்துள்ளது.",
        "அந்த ஹோட்டலின் இருப்பிடம் வெளியிடப்படாத நிலையில், ராஜபக்சேவின் பாதுகாப்பை உறுதி செய்வதற்காக சிறப்புப் பிரிவுப் பணியகத்தைச் சேர்ந்த சிவில் உடையில் போலீஸ் அதிகாரிகள் நிறுத்தப்பட்டுள்ளனர். சிக்கலுக்கு உள்ளான முன்னாள் இலங்கை ஜனாதிபதியை நாட்டில் தங்கியிருக்கும் போது ஹோட்டலிலேயே தங்குமாறு அதிகாரிகள் கேட்டுள்ளதாக அந்த செய்தியில் தெரிவிக்கப்பட்டுள்ளது.",
        "சிங்கப்பூர் விசா காலாவதியான அதே நாளில் ராஜபக்சே பாங்காக் வந்தார். அவர் வேறொரு நாட்டில் நிரந்தர புகலிடம் கோருவதற்கு முன்பு தற்காலிகமாக இங்கு தங்கினார்.",
        "மனிதாபிமான காரணங்களுக்காக 73 வயதான இலங்கைத் தலைவர் தாய்லாந்திற்கு தற்காலிக விஜயம் செய்ததை பிரதமர் பிரயுத் சான்-ஓ-சா புதன்கிழமை உறுதிப்படுத்தினார், மேலும் நிரந்தர புகலிடம் தேடும் போது ராஜ்யத்தில் அரசியல் நடவடிக்கைகளை மேற்கொள்ள மாட்டேன் என்று உறுதியளித்தார். நாடு.",
        "ஜூலை 13 அன்று மாலத்தீவுக்கு தப்பிச் சென்ற பிறகு, ராஜபக்சே சிங்கப்பூருக்குப் பறந்தார், அங்கு இலங்கையின் முன்னோடியில்லாத பொருளாதார நெருக்கடிக்கு பல மாத எதிர்ப்புகளுக்குப் பிறகு ஒரு நாள் கழித்து ராஜினாமா செய்வதாக அறிவித்தார்.(PTI)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ச",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "பாங்காக்",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாங்காக்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "தாய்லாந்து",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "வெள்ளி",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ராஜபக்சே",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "தாய்லாந்து",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "மூன்று",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "சிங்கப்பூர்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "6",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "டான் முயாங் சர்வதேச விமான நிலையம்",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "சுமார் 8 மணி",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "வியாழன்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஃபூகெட்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாங்காக்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாங்காக் போஸ்ட்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "சிறப்பு கிளை பணியகம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ராஜபக்சே",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "LOC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ராஜபக்சே",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாங்காக்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சிங்கப்பூர்",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பிரயுத் சான்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "புதன்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "தாய்லாந்து",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "73 வயதானவர்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "மாலத்தீவுகள்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜூலை 13",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ராஜபக்சே",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "சிங்கப்பூர்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "மாதங்களுக்கு பிறகு ஒரு நாள் கழித்து",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கையின்",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}