{
  "newspaper_id": "ada-lk",
  "url": "https://www.ada.lk/breaking_news/පළාත්-හතරකට-වහින්න-වායුගෝලය-හැදෙයි/11-396680",
  "time_ut": 1661738421,
  "original_lang": "si",
  "original_title": "පළාත් හතරකට වහින්න වායුගෝලය හැදෙයි",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "The atmosphere is formed to rain in four provinces",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "The Department of Meteorology says that in the next few days favorable atmospheric conditions are being created for thunderstorms in the evening in Uva, Eastern, North Central and Northern provinces.",
        "The EMA Department states that there will be several periods of rain in Western, Sabaragamuwa and North-Western provinces and in Kandy, Nuwara Eliya, Galle and Matara districts today. It is seen in the announcement issued by the Department of Meteorology this morning that rain or thundershowers will occur in other areas in the evening or at night.",
        "It is also stated in the announcement that heavy rainfall of more than 75 mm may occur in some places in Uruwa, Eastern, North Central and Northern provinces.",
        "As the sun is moving towards the south, the sun will reach the top of Manniyakulam, Ariviyal and Valayanmadam today at 12.11pm, the Department of Tourism further says."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "four",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "The Department of Meteorology",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the next few days",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Uva",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Eastern",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "North Central",
            "label": "LOC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "EMA Department",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sabaragamuwa",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "North-Western",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kandy",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Galle",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Matara",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Department of Meteorology",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "this morning",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "night",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "more than 75",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Eastern",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "North Central",
            "label": "LOC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Manniyakulam",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ariviyal",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Valayanmadam",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "12.11pm",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Department of Tourism",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "පළාත් හතරකට වහින්න වායුගෝලය හැදෙයි",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "ඉදිරි දින කිහිපය තුළ ඌව, නැගෙනහිර, උතුරු මැද හා උතුරු පළාත්වලට සවස් කාලයේදී ගිගුරුම් සහිත වැසි සඳහා හිතකර වායුගෝලීය තත්ත්වයක් නිර්මාණය වෙමින් පවතින බව කාලගුණ විද්‍යා දෙපාර්තමේන්තුව පවසයි.",
        "අද දිනයේදී බස්නාහිර, සබරගමුව හා වයඹ පළාත්වලත් මහනුවර, නුවරඑළිය, ගාල්ල හා මාතර දිස්ත්‍රික්කවලත් වැසිවාර කිහිපයක් ඇතිවන බව ඒම දෙපාර්තමේන්තුව සඳහන් කරයි. සෙසු ප්‍ර දේශවල සවස් කාලයේදී හෝ රාත්‍රී කාලයේදී තැනින් තැන වැසි හෝ ගිගුරුම් සහිත වැසි ඇතිවන බවද කාලගුණ විදයා දෙපාර්තමේ්නතුව අද අලුයම නිකුත් කළ නිවේදනයේ දැක්වෙයි.",
        "උෘව, නැගෙනහිර, උතුරුමැද හා උතුරු පළාත්වල ඇතැම් ස්ථානවලට මිලි මීටර් 75කට වැඩි තරමක තද වර්ෂාපතනයත් ඇතිවිය හැකි බවද ඒම නිවේදනයේ දැක්වෙයි.",
        "දෘෂ්‍ය ලෙස සූර්යයා දකුණට ගමන් කිරීමේීදී අද දහවල් 12.11ට මන්නියකුලම්, අරිවියල් හා වලෛයන්මදම් ප්‍ර දේශවලට හිරු මුදුන්ව පවතින බවද ඒම දෙපාර්තමේන්තුව වැඩිදුරටත් පවසයි."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "හතර",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "කාලගුණ විද්‍යා දෙපාර්තමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉදිරි දින කිහිපය",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඌව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "නැගෙනහිර",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "උතුරු මැද",
            "label": "LOC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "EMA දෙපාර්තමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "සබරගමුව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "වයඹ",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "මහනුවර",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගාල්ල",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මාතර",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "කාලගුණ විද්‍යා දෙපාර්තමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "මේ උදෑසන",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "රෑ",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "75 ට වැඩි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "නැගෙනහිර",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "උතුරු මැද",
            "label": "LOC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "මන්නියාකුලම්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "අරිවියල්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "වලයන්මඩම්",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "12.11 ප.ව",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "සංචාරක දෙපාර්තමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "நான்கு மாகாணங்களில் மழை பெய்யும் வகையில் வளிமண்டலம் உருவாகியுள்ளது",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "எதிர்வரும் சில நாட்களில் ஊவா, கிழக்கு, வடமத்திய மற்றும் வடமாகாணங்களில் மாலை வேளையில் இடியுடன் கூடிய மழை பெய்யக்கூடிய சாதகமான வளிமண்டல நிலை உருவாகும் என வளிமண்டலவியல் திணைக்களம் தெரிவித்துள்ளது.",
        "மேல், சப்ரகமுவ மற்றும் வடமேல் மாகாணங்களிலும் கண்டி, நுவரெலியா, காலி மற்றும் மாத்தறை மாவட்டங்களிலும் இன்று பல காலகட்டங்களில் மழை பெய்யும் என EMA திணைக்களம் தெரிவித்துள்ளது. ஏனைய பிரதேசங்களில் மாலை அல்லது இரவு வேளைகளில் மழையோ அல்லது இடியுடன் கூடிய மழையோ பெய்யக் கூடிய சாத்தியம் காணப்படுவதாக வளிமண்டலவியல் திணைக்களம் இன்று காலை விடுத்துள்ள அறிவிப்பில் காணப்படுகின்றது.",
        "ஊருவ, கிழக்கு, வடமத்திய மற்றும் வடமாகாணங்களில் சில இடங்களில் 75 மில்லிமீற்றருக்கும் அதிகமான பலத்த மழை பெய்யக்கூடும் எனவும் அந்த அறிவிப்பில் குறிப்பிடப்பட்டுள்ளது.",
        "சூரியன் தெற்கு நோக்கி நகர்வதால், இன்று மதியம் 12.11 மணிக்கு மண்ணியகுளம், அறிவியல், வலையன்மடம் ஆகிய பகுதிகளில் சூரியன் தென்படும் என சுற்றுலாத்துறை மேலும் தெரிவித்துள்ளது."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "நான்கு",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "வளிமண்டலவியல் திணைக்களம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "அடுத்த சில நாட்கள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஊவா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "கிழக்கு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "வட மத்திய",
            "label": "LOC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "EMA துறை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "சப்ரகமுவ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "வடமேற்கு",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "கண்டி",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "காலி",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "மாத்தறை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "வளிமண்டலவியல் திணைக்களம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று காலை",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "இரவு",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "75க்கு மேல்",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "கிழக்கு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "வட மத்திய",
            "label": "LOC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "மன்னியகுளம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "அறிவியல்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "வலையன்மடம்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "மதியம் 12.11 மணி",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சுற்றுலா துறை",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}