{
  "newspaper_id": "economy-next-com",
  "url": "https://economynext.com/sri-lanka-china-fertilizer-kerfuffle-committee-appointed-on-money-paid-for-shipment-99350/",
  "time_ut": 1662027060,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Sri Lanka-China fertilizer kerfuffle: Committee appointed on money paid for shipment",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Sri Lanka-China fertilizer kerfuffle: Committee appointed on money paid for shipment",
      "author": "",
      "body_lines": [
        "ECONOMYNEXT – Sri Lanka’s ministry of agriculture has appointed a committee to determine steps to be taken about 6.9 million US dollars the cash-strapped nation was compelled to a pay Chinese fertilizer company last year over a deal that had gone awry.",
        "Agriculture Minister Mahinda Amaraweera told parliament on Thursday September 01 that the committee is headed by the secretary to the ministry and that the Attorney General has also advised on a course of action.",
        "Amaraweera said that, so far, efforts to obtain a refund or a consignment of chemical fertilizer in place of the money have turned futile.",
        "“Action has to be taken soon,” he said, responding to opposition lawmakers.",
        "In December 2021, at a time when Sri Lanka’s ill-advised foray into 100-percent organic farming, the government decided to pay 6.9 million dollars to China’s Qingdao Seawin Biotech Group Co Ltd, whose organic fertilizer was rejected by the island nation.",
        "Sri Lanka’s National Plant Quarantine Service (NPQS) had claimed that samples of the fertilizer contained harmful bacteria, prompting the Chinese company to demand 8 million US dollars from the agency in early November.",
        "Related: Chinese fertilizer firm demands US$8mn in damages from Sri Lanka testing agency",
        "The shipment was rejected by Sri Lanka while en route to the island, with the authorities denying entry to what opposition lawmakers and other critics had called a ship of faeces.",
        "Sri Lanka’s scientific findings were roundly rejected by the Chinese company, with the Chinese embassy in Colombo going as far as to blacklist the state-run People’s Bank for not making the payment owed to the company.",
        "The Chinese company subsequently sought arbitration in Singapore, and Sri Lanka later decided to settle the matter by paying 6.9 million dollars to the fertilizer company, on terms purportedly agreeable to both parties.",
        "Sri Lanka’s state-run People’s Bank made the payment on an letter of credit it had issued after a court order barring the lender, was removed.",
        "The botched deal, analysts say, soured China’s relations Sri Lanka.",
        "The Indian Ocean country is now going through the worst currency crisis in its central bank’s history. (Colombo/Sep01/2022)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Sri Lanka",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka’s",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ministry of agriculture",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "about 6.9 million US dollars",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "Chinese",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "last year",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Mahinda Amaraweera",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Thursday September 01",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Amaraweera",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "December 2021",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka’s",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "100-percent",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "6.9 million dollars",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "China",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Qingdao Seawin Biotech Group Co Ltd",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka’s",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "National Plant Quarantine Service",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "NPQS",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Chinese",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "8 million US dollars",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "early November",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Chinese",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka’s",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Chinese",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Chinese",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Colombo",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "People’s Bank",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Chinese",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Singapore",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "6.9 million dollars",
            "label": "MONEY"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka’s",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "People’s Bank",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "China",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Indian Ocean",
            "label": "LOC"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "ශ්‍රී ලංකා-චීන පොහොර කර්ෆෆල්: නැව්ගත කිරීම සඳහා ගෙවූ මුදල් පිළිබඳ කමිටුවක් පත් කෙරේ",
      "author": "",
      "body_lines": [
        "ECONOMYNEXT - ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ කෘෂිකර්ම අමාත්‍යාංශය විසින් ඇමරිකානු ඩොලර් මිලියන 6.9 ක් පමණ ගත යුතු පියවර තීරණය කිරීම සඳහා කමිටුවක් පත් කර ඇති අතර, මුදල් හිඟකමෙන් පෙළෙන ජාතිය පසුගිය වසරේ අක්‍රමිකතා සිදු වූ ගනුදෙනුවක් හේතුවෙන් වැටුප් ගෙවීමට චීන පොහොර සමාගමකට බල කෙරුනි.",
        "කෘෂිකර්ම අමාත්‍ය මහින්ද අමරවීර සැප්තැම්බර් 01 බ්‍රහස්පතින්දා පාර්ලිමේන්තුවට ප්‍රකාශ කළේ එම කමිටුවේ ප්‍රධානත්වය අමාත්‍යාංශ ලේකම්වරයාගේ ප්‍රධානත්වයෙන් බවත් නීතිපතිවරයා විසින් ක්‍රියා මාර්ගයක් පිළිබඳව ද උපදෙස් දී ඇති බවත්ය.",
        "අමරවීර මහතා පැවසුවේ, මේ වන විට මුදල් ආපසු ලබා ගැනීමට හෝ එම මුදල් වෙනුවට රසායනික පොහොර තොගයක් ලබා ගැනීමට ගත් උත්සාහයන් නිෂ්ඵල වී ඇති බවයි.",
        "විපක්ෂ මන්ත්‍රීවරුන්ට ප්‍රතිචාර දක්වමින් ඔහු පැවසුවේ “ඉක්මනින් පියවර ගත යුතුයි.",
        "2021 දෙසැම්බරයේදී, සියයට 100 ක කාබනික ගොවිතැන සඳහා ශ්‍රී ලංකාව අවවාදාත්මකව ගමන් කළ අවස්ථාවක, දිවයින ජාතිය විසින් කාබනික පොහොර ප්‍රතික්ෂේප කරන ලද චීනයේ Qingdao Seawin Biotech Group Co Ltd වෙත ඩොලර් මිලියන 6.9 ක් ගෙවීමට රජය තීරණය කළේය.",
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ ජාතික ශාක නිරෝධායන සේවාව (NPQS) පොහොර සාම්පලවල හානිකර බැක්ටීරියා අඩංගු බව ප්‍රකාශ කර ඇති අතර, නොවැම්බර් මස මුලදී ඒජන්සියෙන් ඩොලර් මිලියන 8 ක් ඉල්ලා සිටීමට චීන සමාගම පොළඹවා ඇත.",
        "ආශ්‍රිත: චීන පොහොර සමාගම ශ්‍රී ලංකා පරීක්ෂණ ඒජන්සියෙන් ඇමෙරිකානු ඩොලර් මිලියන 8 ක වන්දියක් ඉල්ලා සිටී",
        "විපක්ෂයේ නීති සම්පාදකයින් සහ අනෙකුත් විවේචකයින් අසූචි නැවක් ලෙස හැඳින්වූ දෙයට ඇතුළුවීම බලධාරීන් විසින් ප්‍රතික්ෂේප කිරීමත් සමඟ දිවයිනට යන අතරතුර ශ්‍රී ලංකාව විසින් නැව්ගත කිරීම ප්‍රතික්ෂේප කරන ලදී.",
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ විද්‍යාත්මක සොයාගැනීම් චීන සමාගම විසින් සම්පූර්ණයෙන් ප්‍රතික්ෂේප කරන ලද අතර, කොළඹ චීන තානාපති කාර්යාලය සමාගමට ගෙවිය යුතු මුදල් නොගෙවීම නිසා රාජ්‍ය පාලනය වන මහජන බැංකුව අසාදු ලේඛනගත කිරීමට තරම් දුරදිග ගියේය.",
        "චීන සමාගම පසුව සිංගප්පූරුවේ බේරුම්කරණයක් ඉල්ලා සිටි අතර, පසුව ශ්‍රී ලංකාව පොහොර සමාගමට ඩොලර් මිලියන 6.9 ක් ගෙවා ප්‍රශ්නය විසඳා ගැනීමට තීරණය කළේ දෙපාර්ශවයටම එකඟ විය හැකි කොන්දේසි මත ය.",
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ රාජ්‍ය මහජන බැංකුව ණය දෙන්නා තහනම් කරමින් අධිකරණ නියෝගයක් ඉවත් කිරීමෙන් පසු නිකුත් කරන ලද ණයවර ලිපියක් මත මෙම ගෙවීම සිදු කළේය.",
        "විශ්ලේෂකයින් පවසන්නේ මෙම කඩාකප්පල්කාරී ගනුදෙනුව චීනයේ ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ සබඳතා පළුදු කිරීමට හේතු වූ බවයි.",
        "ඉන්දියානු සාගර රට දැන් එහි මහ බැංකු ඉතිහාසයේ දරුණුතම මුදල් අර්බුදය හරහා ගමන් කරමින් සිටී. (කොළඹ/සැප්.01/2022)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "කෘෂිකර්ම අමාත්යාංශය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඇමරිකානු ඩොලර් මිලියන 6.9 ක් පමණ වේ",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "චීන",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගිය අවුරුද්දේ",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "මහින්ද අමරවීර",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "සැප්තැම්බර් 01 බ්‍රහස්පතින්දා",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "අමරවීර",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "දෙසැම්බර් 2021",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "100-සියයට",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඩොලර් මිලියන 6.9 කි",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "චීනය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Qingdao Seawin Biotech Group Co Ltd",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජාතික ශාක නිරෝධායන සේවය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "NPQS",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "චීන",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඩොලර් මිලියන 8 කි",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "නොවැම්බර් මුල",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "චීන",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "චීන",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "චීන",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "කොළඹ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "මහජන බැංකුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "චීන",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "සිංගප්පූරුව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඩොලර් මිලියන 6.9 කි",
            "label": "MONEY"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මහජන බැංකුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "චීනය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දියන් සාගරය",
            "label": "LOC"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "இலங்கை-சீனா உரக் கசிவு: ஏற்றுமதிக்காக செலுத்தப்பட்ட பணத்தின் மீது குழு நியமிக்கப்பட்டுள்ளது",
      "author": "",
      "body_lines": [
        "பொருளாதாரம் - இலங்கையின் விவசாய அமைச்சு சுமார் 6.9 மில்லியன் அமெரிக்க டொலர்களை எடுப்பதற்கான நடவடிக்கைகளைத் தீர்மானிப்பதற்கு ஒரு குழுவை நியமித்துள்ளது.",
        "அமைச்சின் செயலாளரின் தலைமையில் இந்தக் குழு செயற்படுவதுடன், சட்டமா அதிபரும் நடவடிக்கை எடுப்பது குறித்து ஆலோசனை வழங்கியுள்ளதாக விவசாய அமைச்சர் மஹிந்த அமரவீர செப்டம்பர் 01 வியாழக்கிழமை பாராளுமன்றத்தில் தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "இதுவரை பணத்தை மீளப் பெறுவதற்கான முயற்சிகள் அல்லது பணத்திற்குப் பதிலாக இரசாயன உரப் பொருட்களைப் பெறுவதற்கான முயற்சிகள் பலனளிக்கவில்லை என்று அமரவீர கூறினார்.",
        "\"விரைவில் நடவடிக்கை எடுக்க வேண்டும்,\" என்று அவர் எதிர்க்கட்சி சட்டமன்ற உறுப்பினர்களுக்கு பதிலளித்தார்.",
        "2021 டிசம்பரில், 100 சதவீத இயற்கை விவசாயத்தில் இலங்கையின் தவறான ஆலோசனையின் போது, ​​தீவு தேசத்தால் கரிம உரத்தை நிராகரித்த சீனாவின் Qingdao Seawin Biotech Group Co Ltd நிறுவனத்திற்கு 6.9 மில்லியன் டாலர்களை வழங்க அரசாங்கம் முடிவு செய்தது.",
        "இலங்கையின் தேசிய தாவரத் தனிமைப்படுத்தல் சேவை (NPQS) உரத்தின் மாதிரிகளில் தீங்கு விளைவிக்கும் பாக்டீரியாக்கள் இருப்பதாகக் கூறியதால், சீன நிறுவனம் நவம்பர் தொடக்கத்தில் நிறுவனத்திடம் இருந்து 8 மில்லியன் அமெரிக்க டாலர்களைக் கோரியது.",
        "தொடர்புடையது: சீன உர நிறுவனம் 8 மில்லியன் அமெரிக்க டாலர்களை இலங்கை சோதனை நிறுவனத்திடம் இருந்து கோருகிறது",
        "தீவுக்குச் செல்லும் வழியில் இலங்கையால் ஏற்றுமதி நிராகரிக்கப்பட்டது, எதிர்க்கட்சி சட்டமியற்றுபவர்கள் மற்றும் பிற விமர்சகர்கள் மலக் கப்பல் என்று அழைத்ததற்கு அதிகாரிகள் அனுமதி மறுத்தனர்.",
        "இலங்கையின் விஞ்ஞான கண்டுபிடிப்புகள் சீன நிறுவனத்தால் முழுமையாக நிராகரிக்கப்பட்டன, கொழும்பில் உள்ள சீனத் தூதரகம், நிறுவனத்திற்கு செலுத்த வேண்டிய பணத்தைச் செலுத்தாததற்காக அரசு நடத்தும் மக்கள் வங்கியை கறுப்புப் பட்டியலில் சேர்க்கும் அளவிற்குச் சென்றது.",
        "சீன நிறுவனம் பின்னர் சிங்கப்பூரில் நடுவர் மன்றத்தை நாடியது, பின்னர் இலங்கை இரு தரப்பினருக்கும் ஒப்புக்கொள்ளக்கூடிய நிபந்தனைகளின் அடிப்படையில் 6.9 மில்லியன் டாலர்களை உர நிறுவனத்திற்கு செலுத்தி பிரச்சினையை தீர்க்க முடிவு செய்தது.",
        "கடனளிப்பவருக்கு தடை விதிக்கப்பட்ட நீதிமன்ற உத்தரவு நீக்கப்பட்ட பின்னர், இலங்கையின் அரசால் நடத்தப்படும் மக்கள் வங்கி, அது வழங்கிய கடன் கடிதத்தின் அடிப்படையில் பணம் செலுத்தியது.",
        "சீர்குலைந்த ஒப்பந்தம், சீனாவின் இலங்கை உறவில் விரிசலை ஏற்படுத்தியதாக ஆய்வாளர்கள் கூறுகின்றனர்.",
        "இந்தியப் பெருங்கடல் நாடு இப்போது அதன் மத்திய வங்கியின் வரலாற்றில் மிக மோசமான நாணய நெருக்கடியை சந்தித்து வருகிறது. (கொழும்பு/செப்01/2022)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "இலங்கை",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கையின்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "விவசாய அமைச்சகம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "சுமார் 6.9 மில்லியன் அமெரிக்க டாலர்கள்",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "சீன",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "கடந்த ஆண்டு",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "மஹிந்த அமரவீர",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "செப்டம்பர் 01 வியாழன்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "அமரவீர",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "டிசம்பர் 2021",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கையின்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "100 சதவீதம்",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "6.9 மில்லியன் டாலர்கள்",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "சீனா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Qingdao Seawin Biotech Group Co Ltd",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கையின்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "தேசிய தாவர தனிமைப்படுத்தப்பட்ட சேவை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "NPQS",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "சீன",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "8 மில்லியன் அமெரிக்க டாலர்கள்",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "நவம்பர் தொடக்கத்தில்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "சீன",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கையின்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சீன",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "சீன",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "கொழும்பு",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "மக்கள் வங்கி",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "சீன",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "சிங்கப்பூர்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "6.9 மில்லியன் டாலர்கள்",
            "label": "MONEY"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கையின்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "மக்கள் வங்கி",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "சீனா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இந்திய பெருங்கடல்",
            "label": "LOC"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}