{
  "newspaper_id": "ada-lk",
  "url": "https://www.ada.lk/breaking_news/හිටපු-ජනපතිගෙන්-CIDයට-පැය-පහක-ප්‍රකාශයක්/11-396438",
  "time_ut": 1660912539,
  "original_lang": "si",
  "original_title": "හිටපු ජනපතිගෙන් CIDයට පැය පහක ප්‍රකාශයක්",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "A five-hour statement from the former president to the CID",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "The Criminal Investigation Department has given a five-hour statement from former President Maithripala Sirisena regarding the President's pardoning of a person named Shramanta Jayamaha who was in prison after receiving the death penalty.",
        "According to a complaint made by Ratana Thera in Athuli, an investigation is going on and this statement has been recorded from the former President in relation to that investigation.",
        "Shramanta was convicted and serving a prison sentence in relation to the Royal Park murder incident which caused a great controversy and the former President arranged for him to receive a presidential pardon."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "five-hour",
          "label": "TIME"
        },
        {
          "text": "CID",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "The Criminal Investigation Department",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "five-hour",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "Maithripala Sirisena",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Shramanta Jayamaha",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Ratana Thera",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Athuli",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Shramanta",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Royal Park",
            "label": "FAC"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "හිටපු ජනපතිගෙන් CIDයට පැය පහක ප්‍රකාශයක්",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "මරණ දඬුවම් ලබා බන්ධනාගාරගතව සිටි ශ්‍රමන්ත ජයමහ නම් පුද්ගලයාට ජනපති සමාව දිම සම්බන්ධයෙන් හිටපු ජනපති මෛත්‍රිපාල සිරිසේන මහතාගෙන් අපරාධ පරික්ෂණ දෙපාර්තමේන්තුව පැය පහක ප්‍රකාශයක් ලබා දී තිබේ.",
        "අතුරුලියේ රතන හිමියන් කරනු ලැබූ පැමිණිල්ලක් අනුව මේ පිළිබඳව විමර්ශනයක් පැවැත්වෙන අතර එම විමර්ශනයට අදාළව හිටපු ජනපතිවරයාගෙන් මෙම ප්‍රකාශය සටහන් කරගෙන තිබේ.",
        "මහත් ආන්දෝලනයකට තුඩුදුන් රෝයල් පාක් ඝාතන සිද්ධියට අදාළව ශ්‍රමන්ත වරදකරු වී සිර දඩුවම් විදිමින් සිටි අතර හිටපු ජනපතිවරයා ඔහුට ජනපති සමාව දීමට කටයුතු කළේය."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "පැය පහක්",
          "label": "TIME"
        },
        {
          "text": "CID",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "අපරාධ පරීක්ෂණ දෙපාර්තමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "පැය පහක්",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "මෛත්‍රීපාල සිරිසේන",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රමන්ත ජයමහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "රතන හිමි",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "අතුලි",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රමන්ත",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "රාජකීය උද්යානය",
            "label": "FAC"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "முன்னாள் ஜனாதிபதியிடமிருந்து குற்றப் புலனாய்வுப் பிரிவினரிடம் ஐந்து மணிநேர வாக்குமூலம்",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "மரண தண்டனை பெற்று சிறையில் இருந்த ஷ்ரமந்த ஜயமஹா என்ற நபருக்கு ஜனாதிபதி மன்னிப்பு வழங்கியமை தொடர்பில் முன்னாள் ஜனாதிபதி மைத்திரிபால சிறிசேனவிடம் குற்றப் புலனாய்வு திணைக்களம் ஐந்து மணிநேர வாக்குமூலம் வழங்கியுள்ளது.",
        "அத்துலியில் ரதன தேரர் செய்த முறைப்பாட்டின் பிரகாரம் விசாரணைகள் இடம்பெற்று வருவதாகவும், அந்த விசாரணை தொடர்பில் முன்னாள் ஜனாதிபதியிடம் இந்த வாக்குமூலம் பதிவு செய்யப்பட்டுள்ளதாகவும் தெரிவிக்கப்பட்டுள்ளது.",
        "பெரும் சர்ச்சையை ஏற்படுத்திய றோயல் பார்க் கொலைச் சம்பவம் தொடர்பில் ஷ்ரமந்தா குற்றவாளியாகி சிறைத்தண்டனை அனுபவித்து வரும் நிலையில் அவருக்கு ஜனாதிபதி மன்னிப்பு வழங்குவதற்கு முன்னாள் ஜனாதிபதி ஏற்பாடு செய்திருந்தார்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ஐந்து மணி நேரம்",
          "label": "TIME"
        },
        {
          "text": "சி.ஐ.டி",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "குற்றப் புலனாய்வுத் துறை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஐந்து மணி நேரம்",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "மைத்திரிபால சிறிசேன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஷ்ரமந்த ஜயமஹா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ரதன தேரர்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "அதுலி",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஷ்ரமந்தா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ராயல் பார்க்",
            "label": "FAC"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}