{
  "newspaper_id": "ada-lk",
  "url": "https://www.ada.lk/breaking_news/අමාත්‍ය-මණ්ඩලය-දිවුරුම්-දීම-ආරම්භ-වෙයි/11-395658",
  "time_ut": 1658476380,
  "original_lang": "si",
  "original_title": "අමාත්‍ය මණ්ඩලය දිවුරුම් දීම ආරම්භ වෙයි",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "The swearing-in of the Cabinet begins",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "The swearing-in of the new government's cabinet has already begun at the Prime Minister's Office. It is reported that the former ministers have taken the oath in their posts.",
        "Prime Minister Dinesh Gunawardena - Public Administration, Provincial Councils and Local Government, Home Affairs"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Cabinet",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "Dinesh Gunawardena",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Provincial Councils and Local Government",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "අමාත්‍ය මණ්ඩලය දිවුරුම් දීම ආරම්භ වෙයි",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "නව රජයේ අමාත්‍ය මණ්ඩලය දිවුරුම් දීම මේ වන විට අග්‍රාමාත්‍ය කාර්යාලයේදී ආරම්භ වී තිබේ. හිටපු ආමාත්‍යවරුන්ම සිය ධුරවල මෙසේ දිවුරුම්දිම සිදුකර ඇති බව වාර්තා වෙයි.",
        "අග්‍රාමාත්‍ය දිනේෂ් ගුණවර්ධන - රාජ්‍ය පරිපාලන, පළාත් සභා හා පළාත් පාලන, ස්වදේශ කටයුතු"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "මණ්ඩල",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "දිනේෂ් ගුණවර්ධන",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "පළාත් සභා සහ පළාත් පාලන",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "அமைச்சரவை பதவியேற்பு விழா தொடங்குகிறது",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "புதிய அரசாங்கத்தின் அமைச்சரவை பதவியேற்பு நிகழ்வு பிரதமர் அலுவலகத்தில் ஏற்கனவே ஆரம்பமாகியுள்ளது. முன்னாள் அமைச்சர்கள் பதவிப் பிரமாணம் செய்து கொண்டதாகத் தெரிவிக்கப்படுகிறது.",
        "பிரதமர் தினேஷ் குணவர்தன - பொது நிர்வாகம், மாகாண சபைகள் மற்றும் உள்ளூராட்சி, உள்நாட்டலுவல்கள்"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "மந்திரி சபை",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "தினேஷ் குணவர்தன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "மாகாண சபைகள் மற்றும் உள்ளூராட்சி",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}