{
  "newspaper_id": "daily-ft-lk",
  "url": "https://www.ft.lk/business/All-time-record-prices-achieved-by-Forbes-Walker-Tea-Brokers/34-737861",
  "time_ut": 1658688718,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "All-time record prices achieved by Forbes & Walker Tea Brokers",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "All-time record prices achieved by Forbes & Walker Tea Brokers",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "Demodera Estate achieved an all-time record price of Rs. 3,500 per kg for a BOP1 grade in the Uva Medium Category at the weekly online tea auctions held on 19/20 July.",
        "This estate, reputed for manufacturing high quality teas, has obtained the Rainforest Alliance certification, and ensures that all quality standards are met in their production process.",
        "Demodera Estate is managed by Hapugastenne Plantations PLC, an associate of Browns Power Holdings Ltd., under the stewardship of Group Manager Nelantha Silva.",
        "Senhora Synergies Group showcased their outstanding capabilities yet again in manufacturing high quality ‘Ceylon Tea’ with Harangalla Tea Factory achieving yet another all-time record price of Rs. 3,550 per kg for a FBOP grade in the Western Medium Grown category at the online tea auctions held on 19/20 July.",
        "Harangalla Tea Factory which is situated in the Kotmale agro-climatic sub district at an elevation of 1,163 metres is ISO 22000 and HACCP certified, ensuring good quality standards are met throughout the production process.",
        "Bambrakelly Estate achieved an all-time record price of Rs. 3,150 per kg on a OP1 grade in the Western High category at the tea auctions held on 19/20 July.",
        "This Estate is situated in Lindula, Nuwara Eliya is Rainforest Alliance and ISO 22000:2018 certified and is reputed for manufacturing high-quality tea ‘Ceylon Tea.’",
        "Bambrakelly Estate is managed by Horana Plantations PLC under the stewardship of Subash Narayanan.",
        "Galpaditenne Tea Factory under the selling mark of Suduwelipothahena achieved an all-time record price of Rs. 3,150 per kg on a PF1 grade in the Low Grown CTC category at the weekly online tea auctions held on 19/20 July.",
        "Galpaditenne Tea Factory situated in Lellopitiya, Ratnapura is equipped with state-of-the-art machinery and technology to produce high-quality CTC teas.",
        "The factory is owned and managed by the KDU Group which was founded by the late K.D. Upasena and is now operating under the guidance of his sons KDU Group Chairman Saman Upasena and KDU Group Managing Director Thushan Upasena. Their passion for tea manufacture has alleviated its product and process to maintain the highest standards, which accounts for Suduwelipothahena teas consistently being sold at premium prices amongst the private factories manufacturing and selling commercial quantities of CTC grades in the Low Grown region.",
        "Muswenna Tea Factory achieves an equal all-time record price at the Colombo Tea Auctions",
        "Muswenna Tea Factory in Imaduwa, Galle achieved an equal all-time record price of Rs. 9,950 per kg for a FBOPFEXSP grade in the Premium Flowery category at the weekly tea auctions held on 19/20 July.",
        "The estate/factory is owned and managed by distinguished tea producer R.G. Jinadasa. His passion in manufacturing high-quality ‘Ceylon Tea’ is evident by his success amongst the private factories producing and selling Orthodox Leafy grades in the Low Grown Region.",
        "The cutting-edge manufacturing process implemented at Muswenna Tea Factory accounts for Muswenna teas consistently being sold at premium prices.",
        "Jinadasa’s career in tea industry which commenced as a Tea Inspector at Sri Lanka Tea, now spans over four decades. He is competently assisted by his son, Director Madushanka Malithand experienced Factory Executive Sisira Chinthaka who were instrumental in achieving this feat.",
        "Muswenna Tea Factory is ISO 22000:2018, HACCP and GMP certified and has an annual production of approximately 450,000 kg.",
        "uswenna teas are exclusively sold and marketed by Forbes & Walker Tea Brokers Ltd."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Forbes & Walker Tea Brokers",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "the Uva Medium Category",
            "label": "EVENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "weekly",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "19/20 July",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Rainforest Alliance",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Hapugastenne Plantations PLC",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Browns Power Holdings Ltd.",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Group",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Nelantha Silva",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Senhora Synergies Group",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Harangalla Tea Factory",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "3,550",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "FBOP",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "19/20 July",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Harangalla Tea Factory",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kotmale",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "1,163 metres",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "ISO 22000",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Bambrakelly Estate",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "3,150 per kg",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "19/20 July",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Lindula",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Rainforest Alliance",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ISO",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Bambrakelly Estate",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Horana Plantations PLC",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Subash Narayanan",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Galpaditenne Tea Factory",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Suduwelipothahena",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "3,150 per kg",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "CTC",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "weekly",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "19/20 July",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Galpaditenne Tea Factory",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Lellopitiya",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ratnapura",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "CTC",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the KDU Group",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "K.D. Upasena",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "KDU Group",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Saman Upasena",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "KDU Group",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Thushan Upasena",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Suduwelipothahena",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "CTC",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Muswenna Tea Factory",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Colombo Tea Auctions",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Muswenna Tea Factory",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Imaduwa",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Galle",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "9,950 per kg",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "Premium Flowery",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "weekly",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "19/20 July",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "R.G. Jinadasa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Orthodox Leafy",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Low Grown Region",
            "label": "EVENT"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Muswenna Tea Factory",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Muswenna",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Jinadasa",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "four decades",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Madushanka Malithand",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sisira Chinthaka",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Muswenna Tea Factory",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ISO 22000:2018",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "GMP",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "approximately 450,000 kg",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Forbes & Walker Tea Brokers Ltd.",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "Forbes & Walker Tea Brokers විසින් අත්පත් කරගත් සර්වකාලීන වාර්තාගත මිල ගණන්",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "දෙමෝදර වතුයාය සර්වකාලීන වාර්තාගත මිල රු. ජුලි 19/20 දිනවල පැවැත්වෙන සතිපතා ඔන්ලයින් තේ වෙන්දේසියේදී ඌව මධ්‍ය කාණ්ඩයේ BOP1 ශ්‍රේණියක් සඳහා කිලෝග්‍රෑමයකට රුපියල් 3,500ක්.",
        "උසස් තත්ත්වයේ තේ නිෂ්පාදනය සඳහා කීර්තිමත් මෙම වතුයාය, Rainforest Alliance සහතිකය ලබාගෙන ඇති අතර, ඔවුන්ගේ නිෂ්පාදන ක්‍රියාවලියේදී සියලුම තත්ත්ව ප්‍රමිතීන් සපුරා ඇති බව සහතික කරයි.",
        "සමූහ කළමනාකාර නෙලන්ත සිල්වා මහතාගේ භාරකාරත්වය යටතේ සීමාසහිත Browns Power Holdings සමාගමෙහි සහකාරියක් වන Hapugastenne Plantations PLC විසින් දෙමෝදර වතුයාය කළමනාකරණය කරයි.",
        "සෙන්හෝරා සිනර්ජීස් සමූහය, හරංගල්ල තේ කම්හල සමඟින් උසස් තත්ත්වයේ ‘සිලෝන් ටී’ නිෂ්පාදනය කිරීමේ ඔවුන්ගේ විශිෂ්ට හැකියාවන් යළිත් වරක් ප්‍රදර්ශනය කළේ, තවත් සර්වකාලීන වාර්තාගත මිල රු. ජුලි 19/20 යන දිනවල පැවති ඔන්ලයින් තේ වෙන්දේසියේදී බටහිර මධ්‍යම වැඩුණු කාණ්ඩයේ FBOP ශ්‍රේණියක් සඳහා කිලෝග්‍රෑමයකට රුපියල් 3,550 කි.",
        "කොත්මලේ කෘෂි දේශගුණික උප දිස්ත්‍රික්කයේ මීටර් 1,163 ක උන්නතාංශයක පිහිටා ඇති හරංගල්ල තේ කර්මාන්ත ශාලාව ISO 22000 සහ HACCP සහතිකය ලබා ඇති අතර නිෂ්පාදන ක්‍රියාවලිය පුරාම හොඳ තත්ත්ව ප්‍රමිතීන් සපුරාලීම සහතික කරයි.",
        "බම්බ්‍රකෙලි වතුයාය සර්වකාලීන වාර්තාගත මිල රු. ජුලි 19/20 දින පැවති තේ වෙන්දේසියේදී බටහිර උසස් කාණ්ඩයේ OP1 ශ්‍රේණියේ කිලෝග්‍රෑමයකට රු. 3,150 කි.",
        "මෙම වතුයාය නුවරඑළිය ලිඳුල ප්‍රදේශයේ පිහිටා ඇති අතර එය වැසි වනාන්තර සන්ධානයක් වන අතර ISO 22000:2018 සහතිකය ලබා ඇති අතර උසස් තත්ත්වයේ තේ නිෂ්පාදනය සඳහා ප්‍රසිද්ධියක් උසුලයි.",
        "බම්බ්‍රකැලි වතුයාය සුභාෂ් නාරායනන්ගේ භාරකාරත්වය යටතේ හොරණ ප්ලාන්ටේෂන් පීඑල්සී විසින් කළමනාකරණය කරනු ලැබේ.",
        "සුදුවැලිපොතහේන විකුණුම් ලකුණ යටතේ ගල්පාඩිතැන්නේ තේ කම්හල සර්වකාලීන වාර්තාගත මිල රු. ජුලි 19/20 දිනවල පැවති සතිපතා ඔන්ලයින් තේ වෙන්දේසියේදී අඩු වර්ධනයක් සහිත CTC කාණ්ඩයේ PF1 ශ්‍රේණියේ කිලෝග්‍රෑමයකට රුපියල් 3,150 කි.",
        "රත්නපුර ලෙල්ලෝපිටිය ප්‍රදේශයේ පිහිටි ගල්පාඩිතැන්නේ තේ කම්හල උසස් තත්ත්වයේ CTC තේ නිෂ්පාදනය සඳහා අති නවීන යන්ත්‍ර සූත්‍රවලින් සහ තාක්ෂණයෙන් සමන්විතය.",
        "මෙම කර්මාන්තශාලාව හිමිකාරීත්වය දරන්නේ සහ කළමනාකරණය කරනු ලබන්නේ නැසීගිය K.D විසින් ආරම්භ කරන ලද KDU සමූහය විසිනි. උපසේන දැන් ක්‍රියාත්මක වන්නේ ඔහුගේ පුතුන් වන KDU සමූහ ව්‍යාපාරයේ සභාපති සමන් උපසේන සහ KDU සමූහ කළමනාකාර අධ්‍යක්ෂ තුෂාන් උපසේන යන අයගේ මගපෙන්වීම යටතේය. තේ නිෂ්පාදනය කෙරෙහි ඔවුන් දක්වන උනන්දුව නිසා එහි නිෂ්පාදනය සහ ක්‍රියාවලිය ඉහළම ප්‍රමිතියෙන් පවත්වා ගැනීමට හැකි වී ඇති අතර, අඩු වගා කළ කලාපයේ CTC ශ්‍රේණිවල වාණිජ ප්‍රමාණයන් නිෂ්පාදනය කරන සහ අලෙවි කරන පුද්ගලික කර්මාන්තශාලා අතර සුදුවැලිපොතහේන තේ අඛණ්ඩව වාරික මිලට අලෙවි වේ.",
        "මුස්වැන්න තේ කම්හල කොළඹ තේ වෙන්දේසියේදී සමාන සර්වකාලීන වාර්තාගත මිලක් ලබා ගනී",
        "ගාල්ල ඉමදූව මුස්වැන්න තේ කම්හල සර්වකාලීන වාර්තාගත මිල රු. ජුලි 19/20 දිනවල පැවති සතිපතා තේ වෙන්දේසියේදී වාරික මල් කාණ්ඩයේ FBOPFEXSP ශ්‍රේණියක් සඳහා කිලෝග්‍රෑමයකට රුපියල් 9,950 කි.",
        "වත්ත/කම්හල හිමිකාරීත්වය දරන අතර කළමනාකරණය කරනු ලබන්නේ කීර්තිමත් තේ නිෂ්පාදකයෙකු වන ආර්.ජී. ජිනදාස ය. උසස් තත්ත්වයේ ‘සිලෝන් ටී’ නිෂ්පාදනය කිරීමට ඔහු තුළ ඇති ආශාව අඩු වර්ධනය වූ කලාපයේ ඕතඩොක්ස් කොළ ශ්‍රේණි නිෂ්පාදනය කර අලෙවි කරන පෞද්ගලික කර්මාන්තශාලා අතර ඔහු ලැබූ සාර්ථකත්වයෙන් පැහැදිලි වේ.",
        "මුස්වැන්න තේ කර්මාන්ත ශාලාවේ ක්‍රියාත්මක කරන ලද අති නවීන නිෂ්පාදන ක්‍රියාවලිය හේතුවෙන් මුස්වැන්න තේ අඛණ්ඩව වාරික මිලට අලෙවි වේ.",
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකා තේ ආයතනයේ තේ පරීක්ෂකවරයකු ලෙස ආරම්භ කළ ජිනදාසගේ තේ කර්මාන්තයේ වෘත්තීය ජීවිතය මේ වන විට දශක හතරක් ඉක්මවයි. මෙම ජයග්‍රහණය සඳහා මූලික වූ ඔහුගේ පුත් අධ්‍යක්‍ෂ මධුශංක මලිතාන්ද්‍ගේ පළපුරුදු කර්මාන්තශාලා විධායක සිසිර චින්තක ඔහුට දක්ෂ ලෙස සහාය දක්වයි.",
        "මුස්වැන්න තේ කම්හල ISO 22000:2018, HACCP සහ GMP සහතික කර ඇති අතර දළ වශයෙන් 450,000 kg වාර්ෂික නිෂ්පාදනයක් ඇත.",
        "uswenna තේ පමණක් Forbes සහ Walker Tea Brokers විසින් අලෙවි කරනු ලැබේ."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ෆෝබ්ස් සහ වෝකර් තේ තැරැව්කරුවන්",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ඌව මධ්‍යම කාණ්ඩය",
            "label": "EVENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "සතිපතා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "19/20 ජූලි",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "වැසි වනාන්තර සන්ධානය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "හපුගස්තැන්න වැවිලි පීඑල්සී",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Browns Power Holdings Ltd.",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "සමූහය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "නෙලන්ත සිල්වා",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Senhora Synergies Group",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "හරංගල්ල තේ කර්මාන්ත ශාලාව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "3,550 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "FBOP",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "19/20 ජූලි",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "හරංගල්ල තේ කර්මාන්ත ශාලාව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "කොත්මලේ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මීටර් 1,163 කි",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "ISO 22000",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "බම්බ්‍රකෙලි වතුයාය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "3,150 කි",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "19/20 ජූලි",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ලිඳුල",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "වැසි වනාන්තර සන්ධානය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ISO",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "බම්බ්‍රකෙලි වතුයාය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "හොරණ වැවිලි පීඑල්සී",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "සුභාෂ් නාරායනන්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ගල්පඩිතැන්නේ තේ කර්මාන්ත ශාලාව",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "සුදුවැලිපොතහේන",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "3,150 කි",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "CTC",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "සතිපතා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "19/20 ජූලි",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ගල්පඩිතැන්නේ තේ කර්මාන්ත ශාලාව",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ලෙල්ලෝපිටිය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "රත්නපුරය",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "CTC",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "KDU සමූහය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "කේ.ඩී. උපසේන",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "KDU සමූහය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "සමන් උපසේන",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "KDU සමූහය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "තුෂාන් උපසේන",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "සුදුවැලිපොතහේන",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "CTC",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "මුස්වැන්න තේ කම්හල",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "කොළඹ තේ වෙන්දේසි",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "මුස්වැන්න තේ කම්හල",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉමදූව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගාල්ල",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "9,950 කි",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "වාරික මල්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "සතිපතා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "19/20 ජූලි",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ආර්.ජී. ජිනදාස ය",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඕතඩොක්ස් කොළ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "අඩු වර්ධනය වූ කලාපය",
            "label": "EVENT"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "මුස්වැන්න තේ කම්හල",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "මුස්වැන්න",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Jinadasa",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "දශක හතරක්",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මධුශංක මලිතාන්ඩ්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "සිසිර චින්තක",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "මුස්වැන්න තේ කම්හල",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ISO 22000:2018",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "GMP",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ආසන්න වශයෙන් 450,000 kg",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Forbes & Walker Tea Brokers Ltd.",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "ஃபோர்ப்ஸ் & வாக்கர் டீ தரகர்கள் அடைந்த அனைத்து நேர சாதனை விலைகள்",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "டெமோடெரா எஸ்டேட் அனைத்து நேர சாதனை விலையான ரூ. ஜூலை 19/20 அன்று நடைபெற்ற வாராந்திர ஆன்லைன் தேயிலை ஏலத்தில் ஊவா நடுத்தர பிரிவில் BOP1 தரத்திற்கு கிலோ ஒன்றுக்கு 3,500 ரூபாய்.",
        "உயர்தர தேயிலைகளை உற்பத்தி செய்வதில் பெயர் பெற்ற இந்த எஸ்டேட், ரெயின்ஃபாரெஸ்ட் அலையன்ஸ் சான்றிதழைப் பெற்றுள்ளது, மேலும் அவற்றின் உற்பத்தி செயல்பாட்டில் அனைத்து தரத் தரங்களும் பூர்த்தி செய்யப்படுவதை உறுதி செய்கிறது.",
        "குழு முகாமையாளர் நெலந்த சில்வாவின் மேற்பார்வையின் கீழ், பிரவுன்ஸ் பவர் ஹோல்டிங்ஸ் லிமிடெட் உடன் இணைந்த ஹபுகஸ்டன் பிளான்டேஷன்ஸ் பிஎல்சியால் டெமோடெரா தோட்டம் நிர்வகிக்கப்படுகிறது.",
        "சென்ஹோரா சினெர்ஜிஸ் குழுமம், ஹரங்கல்லா தேயிலை தொழிற்சாலையுடன் உயர் தரமான ‘சிலோன் டீ’ தயாரிப்பதில் தங்களின் சிறப்பான திறன்களை மீண்டும் வெளிப்படுத்தியது, மேலும் ரூ. ஜூலை 19/20 அன்று நடைபெற்ற ஆன்லைன் தேயிலை ஏலத்தில் மேற்கத்திய நடுத்தர வளர்ந்த பிரிவில் FBOP கிரேடுக்கு கிலோ ஒன்றுக்கு 3,550 ரூபாய்.",
        "1,163 மீற்றர் உயரத்தில் கொத்மலை விவசாய காலநிலை உப மாவட்டத்தில் அமைந்துள்ள ஹரங்கல்ல தேயிலை தொழிற்சாலை ISO 22000 மற்றும் HACCP தரச்சான்றிதழ் பெற்றுள்ளதுடன், உற்பத்தி செயல்முறை முழுவதும் நல்ல தரமான தரங்களை பூர்த்தி செய்வதை உறுதி செய்கிறது.",
        "பாம்ப்ரகெல்லி எஸ்டேட் அனைத்து நேர சாதனை விலையான ரூ. ஜூலை 19/20 அன்று நடைபெற்ற தேயிலை ஏலத்தில் மேற்கத்திய உயர் பிரிவில் OP1 தரத்தில் கிலோ ஒன்றுக்கு 3,150 ரூபாய்.",
        "நுவரெலியாவின் லிந்துலையில் அமைந்துள்ள இந்த தோட்டமானது மழைக்காடு கூட்டமைப்பு மற்றும் ISO 22000:2018 தரச்சான்றிதழ் பெற்றுள்ளது மற்றும் உயர்தர தேயிலை 'சிலோன் தேயிலை' தயாரிப்பதில் புகழ் பெற்றது.",
        "பாம்ப்ரகெல்லி தோட்டம் சுபாஷ் நாராயணனின் வழிகாட்டுதலின் கீழ் ஹொரணா பிளான்டேஷன்ஸ் பிஎல்சியால் நிர்வகிக்கப்படுகிறது.",
        "சுதுவெலிபொதஹேன விற்பனைச் சின்னத்தின் கீழ் கல்பாடிதென்ன தேயிலை தொழிற்சாலை அனைத்து கால சாதனை விலையாக ரூ. ஜூலை 19/20 அன்று நடைபெற்ற வாராந்திர ஆன்லைன் தேயிலை ஏலத்தில், குறைந்த வளர்ந்த CTC பிரிவில், PF1 தரத்தில் ஒரு கிலோவுக்கு 3,150 ரூபாய்.",
        "இரத்தினபுரி, லெல்லோபிட்டியவில் அமைந்துள்ள கல்படிதென்ன தேயிலை தொழிற்சாலை உயர்தர CTC தேயிலைகளை உற்பத்தி செய்வதற்கான அதிநவீன இயந்திரங்கள் மற்றும் தொழில்நுட்பத்துடன் பொருத்தப்பட்டுள்ளது.",
        "இந்த தொழிற்சாலை KDU குழுமத்திற்கு சொந்தமானது மற்றும் நிர்வகிக்கப்படுகிறது, இது மறைந்த K.D ஆல் நிறுவப்பட்டது. உபசேன மற்றும் இப்போது அவரது மகன்களான KDU குழுமத்தின் தலைவர் சமன் உபசேன மற்றும் KDU குழுமத்தின் முகாமைத்துவ பணிப்பாளர் துஷான் உபசேன ஆகியோரின் வழிகாட்டுதலின் கீழ் இயங்கி வருகிறார். தேயிலை உற்பத்தியில் அவர்களின் ஆர்வம் அதன் தயாரிப்பு மற்றும் செயல்முறையை மிக உயர்ந்த தரத்தை பராமரிப்பதற்குத் தணித்துள்ளது, இது குறைந்த வளர்ச்சியடைந்த பிராந்தியத்தில் CTC தரங்களை உற்பத்தி செய்யும் தனியார் தொழிற்சாலைகள் மற்றும் விற்பனை செய்யும் தனியார் தொழிற்சாலைகள் மத்தியில் பிரீமியம் விலையில் தொடர்ந்து விற்பனை செய்யப்படுகிறது.",
        "முஸ்வென்னா தேயிலை தொழிற்சாலை கொழும்பு தேயிலை ஏலத்தில் சமமான சாதனை விலையை எட்டியுள்ளது",
        "காலி, இமதுவவில் உள்ள முஸ்வென்ன தேயிலை தொழிற்சாலையானது, அனைத்து கால சாதனை விலையான ரூ. ஜூலை 19/20 அன்று நடைபெற்ற வாராந்திர தேயிலை ஏலத்தில் பிரீமியம் பூ வகைகளில் FBOPFEXSP கிரேடுக்கு கிலோ ஒன்றுக்கு 9,950 ரூபாய்.",
        "எஸ்டேட்/தொழிற்சாலையானது புகழ்பெற்ற தேயிலை உற்பத்தியாளரான ஆர்.ஜி.க்கு சொந்தமானது மற்றும் நிர்வகிக்கப்படுகிறது. ஜினதாச. உயர்தர 'சிலோன் தேயிலை' தயாரிப்பதில் அவரது ஆர்வம், குறைந்த வளர்ச்சியடைந்த பிராந்தியத்தில் ஆர்த்தடாக்ஸ் லீஃபி தரங்களை உற்பத்தி செய்து விற்பனை செய்யும் தனியார் தொழிற்சாலைகளில் அவர் பெற்ற வெற்றியின் மூலம் வெளிப்படுகிறது.",
        "முஸ்வென்னா தேயிலை தொழிற்சாலையில் நடைமுறைப்படுத்தப்பட்ட அதிநவீன உற்பத்தி செயல்முறையானது முஸ்வென்னா தேயிலைகள் பிரீமியம் விலையில் தொடர்ந்து விற்பனை செய்யப்படுவதற்கு காரணமாகும்.",
        "இலங்கை தேயிலை நிறுவனத்தில் தேயிலை பரிசோதகராக ஆரம்பித்த ஜினதாசவின் தேயிலை தொழில் வாழ்க்கை தற்போது நான்கு தசாப்தங்களுக்கும் மேலாக நீண்டுள்ளது. இச்சாதனையை அடைவதற்கு உறுதுணையாக இருந்த அவரது மகனும், பணிப்பாளருமான மதுஷங்க மலிதாண்ட் அனுபவம் வாய்ந்த தொழிற்சாலை நிர்வாகி சிசிர சிந்தக அவருக்குத் திறமையாக உதவுகிறார்.",
        "முஸ்வென்னா தேயிலை தொழிற்சாலை ISO 22000:2018, HACCP மற்றும் GMP சான்றளிக்கப்பட்டது மற்றும் ஆண்டுக்கு சுமார் 450,000 கிலோ உற்பத்தியைக் கொண்டுள்ளது.",
        "uswenna தேயிலைகள் பிரத்தியேகமாக Forbes & Walker Tea Brokers Ltd ஆல் விற்பனை செய்யப்பட்டு சந்தைப்படுத்தப்படுகின்றன."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ஃபோர்ப்ஸ் & வாக்கர் டீ தரகர்கள்",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ஊவா நடுத்தர வகை",
            "label": "EVENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "வாரந்தோறும்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "19/20 ஜூலை",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "மழைக்காடு கூட்டணி",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Hapugastenne Plantations PLC",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "பிரவுன்ஸ் பவர் ஹோல்டிங்ஸ் லிமிடெட்.",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "குழு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "நெலந்த சில்வா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "சென்ஹோரா சினெர்ஜிஸ் குழு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஹரங்கல்ல தேயிலை தொழிற்சாலை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "3,550",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "FBOP",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "19/20 ஜூலை",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஹரங்கல்ல தேயிலை தொழிற்சாலை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "கொத்மலை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "1,163 மீட்டர்",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "ISO 22000",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பாம்ப்ரகெல்லி எஸ்டேட்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஒரு கிலோ 3,150 ரூபாய்",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "19/20 ஜூலை",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "லிந்துலா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "மழைக்காடு கூட்டணி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஐஎஸ்ஓ",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பாம்ப்ரகெல்லி எஸ்டேட்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஹொரண தோட்டங்கள் பிஎல்சி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "சுபாஷ் நாராயணன்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "கல்பாடிதென்னே தேயிலை தொழிற்சாலை",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "சுதுவெலிபொதஹேன",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஒரு கிலோ 3,150 ரூபாய்",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "CTC",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "வாரந்தோறும்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "19/20 ஜூலை",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "கல்பாடிதென்னே தேயிலை தொழிற்சாலை",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "லெல்லோபிட்டிய",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இரத்தினபுரி",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "CTC",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "KDU குழு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "கே.டி. உபசேனா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "KDU குழு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "சமன் உபசேன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "KDU குழு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "துஷான் உபசேன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "சுதுவெலிபொதஹேன",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "CTC",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "முஸ்வென்னா தேயிலை தொழிற்சாலை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "கொழும்பு தேயிலை ஏலம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "முஸ்வென்னா தேயிலை தொழிற்சாலை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இமதுவா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "காலி",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஒரு கிலோ 9,950",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "பிரீமியம் பூக்கள்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "வாரந்தோறும்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "19/20 ஜூலை",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஆர்.ஜி. ஜினதாச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆர்த்தடாக்ஸ் இலை",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "குறைந்த வளர்ந்த பகுதி",
            "label": "EVENT"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "முஸ்வென்னா தேயிலை தொழிற்சாலை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "முஸ்வென்னா",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Jinadasa",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "நான்கு தசாப்தங்கள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "மதுஷங்க மலிதந்த்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "சிசிர சிந்தக",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "முஸ்வென்னா தேயிலை தொழிற்சாலை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ISO 22000:2018",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜிஎம்பி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "தோராயமாக 450,000 கிலோ",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Forbes & Walker Tea Brokers Ltd.",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}