{
  "newspaper_id": "ada-derana-lk",
  "url": "http://www.adaderana.lk/news/84706/myanmars-aung-san-suu-kyi-sentenced-to-3-years-in-prison-over-election-fraud",
  "time_ut": 1662102240,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Myanmar’s Aung San Suu Kyi sentenced to 3 years in prison over election fraud",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Myanmar’s Aung San Suu Kyi sentenced to 3 years in prison over election fraud",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "Myanmar’s deposed former leader Aung San Suu Kyi was found guilty of electoral fraud on Friday and sentenced by a judge to three years in jail with hard labour, according to a source familiar with the proceedings.",
        "The Nobel laureate and figurehead of Myanmar’s opposition to decades of military rule has been detained since a coup early last year and has already been sentenced to more than 17 years in prison. She denies all the allegations against her.",
        "On Friday, she was judged to have committed fraud in a November 2020 general election that her National League for Democracy (NLD) won with an overwhelming legislative majority, trouncing a party created by the powerful military.",
        "The source, who declined to be identified because they were not authorised to speak to media, said it was unclear what hard labour would entail. Co-defendant Win Myint, the deposed president, was given the same sentence, the source said.",
        "A spokesperson for the ruling military council did not immediately respond to a request for comment. The junta has said Suu Kyi is being given due process.",
        "The military seized power in February 2021 to stop Suu Kyi’s NLD from forming a new government after the election that it said had instances of fraud that had not properly been investigated.",
        "Suu Kyi, 76, has been on trial for more than a year on multiple charges, ranging from corruption and incitement to leaks of official secrets, for which the combined maximum sentences is more than 190 years.",
        "Her trials have been held behind closed doors in the capital, Naypyitaw, and the junta’s statements on the proceedings have been limited. A gag order has been imposed on Suu Kyi’s lawyers."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Myanmar",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "3 years",
          "label": "DATE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Myanmar",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Aung San Suu Kyi",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Friday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "three years",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Nobel",
            "label": "WORK_OF_ART"
          },
          {
            "text": "Myanmar",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "early last year",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "more than 17 years",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Friday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "November 2020",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "National League for Democracy",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "NLD",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Win Myint",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Suu Kyi",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "February 2021",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Suu Kyi’s",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Suu Kyi",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "76",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "more than a year",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "more than 190 years",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Naypyitaw",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Suu Kyi’s",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "මැතිවරණ දූෂණ සම්බන්ධයෙන් මියන්මාරයේ අවුන්සාන් සුකීට වසර 3ක සිර දඬුවම්",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "මියන්මාරයේ බලයෙන් පහ කරන ලද හිටපු නායිකා අවුන්සාන් සුකී සිකුරාදා මැතිවරණ වංචාවකට වරදකරු වූ අතර විනිසුරුවරයෙකු විසින් බරපතල වැඩ සහිත වසර තුනක සිරදඬුවම් නියම කරන ලද බව ක්‍රියාදාමයට හුරුපුරුදු මූලාශ්‍රයක් පවසයි.",
        "නොබෙල් ත්‍යාගලාභියා සහ මියන්මාරයේ දශක ගනනාවක මිලිටරි පාලනයට එරෙහි ප්‍රධානියා පසුගිය වසරේ මුල කුමන්ත්‍රණයකින් පසුව රඳවාගෙන සිටින අතර දැනටමත් වසර 17 කට වැඩි සිරදඬුවම් නියම කර ඇත. ඇය තමාට එරෙහි සියලු චෝදනා ප්‍රතික්ෂේප කරයි.",
        "බලගතු හමුදාව විසින් නිර්මාණය කරන ලද පක්ෂයක් පරාජය කරමින් ඇයගේ ප්‍රජාතන්ත්‍රවාදය සඳහා වූ ජාතික ලීගය (NLD) අතිවිශාල ව්‍යවස්ථාදායක බහුතරයකින් ජයග්‍රහණය කළ 2020 නොවැම්බර් මහ මැතිවරණයේදී ඇය වංචාවක් කර ඇති බවට සිකුරාදා විනිශ්චය කරන ලදී.",
        "මාධ්‍ය වෙත කතා කිරීමට ඔවුන්ට බලය නොමැති නිසා හඳුනා ගැනීම ප්‍රතික්ෂේප කළ මූලාශ්‍රය, වෙහෙස මහන්සි වී වැඩ කිරීම කුමක් වේද යන්න පැහැදිලි නැත. බලයෙන් පහ කරන ලද ජනාධිපති සම-විත්තිකරු Win Myint ට ද එම දඬුවම ලබා දී ඇති බව මූලාශ්‍රය පවසයි.",
        "පාලක හමුදා කවුන්සිලයේ ප්‍රකාශකයෙකු අදහස් දැක්වීම සඳහා වූ ඉල්ලීමකට වහාම ප්‍රතිචාර දැක්වූයේ නැත. ජුන්ටාව පවසා ඇත්තේ සුකීට නිසි ක්‍රියාවලියක් ලබා දෙන බවයි.",
        "මැතිවරණයෙන් පසු සූ කීගේ එන්එල්ඩී නව රජයක් පිහිටුවීම නැවැත්වීම සඳහා 2021 පෙබරවාරි මාසයේදී හමුදාව බලය අල්ලා ගත් අතර එය නිසි ලෙස විමර්ශනය නොකළ වංචා පිළිබඳ අවස්ථා ඇති බව පැවසීය.",
        "76 හැවිරිදි Suu Kyi, දූෂණය සහ උසිගැන්වීමේ සිට නිල රහස් හෙළිදරව් කිරීම දක්වා බහුවිධ චෝදනා යටතේ වසරකට වැඩි කාලයක් නඩු විභාගයට ලක්ව ඇති අතර, ඒ සඳහා ඒකාබද්ධ උපරිම දඬුවම් වසර 190 කට වඩා වැඩි ය.",
        "ඇයගේ නඩු විභාග අගනුවර වන Naypyitaw හි සංවෘත දොරවල් පිටුපස පවත්වා ඇති අතර, නඩු කටයුතු පිළිබඳ ජුන්ටාව ප්‍රකාශ සීමා කර ඇත. සුකීගේ නීතීඥයින්ට පට්ට නියෝගයක් පනවා ඇත."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "මියන්මාරය",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "අවුරුදු 3 යි",
          "label": "DATE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "මියන්මාරය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Aung San Suu Kyi",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "සිකුරාදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "වසර තුනක්",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "නොබෙල්",
            "label": "WORK_OF_ART"
          },
          {
            "text": "මියන්මාරය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "පසුගිය වසරේ මුල",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "අවුරුදු 17 ට වැඩි",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "සිකුරාදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "නොවැම්බර් 2020",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ප්රජාතන්ත්රවාදය සඳහා ජාතික ලීගය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "එන්එල්ඩී",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Myint දිනන්න",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Suu Kyi",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "2021 පෙබරවාරි",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Suu Kyi ගේ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Suu Kyi",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "76",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "වසරකට වැඩි කාලයක්",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "අවුරුදු 190 කට වඩා",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Naypyitaw",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Suu Kyi ගේ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "தேர்தல் முறைகேடு வழக்கில் மியான்மர் ஆங் சான் சூகிக்கு 3 ஆண்டுகள் சிறை தண்டனை விதிக்கப்பட்டுள்ளது",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "மியான்மரின் பதவி நீக்கம் செய்யப்பட்ட முன்னாள் தலைவர் ஆங் சான் சூகி வெள்ளிக்கிழமை தேர்தல் மோசடியில் ஈடுபட்டதாகக் கண்டறியப்பட்டு நீதிபதியால் மூன்று ஆண்டுகள் கடுங்காவல் சிறைத்தண்டனை விதிக்கப்பட்டதாக நடைமுறைகளை நன்கு அறிந்த ஒரு வட்டாரம் தெரிவித்துள்ளது.",
        "நோபல் பரிசு பெற்றவரும், பல தசாப்த கால இராணுவ ஆட்சிக்கு மியான்மரின் எதிர்ப்பின் தலைவருமான கடந்த ஆண்டின் தொடக்கத்தில் ஒரு சதிப்புரட்சிக்குப் பின்னர் தடுத்து வைக்கப்பட்டு ஏற்கனவே 17 ஆண்டுகளுக்கும் மேலாக சிறைத்தண்டனை விதிக்கப்பட்டுள்ளார். தன் மீதான அனைத்து குற்றச்சாட்டுகளையும் அவர் மறுக்கிறார்.",
        "வெள்ளிக்கிழமை, நவம்பர் 2020 பொதுத் தேர்தலில் அவர் மோசடி செய்ததாகத் தீர்ப்பளிக்கப்பட்டது, அவரது தேசிய ஜனநாயக லீக் (NLD) அதிக சட்டமன்ற பெரும்பான்மையுடன் வென்றது, சக்திவாய்ந்த இராணுவத்தால் உருவாக்கப்பட்ட ஒரு கட்சியை வீழ்த்தியது.",
        "ஊடகங்களுடன் பேசுவதற்கு அவர்களுக்கு அதிகாரம் இல்லாததால் அடையாளம் காண மறுத்த ஆதாரம், கடின உழைப்பு என்ன என்பது தெளிவாக இல்லை என்று கூறினார். பதவி நீக்கம் செய்யப்பட்ட ஜனாதிபதியின் இணை பிரதிவாதியான Win Myint க்கும் அதே தண்டனை வழங்கப்பட்டதாக அந்த வட்டாரம் தெரிவித்துள்ளது.",
        "ஆளும் இராணுவக் குழுவின் செய்தித் தொடர்பாளர் கருத்துக்கான கோரிக்கைக்கு உடனடியாக பதிலளிக்கவில்லை. சூகிக்கு உரிய நடைமுறை வழங்கப்படுவதாக ராணுவ ஆட்சிக்குழு கூறியுள்ளது.",
        "தேர்தலுக்குப் பிறகு சூகியின் என்எல்டி புதிய அரசாங்கத்தை அமைப்பதைத் தடுக்க பிப்ரவரி 2021 இல் இராணுவம் அதிகாரத்தைக் கைப்பற்றியது, அது முறையான விசாரணைக்கு உட்படுத்தப்படாத மோசடி சம்பவங்கள் இருப்பதாகக் கூறியது.",
        "76 வயதான சூ கி, ஊழல் மற்றும் தூண்டுதல் முதல் உத்தியோகபூர்வ ரகசியங்கள் கசிவு வரை பல குற்றச்சாட்டுகளில் ஒரு வருடத்திற்கும் மேலாக விசாரணைக்கு உட்படுத்தப்பட்டுள்ளார்.",
        "அவரது விசாரணைகள் தலைநகரான நேபிடாவில் மூடிய கதவுகளுக்குப் பின்னால் நடைபெற்றன, மேலும் நடவடிக்கைகள் குறித்த இராணுவ ஆட்சிக்குழுவின் அறிக்கைகள் குறைவாகவே உள்ளன. சூகியின் வழக்கறிஞர்கள் மீது காழ்ப்புணர்ச்சி உத்தரவு பிறப்பிக்கப்பட்டுள்ளது."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "மியான்மர்",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "3 ஆண்டுகள்",
          "label": "DATE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "மியான்மர்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Aung San Suu Kyi",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "வெள்ளி",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "மூன்று வருடங்கள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "நோபல்",
            "label": "WORK_OF_ART"
          },
          {
            "text": "மியான்மர்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "கடந்த ஆண்டு தொடக்கத்தில்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "17 ஆண்டுகளுக்கும் மேலாக",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "வெள்ளி",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "நவம்பர் 2020",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜனநாயகத்திற்கான தேசிய லீக்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "என்.எல்.டி",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "வின் மைண்ட்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Suu Kyi",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பிப்ரவரி 2021",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சூ கியின்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Suu Kyi",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "76",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஒரு வருடத்திற்கும் மேலாக",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "190 ஆண்டுகளுக்கும் மேலாக",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "நய்பிடாவ்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "சூ கியின்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}