{
  "newspaper_id": "economy-next-com",
  "url": "https://economynext.com/sri-lanka-main-opposition-demands-to-know-if-cope-copa-chairs-will-be-theirs-99134/",
  "time_ut": 1661747580,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Sri Lanka main opposition demands to know if COPE, COPA chairs will be theirs",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Sri Lanka main opposition demands to know if COPE, COPA chairs will be theirs",
      "author": "",
      "body_lines": [
        "ECONOMYNEXT – Sri Lanka opposition leader Sajith Premadasa has asked the government whether opposition MPs Kabir Hashim and Eran Wickramaratne are still going to be appointed chairs of the Committee on Public Enterprises (COPE) and Committee on Public Accounts (COPA) as promised.",
        "Several main opposition Samagi Jana Balawegaya (SJB) MPs speaking in parliament on Monday August 29 claimed that President Ranil Wickremesinghe when he was prime minister a few months earlier had said the chairmanship of COPE, COPA and the Committee on Public Finance must go to the opposition.",
        "SJB MP Harsha de Silva has already been appointed chair of the Committee on Public Finance.",
        "Sri Lanka opposition MP Harsha de Silva chairs first public finance committee meeting",
        "Opposition leader Premadasa and chief opposition whip Lakshman Kiriella asked whether standing orders in parliament were going to be suspended in order to make the appointments.",
        "Leader of the House and Education Minister Susil Premajayantha proposed that an agreement on the matter be reached at the next meeting of the Committee on Parliamentary Business chaired by Speaker Mahinda Yapa Abeywardena who is currently out of the country. It would be more prudent to discuss the matter in the presence of the speaker as there is no consensus yet on whether the chairmanships should definitely go to the opposition, said Premajayantha.",
        "MP Kiriella responded that a government MP had said that promises made at the height of the Aragalaya (Struggle) protests don’t count anymore. (Colombo/Aug29/2022)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Sri Lanka",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "COPE",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "COPA",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sajith Premadasa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kabir Hashim",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Eran Wickramaratne",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Committee on Public Enterprises",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "COPE",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Committee on Public Accounts",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Samagi",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Jana Balawegaya",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "SJB",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Monday August 29",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "a few months earlier",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "COPE",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "COPA",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Committee on Public Finance",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Harsha de Silva",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Committee on Public Finance",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Harsha de Silva",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Premadasa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Lakshman Kiriella",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "House",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Education",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Susil Premajayantha",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Committee on Parliamentary Business",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Mahinda Yapa Abeywardena",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Premajayantha",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Kiriella",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "ශ්‍රී ලංකා ප්‍රධාන විපක්ෂය ඉල්ලා සිටින්නේ කෝප්, කෝපා පුටු තමන්ට හිමි වේද යන්නයි",
      "author": "",
      "body_lines": [
        "ECONOMYNEXT – පොරොන්දු වූ පරිදි පොදු ව්‍යාපාර කාරක සභාවේ (කෝප්) සහ රාජ්‍ය ගිණුම් කාරක සභාවේ (COPA) සභාපතිවරුන් ලෙස විපක්ෂයේ මන්ත්‍රීවරුන් වන කබීර් හෂීම් සහ ඉරාන් වික්‍රමරත්න තවමත් පත් කිරීමට යන්නේ දැයි ශ්‍රී ලංකා විපක්ෂ නායක සජිත් ප්‍රේමදාස රජයෙන් විමසා තිබේ.",
        "අගෝස්තු 29 සඳුදා පාර්ලිමේන්තුවේදී අදහස් දැක්වූ ප්‍රධාන විපක්ෂයේ සමගි ජන බලවේගයේ (SJB) මන්ත්‍රීවරු කිහිප දෙනෙක් කියා සිටියේ මීට මාස කිහිපයකට පෙර රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතා අගමැතිව සිටියදී කෝප්, කෝපා සහ රාජ්‍ය මුදල් කාරක සභාවේ සභාපතිකම විපක්ෂයට යා යුතු බව ප්‍රකාශ කළ බවයි. .",
        "SJB පාර්ලිමේන්තු මන්ත්‍රී හර්ෂ ද සිල්වා දැනටමත් රාජ්‍ය මුදල් පිළිබඳ කාරක සභාවේ සභාපතිවරයා ලෙස පත් කර ඇත.",
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකා විපක්ෂ පාර්ලිමේන්තු මන්ත්‍රී හර්ෂ ද සිල්වා ප්‍රථම රාජ්‍ය මූල්‍ය කමිටු රැස්වීමේ මුලසුන හොබවයි",
        "විපක්ෂ නායක ප්‍රේමදාස සහ විපක්ෂයේ ප්‍රධාන සංවිධායක ලක්ෂ්මන් කිරිඇල්ල විමසා සිටියේ පත්කිරීම් සිදුකිරීමට පාර්ලිමේන්තුවේ ස්ථාවර නියෝග අත්හිටුවීමට යන්නේ දැයි කියාය.",
        "දැනට රටින් බැහැරව සිටින කථානායක මහින්ද යාපා අබේවර්ධන මහතාගේ ප්‍රධානත්වයෙන් රැස්වන පාර්ලිමේන්තු කටයුතු පිළිබඳ මීළඟ රැස්වීමේදී ඒ පිළිබඳ එකඟතාවකට පැමිණිය යුතු බවට සභානායක සහ අධ්‍යාපන ඇමැති සුසිල් ප්‍රේමජයන්ත මහතා යෝජනා කළේය. සභාපති ධුර නියත වශයෙන්ම විපක්ෂයට යා යුතුද යන්න පිළිබඳව තවමත් එකඟතාවයක් නොමැති බැවින් කථානායකවරයා ඉදිරියේ මේ පිළිබඳව සාකච්ඡා කිරීම වඩාත් ඥානාන්විත වනු ඇතැයි ප්‍රේමජයන්ත පැවසීය.",
        "කිරිඇල්ල මන්ත්‍රීවරයා ප්‍රතිචාර දක්වමින් කියා සිටියේ අරගලය (අරගල) විරෝධතාවයේ උච්චතම අවස්ථාවේදී දුන් පොරොන්දු තවදුරටත් ගණන් නොගන්නා බව ආණ්ඩුවේ මන්ත්‍රීවරයෙකු පවසා ඇති බවයි. (කොළඹ/අගෝස්තු 29/2022)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "කෝප්",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "COPA",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "සජිත් ප්‍රේමදාස",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "කබීර් හෂීම්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "එරාන් වික්‍රමරත්න",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "පොදු ව්‍යාපාර පිළිබඳ කාරක සභාව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "කෝප්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "රාජ්ය ගිණුම් පිළිබඳ කාරක සභාව",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "සමගි",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජන බලවේගය",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "එස්.ජේ.බී",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "අගෝස්තු 29 සඳුදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "මාස කිහිපයකට පෙර",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "කෝප්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "COPA",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "රාජ්ය මුදල් පිළිබඳ කාරක සභාව",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "හර්ෂ ද සිල්වා",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "රාජ්ය මුදල් පිළිබඳ කාරක සභාව",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "හර්ෂ ද සිල්වා",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ප්‍රේමදාස ය",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ලක්ෂ්මන් කිරිඇල්ල",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "නිවස",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "අධ්යාපන",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "සුසිල් ප්‍රේමජයන්ත",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තු කටයුතු පිළිබඳ කාරක සභාව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "මහින්ද යාපා අබේවර්ධන",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ප්‍රේමජයන්ත",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "කිරිඇල්ල",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "கோப், கோபா கதிரைகள் தங்களுடையதா என்பதை அறிய இலங்கை பிரதான எதிர்க்கட்சி கோருகிறது",
      "author": "",
      "body_lines": [
        "பொருளாதாரம் - வாக்குறுதியளித்தபடி பொது நிறுவனங்கள் மீதான குழு (கோப்) மற்றும் பொதுக் கணக்குகள் குழு (கோபா) ஆகியவற்றின் தலைவர்களாக எதிர்க்கட்சி எம்.பி.க்களான கபீர் ஹாசிம் மற்றும் எரான் விக்கிரமரத்ன ஆகியோர் இன்னும் நியமிக்கப்படப் போகிறார்கள் என்று இலங்கை எதிர்க்கட்சித் தலைவர் சஜித் பிரேமதாச அரசாங்கத்திடம் கேட்டுள்ளார்.",
        "பல பிரதான எதிர்க்கட்சியான சமகி ஜன பலவேகய (SJB) பாராளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர்கள் ஆகஸ்ட் 29 திங்கட்கிழமை பாராளுமன்றத்தில் பேசுகையில், ஜனாதிபதி ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க சில மாதங்களுக்கு முன்னர் பிரதமராக இருந்தபோது கோப், கோபா மற்றும் பொது நிதிக் குழுவின் தலைவர்கள் எதிர்க்கட்சிக்கு செல்ல வேண்டும் என்று கூறியதாகக் கூறினர். .",
        "SJB பாராளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர் ஹர்ஷ டி சில்வா ஏற்கனவே பொது நிதி தொடர்பான குழுவின் தலைவராக நியமிக்கப்பட்டுள்ளார்.",
        "இலங்கை எதிர்க்கட்சி எம்பி ஹர்ஷ டி சில்வா முதல் பொது நிதிக் குழு கூட்டத்திற்கு தலைமை தாங்கினார்",
        "நியமனங்களை வழங்குவதற்காக பாராளுமன்ற நிலையியற் கட்டளைகளை இடைநிறுத்தப் போகின்றதா என எதிர்க்கட்சித் தலைவர் பிரேமதாச மற்றும் எதிர்க்கட்சி பிரதம கொறடா லக்ஷ்மன் கிரியெல்ல ஆகியோர் வினவினார்கள்.",
        "தற்போது நாட்டிற்கு வெளியே உள்ள சபாநாயகர் மஹிந்த யாப்பா அபேவர்தன தலைமையில் பாராளுமன்ற அலுவல்கள் குழுவின் அடுத்த கூட்டத்தில் இந்த விடயம் தொடர்பில் இணக்கப்பாடு எட்டப்படும் என அவைத் தலைவரும் கல்வி அமைச்சருமான சுசில் பிரேமஜயந்த முன்மொழிந்தார். தலைவர் பதவிகள் கண்டிப்பாக எதிர்க்கட்சிக்கு செல்ல வேண்டுமா என்பது குறித்து இன்னும் ஒருமித்த கருத்து ஏற்படாததால், சபாநாயகர் முன்னிலையில் இந்த விஷயத்தை விவாதிப்பது மிகவும் விவேகமானதாக இருக்கும் என்று பிரேமஜயந்த கூறினார்.",
        "இதற்கு பதிலளித்த பாராளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர் கிரியெல்ல, அறகலய (போராட்டம்) போராட்டத்தின் உச்சக்கட்டத்தில் வழங்கப்பட்ட வாக்குறுதிகள் இனி எண்ணப்படாது என அரசாங்கத்தின் பாராளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர் ஒருவர் கூறியதாக தெரிவித்தார். (கொழும்பு/ஆகஸ்ட்29/2022)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "இலங்கை",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "கோப்",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "COPA",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சஜித் பிரேமதாச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "கபீர் ஹாசிம்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "எரான் விக்கிரமரத்ன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "பொது நிறுவனங்களுக்கான குழு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "கோப்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "பொது கணக்குகளுக்கான குழு",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "சமகி",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜன பலவேகயா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "எஸ்.ஜே.பி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆகஸ்ட் 29 திங்கட்கிழமை",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "சில மாதங்களுக்கு முன்பு",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "கோப்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "COPA",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "பொது நிதிக்கான குழு",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஹர்ஷ டி சில்வா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "பொது நிதிக்கான குழு",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஹர்ஷ டி சில்வா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பிரேமதாச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "லக்ஷ்மன் கிரியெல்ல",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "வீடு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "கல்வி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "சுசில் பிரேமஜயந்த",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்ற விவகாரங்களுக்கான குழு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "மஹிந்த யாப்பா அபேவர்தன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "பிரேமஜயந்த",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "கிரியெல்ல",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}