{
  "newspaper_id": "tamil-mirror-lk",
  "url": "https://www.tamilmirror.lk/செய்திகள்/இலங்கைக்கு-ஆதரவளிப்போம்-பொரிஸ்-ஜோன்சன்/175-303471",
  "time_ut": 1662143449,
  "original_lang": "ta",
  "original_title": "இலங்கைக்கு ஆதரவளிப்போம்: பொரிஸ் ஜோன்சன்",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Let's support Sri Lanka: Boris Johnson",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "Amid the economic and social challenges the country is currently facing, British Prime Minister Boris Johnson has said that Britain will continue to support the people of Sri Lanka.",
        "The British Prime Minister said this in his message congratulating Ranil Wickremesinghe on his inauguration as the President of Sri Lanka.",
        "British Prime Minister Boris Johnson has praised President Ranil Wickremesinghe's efforts to establish a government that prioritizes finding permanent solutions to the problems faced by the people of Sri Lanka.",
        "He also mentioned that following democratic principles and achieving democratic harmony will lead to the victory of President Ranil Wickremesinghe.",
        "I am confident that you will be able to see progress very soon with the cooperation of the International Monetary Fund. Boris Johnson also mentioned that Britain is waiting to work with its international partners to help Sri Lanka in this matter. (a)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Sri Lanka",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "Boris Johnson",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "British",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Boris Johnson",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Britain",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "British",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "British",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Boris Johnson",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the International Monetary Fund",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Boris Johnson",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Britain",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවට සහය දෙමු: බොරිස් ජොන්සන්",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "රට මේ වන විට මුහුණ දී සිටින ආර්ථික සහ සමාජීය අභියෝග මධ්‍යයේ බ්‍රිතාන්‍ය අග්‍රාමාත්‍ය බොරිස් ජොන්සන් ප්‍රකාශ කළේ ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ ජනතාවට බ්‍රිතාන්‍යය අඛණ්ඩව සහය ලබා දෙන බවයි.",
        "බ්‍රිතාන්‍ය අග්‍රාමාත්‍යවරයා මේ බව කියා සිටියේ ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ ජනාධිපතිවරයා ලෙස දිවුරුම් දුන් රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතාට සුබ පැතුම් එක් කරමින් සිය පණිවිඩය නිකුත් කරමින්.",
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ ජනතාව මුහුණ දෙන ගැටලුවලට ස්ථිර විසඳුම් සෙවීමට ප්‍රමුඛත්වය දෙන රජයක් පිහිටුවීමට ජනාධිපති රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතා ගන්නා උත්සාහය බ්‍රිතාන්‍ය අගමැති බොරිස් ජොන්සන්ගේ පැසසුමට ලක්ව තිබේ.",
        "ප‍්‍රජාතන්ත‍්‍රවාදී ප‍්‍රතිපත්ති පිළිපැදීම සහ ප‍්‍රජාතන්ත‍්‍රවාදී සංහිඳියාව ඇති කිරීම ජනාධිපති රනිල් වික‍්‍රමසිංහ මහතාගේ ජයග‍්‍රහණයට හේතුවන බවද ඔහු සඳහන් කළා.",
        "ජාත්‍යන්තර මූල්‍ය අරමුදලේ සහයෝගීතාවයෙන් ඔබට ඉතා ඉක්මනින් ප්‍රගතියක් දැකීමට හැකි වනු ඇතැයි මට විශ්වාසයි. මෙම කාරණයේදී ශ්‍රී ලංකාවට උපකාර කිරීම සඳහා බ්‍රිතාන්‍යය සිය ජාත්‍යන්තර හවුල්කරුවන් සමඟ කටයුතු කිරීමට බලා සිටින බව ද බොරිස් ජොන්සන් සඳහන් කළේය. (ඒ)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "බොරිස් ජොන්සන්",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "බ්රිතාන්ය",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "බොරිස් ජොන්සන්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "බ්රිතාන්යය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "බ්රිතාන්ය",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "බ්රිතාන්ය",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "බොරිස් ජොන්සන්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ජාත්‍යන්තර මුල්‍ය අරමුදල",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "බොරිස් ජොන්සන්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "බ්රිතාන්යය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "இலங்கைக்கு ஆதரவளிப்போம்: பொரிஸ் ஜோன்சன்",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "நாடு தற்போது எதிர்கொண்டுள்ள பொருளாதார, சமூக சவால்களுக்கு மத்தியில், பிரித்தானியா இலங்கை மக்களுக்கு தொடர்ந்தும் ஆதரவளிக்கும் என பிரித்தானியப் பிரதமர் பொரிஸ் ஜோன்சன் தெரிவித்துள்ளார்.",
        "இலங்கையின் ஜனாதிபதியாக ரணில் விக்ரமசிங்க அவர்கள் பதவியேற்றமைக்கு வாழ்த்துத் தெரிவித்து அனுப்பியுள்ள செய்தியில் பிரித்தானியப் பிரதமர் இதனைத் தெரிவித்துள்ளார்.",
        "இலங்கை மக்கள் எதிர்நோக்கியுள்ள பிரச்சினைகளுக்கு நிரந்தர தீர்வுகாண்பதற்கு முன்னுரிமையளிக்கும், அரசாங்கமொன்றை நிறுவுவதற்கு ஜனாதிபதி ரணில் விக்ரமசிங்க அவர்கள் எடுத்துள்ள முயற்சிகளுக்கு பிரித்தானியப் பிரதமர் பொரிஸ் ஜோன்சன் பாராட்டு தெரிவித்துள்ளார்.",
        "ஜனநாயக கொள்கைகளை பின்பற்றுவது, ஜனநாயக இணக்கப்பாட்டை எட்டுவது என்பன ஜனாதிபதி ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்கவின் வெற்றிக்கு வழிவகுக்கும் என்றும் அவர் குறிப்பிட்டுள்ளார்.",
        "சர்வதேச நாணய நிதியத்தின் ஒத்துழைப்புடன் மிக விரைவில் உங்களால் முன்னேற்றத்தைக் காண முடியும் என்பதில் எனக்கு நம்பிக்கையுண்டு. இவ்விடயத்தில் இலங்கைக்கு உதவ, தமது சர்வதேச பங்குதாரர்களுடன் பிரித்தானியா இணைந்து செயற்பட காத்திருப்பதாகவும் என்றும் பொரிஸ் ஜோன்சன்  குறிப்பிட்டுள்ளார். (a)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "இலங்கை",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "போரிஸ் ஜான்சன்",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "பிரிட்டிஷ்",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "போரிஸ் ஜான்சன்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "பிரிட்டன்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பிரிட்டிஷ்",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பிரிட்டிஷ்",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "போரிஸ் ஜான்சன்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "சர்வதேச நாணய நிதியம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "போரிஸ் ஜான்சன்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "பிரிட்டன்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}