{
  "newspaper_id": "economy-next-com",
  "url": "https://economynext.com/sri-lanka-to-change-laws-to-facilitate-state-timber-corporation-exports-98914/",
  "time_ut": 1661255100,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Sri Lanka to change laws to facilitate State Timber Corporation exports",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Sri Lanka to change laws to facilitate State Timber Corporation exports",
      "author": "Chanka Jayasinghe",
      "body_lines": [
        "ECOOMYNEXT –  Sri Lanka’s cabinet of ministers have approved a proposed amendment to a law that will enable the State Timber Corporation to to export timber and collaborate with the private, an official said.",
        "Cabinet spokesman Bandula Gunawardena told reporters at the weekly cabinet press briefing on Tuesday August 23 that approval has been granted to amend the State Industrial Corporations Act (No 49 of 1957) which the State Timber Corporation was established under, in accordance with the current objectives of the government and the country.",
        "“Lately the timber corporation has been mostly engaged in value addition activities. Many furniture and other products are presented by designers in the corporation and these products have a great value in the international market as well,” said Gunawardena.",
        "However, he said, the corporation does not have the authority to export its products, and amendments will be made to the relevant act to give the corporation permission to export and collaborate with the private sector in a bid to improve businesses, he said.  (Colombo/Aug23/2022)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Sri Lanka",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "State Timber Corporation",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ECOOMYNEXT",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka’s",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the State Timber Corporation",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Cabinet",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Bandula Gunawardena",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "weekly",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Tuesday August 23",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the State Industrial Corporations Act",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "No 49 of 1957",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the State Timber Corporation",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Gunawardena",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        []
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "ශ්‍රී ලංකාව රාජ්‍ය දැව සංස්ථාවේ අපනයනය පහසු කිරීම සඳහා නීති වෙනස් කිරීමට",
      "author": "චංක ජයසිංහ",
      "body_lines": [
        "ECOOMYNEXT -  රාජ්‍ය දැව සංස්ථාවට දැව අපනයනය කිරීමට සහ පුද්ගලික සමඟ සහයෝගයෙන් කටයුතු කිරීමට හැකි වන පරිදි නීතියක් සඳහා යෝජිත සංශෝධනයක් ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ අමාත්‍ය මණ්ඩලය විසින් අනුමත කර ඇති බව නිලධාරියෙක් පැවසීය.",
        "අමාත්‍ය මණ්ඩල ප්‍රකාශක බන්දුල ගුණවර්ධන මහතා අගෝස්තු 23 වැනි අඟහරුවාදා සතිපතා කැබිනට් මාධ්‍ය හමුවේදී මාධ්‍යවේදීන් අමතමින් කියා සිටියේ වත්මන් අරමුණු අනුව රාජ්‍ය දැව සංස්ථාව පිහිටුවා ඇති රාජ්‍ය කාර්මික සංස්ථා පනත (1957 අංක 49) සංශෝධනය කිරීමට අනුමැතිය ලැබී ඇති බවයි. රජය සහ රට.",
        "“පසුගිය කාලයේ දැව සංස්ථාව වැඩිපුරම නිරත වුණේ අගය එකතු කිරීමේ කටයුතුවලයි. බොහෝ ගෘහ භාණ්ඩ සහ අනෙකුත් නිෂ්පාදන සංස්ථාවේ නිර්මාණකරුවන් විසින් ඉදිරිපත් කරනු ලබන අතර ජාත්‍යන්තර වෙළඳපොලේ ද මෙම නිෂ්පාදනවලට විශාල වටිනාකමක් තිබෙනවා” යැයි ගුණවර්ධන මහතා පැවසීය.",
        "කෙසේ වෙතත්, සංස්ථාවට තම නිෂ්පාදන අපනයනය කිරීමට බලයක් නොමැති බවත්, ව්‍යාපාර වැඩිදියුණු කිරීම සඳහා අපනයනය කිරීමට සහ පෞද්ගලික අංශය සමඟ සහයෝගයෙන් කටයුතු කිරීමට සංස්ථාවට අවසර දීම සඳහා අදාළ පනතට සංශෝධන සිදු කරන බවත් ඔහු පැවසීය. (කොළඹ/අගෝස්තු 23/2022)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "රාජ්ය දැව සංස්ථාව",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ECOOMYNEXT",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "රාජ්ය දැව සංස්ථාව",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "මණ්ඩල",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "බන්දුල ගුණවර්ධන",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "සතිපතා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "අගෝස්තු 23 අඟහරුවාදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "රාජ්ය කාර්මික සංස්ථා පනත",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "1957 අංක 49",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "රාජ්ය දැව සංස්ථාව",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ගුණවර්ධන ය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        []
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "அரச மரக் கூட்டுத்தாபன ஏற்றுமதியை இலகுபடுத்தும் வகையில் இலங்கை சட்டங்களை மாற்றவுள்ளது",
      "author": "சங்க ஜெயசிங்க",
      "body_lines": [
        "ECOOMYNEXT –  அரச மரக் கூட்டுத்தாபனத்திற்கு மரங்களை ஏற்றுமதி செய்வதற்கும் தனியாருடன் இணைந்து செயற்படுவதற்கும் உதவும் சட்டத்தில் முன்மொழியப்பட்ட திருத்தத்திற்கு இலங்கையின் அமைச்சர்கள் அமைச்சரவை ஒப்புதல் அளித்துள்ளதாக அதிகாரி ஒருவர் தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "அரச மரக் கூட்டுத்தாபனம் ஸ்தாபிக்கப்பட்ட அரச கைத்தொழில் கூட்டுத்தாபனங்கள் சட்டத்தை (1957 இலக்கம் 49) தற்போதைய நோக்கங்களுக்கு ஏற்ப திருத்துவதற்கு அனுமதி வழங்கப்பட்டுள்ளதாக அமைச்சரவைப் பேச்சாளர் பந்துல குணவர்தன செவ்வாய்க்கிழமை வாராந்த அமைச்சரவை செய்தியாளர் மாநாட்டில் தெரிவித்தார். அரசாங்கம் மற்றும் நாடு.",
        "“சமீப காலமாக மரக் கூட்டுத்தாபனம் பெரும்பாலும் மதிப்பு கூட்டல் நடவடிக்கைகளில் ஈடுபட்டு வருகிறது. பல தளபாடங்கள் மற்றும் பிற தயாரிப்புகள் கூட்டுத்தாபனத்தில் வடிவமைப்பாளர்களால் வழங்கப்படுகின்றன, மேலும் இந்த தயாரிப்புகளுக்கு சர்வதேச சந்தையிலும் பெரும் மதிப்பு உள்ளது, ”என்று குணவர்தன கூறினார்.",
        "இருப்பினும், அதன் தயாரிப்புகளை ஏற்றுமதி செய்ய மாநகராட்சிக்கு அதிகாரம் இல்லை, மேலும் வணிகத்தை மேம்படுத்தும் முயற்சியில் ஏற்றுமதி மற்றும் தனியார் துறையுடன் ஒத்துழைக்க மாநகராட்சிக்கு அனுமதி வழங்க சம்பந்தப்பட்ட சட்டத்தில் திருத்தங்கள் செய்யப்படும், என்றார். (கொழும்பு/ஆகஸ்ட்23/2022)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "இலங்கை",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "மாநில மரக் கழகம்",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ECOOMYNEXT",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கையின்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "மாநில மரக் கழகம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "மந்திரி சபை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "பந்துல குணவர்தன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "வாரந்தோறும்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆகஸ்ட் 23 செவ்வாய்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "மாநில தொழில் நிறுவனங்கள் சட்டம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "1957 இன் எண் 49",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "மாநில மரக் கழகம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "குணவர்தன",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        []
      ]
    }
  }
}