{
  "newspaper_id": "lankadeepa-lk",
  "url": "https://www.lankadeepa.lk/latest_news/බුලත්සිංහල-ගම්-රැසක්-ජලයෙන්-යට-වෙයි/1-619103",
  "time_ut": 1662012084,
  "original_lang": "si",
  "original_title": "බුලත්සිංහල ගම් රැසක් ජලයෙන් යට වෙයි",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Many Bulathsinhala villages will be submerged",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "According to the irrigation engineers, two sluice gates of the Kukulegaga Reservoir have been opened due to the heavy rainfall, and a water capacity of about 200 cubic meters per tappere is being released into the small river.",
        "Due to this, many low lands and several roads in Bulathsinhala area have been flooded, according to Mr. Prasad Perera, Divisional Secretary of Bulathsinhala.",
        "As of now, several areas including the Paragoda Atambagas junction on the Bulathsinghala Molkawa main road have been flooded, traffic has come to a standstill and the people are facing severe difficulties.",
        "Even now, there is heavy rain in those areas and people are seen using their fingers to travel."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Bulathsinhala",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "two",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Kukulegaga Reservoir",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "about 200 cubic meters",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Bulathsinhala",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Prasad Perera",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Divisional",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Bulathsinhala",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Paragoda Atambagas",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        []
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "බුලත්සිංහල ගම් රැසක් ජලයෙන් යට වෙයි",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "පවතින අධික වර්ෂාපතනයත් සමඟ කුකුලෙගග ජලාශයේ වාන් දොරටු දෙකක් මේ වන විට විවර කර ඇති අතර ඉන් තප්පරේට ඝන මීටර් 200 ක පමණ ජල ධාරිතාවක් කුඩා ගඟට මුදා හරින බව වාරිමාර්ග ඉන්ජේනේරුවෝ පවසති.",
        "මේ හේතුවෙන් බුලත්සිංහල ප්‍රදේශයේ පහත් බිම් රැසක් සහ මාර්ග කිහිපයක් ජලයෙන් යටවී ඇතැයි බුලත්සිංහල ප්‍රාදේශීය ලේකම් ප්‍රසාද් පෙරේරා මහතා පවසයි.",
        "මේ වනවිට බුලත්සිංහල මෝල්කාව ප්‍රධාන මාර්ගයේ පරගොඩ ඇටඹගස් හන්දිය ඇතුළු ප්‍රදේශ කිහිපයක් ජලයෙන් යටවීම නිසා ගමනාගමන කටයුතු සම්පූර්ණයෙන්ම ඇණ හිට ඇති අතර ජනතාව දැඩි දුෂ්කරතාවන්ට මුහුනපා සිටිති.",
        "මේ වන විටත් එම ප්‍රදේශවලට අධික වැසි තත්වයක් පවතින අතර ජනතාව අඟුල් ආදී යොදා ගනිමින් ගමනාගමන කටයුතු සිදුකරන ගන්නා ආකාරය දක්නට ලැබේ."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "බුලත්සිංහල",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "දෙක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "කුකුළේගග ජලාශය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඝන මීටර් 200 ක් පමණ",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "බුලත්සිංහල",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ප්‍රසාද් පෙරේරා",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "කොට්ඨාශ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "බුලත්සිංහල",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "පරගොඩ ඇටඹගස්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        []
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "புலத்சிங்கள கிராமங்கள் பல நீரில் மூழ்கும்",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "கடும் மழை காரணமாக குக்குலேககா நீர்த்தேக்கத்தின் இரண்டு வான் கதவுகள் திறக்கப்பட்டுள்ளதாகவும், தப்பேர் ஒன்றுக்கு சுமார் 200 கன மீற்றர் நீர் கொள்ளளவு சிறிய ஆற்றில் திறந்து விடப்படுவதாக நீர்ப்பாசன பொறியியலாளர்கள் தெரிவிக்கின்றனர்.",
        "இதன் காரணமாக புலத்சிங்கள பிரதேசத்தில் பல தாழ் நிலங்களும் பல வீதிகளும் வெள்ளத்தில் மூழ்கியுள்ளதாக புலத்சிங்கள பிரதேச செயலாளர் திரு.பிரசாத் பெரேரா தெரிவித்துள்ளார்.",
        "தற்போது புலத்சிங்கள மொல்காவ பிரதான வீதியின் பரகொட அதம்பகஸ் சந்தி உட்பட பல பகுதிகள் வெள்ளத்தில் மூழ்கி போக்குவரத்து ஸ்தம்பித்து மக்கள் கடும் சிரமங்களை எதிர்நோக்கியுள்ளனர்.",
        "தற்போதும் அப்பகுதிகளில் கனமழை பெய்து வருவதால் மக்கள் விரலைப் பயன்படுத்தி பயணிக்கின்றனர்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "புலத்சிங்கள",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "இரண்டு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "குகுலேகாகா நீர்த்தேக்கம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "சுமார் 200 கன மீட்டர்",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "புலத்சிங்கள",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "பிரசாத் பெரேரா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "பிரிவு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "புலத்சிங்கள",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பரகோடா அடம்பகாஸ்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        []
      ]
    }
  }
}