{
  "newspaper_id": "daily-ft-lk",
  "url": "https://www.ft.lk/news/SLPP-pays-tribute-to-service-rendered-by-President-Gotabaya-Rajapaksa/56-737577",
  "time_ut": 1657911877,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "SLPP pays tribute to service rendered by President Gotabaya Rajapaksa",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "SLPP pays tribute to service rendered by President Gotabaya Rajapaksa",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "The Sri Lanka Podujana Peramuna (SLPP), issuing a statement on the resignation of President Gotabaya Rajapaksa, paid tribute to the service rendered by the Sri Lankan leader during his short tenure as the eighth Executive President of Sri Lanka.",
        "The Sri Lanka Podujana Peramuna said that the most seen in the political world are attempts to take political power, and relinquishing power and positions is very rare.",
        "“In the history of the country, no Executive President has left office before the end of his term. It is indeed a difficult decision.”",
        "The SLPP pointed out that President Gotabaya Rajapaksa has reached that difficult decision and that he signed the letter of resignation related to leaving the Presidency with half of his term remaining.",
        "The SLPP noted that Gotabaya Rajapaksa, who played a decisive role in bringing peace to the motherland by ending 30 years of terrible terrorism, won the last Presidential Election with a historic mandate.",
        "He had to face the complex challenge of saving the lives of his fellow countrymen from the COVID epidemic even before three months had passed since assuming the office of President.",
        "The Podujana Peramuna mentioned that even the international community had accepted that the President of Sri Lanka had succeeded in properly managing the COVID disaster.",
        "Sri Lanka’s foreign exchange problem, which was in the make due to long-term reasons, developed into a serious crisis in the face of the COVID disaster.",
        "Saluting Gotabaya Rajapaksa for his service as a war hero on the battlefield, as the State Defence Secretary and as the President of the Democratic Socialist Republic of Sri Lanka, Sri Lanka Podujana Peramuna also emphasised that a dialogue about the values of an honest man like Gotabaya Rajapaksa will definitely be created through the conscience of future citizens."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Gotabaya Rajapaksa",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "Podujana Peramuna",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Gotabaya Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lankan",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "eighth",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "Podujana Peramuna",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "Gotabaya Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "half",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Gotabaya Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "30 years",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "three months",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka’s",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Gotabaya Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the State Defence",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Democratic Socialist Republic of Sri Lanka",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Podujana Peramuna",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Gotabaya Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "ජනාධිපති ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ මහතා ඉටුකළ සේවයට ශ්‍රී ලංකා පොදුජන පෙරමුණේ ප්‍රණාමය",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "ජනාධිපති ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ මහතාගේ ඉල්ලා අස්වීම පිළිබඳව නිවේදනයක් නිකුත් කරමින් ශ්‍රී ලංකා පොදුජන පෙරමුණ (SLPP) ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ අටවැනි විධායක ජනාධිපතිවරයා ලෙස කෙටි ධුර කාලය තුළ ශ්‍රී ලංකා නායකයා කළ සේවයට උපහාර පුද කළේය.",
        "දේශපාලන ලෝකයේ වැඩිපුරම දකින්නට ලැබෙන්නේ දේශපාලන බලය ලබා ගැනීමේ උත්සාහයන් බවත්, බලය සහ තනතුරු අත්හැරීම ඉතා දුර්ලභ බවත් ශ්‍රී ලංකා පොදුජන පෙරමුණ ප්‍රකාශ කළේය.",
        "“රටේ ඉතිහාසයේ කිසිම විධායක ජනාධිපතිවරයකු තම ධුර කාලය අවසන් වීමට පෙර ධුරවලින් ඉවත් වී නැහැ. ඇත්තටම ඒක අමාරු තීරණයක්.”",
        "ජනාධිපති ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ මහතා එම අසීරු තීරණයට එළැඹ ඇති බවත් ඔහුගේ ධූර කාලයෙන් අඩක් ඉතිරිව තිබියදී ජනාධිපති ධූරයෙන් ඉවත්වීමට අදාළ ඉල්ලා අස්වීමේ ලිපියට ඔහු අත්සන් කළ බවත් ශ්‍රී ලංකා පොදුජන පෙරමුණ පෙන්වා දෙනවා.",
        "තිස් වසරක බිහිසුණු ත්‍රස්තවාදය අවසන් කරමින් මාතෘ භූමියට සාමය උදාකරලීමට තීරණාත්මක කාර්යභාරයක් ඉටුකළ ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ මහතා පසුගිය ජනාධිපතිවරණයේදී ඓතිහාසික ජනවරමක් සහිතව ජයග්‍රහණය කළ බව ශ්‍රී ලංකා පොදුජන පෙරමුණ සඳහන් කළේය.",
        "ජනාධිපති ධූරයට පත්වී මාස තුනක් ගතවීමටත් පෙර කොවිඩ් වසංගතයෙන් තම සහෝදර රටවැසියන්ගේ ජීවිත බේරා ගැනීමේ සංකීර්ණ අභියෝගයට මුහුණ දීමට ඔහුට සිදු විය.",
        "කොවිඩ් ව්‍යසනය නිසි ලෙස කළමනාකරණය කිරීමට ශ්‍රී ලංකා ජනාධිපතිවරයා සමත් වූ බව ජාත්‍යන්තර ප්‍රජාව පවා පිළිගෙන ඇති බව පොදුජන පෙරමුණ සඳහන් කළා.",
        "දිගුකාලීන හේතූන් මත ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ විදේශ විනිමය ගැටලුව කොවිඩ් ව්‍යසනය හමුවේ බරපතල අර්බුදයක් දක්වා වර්ධනය විය.",
        "යුද බිමේ රණවිරුවෙකු ලෙසත්, රාජ්‍ය ආරක්ෂක ලේකම්වරයා ලෙසත්, ශ්‍රී ලංකා ප්‍රජාතාන්ත්‍රික සමාජවාදී ජනරජයේ සභාපතිවරයා ලෙසත් ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ මහතා කළ සේවයට ආචාර කරමින් ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ මහතා වැනි අවංක මිනිසෙකුගේ වටිනාකම් පිළිබඳ සංවාදයක් ගොඩනැගිය යුතු බව ශ්‍රී ලංකා පොදුජන පෙරමුණ ද අවධාරණය කළේය. අනාගත පුරවැසියන්ගේ හෘදය සාක්ෂිය තුළින් අනිවාර්යයෙන්ම රාජපක්ෂ නිර්මාණය වනු ඇත."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "පොදුජන පෙරමුණ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලාංකික",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "අටවැනි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "පොදුජන පෙරමුණ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "අඩක්",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "අවුරුදු 30 යි",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "මාස තුනක්",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "රාජ්ය ආරක්ෂක",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකා ප්‍රජාතාන්ත්‍රික සමාජවාදී ජනරජය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "පොදුජන පෙරමුණ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "ஜனாதிபதி கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ஷ ஆற்றிய சேவைக்கு SLPP அஞ்சலி செலுத்துகிறது",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "ஸ்ரீலங்கா பொதுஜன பெரமுன (SLPP), ஜனாதிபதி கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்சவின் இராஜினாமா குறித்து அறிக்கை ஒன்றை வெளியிட்டு, இலங்கையின் எட்டாவது நிறைவேற்று ஜனாதிபதியாக இருந்த குறுகிய காலத்தில் இலங்கைத் தலைவர் ஆற்றிய சேவைக்கு அஞ்சலி செலுத்தியது.",
        "அரசியல் உலகில் அதிகம் காணப்படுவது அரசியல் அதிகாரத்தை கைப்பற்றும் முயற்சிகள் எனவும், அதிகாரத்தையும் பதவிகளையும் துறப்பது மிகவும் அரிதானது எனவும் ஸ்ரீலங்கா பொதுஜன பெரமுன தெரிவித்துள்ளது.",
        "“நாட்டின் வரலாற்றில், எந்தவொரு நிறைவேற்று ஜனாதிபதியும் தனது பதவிக்காலம் முடிவதற்குள் பதவியை விட்டு வெளியேறியதில்லை. இது உண்மையில் கடினமான முடிவுதான்” என்றார்.",
        "ஜனாதிபதி கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ஷ அந்த கடினமான முடிவை எட்டியுள்ளதாகவும், ஜனாதிபதி பதவியில் இருந்து விலகுவது தொடர்பான இராஜினாமா கடிதத்தில் அவர் கையொப்பமிட்டதாகவும் SLPP சுட்டிக்காட்டியுள்ளது.",
        "30 வருடகால பயங்கரமான பயங்கரவாதத்தை முடிவுக்குக் கொண்டு வந்து தாய்நாட்டில் சமாதானத்தை ஏற்படுத்துவதில் தீர்க்கமான பங்களிப்பை ஆற்றிய கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ஷ, கடந்த ஜனாதிபதித் தேர்தலில் வரலாற்று சிறப்புமிக்க ஆணையுடன் வெற்றி பெற்றதாக ஸ்ரீலங்கா பொதுஜன பெரமுன குறிப்பிட்டுள்ளது.",
        "ஜனாதிபதியாகப் பதவியேற்று மூன்று மாதங்கள் கடப்பதற்கு முன்பே, கோவிட் தொற்றிலிருந்து தனது சக நாட்டு மக்களின் உயிரைக் காப்பாற்றும் சிக்கலான சவாலை அவர் எதிர்கொள்ள வேண்டியிருந்தது.",
        "கொவிட் அனர்த்தத்தை சரியாக நிர்வகிப்பதில் இலங்கை ஜனாதிபதி வெற்றி பெற்றுள்ளார் என்பதை சர்வதேச சமூகம் கூட ஏற்றுக்கொண்டுள்ளதாக பொதுஜன பெரமுன குறிப்பிட்டுள்ளது.",
        "நீண்ட கால காரணங்களால் உருவாக்கத்தில் இருந்த இலங்கையின் அந்நிய செலாவணி பிரச்சனை, கோவிட் பேரழிவை எதிர்கொள்ளும் வகையில் கடுமையான நெருக்கடியாக வளர்ந்தது.",
        "கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ச, போர்க்களத்தில் போர் வீரனாகவும், அரச பாதுகாப்புச் செயலாளராகவும், இலங்கை ஜனநாயக சோசலிசக் குடியரசின் தலைவராகவும் கோத்தபய ராஜபக்ச ஆற்றிய சேவைக்கு வணக்கம் செலுத்திய ஸ்ரீலங்கா பொதுஜன பெரமுன, கோட்டாபய போன்ற நேர்மையான மனிதரின் விழுமியங்கள் பற்றிய உரையாடலையும் வலியுறுத்தியது. வருங்கால பிரஜைகளின் மனசாட்சி மூலம் ராஜபக்சே நிச்சயம் உருவாக்கப்படுவார்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ச",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "பொதுஜன பெரமுன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "எட்டாவது",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "பொதுஜன பெரமுன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாதி",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "30 ஆண்டுகள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "மூன்று மாதங்கள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கையின்",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "மாநில பாதுகாப்பு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை ஜனநாயக சோசலிச குடியரசு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "பொதுஜன பெரமுன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}