{
  "newspaper_id": "ada-derana-lk",
  "url": "http://www.adaderana.lk/news/84769/two-more-train-journeys-for-ella-odyssey",
  "time_ut": 1662378120,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Two more train journeys for ‘Ella Odyssey’",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Two more train journeys for ‘Ella Odyssey’",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "In addition to the existing train journeys, it has been planned to add two more train journeys to the “Ella Odyssey”, the new train service launched on the Up-country railway line to operate in the weekends.",
        "The additional train journeys will be added to the schedule from September 08, 2022.",
        "The Deputy General Manager of Railways, T.S. Polwattage said that the decision was made due to the request from local tourists.",
        "Accordingly, the train will operate from Colombo to Badulla every Thursday and from Badulla to Colombo on every Friday.",
        "The seat reservations can be done within 14 days before the journey, said the Deputy General Manager of Railways."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Two",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "two",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "the “Ella Odyssey”",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "September 08, 2022",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Railways",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "T.S. Polwattage",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Badulla",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Thursday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Badulla",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "every Friday",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "14 days",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Railways",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "‘Ella Odyssey’ සඳහා තවත් දුම්රිය ගමන් දෙකක්",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "දැනට පවතින දුම්රිය ගමන්වාරවලට අමතරව සති අන්තයේ ක්‍රියාත්මක වන පරිදි උඩරට දුම්රිය මාර්ගයේ ආරම්භ කරන ලද නව දුම්රිය සේවාව වන “Ella Odyssey” සඳහා තවත් දුම්රිය ගමන් වාර දෙකක් එක් කිරීමට සැලසුම් කර ඇත.",
        "අමතර දුම්රිය ගමන් වාර 2022 සැප්තැම්බර් 08 දින සිට කාලසටහනට එක් කෙරේ.",
        "දුම්රිය දෙපාර්තමේන්තුවේ නියෝජ්‍ය සාමාන්‍යාධිකාරී ටී. පොල්වත්තගේ කියා සිටියේ දේශීය සංචාරකයින්ගේ ඉල්ලීම මත මෙම තීරණය ගත් බවයි.",
        "ඒ අනුව සෑම බ්‍රහස්පතින්දා දිනකම කොළඹ සිට බදුල්ල දක්වාත්, සෑම සිකුරාදා දිනකම බදුල්ල සිට කොළඹ දක්වාත් දුම්රිය ධාවනය කෙරේ.",
        "ආසන වෙන්කරවා ගැනීම ගමනට දින 14කට පෙර සිදු කළ හැකි බව දුම්රිය නියෝජ්‍ය සාමාන්‍යාධිකාරීවරයා පැවසීය."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "දෙක",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "දෙක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "\"Ella Odyssey\"",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "සැප්තැම්බර් 08, 2022",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "දුම්රිය මාර්ග",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ටී.එස්. පොල්වත්තගේ",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "බදුල්ල",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "බ්රහස්පතින්දා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "බදුල්ල",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "සෑම සිකුරාදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "දින 14 යි",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "දුම්රිය මාර්ග",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "‘எல்லா ஒடிஸி’க்கு மேலும் இரண்டு ரயில் பயணங்கள்",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "தற்போதுள்ள ரயில் பயணங்களுக்கு மேலதிகமாக, வார இறுதி நாட்களில் இயங்கும் வகையில் மலையக ரயில் பாதையில் ஆரம்பிக்கப்பட்டுள்ள புதிய ரயில் சேவையான “எல்லா ஒடிஸி”யுடன் மேலும் இரண்டு ரயில் பயணங்களைச் சேர்க்க திட்டமிடப்பட்டுள்ளது.",
        "கூடுதல் ரயில் பயணங்கள் செப்டம்பர் 08, 2022 முதல் அட்டவணையில் சேர்க்கப்படும்.",
        "ரயில்வே துணைப் பொது மேலாளர் டி.எஸ். உள்ளூர் சுற்றுலா பயணிகளின் கோரிக்கைக்கு அமைய இந்த தீர்மானம் எடுக்கப்பட்டுள்ளதாக பொல்வத்தகே தெரிவித்துள்ளார்.",
        "அதன்படி, ஒவ்வொரு வியாழன் தோறும் கொழும்பில் இருந்து பதுளைக்கும், ஒவ்வொரு வெள்ளிக்கிழமையும் பதுளையில் இருந்து கொழும்புக்கும் இந்த ரயில் சேவையில் ஈடுபடும்.",
        "பயணத்திற்கு முன் 14 நாட்களுக்குள் இருக்கை முன்பதிவு செய்து கொள்ளலாம் என ரயில்வே துணை பொது மேலாளர் தெரிவித்துள்ளார்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "இரண்டு",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "இரண்டு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "\"எல்லா ஒடிஸி\"",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "செப்டம்பர் 08, 2022",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ரயில்வே",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "டி.எஸ். போல்வட்டகே",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பதுளை",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "வியாழன்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "பதுளை",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஒவ்வொரு வெள்ளிக்கிழமை",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "14 நாட்கள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரயில்வே",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}