{
  "newspaper_id": "virakesari-lk",
  "url": "http://www.virakesari.lk/article/131223",
  "time_ut": 1657469619,
  "original_lang": "ta",
  "original_title": "பந்துல, ஹரின், மனுஷ, தம்மிக அமைச்சு பதவிகளிலிருந்து விலகினர்",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Bandula, Harin, Manusha and Dhammi resigned from the ministry posts",
      "author": "T Yuwaraj",
      "body_lines": [
        "Bandula Gunawardena, Hareen Fernando, Manusha Nanayakkara and Thammika Perera have resigned from the cabinet positions headed by President Gotabaya Rajapaksa. They resigned following the people's protest that took place the day before yesterday demanding the resignation of the President and the Prime Minister.",
        "Bandula Gunawardena, who served as the Minister of Transport, Highways and Media Department, resigned the day before yesterday. He has also announced that he has decided to leave the Sri Lanka Podujana Peramuna Party and work independently in the Parliament.",
        "Harin Fernando, who served as the Minister of Tourism and Land Affairs in the government led by Prime Minister Ranil Wickremesinghe, and Manusha Nanayakkara, who served as the Minister of Foreign Employment, have resigned from their ministerial positions the day before yesterday.",
        "Hareen Fernando and Manusha Nanayakkara have mentioned that they have decided to resign from the ministerial posts to form an interim government by uniting all the political parties.",
        "Mahinda Amaraweera has mentioned that he is stepping down from the posts of the Ministry of Agriculture and Forestry after the successful distribution of 40,000 metric tons of urea fertilizer to the farmers under the Indian Loan Assistance Scheme.",
        "Investment Promotion Minister Tammika Perera has informed the President's Secretary in writing yesterday that she is resigning from her posts."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Bandula",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "Harin",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "Manusha",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "Dhammi",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Bandula Gunawardena",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Hareen Fernando",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Manusha Nanayakkara",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Perera",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Gotabaya Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the day before yesterday",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Bandula Gunawardena",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Media Department",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the day before yesterday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Harin Fernando",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Manusha Nanayakkara",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the day before yesterday",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Hareen Fernando",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Manusha Nanayakkara",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the Ministry of Agriculture and Forestry",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "40,000 metric tons",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Indian Loan Assistance Scheme",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Investment Promotion",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Tammika Perera",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "yesterday",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "බන්දුල, හරීන්, මනූෂ, ධම්මි ඇමැති ධුරවලින් ඉල්ලා අස්වුණා",
      "author": "ටී යුවරාජ්",
      "body_lines": [
        "බන්දුල ගුණවර්ධන, හරේන් ප්‍රනාන්දු, මනූෂ නානායක්කාර සහ තම්මික පෙරේරා ජනාධිපති ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ මහතාගේ ප්‍රධානත්වයෙන් යුත් කැබිනට් මණ්ඩලයෙන් ඉල්ලා අස්වී තිබේ. ජනාධිපතිවරයාට සහ අගමැතිට ඉල්ලා අස්වන ලෙස බලකරමින් පෙරේදා පැවැති ජනතා විරෝධතාවයෙන් අනතුරුව ඔවුන් ඉල්ලා අස්විය.",
        "ප්‍රවාහන, මහාමාර්ග හා ජනමාධ්‍ය අමාත්‍යවරයා ලෙස කටයුතු කළ බන්දුල ගුණවර්ධන පෙරේදා ඉල්ලා අස්වූ අතර ශ්‍රී ලංකා පොදුජන පෙරමුණෙන් ඉවත් වී පාර්ලිමේන්තුවේ ස්වාධීනව කටයුතු කිරීමට තීරණය කර ඇති බව ද ඔහු ප්‍රකාශ කළා.",
        "අග්‍රාමාත්‍ය රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ ප්‍රමුඛ රජයේ සංචාරක හා ඉඩම් කටයුතු අමාත්‍යවරයා ලෙස කටයුතු කළ හරීන් ප්‍රනාන්දු සහ විදේශ රැකියා අමාත්‍යවරයා ලෙස කටයුතු කළ මනූෂ නානායක්කාර පෙරේදා සිය අමාත්‍ය ධුරවලින් ඉල්ලා අස්වී තිබෙනවා.",
        "හරීන් ප්‍රනාන්දු සහ මනූෂ නානායක්කාර සඳහන් කර ඇත්තේ තමන් අමාත්‍ය ධුරවලින් ඉල්ලා අස්වීමට තීරණය කර ඇත්තේ සියලු දේශපාලන පක්ෂ ඒකරාශී කර අන්තර්කාලීන ආණ්ඩුවක් පිහිටුවීමට බවයි.",
        "ඉන්දීය ණය ආධාර යෝජනා ක්‍රමය යටතේ යූරියා පොහොර මෙට්‍රික් ටොන් 40,000ක් ගොවීන්ට බෙදාදීම සාර්ථක වීමෙන් පසු තමා කෘෂිකර්ම හා වන සංවර්ධන අමාත්‍යාංශයේ ධුරවලින් ඉවත් වන බව මහින්ද අමරවීර සඳහන් කළේය.",
        "ආයෝජන ප්‍රවර්ධන අමාත්‍ය ටම්මික පෙරේරා ඊයේ ජනාධිපති ලේකම්වරයාට ලිඛිතව දැනුම් දී ඇත්තේ තමන් සිය ධුරවලින් ඉල්ලා අස්වන බවයි."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "බන්දුල",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "හරීන්",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "මනූෂා",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "ධම්මි",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "බන්දුල ගුණවර්ධන",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "හරීන් ප්‍රනාන්දු",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "මනූෂ නානායක්කාර",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "පෙරේරා",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "පෙරේදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "බන්දුල ගුණවර්ධන",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "මාධ්‍ය දෙපාර්තමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "පෙරේදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "හරීන් ප්‍රනාන්දු",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "මනූෂ නානායක්කාර",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "පෙරේදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "හරීන් ප්‍රනාන්දු",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "මනූෂ නානායක්කාර",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "කෘෂිකර්ම හා වන විද්‍යා අමාත්‍යාංශය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "මෙට්‍රික් ටොන් 40,000 කි",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දියානු ණය ආධාර යෝජනා ක්රමය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ආයෝජන ප්රවර්ධනය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "තම්මික පෙරේරා",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඊයේ",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "பந்துல, ஹரின், மனுஷ, தம்மிக அமைச்சு பதவிகளிலிருந்து விலகினர்",
      "author": "T Yuwaraj",
      "body_lines": [
        "ஜனாதிபதி கோட்டபய ராஜபக்ஷ தலைமையிலான அமைச்சரவை அமைச்சு பதவிகளில் இருந்து பந்துல குணவர்தன, ஹரீன் பெர்னான்டோ,மனுஷ நாணயக்கார மற்றும் தம்மிக பெரேரா ஆகியோர் விலகியுள்ளார்கள். ஜனாதிபதி,  பிரதமர் ஆகியோரை பதவி விலக கோரி நேற்று முன்தினம் இடம்பெற்ற மக்கள் போராட்டத்தை தொடர்ந்து இவர்கள் பதவி விலகினர்.",
        "போக்குவரத்து, நெடுஞ்சாலைகள் மற்றும் ஊடகத்துறை அமைச்சராக பதவி வகித்த பந்துல குணவர்தன நேற்று முன்தினம் பதவி விலகினார்.அத்துடன் ஸ்ரீ லங்கா பொதுஜன பெரமுன கட்சியில் இருந்து விலகி பாராளுமன்றில் சுயாதீனமாக செயற்பட தீர்மானித்துள்ளதாகவும் அறிவித்துள்ளார்.",
        "பிரதமர் ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க தலைமையிலான அரசாங்கத்தில் சுற்றுலாத்துறை,காணி விவகாரங்கள் அமைச்சராக பதவி வகித்த ஹரின் பெர்னான்டோ மற்றும் வெளிநாட்டு வேலைவாய்ப்புகள் அமைச்சராக பதவி வகித்த மனுஷ நாணயக்கார ஆகியோர் நேற்று முன்தினம் அமைச்சு பதவிகளில் இருந்து விலகியுள்ளர்.",
        "சகல அரசியல் கட்சிகளையும் ஒன்றினைத்து இடைக்கால அரசாங்கத்தை ஸ்தாபிக்க வேண்டும் என்பதற்காகவே தாங்கள் அமைச்சு பதவிகளில் இருந்து விலக தீர்மானித்ததாக ஹரீன் பெர்னான்டோ,மனுஷ நாணயக்கார ஆகியோர் குறிப்பிட்டுள்ளனர்.",
        "இந்திய கடனுதவி திட்டத்தின் கீழ் கிடைக்கப்பெறவுள்ள 40,000 மெற்றிக்தொன் யூரியா உரத்தை விவசாயிகளுக்கு வெற்றிகரமாக பகிர்ந்தளித்ததை தொடர்ந்து தான் விவசாயத்துறை மற்றும் வனஜீனராசிகள் அமைச்சு பதவிகளில் இருந்து விலகுவதாக மஹிந்த அமரவீர குறிப்பிட்டுள்ளார்.",
        "முதலீட்டு ஊக்குவிப்பு அமைச்சர் தம்மிக்க பெரேரா தனது பதவிகளில் இருந்து விலகுவதாக நேற்றைய தினம் ஜனாதிபதியின் செயலாளருக்கு எழுத்து மூலமாக அறிவித்துள்ளார்.நாட்டில் ஏற்பட்டுள்ள குழப்பமான நெருக்கடியினை கருத்திற்கொண்டு தான் இத்தீர்மானத்தை முன்னெடுத்ததாக அவர் குறிப்பிட்டுள்ளார்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "பந்துல",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "ஹரின்",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "மனுஷா",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "தம்மி",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "பந்துல குணவர்தன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஹரீன் பெர்னாண்டோ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "மனுஷ நாணயக்கார",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "பெரேரா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "நேற்று முன்தினம்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பந்துல குணவர்தன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஊடகத்துறை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "நேற்று முன்தினம்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஹரின் பெர்னாண்டோ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "மனுஷ நாணயக்கார",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "நேற்று முன்தினம்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஹரீன் பெர்னாண்டோ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "மனுஷ நாணயக்கார",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "விவசாயம் மற்றும் வனத்துறை அமைச்சகம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "40,000 மெட்ரிக் டன்",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்திய கடன் உதவித் திட்டம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "முதலீட்டு ஊக்குவிப்பு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "தம்மிக்க பெரேரா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "நேற்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}