{
  "newspaper_id": "virakesari-lk",
  "url": "http://www.virakesari.lk/article/131576",
  "time_ut": 1657955690,
  "original_lang": "ta",
  "original_title": "அ.தி.மு.க.வை கைப்பற்றிய எடப்பாடி",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Edappadi captured ADMK",
      "author": "Digital Desk 5",
      "body_lines": [
        "Tamil Nadu's political arena has once again reached a peak of excitement due to the intra-party conflict of the political movement.",
        "The ADMK is a wing of the two-pronged Dravidian parties that have been ruling Tamil Nadu for more than fifty years. This political movement, started by the late revolutionary leader MGR and built by the late revolutionary leader Jayalalithaa, faltered without popular leaders to guide them after their demise.",
        "In the past, Edappadi Palaniswami took over as Chief Minister with majority support from legislators and senior, leading administrators. After becoming Chief Minister, he started to develop his dominance in the party.",
        "Now he has easily spread a net for Panneerselvam, who was supposed to be his lion, and defeated him. Now ADMK It has been announced that the party will run under the sole leadership of Edappadi Palaniswami. It is also said that the ADMK, which has assumed a single leadership, will continue to act as a political movement against the powerful DMK.",
        "Panneerselvam is selfish. Allegations were made that he proposed only selfish politics and failed to save his supporters and the party and caused the downfall of the party.",
        "Also, to the extent that no party dares to do charity, when the general meeting is held, the party's head office is occupied by the party's founder, revolutionary leader MGR. And he was also criticized for breaking into the office used by Jayalalithaa, the revolutionary leader who built and saved the party, and taking away documents from it.",
        "Edappadi is not a personable leader. An unsullied hand has no owner. However, because of Panneerselvam's weak or impossible approach, the majority of party cadres and workers supported Edappadi.",
        "BJP Edappadi's supporters had been continuously campaigning that Panneerselvam's behavior in favor of the leadership would cause a huge split in the ADMK and a situation where the majority of the party members would have to support the BJP without any other option.",
        "ADMK seems to prove it. Panneerselvam, who was in the position of coordinator, did not engage in serious politics against the Tamil Nadu government for the past one year, MGR. And what Jayalalithaa did not dare to do in public... his successor Lok Sabha member Rabindranath had paved the way.",
        "Which ADMK did not meet the Chief Minister of Tamil Nadu M.K.Stalin in person, Rabindranath wore a shawl and gave him a certificate saying 'Government is going well'. Charity is also considered unacceptable.",
        "It was only after this event that Panneerselvam began to lose confidence from his supporters. Moreover, Panneerselvam's actions as an indirect catalyst for the development of BJP in the last one year have resulted in overall loss of confidence in him.",
        "A.D.M.K. Panneerselvam, who caused the Supreme Court to intervene in the matter of the Executive Committee and the General Committee, was strongly opposed by all the party's organizations. Even those who were opposed to Edappadi's approach could not accept what Panneerselvam had done.",
        "Thus his political future has almost reached a stage of completion. At present, Panneerselvam should start a new party or join the BJP. As none of this is an immediate possibility, Panneerselvam's political future has become bleak.",
        "Is it healthy that Edappadi, who saw a boom in politics after the Gouvathur incident, continues to follow the same politics firmly..? That will be decided by the time and the majority of the Executive Committee and General Committee members.",
        "In the matter of Panneerchelvam, he and DMK. Although he has criticized the 'behind the scenes relationship' between the BJP and BJP, it is important to note that the current power struggle is not a personal power struggle between Panneerselvam and Edappadi Palanichamy.",
        "At the same time, the Kodanadu murder and robbery case against Edappadi, who is now the sole leader of the ADMK, can be turned against him anytime. He may be arrested. Who will lead the ADMK during that time? The question arises. In this case, Edappadi has been selected as the interim general secretary of the party.",
        "Also, DMK, ADMK Tamil Nadu has seen progress in many fields during the last fifty years of rule by the Dravidian parties with bipartisan political power. Tamil Nadu's progress in social justice and women's development was achieved only by the Dravidian-minded rulers.",
        "Therefore, DMK will never risk this in the future. and ADMK. The leaders of the two political movements, though different in policy, have to act with one voice for the interests of the people of Tamil Nadu.",
        "Congress, which was the ruling party in 1967, lost to the DMK and has been operating in coalition politics with the DMK. A similar situation may befall ADMK in future. Because the party is working with a principled alliance rather than an electoral alliance with the BJP, talking politics of Hinduism and nationalism and trying to dissolve the party like the Congress party.",
        "This is why leaders such as Amit Shah and Modi, when they travel to Tamil Nadu, put forward the issue of 'competition between DMK and BJP'. ADMK's Interim General Secretary and future General Secretary Edappadi called it an autonomous political movement of ADMK. The expectation to run is strong.",
        "Now BJP is in the internal party issue of ADMK. The election of the President is the reason why the Panchayat is not done. If any action is taken in favor of Panneerselvam, Edappadi's support of legislators, members of Lok Sabha and Rajya Sabha, BJP Silence follows as candidate Draupadi Murmu is not supported and may be boycotted.",
        "After the completion of the election of the President of the Republic of India, the ADMK BJP on the issue. The Panneerchelvam side is now hopeful that some criticism will be presented or some action taken."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Tamil Nadu's",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "two",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Dravidian",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Tamil Nadu",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "more than fifty years",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "MGR",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Jayalalithaa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Edappadi Palaniswami",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Panneerselvam",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Edappadi Palaniswami",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ADMK",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "DMK",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "MGR",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Jayalalithaa",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Panneerselvam",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Edappadi",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "BJP Edappadi's",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Panneerselvam",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ADMK",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "BJP",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Tamil Nadu",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the past one year",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "MGR",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Lok Sabha",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Rabindranath",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Tamil Nadu M.K.Stalin",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Panneerselvam",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Panneerselvam",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "BJP",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the last one year",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "A.D.M.K. Panneerselvam",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Supreme Court",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Executive Committee",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the General Committee",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Edappadi",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Panneerselvam",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Panneerselvam",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "BJP",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Panneerselvam",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Edappadi",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Gouvathur",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Executive Committee",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "General Committee",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Panneerchelvam",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "DMK",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "BJP",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "BJP",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Panneerselvam",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Edappadi Palanichamy",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Kodanadu",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Edappadi",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ADMK",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ADMK",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Edappadi",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "DMK",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Tamil Nadu",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the last fifty years",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Dravidian",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Tamil Nadu's",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Dravidian",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "DMK",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ADMK",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "two",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "one",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Tamil Nadu",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Congress",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "1967",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "DMK",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "DMK",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "BJP",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Congress",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Amit Shah",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Tamil Nadu",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "DMK",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "BJP",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ADMK's Interim General",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Edappadi",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ADMK",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "BJP",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ADMK",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Panchayat",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Panneerselvam",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Edappadi",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Lok Sabha",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Rajya Sabha",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "BJP Silence",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Draupadi Murmu",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the Republic of India",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ADMK BJP",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Panneerchelvam",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "එඩප්පාඩි ADMK අල්ලා ගත්තේය",
      "author": "ඩිජිටල් මේසය 5",
      "body_lines": [
        "දේශපාලන ව්‍යාපාරයේ අභ්‍යන්තර පක්ෂ ගැටුම හේතුවෙන් තමිල්නාඩු දේශපාලන කරළිය යළිත් වරක් උද්වේගකර උච්චතම ස්ථානයකට පැමිණ තිබේ.",
        "ADMK යනු වසර පනහකට වැඩි කාලයක් තමිල්නාඩුව පාලනය කරන ද්‍රවිඩ ද්‍රවිඩ පක්ෂ දෙකේ අංශයකි. දිවංගත විප්ලවවාදී නායක එම්ජීආර් විසින් ආරම්භ කර දිවංගත විප්ලවවාදී නායිකා ජයලලිතා ගොඩනැගූ මෙම දේශපාලන ව්‍යාපාරය ඔවුන්ගේ අභාවයෙන් පසු ඔවුන්ට මග පෙන්වීමට ජනප්‍රිය නායකයින් නොමැතිව අඩපණ විය.",
        "පසුගිය කාලයේ එඩප්පාඩි පලනිස්වාමි මහ ඇමති ධූරය භාර ගත්තේ ව්‍යවස්ථාදායකයන්ගේ සහ ජ්‍යෙෂ්ඨ, ප්‍රමුඛ පරිපාලකයන්ගේ බහුතර සහයෝගය ඇතිවය. මහඇමති වූ පසු ඔහු පක්ෂය තුළ තම ආධිපත්‍යය වර්ධනය කර ගැනීමට පටන් ගත්තේය.",
        "දැන් ඔහු තම සිංහයා වීමට නියමිතව සිටි පන්නීර්සෙල්වම්ට ඉතා පහසුවෙන් දැලක් එළවා ඔහුව පරාජය කර ඇත. දැන් ඒ.ඩී.එම්.කේ පක්ෂය එඩප්පාඩි පලනිස්වාමිගේ තනි නායකත්වය යටතේ ක්‍රියාත්මක වන බව නිවේදනය කර ඇත. තනි නායකත්වයක් භාරගත් ADMK පක්ෂය ප්‍රබල DMK පක්ෂයට එරෙහි දේශපාලන ව්‍යාපාරයක් ලෙස තවදුරටත් කටයුතු කරනු ඇතැයිද පැවසේ.",
        "පන්නීර්සෙල්වම් ආත්මාර්ථකාමී ය. ආත්මාර්ථකාමී දේශපාලනය පමණක් යෝජනා කළ ඔහු තම ආධාරකරුවන් සහ පක්ෂය බේරා ගැනීමට අපොහොසත් වී පක්ෂයේ කඩා වැටීමට හේතු වූ බවට චෝදනා එල්ල වුණා.",
        "ඒ වගේම කිසිම පක්ෂයක් පුණ්‍ය කටයුතු කිරීමට ධෛර්යවත් නොවන තරමට මහා සභා රැස්වීම පැවැත්වෙන විට පක්ෂයේ ප්‍රධාන කාර්යාලයේ සිටින්නේ පක්ෂයේ නිර්මාතෘ විප්ලවවාදී නායක එම්.ජී.ආර්. එමෙන්ම පක්ෂය ගොඩනැගූ සහ බේරාගත් විප්ලවවාදී නායිකාව වූ ජයලලිතා භාවිතා කළ කාර්යාලයට කඩා වැදී එහි ලියකියවිලි රැගෙන යාම සම්බන්ධයෙන්ද ඔහුට විවේචන එල්ල විය.",
        "එඩප්පාඩි පෞරුෂයක් ඇති නායකයෙක් නොවේ. නොකැළැල් අතකට අයිතිකාරයෙක් නැත. කෙසේ වෙතත්, පන්නීර්සෙල්වම්ගේ දුර්වල හෝ කළ නොහැකි ප්‍රවේශය නිසා, බහුතර පක්ෂ කේඩරයින් සහ කම්කරුවන් එඩප්පාඩිට සහාය දුන්හ.",
        "බී.ජේ.පී පන්නීර්සෙල්වම් නායකත්වයට පක්‍ෂව හැසිරීම නිසා ඒඩීඑම්කේ තුළ විශාල භේදයක් ඇති වන බවත්, පාක්ෂිකයන් බහුතරයකට වෙනත් විකල්පයක් නොමැතිව භාරතීය ජනතා පක්ෂයට සහය දැක්වීමට සිදුවන තත්ත්වයක් උදාවනු ඇති බවත් එඩප්පාඩිගේ ආධාරකරුවෝ දිගින් දිගටම ප්‍රචාරක කටයුතු කරමින් සිටියහ.",
        "ADMK එය ඔප්පු කරන බව පෙනේ. සම්බන්ධීකාරක තනතුරේ සිටි පන්නීර්සෙල්වම් පසුගිය වසරක කාලය තුළ තමිල්නාඩු රජයට එරෙහිව බරපතළ දේශපාලනයක් නොකළ එම්.ජී.ආර්. එමෙන්ම ජයලලිතා ප්‍රසිද්ධියේ කිරීමට එඩිතර නොවූ දේ... ඔහුගේ අනුප්‍රාප්තිකයා වූ ලෝක් සභා මන්ත්‍රී රබීන්ද්‍රනාත් ඊට පාර කැපුවා.",
        "තමිල්නාඩු මහ ඇමති එම්.කේ.ස්ටාලින්ව පෞද්ගලිකව මුණ නොගැසුනු ADMK කොයි ADMK ද, රබීන්ද්‍රනාත් සාලුවක් දාගෙන 'ආණ්ඩුව හොඳින් යනවා' කියලා සහතිකයක් දුන්නා. දානය ද පිළිගත නොහැකි යැයි සැලකේ.",
        "පන්නීර්සෙල්වම්ට ඔහුගේ ආධාරකරුවන්ගෙන් විශ්වාසය නැති වීමට පටන් ගත්තේ මෙම සිදුවීමෙන් පසුවය. එපමණක් නොව, පසුගිය වසරක කාලය තුළ භාරතීය ජනතා පක්ෂයේ වර්ධනය සඳහා වක්‍ර උත්ප්‍රේරකයක් ලෙස පන්නීර්සෙල්වම්ගේ ක්‍රියා හේතුවෙන් ඔහු කෙරෙහි සමස්ත විශ්වාසය නැති වී ඇත.",
        "ඒ.ඩී.එම්.කේ. විධායක කාරක සභාව සහ මහා කාරක සභාව සම්බන්ධයෙන් ශ්‍රේෂ්ඨාධිකරණය මැදිහත් වීමට හේතු වූ පන්නීර්සෙල්වම් මහතාට පක්ෂයේ සියලුම සංවිධානවල දැඩි විරෝධය එල්ල විය. එඩප්පාඩිගේ ප්‍රවේශයට විරුද්ධ වූවන්ට පවා පන්නීර්සෙල්වම් කළ දේ පිළිගත නොහැකි විය.",
        "මේ අනුව ඔහුගේ දේශපාලන අනාගතය බොහෝ දුරට අවසන් අදියරකට පැමිණ තිබේ. මේ වන විට පන්නීර්සෙල්වම් නව පක්ෂයක් ආරම්භ කිරීම හෝ භාරතීය ජනතා පක්ෂයට එක්විය යුතුය. මේ කිසිවක් ක්ෂණිකව සිදුවිය හැකි දෙයක් නොවන බැවින් පන්නීර්සෙල්වම්ගේ දේශපාලන අනාගතය අඳුරු වී ඇත.",
        "ගූවතූර් සිද්ධියෙන් පසු දේශපාලනයේ පිම්බීමක් දුටු එඩප්පාඩි තවදුරටත් එම දේශපාලනයම දැඩිව අනුගමනය කිරීම සෞඛ්‍ය සම්පන්නද..? එය විධායක කමිටු සහ මහා කමිටු සාමාජිකයින්ගේ කාලය සහ බහුතරය විසින් තීරණය කරනු ඇත.",
        "පන්නීර්චෙල්වම්ගේ කාරණයේදී ඔහු සහ ඩී.එම්.කේ. භාරතීය ජනතා පක්ෂය සහ භාරතීය ජනතා පක්ෂය අතර 'තිරය පිටුපස සබඳතාව' ඔහු විවේචනය කළද, වත්මන් බල අරගලය පන්නීර්සෙල්වම් සහ එඩප්පාඩි පලනිචාමි අතර පෞද්ගලික බල අරගලයක් නොවන බව සැලකිල්ලට ගැනීම වැදගත්ය.",
        "ඒ සමගම, දැන් ADMK හි එකම නායකයා වන එඩප්පාඩිට එරෙහි කොඩනාඩු මිනීමැරුම් හා මංකොල්ලකෑමේ නඩුව ඕනෑම වේලාවක ඔහුට එරෙහිව හැරවිය හැකිය. ඔහු අත්අඩංගුවට ගැනීමට ඉඩ ඇත. එම කාලය තුළ ADMK නායකත්වය දරන්නේ කවුද? යන ප්‍රශ්නය මතු වේ. මෙහිදී එඩප්පාඩි පක්‍ෂයේ අන්තර්වාර මහලේකම්වරයා ලෙස තෝරාගෙන ඇත.",
        "එසේම ඩී.එම්.කේ., ඒ.ඩී.එම්.කේ ද්විපාර්ශ්වික දේශපාලන බලය සහිත ද්‍රවිඩ පක්ෂ විසින් පසුගිය වසර පනහක පාලන කාලය තුළ තමිල්නාඩුව බොහෝ ක්ෂේත්‍රවල ප්‍රගතියක් අත්කරගෙන ඇත. තමිල්නාඩුවේ සමාජ සාධාරණත්වයේ සහ කාන්තා සංවර්ධනයේ ප්‍රගතිය අත්පත් කරගනු ලැබුවේ ද්‍රවිඩ මනසක් ඇති පාලකයන් විසිනි.",
        "ඒ නිසා මින් ඉදිරියට ඩී.එම්.කේ. සහ ඒ.ඩී.එම්.කේ. දේශපාලන ව්‍යාපාර දෙකේ නායකයන්ට ප්‍රතිපත්තිමය වශයෙන් වෙනස් වුවද තමිල්නාඩු ජනතාවගේ අවශ්‍යතා වෙනුවෙන් එක හඬින් ක්‍රියා කිරීමට සිදුවේ.",
        "1967 දී පාලක පක්ෂය වූ කොංග්‍රසය DMK පක්ෂයට පරාජය වූ අතර DMK පක්ෂය සමඟ සභාග දේශපාලනයේ ක්‍රියා කරයි. ඉදිරියේදී ADMK ට ද එවැනිම තත්වයක් ඇති විය හැක. මොකද පක්‍ෂය භාරතීය ජනතා පක්‍ෂය සමඟ මැතිවරණ සන්ධානයකට වඩා ප්‍රතිපත්තිගරුක සන්ධානයකින් කටයුතු කරමින් හින්දු ආගමේ සහ ජාතිකවාදයේ දේශපාලනය කතා කරමින් කොංග්‍රස් පක්‍ෂය මෙන් පක්‍ෂය දියකර හැරීමට උත්සාහ කරන බැවිනි.",
        "අමිත් ෂා, මෝදි වැනි නායකයන් තමිල්නාඩුවට යන විට ‘ඩීඑම්කේ සහ භාරතීය ජනතා පක්ෂය අතර තරගය’ යන ප්‍රශ්නය ඉදිරිපත් කරන්නේ මේ නිසාය. ADMK අතුරු මහලේකම් සහ අනාගත මහලේකම් Edappadi එය ADMK හි ස්වාධීන දේශපාලන ව්‍යාපාරයක් ලෙස හැඳින්වීය. දුවන්න බලාපොරොත්තුව ශක්තිමත්.",
        "දැන් BJP සිටින්නේ ADMK හි අභ්‍යන්තර පක්ෂ ප්‍රශ්නයේ ය. පංචායතනය නොකෙරෙන්නේ ජනාදිපති වරණයයි. පන්නීර්සෙල්වම්ට පක්ෂව කිසියම් ක්‍රියාමාර්ගයක් ගනු ලැබුවහොත්, එඩප්පාඩිගේ සහය ව්‍යවස්ථාදායකයන්ගේ, ලෝක් සභා සහ රාජ්‍ය සභා මන්ත්‍රීවරුන්, බී.ජේ.පී. අපේක්ෂක ද්‍රෞපදී මුර්මුට සහය නොදක්වන බැවින් සහ වර්ජනය කළ හැකි බැවින් නිශ්ශබ්දතාව අනුගමනය කරයි.",
        "ඉන්දීය ජනරජයේ ජනාධිපතිවරයා තෝරා පත් කර ගැනීම අවසන් වූ පසු ඒ.ඩී.එම්.කේ ප්‍රශ්නය සම්බන්ධයෙන් බී.ජේ.පී. පන්නීර්චෙල්වම් පාර්ශ්වය දැන් බලාපොරොත්තුවෙන් සිටින්නේ යම් විවේචනයක් හෝ යම් ක්‍රියාමාර්ගයක් ගනු ඇතැයි කියාය."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "තමිල්නාඩුවේ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "දෙක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ද්‍රවිඩය",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "තමිල්නාඩුව",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "අවුරුදු පනහකට වැඩි කාලයක්",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "එම්.ජී.ආර්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජයලලිතා",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "එඩප්පාඩි පලනිස්වාමි",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "පන්නීර්සෙල්වම්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "එඩප්පාඩි පලනිස්වාමි",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඒ.ඩී.එම්.කේ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඩී.එම්.කේ",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "එම්.ජී.ආර්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජයලලිතා",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "පන්නීර්සෙල්වම්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "එඩප්පාඩි",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "BJP එඩප්පාඩිගේ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "පන්නීර්සෙල්වම්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඒ.ඩී.එම්.කේ",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "බී.ජේ.පී",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "තමිල්නාඩුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "පසුගිය වසරක",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "එම්.ජී.ආර්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ලෝක් සභාව",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "රවීන්ද්‍රනාත්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "තමිල්නාඩු එම්.කේ.ස්ටාලින්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "පන්නීර්සෙල්වම්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "පන්නීර්සෙල්වම්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "බී.ජේ.පී",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "පසුගිය වසර",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ඒ.ඩී.එම්.කේ. පන්නීර්සෙල්වම්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රේෂ්ඨාධිකරණය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "විධායක කමිටුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "මහා කාරක සභාව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "එඩප්පාඩි",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "පන්නීර්සෙල්වම්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "පන්නීර්සෙල්වම්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "බී.ජේ.පී",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "පන්නීර්සෙල්වම්",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "එඩප්පාඩි",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගෞවතූර්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "විධායක කමිටුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "මහා කමිටුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "පන්නීර්චෙල්වම්",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඩී.එම්.කේ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "බී.ජේ.පී",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "බී.ජේ.පී",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "පන්නීර්සෙල්වම්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "එඩප්පාඩි පලනිචාමි",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "කොඩනාඩු",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "එඩප්පාඩි",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඒ.ඩී.එම්.කේ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඒ.ඩී.එම්.කේ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "එඩප්පාඩි",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ඩී.එම්.කේ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "තමිල්නාඩුව",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "පසුගිය වසර පනහ",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ද්‍රවිඩය",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "තමිල්නාඩුවේ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ද්‍රවිඩය",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ඩී.එම්.කේ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඒ.ඩී.එම්.කේ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "දෙක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "එක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "තමිල්නාඩුව",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "කොංග්රසය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "1967",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඩී.එම්.කේ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඩී.එම්.කේ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "බී.ජේ.පී",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "කොංග්රසය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "අමිත් ෂා",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "තමිල්නාඩුව",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඩී.එම්.කේ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "බී.ජේ.පී",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ADMK හි අන්තර්වාර ජනරාල්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "එඩප්පාඩි",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඒ.ඩී.එම්.කේ",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "බී.ජේ.පී",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඒ.ඩී.එම්.කේ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "පංචායතනය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "පන්නීර්සෙල්වම්",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "එඩප්පාඩි",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ලෝක් සභාව",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "රාජ්ය සභාව",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "BJP නිශ්ශබ්දතාව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ද්‍රෞපදී මුර්මු",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දීය ජනරජය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ADMK BJP",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "පන්නීර්චෙල්වම්",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "அ.தி.மு.க.வை கைப்பற்றிய எடப்பாடி",
      "author": "Digital Desk 5",
      "body_lines": [
        "தமிழக அரசியல் களம் மீண்டும் ஒரு முறை அரசியல் இயக்கத்தின் உட்கட்சி பூசல் காரணமாக உச்சகட்ட பரபரப்பை எட்டி சற்று ஓய்வடைந்திருக்கின்றது.",
        "கடந்த ஐம்பது ஆண்டுகளுக்கும் மேலாக தமிழகத்தை ஆளும் இருமுனை திராவிட கட்சிகளின் ஒரு முனையாக திகழ்வது அ.தி.மு.க. மறைந்த புரட்சித் தலைவர் எம்.ஜி.ஆரால் ஆரம்பிக்கப்பட்டு, மறைந்த புரட்சித்தலைவி ஜெயலலிதாவால் கட்டி காக்கப்பட்ட இந்த அரசியல் இயக்கம், அவர்களின் மறைவிற்குப் பிறகு வழிநடத்த மக்கள் செல்வாக்குப் பெற்ற தலைவர்கள் இல்லாமல் தள்ளாடியது.",
        "கடந்த காலத்தில் சட்டமன்ற உறுப்பினர்கள் மற்றும் மூத்த, முன்னணி நிர்வாகிகளின் பெரும்பான்மையான ஆதரவுடன் எடப்பாடி பழனிச்சாமி முதல்வராக பொறுப்பேற்றுக் கொண்டார். முதல்வரானதும் கட்சியில் தன் ஆதிக்கத்தை வளர்த்தெடுக்க தொடங்கினார்.",
        "தற்போது தனக்கு சிம்மசொப்பனமாகவிருந்த பன்னீர்செல்வத்துக்கு எளிதாக வலை விரித்து, எதிர்த்து வீழ்த்தியிருக்கிறார். இனி அ.தி.மு.க. எடப்பாடி பழனிச்சாமி என்பவரின் ஒற்றை தலைமையில் இயங்கும் கட்சி என்று அறிவிக்கப்பட்டிருக்கிறது. தற்போது ஒற்றை தலைமையை ஏற்றுள்ள அ.தி.மு.க., தொடர்ந்து வலிமையான தி.மு.க.விற்கு எதிரான அரசியல் இயக்கமாக செயற்படவுள்ளதாகவும் கூறப்பட்டுள்ளது.",
        "பன்னீர்செல்வம் சுயநலவாதி. சுயநல அரசியலை மட்டுமே முன்மொழிந்து, அவருடைய ஆதரவாளர்களையும் காப்பாற்றாமல், கட்சியையும் காப்பாற்றாமல், கட்சியின் வீழ்ச்சிக்கும் காரணமாக இருந்தார் என்று குற்றச்சாட்டுக்கள் சுமத்தப்பட்டன.",
        "அத்துடன் எந்த கட்சி தொண்டனும் செய்ய துணியாத அளவிற்கு, பொதுக்குழு நடைபெறும் போது, கட்சியின் தலைமை அலுவலகத்தை, கட்சியின் நிறுவனரான புரட்சித்தலைவர் எம்.ஜி.ஆர். மற்றும் கட்சியை கட்டிக் காப்பாற்றிய புரட்சித்தலைவி ஜெயலலிதா ஆகியோர் பயன்படுத்திய அலுவலகத்தை உடைத்து, அதிலிருந்து ஆவணங்களை அள்ளிச் சென்றமையானது ஏற்றுக்கொள்ள முடியாதது என்ற விமர்சனத்திற்கும் உள்ளானார்.",
        "எடப்பாடி ஆளுமை மிக்க தலைவர் அல்ல. கறை படியாத கரத்திற்கு சொந்தக்காரர் இல்லை. எனினும், பன்னீர்செல்வத்தின் பலவீனமான அல்லது சாத்தியமற்ற அணுகுமுறையின் காரணமாகவே, கட்சியின் பெரும்பான்மையான நிர்வாகிகளும், தொண்டர்களும் எடப்பாடிக்கு ஆதரவு அளித்துள்ளனர்.",
        "பா.ஜ.க. தலைமைக்கு சாதகமாக பன்னீர்செல்வம் நடந்து கொள்வதாலும், அ.தி.மு.க.வில் பாரிய பிளவை ஏற்படுத்தி, அக்கட்சியின் பெரும்பான்மை உறுப்பினர்கள் வேறு வழியில்லாமல் பா.ஜ.க.விற்கு ஆதரவு தெரிவிக்க வேண்டிய சூழல் உருவாகும் என்று எடப்பாடியின் ஆதரவாளர்கள் தொடர்ச்சியாக பிரசாரம் செய்து வந்தனர்.",
        "அதனை மெய்ப்பிப்பது போல் அ.தி.மு.க. ஒருங்கிணைப்பாளர் என்ற பதவியில் இருந்த பன்னீர்செல்வம், கடந்த ஓராண்டாக தமிழக அரசுக்கு எதிராக தீவிரமான அரசியலை மேற்கொள்ளாமல், எம்.ஜி.ஆர். மற்றும் ஜெயலலிதா ஆகியோர் பொதுவெளியில் செய்ய துணியாத காரியத்தை.. அவரின் வாரிசான மக்களவை உறுப்பினர் ரவீந்திரநாத் மேற்கொள்வதற்கு வழிசமைத்திருந்தார்.",
        "தமிழக முதல்வரான மு.க.ஸ்டாலினை நேரில் சந்தித்த, ரவீந்திரநாத்  சால்வை அணிவித்து, ‘அரசு நன்றாக நடைபெறுகிறது’ என்று நற்சான்றிதழை வழங்கியதை எந்த அ.தி.மு.க. தொண்டனும் ஏற்றுக்கொள்ள முடியாதவொரு விடயமாகவே கொள்ளப்படுகின்றது.",
        "இந்த நிகழ்வின் பின்னர் தான், பன்னீர்செல்வம் தனது ஆதரவாளர்களிடத்திலிருந்து நம்பிக்கையை இழக்கத் தொடங்கினார். மேலும் கடந்த ஓராண்டில் பா.ஜ.க.வின் வளர்ச்சிக்கு மறைமுக தூண்டுக்கோலாகவும் பன்னீர்செல்வம் செயற்பட்டமையும் அவர் மீது ஒட்டுமொத்தமாக நம்பிக்கை வீழ்வதற்கு வித்திட்டது.",
        "அ.தி.மு.க. செயற்குழு மற்றும் பொதுக்குழு விவகாரத்தில் உச்சநீதிமன்றம் தலையிடுவதற்கு காரணமான பன்னீர்செல்வத்தை அக்கட்சியின் அனைத்து அமைப்பினரும் உறுதியாக எதிர்த்தனர். எடப்பாடியின் அணுகுமுறைகளுக்கு எதிராக இருப்பவர்கள் கூட, பன்னீர்செல்வம் செய்த காரியத்தை ஏற்றுக் கொள்ளத்தயாராக இல்லை.",
        "இதனால் அவரின் அரசியல் எதிர்காலம் என்பது ஏறக்குறைய நிறைவடையும் நிலையை எட்டியுள்ளது. தற்போதைய நிலையில் பன்னீர்செல்வம் புதியகட்சியைத் தொடங்க வேண்டும் அல்லது பா.ஜ.க.வில் இணைய வேண்டும். இவை எதுவும் உடனடி சாத்தியமில்லை என்பதால், பன்னீர்செல்வத்தின் அரசியல் எதிர்காலம் இருள் சூழ்ந்து விட்ட நிலையை அடைந்துள்ளது.",
        "கூவத்தூர் சம்பவத்திற்கு பிறகு அரசியலில் ஏற்றம் கண்ட எடப்பாடி, தொடர்ந்து அதேபாணியிலான அரசியலை உறுதியாக பின்பற்றி வருவது ஆரோக்கியமானதா..? என்பதை காலமும், செயற்குழு மற்றும் பொதுக்குழு உறுப்பினர்களின் பெரும்பான்மையும் தான் தீர்மானிக்கும்.",
        "பன்னீர்ச்செல்வத்தின் விவகாரத்தில் அவருக்கும், தி.மு.க. மற்றும் பா.ஜ.க.விற்கும் இடையேயான ‘திரைமறைவு உறவு’ குறித்து அவர் விமர்சனம் செய்திருந்தாலும், தற்போது நடைபெற்ற அதிகாரப் போட்டி என்பது பன்னீர்செல்வம் மற்றும் எடப்பாடி பழனிச்சாமி ஆகிய இருவருக்கும் இடையேயான தனிப்பட்ட அதிகார போட்டி அல்ல என்றே கொள்ள வேண்டியுள்ளது.",
        "இதேதருணத்தில் தற்போது அ.தி.மு.க.வின் ஒற்றை தலைமையாக உயர்ந்திருக்கும் எடப்பாடி மீதான கொடநாடு கொலை, கொள்ளை வழக்கு விவகாரம் எப்போது வேண்டுமானாலும் அவருக்கு எதிராக திரும்பக் கூடும். அவர் கைது செய்யப்படக்கூடும். அதன் போது அ.தி.மு.க.வை வழிநடத்துபவர்கள் யார்? என்ற கேள்வி எழும். இந்நிலையில் தான் எடப்பாடி கட்சியின் இடைக்கால பொதுச்செயலாளராக தெரிவு செய்யப்பட்டிருக்கிறார்.",
        "மேலும், தி.மு.க., அ.தி.மு.க. என்ற இருமுனை அரசியல் ஆட்சியதிகாரம் கொண்ட திராவிட கட்சிகளின் கடந்த ஐம்பது ஆண்டுகால ஆட்சியில், தமிழகம் பல துறைகளில் முன்னேற்றம் கண்டிருக்கிறது. குறிப்பாக சமூக நீதி, பெண்கள் மேம்பாடு ஆகிய இரண்டு விடயத்தில் தமிழகத்தின் முன்னேற்றம், திராவிட சிந்தனை கொண்ட ஆட்சியாளர்களால் தான் நிறைவேறியது.",
        "எனவே இதற்கு எதிர்காலத்தில் ஒருபோதும் ஆபத்து ஏற்படாத வண்ணம், தி.மு.க. மற்றும் அ.தி.மு.க. ஆகிய இரண்டு அரசியல் இயக்கங்களை சேர்ந்த தலைவர்கள், கொள்கை ரீதியாக வேறுபட்டு இருந்தாலும், தமிழக மக்களின் நலன்களுக்காக ஒருமித்த குரலில் செயற்பட வேண்டியுள்ளது.",
        "1967ஆம் ஆண்டில் ஆளுங்கட்சியாக இருந்த காங்கிரஸ், தி.மு.க.விடம் தோல்வி அடைந்து, தி.மு.க.வின் கூட்டணி அரசியலில் இயங்கி வருகிறது. இதேபோன்றதொரு நிலை எதிர்காலத்தில் அ.தி.மு.க.விற்கும் ஏற்படக்கூடும். ஏனெனில் அக்கட்சி பா.ஜ.க.வுடன் தேர்தல் கூட்டணியாக இல்லாமல் கொள்கை ரீதியான கூட்டணியுடன் செயல்பட்டு, இந்துத்துவம் மற்றும் தேசியம் குறித்த அரசியலைப் பேசி, அக்கட்சி காங்கிரஸ் கட்சியை போல் கரைக்க முயற்சிக்கிறது.",
        "இதனால் தான் அமித்ஷா, மோடி உள்ளிட்ட தலைவர்கள் தமிழகத்தில் பயணம் மேற்கொள்ளும் பொழுது, ‘தி.மு.க.விற்கும், பா.ஜ.க.விற்கும் இடையே தான் போட்டி’ என்றதொரு விடயத்தை முன் வைக்கிறார்கள். இதனை அ.தி.மு.க.வின் இடைக்கால பொதுச்செயலாளர் மற்றும் எதிர்கால பொதுச் செயலாளரான எடப்பாடி தன்னாட்சி அதிகாரம் பெற்ற அரசியல் இயக்கமாக அ.தி.மு.க. இயங்கவேண்டும் என்ற எதிர்பார்ப்பு வலுத்துள்ளது.",
        "தற்போது அ.தி.மு.க.வின் உட்கட்சி விவகாரத்தில் பா.ஜ.க. உட்புகுந்து பஞ்சாயத்து செய்யாததற்கு, குடியரசு தலைவர் தேர்தல் தான் காரணமாகிறது. பன்னீர்செல்வத்திற்கு ஆதரவாக ஏதேனும் நடவடிக்கை எடுத்தால், எடப்பாடியின் ஆதரவு சட்டமன்ற உறுப்பினர்களும், மக்களவை மற்றும் மாநிலங்களவை உறுப்பினர்களும், பா.ஜ.க. வேட்பாளரான திரௌபதி முர்மூவிற்கு ஆதரவளிக்காமல், புறக்கணிக்க கூடிய நிலை ஏற்படக்கூடும் என்பதால் அமைதி பின்பற்றப்படுகின்றது.",
        "இந்திய குடியரசு தலைவர் தேர்தல் நிறைவடைந்த பிறகு, அ.தி.மு.க. விவகாரம் குறித்து பா.ஜ.க. ஏதேனும் விமர்சனத்தை முன்வைக்க கூடும் என்றும் அல்லது சில நடவடிக்கைகளை மேற்கொள்ள கூடும் என்றும் பன்னீர்ச்செல்வம் தரப்பு இப்போதைக்கு நம்பிக்கை வைத்துள்ளது."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "தமிழ்நாட்டின்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இரண்டு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "திராவிடம்",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "தமிழ்நாடு",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஐம்பது ஆண்டுகளுக்கும் மேலாக",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "எம்.ஜி.ஆர்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜெயலலிதா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "எடப்பாடி பழனிசாமி",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பன்னீர்செல்வம்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "எடப்பாடி பழனிசாமி",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "அ.தி.மு.க",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "தி.மு.க",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "எம்.ஜி.ஆர்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜெயலலிதா",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பன்னீர்செல்வம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "எடப்பாடி",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பாஜக எடப்பாடியின்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "பன்னீர்செல்வம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "அ.தி.மு.க",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "பா.ஜ.க",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "தமிழ்நாடு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "கடந்த ஒரு வருடம்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "எம்.ஜி.ஆர்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "மக்களவை",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரவீந்திரநாத்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "தமிழக மு.க.ஸ்டாலின்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பன்னீர்செல்வம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "பன்னீர்செல்வம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "பா.ஜ.க",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "கடந்த ஒரு வருடம்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "அ.தி.மு.க. பன்னீர்செல்வம்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "உச்ச நீதிமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "செயற்குழு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "பொதுக்குழு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "எடப்பாடி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "பன்னீர்செல்வம்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பன்னீர்செல்வம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "பா.ஜ.க",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "பன்னீர்செல்வம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "எடப்பாடி",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "கூவத்தூர்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "செயற்குழு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "பொதுக்குழு",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பன்னீர்செல்வம்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "தி.மு.க",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "பா.ஜ.க",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "பா.ஜ.க",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "பன்னீர்செல்வம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "எடப்பாடி பழனிச்சாமி",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "கொடநாடு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "எடப்பாடி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "அ.தி.மு.க",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "அ.தி.மு.க",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "எடப்பாடி",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "தி.மு.க",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "தமிழ்நாடு",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "கடந்த ஐம்பது வருடங்கள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "திராவிடம்",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "தமிழ்நாட்டின்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "திராவிடம்",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "தி.மு.க",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "அ.தி.மு.க",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இரண்டு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஒன்று",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "தமிழ்நாடு",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "காங்கிரஸ்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "1967",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "தி.மு.க",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "தி.மு.க",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "பா.ஜ.க",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "காங்கிரஸ்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
