{
  "newspaper_id": "lankadeepa-lk",
  "url": "https://www.lankadeepa.lk/news/පොලිස්පති-ජනපති-හමුවක්/101-618640",
  "time_ut": 1661262489,
  "original_lang": "si",
  "original_title": "පොලිස්පති-ජනපති හමුවක්",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "A meeting between the Inspector General of Police and the President",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "President Ranil Wickramasinghe and Inspector General of Police C.D. A meeting between Mr. Wickramaratne took place at the President's office today (23) afternoon.",
        "This meeting was traditionally held after Mr. Ranil Wickramasinghe assumed office as President and Commander-in-Chief, and commemorative gifts were also exchanged."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "the Inspector General of Police",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickramasinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Inspector General of Police",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Wickramaratne",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "23) afternoon",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickramasinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "පොලිස්පති-ජනපති හමුවක්",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "ජනාධිපති රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතා සහ පොලිස්පති සී.ඩී. වික්‍රමරත්න මහතා අතර හමුවක් ජනාධිපති කාර්යාලයේ දී අද (23) පස්වරුවේ සිදු විය.",
        "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතා ජනාධිපති සහ සේනාධිනායක ධූරයේ වැඩ බාර ගැනීමෙන් අනතුරුව සාම්ප්‍රදායිකව මෙම හමුව සිදු වූ අතර සමරු තිළිණ හුවමාරු කර ගැනීම ද සිදු කෙරිණ."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "පොලිස්පති",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "පොලිස්පති",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "වික්‍රමරත්න",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "23) සවස",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "பொலிஸ் மா அதிபர் மற்றும் ஜனாதிபதிக்கு இடையில் சந்திப்பு",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "ஜனாதிபதி ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க மற்றும் பொலிஸ் மா அதிபர் சி.டி. விக்கிரமரத்னவுக்கும் இடையிலான சந்திப்பு இன்று (23) பிற்பகல் ஜனாதிபதி அலுவலகத்தில் இடம்பெற்றது.",
        "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க ஜனாதிபதியாகவும் தளபதியாகவும் பதவியேற்றதன் பின்னர் இந்த சந்திப்பு பாரம்பரியமாக இடம்பெற்றதுடன் நினைவு பரிசுகளும் பரிமாறிக்கொள்ளப்பட்டன."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "இன்ஸ்பெக்டர் ஜெனரல் ஆஃப் போலீஸ்",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்ஸ்பெக்டர் ஜெனரல் ஆஃப் போலீஸ்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "விக்கிரமரத்ன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "23) பிற்பகல்",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}