{
  "newspaper_id": "ada-lk",
  "url": "https://www.ada.lk/technology/Number-Portability-සේවාව-සදහා-නීතිමය-අනුමැතිය/5-386003",
  "time_ut": 1634190483,
  "original_lang": "si",
  "original_title": "Number Portability සේවාව සදහා නීතිමය අනුමැතිය",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Legal approval for Number Portability service",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "Oshadha Senanayake, Director General of the Telecommunications Regulatory Commission, has said that all telephone subscribers have received legal approval for the Number Portability service.",
        "He mentioned this at the press conference held at the Presidential Media Center.",
        "That all telephone subscribers have received legal approval for the Number Portability service,",
        "The Director General of the Telecommunications Regulatory Commission Mr. Oshadha Senanayake made the announcement at the press conference which is now being held at the Presidential Media Centre. #lka"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Number Portability",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "the Telecommunications Regulatory Commission",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the Presidential Media Center",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "the Telecommunications Regulatory Commission",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Oshadha Senanayake",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Presidential Media Centre",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "Number Portability සේවාව සදහා නීතිමය අනුමැතිය",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "සියළුම දුරකථන ග්‍රාහකයින්ට තම දුරකථන අංකය වෙනත් ජාලයක් වෙත රැගෙන යාමේ (Number Portability) සේවාව සදහා නීතිමය අනුමැතිය හිමි වූ බව, විදුලි සංදේශ නියාමන කොමිෂන් සභාවේ අධ්‍යක්ෂ ජනරාල් ඕෂධ සේනානායක පවසා සිටියි.",
        "ජනාධිපති මාධ්‍ය කේන්ද්‍රයේදී පැවැත්වෙන මාධ්‍ය හමුවේදී ඔහු මේ බව සඳහන් කර සිටියේ​ය.",
        "සියළුම දුරකථන ග්‍රාහකයින්ට තම දුරකථන අංකය වෙනත් ජාලයක් වෙත රැගෙන යාමේ (Number Portability) සේවාව සදහා නීතිමය අනුමැතිය හිමි වූ බව,",
        "දැන් ජනාධිපති මාධ්‍ය කේන්ද්‍රයේදී පැවැත්වෙන මාධ්‍ය හමුවේදී, විදුලි සංදේශ නියාමන කොමිෂන් සභාවේ අධ්‍යක්ෂ ජනරාල් ඕෂධ සේනානායක මහතා ප්‍රකාශ කලා.#lka"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "අංක අතේ ගෙන යා හැකි හැකියාව",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "විදුලි සංදේශ නියාමන කොමිෂන් සභාව",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ජනාධිපති මාධ්‍ය මධ්‍යස්ථානය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "විදුලි සංදේශ නියාමන කොමිෂන් සභාව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඕෂධ සේනානායක",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජනාධිපති මාධ්‍ය මධ්‍යස්ථානය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "நம்பர் போர்டபிலிட்டி சேவைக்கான சட்டப்பூர்வ ஒப்புதல்",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "அனைத்து தொலைபேசி சந்தாதாரர்களும் நம்பர் போர்டபிலிட்டி சேவைக்கான சட்ட அங்கீகாரத்தைப் பெற்றுள்ளதாக தொலைத்தொடர்பு ஒழுங்குமுறை ஆணைக்குழுவின் பணிப்பாளர் நாயகம் ஓஷத சேனாநாயக்க தெரிவித்துள்ளார்.",
        "ஜனாதிபதி ஊடக மையத்தில் நடைபெற்ற ஊடகவியலாளர் சந்திப்பில் அவர் இதனைக் குறிப்பிட்டுள்ளார்.",
        "அனைத்து தொலைபேசி சந்தாதாரர்களும் எண் போர்ட்டபிலிட்டி சேவைக்கு சட்டப்பூர்வ அங்கீகாரம் பெற்றுள்ளனர்,",
        "ஜனாதிபதி ஊடக மையத்தில் தற்போது இடம்பெற்றுவரும் ஊடகவியலாளர் சந்திப்பில் தொலைத்தொடர்பு ஒழுங்குமுறை ஆணைக்குழுவின் பணிப்பாளர் நாயகம் திரு.ஓஷத சேனாநாயக்க இதனைத் தெரிவித்தார்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "எண் பெயர்வுத்திறன்",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "தொலைத்தொடர்பு ஒழுங்குமுறை ஆணையம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஜனாதிபதி ஊடக மையம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "தொலைத்தொடர்பு ஒழுங்குமுறை ஆணையம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஓஷத சேனாநாயக்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜனாதிபதி ஊடக மையம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}