{
  "newspaper_id": "lankadeepa-lk",
  "url": "https://www.lankadeepa.lk/news/බසයක්-පෙරලී-18ක්-රෝහලට/101-618999",
  "time_ut": 1661843892,
  "original_lang": "si",
  "original_title": "බසයක් පෙරලී 18ක් රෝහලට",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "A bus overturned and 18 were taken to the hospital",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "18 passengers have been injured when a private bus running from Nuwara Eliya Udupusellawa to Batticaloa overturned at Mahawwa bend in Walapane, said Chief Inspector of Police N.D. Hettiarachchi, Station Commander of Walapane Police.",
        "The Chief Inspector of Police said that the bus carrying a group of people who had come from Batticaloa to attend a wedding ceremony in Udupussalla was returning to Batticaloa on (30) when the bus overturned on the main road in the area with a high wall.",
        "Five women who were injured in the accident have been admitted to the Rikilagaskada District General Hospital and the other injured have been admitted to the Walapane Regional Hospital.",
        "Walapane police, who are investigating the accident, said that the road the bus was traveling on was a road with a high embankment and a sudden technical fault in the bus's braking system caused the accident."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "18",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "18",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Nuwara Eliya Udupusellawa",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Mahawwa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Walapane",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Police N.D. Hettiarachchi",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Udupussalla",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Batticaloa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "30",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Five",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Rikilagaskada District General Hospital",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Walapane Regional Hospital",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        []
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "බසයක් පෙරලී 18ක් රෝහලට",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "නුවරඑලිය උඩුපුස්සැල්ලාව සිට මඩකලපුව දක්වා ධාවනය වු පෞද්ගලික බස් රථයක් වලපනේ මහව්ව වංගුවේදී  පෙරලිමෙන් මගීන් 18 දෙනකු තුවාල ලබා ඇතැයි වලපනේ පොලිසියේ ස්ථානාධිපති ප්‍රධාන පොලිස් පරික්ෂක එන්.ඩි.හෙට්ටිආරච්චි මහතා පවසයි.",
        "මඩකලපුවේ සිට උඩුපුස්සැල්ලාවේ විවාහ මංගල උත්සවයකට පැමිණි පිරිසක් රැගත් එම බසය උත්සවය අවසන් වි (30) දින ආපසු මඩකලපුව දක්වා ගමන් කරමින් සිටියදි අධික බැවුමක් සහිත ප්‍රදේශයේදි බස් රථය ප්‍රධාන මාර්ගය හරහා පෙරලි ගොස් ඇති බවයි මුලස්ථාන ප්‍රධාන පොලිස් පරික්ෂකවරයා කියා සිටියේ.",
        "අනතුරෙන් තුවාල ලැබු කාන්තාවන් පස්දෙනකු රිකිල්ලගස්කඩ දිස්ත්‍රික් මහ රෝහලට සහ අනෙකුත් තුවාලකරුවන් වලපනේ ප්‍රාදේශිය රෝහලේ ඇතුලත් කර ඇති බවත්, අනතුරෙන් තුවාල ලැබු අයගේ තත්ත්වය බරපතල නොවන බවයි වලපනේ පොලිසිය කියා සිටියේ.",
        "බස් රථය ගමන් ගත් මාර්ගය අධික බැවුමක් සහිත මාර්ගයක් බවත්, බස් රථයේ තිරිංග පද්ධතියේ හදිසියේ ඇති වු කාර්මික දෝෂයක් අනතුරට හේතුව වි ඇති බවයි අනතුර පිලිබදව පරික්ෂණ පවත්වන වලපනේ පොලිසිය කියා සිටියේ."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "18",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "18",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "නුවරඑළිය උඩුපුස්සැල්ලාව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "මහව්ව",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "වලපනේ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "පොලිස් එන්.ඩී.හෙට්ටිආරච්චි",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "උඩුපුස්සල්ල",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "මඩකලපුව",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "30",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "පහ",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "රිකිලිගස්කඩ දිස්ත්‍රික් මහ රෝහල",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "වලපනේ ප්‍රාදේශීය රෝහල",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        []
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "பேருந்து கவிழ்ந்து விபத்துக்குள்ளானதில் 18 பேர் மருத்துவமனைக்கு கொண்டு செல்லப்பட்டனர்",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "நுவரெலியா உடுப்புசெல்லாவயிலிருந்து மட்டக்களப்பு நோக்கிச் சென்ற தனியார் பேருந்து ஒன்று வலப்பனை மஹவ்வ வளைவில் கவிழ்ந்து விபத்துக்குள்ளானதில் 18 பயணிகள் காயமடைந்துள்ளதாக வளப்பனை பொலிஸ் நிலையப் பொறுப்பதிகாரி பிரதான பொலிஸ் பரிசோதகர் என்.டி.ஹெட்டியாராச்சி தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "மட்டக்களப்பில் இருந்து உடுபுஸ்ஸல்லாவில் இடம்பெற்ற திருமண நிகழ்வொன்றில் கலந்துகொள்வதற்காக வந்த குழுவினரை ஏற்றிச் சென்ற பேரூந்து விழா முடிந்து (30) மீண்டும் மட்டக்களப்பு நோக்கி வந்து கொண்டிருந்ததாக பிரதான பொலிஸ் பரிசோதகர் தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "விபத்தில் காயமடைந்த 5 பெண்கள் ரிக்கிலகஸ்கட மாவட்ட பொது வைத்தியசாலையிலும், காயமடைந்த ஏனையவர்கள் வலப்பனை பிரதேச வைத்தியசாலையிலும் அனுமதிக்கப்பட்டுள்ளனர்.",
        "விபத்து தொடர்பில் விசாரணைகளை மேற்கொண்டு வரும் வளப்பனை பொலிஸார், பேருந்து பயணித்த பாதை உயரமான மேடுகளை கொண்ட வீதி எனவும், பேருந்தின் பிரேக்கிங் சிஸ்டத்தில் ஏற்பட்ட திடீர் தொழிநுட்பக் கோளாறே விபத்துக்குக் காரணம் எனவும் தெரிவித்தனர்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "18",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "18",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "நுவரெலியா உடுபுசெல்லாவ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "மஹவ்வா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "வலப்பனே",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "பொலிஸ் என்.டி.ஹெட்டியாராச்சி",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "உடுபுஸ்ஸல்லா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "மட்டக்களப்பு",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "30",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஐந்து",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரிக்கிலகஸ்கட மாவட்ட பொது வைத்தியசாலை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "வலப்பனை பிராந்திய வைத்தியசாலை",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        []
      ]
    }
  }
}