{
  "newspaper_id": "daily-mirror-lk",
  "url": "https://www.dailymirror.lk/breaking_news/Droupadi-Murmu-elected-15th-President-of-India/108-241596",
  "time_ut": 1658467438,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Droupadi Murmu elected 15th President of India",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Droupadi Murmu elected 15th President of India",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "NDA’s presidential nominee Droupadi Murmu on Thursday became the first tribal woman to be elected as President of India by defeating her rival, opposition candidate Yashwant Sinha, by a margin of 947 votes, bagging 64.03% of the electoral college votes against Sinha’s share of 35.97%.",
        "Murmu, 64, is only the second former member of BJP after President Ram Nath Kovind to be elected President. She bagged votes from a total of 2,824 electors, including 540 MPs, while Sinha won the support of 1,877 electors, including 208 MPs.",
        "Though the results of the presidential contest were a foregone conclusion, and the opposition managers had no illusions about the eventual verdict, the anti-BJP bloc can derive some satisfaction from the fact that their tally was better than what they had achieved five years ago when the NDA nominee beat opposition’s candidate Meira Kumar.",
        "In fact, Murmu’s first preference vote share - 64.03% - is the lowest since President V V Giri’s 48.01% in the 1969 presidential polls.",
        "However, there are doubts that the opposition managed to achieve the objective they sought to realise by pitching this as a battle of ideologies. The support of parties like BSP and JD(S) for Murmu, the last-minute dramatic defection of her fellow Santhal, Jharkhand CM Hemant Soren, and confusing messages from senior figures like TMC boss Mamata Banerjee muddied the message. (Timed of India)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Droupadi Murmu",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "15th",
          "label": "ORDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "India",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "NDA",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Droupadi Murmu",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Thursday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "first",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "India",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Yashwant Sinha",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "947",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "64.03%",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "the electoral college",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "35.97%",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Murmu",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "64",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "second",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "BJP",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ram Nath Kovind",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "2,824",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "540",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sinha",
            "label": "PRODUCT"
          },
          {
            "text": "1,877",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "208",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "anti-BJP",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "five years ago",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "NDA",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Meira Kumar",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Murmu",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "first",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "64.03%",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "V V Giri’s",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "48.01%",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "1969",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "BSP",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "JD(S",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Murmu",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Hemant Soren",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "TMC",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Timed of India",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "Droupadi Murmu ඉන්දියාවේ 15 වැනි ජනාධිපතිවරයා ලෙස තේරී පත් විය",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "NDA හි ජනාධිපති අපේක්ෂක Droupadi Murmu බ්‍රහස්පතින්දා ඉන්දියාවේ ජනාධිපති ලෙස තේරී පත් වූ පළමු ගෝත්‍රික කාන්තාව බවට පත් වූයේ ඇගේ ප්‍රතිවාදියා වූ විපක්ෂයේ අපේක්ෂක යෂ්වන්ත් සිංහා ඡන්ද 947 කින් පරදවා සිංහාගේ කොටසට එරෙහිව 64.03% මැතිවරණ විද්‍යාල ඡන්ද ලබා ගනිමින් .",
        "64 හැවිරිදි මුර්මු, ජනාධිපති රාම් නාත් කෝවින්ද්ගෙන් පසුව ජනාධිපති ලෙස තේරී පත් වූ භාරතීය ජනතා පක්ෂයේ දෙවන හිටපු සාමාජිකයා වේ. ඇය මන්ත්‍රීවරුන් 540 ක් ඇතුළුව මුළු ඡන්දදායකයන් 2,824 කින් ඡන්ද ලබා ගත් අතර සිංහා මන්ත්‍රීවරුන් 208 ක් ඇතුළුව ඡන්දදායකයින් 1,877 ක සහාය ලබා ගත්තේය.",
        "ජනාධිපතිවරණ තරඟයේ ප්‍රතිඵල කල්ගත වූවක් වුවද, අවසාන තීන්දුව ගැන විපක්ෂයේ කළමනාකරුවන්ට මිත්‍යාවක් නොතිබුණද, වසර පහකට පෙර ඔවුන් ලබා ගත් ප්‍රමාණයට වඩා ඔවුන්ගේ සංඛ්‍යාව ඉහළ මට්ටමක පැවතීම ගැන BJP විරෝධී කණ්ඩායමට යම් තෘප්තියක් ලැබිය හැකිය. එන්ඩීඒ අපේක්ෂකයා විපක්ෂයේ අපේක්ෂක මීරා කුමාර් පරාජය කළේය.",
        "ඇත්ත වශයෙන්ම, මුර්මුගේ පළමු මනාප ඡන්ද ප්‍රතිශතය - 64.03% - 1969 ජනාධිපතිවරණ ඡන්ද විමසීමේදී ජනාධිපති වී වී ගිරිගේ 48.01% න් පසු අඩුම අගයයි.",
        "කෙසේ වෙතත්, මෙය මතවාදයන්ගේ සටනක් ලෙස ඉදිරිපත් කරමින් තමන් සාක්ෂාත් කර ගැනීමට අපේක්ෂා කළ අරමුණ ඉටුකර ගැනීමට විපක්ෂය සමත් වූ බවට සැකයක් පවතී. BSP සහ JD(S) වැනි පක්‍ෂ මුර්මුට සහය දීම, අවසාන මොහොතේ ඇගේ සහෝදර සන්තාල්, ජාර්කන්ඩ් මහ ඇමති හේමන්ත් සෝරන්ගේ නාටකාකාර ලෙස ඉවත්වීම සහ TMC ලොක්කා මමතා බැනර්ජි වැනි ජ්‍යෙෂ්ඨ පුද්ගලයින්ගේ ව්‍යාකූල පණිවිඩ පණිවිඩය මඩ කළේය. (ඉන්දියාවේ වේලාව)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ද්‍රෞපදී මුර්මු",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "15 වැනි",
          "label": "ORDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "ඉන්දියාව",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "එන්.ඩී.ඒ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ද්‍රෞපදී මුර්මු",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "බ්රහස්පතින්දා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "පළමුවන",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "යෂ්වන්ත් සිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "947",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "64.03%",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "මැතිවරණ විද්යාලය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "35.97%",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "මුර්මු",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "64",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "දෙවැනි",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "බී.ජේ.පී",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "රාම් නාත් කෝවින්ද්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "2,824 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "540",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "සිංහ",
            "label": "PRODUCT"
          },
          {
            "text": "1,877 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "208",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "BJP විරෝධී",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "අවුරුදු පහකට පෙර",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "එන්.ඩී.ඒ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "මීරා කුමාර",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "මුර්මු",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "පළමුවන",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "64.03%",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "වී වී ගිරිගේ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "48.01%",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "1969",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "බීඑස්පී",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "JD(S",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "මුර්මු",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "හේමන්ත් සෝරන්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ටී.එම්.සී",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දියාවේ කාලානුරූපව",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "இந்தியாவின் 15வது ஜனாதிபதியாக திரௌபதி முர்மு தேர்ந்தெடுக்கப்பட்டார்",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "தேசிய ஜனநாயகக் கூட்டணியின் ஜனாதிபதி வேட்பாளர் திரௌபதி முர்மு வியாழன் அன்று தனது போட்டியாளரான எதிர்க்கட்சி வேட்பாளரான யஷ்வந்த் சின்ஹாவை 947 வாக்குகள் வித்தியாசத்தில் தோற்கடித்து, சின்ஹாவின் பங்கான 35.97% க்கு எதிராக 64.03% தேர்தல் கல்லூரி வாக்குகளைப் பெற்று, இந்தியாவின் ஜனாதிபதியாகத் தேர்ந்தெடுக்கப்பட்ட முதல் பழங்குடிப் பெண்மணி ஆனார். .",
        "64 வயதான முர்மு, குடியரசுத் தலைவர் ராம்நாத் கோவிந்திற்குப் பிறகு குடியரசுத் தலைவராக தேர்ந்தெடுக்கப்பட்ட இரண்டாவது முன்னாள் பாஜக உறுப்பினர் ஆவார். அவர் 540 எம்.பி.க்கள் உட்பட மொத்தம் 2,824 வாக்காளர்களிடமிருந்து வாக்குகளைப் பெற்றார், அதே நேரத்தில் சின்ஹா ​​208 எம்.பி.க்கள் உட்பட 1,877 வாக்காளர்களின் ஆதரவைப் பெற்றார்.",
        "குடியரசுத் தலைவர் போட்டியின் முடிவுகள் முன்கூட்டியே முடிவடைந்தாலும், இறுதித் தீர்ப்பைப் பற்றி எதிர்க்கட்சி மேலாளர்களுக்கு மாயை இல்லை என்றாலும், பாஜக-எதிர்ப்பு கூட்டணி ஐந்து ஆண்டுகளுக்கு முன்பு அவர்கள் அடைந்ததை விட அவர்களின் எண்ணிக்கை சிறப்பாக இருந்ததில் இருந்து ஓரளவு திருப்தி அடைய முடியும். NDA வேட்பாளர் எதிர்க்கட்சிகளின் வேட்பாளர் மீரா குமாரை தோற்கடித்தார்.",
        "உண்மையில், முர்முவின் முதல் விருப்பு வாக்குப் பங்கு - 64.03% - 1969 ஜனாதிபதித் தேர்தலில் ஜனாதிபதி வி.வி.கிரி பெற்ற 48.01%க்குப் பிறகு மிகக் குறைவானது.",
        "எவ்வாறாயினும், இதை ஒரு சித்தாந்தப் போராக முன்வைத்து எதிர்க்கட்சிகள் தாங்கள் அடைய விரும்பிய நோக்கத்தை அடைய முடிந்தது என்பதில் சந்தேகம் உள்ளது. முர்முவுக்கு பிஎஸ்பி மற்றும் ஜேடி(எஸ்) போன்ற கட்சிகளின் ஆதரவு, அவரது சக சந்தால், ஜார்க்கண்ட் முதல்வர் ஹேமந்த் சோரன் கடைசி நிமிடத்தில் அதிரடியாக விலகியது, டிஎம்சி தலைவர் மம்தா பானர்ஜி போன்ற மூத்த பிரமுகர்களின் குழப்பமான செய்திகள் செய்தியை குழப்பிவிட்டன. (இந்தியாவின் நேரம்)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "திரௌபதி முர்மு",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "15வது",
          "label": "ORDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "இந்தியா",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "தே.மு.தி.க",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "திரௌபதி முர்மு",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "வியாழன்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "முதலில்",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்தியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "யஷ்வந்த் சின்ஹா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "947",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "64.03%",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "தேர்தல் கல்லூரி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "35.97%",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "முர்மு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "64",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இரண்டாவது",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "பா.ஜ.க",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ராம் நாத் கோவிந்த்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "2,824",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "540",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "சின்ஹா",
            "label": "PRODUCT"
          },
          {
            "text": "1,877",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "208",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பாஜக எதிர்ப்பு",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஐந்து வருடங்களுக்கு முன்பு",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "தே.மு.தி.க",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "மீரா குமார்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "முர்மு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "முதலில்",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "64.03%",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "வி வி கிரியின்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "48.01%",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "1969",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பி.எஸ்.பி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜேடி(எஸ்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "முர்மு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஹேமந்த் சோரன்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "டி.எம்.சி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்தியாவின் நேரம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}