{
  "newspaper_id": "news-first-lk",
  "url": "https://www.newsfirst.lk/2022/07/21/attacks-on-presidents-private-residence-police-seek-video-photos-for-probe/",
  "time_ut": 1658406660,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Attacks on President’s private residence: Police seek video & photos for probe",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Attacks on President’s private residence: Police seek video & photos for probe",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); Sri Lanka Police is requesting the public to provide any video or image in their possession in connection to the attacks on President Ranil Wickremesinghe’s private residence located in Colombo, and his official car.",
        "In a statement Sri Lanka Police requested that the material be sent via whatsapp to 0718 594 950.",
        "The Criminal Investigations Department is conducting an investigation in to the attacks on President Ranil Wickremesinghe’s private residence located in Colombo, and his official car, that took place on the 9th of July 2022.",
        "Attacks on President’s private residence: Police seek video & photos for probe"
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "News 1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka Police",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Colombo",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka Police",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "The Criminal Investigations Department",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Colombo",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "July 2022",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        []
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "ජනපතිගේ පෞද්ගලික නිවසට ප්‍රහාර: පොලිසිය පරීක්‍ෂණයට වීඩියෝ සහ ඡායාරූප සොයයි",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); ජනාධිපති රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතාගේ කොළඹ පිහිටි පෞද්ගලික නිවසට සහ ඔහුගේ නිල රථයට එල්ල වූ ප්‍රහාරයට අදාළව තමන් සන්තකයේ ඇති වීඩියෝ පටයක් හෝ පින්තූරයක් ලබාදෙන ලෙස ශ්‍රී ලංකා පොලිසිය මහජනතාවගෙන් ඉල්ලා සිටී.",
        "නිවේදනයක් නිකුත් කරමින් ශ්‍රී ලංකා පොලිසිය ඉල්ලා සිටින්නේ එම තොරතුරු whatsapp හරහා 0718 594 950 ට එවන ලෙසයි.",
        "2022 ජුලි මස 09 වන දින ජනාධිපති රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතාගේ කොළඹ පිහිටි පෞද්ගලික නිවසට සහ ඔහුගේ නිල රථයට එල්ල වූ ප්‍රහාරයන් සම්බන්ධයෙන් අපරාධ පරීක්ෂණ දෙපාර්තමේන්තුව පරීක්ෂණයක් පවත්වයි.",
        "ජනපතිගේ පෞද්ගලික නිවසට ප්‍රහාර: පොලිසිය පරීක්‍ෂණයට වීඩියෝ සහ ඡායාරූප සොයයි"
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "News 1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකා පොලිසිය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "කොළඹ",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකා පොලිසිය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "අපරාධ පරීක්ෂණ දෙපාර්තමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "කොළඹ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "2022 ජූලි",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        []
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "ஜனாதிபதியின் தனிப்பட்ட இல்லத்தின் மீதான தாக்குதல்: விசாரணைக்காக காணொளி மற்றும் புகைப்படங்களை பொலிஸார் நாடியுள்ளனர்",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); கொழும்பில் அமைந்துள்ள ஜனாதிபதி ரணில் விக்ரமசிங்கவின் தனிப்பட்ட இல்லம் மற்றும் அவரது உத்தியோகபூர்வ கார் மீதான தாக்குதல்கள் தொடர்பில் தம்மிடம் உள்ள காணொளி அல்லது புகைப்படங்களை வழங்குமாறு பொதுமக்களிடம் சிறிலங்கா பொலிஸார் கோரிக்கை விடுத்துள்ளனர்.",
        "0718 594 950 என்ற எண்ணுக்கு whatsapp ஊடாக தகவல்களை அனுப்புமாறு இலங்கை பொலிஸார் ஒரு அறிக்கையில் கோரியுள்ளனர்.",
        "கொழும்பில் அமைந்துள்ள ஜனாதிபதி ரணில் விக்ரமசிங்கவின் தனிப்பட்ட இல்லம் மற்றும் அவரது உத்தியோகபூர்வ கார் மீது 2022 ஆம் ஆண்டு ஜூலை மாதம் 9 ஆம் திகதி இடம்பெற்ற தாக்குதல்கள் தொடர்பில் குற்றப் புலனாய்வுத் திணைக்களம் விசாரணைகளை முன்னெடுத்து வருகின்றது.",
        "ஜனாதிபதியின் தனிப்பட்ட இல்லத்தின் மீதான தாக்குதல்: விசாரணைக்காக காணொளி மற்றும் புகைப்படங்களை பொலிஸார் நாடியுள்ளனர்"
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "News 1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை காவல்துறை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "கொழும்பு",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை காவல்துறை",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "குற்றப் புலனாய்வுத் திணைக்களம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "கொழும்பு",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜூலை 2022",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        []
      ]
    }
  }
}