{
  "newspaper_id": "news-first-lk",
  "url": "https://www.newsfirst.lk/2022/08/26/rainfall-likely-tonight-26/",
  "time_ut": 1661515140,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Rainfall likely tonight (26)",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Rainfall likely tonight (26)",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); Department of Meteorology informs that showers will occur at times in Sabaragamuwa province and in Kandy and Nuwara-Eliya districts.",
        "Several spells of showers will occur in Western and North-western provinces and Galle and Matara districts.",
        "Showers or thundershowers will occur at several places in Uva, Eastern, and North-Central provinces and Mullaitivu district during the evening or night.",
        "The general public is kindly requested to take adequate precautions to minimize damages caused by temporary localized strong winds and lightning during thundershowers.",
        "“I’d love to speak like I used to, but I cannot,” – Ranjan talks to the press after released from prison",
        "SJB wants full Presidential Pardon for Ranjan Ramanayake with Political Rights"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "tonight",
          "label": "TIME"
        },
        {
          "text": "26",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "News 1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Department of Meteorology",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sabaragamuwa province",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kandy",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Nuwara-Eliya",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Western",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "North",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "Galle",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Matara",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Uva",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Eastern",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "North-Central",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Mullaitivu",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "evening",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "night",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "Ranjan",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "SJB",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Presidential Pardon for Ranjan Ramanayake",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "අද (26) රාත්‍රියේ වැසි ඇති විය හැක.",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); සබරගමුව පළාතේ සහ මහනුවර සහ නුවරඑළිය දිස්ත්‍රික්කවල විටින් විට වැසි ඇති වන බව කාලගුණ විද්‍යා දෙපාර්තමේන්තුව දන්වා සිටියි.",
        "බස්නාහිර සහ වයඹ පළාත්වලත් ගාල්ල සහ මාතර දිස්ත්‍රික්කවලත් වැසි වාර කිහිපයක් ඇතිවේ.",
        "ඌව, නැගෙනහිර සහ උතුරු-මැද පළාත්වලත් මුලතිව් දිස්ත්‍රික්කයේත් සවස් කාලයේ හෝ රාත්‍රී කාලයේ තැනින් තැන වැසි හෝ ගිගුරුම් සහිත වැසි ඇති වේ.",
        "ගිගුරුම් සහිත වැසි ඇති වන විට එම ප්‍රදේශවල තාවකාලික තද සුළං සහ අකුණු මඟින් සිදුවන අනතුරු අවම කර ගැනීමට ප්‍රමාණවත් පියවර ගන්නා ලෙස සාමාන්‍ය ජනතාවගෙන් කාරුණිකව ඉල්ලා සිටියි.",
        "\"මම ඉස්සර වගේ කතා කරන්න කැමතියි, නමුත් මට බැහැ\" - රංජන් බන්ධනාගාරයෙන් නිදහස් වූ පසු මාධ්‍ය වෙත කතා කරයි",
        "SJB දේශපාලන අයිතිවාසිකම් ඇති රන්ජන් රාමනායකට පූර්ණ ජනාධිපති සමාව අවශ්‍යයි"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "අද රෑ",
          "label": "TIME"
        },
        {
          "text": "26",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "News 1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "කාලගුණ විද්‍යා දෙපාර්තමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "සබරගමුව පළාත",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මහනුවර",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "නුවරඑළිය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "බටහිර",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "උතුරු",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගාල්ල",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මාතර",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ඌව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "නැගෙනහිර",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "උතුරු මැද",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "මුලතිව්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "සවස",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "රෑ",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "රන්ජන්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "එස්.ජේ.බී",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "රන්ජන් රාමනායකට ජනාධිපති සමාව",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "இன்று இரவு (26) மழை பெய்யக்கூடும்",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); சப்ரகமுவ மாகாணத்திலும் கண்டி மற்றும் நுவரெலியா மாவட்டங்களிலும் அவ்வப்போது மழை பெய்யும் என வளிமண்டலவியல் திணைக்களம் தெரிவித்துள்ளது.",
        "மேல் மற்றும் வடமேல் மாகாணங்களிலும் காலி மற்றும் மாத்தறை மாவட்டங்களிலும் பல தடவைகள் மழை பெய்யும்.",
        "ஊவா, கிழக்கு மற்றும் வடமத்திய மாகாணங்களிலும் முல்லைத்தீவு மாவட்டத்திலும் பல இடங்களில் மாலை அல்லது இரவு வேளைகளில் மழை அல்லது இடியுடன் கூடிய மழை பெய்யும்.",
        "இடியுடன் கூடிய மழையின் போது தற்காலிகமாக பலத்த காற்று மற்றும் மின்னல் தாக்கங்களினால் ஏற்படக்கூடிய பாதிப்புகளை குறைத்துக்கொள்ள போதிய முன்னெச்சரிக்கை நடவடிக்கைகளை எடுக்குமாறு பொதுமக்கள் அன்புடன் கேட்டுக்கொள்ளப்படுகிறார்கள்.",
        "\"நான் முன்பு போல் பேச விரும்புகிறேன், ஆனால் என்னால் முடியாது,\" - சிறையில் இருந்து வெளிவந்த பிறகு ரஞ்சன் செய்தியாளர்களிடம் பேசுகிறார்",
        "அரசியல் உரிமைகளுடன் கூடிய ரஞ்சன் ராமநாயக்கவிற்கு ஜனாதிபதியின் முழுமையான மன்னிப்பை SJB விரும்புகிறது"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "இன்றிரவு",
          "label": "TIME"
        },
        {
          "text": "26",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "News 1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "வளிமண்டலவியல் திணைக்களம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "சப்ரகமுவ மாகாணம்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "கண்டி",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "நுவரெலியா",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "மேற்கு",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "வடக்கு",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "காலி",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "மாத்தறை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஊவா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "கிழக்கு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "வட-மத்திய",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "முல்லைத்தீவு",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "சாயங்காலம்",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "இரவு",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "ரஞ்சன்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "எஸ்.ஜே.பி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரஞ்சன் ராமநாயக்கவுக்கு ஜனாதிபதி மன்னிப்பு",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}