{
  "newspaper_id": "news-first-lk",
  "url": "https://www.newsfirst.lk/2022/09/02/suspect-arrested-after-failed-assassination-attempt-on-argentine-vice-president/",
  "time_ut": 1662111600,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Suspect arrested after failed assassination attempt on Argentine vice president",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Suspect arrested after failed assassination attempt on Argentine vice president",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "(CNN)A man has been arrested after attempting to shoot Cristina Fernández de Kirchner, Argentina's vice-president and former President, at point blank range outside her home in Buenos Aires on Thursday.",
        "Video of the incident shows the vice president smiling as she walks by a crowd of people. A man in the crowd then surges forward, pointing a gun at Fernández de Kirchner's face and apparently attempting a shot. No bullets are fired and the two-time former President flinches backward, unharmed.",
        "The attacker was taken into custody after a few seconds of confusion and panic.",
        "Argentina's official news agency, Télam, identified the man as a Brazilian national, later updating his name to Fernando Andre Sabag Montiel.",
        "The Argentine Ministry of Security confirmed the weapon used in the incident was a .380 firearm with bullets inside.",
        "\"Cristina is still alive because — for some reason we can't technically confirm at this moment — the weapon, which was armed with five bullets, did not shoot although the trigger was pulled,\" said Argentine President Alberto Fernández in a televised address Thursday evening.",
        "He called the assassination attempt an attack on democracy, saying, \"We must eradicate hate and violence from our media and political discourse.\" He declared Friday a national holiday for the country to rally together in support of Fernández de Kirchner.",
        "Former Argentine President Mauricio Macri also renounced the attack on Thursday, calling for an \"immediate and profound clarification by the justice system and the security forces.\"",
        "Fernández de Kirchner is among Argentina's most prominent political figures, having served as President from 2007 to 2015, before taking office as vice president in 2019.",
        "Her supporters have been holding rallies outside her home for several days, in response to an ongoing trial in which she is accused of corruption during her term as President.",
        "Earlier in August, a federal prosecutor called for Fernández de Kirchner to serve a 12-year prison sentence. The court is yet to rule on the request.",
        "Days later, her supporters clashed with police in the Argentine capital, with Télam reporting police used sticks and tear gas on protesters after a group of people knocked down fences near her home.",
        "During the national address on Thursday, President Fernández said he had been in touch with the judge assigned to the case to act as quickly as possible.",
        "Argentina has been roiled by demonstrations this summer, with thousands taking to the streets protesting the administration's management of soaring inflation and corruption allegations.",
        "In 2016 a judge indicted Fernández de Kirchner along with 11 others on charges of corruption, illicit association, and aggravated fraudulent administration, freezing $643 million of her assets.",
        "Fernández de Kirchner was charged for allegedly directing public road works to a company called Austral Constructions during her presidency. At the time, she had criticized the investigation as being politically motivated.",
        "She was also simultaneously on trial for another corruption case, in which she was accused of allegedly meddling with the sale of US dollars by the nation's central bank. The case was dismissed in 2021, with the court ruling in favor of Fernández de Kirchner, according to CNN affiliate CNN Español.",
        "Suspect arrested after failed assassination attempt on Argentine vice president"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Argentine",
          "label": "NORP"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "CNN)A",
            "label": "PRODUCT"
          },
          {
            "text": "Cristina Fernández de Kirchner",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Argentina",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Thursday",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Fernández de Kirchner's",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "two",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "a few seconds",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Argentina",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Télam",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Brazilian",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Fernando Andre",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "The Argentine Ministry of Security",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Cristina",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "five",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Argentine",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Alberto Fernández",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Thursday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "evening",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Friday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Fernández de Kirchner",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Argentine",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Mauricio Macri",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Thursday",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Fernández de Kirchner",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Argentina",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "2019",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "several days",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Earlier in",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "August",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Fernández de Kirchner",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "12-year",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Days later",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Argentine",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Télam",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Thursday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Fernández",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Argentina",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "this summer",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "thousands",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "2016",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Fernández de Kirchner",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "11",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "$643 million",
            "label": "MONEY"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Fernández de Kirchner",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Austral Constructions",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "2021",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Fernández de Kirchner",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "CNN",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "CNN",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Español",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Argentine",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "ආර්ජන්ටිනාවේ උප ජනාධිපති ඝාතන තැත අසාර්ථක වීමෙන් පසු සැකකරු අත්අඩංගුවට",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "(CNN)ආජන්ටිනාවේ උප ජනාධිපති සහ හිටපු ජනාධිපතිනි Cristina Fernández de Kirchner ට බ්‍රහස්පතින්දා බුවනෝස් අයර්ස් හි ඇගේ නිවසින් පිටත හිස් පරාසයක වෙඩි තැබීමට උත්සාහ කිරීමෙන් පසු පුද්ගලයෙකු අත්අඩංගුවට ගෙන තිබේ.",
        "සිද්ධියේ වීඩියෝවේ දැක්වෙන්නේ උප සභාපතිනිය සෙනඟක් මැදින් යද්දී සිනා සෙන ආකාරයයි. පසුව සමූහයා අතර සිටි මිනිසෙක් ෆර්නැන්ඩස් ද කර්ච්නර්ගේ මුහුණ දෙසට තුවක්කුවක් දිගු කර වෙඩි තැබීමට උත්සාහ කරයි. වෙඩි නොවදින අතර දෙවතාවක් හිටපු ජනපතිවරයා කිසිදු හානියක් නොවී පසුපසට පැන්නේය.",
        "තත්පර කිහිපයක ව්‍යාකූලත්වයකින් සහ භීතියකින් පසුව ප්‍රහාරකයා අත්අඩංගුවට ගෙන ඇත.",
        "ආර්ජන්ටිනාවේ නිල ප්‍රවෘත්ති ඒජන්සිය වන Télam මෙම පුද්ගලයා බ්‍රසීල ජාතිකයෙකු ලෙස හඳුනාගෙන පසුව ඔහුගේ නම Fernando Andre Sabag Montiel ලෙස යාවත්කාලීන කළේය.",
        "ආජන්ටිනාවේ ආරක්ෂක අමාත්‍යාංශය තහවුරු කළේ සිද්ධියට යොදාගෙන ඇත්තේ වෙඩි උණ්ඩ සහිත .380 ගිනි අවියක් බවයි.",
        "\"ක්‍රිස්ටිනා තවමත් ජීවතුන් අතර සිටින්නේ - කිසියම් හේතුවක් නිසා අපට මේ මොහොතේ තාක්‍ෂණිකව තහවුරු කළ නොහැක - වෙඩි උණ්ඩ පහකින් සන්නද්ධ වූ ආයුධය, කොකා ඇදී ගියත් වෙඩි තැබුවේ නැත,\" ආර්ජන්ටිනාවේ ජනාධිපති ඇල්බර්ටෝ ෆර්නැන්ඩස් බ්‍රහස්පතින්දා රූපවාහිනී දේශනයකදී පැවසීය. සවස.",
        "මෙම ඝාතන උත්සාහය ප්‍රජාතන්ත්‍රවාදයට එරෙහි ප්‍රහාරයක් ලෙස හැඳින්වූ ඔහු, “අපගේ මාධ්‍ය සහ දේශපාලන කතිකාවෙන් වෛරය සහ ප්‍රචණ්ඩත්වය අප විසින් තුරන් කළ යුතුයි” යනුවෙන් පැවසීය. Fernández de Kirchner ට සහය දැක්වීම සඳහා එකට පෙළ ගැසීමට ඔහු සිකුරාදා ජාතික නිවාඩු දිනයක් ලෙස ප්‍රකාශයට පත් කළේය.",
        "හිටපු ආර්ජන්ටිනාවේ ජනාධිපති මොරිසියෝ මැක්‍රි ද බ්‍රහස්පතින්දා ප්‍රහාරය ප්‍රතික්ෂේප කරමින්, \"අධිකරණ පද්ධතිය සහ ආරක්ෂක හමුදාවන් විසින් වහා සහ ගැඹුරු පැහැදිලි කිරීමක්\" ඉල්ලා සිටියේය.",
        "Fernández de Kirchner ආර්ජන්ටිනාවේ ප්‍රමුඛතම දේශපාලන පුද්ගලයින් අතර වන අතර, 2019 දී උප ජනාධිපති ලෙස බලයට පත් වීමට පෙර 2007 සිට 2015 දක්වා ජනාධිපති ලෙස සේවය කර ඇත.",
        "ඇයගේ ජනාධිපති ධුර කාලය තුළ දූෂණ චෝදනා එල්ල වී ඇති නඩුවකට ප්‍රතිචාර වශයෙන් ඇයගේ ආධාරකරුවන් දින කිහිපයක් තිස්සේ ඇගේ නිවසින් පිටත රැලි පවත්වමින් සිටිති.",
        "අගෝස්තු මස මුලදී, ෆෙඩරල් අභිචෝදකයෙකු ෆර්නැන්ඩස් ද කර්ච්නර්ට වසර 12 ක සිර දඬුවමක් නියම කරන ලෙස ඉල්ලා සිටියේය. එම ඉල්ලීම සම්බන්ධයෙන් අධිකරණය තවමත් තීන්දුවක් ලබා දී නැත.",
        "දින කිහිපයකට පසු, ඇයගේ ආධාරකරුවන් ආර්ජන්ටිනාවේ අගනුවරදී පොලිසිය සමඟ ගැටී ඇති අතර, Télam වාර්තා කිරීමත් සමඟ, ඇයගේ නිවස අසල වැටවල් කඩා දැමූ පිරිසක් විරෝධතාකරුවන්ට පොලිසිය පොලු සහ කඳුළු ගෑස් භාවිතා කළහ.",
        "බ්‍රහස්පතින්දා ජාතික දේශනය අතරතුර, ජනාධිපති ෆර්නැන්ඩස් පැවසුවේ හැකි ඉක්මනින් ක්‍රියා කිරීම සඳහා නඩුවට පවරා ඇති විනිසුරුවරයා සමඟ තමා සම්බන්ධ වූ බවයි.",
        "ඉහල යන උද්ධමනය සහ දූෂණ චෝදනා පිලිබඳ පරිපාලනයේ කළමනාකාරීත්වයට විරෝධය පල කරමින් දහස් ගනනක් වීදි බැස සිටීමත් සමග, මෙම ගිම්හානයේදී ආර්ජන්ටිනාව පෙලපාලි වලින් කම්පා වී ඇත.",
        "2016 දී විනිසුරුවරයෙකු විසින් Fernández de Kirchner සහ තවත් 11 දෙනෙකුට දූෂණ, නීති විරෝධී ඇසුර සහ නරක් වූ වංචනික පරිපාලනය යන චෝදනා යටතේ අධිචෝදනා පවරමින්, ඇයගේ වත්කම්වලින් ඩොලර් මිලියන 643 ක් කැටිකර ඇත.",
        "Fernández de Kirchner ට චෝදනා එල්ල වූයේ ඇයගේ ජනාධිපති ධුර කාලය තුළ Austral Constructions නම් සමාගමකට පොදු මාර්ග කටයුතු මෙහෙයවීම සම්බන්ධයෙන් ය. එම පරීක්ෂණය දේශපාලන අරමුණක් මත සිදු වූවක් බවට ඇය එම අවස්ථාවේදී විවේචනය කර තිබුණා.",
        "ජාතික මහ බැංකුව විසින් ඇමරිකානු ඩොලර් විකිණීමට මැදිහත් වූ බවට චෝදනා කරන ලද තවත් දූෂණ නඩුවක් සඳහා ඇය එකවරම නඩු විභාගයට ලක්ව සිටියාය. CNN අනුබද්ධ CNN Español ට අනුව, 2021 දී නඩුව නිෂ්ප්‍රභ කරන ලදී, අධිකරණය Fernández de Kirchner ට පක්ෂව තීන්දුවක් ලබා දුන්නේය.",
        "ආර්ජන්ටිනාවේ උප ජනාධිපති ඝාතන තැත අසාර්ථක වීමෙන් පසු සැකකරු අත්අඩංගුවට"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ආර්ජන්ටිනාව",
          "label": "NORP"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "සීඑන්එන්) ඒ",
            "label": "PRODUCT"
          },
          {
            "text": "Cristina Fernández de Kirchner",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ආර්ජන්ටිනාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "බ්රහස්පතින්දා",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ෆර්නැන්ඩස් ද කර්ච්නර්ගේ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "දෙක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "තත්පර කිහිපයක්",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ආර්ජන්ටිනාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ටෙලම්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "බ්රසීලියානු",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ප්‍රනාන්දු අන්දරේ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ආර්ජන්ටිනාවේ ආරක්ෂක අමාත්යාංශය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ක්රිස්ටිනා",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "පහ",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ආර්ජන්ටිනාව",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඇල්බර්ටෝ ෆර්නැන්ඩස්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "බ්රහස්පතින්දා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "සවස",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "සිකුරාදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ෆර්නැන්ඩස් ද කර්ච්නර්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ආර්ජන්ටිනාව",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "මොරිසියෝ මැක්රි",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "බ්රහස්පතින්දා",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ෆර්නැන්ඩස් ද කර්ච්නර්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ආර්ජන්ටිනාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "2019",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "දින කිහිපයක්",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "මීට පෙර දී",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "අගෝස්තු",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ෆර්නැන්ඩස් ද කර්ච්නර්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "අවුරුදු 12",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "දවස් ගානකට පස්සේ",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ආර්ජන්ටිනාව",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ටෙලම්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "බ්රහස්පතින්දා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ෆර්නැන්ඩස්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ආර්ජන්ටිනාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මේ ගිම්හානයේ",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "දහස්",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "2016",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ෆර්නැන්ඩස් ද කර්ච්නර්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "11",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඩොලර් මිලියන 643 කි",
            "label": "MONEY"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ෆර්නැන්ඩස් ද කර්ච්නර්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඕස්ට්රේලියානු ඉදිකිරීම්",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "2021",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ෆර්නැන්ඩස් ද කර්ච්නර්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "සීඑන්එන්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "සීඑන්එන්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Español",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ආර්ජන්ටිනාව",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "அர்ஜென்டினாவின் துணை ஜனாதிபதியை படுகொலை செய்ய முயற்சி தோல்வியடைந்ததை அடுத்து சந்தேக நபர் கைது செய்யப்பட்டுள்ளார்",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "(CNN) அர்ஜென்டினாவின் துணைத் தலைவரும் முன்னாள் ஜனாதிபதியுமான கிறிஸ்டினா பெர்னாண்டஸ் டி கிர்ச்னரை வியாழன் அன்று பியூனஸ் அயர்ஸில் உள்ள அவரது வீட்டிற்கு வெளியே வெற்றுத் தூரத்தில் சுட முயன்ற நபர் ஒருவர் கைது செய்யப்பட்டுள்ளார்.",
        "இந்த சம்பவத்தின் காணொளியில் துணை ஜனாதிபதி சிரித்துக்கொண்டே மக்கள் கூட்டத்தினூடே நடந்து செல்கிறார். கூட்டத்திலிருந்த ஒரு நபர், ஃபெர்னாண்டஸ் டி கிர்ச்னரின் முகத்தை நோக்கி துப்பாக்கியை சுட்டிக்காட்டி, சுட முயல்கிறார். தோட்டாக்கள் எதுவும் வீசப்படவில்லை, இரண்டு முறை முன்னாள் ஜனாதிபதி, காயமின்றி பின்னோக்கிச் செல்கிறார்.",
        "சில நொடிகள் குழப்பம் மற்றும் பீதிக்குப் பிறகு தாக்குதல் நடத்தியவர் கைது செய்யப்பட்டார்.",
        "அர்ஜென்டினாவின் அதிகாரப்பூர்வ செய்தி நிறுவனமான Télam, அந்த நபரை பிரேசில் நாட்டவர் என்று அடையாளம் காட்டியது, பின்னர் அவரது பெயரை பெர்னாண்டோ ஆண்ட்ரே சபாக் மான்டியேல் எனப் புதுப்பித்தது.",
        "இந்த சம்பவத்தில் பயன்படுத்தப்பட்ட ஆயுதம் .380 துப்பாக்கி தோட்டாக்கள் என அர்ஜென்டினா பாதுகாப்பு அமைச்சகம் உறுதி செய்துள்ளது.",
        "\"கிறிஸ்டினா இன்னும் உயிருடன் இருக்கிறார், ஏனென்றால் சில காரணங்களால் இந்த நேரத்தில் தொழில்நுட்ப ரீதியாக உறுதிப்படுத்த முடியவில்லை - ஐந்து தோட்டாக்களுடன் ஆயுதம் ஏந்திய ஆயுதம், தூண்டுதல் இழுக்கப்பட்டாலும் சுடவில்லை\" என்று அர்ஜென்டினா ஜனாதிபதி ஆல்பர்டோ பெர்னாண்டஸ் வியாழக்கிழமை தொலைக்காட்சி உரையில் கூறினார். சாயங்காலம்.",
        "படுகொலை முயற்சி ஜனநாயகத்தின் மீதான தாக்குதல் என்று அவர் கூறினார், \"எங்கள் ஊடகங்கள் மற்றும் அரசியல் சொற்பொழிவுகளில் இருந்து வெறுப்பையும் வன்முறையையும் நாம் ஒழிக்க வேண்டும்.\" ஃபெர்னாண்டஸ் டி கிர்ச்னருக்கு ஆதரவாக ஒன்று திரள்வதற்காக அவர் வெள்ளிக்கிழமையை தேசிய விடுமுறையாக அறிவித்தார்.",
        "முன்னாள் அர்ஜென்டினா ஜனாதிபதி மொரிசியோ மக்ரியும் வியாழன் அன்று தாக்குதலை கைவிட்டு, \"நீதி அமைப்பு மற்றும் பாதுகாப்புப் படைகளால் உடனடி மற்றும் ஆழமான தெளிவுபடுத்தலுக்கு\" அழைப்பு விடுத்தார்.",
        "ஃபெர்னாண்டஸ் டி கிர்ச்னர் அர்ஜென்டினாவின் மிக முக்கியமான அரசியல் பிரமுகர்களில் ஒருவர், 2019 இல் துணை ஜனாதிபதியாக பதவியேற்பதற்கு முன்பு 2007 முதல் 2015 வரை ஜனாதிபதியாக பணியாற்றினார்.",
        "அவர் ஜனாதிபதியாக இருந்த காலத்தில் ஊழல் செய்ததாக குற்றம் சாட்டப்பட்ட வழக்கு விசாரணைக்கு பதிலளிக்கும் விதமாக, அவரது ஆதரவாளர்கள் பல நாட்களாக அவரது வீட்டிற்கு வெளியே பேரணிகளை நடத்தி வருகின்றனர்.",
        "முன்னதாக ஆகஸ்ட் மாதம், பெர்னாண்டஸ் டி கிர்ச்னரை 12 ஆண்டு சிறைத்தண்டனை அனுபவிக்குமாறு ஒரு கூட்டாட்சி வழக்கறிஞர் அழைப்பு விடுத்தார். இந்த கோரிக்கை மீது நீதிமன்றம் இன்னும் தீர்ப்பளிக்கவில்லை.",
        "சில நாட்களுக்குப் பிறகு, அவரது ஆதரவாளர்கள் அர்ஜென்டினா தலைநகரில் பொலிஸாருடன் மோதினர், தெலாம் அறிக்கையின்படி, அவரது வீட்டின் அருகே ஒரு குழு மக்கள் வேலிகளை இடித்ததை அடுத்து, எதிர்ப்பாளர்கள் மீது காவல்துறையினர் தடியடி மற்றும் கண்ணீர் புகைக் குண்டுகளைப் பயன்படுத்தினர்.",
        "வியாழன் அன்று தேசிய உரையின் போது, ​​​​ஜனாதிபதி பெர்னாண்டஸ், முடிந்தவரை விரைவாக செயல்பட, வழக்கிற்கு நியமிக்கப்பட்ட நீதிபதியுடன் தொடர்பு கொண்டதாகக் கூறினார்.",
        "இந்த கோடையில் ஆர்ஜென்டீனா ஆர்ப்பாட்டங்களால் கொந்தளித்தது, பணவீக்கம் மற்றும் ஊழல் குற்றச்சாட்டுகளின் நிர்வாகத்தின் நிர்வாகத்தை எதிர்த்து ஆயிரக்கணக்கானோர் தெருக்களில் இறங்கினர்.",
        "2016 ஆம் ஆண்டில், ஒரு நீதிபதி பெர்னாண்டஸ் டி கிர்ச்னர் மற்றும் 11 பேர் மீது ஊழல், சட்டவிரோத தொடர்பு மற்றும் மோசமான மோசடி நிர்வாகத்தின் குற்றச்சாட்டுகளின் கீழ் குற்றஞ்சாட்டினார், மேலும் அவரது $643 மில்லியன் சொத்துக்களை முடக்கினார்.",
        "பெர்னாண்டஸ் டி கிர்ச்னர் தனது ஜனாதிபதியாக இருந்தபோது ஆஸ்ட்ரல் கன்ஸ்ட்ரக்ஷன்ஸ் என்ற நிறுவனத்திற்கு பொதுச் சாலைப் பணிகளை இயக்கியதாகக் குற்றம் சாட்டப்பட்டார். அப்போது, ​​விசாரணை அரசியல் உள்நோக்கம் கொண்டது என்று விமர்சித்திருந்தார்.",
        "அவர் அதே நேரத்தில் மற்றொரு ஊழல் வழக்கு விசாரணையில் இருந்தார், அதில் அவர் நாட்டின் மத்திய வங்கியால் அமெரிக்க டாலர்கள் விற்பனையில் தலையிட்டதாகக் குற்றம் சாட்டப்பட்டார். CNN துணை நிறுவனமான CNN Español படி, ஃபெர்னாண்டஸ் டி கிர்ச்னருக்கு ஆதரவாக நீதிமன்றம் தீர்ப்பளித்ததன் மூலம், 2021 இல் வழக்கு தள்ளுபடி செய்யப்பட்டது.",
        "அர்ஜென்டினாவின் துணை ஜனாதிபதியை படுகொலை செய்ய முயற்சி தோல்வியடைந்ததை அடுத்து சந்தேக நபர் கைது செய்யப்பட்டுள்ளார்"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "அர்ஜென்டினா",
          "label": "NORP"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "சிஎன்என்) ஏ",
            "label": "PRODUCT"
          },
          {
            "text": "கிறிஸ்டினா பெர்னாண்டஸ் டி கிர்ச்னர்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "அர்ஜென்டினா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "வியாழன்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பெர்னாண்டஸ் டி கிர்ச்னர்ஸ்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இரண்டு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "சில வினாடிகள்",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "அர்ஜென்டினா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "தெலம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "பிரேசிலியன்",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "பெர்னாண்டோ ஆண்ட்ரே",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "அர்ஜென்டினா பாதுகாப்பு அமைச்சகம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "கிறிஸ்டினா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஐந்து",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "அர்ஜென்டினா",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆல்பர்டோ பெர்னாண்டஸ்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "வியாழன்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சாயங்காலம்",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "வெள்ளி",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "பெர்னாண்டஸ் டி கிர்ச்னர்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "அர்ஜென்டினா",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "மொரிசியோ மேக்ரி",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "வியாழன்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பெர்னாண்டஸ் டி கிர்ச்னர்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "அர்ஜென்டினா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "2019",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பல நாட்கள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "முன்னதாக உள்ள",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆகஸ்ட்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "பெர்னாண்டஸ் டி கிர்ச்னர்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "12-ஆண்டு",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "நாட்கள் கழித்து",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "அர்ஜென்டினா",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "தெலம்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "வியாழன்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "பெர்னாண்டஸ்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "அர்ஜென்டினா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்த கோடை",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆயிரக்கணக்கான",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "2016",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "பெர்னாண்டஸ் டி கிர்ச்னர்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "11",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "$643 மில்லியன்",
            "label": "MONEY"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பெர்னாண்டஸ் டி கிர்ச்னர்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆஸ்திரேலிய கட்டுமானங்கள்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "2021",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "பெர்னாண்டஸ் டி கிர்ச்னர்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "சிஎன்என்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "சிஎன்என்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "எஸ்பானோல்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "அர்ஜென்டினா",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}