{
  "newspaper_id": "news-first-lk",
  "url": "https://www.newsfirst.lk/2022/07/10/attack-on-journalists-prosecute-under-torture-act/",
  "time_ut": 1657462620,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Attack on Journalists: Prosecute under Torture Act",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Attack on Journalists: Prosecute under Torture Act",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); MTV Channel (Private) Limited in a letter to the IGP demand that the Special Task Force Officers and Police Officers who illegally and unlawfully, brutally attacked News 1st Journalists should be charged under the provisions of the Convention Against Torture and Other Cruel, Inhuman, or Degrading Treatment or Punishment Act.",
        "MTV Channel (Private) Limited stresses that the said officers are liable to be prosecuted under the said act which is also the Torture Act of Sri Lanka.",
        "MTV Channel (Private) Limited also urges the response for the following three matters of concern;",
        "1. Under whose direction were the assaults on our News 1st journalists made?",
        "2. What immediate disciplinary action will be taken against the illegal and unlawful assaults?",
        "3. What remedial measures will be taken to ensure media freedom?",
        "MTV Channel (Private) Limited urges Inspector General of Police C. D. Wickramaratne to ensure that there are no such attempts to intimidate us or to act in any manner, either by himself or by directing any third parties, to prevent our media or journalists from continuing to professionally discharge our responsibilities and duties as a broadcast media organization, and body of professionals."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "MTV Channel",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "IGP",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Special Task Force Officers",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "News 1st",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Convention Against Torture and Other Cruel",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Inhuman",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "MTV Channel",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Torture Act",
            "label": "LAW"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "MTV Channel",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "three",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "1",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "News 1st",
            "label": "EVENT"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "2",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "3",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "MTV Channel",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Police C. D. Wickramaratne",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "third",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "මාධ්‍යවේදීන්ට පහරදීම: වධහිංසා පනත යටතේ නඩු පවරන්න",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); News 1st මාධ්‍යවේදීන්ට නීති විරෝධීව සහ නීතිවිරෝධී ලෙස අමානුෂික ලෙස පහර දුන් විශේෂ කාර්ය බළකා නිලධාරීන්ට සහ පොලිස් නිලධාරීන්ට වධහිංසාවට සහ වෙනත් කුරිරු, අමානුෂික හෝ සම්මුතියේ විධිවිධාන යටතේ නඩු පැවරිය යුතු බව MTV Channel (Private) Limited පොලිස්පතිවරයා වෙත ලිපියක් යොමු කරමින් ඉල්ලා සිටියි. අවමන් සහගත සැලකීම හෝ දඬුවම් පනත.",
        "MTV Channel (Private) Limited අවධාරණය කරන්නේ ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ වධහිංසා පනත ද වන එම පනත යටතේ එම නිලධාරීන්ට නඩු පැවරිය හැකි බවයි.",
        "MTV Channel (Private) Limited පහත සඳහන් කරුණු තුන සඳහා ප්‍රතිචාර දක්වන ලෙස ඉල්ලා සිටී;",
        "1. අපේ News 1st මාධ්‍යවේදීන්ට පහරදීම් සිදු කළේ කාගේ මඟ පෙන්වීම යටතේද?",
        "2. නීති විරෝධී සහ නීති විරෝධී පහරදීම්වලට එරෙහිව වහාම ගනු ලබන විනය ක්‍රියාමාර්ග මොනවාද?",
        "3. මාධ්‍ය නිදහස තහවුරු කිරීමට ගන්නා ප්‍රතිකර්ම මොනවාද?",
        "සීමාසහිත MTV Channel (Private) Limited පොලිස්පති C. D. වික්‍රමරත්නගෙන් ඉල්ලා සිටින්නේ අපව බිය ගැන්වීමට හෝ තමා විසින් හෝ කිසිදු තෙවන පාර්ශ්වයක් මෙහෙයවීමෙන් හෝ අපගේ මාධ්‍ය හෝ මාධ්‍යවේදීන් දිගින් දිගටම සිදු කිරීම වැළැක්වීමට එවැනි උත්සාහයන් සිදු නොවන බවට සහතික වන ලෙසයි. විකාශන මාධ්‍ය සංවිධානයක් සහ වෘත්තිකයන්ගේ මණ්ඩලයක් ලෙස අපගේ වගකීම් සහ යුතුකම් වෘත්තීයමය වශයෙන් ඉටු කරන්න."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "MTV නාලිකාව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "පොලිස්පති",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "විශේෂ කාර්ය බළකායේ නිලධාරීන්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "News 1st",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "වධහිංසා සහ වෙනත් කුරිරුකම්වලට එරෙහි සම්මුතිය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "අමානුෂිකයි",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "MTV නාලිකාව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "වධහිංසා පනත",
            "label": "LAW"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "MTV නාලිකාව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "තුන්",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "1",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "News 1st",
            "label": "EVENT"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "2",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "3",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "MTV නාලිකාව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "පොලිස් සී.ඩී.වික්‍රමරත්න",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "තෙවන",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "ஊடகவியலாளர்கள் மீதான தாக்குதல்: சித்திரவதை சட்டத்தின் கீழ் வழக்குப்பதிவு",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); MTV Channel (Private) Limited IGPக்கு எழுதிய கடிதத்தில், News 1st ஊடகவியலாளர்களை சட்டவிரோதமாகவும், சட்டவிரோதமாகவும், கொடூரமாக தாக்கிய சிறப்பு அதிரடிப்படை அதிகாரிகள் மற்றும் காவல்துறை அதிகாரிகள் மீது சித்திரவதை மற்றும் பிற கொடூரமான, மனிதாபிமானமற்ற, அல்லது இழிவான சிகிச்சை அல்லது தண்டனைச் சட்டம்.",
        "MTV Channel (Private) Limited, மேற்கூறிய அதிகாரிகள் இலங்கையின் சித்திரவதைச் சட்டமான மேற்படி சட்டத்தின் கீழ் வழக்குத் தொடரப்படுவார்கள் என்று வலியுறுத்துகிறது.",
        "MTV சேனல் (பிரைவேட்) லிமிடெட் பின்வரும் மூன்று கவலைக்குரிய விஷயங்களுக்கு பதிலையும் வலியுறுத்துகிறது;",
        "1. யாருடைய வழிகாட்டுதலின் கீழ் நமது நியூஸ் 1ஸ்ட் பத்திரிகையாளர்கள் மீது தாக்குதல் நடத்தப்பட்டது?",
        "2. சட்டவிரோத மற்றும் சட்டவிரோத தாக்குதல்களுக்கு எதிராக உடனடியாக என்ன ஒழுங்கு நடவடிக்கை எடுக்கப்படும்?",
        "3. ஊடக சுதந்திரத்தை உறுதிப்படுத்த என்ன திருத்த நடவடிக்கைகள் எடுக்கப்படும்?",
        "எம்டிவி சேனல் (பிரைவேட்) லிமிடெட் பொலிஸ் மா அதிபர் சி.டி. விக்கிரமரத்னவிடம் எங்களை அச்சுறுத்தும் முயற்சிகள் இல்லை என்பதை உறுதிப்படுத்துமாறு கேட்டுக்கொள்கிறது. ஒரு ஒளிபரப்பு ஊடக அமைப்பு மற்றும் நிபுணர்களின் அமைப்பாக எங்கள் பொறுப்புகள் மற்றும் கடமைகளை தொழில்ரீதியாக நிறைவேற்றுகிறோம்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "எம்டிவி சேனல்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஐ.ஜி.பி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "சிறப்பு அதிரடிப்படை அதிகாரிகள்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "News 1st",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "சித்திரவதை மற்றும் பிற கொடுமைகளுக்கு எதிரான மாநாடு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "மனிதாபிமானமற்ற",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "எம்டிவி சேனல்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "சித்திரவதை சட்டம்",
            "label": "LAW"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "எம்டிவி சேனல்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "மூன்று",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "1",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "News 1st",
            "label": "EVENT"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "2",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "3",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "எம்டிவி சேனல்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "பொலிஸ் சி.டி.விக்கிரமரத்ன",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "மூன்றாவது",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}