{
  "newspaper_id": "lankadeepa-lk",
  "url": "https://www.lankadeepa.lk/latest_news/කාර්-දුම්රිය-ගැටී-දැරියක්-මරුට:-5ක්-රෝහලට/1-616602",
  "time_ut": 1658125546,
  "original_lang": "si",
  "original_title": "කාර්-දුම්රිය ගැටී දැරියක් මරුට: 5ක් රෝහලට",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Girl killed in car-train collision: 5 hospitalized",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "A seven-year-old girl and a pregnant mother who were traveling in the car were killed when a train collided with a car trying to drive through the railway crossing while the warning signals were flashing at the Makuluwa Gangarama railway crossing in Galle, Galle Harbor Police said.",
        "A pregnant mother named KLS Shadila Hansi and L. A girl named Yu Dissanayake (07) is a resident of Homagama Kiriwatthuduwa area. The other injured are residents of Makuluwa area.",
        "07 relatives of several families were traveling in the car. It has been revealed in the police investigation that they were traveling in the car to attend a wedding ceremony held in Piliyandala area.",
        "The car was moving towards Makuluwa from Galle. The police said that the car drove through the railway crossing while the warning lights were on at Makuluwa Gangarama railway crossing.",
        "Even though the train is moving forward, the car will stop in the middle of the railway crossing. It has been revealed in the police investigations that the train has a bump.",
        "Three men, one woman and a small child were injured. Hospital sources say that the condition of the injured is serious."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "5",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "seven-year-old",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Makuluwa Gangarama",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "Galle",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Galle Harbor Police",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Shadila Hansi",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "L. A",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Yu Dissanayake",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "07",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Homagama Kiriwatthuduwa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Makuluwa",
            "label": "LOC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "07",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Piliyandala",
            "label": "LOC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Galle",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Makuluwa Gangarama",
            "label": "FAC"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "Three",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "one",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "කාර්-දුම්රිය ගැටී දැරියක් මරුට: 5ක් රෝහලට",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "ගාල්ල මකුළුව ගංගාරාම දුම්රිය හරස් මාර්ගයේ අනතුරු ඇගවිමේ සංඥා දැල්වෙමින් තිබියදි මෝටර් රථයක් දුම්රිය හරස් මාර්ගය හරහා ධාවනය කරවීමට උත්සහ කිරීමේදී දුම්රියේ ගැටිමෙන් මෝටර් රථයේ ගමන්ගත් හත් හැවිරිදි දැරියක් සහ ගැබනි මවක් මියගොස් පස් දෙනකු බරපතල තුවාල ලබා ගාල්ල කරාපිටිය ශික්ෂණ රෝහලට ඇතුළත් කර ඇතැයි ගාල්ල වරාය පොලිසිය පවසයි.",
        "මෙම අනතුරින් මියගොස් ඇත්තේ කේ.එල්.එස් ෂාඩිලා හංසි නැමති ගැබනි මවක් හා එල්. යු දිසානායක (07) නැමති දැරියකි ඇය හෝමාගම කිරිවත්තුඩුව  ප්‍රදේශයේ පදිංචිකාරියකි. අනික් තුවාලකරුවන් මකුළුව ප්‍රදේශයේ පදිංචිකරුවන් වෙති.",
        "මෝටර් රථයේ පවුල්කිහිපයක ඥාතින් 07 දෙනෙකු ගමන්කොට ඇත. ඔවුන් පිළියන්දල ප්‍රදේශයේ පැවැත්වෙන මංගල උත්සවයකට සහභාගිවිම සදහා මෝටර් රථයේ ගමන්කරමින් සිටි ඇති බව පොලිස් පරික්ෂණවලදි අනාවරණය වි ඇත.",
        "මෝටර් රථය ගාල්ල දෙස සිට මකුළුව දෙසට ගමන්කරමින් සිට ඇත. මකුළුව ගංගාරාම දුම්රිය හරස් මාර්ගයේ අනතුරු ඇගවිමේ විදුලි සංඥා දැල්වෙමින් තිබියදි මෝටර් රථය දුම්රිය හරස් මාර්ගය හරහා ධාවනය කොට ඇතැයි පොලිසිය පවසයි.",
        "දුම්රිය ඉදිරියට ධාවනය වනවාත්  සමග මෝටර් රථය දුම්රිය හරස් මාර්ගය මැද නතරවි දුම්රියේ ගැටි ඇති බව පොලිස් පරික්ෂණවලදි අනාවරණය වි ඇත.",
        "තුවාල ලබා ඇත්තේ පිරිමි පුද්ගලයන් තිදෙනකු එක් කාන්තාවක හා කුඩා දරුවෙකි. තුවාලකරුවන්ගේ තත්වය බරපතල බව රෝහල් ආරංචි මාර්ග සදහන් කරයි."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "5",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "අවුරුදු හතක් වයසැති",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මකුළුව ගංගාරාමය",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගාල්ල",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගාලු වරාය පොලිසිය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ෂඩිලා හංසි",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "එල්. ඒ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "යූ දිසානායක",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "07",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Homagama Kiriwatthuduwa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "මකුළුව",
            "label": "LOC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "07",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "පිළියන්දල",
            "label": "LOC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ගාල්ල",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මකුළුව ගංගාරාමය",
            "label": "FAC"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "තුන්",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "එක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "கார்-ரயில் மோதி சிறுமி பலி: 5 பேர் மருத்துவமனையில்",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "காலி துறைமுகம், மகுலுவ கங்காராம புகையிரத கடவையில் எச்சரிக்கை சமிக்ஞைகள் ஒளிரும் போது, ​​புகையிரத கடவை வழியாக செல்ல முற்பட்ட கார் மீது புகையிரதம் மோதியதில் காரில் பயணித்த ஏழு வயது சிறுமியும் கர்ப்பிணி தாயும் உயிரிழந்துள்ளனர். போலீசார் தெரிவித்தனர்.",
        "கேஎல்எஸ் ஷதிலா ஹன்சி என்ற கர்ப்பிணித் தாய் மற்றும் எல். ஹோமாகம கிரிவத்துடுவ பிரதேசத்தை வசிப்பிடமாகக் கொண்ட யு திஸாநாயக்க (07) என்ற சிறுமி. காயமடைந்த ஏனையோர் மகுலுவ பிரதேசத்தைச் சேர்ந்தவர்களாவர்.",
        "காரில் பல குடும்பங்களைச் சேர்ந்த 07 உறவினர்கள் பயணித்துள்ளனர். பிலியந்தலை பிரதேசத்தில் இடம்பெற்ற திருமண நிகழ்வொன்றில் கலந்துகொள்வதற்காக இவர்கள் காரில் பயணித்துள்ளதாக பொலிஸாரின் விசாரணையில் தெரியவந்துள்ளது.",
        "கார் காலியிலிருந்து மகுலுவ நோக்கி சென்று கொண்டிருந்தது. மகுலுவ கங்காராம புகையிரத கடவையில் எச்சரிக்கை விளக்குகள் எரிந்திருந்த வேளையில் புகையிரத கடவையின் ஊடாக கார் பயணித்துள்ளதாக பொலிஸார் தெரிவித்தனர்.",
        "ரயில் முன்னோக்கிச் சென்றாலும், ரயில் கடவையின் நடுவே கார் நிற்கும்.ரயிலில் குண்டும் குழியுமாக இருப்பது போலீஸ் விசாரணையில் தெரியவந்துள்ளது.",
        "மூன்று ஆண்கள், ஒரு பெண் மற்றும் ஒரு சிறு குழந்தை காயமடைந்தனர். காயமடைந்தவர்களின் நிலைமை கவலைக்கிடமாக இருப்பதாக வைத்தியசாலை வட்டாரங்கள் தெரிவிக்கின்றன."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "5",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ஏழு வயது",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "மகுலுவ கங்காராம",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "காலி",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "காலி துறைமுக பொலிஸ்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஷதிலா ஹன்சி",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "எல். ஏ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "யூ திஸாநாயக்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "07",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Homagama Kiriwatthuduwa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "மகுலுவ",
            "label": "LOC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "07",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "பிலியந்தலை",
            "label": "LOC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "காலி",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "மகுலுவ கங்காராம",
            "label": "FAC"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "மூன்று",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஒன்று",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}