{
  "newspaper_id": "ada-derana-lk",
  "url": "http://www.adaderana.lk/news/83494/duration-for-lodging-complaints-on-property-damage-during-unrest-extended",
  "time_ut": 1657208700,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Duration for lodging complaints on property damage during unrest extended",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Duration for lodging complaints on property damage during unrest extended",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "The duration for lodging complaints to the victims of property damage as a result of the act of vandalism in several parts of the country from March 31 to May 15, extended until July 22, the Government Information Department said.",
        "The President on June 01 appointed a three-member Presidential Commission to inquire into the incidents of arson, looting, murders, injuries caused to individuals and damages to properties in parts of the country between March 31 and May 15, 2022.",
        "The commission of inquiry is headed by Supreme Court Justice Buwaneka Aluvihare and also includes former Senior DIG S.M. Wickramasinghe and Additional Chief Assessor N.A.S. Wasantha Kumara.",
        "Meanwhile the Additional Secretary to the President Mr. Buwaneka Herath was appointed as the Secretary to the commission."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "March 31 to May 15",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "July 22",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Government Information Department",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "June 01",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "three",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Presidential Commission",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "between March 31",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "May 15, 2022",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Supreme Court",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Buwaneka Aluvihare",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "N.A.S.",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Wasantha Kumara",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Buwaneka Herath",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "නොසන්සුන්තා අතරතුර දේපල හානි පිළිබඳ පැමිණිලි ඉදිරිපත් කිරීමේ කාලය දීර්ඝ කෙරේ",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "පසුගිය මාර්තු 31 වැනිදා සිට මැයි 15 වැනිදා දක්වා දිවයිනේ ප්‍රදේශ කිහිපයක සිදුවූ විනාශකාරී ක්‍රියාවන් හේතුවෙන් දේපළ හානිවලට ලක්වූවන්ට පැමිණිලි කිරීමේ කාලය ජූලි 22 වැනිදා දක්වා දීර්ඝ කළ බව රජයේ ප්‍රවෘත්ති දෙපාර්තමේන්තුව පවසයි.",
        "2022 මාර්තු 31 සිට මැයි 15 දක්වා කාලය තුළ දිවයිනේ ප්‍රදේශ කිහිපයක සිදුවූ ගිනි තැබීම්, මංකොල්ලකෑම්, මිනීමැරුම්, පුද්ගලයන්ට තුවාල සිදුකිරීම් සහ දේපළවලට අලාභහානි සිදුකිරීම් පිළිබඳ සොයා බැලීම සඳහා ජනාධිපතිවරයා විසින් ත්‍රිපුද්ගල ජනාධිපති කොමිසමක් පත් කළේ ජුනි 01 වැනිදාය.",
        "ශ්‍රේෂ්ඨාධිකරණ විනිසුරු බුවනෙක අලුවිහාරේ මහතාගේ ප්‍රධානත්වයෙන් යුත් මෙම විමර්ශන කොමිසමට හිටපු ජ්‍යෙෂ්ඨ නියෝජ්‍ය පොලිස්පති එස්.එම්. වික්‍රමසිංහ සහ අතිරේක ප්‍රධාන තක්සේරුකරු එන්.ඒ.එස්. වසන්ත කුමාර.",
        "මේ අතර එම කොමිසමේ ලේකම්වරයා ලෙස ජනාධිපති අතිරේක ලේකම් බුවනෙක හේරත් මහතා පත් කරනු ලැබුවා."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "මාර්තු 31 සිට මැයි 15 දක්වා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජූලි 22",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "රජයේ ප්‍රවෘත්ති දෙපාර්තමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ජුනි 01",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "තුන්",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජනාධිපති කොමිසම",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "මාර්තු 31 අතර",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "2022 මැයි 15",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රේෂ්ඨාධිකරණය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "බුවනෙක අලුවිහාරේ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "එන්.ඒ.එස්.",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "වසන්ත කුමාර",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "බුවනෙක හේරත්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "அமைதியின்மையின் போது சொத்து சேதம் குறித்து புகார் அளிக்கும் காலம் நீட்டிக்கப்பட்டுள்ளது",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "கடந்த மார்ச் 31ஆம் திகதி முதல் மே 15ஆம் திகதி வரை நாட்டின் பல பகுதிகளில் இடம்பெற்ற நாசகார நடவடிக்கைகளின் விளைவாக சொத்துக்களுக்கு சேதம் விளைவிப்பவர்களுக்கு முறைப்பாடு செய்யும் கால அவகாசம் ஜூலை 22ஆம் திகதி வரை நீடிக்கப்பட்டுள்ளதாக அரசாங்க தகவல் திணைக்களம் தெரிவித்துள்ளது.",
        "2022ஆம் ஆண்டு மார்ச் 31ஆம் திகதி முதல் மே 15ஆம் திகதி வரை நாட்டின் சில பகுதிகளில் இடம்பெற்ற தீவைப்பு, கொள்ளை, கொலைகள், தனிநபர்களுக்கு ஏற்பட்ட காயங்கள் மற்றும் சொத்துக்களுக்கு சேதம் ஏற்படுத்திய சம்பவங்கள் குறித்து விசாரிப்பதற்காக மூன்று பேர் கொண்ட ஜனாதிபதி ஆணைக்குழுவை ஜனாதிபதி ஜூன் 01ஆம் திகதி நியமித்தார்.",
        "உச்ச நீதிமன்ற நீதியரசர் புவனேக அலுவிஹாரே தலைமையிலான விசாரணைக் குழுவில் முன்னாள் சிரேஷ்ட பிரதி பொலிஸ் மா அதிபர் எஸ்.எம். விக்கிரமசிங்க மற்றும் மேலதிக பிரதம மதிப்பீட்டாளர் என்.ஏ.எஸ். வசந்த குமார.",
        "இதேவேளை, ஜனாதிபதியின் மேலதிக செயலாளர் திரு.புவனேக ஹேரத் ஆணைக்குழுவின் செயலாளராக நியமிக்கப்பட்டுள்ளார்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "மார்ச் 31 முதல் மே 15 வரை",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜூலை 22",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "அரசாங்க தகவல் திணைக்களம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஜூன் 01",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "மூன்று",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜனாதிபதி ஆணைக்குழு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "மார்ச் 31 க்கு இடையில்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "மே 15, 2022",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "உச்ச நீதிமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "புவனேக அலுவிஹாரே",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "என்.ஏ.எஸ்.",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "வசந்த குமார",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "புவனேக ஹேரத்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}