{
  "newspaper_id": "ada-derana-lk",
  "url": "http://www.adaderana.lk/news/83499/former-japanese-pm-shinzo-abe-injured-in-apparent-shooting",
  "time_ut": 1657251360,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Former Japanese PM Shinzo Abe injured in apparent shooting",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Former Japanese PM Shinzo Abe injured in apparent shooting",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "Japanese former prime minister Shinzo Abe was taken to hospital on Friday after being shot from behind by what appeared to be a man with a shotgun while delivering a speech in the western city of Nara, public broadcaster NHK said.",
        "Abe, 67, appeared to be in a state of cardiac arrest, the network said and Kyodo news agency. Shots were heard and a white puff of smoke was seen as Abe made a campaign stump speech outside a train station, NHK said.",
        "An NHK reporter on the scene said they could hear two consecutive bangs during Abe’s speech.",
        "Abe served two terms as prime minister to become Japan’s longest-serving premier before stepping down in 2020 citing ill health.",
        "But he has remained a dominant presence over the ruling Liberal Democratic party (LDP) party, controlling one of its major factions.",
        "His protege, Prime Minister Fumio Kishida, faces an upper house election on Sunday in which analysts say he hopes to emerge from Abe’s shadow and define his premiership.",
        "Abe has been best known for his signature “Abenomics” policy featured bold monetary easing and fiscal spending.",
        "He also bolstered defence spending after years of declines and expanded the military’s ability to project power abroad.",
        "In a historic shift in 2014, his government reinterpreted the postwar, pacifist constitution to allow troops to fight overseas for the first time since World War Two.",
        "The following year, legislation ended a ban on exercising the right of collective self-defence, or defending a friendly country under attack.",
        "Abe, however, did not achieve his long-held goal of revising the U.S.-drafted constitution by writing the Self-Defense Forces, as Japan’s military in known, into the pacifist Article 9.",
        "He was instrumental in winning the 2020 Olympics for Tokyo, cherishing a wish to preside over the Games, which were postponed by a year to 2021 because of the COVID-19 pandemic.",
        "Abe first took office in 2006 as Japan’s youngest prime minister since World War Two. After a year plagued by political scandals, voter outrage at lost pension records, and an election drubbing for his ruling party, Abe quit citing ill health.",
        "Abe hails from a wealthy political family that included a foreign minister father and a great-uncle who served as premier."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Japanese",
          "label": "NORP"
        },
        {
          "text": "Shinzo Abe",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Japanese",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Shinzo Abe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Friday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Nara",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Abe",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "67",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kyodo",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Abe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "NHK",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "NHK",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "two",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Abe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Abe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "two",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Japan",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "2020",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Liberal Democratic party",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "LDP",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "one",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Fumio Kishida",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sunday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Abe",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Abe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "years",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "2014",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "first",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "World War Two",
            "label": "EVENT"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "The following year",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the Self-Defense Forces",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Japan",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Article 9",
            "label": "LAW"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the 2020",
            "label": "EVENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "Olympics",
            "label": "EVENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "Tokyo",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Games",
            "label": "EVENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "a year to 2021",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Abe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "2006",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Japan",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "World War Two",
            "label": "EVENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "a year",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Abe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Abe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "ජපානයේ හිටපු අගමැති ෂින්සෝ අබේ වෙඩි තැබීමකින් තුවාල ලබා තිබේ",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "ජපාන හිටපු අගමැති ෂින්සෝ අබේ සිකුරාදා බටහිර නාරා නගරයේ දේශනයක් පවත්වමින් සිටියදී තුවක්කුවක් අතැතිව සිටි පුද්ගලයෙකුගේ පිටුපසින් වෙඩි තැබීමෙන් පසු රෝහල් ගත කළ බව මහජන විකාශක එන්එච්කේ පැවසීය.",
        "67 හැවිරිදි අබේ, හෘදයාබාධයකට ලක්ව සිටින බව පෙනී ගිය බව ජාලය සහ Kyodo ප්‍රවෘත්ති ඒජන්සිය පවසයි. අබේ දුම්රිය ස්ථානයකින් පිටත මැතිවරණ ප්‍රචාරක කඳේ කතාවක් කරන විට වෙඩි හඬ ඇසුණු අතර සුදු පැහැති දුමාරයක් දිස් වූ බව එන්එච්කේ පැවසීය.",
        "එම ස්ථානයේ සිටි එන්එච්කේ වාර්තාකරුවෙකු පැවසුවේ අබේගේ කතාව අතරතුර ඔවුන්ට පිට පිට පිපිරුම් දෙකක් ඇසෙන බවයි.",
        "2020 දී අයහපත් සෞඛ්‍ය තත්ත්වයක් හේතුවෙන් ඉල්ලා අස්වීමට පෙර අබේ ජපානයේ දීර්ඝතම අගමැති ධුරයට පත් වීමට අගමැති ලෙස වාර දෙකක් සේවය කළේය.",
        "එහෙත් ඔහු එහි ප්‍රධාන කන්ඩායමක් පාලනය කරමින් පාලක ලිබරල් ඩිමොක්‍රටික් පක්ෂය (එල්ඩීපී) පක්ෂයට වඩා ප්‍රමුඛ පැවැත්මක් ලෙස පවතී.",
        "ඔහුගේ අනුගාමිකයෙකු වන අගමැති ෆුමියෝ කිෂිඩා ඉරිදා ඉහළ මන්ත්‍රී මැතිවරනයකට මුහුණ දෙයි, විශ්ලේෂකයින් පවසන්නේ ඔහු අබේගේ සෙවනැල්ලෙන් මතු වී ඔහුගේ අගමැතිකම නිර්වචනය කිරීමට බලාපොරොත්තු වන බවයි.",
        "Abe වඩාත් ප්‍රසිද්ධියට පත්ව ඇත්තේ ඔහුගේ අත්සන සහිත “Abenomics” ප්‍රතිපත්තියේ නිර්භීත මුදල් ලිහිල් කිරීම් සහ මූල්‍ය වියදම් සඳහා ය.",
        "වසර ගණනාවක පසුබෑමෙන් පසු ඔහු ආරක්ෂක වියදම් ශක්තිමත් කළ අතර විදේශයන්හි බලය ප්‍රක්ෂේපණය කිරීමට හමුදාවට ඇති හැකියාව පුළුල් කළේය.",
        "2014 හි ඓතිහාසික මාරුවකදී, ඔහුගේ ආන්ඩුව දෙවන ලෝක යුද්ධයෙන් පසු පළමු වතාවට හමුදාවන්ට විදේශයන්හි සටන් කිරීමට ඉඩ සලසන පශ්චාත් යුධ, සාමවාදී ව්‍යවස්ථාව නැවත අර්ථකථනය කළේය.",
        "ඊළඟ වසරේ, නීති සම්පාදනය මගින් සාමූහික ආත්මාරක්ෂාව පිළිබඳ අයිතිය ක්‍රියාත්මක කිරීම හෝ ප්‍රහාරයට ලක් වූ මිත්‍ර රටක් ආරක්ෂා කිරීම තහනම් කරන ලදී.",
        "කෙසේ වෙතත්, අබේ, ජපානයේ මිලිටරිය ලෙස හැඳින්වෙන ස්වයං-ආරක්ෂක බලකායන් සාමවාදී 9 වැනි වගන්තියට ලිවීමෙන් එක්සත් ජනපද කෙටුම්පත් කරන ලද ව්‍යවස්ථාව සංශෝධනය කිරීමේ ඔහුගේ දිගුකාලීන ඉලක්කය සපුරා ගත්තේ නැත.",
        "COVID-19 වසංගතය හේතුවෙන් 2021 දක්වා වසරකින් කල් දැමූ ක්‍රීඩා උළෙලේ මුලසුන දැරීමේ ආශාව අගය කරමින් ඔහු ටෝකියෝ සඳහා 2020 ඔලිම්පික් උළෙල ජයග්‍රහණය කිරීමට ප්‍රධාන විය.",
        "දෙවන ලෝක යුද්ධයෙන් පසු ජපානයේ ලාබාලතම අගමැති ලෙස අබේ ප්‍රථම වරට 2006 දී බලයට පත් විය. දේශපාලන අපකීර්තිය, නැතිවූ විශ්‍රාම වැටුප් වාර්තා පිළිබඳ ඡන්දදායකයින්ගේ කෝපය සහ ඔහුගේ පාලක පක්ෂයට මැතිවරණයකින් පරාජයට පත්වීමෙන් වසරකට පසු, අබේ අසනීප බව පවසමින් ඉල්ලා අස්විය.",
        "අබේ විදේශ ඇමති පියෙකු සහ අගමැති ලෙස කටයුතු කළ ලොකු මාමා ඇතුළු ධනවත් දේශපාලන පවුලකින් පැවත එන්නකි."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ජපන්",
          "label": "NORP"
        },
        {
          "text": "Shinzo Abe",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ජපන්",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Shinzo Abe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "සිකුරාදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "නාරා",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "අබේ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "67",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "කියෝඩෝ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "අබේ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "එන්එච්කේ",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "එන්එච්කේ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "දෙක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "අබේ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "අබේ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "දෙක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජපානය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "2020",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ලිබරල් ඩිමොක්‍රටික් පක්ෂය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "LDP",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "එක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Fumio Kishida",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉරිදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "අබේ",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "අබේ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "වසර",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "2014",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "පළමුවන",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "දෙවන ලෝක යුද්ධය",
            "label": "EVENT"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "පහත සඳහන් වසරේ",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ස්වයං ආරක්ෂක බලකායන්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජපානය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "9 වැනි වගන්තිය",
            "label": "LAW"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "2020",
            "label": "EVENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඔලිම්පික්",
            "label": "EVENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "ටෝකියෝ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ක්රීඩා",
            "label": "EVENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "2021ට අවුරුද්දක්",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "අබේ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "2006",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජපානය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "දෙවන ලෝක යුද්ධය",
            "label": "EVENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "අවුරුද්දක්",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "අබේ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "අබේ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "ஜப்பான் முன்னாள் பிரதமர் ஷின்சோ அபே துப்பாக்கிச் சூட்டில் காயமடைந்தார்",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "ஜப்பானின் முன்னாள் பிரதமர் ஷின்சோ அபே வெள்ளிக்கிழமையன்று மேற்கு நகரமான நாராவில் உரை நிகழ்த்திக் கொண்டிருந்தபோது துப்பாக்கியால் சுடப்பட்ட ஒரு நபரால் சுடப்பட்டதால் மருத்துவமனைக்கு அழைத்துச் செல்லப்பட்டார் என்று பொது ஒளிபரப்பு NHK தெரிவித்துள்ளது.",
        "67 வயதான அபே, மாரடைப்பு நிலையில் இருப்பதாகத் தெரிகிறது என்று நெட்வொர்க் மற்றும் கியோடோ செய்தி நிறுவனம் தெரிவித்துள்ளது. அபே ஒரு ரயில் நிலையத்திற்கு வெளியே பிரச்சார ஸ்டம்ப் உரையை நிகழ்த்தியபோது துப்பாக்கிச் சூட்டுச் சத்தம் கேட்டது மற்றும் வெண்மையான புகை மூட்டம் காணப்பட்டது என்று NHK தெரிவித்துள்ளது.",
        "அபேயின் உரையின் போது தொடர்ச்சியாக இரண்டு சத்தம் கேட்டதாக சம்பவ இடத்தில் இருந்த NHK செய்தியாளர் கூறினார்.",
        "உடல்நலக்குறைவைக் காரணம் காட்டி 2020 இல் பதவி விலகுவதற்கு முன்பு அபே இரண்டு முறை பிரதமராகப் பதவி வகித்தார்.",
        "ஆனால் அவர் ஆளும் லிபரல் டெமாக்ரடிக் கட்சி (LDP) கட்சியின் மேலாதிக்க முன்னிலையில் இருந்து, அதன் முக்கிய பிரிவுகளில் ஒன்றைக் கட்டுப்படுத்துகிறார்.",
        "அவரது ஆதரவாளரான பிரதம மந்திரி ஃபுமியோ கிஷிடா, ஞாயிற்றுக்கிழமை ஒரு மேல்சபைத் தேர்தலை எதிர்கொள்கிறார், அதில் அவர் அபேயின் நிழலில் இருந்து வெளிப்பட்டு தனது பிரதமர் பதவியை வரையறுப்பார் என்று ஆய்வாளர்கள் கூறுகின்றனர்.",
        "அபே தனது கையொப்பமான \"அபெனோமிக்ஸ்\" கொள்கையில் தைரியமான பணமதிப்பு நீக்கம் மற்றும் நிதிச் செலவினங்களுக்காக மிகவும் பிரபலமானவர்.",
        "அவர் பல வருடங்கள் சரிவுக்குப் பிறகு பாதுகாப்பு செலவினங்களை உயர்த்தினார் மற்றும் வெளிநாட்டில் அதிகாரத்தை வெளிப்படுத்தும் இராணுவத்தின் திறனை விரிவுபடுத்தினார்.",
        "2014 இல் ஒரு வரலாற்று மாற்றத்தில், இரண்டாம் உலகப் போருக்குப் பிறகு முதன்முறையாக துருப்புக்கள் வெளிநாடுகளில் சண்டையிட அனுமதிக்கும் வகையில், போருக்குப் பிந்தைய, அமைதிவாத அரசியலமைப்பை அவரது அரசாங்கம் மறுபரிசீலனை செய்தது.",
        "அடுத்த ஆண்டு, கூட்டுத் தற்காப்பு உரிமையைப் பயன்படுத்துவதற்கு அல்லது தாக்குதலுக்கு உள்ளான நட்பு நாட்டைப் பாதுகாப்பதற்கான தடையை சட்டம் முடிவுக்குக் கொண்டு வந்தது.",
        "எவ்வாறாயினும், ஜப்பானின் இராணுவம் என்று அறியப்பட்ட தற்காப்புப் படைகளை அமைதிவாதப் பிரிவு 9 இல் எழுதுவதன் மூலம் அமெரிக்க-வரைவு அரசியலமைப்பை திருத்தும் தனது நீண்டகால இலக்கை அபே அடையவில்லை.",
        "டோக்கியோவுக்கான 2020 ஒலிம்பிக்கை வெல்வதில் அவர் முக்கியப் பங்காற்றினார், கோவிட்-19 தொற்றுநோய் காரணமாக ஒரு வருடம் 2021 க்கு ஒத்திவைக்கப்பட்ட விளையாட்டுப் போட்டிகளுக்குத் தலைமை தாங்க வேண்டும் என்ற விருப்பத்தை விரும்பினார்.",
        "இரண்டாம் உலகப் போருக்குப் பிறகு ஜப்பானின் இளைய பிரதமராக அபே முதன்முதலில் 2006 இல் பதவியேற்றார். அரசியல் ஊழல்கள், தொலைந்து போன ஓய்வூதியப் பதிவுகள் மற்றும் தேர்தல் தோல்வி ஆகியவற்றால் பாதிக்கப்பட்ட ஒரு வருடத்திற்குப் பிறகு, அபே உடல்நலக்குறைவு காரணமாக பதவி விலகினார்.",
        "அபே ஒரு பணக்கார அரசியல் குடும்பத்தைச் சேர்ந்தவர், அதில் வெளியுறவு மந்திரி தந்தை மற்றும் பிரதமராக பணியாற்றிய பெரிய மாமா ஆகியோர் அடங்குவர்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ஜப்பானியர்",
          "label": "NORP"
        },
        {
          "text": "Shinzo Abe",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ஜப்பானியர்",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Shinzo Abe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "வெள்ளி",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "நாரா",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "அபே",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "67",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "கியோடோ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "அபே",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "NHK",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "NHK",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இரண்டு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "அபே",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "அபே",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இரண்டு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜப்பான்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "2020",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "லிபரல் டெமாக்ரடிக் கட்சி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "எல்டிபி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஒன்று",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Fumio Kishida",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஞாயிற்றுக்கிழமை",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "அபே",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "அபே",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஆண்டுகள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "2014",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "முதலில்",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "இரண்டாம் உலக போர்",
            "label": "EVENT"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "அடுத்த ஆண்டு",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "தற்காப்புப் படைகள்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜப்பான்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "கட்டுரை 9",
            "label": "LAW"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "2020",
            "label": "EVENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஒலிம்பிக்",
            "label": "EVENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "டோக்கியோ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "விளையாட்டுகள்",
            "label": "EVENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "2021 க்கு ஒரு வருடம்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "அபே",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "2006",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜப்பான்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இரண்டாம் உலக போர்",
            "label": "EVENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஒரு வருடம்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "அபே",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "அபே",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}