{
  "newspaper_id": "daily-ft-lk",
  "url": "https://www.ft.lk/news/AmCham-SL-and-Habitat-for-Humanity-join-hands-for-Humanitarian-Emergency-Relief-mission/56-738549",
  "time_ut": 1660178731,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "AmCham SL and Habitat for Humanity join hands for Humanitarian Emergency Relief mission",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "AmCham SL and Habitat for Humanity join hands for Humanitarian Emergency Relief mission",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "US Ambassador Julie J. Chung, AmCham SL and several individual donors present a cheque of Rs. 5 million towards the Humanitarian Emergency Relief Program (H-ERP) to Habitat for Humanity Sri Lanka",
        "US Ambassador Julie J. Chung distributes a pack of dry food rations to a deserving family of the Nayanalokagama village",
        "AmCham SL President Lakshan Madurasinghe distributes a pack of dry food rations to a deserving family of the Nayanalokagama village",
        "Michael Perera distributes a pack of dry food rations to a deserving family of the Nayanalokagama village",
        "US Ambassador to Sri Lanka Julie J. Chung inaugurated the emergency food distribution program launched by Habitat for Humanity Sri Lanka and the American Chamber of Commerce Sri Lanka (AmCham SL), at the Nayanalokagama village in Katana, Negombo, on 22 July. The Nayanalokagama village is considered the only dedicated village for visually impaired persons in the South Asian region and has been a part of Habitat for Humanity Sri Lanka’s housing assistance projects in recent years.",
        "The ‘Humanitarian Emergency Relief Program’, which is Habitat for Humanity’s humanitarian relief response to assist vulnerable and marginalised communities severely impacted by Sri Lanka’s worst economic crisis, aims to provide essential dry food rations to identified families for a period of two months initially. The inaugural program in the village of Nayanalokagama, saw 100 families receive the food rations from Ambassador Julie Chung, and several donors who were present at the event.",
        "Speaking at the inaugural event, Ambassador Chung said, “Sri Lanka is in the middle of one of the greatest economic crises it has ever experienced. Long power outages, as well as significant shortages of food, medication, fuel, and other essential necessities are generally affecting its 22 million people. Understanding the need of the hour, projects such as the Humanitarian Emergency Relief Program are crucial in supporting the many vulnerable families across the country, and we are committed to supporting such initiatives.” She concluded by encouraging the beneficiaries and assuring them of the support and friendship of the US business community in Sri Lanka.",
        "District Secretary Gampaha W.S. Sathyananda, speaking at the inauguration stated that the timely intervention of Habitat Sri Lanka and AmCham SL, is laudable and a great benefit to the poor and the low-income segments of society in the district and fulfils a great need which the government is unable to meet in its entirety in the present situation of the country.",
        "AmCham SL Secretariat General Manager and Head Vrai Raymond expressing her views said, “While AmCham SL is primarily a business organisation that works closely with the Sri Lankan private sector to enhance bilateral trade and commerce with the US, social responsibility is at the heart of the organisation, and we are therefore honoured to partner with Habitat for Humanity Sri Lanka to stand with those vulnerable fellow Sri Lankans in navigating the current crisis.” She noted that the donation of Rs. 5 million towards the first phase of this program was made possible by AmCham members, partners and well-wishers both here and across the globe, including several Sri Lankan cricketers, and gratefully acknowledged their contributions.",
        "Speaking at the event, Habitat for Humanity Sri Lanka National Director Yu Hwa Li commented, “We firmly believe that this is a timely and a much-needed intervention, with many vulnerable families unable to meet their basic needs amidst this crisis. Our goal is to provide sufficient quantities of dry food sufficient for two months to these families and together with AmCham SL, we look forward to continuing this initiative in several other districts in Sri Lanka, as well as extending the duration of the program if we are able to.”",
        "Associated at the event were US Mission in Colombo Head of the Economic Unit Phillip Loosli, Divisional Secretary Katana Priyanka Kodithuwakku, AmCham SL President Lakshan Madurasinghe, and several individual donors to the Humanitarian Emergency Relief Program initiative, including Mr. and Mrs. Dilum Chandrasoma and Michael Perera."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Humanitarian",
          "label": "NORP"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "US",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Julie J. Chung",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "AmCham SL",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Rs",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "5 million",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Humanitarian Emergency Relief Program",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "H-ERP",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Habitat for Humanity Sri Lanka",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "US",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Julie J. Chung",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Lakshan Madurasinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Michael Perera",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "US",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "Julie J. Chung",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Habitat for Humanity Sri Lanka",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the American Chamber of Commerce Sri Lanka",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "AmCham SL",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Katana",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Negombo",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "22 July",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "South Asian",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Habitat for Humanity Sri Lanka’s",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "recent years",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Habitat",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka’s",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "a period of two months",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Nayanalokagama",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "100",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Julie Chung",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Chung",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "22 million",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Humanitarian Emergency Relief Program",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "US",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Gampaha W.S. Sathyananda",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Habitat Sri Lanka",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "AmCham SL",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "AmCham SL Secretariat General",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Vrai Raymond",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "While AmCham SL",
            "label": "WORK_OF_ART"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lankan",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "US",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Habitat for Humanity Sri Lanka",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lankans",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "5 million",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "first",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "AmCham",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lankan",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Yu Hwa Li",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "two months",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "AmCham SL",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Phillip Loosli",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Divisional",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Katana Priyanka Kodithuwakku",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Lakshan Madurasinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Humanitarian Emergency Relief Program",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Dilum Chandrasoma",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Michael Perera",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "AmCham SL සහ Habitat for Humanity මානුෂීය හදිසි සහන මෙහෙයුම සඳහා අත්වැල් බැඳගනී",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "එක්සත් ජනපද තානාපතිනි Julie J. Chung, AmCham SL සහ තනි පුද්ගල පරිත්‍යාගශීලීන් කිහිප දෙනෙකු විසින් රු. මානුෂීය හදිසි සහන වැඩසටහන (H-ERP) සඳහා Habitat for Humanity Sri Lanka වෙත මිලියන 5ක්",
        "නයනාලෝකගම ගම්මානයේ සුදුසු පවුලකට වියළි ආහාර සලාක පැකට්ටුවක් බෙදාදීම අමෙරිකානු තානාපතිනී ජුලී ජේ.චුන්ග් අතින්.",
        "AmCham SL සභාපති ලක්ෂාන් මධුරසිංහ මහතා අතින් නයනාලෝකගම ගම්මානයේ සුදුසු පවුලකට වියළි ආහාර සලාක පැකට්ටුවක් බෙදා දෙයි",
        "නයනාලෝකගම ගම්මානයේ සුදුසු පවුලකට මයිකල් පෙරේරා මහතා වියළි ආහාර සලාකයක් බෙදා දෙයි",
        "Habitat for Humanity Sri Lanka සහ American Chamber of Commerce Sri Lanka (AmCham SL) විසින් දියත් කරන ලද හදිසි ආහාර බෙදා හැරීමේ වැඩසටහන ජුලි 22 වන දින මීගමුව කටාන නයනාලෝකගම ගම්මානයේ දී ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ එක්සත් ජනපද තානාපතිනී Julie J. Chung විසින් ආරම්භ කරන ලදී. නයනාලෝකගම ගම්මානය දකුණු ආසියානු කලාපයේ දෘෂ්‍යාබාධිත පුද්ගලයන් සඳහා වෙන්වූ එකම ගම්මානය ලෙස සැලකෙන අතර මෑත වසරවලදී Habitat for Humanity Sri Lanka හි නිවාස ආධාර ව්‍යාපෘතිවල කොටසක් ද වේ.",
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ දරුණුතම ආර්ථික අර්බුදයෙන් දැඩි ලෙස පීඩාවට පත් වූ අවදානමට ලක්විය හැකි සහ ආන්තික ප්‍රජාවන්ට උපකාර කිරීම සඳහා මනුෂ්‍යත්වයේ මානුෂීය සහන ප්‍රතිචාර සඳහා වාසස්ථානය වන ‘මානුෂීය හදිසි සහන වැඩසටහන’ මූලික වශයෙන් මාස දෙකක කාලයක් හඳුනාගත් පවුල් සඳහා අත්‍යවශ්‍ය වියළි ආහාර සලාක ලබා දීම අරමුණු කරයි. නයනාලෝකගම ගම්මානයේ පැවති සමාරම්භක වැඩසටහනේදී පවුල් 100 කට මෙම ආහාර සලාක ලබා දුන්නේ තානාපතිනි ජුලී චුන්ග් මහත්මිය ඇතුළු පරිත්‍යාගශීලීන් කිහිප දෙනෙකු විසිනි.",
        "සමාරම්භක උත්සවයේදී අදහස් දැක්වූ තානාපති චුන්ග් මහතා, “ශ්‍රී ලංකාව මෙතෙක් අත්විඳින ලද දැවැන්තම ආර්ථික අර්බුදයකට මැදිව සිටී. දිගු විදුලිය ඇනහිටීම් මෙන්ම ආහාර, ඖෂධ, ඉන්ධන සහ අනෙකුත් අත්‍යවශ්‍ය අවශ්‍යතාවල සැලකිය යුතු හිඟයක් සාමාන්‍යයෙන් එහි මිලියන 22 ක ජනතාව කෙරෙහි බලපායි. කාලීන අවශ්‍යතාවය අවබෝධ කර ගනිමින්, මානුෂීය හදිසි සහන වැඩසටහන වැනි ව්‍යාපෘති රට පුරා විපතට පත් පවුල් රැසකට ආධාර කිරීමේදී ඉතා වැදගත් වන අතර, එවැනි මුලපිරීම් සඳහා සහය දැක්වීමට අපි කැපවී සිටිමු. ඇය අවසන් කළේ ප්‍රතිලාභීන් දිරිමත් කරමින් ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ එක්සත් ජනපද ව්‍යාපාරික ප්‍රජාවේ සහයෝගය සහ මිත්‍රත්වය ඔවුන්ට සහතික කරමිනි.",
        "ගම්පහ දිස්ත්‍රික් ලේකම් ඩබ්ලිව්. සත්‍යානන්ද මහතා සමාරම්භක අවස්ථාවට එක්වෙමින් ප්‍රකාශ කළේ Habitat Sri Lanka සහ AmCham SL හි කාලීන මැදිහත්වීම ප්‍රශංසනීය බවත් දිස්ත්‍රික්කයේ දිළිඳු සහ අඩු ආදායම්ලාභී කොටස් සඳහා විශාල ප්‍රතිලාභයක් ලබා දෙන බවත් රජයට කළ නොහැකි විශාල අවශ්‍යතාවයක් ඉටු කරන බවත්ය. රටේ වත්මන් තත්ත්වය තුළ සම්පූර්ණයෙන්ම හමුවන්න.",
        "AmCham ශ්‍රී ලංකා මහලේකම් කාර්යාලයේ සාමාන්‍යාධිකාරී සහ ප්‍රධානී Vrai Raymond මහත්මිය අදහස් දක්වමින් කියා සිටියේ, \"AmCham SL යනු මූලික වශයෙන් එක්සත් ජනපදය සමඟ ද්විපාර්ශ්වික වෙළඳාම සහ වාණිජ්‍යය වැඩිදියුණු කිරීම සඳහා ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ පුද්ගලික අංශය සමඟ සමීපව කටයුතු කරන ව්‍යාපාරික සංවිධානයක් වන අතර, සමාජ වගකීම එහි හදවතේ පවතී. සංවිධානය වන අතර, එබැවින් වත්මන් අර්බුදයේ සැරිසැරීමේදී එම අවදානමට ලක්විය හැකි සෙසු ශ්‍රී ලාංකිකයන් සමඟ සිටීමට Habitat for Humanity Sri Lanka සමඟ හවුල් වීමට ලැබීම අපට ගෞරවයක්.” රුපියල් 1000 ක පරිත්‍යාගයක් ලබා දුන් බව ඇය සඳහන් කළාය. මෙම වැඩසටහනේ පළමු අදියර සඳහා මිලියන 5ක් ශ්‍රී ලංකා ක්‍රිකට් ක්‍රීඩකයින් ඇතුළු ලොව පුරා සිටින AmCham සාමාජිකයින්, හවුල්කරුවන් සහ සුභ පතන්නන් විසින් ලබා දීමට හැකි වූ අතර ඔවුන්ගේ දායකත්වය කෘතඥපූර්වකව පිළිගත්තේය.",
        "මෙම අවස්ථාවට අදහස් දක්වමින් Habitat for Humanity Sri Lanka ජාතික අධ්‍යක්ෂ Yu Hwa Li අදහස් දක්වමින්, “මෙම අර්බුද මධ්‍යයේ බොහෝ අවදානමට ලක්වන පවුල්වලට තම මූලික අවශ්‍යතා සපුරා ගැනීමට නොහැකිව සිටින මෙය කාලෝචිත සහ අත්‍යවශ්‍ය මැදිහත්වීමක් බව අපි තරයේ විශ්වාස කරමු. මෙම පවුල් සඳහා මාස දෙකකට ප්‍රමාණවත් වියළි ආහාර ප්‍රමාණවත් ප්‍රමාණයක් ලබා දීම අපගේ අරමුණ වන අතර AmCham SL සමඟ එක්ව ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ තවත් දිස්ත්‍රික්ක කිහිපයක මෙම වැඩසටහන අඛණ්ඩව ක්‍රියාත්මක කිරීමටත්, අප සිටී නම් වැඩසටහනේ කාලසීමාව දීර්ඝ කිරීමටත් අපි බලාපොරොත්තු වෙමු. හැකි.\"",
        "මෙම අවස්ථාවට සම්බන්ධ වුයේ කොළඹ එක්සත් ජනපද දූත මණ්ඩල ආර්ථික ඒකකයේ ප්‍රධානී පිලිප් ලූස්ලි, ප්‍රාදේශීය ලේකම් කටාන ප්‍රියංක කොඩිතුවක්කු, ඇම්චෑම් ශ්‍රී ලංකා සභාපති ලක්ෂාන් මධුරසිංහ, දිලුම් චන්ද්‍රසෝම සහ එම මහත්මිය ඇතුළු මානුෂීය හදිසි සහන වැඩසටහන සඳහා තනි පුද්ගල පරිත්‍යාගශීලීන් කිහිප දෙනෙකි. මයිකල් පෙරේරා."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "මානුෂීය",
          "label": "NORP"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "එක්සත් ජනපදය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජුලී ජේ චුං",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "AmCham SL",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "රුපියල්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "මිලියන 5 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "මානුෂීය හදිසි සහන වැඩසටහන",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "H-ERP",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "මනුෂ්‍යත්වය සඳහා වාසස්ථානය ශ්‍රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "එක්සත් ජනපදය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජුලී ජේ චුං",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ලක්ෂාන් මධුරසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "මයිකල් පෙරේරා",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "එක්සත් ජනපදය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජුලී ජේ චුං",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "මනුෂ්‍යත්වය සඳහා වාසස්ථානය ශ්‍රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකා ඇමරිකානු වාණිජ මණ්ඩලය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "AmCham SL",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "කටාන",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මීගමුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "22 ජූලි",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "දකුණු ආසියානු",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ මනුෂ්‍යත්වය සඳහා වාසස්ථානය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "පසුගිය වසරවල",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "වාසස්ථාන",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මාස දෙකක කාලයක්",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "නයනාලෝකගම",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "100",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජූලි චුන්ග්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "චුන්ග්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "මිලියන 22 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "මානුෂීය හදිසි සහන වැඩසටහන",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "එක්සත් ජනපදය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ගම්පහ ඩබ්ලිව්.එස්. සත්‍යානන්දයි",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "වාසස්ථාන ශ්‍රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "AmCham SL",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "AmCham SL මහලේකම් කාර්යාලය",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Vrai රේමන්ඩ්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "අතර AmCham SL",
            "label": "WORK_OF_ART"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලාංකික",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "එක්සත් ජනපදය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මනුෂ්‍යත්වය සඳහා වාසස්ථානය ශ්‍රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලාංකිකයන්",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "මිලියන 5 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "පළමුවන",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඇම්චෑම්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලාංකික",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Yu Hwa Li",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "මාස දෙකක්",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "AmCham SL",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "පිලිප් ලූස්ලි",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "කොට්ඨාශ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "කටාන ප්‍රියංකා කොඩිතුවක්කු",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ලක්ෂාන් මධුරසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "මානුෂීය හදිසි සහන වැඩසටහන",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "දිලුම් චන්ද්‍රසෝම",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "මයිකල් පෙරේරා",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "மனிதாபிமான அவசரகால நிவாரண பணிக்காக AmCham SL மற்றும் Habitat for Humanity ஆகியவை கைகோர்க்கின்றன",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "அமெரிக்கத் தூதுவர் ஜூலி ஜே. சுங், AmCham SL மற்றும் பல தனிப்பட்ட நன்கொடையாளர்கள் ரூ. மனிதநேய அவசரகால நிவாரணத் திட்டத்திற்கு (H-ERP) 5 மில்லியன் மனிதநேய இலங்கைக்கான வாழ்விடம்",
        "அமெரிக்கத் தூதுவர் ஜூலி ஜே. சுங், நயனலோககம கிராமத்தைச் சேர்ந்த தகுதியான குடும்பத்திற்கு உலர் உணவுப் பொதியை விநியோகித்தார்.",
        "AmCham SL தலைவர் லக்ஷான் மதுரசிங்கவினால் நயனலோககம கிராமத்தின் தகுதியான குடும்பத்திற்கு உலர் உணவுப் பொதி விநியோகம்",
        "நயனலோககம கிராமத்தின் தகுதியான குடும்பத்திற்கு உலர் உணவுப் பொதியை மைக்கல் பெரேரா வழங்கினார்.",
        "Habitat for Humanity Sri Lanka மற்றும் American Chamber of Commerce Sri Lanka (AmCham SL) ஆகியவற்றால் ஆரம்பிக்கப்பட்ட அவசரகால உணவு விநியோகத் திட்டத்தை இலங்கைக்கான அமெரிக்கத் தூதுவர் ஜூலி ஜே.சுங் ஜூலை 22 அன்று நீர்கொழும்பு, கட்டானாவில் உள்ள நயனலோககம கிராமத்தில் ஆரம்பித்து வைத்தார். நயனலோககம கிராமம் தெற்காசியப் பிராந்தியத்தில் பார்வையற்றோருக்கான ஒரே அர்ப்பணிக்கப்பட்ட கிராமமாகக் கருதப்படுகிறது மற்றும் அண்மைய வருடங்களில் ஹபிடேட் ஃபார் ஹுமானிட்டி ஸ்ரீலங்காவின் வீடமைப்பு உதவித் திட்டங்களின் ஒரு பகுதியாக இருந்து வருகிறது.",
        "இலங்கையின் மிக மோசமான பொருளாதார நெருக்கடியினால் கடுமையாகப் பாதிக்கப்பட்டுள்ள பாதிக்கப்படக்கூடிய மற்றும் ஒதுக்கப்பட்ட சமூகங்களுக்கு உதவுவதற்காக மனிதநேயத்தின் மனிதாபிமான நிவாரணப் பதிலளிப்பதற்கான வாழ்விடமான ‘மனிதாபிமான அவசரகால நிவாரணத் திட்டம்’, இரண்டு மாத காலத்திற்கு அடையாளம் காணப்பட்ட குடும்பங்களுக்கு அத்தியாவசிய உலர் உணவுப் பொருட்களை வழங்குவதை நோக்கமாகக் கொண்டுள்ளது. நயனலோககம கிராமத்தில் ஆரம்பமான நிகழ்வில் 100 குடும்பங்கள் தூதர் ஜூலி சுங் மற்றும் நிகழ்வில் கலந்துகொண்ட பல நன்கொடையாளர்களிடமிருந்து உணவுப் பொருட்களைப் பெற்றுக்கொண்டனர்.",
        "தொடக்க நிகழ்வில் உரையாற்றிய தூதுவர் சுங், “இலங்கை இதுவரை சந்தித்திராத மிகப் பெரிய பொருளாதார நெருக்கடியின் மத்தியில் உள்ளது. நீண்ட கால மின்வெட்டு, அத்துடன் உணவு, மருந்து, எரிபொருள் மற்றும் பிற அத்தியாவசிய தேவைகளின் குறிப்பிடத்தக்க பற்றாக்குறை பொதுவாக அதன் 22 மில்லியன் மக்களை பாதிக்கிறது. காலத்தின் தேவையைப் புரிந்துகொண்டு, மனிதாபிமான அவசரகால நிவாரணத் திட்டம் போன்ற திட்டங்கள், நாடு முழுவதும் பல பாதிப்புக்குள்ளான குடும்பங்களுக்கு ஆதரவளிப்பதில் முக்கியமானவை, மேலும் இதுபோன்ற முயற்சிகளுக்கு ஆதரவளிக்க நாங்கள் கடமைப்பட்டுள்ளோம். பயனாளிகளை ஊக்குவிப்பதன் மூலமும், இலங்கையில் உள்ள அமெரிக்க வர்த்தக சமூகத்தின் ஆதரவையும் நட்புறவையும் அவர்களுக்கு உறுதியளிப்பதன் மூலமும் அவர் முடித்தார்.",
        "மாவட்டச் செயலாளர் கம்பஹா டபிள்யூ.எஸ். சத்தியானந்தா அவர்கள் உரையாற்றுகையில், Habitat Sri Lanka மற்றும் AmCham SL ஆகியவற்றின் சரியான நேரத்தில் தலையீடு பாராட்டத்தக்கது மற்றும் மாவட்டத்தில் உள்ள ஏழை மற்றும் சமூகத்தின் குறைந்த வருமானம் பெறும் பிரிவினருக்கு பெரும் நன்மை மற்றும் அரசாங்கத்தால் செய்ய முடியாத ஒரு பெரிய தேவையை நிறைவேற்றுகிறது. நாட்டின் தற்போதைய சூழ்நிலையில் முழுமையாக சந்திக்கவும்.",
        "AmCham SL செயலகத்தின் பொது முகாமையாளரும் தலைவருமான Vrai Raymond தனது கருத்துக்களைத் தெரிவிக்கையில், “AmCham SL முதன்மையாக அமெரிக்காவுடனான இருதரப்பு வர்த்தகம் மற்றும் வர்த்தகத்தை மேம்படுத்துவதற்காக இலங்கையின் தனியார் துறையுடன் நெருக்கமாகச் செயற்படும் ஒரு வணிக அமைப்பாகும். அமைப்பு, எனவே தற்போதைய நெருக்கடிக்கு வழிசெலுத்துவதில் பாதிக்கப்படக்கூடிய சக இலங்கையர்களுடன் நிற்பதற்கு Habitat for Humanity Sri Lanka உடன் கைகோர்ப்பதை நாங்கள் பெருமையாக கருதுகிறோம். நன்கொடையாக ரூ. இந்த நிகழ்ச்சித்திட்டத்தின் முதற்கட்டமாக 5 மில்லியன் இலங்கை கிரிக்கெட் வீரர்கள் உட்பட இங்கும் உலகெங்கிலும் உள்ள AmCham உறுப்பினர்கள், பங்காளிகள் மற்றும் நலம் விரும்பிகளால் சாத்தியமானது, மேலும் அவர்களின் பங்களிப்பை நன்றியுடன் ஒப்புக்கொண்டது.",
        "நிகழ்வில் பேசிய Habitat for Humanity Sri Lanka தேசிய பணிப்பாளர் Yu Hwa Li கருத்து தெரிவிக்கையில், “இந்த நெருக்கடிக்கு மத்தியில் பல பாதிப்புக்குள்ளான குடும்பங்கள் தமது அடிப்படைத் தேவைகளை பூர்த்தி செய்ய முடியாத நிலையில், இது ஒரு சரியான நேரத்தில் மற்றும் மிகவும் தேவையான தலையீடு என்று நாங்கள் உறுதியாக நம்புகிறோம். இந்த குடும்பங்களுக்கு இரண்டு மாதங்களுக்கு போதுமான உலர் உணவுகளை வழங்குவதே எங்கள் இலக்காகும், மேலும் AmCham SL உடன் இணைந்து, இந்த முயற்சியை இலங்கையின் பல மாவட்டங்களில் தொடரவும், நாங்கள் இருந்தால் திட்டத்தின் காலத்தை நீட்டிக்கவும் நாங்கள் எதிர்நோக்குகிறோம். முடியும்.\"",
        "இந்நிகழ்வில், கொழும்பில் உள்ள அமெரிக்க தூதரகத்தின் பொருளாதாரப் பிரிவின் தலைவர் பிலிப் லூஸ்லி, பிரதேச செயலாளர் கட்டான பிரியங்க கொடித்துவக்கு, AmCham SL தலைவர் லக்ஷான் மதுரசிங்க மற்றும் மனிதாபிமான அவசரகால நிவாரணத் திட்ட முயற்சிக்கு தனிப்பட்ட நன்கொடையாளர்கள் திரு மற்றும் திருமதி திலும் சந்திரசோம உட்பட பலர் கலந்துகொண்டனர். மைக்கேல் பெரேரா."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "மனிதாபிமானம்",
          "label": "NORP"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "எங்களுக்கு",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜூலி ஜே. சுங்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "அம்சாம் எஸ்.எல்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரூ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "5 மில்லியன்",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "மனிதாபிமான அவசர நிவாரணத் திட்டம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "எச்-ஈஆர்பி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "மனிதநேயத்திற்கான வாழ்விடம் இலங்கை",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "எங்களுக்கு",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜூலி ஜே. சுங்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "லக்ஷன் மதுரசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "மைக்கேல் பெரேரா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "எங்களுக்கு",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜூலி ஜே. சுங்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "மனிதநேயத்திற்கான வாழ்விடம் இலங்கை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "அமெரிக்க வர்த்தக சம்மேளனம் இலங்கை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "அம்சாம் எஸ்.எல்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "கட்டானா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "நீர்கொழும்பு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "22 ஜூலை",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "தெற்காசிய",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "மனித நேயத்திற்கான வாழ்விடம் இலங்கை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "சமீபத்திய ஆண்டுகளில்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "வாழ்விடம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கையின்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இரண்டு மாத காலம்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "நயனலோககம",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "100",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜூலி சுங்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "சுங்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "22 மில்லியன்",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "மனிதாபிமான அவசர நிவாரணத் திட்டம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "எங்களுக்கு",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "கம்பஹா டபிள்யூ.எஸ். சத்யானந்தா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "வாழ்விடம் இலங்கை",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "அம்சாம் எஸ்.எல்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "AmCham SL பொதுச் செயலகம்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "வ்ராய் ரேமண்ட்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "அதேசமயம் AmCham SL",
            "label": "WORK_OF_ART"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "எங்களுக்கு",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "மனிதநேயத்திற்கான வாழ்விடம் இலங்கை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கையர்கள்",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "5 மில்லியன்",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "முதலில்",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "AmCham",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Yu Hwa Li",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இரண்டு மாதங்கள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "அம்சாம் எஸ்.எல்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பிலிப் லூஸ்லி",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "பிரிவு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "கட்டான பிரியங்கா கொடித்துவக்கு",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "லக்ஷன் மதுரசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "மனிதாபிமான அவசர நிவாரணத் திட்டம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "திலும் சந்திரசோம",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "மைக்கேல் பெரேரா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}