{
  "newspaper_id": "tamil-mirror-lk",
  "url": "https://www.tamilmirror.lk/செய்திகள்/கையொப்பமிட-ஜனாதிபதி-ரணில்-மறுப்பு/175-303326",
  "time_ut": 1661942521,
  "original_lang": "ta",
  "original_title": "கையொப்பமிட ஜனாதிபதி ரணில் மறுப்பு",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "President Ranil refused to sign",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "Today (31), President Ranil Wickremesinghe announced to the High Court through the Attorney General that he will not sign the execution of the death sentence.",
        "Former President Maithripala Sirisena had decided in 2019 to carry out the sentence of four drug-related convicts sentenced to death.",
        "The fundamental rights petitions filed seeking quashing of the decision were heard by Justices Vijith Mallalkoda, L.D.P. It was taken up for consideration today (31), in the presence of a panel comprising Tehiteniya and Murtu Fernando.",
        "At that time, Additional Solicitor General Nerin Pulle, appearing on behalf of the Attorney General, announced the above decision of President Ranil.",
        "The Additional Solicitor General informed the House that when the Attorney General questioned the President on this matter, the President said that he would not sign the execution of the death sentence.",
        "It was pointed out in the forum that the President had informed the Attorney General to announce his decision when the petitions in this regard are taken up for consideration in the High Court.",
        "The government has taken a decision in principle not to implement the death penalty and there is no change in that decision.",
        "Following this, Justice Vijith Malalkoda informed the petitioners to inform the petitioners in the next session whether there is an opportunity to proceed with the petitions, and fixed February 23 as the date for consideration of the petition."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Ranil",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "31",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the High Court",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Maithripala Sirisena",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "2019",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "four",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "31",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Tehiteniya",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Murtu Fernando",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Additional Solicitor",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Nerin Pulle",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ranil",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "House",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "Vijith Malalkoda",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "February 23",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "ජනාධිපති රනිල් අත්සන් කිරීම ප්‍රතික්ෂේප කළේය",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "මරණීය දණ්ඩනය ක්‍රියාත්මක කිරීමට තමා අත්සන් නොකරන බව අද (31) ජනාධිපති රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතා නීතිපතිවරයා හරහා මහාධිකරණයට දැනුම් දුන්නේය.",
        "මත්ද්‍රව්‍ය ජාවාරමට සම්බන්ධ වරදකරුවන් සිව් දෙනෙකුට මරණ දණ්ඩනය නියම වී ඇති අතර 2019 වසරේ දී එම දඬුවම ක්‍රියාත්මක කිරීමට හිටපු ජනාධිපති මෛත්‍රීපාල සිරිසේන මහතා තීරණය කර තිබුණා.",
        "එම තීන්දුව අවලංගු කරන ලෙස ඉල්ලා ගොනු කර තිබූ මූලික අයිතිවාසිකම් පෙත්සම් විභාගයට ගැනුණේ විජිත් මල්ලල්කොඩ, එල්.ඩී.පී. එය අද (31) සලකා බැලුණේ තෙහිතේණිය සහ මුර්තු ප්‍රනාන්දු යන මහත්ම මහත්මීන්ගෙන් සැදුම්ලත් මණ්ඩලයක් හමුවේයි.",
        "එම අවස්ථාවේදී නීතිපතිවරයා වෙනුවෙන් පෙනී සිටි අතිරේක සොලිසිටර් ජනරාල් නෙරින් පුල්ලේ මහතා ජනාධිපති රනිල්ගේ ඉහත තීරණය ප්‍රකාශ කළේය.",
        "මේ සම්බන්ධයෙන් නීතිපතිවරයා ජනාධිපතිවරයාගෙන් ප්‍රශ්න කළ විට මරණීය දණ්ඩනය ක්‍රියාත්මක කිරීමට තමා අත්සන් නොකරන බව ජනාධිපතිවරයා ප්‍රකාශ කළ බව අතිරේක සොලිසිටර් ජනරාල්වරයා සභාවට දන්වා සිටියේය.",
        "ඊට අදාළ පෙත්සම් මහාධිකරණයේ සළකා බැලීමේදී සිය තීරණය ප්‍රකාශ කරන ලෙස ජනාධිපතිවරයා නීතිපතිවරයාට දැනුම් දී ඇති බව එම සංසදයේදී පෙන්වා දුන්නා.",
        "මරණීය දණ්ඩනය ක්‍රියාත්මක නොකිරීමට රජය ප්‍රතිපත්තිමය තීරණයක් ගෙන ඇති අතර එම තීරණයේ වෙනසක් නොමැත.",
        "ඉන් අනතුරුව පෙත්සම් විභාග කිරීමට අවස්ථාවක් තිබේද යන්න ඉදිරි සැසියේදී පෙත්සම්කරුවන්ට දන්වන ලෙස විනිසුරු විජිත් මලල්කොඩ මහතා පෙත්සම්කරුවන්ට දැනුම් දුන් අතර පෙත්සම සලකා බැලීම සඳහා පෙබරවාරි 23 වැනි දින නියම කළේය."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "රනිල්",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "31",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "මහාධිකරණය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "මෛත්‍රීපාල සිරිසේන",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "2019",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "හතර",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "31",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "තෙහිතේණිය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "මුර්තු ප්‍රනාන්දු",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "අතිරේක සොලිසිටර්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "නෙරින් පුල්ලේ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "රනිල්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "නිවස",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "විජිත් මලල්කොඩ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "පෙබරවාරි 23",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "கையொப்பமிட ஜனாதிபதி ரணில் மறுப்பு",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "மரண தண்டனையை நிறைவேற்றுவதற்கு கையொப்பமிடப் போவதில்லை என்று ஜனாதிபதி ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க, சட்டமா அதிபர் ஊடாக உயர்நீதிமன்றத்துக்கு, இன்று (31) அறிவித்தார்.",
        "போதைப் பொருள் தொடர்பில் மரண தண்டனை விதிக்கப்பட்ட நான்கு குற்றவாளிகளுக்கு தண்டனையை நிறைவேற்றுவதற்கு முன்னாள் ஜனாதிபதி மைத்திரிபால சிறிசேன 2019ஆம் ஆண்டு தீர்மானித்திருந்தார்.",
        "அந்த தீர்மானத்தை இரத்து செயய்யக் கோரி தாக்கல் செய்யப்பட்ட அடிப்படை உரிமைகள் மனுக்கள், நீதியரசர்களான விஜித் மல்லல்கொட, எல்.டி.பி. தெஹிதெனிய மற்றும் முர்து பெர்னாண்டோ ஆகியோரடங்கய குழாம் முன்னிலையில், இன்று (31) பரிசீலனைக்கு எடுத்துக் கொள்ளப்பட்டது.",
        "அதன்போது, சட்டமா அதிபர் சார்பில் ஆஜரான மேலதிக சொலிசிட்டர் ஜெனரல் நெரின் புள்ளே, ஜனாதிபதி ரணிலின் மேற்குறிப்பிட்ட தீர்மானத்தை அறிவித்தார்.",
        "இவ்விடயம் குறித்து, சட்டமா அதிபரால், ஜனாதிபதியிடம் வினவப்பட்ட போது, மரண தண்டனையை நிறைவேற்றுவதற்கு தான் கையெழுத்திடப் போவதில்லை என்று ஜனாதிபதி தெரிவித்தாக மேலதிக சொலிசிட்டர் ஜெனரல் மன்றுக்கு அறிவித்தார்.",
        "இது குறித்த மனுக்கள், உயர்நீதிமன்றத்தில் பரிசீலனைக்கு எடுத்துக் கொள்ளப்படும் போது தனது தீர்மானத்தை அறிவிக்குமாறு, சட்டமா அதிபரிடம் ஜனாதிபதி தெரிவித்ததாகவும் மன்றில் சுட்டிக்காட்டப்பட்டது.",
        "மரண தண்டனையை அமுல்படுத்துவதில்லை என அரசாங்கம் கொள்கை ரீதியில் தீர்மானம் எடுத்துள்ளதாகவும் அந்த தீர்மானத்தில் எந்த மாற்றமும் இல்லை என்றும்",
        "இதனையடுத்து மனுக்களை தொடர்ந்து முன்னெடுத்துச் செல்வதற்கான சந்தர்ப்பம் உள்ளதா என்பது குறித்து அடுத்த அமர்வில் அறிவிக்குமாறு மனுதாரர்களுக்கு அறிவித்த நீதியரசர் விஜித் மலல்கொட, மனு மீதான பரிசீலனைக்கான தினமாக பெப்ரவரி 23ஆம் திகதியை நிர்ணயித்தார்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ரணில்",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "31",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "உயர் நீதிமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "மைத்திரிபால சிறிசேன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "2019",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "நான்கு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "31",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "தெஹிதெனிய",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "முர்து பெர்னாண்டோ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "கூடுதல் வழக்கறிஞர்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "நேரின் புள்ளே",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரணில்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "வீடு",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "விஜித் மலல்கொட",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "பிப்ரவரி 23",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}