{
  "newspaper_id": "lankadeepa-lk",
  "url": "https://www.lankadeepa.lk/latest_news/කළුබෝවිල-රෝහලේ-නාඳුනන-සිරුරු-28ක්/1-618542",
  "time_ut": 1661159199,
  "original_lang": "si",
  "original_title": "කළුබෝවිල රෝහලේ නාඳුනන සිරුරු 28ක්",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "28 unidentified bodies in Kalubowila Hospital",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "It is reported that twenty-eight unidentified corpses have been kept in the mortuary of the Kalubowila Teaching Hospital for nearly a year, and its daily activities have been severely disrupted.",
        "The mortuary of this hospital has 36 cold rooms, but six of them have not been used for two weeks due to non-repair, so daily services have to be provided from thirty cold rooms.",
        "Information sources say that the body parts sent for medical tests in two other cold storage rooms have to be stored, so there are only 28 cold storage rooms left and unidentified bodies have been stored in them.",
        "It is said that in some cases, two or three unidentified corpses have to be stored in one cold room because the corpses of people dying of covid infection have to be buried at the morgue.",
        "Due to this situation, the dead bodies which are brought to this hospital daily from nearby hospitals for expert forensic reports have to be kept outside the cold rooms until the tests are completed and sometimes if the guardians of the deceased are late in coming from far away, the dead bodies are kept outside. It is also said to be extended.",
        "It is said that the main reason for this is that the post-mortem examination of the unidentified dead bodies brought from the police domains of Wellawatta, Mirihana, Piyandala, Homagama, Kaduwela, Welikada, Kottawa, Mount Talangama, Kohuwala, Dehiwala, Boralasgamuwa, was not completed."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "28",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "Kalubowila Hospital",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "twenty-eight",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "nearly a year",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "daily",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "36",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "six",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "two weeks",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "thirty",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "two",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "only 28",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "two",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "three",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "one",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "morgue",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "Wellawatta",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Mirihana",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Piyandala",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Homagama",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kaduwela",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Welikada",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kottawa",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kohuwala",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Dehiwala",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Boralasgamuwa",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "කළුබෝවිල රෝහලේ නාඳුනන සිරුරු 28ක්",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "කළුබෝවිල ශික්ෂණ රෝහලේ මෘත ශරීරාගාරයේ හඳුනා නොගත් මළසිරුරු විසි අටක් වසරකට ආසන්න කාලයක සිට තැන්පත් කර තිබීමෙන් එහි දෛනික කටයුතු වලට දැඩි බාධා එල්ල වී ඇතැයි වාර්තා වේ.",
        "මෙම රෝහලේ මෘත ශරීරාගාරයේ ශීතාගාර 36 ඇතත් ඉන් හයක් සති දෙකක පමණ සිට අළුත්වැඩියා නොකිරීමෙන් භාවිතයට නොගැනීම නිසා ශීතාගාර තිහකින් දෛනික සේවා සැපයීමට සිදු සිදුව තිබේ",
        "ඉන් තවත් ශීතාගාර දෙකක වෛද්‍ය පරීක්ෂණ සඳහා යොමු කෙරෙන ශරීර අවයව කොටස් තැන්පත් කර තැබීමට සිදු ව ඇති බැවින් ඉතිරිව ඇත්තේ ශීතාගාර 28 පමණක් වන අතර ඒවායේ හඳුනා නොගත් මලසිරුරු මෙසේ තැන්පත් කර තැබීමෙන් මෙම තත්ත්වය උදාවී ඇතැයි තතුදත් ආරංචි මාර්ග පවසයි .",
        "මෙහිදී කෝවිඩ් ආසාදිතව මියයන පුද්ගල මළ සිරුරු මෘත ශරීරාගාරයට පැමිණීමේදී ඒවා තැන්පත් කිරීමට පහසුකම් සැලසිය යුතු නිසා ඇතැම් අවස්ථාවලදී හඳුනා නොගත් මළසිරුරු දෙක තුනක් එක ශීතාගාරයක බහා තැබීමට සිදුව ඇතැයි පැවසේ.",
        "මෙවන් තත්ත්වයක් මත විශේෂඥ අධිකරණ වෛද්‍ය වාර්තා සඳහා අවට රෝහල් වලින් මෙම රෝහලට දෛනිකව ගෙන එන මළ සිරුරු පරීක්ෂණ අවසන් වන තෙක් ශීතාගාර වලින් බාහිරව තැබීමට සිදුව ඇති අතර යම් විටෙක මිය ගිය පුද්ගලයාගේ භාරකරුවන් දුර බැහැරක සිට පැමිණීමට ප්‍රමාද වුවහොත් එම මළ සිරුරු එළිමහනේ තැන්පත් කර තැබෙන කාල සීමාව දීර්ඝ වන බව ද පැවසේ.",
        "මීට ප්‍රධානතම හේතුව වී ඇත්තේ වැල්ලවත්ත මිරිහාන පිළියන්දල හෝමාගම කඩුවෙල වැලිකඩ කොට්ටාව ගල්කිස්ස තලංගම කොහුවල දෙහිවල බොරලැස්ගමුව යන පොලිස්වසම්වලින් රැගෙන ආ හඳුනානොගත් මළසිරුරුවල පරීක්ෂණ කටයුතු අවසන් කොට පශ්චාත් මරණ පරීක්ෂණ කටයුතු නොකිරීම බවද පැවසේ ."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "28",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "කළුබෝවිල රෝහල",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "විසි අට",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "වසරකට ආසන්න කාලයක්",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "දිනපතා",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "36",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "හය",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "සති දෙකක්",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "තිස්",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "දෙක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "28 ක් පමණි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "දෙක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "තුන්",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "එක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "මෘත ශරීරාගාරය",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "වැල්ලවත්ත",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මිරිහාන",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "පියන්දල",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Homagama",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "කඩුවෙල",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "වැලිකඩ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kottawa",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "කොහුවල",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "දෙහිවල",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "බොරලස්ගමුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "களுபோவில வைத்தியசாலையில் அடையாளம் தெரியாத 28 சடலங்கள்",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "சுமார் ஒரு வருட காலமாக களுபோவில போதனா வைத்தியசாலையின் பிரேத அறையில் இருபத்தெட்டு இனந்தெரியாத சடலங்கள் வைக்கப்பட்டு அதன் அன்றாட நடவடிக்கைகள் பாரியளவில் பாதிக்கப்பட்டுள்ளதாக தெரிவிக்கப்படுகின்றது.",
        "இவ் வைத்தியசாலையின் பிரேத அறையில் 36 குளிர்சாதன அறைகள் உள்ளன.ஆனால் அதில் 6 அறைகள் பழுதுபார்க்கப்படாமல் இரண்டு வாரங்களாகப் பயன்படுத்தப்படாமல் உள்ளதால் முப்பது குளிர்சாதன அறைகளில் இருந்து தினசரி சேவை வழங்க வேண்டியுள்ளது.",
        "மேலும் இரு குளிர்பதன அறைகளில் மருத்துவ பரிசோதனைக்காக அனுப்பப்பட்ட உடல் உறுப்புகள் சேமிக்கப்பட உள்ளதால், 28 குளிர்பதன அறைகள் மட்டுமே எஞ்சியிருப்பதாகவும், அடையாளம் தெரியாத உடல்கள் அதில் பதுக்கி வைக்கப்பட்டுள்ளதாகவும் தகவல்கள் தெரிவிக்கின்றன.",
        "சில சந்தர்ப்பங்களில், இரண்டு அல்லது மூன்று அடையாளம் தெரியாத சடலங்கள் ஒரு குளிர் அறையில் சேமிக்கப்படும் என்று கூறப்படுகிறது, ஏனெனில் கோவிட் தொற்றுக்கு இறப்பவர்களின் சடலங்களை பிணவறையில் புதைக்க வேண்டும்.",
        "இந்த சூழ்நிலையால், நிபுணர் தடயவியல் அறிக்கைக்காக, சுற்றுப்புற மருத்துவமனைகளில் இருந்து தினமும் இம்மருத்துவமனைக்கு கொண்டு வரப்படும் இறந்தவர்களின் உடல்களை, பரிசோதனை முடியும் வரை குளிர்பதனக் கிடங்குக்கு வெளியே வைக்க வேண்டியுள்ளது. , இறந்த உடல்கள் வெளியில் வைக்கப்பட்டுள்ளன.அது நீட்டிக்கப்படும் என்றும் கூறப்படுகிறது.",
        "வெள்ளவத்தை, மிரிஹான, பியந்தல, ஹோமாகம, கடுவெல, வெலிக்கடை, கொட்டாவ, தலங்கம, கொஹுவளை, தெஹிவளை, பொரலஸ்கமுவ, ஆகிய பொலிஸ் பிரதேசங்களில் இருந்து கொண்டு வரப்பட்ட அடையாளம் தெரியாத சடலங்களின் பிரேத பரிசோதனையே இதற்கு முக்கிய காரணம் என தெரிவிக்கப்படுகிறது. முடிக்கப்படவில்லை."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "28",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "களுபோவில வைத்தியசாலை",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "இருபத்தெட்டு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "கிட்டத்தட்ட ஒரு வருடம்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "தினசரி",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "36",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆறு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "இரண்டு வாரங்கள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "முப்பது",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இரண்டு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "28 மட்டுமே",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இரண்டு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "மூன்று",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஒன்று",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "பிணவறை",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "வெள்ளவத்தை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "மிரிஹானா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "பியந்தலா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Homagama",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "கடுவெல",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "வெலிக்கடை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kottawa",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "கொஹுவாலா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "தெஹிவளை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "பொரலஸ்கமுவ",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}