{
  "newspaper_id": "daily-mirror-lk",
  "url": "https://www.dailymirror.lk/breaking_news/SL-receives-second-consignment-of-humanitarian-supplies-donated-by-India/108-239722",
  "time_ut": 1656060076,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": " SL receives second consignment of humanitarian supplies donated by India",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "SL receives second consignment of humanitarian supplies donated by India",
      "body_lines": [
        "A humanitarian consignment worth Rs. 3 billion consisting of 14,700 MT of rice, 250 MT of milk powder and 38 MT of medicines donated by the people of India was handed over by Indian High Commissioner Gopal Baglay today.",
        "This is the second consignment under a larger commitment of 40,000 MT of rice, 500 MT of milk powder and medicines by the State Government of Tamil Nadu, Indian High Commission said in a statement.",
        "\"India’s unprecedented economic, financial and humanitarian assistance to the people of Sri Lanka stands at over US$ 3.5 billion in 2022. In addition to the three credit lines to the tune of more than US$1.5 billion and Forex support of around US$2 billion assistance from the Government and people of India in the form of supply of medicines to several health-related establishments in various parts of Sri Lanka, distribution of kerosene among the fishermen of Sri Lanka, handing over of dry rations to needy sections etc,\" the statement added."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "SL",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "second",
          "label": "ORDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "India",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "3 billion",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "14,700",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "250",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "38",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "India",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Indian",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Gopal Baglay",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "second",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "40,000",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "500",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "the State Government of Tamil Nadu",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Indian High Commission",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "India",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "over US$ 3.5 billion",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "2022",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "three",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "more than US$1.5 billion",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "Forex",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "around US$2 billion",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "India",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "ඉන්දියාව විසින් පරිත්‍යාග කරන ලද මානුෂීය සැපයුම්වල දෙවන තොගය ශ්‍රී ලංකාවට ලැබේ",
      "body_lines": [
        "රු. ඉන්දීය ජනතාව විසින් පරිත්‍යාග කරන ලද සහල් මෙට්‍රික් ටොන් 14,700 ක්, කිරිපිටි මෙට්‍රික් ටොන් 250 ක් සහ ඖෂධ මෙට්‍රික් ටොන් 38 කින් සමන්විත රුපියල් බිලියන 3 ක් ඉන්දීය මහ කොමසාරිස් ගෝපාල් බග්ලේ විසින් අද භාර දෙන ලදී.",
        "තමිල්නාඩු ප්‍රාන්ත රජය විසින් සහල් මෙට්‍රික් ටොන් 40,000 ක්, කිරිපිටි මෙට්‍රික් ටොන් 500 ක් සහ ඖෂධ වැනි විශාල කැපවීමක් යටතේ නිකුත් කරන ලද දෙවැනි තොගය මෙය බව ඉන්දීය මහ කොමසාරිස් කාර්යාලය නිවේදනයක් නිකුත් කරමින් කියා සිටියේය.",
        "\"ඉන්දියාවේ ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ ජනතාවට පෙර නොවූ විරූ ආර්ථික, මූල්‍ය සහ මානුෂීය ආධාර 2022 දී ඇමරිකානු ඩොලර් බිලියන 3.5 ඉක්මවයි. ණය මාර්ග තුනට අමතරව ඇමරිකානු ඩොලර් බිලියන 1.5 කට වඩා වැඩි මුදලක් සහ විදේශ විනිමය ආධාර ඩොලර් බිලියන 2 ක පමණ ආධාර ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ විවිධ ප්‍රදේශවල සෞඛ්‍ය සම්බන්ධ ආයතන කිහිපයකට ඖෂධ සැපයීම, ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ ධීවරයින් අතර භූමිතෙල් බෙදා හැරීම, අවශ්‍යතා ඇති කොටස් වෙත වියළි සලාක ලබාදීම යනාදී ආකාරයෙන් ඉන්දීය රජයෙන් සහ ජනතාවගෙන්\" එම නිවේදනයේ දැක්වේ. එකතු කළා."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "එස්.එල්",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "දෙවැනි",
          "label": "ORDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "ඉන්දියාව",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "බිලියන 3 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "14,700 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "250",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "38",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දීය",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගෝපාල් බග්ලේ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "දෙවැනි",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "40,000 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "500",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "තමිල්නාඩු ප්‍රාන්ත රජය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දීය මහ කොමසාරිස්",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඇමරිකානු ඩොලර් බිලියන 3.5 කට වඩා",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "2022",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "තුන්",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඇමරිකානු ඩොලර් බිලියන 1.5 කට වඩා වැඩි",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "Forex",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඇමරිකානු ඩොලර් බිලියන 2 ක් පමණ",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "இந்தியாவினால் நன்கொடையாக வழங்கப்பட்ட இரண்டாவது மனிதாபிமானப் பொருட்களை SL பெறுகிறது",
      "body_lines": [
        "ஒரு மனிதாபிமானப் பொருள் ரூ. இந்திய மக்களால் வழங்கப்பட்ட 14,700 மெட்ரிக் டன் அரிசி, 250 மெட்ரிக் டன் பால் பவுடர் மற்றும் 38 மெட்ரிக் டன் மருந்துகள் அடங்கிய 3 பில்லியன் ரூபாயை இந்திய உயர்ஸ்தானிகர் கோபால் பாக்லே இன்று வழங்கினார்.",
        "தமிழ்நாடு மாநில அரசின் 40,000 மெட்ரிக் டன் அரிசி, 500 மெட்ரிக் டன் பால் பவுடர் மற்றும் மருந்துகளின் பெரிய உறுதிப்பாட்டின் கீழ் இது இரண்டாவது சரக்கு என்று இந்திய உயர் ஸ்தானிகராலயம் ஒரு அறிக்கையில் தெரிவித்துள்ளது.",
        "\"இலங்கை மக்களுக்கு இந்தியாவின் முன்னோடியில்லாத பொருளாதார, நிதி மற்றும் மனிதாபிமான உதவி 2022 இல் 3.5 பில்லியன் அமெரிக்க டாலர்களாக உள்ளது. மூன்று கடன் வரிகளுக்கு கூடுதலாக 1.5 பில்லியன் அமெரிக்க டாலர்கள் மற்றும் அந்நிய செலாவணி ஆதரவு சுமார் 2 பில்லியன் அமெரிக்க டாலர்கள். இலங்கையின் பல்வேறு பகுதிகளில் உள்ள சுகாதாரம் தொடர்பான பல நிறுவனங்களுக்கு மருந்துகள் வழங்குதல், இலங்கை மீனவர்களுக்கு மண்ணெண்ணெய் விநியோகம், தேவைப்படும் பிரிவினருக்கு உலர் உணவுகளை வழங்குதல் போன்ற வடிவங்களில் இந்திய அரசு மற்றும் மக்களிடம் இருந்து,\" அந்த அறிக்கையில் கூறப்பட்டுள்ளது. சேர்க்கப்பட்டது."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "எஸ்.எல்",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "இரண்டாவது",
          "label": "ORDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "இந்தியா",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "3 பில்லியன்",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "14,700",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "250",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "38",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்தியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்தியன்",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "கோபால் பாக்லே",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இரண்டாவது",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "40,000",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "500",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "தமிழ்நாடு மாநில அரசு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்திய உயர் ஸ்தானிகராலயம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இந்தியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "3.5 பில்லியன் அமெரிக்க டாலர்களுக்கு மேல்",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "2022",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "மூன்று",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "1.5 பில்லியன் அமெரிக்க டாலர்களுக்கு மேல்",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "அந்நிய செலாவணி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "சுமார் 2 பில்லியன் அமெரிக்க டாலர்கள்",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்தியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  },
  "title": " SL receives second consignment of humanitarian supplies donated by India",
  "body_lines": [
    "A humanitarian consignment worth Rs. 3 billion consisting of 14,700 MT of rice, 250 MT of milk powder and 38 MT of medicines donated by the people of India was handed over by Indian High Commissioner Gopal Baglay today.",
    "This is the second consignment under a larger commitment of 40,000 MT of rice, 500 MT of milk powder and medicines by the State Government of Tamil Nadu, Indian High Commission said in a statement.",
    "\"India’s unprecedented economic, financial and humanitarian assistance to the people of Sri Lanka stands at over US$ 3.5 billion in 2022. In addition to the three credit lines to the tune of more than US$1.5 billion and Forex support of around US$2 billion assistance from the Government and people of India in the form of supply of medicines to several health-related establishments in various parts of Sri Lanka, distribution of kerosene among the fishermen of Sri Lanka, handing over of dry rations to needy sections etc,\" the statement added."
  ],
  "translate": {
    "en": {
      "title": "SL receives second consignment of humanitarian supplies donated by India",
      "body_lines": [
        "A humanitarian consignment worth Rs. 3 billion consisting of 14,700 MT of rice, 250 MT of milk powder and 38 MT of medicines donated by the people of India was handed over by Indian High Commissioner Gopal Baglay today.",
        "This is the second consignment under a larger commitment of 40,000 MT of rice, 500 MT of milk powder and medicines by the State Government of Tamil Nadu, Indian High Commission said in a statement.",
        "\"India’s unprecedented economic, financial and humanitarian assistance to the people of Sri Lanka stands at over US$ 3.5 billion in 2022. In addition to the three credit lines to the tune of more than US$1.5 billion and Forex support of around US$2 billion assistance from the Government and people of India in the form of supply of medicines to several health-related establishments in various parts of Sri Lanka, distribution of kerosene among the fishermen of Sri Lanka, handing over of dry rations to needy sections etc,\" the statement added."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "SL",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "second",
          "label": "ORDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "India",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "3 billion",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "14,700",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "250",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "38",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "India",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Indian",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Gopal Baglay",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "second",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "40,000",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "500",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "the State Government of Tamil Nadu",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Indian High Commission",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "India",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "over US$ 3.5 billion",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "2022",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "three",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "more than US$1.5 billion",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "Forex",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "around US$2 billion",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "India",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "ඉන්දියාව විසින් පරිත්‍යාග කරන ලද මානුෂීය සැපයුම්වල දෙවන තොගය ශ්‍රී ලංකාවට ලැබේ",
      "body_lines": [
        "රු. ඉන්දීය ජනතාව විසින් පරිත්‍යාග කරන ලද සහල් මෙට්‍රික් ටොන් 14,700 ක්, කිරිපිටි මෙට්‍රික් ටොන් 250 ක් සහ ඖෂධ මෙට්‍රික් ටොන් 38 කින් සමන්විත රුපියල් බිලියන 3 ක් ඉන්දීය මහ කොමසාරිස් ගෝපාල් බග්ලේ විසින් අද භාර දෙන ලදී.",
        "තමිල්නාඩු ප්‍රාන්ත රජය විසින් සහල් මෙට්‍රික් ටොන් 40,000 ක්, කිරිපිටි මෙට්‍රික් ටොන් 500 ක් සහ ඖෂධ වැනි විශාල කැපවීමක් යටතේ නිකුත් කරන ලද දෙවැනි තොගය මෙය බව ඉන්දීය මහ කොමසාරිස් කාර්යාලය නිවේදනයක් නිකුත් කරමින් කියා සිටියේය.",
        "\"ඉන්දියාවේ ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ ජනතාවට පෙර නොවූ විරූ ආර්ථික, මූල්‍ය සහ මානුෂීය ආධාර 2022 දී ඇමරිකානු ඩොලර් බිලියන 3.5 ඉක්මවයි. ණය මාර්ග තුනට අමතරව ඇමරිකානු ඩොලර් බිලියන 1.5 කට වඩා වැඩි මුදලක් සහ විදේශ විනිමය ආධාර ඩොලර් බිලියන 2 ක පමණ ආධාර ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ විවිධ ප්‍රදේශවල සෞඛ්‍ය සම්බන්ධ ආයතන කිහිපයකට ඖෂධ සැපයීම, ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ ධීවරයින් අතර භූමිතෙල් බෙදා හැරීම, අවශ්‍යතා ඇති කොටස් වෙත වියළි සලාක ලබාදීම යනාදී ආකාරයෙන් ඉන්දීය රජයෙන් සහ ජනතාවගෙන්\" එම නිවේදනයේ දැක්වේ. එකතු කළා."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "එස්.එල්",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "දෙවැනි",
          "label": "ORDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "ඉන්දියාව",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "බිලියන 3 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "14,700 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "250",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "38",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දීය",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගෝපාල් බග්ලේ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "දෙවැනි",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "40,000 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "500",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "තමිල්නාඩු ප්‍රාන්ත රජය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දීය මහ කොමසාරිස්",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඇමරිකානු ඩොලර් බිලියන 3.5 කට වඩා",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "2022",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "තුන්",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඇමරිකානු ඩොලර් බිලියන 1.5 කට වඩා වැඩි",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "Forex",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඇමරිකානු ඩොලර් බිලියන 2 ක් පමණ",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "இந்தியாவினால் நன்கொடையாக வழங்கப்பட்ட இரண்டாவது மனிதாபிமானப் பொருட்களை SL பெறுகிறது",
      "body_lines": [
        "ஒரு மனிதாபிமானப் பொருள் ரூ. இந்திய மக்களால் வழங்கப்பட்ட 14,700 மெட்ரிக் டன் அரிசி, 250 மெட்ரிக் டன் பால் பவுடர் மற்றும் 38 மெட்ரிக் டன் மருந்துகள் அடங்கிய 3 பில்லியன் ரூபாயை இந்திய உயர்ஸ்தானிகர் கோபால் பாக்லே இன்று வழங்கினார்.",
        "தமிழ்நாடு மாநில அரசின் 40,000 மெட்ரிக் டன் அரிசி, 500 மெட்ரிக் டன் பால் பவுடர் மற்றும் மருந்துகளின் பெரிய உறுதிப்பாட்டின் கீழ் இது இரண்டாவது சரக்கு என்று இந்திய உயர் ஸ்தானிகராலயம் ஒரு அறிக்கையில் தெரிவித்துள்ளது.",
        "\"இலங்கை மக்களுக்கு இந்தியாவின் முன்னோடியில்லாத பொருளாதார, நிதி மற்றும் மனிதாபிமான உதவி 2022 இல் 3.5 பில்லியன் அமெரிக்க டாலர்களாக உள்ளது. மூன்று கடன் வரிகளுக்கு கூடுதலாக 1.5 பில்லியன் அமெரிக்க டாலர்கள் மற்றும் அந்நிய செலாவணி ஆதரவு சுமார் 2 பில்லியன் அமெரிக்க டாலர்கள். இலங்கையின் பல்வேறு பகுதிகளில் உள்ள சுகாதாரம் தொடர்பான பல நிறுவனங்களுக்கு மருந்துகள் வழங்குதல், இலங்கை மீனவர்களுக்கு மண்ணெண்ணெய் விநியோகம், தேவைப்படும் பிரிவினருக்கு உலர் உணவுகளை வழங்குதல் போன்ற வடிவங்களில் இந்திய அரசு மற்றும் மக்களிடம் இருந்து,\" அந்த அறிக்கையில் கூறப்பட்டுள்ளது. சேர்க்கப்பட்டது."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "எஸ்.எல்",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "இரண்டாவது",
          "label": "ORDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "இந்தியா",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "3 பில்லியன்",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "14,700",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "250",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "38",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்தியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்தியன்",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "கோபால் பாக்லே",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இரண்டாவது",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "40,000",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "500",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "தமிழ்நாடு மாநில அரசு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்திய உயர் ஸ்தானிகராலயம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இந்தியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "3.5 பில்லியன் அமெரிக்க டாலர்களுக்கு மேல்",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "2022",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "மூன்று",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "1.5 பில்லியன் அமெரிக்க டாலர்களுக்கு மேல்",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "அந்நிய செலாவணி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "சுமார் 2 பில்லியன் அமெரிக்க டாலர்கள்",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்தியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}