{
  "newspaper_id": "virakesari-lk",
  "url": "http://www.virakesari.lk/article/132019",
  "time_ut": 1658471081,
  "original_lang": "ta",
  "original_title": "ஒரே இரவில் காலி முகத்திடலில் இடம்பெற்ற நிகழ்வுகள் கவலையளிக்கின்றன - நியூசிலாந்து",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Disturbing events overnight in Galle - New Zealand",
      "author": "Vishnu",
      "body_lines": [
        "New Zealand High Commissioner Michael Appleton expressed concern over the overnight events in Galle.",
        "On the morning of the 27th, the three forces removed the people who were peacefully protesting in front of the Presidential Secretariat located in the Gallimugattidal area of ​​Colombo.",
        "Following this, New Zealand High Commissioner Michael Appleton expressed concern and condemnation on his official Twitter page.",
        "“The events that took place overnight in Galle are alarming. Freedom of speech, freedom of the media and the right to peaceful protest are the foundations of all free societies. So they should be protected, New Zealand High Commissioner Michael Appleton said."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Galle",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "New Zealand",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "New Zealand",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Michael Appleton",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "overnight",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "Galle",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the morning of the 27th",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "three",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "New Zealand",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Michael Appleton",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Twitter",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Galle",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "New Zealand",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Michael Appleton",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "නවසීලන්තයේ ගාල්ලේ එක රැයකින් කලබලකාරී සිදුවීම්",
      "author": "විෂ්ණු",
      "body_lines": [
        "නවසීලන්ත මහ කොමසාරිස් මයිකල් ඇපල්ටන් ගාල්ලේ එක රැයකින් සිදු වූ සිදුවීම් පිළිබඳව කනස්සල්ල පළ කළේය.",
        "පසුගිය 27 වැනිදා පෙරවරුවේ කොළඹ ගල්ලිමුගට්ටිඩාල් ප්‍රදේශයේ පිහිටි ජනාධිපති ලේකම් කාර්යාලය ඉදිරිපිට සාමකාමීව විරෝධතාවයේ නිරත වූ ජනතාව ත්‍රිවිධ හමුදාව විසින් ඉවත් කරනු ලැබුවා.",
        "ඉන් අනතුරුව නවසීලන්ත මහ කොමසාරිස් මයිකල් ඇපල්ටන් සිය නිල ට්විටර් පිටුවේ කනස්සල්ල සහ හෙළා දැකීම ප්‍රකාශ කළේය.",
        "“ගාල්ලේදී එක රැයකින් සිදුවූ සිදුවීම් භයානකයි. භාෂණයේ නිදහස, මාධ්‍ය නිදහස සහ සාමකාමී විරෝධතා දැක්වීමේ අයිතිය සියලු නිදහස් සමාජයන්හි පදනම වේ. එබැවින් ඔවුන් ආරක්ෂා කළ යුතු බව නවසීලන්ත මහ කොමසාරිස් මයිකල් ඇපල්ටන් පැවසීය."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ගාල්ල",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "නවසීලන්තය",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "නවසීලන්තය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මයිකල් ඇපල්ටන්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "එක රැයකින්",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගාල්ල",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "27 වෙනිදා උදේ",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "තුන්",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "නවසීලන්තය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මයිකල් ඇපල්ටන්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ට්විටර්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ගාල්ල",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "නවසීලන්තය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මයිකල් ඇපල්ටන්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "ஒரே இரவில் காலி முகத்திடலில் இடம்பெற்ற நிகழ்வுகள் கவலையளிக்கின்றன - நியூசிலாந்து",
      "author": "Vishnu",
      "body_lines": [
        "ஒரே இரவில் காலி முகத்திடலில் இடம்பெற்ற நிகழ்வுகள் கவலையளிக்கின்றன என நியூசிலாந்து உயர்ஸ்தானிகர் மைக்கல் எப்பல்டன் கவலை தெரிவித்துள்ளார்.",
        "கொழும்பு, காலிமுகத்திடல் பகுதியில் அமைந்துள்ள ஜனாதிபதி செயலகத்திற்கு முன்னால் அமைதியான போராட்டத்தில் ஈடுபட்டவர்களை 27 ஆம் திகதி இன்று அதிகாலை முப்படையினர் அங்கிருந்து அகற்றினர்.",
        "இதையடுத்து நியூசிலாந்து உயர்ஸ்தானிகர் மைக்கல் எப்பல்டன் தனது உத்தியோகபூர்வ டுவிட்டர் பக்கத்தில் கவலையையும் கண்டனத்தையும் வெளியிட்டார்.",
        "“ ஒரே இரவில் காலி முகத்திடலில் இடம்பெற்ற நிகழ்வுகள் கவலையளிக்கின்றன. பேச்சு சுதந்திரம், ஊடக சுதந்திரம் மற்றும் அமைதியான போராட்டத்திற்கான உரிமை ஆகியவை அனைத்து சுதந்திரமான சமூகங்களின் அடித்தளமாகும். எனவே அவை பாதுகாக்கப்பட வேண்டும் என நியூசிலாந்து உயர்ஸ்தானிகர் மைக்கல் எப்பல்டன் குறிப்பிட்டுள்ளார்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "காலி",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "நியூசிலாந்து",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "நியூசிலாந்து",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "மைக்கேல் ஆப்பிள்டன்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஒரே இரவில்",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "காலி",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "27ம் தேதி காலை",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "மூன்று",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "நியூசிலாந்து",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "மைக்கேல் ஆப்பிள்டன்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ட்விட்டர்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "காலி",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "நியூசிலாந்து",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "மைக்கேல் ஆப்பிள்டன்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}