{
  "newspaper_id": "tamil-mirror-lk",
  "url": "https://www.tamilmirror.lk/செய்திகள்/கோட்டாவின்-செலவுகளை-ஏற்றது-அரசாங்கம்/175-302463",
  "time_ut": 1660670906,
  "original_lang": "ta",
  "original_title": "கோட்டாவின் செலவுகளை ஏற்றது அரசாங்கம்",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "The government bears the expenses of the quota",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "Cabinet Spokesperson Bandula Gunawardena has said that the Sri Lankan government has paid for former President Gotabaya Rajapaksa's flight from Singapore to Thailand.",
        "He said the above while responding to a question raised by a journalist while participating in a press conference announcing the weekly cabinet decisions.",
        "He also said that former President Gotabaya Rajapaksa should be given all the bounties and special privileges enjoyed by the retired executive presidents and the wives of deceased former presidents as per the law."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Spokesperson Bandula Gunawardena",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lankan",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Gotabaya Rajapaksa's",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Singapore",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Thailand",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "weekly",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Gotabaya Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "කෝටාවේ වියදම් රජය දරනවා",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "හිටපු ජනාධිපති ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ මහතා සිංගප්පූරුවේ සිට තායිලන්තය බලා පියාසර කිරීම සඳහා ශ්‍රී ලංකා රජය මුදල් ගෙවා ඇති බව කැබිනට් ප්‍රකාශක බන්දුල ගුණවර්ධන මහතා පවසයි.",
        "සතිපතා පැවැත්වෙන කැබිනට් තීරණ දැනුම්දීමේ මාධ්‍ය හමුවට එක්වෙමින් මාධ්‍යවේදියෙකු නැගූ ප්‍රශ්නයකට පිළිතුරු ලබාදෙමින් ඔහු මේ බව කියා සිටියා.",
        "විශ‍්‍රාමික විධායක ජනාධිපතිවරුන් සහ මියගිය හිටපු ජනාධිපතිවරුන්ගේ බිරින්දෑවරුන්ට නීතියට අනුව හිමිවන සියලූ වරප‍්‍රසාද සහ විශේෂ වරප‍්‍රසාද හිටපු ජනාධිපති ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ මහතාට ද ලබාදිය යුතු බවද ඔහු කියා සිටියා."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ප්‍රකාශක බන්දුල ගුණවර්ධන",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලාංකික",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂගේ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "සිංගප්පූරුව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "තායිලන්තය",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "සතිපතා",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "கோட்டாவின் செலவுகளை ஏற்றது அரசாங்கம்",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "முன்னாள் ஜனாதிபதி கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ஷ சிங்கப்பூரிலிருந்து தாய்லாந்துக்கு செல்வதற்கான விமான செலவுகளை இலங்கை அரசாங்கமே செலுத்தியுள்ளதாக அமைச்சரவை பேச்சாளர் பந்துல குணவர்தன தெரிவித்துள்ளார்.",
        "வாராந்த அமைச்சரவை தீர்மானங்களை அறிவிக்கும் ஊடகவியலாளர் சந்திப்பில் கலந்துகொண்டு ஊடகவியலாளர் எழுப்பியக் கேள்விக்குப் பதிலளித்து உரையாற்றும்போதே அவர் மேற்கண்டவாறு தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "ஓய்வுபெற்ற நிறைவேற்று அதிகாரங்கொண்ட ஒவ்வொரு ஜனாதிபதிகளுக்கும், உயிரிழந்துள்ள முன்னாள் ஜனாதிபதிகளின் மனைவிகளும் சட்டத்தின்படி அனுபவிக்கும் அத்தனை வரப்பிரசாதங்கள், விசேட சலுகைகளையும் முன்னாள் ஜனாதிபதி கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ஷவுக்கும் வழங்க வேண்டும் எனவும் தெரிவித்தார்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "பேச்சாளர் பந்துல குணவர்தன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்சவின்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "சிங்கப்பூர்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "தாய்லாந்து",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "வாரந்தோறும்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}