{
  "newspaper_id": "tamil-mirror-lk",
  "url": "https://www.tamilmirror.lk/செய்திகள்/அவுஸ்திரோலியா-செல்ல-முயன்ற-77-பேர்-கைது/175-300158",
  "time_ut": 1657508302,
  "original_lang": "ta",
  "original_title": "அவுஸ்திரோலியா செல்ல முயன்ற 77 பேர் கைது",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "77 people who tried to go to Australia were arrested",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "77 people were arrested early today (11) for illegally traveling by motor boat from Kaluwangeni beach, Batticaloa to Australia.",
        "17 people, including a woman, have been handed over to the Ebravur police and the other 60 have been taken to the Trincomalee naval camp by boat, the police said.",
        "According to the information received by the Naval Intelligence Unit, at 2 o'clock in the morning today, the boats of the Navy surrounded the engine boat that was traveling in the sea area of ​​the Batticaloa Ebravoor Police Division.",
        "In this, 60 anti-immigrants were arrested and 77 people were arrested by the Naval Intelligence Unit along with the police, including 17 people who were waiting in a van at Kaluwangeni beach to board the said illegal boat. (a)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "77",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "Australia",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "77",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "11",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kaluwangeni beach",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Batticaloa",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Australia",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "17",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "60",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Trincomalee",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the Naval Intelligence Unit",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "2 o'clock in the morning",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Navy",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "​​the Batticaloa Ebravoor Police Division",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "60",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "77",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Naval Intelligence Unit",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "17",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kaluwangeni",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "ඕස්ට්‍රේලියාවට යාමට උත්සාහ කළ 77 දෙනෙකු අත්අඩංගුවට ගැනුණා",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "මඩකලපුව, කලුවාංගේනි වෙරළ තීරයේ සිට ඔස්ට්‍රේලියාව බලා නීතිවිරෝධී ලෙස මෝටර් බෝට්ටුවකින් ගමන් කළ පුද්ගලයින් 77 දෙනෙකු අද (11) අලුයම අත්අඩංගුවට ගෙන තිබෙනවා.",
        "කාන්තාවක් ඇතුළු පුද්ගලයින් 17 දෙනෙකු එබ්‍රාවුර් පොලිසියට භාරදී ඇති අතර අනෙක් 60 දෙනා බෝට්ටුවකින් ත්‍රිකුණාමලය නාවික හමුදා කඳවුර වෙත රැගෙන ගොස් ඇති බව පොලිසිය පවසයි.",
        "නාවික හමුදා බුද්ධි අංශයට ලැබුණු තොරතුරකට අනුව අද අලුයම 2 ට නාවික හමුදාවේ බෝට්ටු මඩකලපුව එබ්‍රවුර් පොලිස් වසමට අයත් මුහුදු ප්‍රදේශයේ ගමන් ගත් එන්ජින් බෝට්ටුව වටකර ඇත.",
        "මෙහිදී සංක්‍රමණ විරෝධීන් 60 දෙනෙකු අත්අඩංගුවට ගෙන ඇති අතර, එම නීතිවිරෝධී බෝට්ටුවට ගොඩවීමට කලුවාංගේනි වෙරළ තීරයේ වෑන් රථයක රැඳී සිටි පුද්ගලයින් 17 දෙනෙකු ඇතුළු 77 දෙනෙකු පොලීසිය සමඟ නාවික හමුදා බුද්ධි අංශය විසින් අත්අඩංගුවට ගනු ලැබුවා. (ඒ)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "77",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "ඕස්ට්රේලියාව",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "77",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "11",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "කලුවාංගේනි වෙරළ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මඩකලපුව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඕස්ට්රේලියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "17",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "60",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ත්රිකුණාමලය",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "නාවික බුද්ධි අංශය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාන්දර 2 යි",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "නාවික",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "මඩකලපුව එබ්‍රවුර් පොලිස් වසමේ",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "60",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "77",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "නාවික බුද්ධි අංශය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "17",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "කලුවංගේනි",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "அவுஸ்திரோலியா செல்ல முயன்ற 77 பேர் கைது",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "மட்டக்களப்பு, களுவங்கேணி கடற்கரையில் இருந்து அவுஸ்திரோலியாவுக்கு இயந்திர படகில் சட்விரோதமாக பயணித்த 77 பேரை இன்று (11) அதிகாலை கைது செய்யப்பட்டுள்ளனர்.",
        "பெண் ஒருவர் உட்பட 17 பேரை ஏறாவூர் பொலிஸாரிடம் ஒப்படைத்துள்ளதுடன் ஏனைய 60 பேரை படகுடன் திருகோணமலை கடற்படை முகாமிற்கு கொண்டு சென்றுள்ளதாக பொலிஸார் தெரிவிதுள்ளனர்.",
        "கடற்படை புலனாய்வு பிரிவுக்கு கிடைத்த தகவல் ஒன்றிற்கு அமைய இன்று அதிகாலை 2 மணி அளவில் மட்டக்களப்பு ஏறாவூர் பொலிஸ் பிரிவிலுள்ள கடல்பகுதியில் பயணித்த இயந்திரப்படகை கடற்படையின் படகுகள் சுற்றிவழைத்தனர்.",
        "இதில் சட்விரோத குடியேற்றக்காரர்கள் 60 பேரை கைது செய்ததுடன் குறித்த சட்டவிரோத படகில் ஏறுவதற்கு களுவங்கேணி கடற்கரையில் வான் ஒன்றில் காத்திருந்த 17 பேர் உட்பட கடற்படை புலனாய்வு பிரிவினர் பொலிஸாருடன் இணைந்து சுற்றிவழைத்து 77 பேரை கைது செய்துள்ளனர். (a)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "77",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "ஆஸ்திரேலியா",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "77",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "11",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "களுவாங்கேணி கடற்கரை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "மட்டக்களப்பு",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆஸ்திரேலியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "17",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "60",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "திருகோணமலை",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "கடற்படை புலனாய்வு பிரிவு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "அதிகாலை 2 மணி",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "கடற்படை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "மட்டக்களப்பு எப்ராவூர் பொலிஸ் பிரிவு",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "60",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "77",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "கடற்படை புலனாய்வு பிரிவு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "17",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "களுவாங்கேணி",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}