{
  "newspaper_id": "virakesari-lk",
  "url": "http://www.virakesari.lk/article/131309",
  "time_ut": 1657619645,
  "original_lang": "ta",
  "original_title": "ரஞ்சன் ராமநாயக்கவை புதிய ஜனாதிபதி விடுவிக்க வேண்டும் - ஹர்ஷண ராஜகருணா",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "New President should release Ranjan Ramanayake - Harshana Rajakaruna",
      "author": "Vishnu",
      "body_lines": [
        "Harshana Rajakaruna, Member of Parliament of United People's Shakti said that the first duty of the new president is to demand the release of Ranjan Ramanayaka.",
        "On Tuesday 12th, members of United People's Power visited former Member of Parliament Ranjan Ramanayaka, who is currently serving his prison sentence in Welikada Prison, Colombo. He said this while commenting to the media.",
        "It has been a year and a half since Ranjan Ramanayake was imprisoned. He went to jail by telling the truth.",
        "We had told the President several times to release him. However, President Gotabaya Rajapakash did not take any action in this regard.",
        "But in the Rajapaksh government, murderers and drug smugglers have been freed in the amnesty.",
        "Former Member of Parliament Ranjan Ramanayake was not jailed for murder or drug trafficking.",
        "He is always telling the truth openly. That is why he has this condition. So after the resignation of Gotabaya Rajapaksh, a new president will be elected.",
        "He said that the first duty of the newly elected president is to release the demand for the release of Ranjan Ramanayake."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Ranjan Ramanayake - Harshana Rajakaruna",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Harshana Rajakaruna",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament of United People's Shakti",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "first",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ranjan Ramanayaka",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Tuesday 12th",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "United People's Power",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ranjan Ramanayaka",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Welikada Prison",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "a year and a half",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ranjan Ramanayake",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Gotabaya Rajapakash",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Rajapaksh",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ranjan Ramanayake",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Gotabaya Rajapaksh",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "first",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ranjan Ramanayake",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "නව ජනපති රන්ජන් රාමනායක නිදහස් කළ යුතුයි - හර්ෂණ රාජකරුණා",
      "author": "විෂ්ණු",
      "body_lines": [
        "නව ජනාධිපතිවරයාගේ පළමු රාජකාරිය රන්ජන් රාමනායක මහතා නිදහස් කරන ලෙස බල කිරීම බව එක්සත් ජනතා ශක්ති පාර්ලිමේන්තු මන්ත්‍රී හර්ෂණ රාජකරුණා මහතා පැවසීය.",
        "මේ වන විට කොළඹ වැලිකඩ බන්ධනාගාරයේ සිරදඬුවම් විඳිමින් සිටින හිටපු පාර්ලිමේන්තු මන්ත්‍රී රන්ජන් රාමනායක මහතා බැලීමට එක්සත් ජනතා බලවේගයේ සාමාජිකයින් 12 අඟහරුවාදා පැමිණියහ. මාධ්‍ය වෙත අදහස් දක්වමින් ඔහු මේ බව පැවසීය.",
        "රන්ජන් රාමනායක සිරගත වී වසර එකහමාරක් ගත වී ඇත. ඇත්ත කියලා හිරේ ගියා.",
        "අපි ජනාධිපතිතුමාට කිහිප වතාවක්ම කියලා තිබුණා එතුමා නිදහස් කරන්න කියලා. එහෙත් ජනාධිපති ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ මේ සම්බන්ධයෙන් කිසිදු පියවරක් ගත්තේ නැත.",
        "නමුත් රාජපක්ෂ ආණ්ඩුවේ මිනීමරුවන් සහ මත්ද්‍රව්‍ය ජාවාරම්කරුවන් පොදු සමාවෙන් නිදහස් කර ඇත.",
        "හිටපු පාර්ලිමේන්තු මන්ත්‍රී රන්ජන් රාමනායක මහතා මිනීමැරුමක් හෝ මත්ද්‍රව්‍ය ජාවාරමක් සම්බන්ධයෙන් සිරගත වූයේ නැත.",
        "ඔහු සෑම විටම විවෘතව ඇත්ත ප්‍රකාශ කරයි. ඒ නිසා තමයි මෙයාට මේ තත්ත්වය තියෙන්නේ. ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ මහතා ඉල්ලා අස්වීමෙන් පසු නව ජනාධිපතිවරයෙකු තෝරා පත් කර ගනු ඇත.",
        "අලුතින් තේරී පත් වූ ජනාධිපතිවරයාගේ පළමු රාජකාරිය වන්නේ රන්ජන් රාමනායක මහතා නිදහස් කරන ලෙසට කරන ලද ඉල්ලීම නිදහස් කිරීම බවද ඔහු පැවසීය."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "රන්ජන් රාමනායක - හර්ෂණ රාජකරුණා",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "හර්ෂණ රාජකරුණා",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "එක්සත් ජනතා ශක්ති පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "පළමුවන",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "රන්ජන් රාමනායක",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "12 අඟහරුවාදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "එක්සත් ජනතා බලය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "රන්ජන් රාමනායක",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "වැලිකඩ බන්ධනාගාරය",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "වසර එකහමාරක්",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "රන්ජන් රාමනායක",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "රන්ජන් රාමනායක",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "පළමුවන",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "රන්ජන් රාමනායක",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "ரஞ்சன் ராமநாயக்கவை புதிய ஜனாதிபதி விடுவிக்க வேண்டும் - ஹர்ஷண ராஜகருணா",
      "author": "Vishnu",
      "body_lines": [
        "புதிய ஜனாதிபதியின் முதலாவது கடமையாக ரஞ்சன் ராமநாயகவை விடுதலை செய்யுமாறு கோரிக்கை விடுக்க இருக்கின்றோம் என ஐக்கிய மக்கள் சக்தி பாராளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர் ஹர்ஷண ராஜகருணா தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "கொழும்பு வெலிகடை சிறைச்சாலையில் சிறைத் தண்டனை அனுபவித்து வரும் முன்னாள் பாராளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர் ரஞ்சன் ராமநாயகவை 12 ஆம் திகதி செவ்வாய்க்கிழமை ஐக்கிய மக்கள் சக்தி உறுப்பினர்கள் பார்வையிடச்சென்றனர். அதன்போது ஊடகங்களுககு கருத்து தெரிவிக்கையிலேயே இவ்வாறு தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "ரஞ்சன் ராமநாயகவை சிறையில் அடைத்து இன்றுடன் ஒன்றரை வருடங்கள் ஆகின்றன. உண்மையை தெரிவித்தே சிறைக்கு சென்றார்.",
        "அவரை விடுதலை செய்யுமாறு நாங்கள் பல தடவைகள் ஜனாதிபதிக்கு தெரிவித்திருந்தோம். என்றாலும்   ஜனாதிபதி கோத்தாபய ராஜபகஷ் அதுதொடர்பில் எந்த நடவடிக்கையும் எடுக்கவில்லை.",
        "ஆனால்  ராஜபக்ஷ் அரசாங்கத்தில் கொலைகாரர்களும், போதைப்பாெருள் கடத்தல்கார்களும் பொது மன்னிப்பில் விடுதலை பெற்றுச்சென்றுள்ளர்.",
        "முன்னாள் பாராளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர் ரன்ஜன் ராமநாயக்க கொலை செய்த குற்றத்துக்கோ அல்லது போதை பொருள் கடத்தல் நடவடிக்கைகளை மேற்கொண்டதாலோ சிறைப்படுத்தவில்லை.",
        "அவர் எப்போதும் உண்மையை வெளிப்படையாக தெரிவித்து வருபவர். அதனால்தான் அவருக்கு இந்த நிலை ஏற்பட்டிருக்கின்றது. எனவே கோத்தாபய ராஜபக்ஷ் பதவி விலகிய பின்னர் புதிய ஜனாதிபதி ஒருவர் தெரிவுசெய்யப்பட இருக்கிறார்.",
        "இவ்வாறு தெரிவுசெய்யப்படும் புதிய ஜனாதிபதிக்கு முதலாவது கடமையாக ரஞ்சன் ராமநாயகவை விடுதலை செய்யும் கோரிக்கையை ஐக்கிய மக்கள் சக்தி விடுக்க இருக்கின்றது என்றார்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ரஞ்சன் ராமநாயக்க - ஹர்ஷன ராஜகருணா",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ஹர்ஷன ராஜகருணா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஐக்கிய மக்கள் சக்தியின் பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "முதலில்",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரஞ்சன் ராமநாயக்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "செவ்வாய் 12",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஐக்கிய மக்கள் சக்தி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரஞ்சன் ராமநாயக்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "வெலிக்கடை சிறைச்சாலை",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஒன்றரை வருடம்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரஞ்சன் ராமநாயக்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ராஜபக்ஷ",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரஞ்சன் ராமநாயக்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ஷ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "முதலில்",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரஞ்சன் ராமநாயக்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}