{
  "newspaper_id": "daily-mirror-lk",
  "url": "https://www.dailymirror.lk/top_story/Its-up-to-GR-if-he-wants-to-engage-in-politics-or-not-Namal/155-244271",
  "time_ut": 1662283387,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "It’s up to GR if he wants to engage in politics or not: Namal",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "It’s up to GR if he wants to engage in politics or not: Namal",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "Former President Gotabaya Rajapaksa will decide whether he will engage in politics or not, MP Namal Rajapaksa said.",
        "“It is the former president who should decide what he will do in the future. We should let him decide whether he wants to engage in politics or not. We don't have the right to take decisions for others,\" he said.",
        "Commenting on the return of the former president from Thailand, the MP said, “unfortunately he left the country, but he has returned now. And that's his right to live as a citizen in the country. We always believe Sri Lanka is a democratic country,\" he said.",
        "He said they would inform the party's executive council once the former president makes his decision.(DSB)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Gotabaya Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Namal Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "Thailand",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        []
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "දේශපාලනය කරනවාද නැද්ද යන්න ජීආර්ට භාරයි: නාමල්",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "තමන් දේශපාලනය කරනවාද නැද්ද යන්න තීරණය කරන්නේ හිටපු ජනාධිපති ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ මහතා බව පාර්ලිමේන්තු මන්ත්‍රී නාමල් රාජපක්ෂ මහතා පවසයි.",
        "“ඉදිරියේදී කුමක් කරන්නේද යන්න තීරණය කළ යුත්තේ හිටපු ජනාධිපතිවරයායි. දේශපාලනය කරනවද නැද්ද කියලා තීරණය කරන්න අපි ඔහුට ඉඩ දිය යුතුයි. අනිත් අය වෙනුවෙන් තීරණ ගන්න අපිට අයිතියක් නැහැ,\" ඔහු පැවසීය.",
        "හිටපු ජනාධිපතිවරයා තායිලන්තයේ සිට මෙරටට පැමිණීම සම්බන්ධයෙන් අදහස් දක්වමින් මන්ත්‍රීවරයා කියා සිටියේ “අවාසනාවකට ඔහු රට හැර ගිය නමුත් දැන් ඔහු පැමිණ තිබෙනවා. ඒ වගේම රටේ පුරවැසියෙකු ලෙස ජීවත් වීමට ඔහුට ඇති අයිතිය එයයි. ශ්‍රී ලංකාව ප්‍රජාතන්ත්‍රවාදී රටක් බව අපි සැමවිටම විශ්වාස කරනවා,\" ඔහු පැවසීය.",
        "හිටපු ජනාධිපතිවරයාගේ තීරණය ගත් පසු ඔවුන් පක්ෂයේ විධායක සභාවට දැනුම් දෙන බව ඔහු පැවසීය.(DSB)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "නාමල් රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "තායිලන්තය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        []
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "அரசியலில் ஈடுபட வேண்டுமா வேண்டாமா என்பது ஜி.ஆரின் விருப்பம்: நாமல்",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "அரசியலில் ஈடுபடுவதா இல்லையா என்பதை முன்னாள் ஜனாதிபதி கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ச தீர்மானிப்பார் என நாடாளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர் நாமல் ராஜபக்ஷ தெரிவித்துள்ளார்.",
        "“எதிர்காலத்தில் என்ன செய்ய வேண்டும் என்பதை முன்னாள் ஜனாதிபதிதான் தீர்மானிக்க வேண்டும். அவர் அரசியலில் ஈடுபடலாமா வேண்டாமா என்பதை அவரே முடிவு செய்ய வேண்டும். மற்றவர்களுக்காக முடிவெடுக்கும் உரிமை எங்களுக்கு இல்லை,'' என்றார்.",
        "தாய்லாந்தில் இருந்து முன்னாள் ஜனாதிபதி நாடு திரும்பியது குறித்து கருத்து தெரிவித்த எம்.பி. அதுவும் நாட்டில் குடிமகனாக வாழ்வதற்கான உரிமை. இலங்கை ஒரு ஜனநாயக நாடு என்று நாங்கள் எப்போதும் நம்புகிறோம்,” என்றார்.",
        "முன்னாள் ஜனாதிபதி தனது முடிவை எடுத்தவுடன் கட்சியின் செயற்குழுவிற்கு அறிவிப்பதாக அவர் கூறினார்.(டிஎஸ்பி)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "நாமல் ராஜபக்ச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "தாய்லாந்து",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        []
      ]
    }
  }
}