{
  "newspaper_id": "daily-ft-lk",
  "url": "https://www.ft.lk/news/Task-Force-for-One-Country-One-Law-report-to-be-submitted-to-Cabinet-P-ment/56-736869",
  "time_ut": 1656532535,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Task Force for “One Country, One Law” report to be submitted to Cabinet, P’ment",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Task Force for “One Country, One Law” report to be submitted to Cabinet, P’ment",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "The report of the Presidential Task Force for “One Country, One Law” was handed over to President Gotabaya Rajapaksa by its Chairman Rajakeeya Panditha Ven. Galagodaaththe Gnanasara Thera yesterday.",
        "The report consists of eight chapters with 43 recommendations and two appendices, prepared after considering views and opinions of over 1,200 witnesses covering all parts of the country, which included professionals, NGOs, different religious groups, different communities, the university community and legal experts.",
        "The President directed that this report be submitted to the Cabinet and the Parliament.",
        "The President appointed the Presidential Task Force, headed by Ven. Galagodaaththe Gnanasara Thera, to study the views and opinions of various factions on the implementation of the concept of ‘One Country, One Law’ in Sri Lanka and present a concept paper with proposals.",
        "Prof. Shanthi Nandana Wijesinghe, Senior Lecturer Weerawardhanalage Sumedha Manjula, Dr. N.G. Sujeewa Panditharathna, Attorney-at-Law Iresh Senevirathne, Attorney-at-Law W.P.J.M.R. Sanjaya Marambe, R.A. Eranda Kumara Navarathna, Pani Wewala, Moulavi M.A.S. Mohamed, Yogeswari Patkunarajah and Aiyampillai Dayanandaraja are the other members of the Task Force. Senior Assistant Secretary to the President Jeewanthi Senanayak served as the Secretary of the Task Force.",
        "Secretary to the President Gamini Senarath, Principal Advisor to President Lalith Weeratunga, and Chief of Staff to the President Anura Dissanayake were also present."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "One",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "One",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "Cabinet",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "the Presidential Task Force",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "One",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "One",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Gotabaya Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Rajakeeya Panditha Ven",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Gnanasara",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "yesterday",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "eight",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "43",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "two",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Cabinet",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the Presidential Task Force",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Galagodaaththe Gnanasara Thera",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "One",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "One",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Shanthi Nandana Wijesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sumedha Manjula",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "N.G. Sujeewa Panditharathna",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sanjaya Marambe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "R.A.",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kumara Navarathna",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Pani Wewala",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Moulavi",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Yogeswari Patkunarajah",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Task Force",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Jeewanthi Senanayak",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Task Force",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Gamini Senarath",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Principal Advisor",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Lalith Weeratunga",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Anura Dissanayake",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "“එක් රටක්, එක නීතියක්” සඳහා වූ කාර්ය සාධක බලකායේ වාර්තාව කැබිනට් මණ්ඩලයට ඉදිරිපත් කිරීමට නියමිතයි.",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "“එකම රටක් එකම නීතියක්” සඳහා වූ ජනාධිපති කාර්ය සාධන බළකායේ වාර්තාව එහි සභාපති රාජකීය පණ්ඩිත පූජ්‍ය පූජ්‍ය හිමිපාණන් විසින් ජනාධිපති ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ මහතා වෙත පිළිගැන්වීය. ගලගොඩඅත්තේ ඥානසාර හිමි ඊයේ.",
        "වෘත්තිකයන්, රාජ්‍ය නොවන සංවිධාන, විවිධ ආගමික කණ්ඩායම්, විවිධ ප්‍රජාවන්, විශ්වවිද්‍යාල ප්‍රජාව සහ නීති විශාරදයින් ඇතුළු දිවයිනේ සෑම ප්‍රදේශයක්ම ආවරණය වන පරිදි සාක්ෂිකරුවන් 1,200කට අධික පිරිසකගේ අදහස් සහ අදහස් සලකා බලා සකස් කරන ලද නිර්දේශ 43කින් සහ උපග්‍රන්ථ දෙකකින් යුත් පරිච්ඡේද අටකින් වාර්තාව සමන්විත වේ.",
        "මෙම වාර්තාව කැබිනට් මණ්ඩලයට සහ පාර්ලිමේන්තුවට ඉදිරිපත් කරන ලෙස ජනාධිපතිවරයා නියෝග කළේය.",
        "ජනාධිපතිවරයා විසින් පූජ්‍ය පූජ්‍ය නාහිමියන්ගේ ප්‍රධානත්වයෙන් ජනාධිපති කාර්ය සාධක බලකාය පත් කළේය. ගලගොඩඅත්තේ ඤාණසාර හිමියන්, ‘එකම රටක් එකම නීතියක්’ සංකල්පය ශ්‍රී ලංකාව තුළ ක්‍රියාත්මක කිරීම සම්බන්ධයෙන් විවිධ පාර්ශ්වවල අදහස් හා අදහස් අධ්‍යයනය කර යෝජනා ඇතුළත් සංකල්ප පත්‍රිකාවක් ඉදිරිපත් කිරීම.",
        "මහාචාර්ය ශාන්ති නන්දන විජේසිංහ, ජ්‍යෙෂ්ඨ කථිකාචාර්ය වීරවර්ධනලාගේ සුමේධ මංජුල, ආචාර්ය එන්.ජී. සුජීව පණ්ඩිතරත්න, නීතිඥ ඉරේෂ් සෙනෙවිරත්න, නීතිඥ ඩබ්ලිව්.පී.ජේ.එම්.ආර්. සංජය මාරඹේ, ආර්.ඒ. එරන්ද කුමාර නවරත්න, පැනි වෑවල, මවුලවි එම්.ඒ.එස්. මොහොමඩ්, යෝගේස්වරී පට්කුනරාජා සහ අයියම්පිල්ලේ දයානන්දරාජා කාර්ය සාධක බලකායේ සෙසු සාමාජිකයින් වේ. ජනාධිපති ජ්‍යෙෂ්ඨ සහකාර ලේකම් ජීවන්ති සේනානායක මහත්මිය කාර්ය සාධක බලකායේ ලේකම්වරිය ලෙස කටයුතු කළාය.",
        "ජනාධිපති ලේකම් ගාමිණී සෙනරත්, ජනාධිපති ප්‍රධාන උපදේශක ලලිත් වීරතුංග, ජනාධිපති කාර්ය මණ්ඩල ප්‍රධානී අනුර දිසානායක යන මහත්වරු ද මේ අවස්ථාවට එක්ව සිටියහ."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "එක",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "එක",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "මණ්ඩල",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ජනාධිපති කාර්ය සාධක බලකාය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "එක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "එක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "රාජකීය පණ්ඩිත හිමි",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඥානසාර",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඊයේ",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "අට",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "43",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "දෙක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "මණ්ඩල",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ජනාධිපති කාර්ය සාධක බලකාය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගලගොඩඅත්තේ ඥානසාර හිමි",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "එක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "එක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශාන්ති නන්දන විජේසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "සුමේධ මංජුල",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "එන්.ජී. සුජීව පණ්ඩිතරත්න",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "සංජය මාරඹේ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ආර්.ඒ.",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "කුමාර නවරත්න",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "පැනි වෑවල",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "මවුලවි",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "යෝගේස්වරී පට්කුනරාජා",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "කාර්ය සාධක බලකාය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජීවන්ති සේනානායක",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "කාර්ය සාධක බලකාය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ගාමිණී සෙනරත්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ප්‍රධාන උපදේශක",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ලලිත් වීරතුංග",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "අනුර දිසානායක",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "\"ஒரு நாடு, ஒரே சட்டம்\" க்கான பணிக்குழு அறிக்கை அமைச்சரவைக்கு சமர்ப்பிக்கப்படும், பி.",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "“ஒரு நாடு ஒரே சட்டம்” என்ற ஜனாதிபதி செயலணியின் அறிக்கை அதன் தலைவர் ராஜகிய பண்டித வணக்கத்தால் ஜனாதிபதி கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ஷவிடம் கையளிக்கப்பட்டது. கலகொடஅத்தே ஞானசார தேரர் நேற்று.",
        "தொழில் வல்லுநர்கள், தன்னார்வ தொண்டு நிறுவனங்கள், பல்வேறு மதக் குழுக்கள், பல்வேறு சமூகங்கள், பல்கலைக்கழக சமூகம் மற்றும் சட்ட வல்லுனர்கள் உட்பட நாட்டின் அனைத்துப் பகுதிகளையும் உள்ளடக்கிய 1,200க்கும் மேற்பட்ட சாட்சிகளின் பார்வைகள் மற்றும் கருத்துகளைப் பரிசீலித்து தயாரிக்கப்பட்ட 43 பரிந்துரைகள் மற்றும் இரண்டு பின்னிணைப்புகளுடன் இந்த அறிக்கை எட்டு அத்தியாயங்களைக் கொண்டுள்ளது.",
        "இந்த அறிக்கையை அமைச்சரவைக்கும் பாராளுமன்றத்திற்கும் சமர்ப்பிக்குமாறு ஜனாதிபதி பணிப்புரை விடுத்தார்.",
        "வணக்கத்துக்குரிய தலைவர் தலைமையில் ஜனாதிபதி செயலணியை ஜனாதிபதி நியமித்தார். கலகொடஅத்தே ஞானசார தேரர், இலங்கையில் ‘ஒரே நாடு, ஒரே சட்டம்’ என்ற கருத்தினை நடைமுறைப்படுத்துவது தொடர்பில் பல்வேறு தரப்பினரின் கருத்துக்களையும் கருத்துக்களையும் ஆராய்ந்து பிரேரணைகளுடன் கூடிய கருத்துருவை சமர்பிக்கவுள்ளார்.",
        "பேராசிரியர் சாந்தி நந்தன விஜேசிங்க, சிரேஷ்ட விரிவுரையாளர் வீரவர்தனலாகே சுமேதா மஞ்சுளா, கலாநிதி என்.ஜி. சுஜீவ பண்டிதரத்ன, சட்டத்தரணி இரேஸ் செனவிரத்ன, சட்டத்தரணி டபிள்யூ.பி.ஜே.எம்.ஆர். சஞ்சய மரம்பே, ஆர்.ஏ. எரந்த குமார நவரத்ன, பானி வேவல, மௌலவி எம்.ஏ.எஸ். மொஹமட், யோகேஸ்வரி பட்குணராஜா மற்றும் ஐயம்பிள்ளை தயானந்தராஜா ஆகியோர் செயலணியின் ஏனைய உறுப்பினர்களாவர். ஜனாதிபதியின் சிரேஷ்ட உதவிச் செயலாளர் ஜீவந்தி சேனாநாயக்க செயலணியின் செயலாளராக கடமையாற்றினார்.",
        "ஜனாதிபதியின் செயலாளர் காமினி செனரத், ஜனாதிபதியின் பிரதான ஆலோசகர் லலித் வீரதுங்க மற்றும் ஜனாதிபதியின் பணிமனைகளின் பிரதானி அனுர திஸாநாயக்க ஆகியோரும் இதில் கலந்துகொண்டனர்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ஒன்று",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "ஒன்று",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "மந்திரி சபை",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ஜனாதிபதி செயலணி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஒன்று",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஒன்று",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ராஜகீய பண்டித வென்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஞானசார",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "நேற்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "எட்டு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "43",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "இரண்டு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "மந்திரி சபை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஜனாதிபதி செயலணி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "கலகொடஅத்தே ஞானசார தேரர்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஒன்று",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஒன்று",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "சாந்தி நந்தன விஜேசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "சுமேதா மஞ்சுளா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "என்.ஜி. சுஜீவ பண்டிதரத்ன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "சஞ்சய மரம்பே",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆர்.ஏ.",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "குமார நவரத்தின",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "பணி வெவல",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "மௌலவி",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "யோகேஸ்வரி பட்குணராஜா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "பணிக்குழு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜீவந்தி சேனாநாயக்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "பணிக்குழு",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "காமினி செனரத்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "முதன்மை ஆலோசகர்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "லலித் வீரதுங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "அனுர திஸாநாயக்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}