{
  "newspaper_id": "lankadeepa-lk",
  "url": "https://www.lankadeepa.lk/latest_news/නාලක-ගොඩහේවාගෙන්-ආණ්ඩුවට-චෝදනාවක්/1-615952",
  "time_ut": 1657102543,
  "original_lang": "si",
  "original_title": "නාලක ගොඩහේවාගෙන් ආණ්ඩුවට චෝදනාවක්",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "An accusation from Nalaka Godaheva to the government",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "Parliament member Dr. Nalaka Godaheva says that the government does not have a plan and does not give space to those who talk about a plan.",
        "The MP states that he did not see any plan in Prime Minister Ranil Wickramasinghe's speech in Parliament yesterday (5), and that the International Monetary Fund is currently backing away from assistance because the government does not have a proper plan.",
        "In a note on his official Facebook account, the member stated that he was ready to comment on the current economic crisis in the parliament today (6) morning, and he was informed by the office of the chief organizer of the ruling party that he would be given 3 minutes. have",
        "He has also stated that he is questioning what is the plan for building the country presented by those who get hours to speak in the parliament."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Nalaka Godaheva",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Nalaka Godaheva",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickramasinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "yesterday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "5",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "the International Monetary Fund",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "6) morning",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "3 minutes",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        []
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "නාලක ගොඩහේවාගෙන් ආණ්ඩුවට චෝදනාවක්",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "ආණ්ඩුවට සැලැස්මක් නොමැති අතර සැලස්මක් ගැන කතාකරන අයට ඉඩක් ද නොදෙන බවත් පාර්ලිමේන්තු මන්ත්‍රී ආචාර්ය නාලක ගොඩහේවා මහතා පවසයි.",
        "අගමැති රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතා පාර්ලිමේන්තුවේදී ඊයේ (5) කළ කතාවේ  කිසිඳු සැලැස්මක් තමන් නොදුටු බවත්, මේ වන විට ජාත්‍යන්තර මූල්‍ය අරමුදල ද සහයදීමට පස්ස ගසමින් සිටින්නේ ආන්ඩුවට නිසි සැලැස්මක් නොමැති නිසා බවත් මන්ත්‍රීවරයා සඳහන් කරයි.",
        "තමන් අද (6) පෙරවරුවේ පාර්ලිමේන්තුවේ දී රටේ වත්මන් ආර්ථික අර්බූදය සම්බන්ධයෙන් අදහස් දැක්වීමට සූදානමින් සිටි බවත්, තමන්ට ලබාදෙන්නේ විනාඩි 3ක් බව ආණ්ඩු පක්ෂයේ ප්‍රධාන සංවිධායක කාර්යාලයෙන් දැනුම් දුන් බවත් විනාඩි 3 කින් කිව හැක්කේ කුමක්ද යන්න ගැටලුවක් බවත් මන්ත්‍රීවරයා සිය නිල ෆේස්බුක් ගිණුමෙහි සටහනක් තබමින් සඳහන් කර තිබේ.",
        "පාර්ලිමේන්තුවේ කතා කිරීමට වරු ගනන් ලැබෙන අය ඉදිරිපත් කරන රට හදන සැලැස්ම කුමක්දැයි තමන් ප්‍රශ්න කරන බව ද ඔහු දක්වා ඇත."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "නාලක ගොඩහේවා",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "නාලක ගොඩහේවා",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඊයේ",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "5",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජාත්‍යන්තර මුල්‍ය අරමුදල",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "6) උදෑසන",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "විනාඩි 3 යි",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        []
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "நாலக கொடஹேவா அரசாங்கத்திற்கு ஒரு குற்றச்சாட்டு",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "அரசாங்கத்திடம் திட்டம் இல்லை, திட்டம் பற்றி பேசுபவர்களுக்கு இடம் கொடுப்பதில்லை என நாடாளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர் கலாநிதி நாலக கொடஹேவா கூறுகிறார்.",
        "பிரதமர் ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க நேற்று (5) பாராளுமன்றத்தில் ஆற்றிய உரையில் எந்தவொரு திட்டத்தையும் காணவில்லை எனவும், அரசாங்கத்திடம் சரியான திட்டம் இல்லாத காரணத்தினால் சர்வதேச நாணய நிதியம் தற்போது உதவி செய்வதில் இருந்து பின்வாங்குவதாகவும் எம்.பி.",
        "இன்று (6) காலை பாராளுமன்றத்தில் தற்போதைய பொருளாதார நெருக்கடி குறித்து கருத்து தெரிவிக்க தயார் என எம்.பி தனது உத்தியோகபூர்வ முகநூல் கணக்கில் பதிவிட்டுள்ள நிலையில், தனக்கு 3 வழங்கப்படும் என ஆளும் கட்சியின் பிரதம அமைப்பாளர் அலுவலகத்தினால் அறிவிக்கப்பட்டுள்ளது. நிமிடங்கள்",
        "பாராளுமன்றத்தில் மணிக்கணக்கில் பேசுபவர்கள் முன்வைக்கும் நாட்டை கட்டியெழுப்புவதற்கான திட்டம் என்ன என கேள்வி எழுப்புவதாகவும் அவர் குறிப்பிட்டுள்ளார்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "நாலக கொடஹேவா",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "நாலக கொடஹேவா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "நேற்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "5",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "சர்வதேச நாணய நிதியம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "6) காலை",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "3 நிமிடங்கள்",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        []
      ]
    }
  }
}