{
  "newspaper_id": "b-b-c-com-sinhala",
  "url": "https://www.bbc.com/sinhala/sri-lanka-62249171",
  "time_ut": 1658467011,
  "original_lang": "si",
  "original_title": "අන්තර්කාලීන ආණ්ඩුවේ අමාත්‍යවරු 18 දෙනා කවුරුන්ද?",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Who are the 18 ministers of the interim government?",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "18 ministers of the new interim government of President Ranil Wickremesinghe took oath before the President at the Prime Minister's Office today (July 22).",
        "Here, Ali Sabri has the position of Minister of Foreign Affairs and Professor G.L. Peiris, who previously held that position, has not been included in the cabinet this time.",
        "Sri Lanka Podujana Peramuna's chairman, Professor GL Peiris, has held senior ministerial positions in successive governments. But the name of Dallas Alahaperuma, who appeared for the election of the President of the Parliament held recently, was confirmed by GL Peiris.",
        "So far no new minister has been sworn in for the positions of defense and finance and accordingly the relevant subjects will be under the president."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "18",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "18",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Prime Minister's Office",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "July 22",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Ali Sabri",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "G.L. Peiris",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Podujana Peramuna's",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "GL Peiris",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Dallas Alahaperuma",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "GL Peiris",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        []
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "අන්තර්කාලීන ආණ්ඩුවේ අමාත්‍යවරු 18 දෙනා කවුරුන්ද?",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "ජනාධිපති රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහගේ නව අන්තර්කාලීන ආණ්ඩුවේ අමාත්‍යවරුන් 18 දෙනෙක් අද (ජූලි 22 වැනිදා) අග්‍රාමාත්‍ය කාර්යාලයේදී ජනාධිපතිවරයා ඉදිරියේ දිව්රුම් දුන්හ.",
        "මෙහිදී අලි සබ්රිට විදේශ කටයුතු අමාත්‍ය ධුරය හිමිව ඇති අතර මීට පෙර එම ධුරයේ කටයුතු කළ මහාචාර්ය ජී.එල් පීරිස් මෙවර කැබිනට් මණ්ඩලයට ඇතුළත් වී නොමැත.",
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකා පොදුජන පෙරමුණේ සභාපතිවරයා වන මහාචාර්ය ජී.එල් පීරීස් මේ දක්වාම පොහොට්ටු ආණ්ඩුවල ජ්‍යෙෂ්ඨ අමාත්‍ය ධුර දරනු ලැබීය. එහෙත් පසුගිය දා පැවති පාර්ලිමේන්තුවේ ජනපතිවරයා තේරීමේ ඡන්දයට ඉදිරිපත් වූ ඩලස් අලහපෙරුමගේ නම ස්ථීර කරනු ලැබුවේ ජී.එල් පීරීස් විසිනි.",
        "ආරක්ෂක, හා මුදල් යන අමාත්‍ය ධුර සඳහා මෙතෙක් නව අමාත්‍යවරයෙක් දිවුරුම් දී නොමැති අතර ඒ අනුව අදාළ විෂයපථයන් ජනාධිපතිවරයා යටතේ පවතිනු ඇත."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "18",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "18",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "අගමැති කාර්යාලය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජූලි 22",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "අලි සබ්රි",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජී.එල් පීරිස්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "පොදුජන පෙරමුණේ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජී එල් පීරිස්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඩලස් අලහපෙරුම",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජී එල් පීරිස්",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        []
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "இடைக்கால அரசாங்கத்தின் 18 அமைச்சர்கள் யார்?",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "ஜனாதிபதி ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்கவின் புதிய இடைக்கால அரசாங்கத்தின் 18 அமைச்சர்கள் இன்று (ஜூலை 22) பிரதமர் அலுவலகத்தில் ஜனாதிபதி முன்னிலையில் சத்தியப்பிரமாணம் செய்துகொண்டனர்.",
        "இங்கு அலி சப்ரிக்கு வெளிவிவகார அமைச்சர் பதவியும், முன்னர் அந்த பதவியை வகித்த பேராசிரியர் ஜி.எல்.பீரிஸ் இம்முறை அமைச்சரவையில் இடம்பெறவில்லை.",
        "ஸ்ரீலங்கா பொதுஜன பெரமுனவின் தலைவர் பேராசிரியர் ஜி.எல்.பீரிஸ், அடுத்தடுத்த அரசாங்கங்களில் சிரேஷ்ட அமைச்சுப் பதவிகளை வகித்துள்ளார். ஆனால் அண்மையில் நடைபெற்ற நாடாளுமன்றத் தலைவர் தேர்தலில் தோற்ற டலஸ் அழகப்பெருமவின் பெயரை ஜீ.எல்.பீரிஸ் உறுதிப்படுத்தினார்.",
        "பாதுகாப்பு மற்றும் நிதி ஆகிய பதவிகளுக்கு இதுவரை எந்த புதிய அமைச்சரும் பதவிப் பிரமாணம் செய்யவில்லை, அதற்கேற்ப சம்பந்தப்பட்ட துறைகள் ஜனாதிபதியின் கீழ் இருக்கும்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "18",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "18",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "பிரதமர் அலுவலகம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜூலை 22",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "அலி சப்ரி",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜி.எல்.பீரிஸ்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பொதுஜன பெரமுனவின்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜி.எல்.பீரிஸ்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "டலஸ் அழகபெரும",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜி.எல்.பீரிஸ்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        []
      ]
    }
  }
}