{
  "newspaper_id": "ada-lk",
  "url": "https://www.ada.lk/breaking_news/තුවාල-වුණ-සෙබලුන්-බලන්න-රනිල්-යනවා-අපි-මීට-කලින්-දැකලා-නෑ/11-395515",
  "time_ut": 1658145193,
  "original_lang": "si",
  "original_title": "තුවාල වුණ සෙබලුන් බලන්න රනිල් යනවා අපි මීට කලින් දැකලා නෑ",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "We have never seen Ranil visiting the wounded soldiers before",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "Former Member of Parliament Mrs. Hirunika Premachandra says that although the Acting President recently visited the Army Hospital to visit the injured soldiers, he has not done such a thing before.",
        "Also, she mentioned that the attention of the Acting Prime Minister is focused on getting the attention of some political groups to free Mr. Ranjan Ramanayake, who is currently serving a prison sentence.",
        "She also said that if Mr. Ranil Wickramasinghe becomes the President in the upcoming election to elect a President in the Parliament, it will become a factor that could turn the country into a lake of blood."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Hirunika Premachandra",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Army Hospital",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Ranjan Ramanayake",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickramasinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "තුවාල වුණ සෙබලුන් බලන්න රනිල් යනවා අපි මීට කලින් දැකලා නෑ",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "තුවාල වූ සෙබලුන් බැලීමට වැඩබලන ජනපතිවරයා පසුගියදා යුද හමුදා රෝහලට ගියත් ඔහු මීට කලින් එවැනි දෙයක් සිදුකර නොමැති බව හිටපු පාර්ලිමේන්තු මන්ත්‍රිනී හිරුණිකා ප්‍රේමචන්ද්‍ර මහත්මිය පවසයි.",
        "එසේම මේ වන විට සිර දඩුවම් විදින රන්ජන් රාමනායක මහතා නිදහස් කිරීමට වැඩබලන අග්‍රාමාත්‍යවරයාගේ අවධානය යොමුව ඇත්තේ ඇතැම් දේශපාලන කණ්ඩායම්හි අවධානය දිනා ගැනිමට බවත් ඇය සඳහන් කළාය.",
        "එසේම ඉදිරියේදී පාර්ලිමේන්තුවේදී ජනපතිවරයෙක් තෝරා ගැනිම වෙනුවෙන් පැවැත්වෙන මැතිවරණයේදී රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතා ජනපතිධුරයට පත්වුවහොත් එය රට ලේ විලක් බවට පත්විය හැකි සාධකයක් වෙනු ඇතැයිද ඇය පැවැසුවාය."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "හිරුණිකා ප්‍රේමචන්ද්‍ර",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "හමුදා රෝහල",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "රන්ජන් රාමනායක",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "காயமடைந்த இராணுவத்தினரை ரணில் சென்று பார்த்ததில்லை",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "முன்னாள் பாராளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர் திருமதி ஹிருணிகா பிரேமச்சந்திர, காயமடைந்த இராணுவத்தினரை பார்வையிடுவதற்காக பதில் ஜனாதிபதி அண்மையில் இராணுவ வைத்தியசாலைக்கு விஜயம் செய்த போதிலும், இதற்கு முன்னர் அவ்வாறானதொன்றை அவர் செய்யவில்லை என தெரிவித்துள்ளார்.",
        "மேலும், தற்போது சிறைத்தண்டனை அனுபவித்து வரும் திரு ரஞ்சன் ராமநாயக்கவை விடுவிக்க சில அரசியல் குழுக்களின் கவனத்தை ஈர்ப்பது தொடர்பில் பதில் பிரதமரின் கவனம் செலுத்தப்பட்டுள்ளதாகவும் அவர் குறிப்பிட்டுள்ளார்.",
        "பாராளுமன்றத்தில் ஜனாதிபதியை தெரிவு செய்யும் தேர்தலில் திரு.ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க ஜனாதிபதியானால் அது நாட்டை இரத்தக் குளமாக மாற்றக்கூடிய காரணியாக மாறும் எனவும் அவர் தெரிவித்துள்ளார்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஹிருணிகா பிரேமச்சந்திர",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இராணுவ மருத்துவமனை",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ரஞ்சன் ராமநாயக்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}