{
  "newspaper_id": "news-first-lk",
  "url": "https://www.newsfirst.lk/2022/09/05/opv-p-627-navy-s-latest-addition-sails-for-colombo-from-seattle/",
  "time_ut": 1662351600,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "OPV P 627 Navy’s latest addition sails for Colombo from Seattle",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "OPV P 627 Navy’s latest addition sails for Colombo from Seattle",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); The Offshore Patrol Vessel P 627, which was formally handed over to the Sri Lanka Navy by the U.S. Coast Guard in October 2021, departed for Sri Lanka from the Port of Seattle, United States on 03rd September 2022. The homebound journey began, after the modernization work of the ship to suit the operational needs of the Sri Lanka Navy.",
        "Sri Lanka Navy officially took delivery of the EX-United States Coast Guard Cutter, USCGC Douglas Munro, provided by the United States, on 26th October 2021.",
        "Subsequently, she was designated with the Pennant Number P 627 in SLN Fleet and is scheduled to be commissioned with a particular ship name, after her arrival in Sri Lanka. Ex-USCGC Douglas Munro, the second ‘Hamilton Class High Endurance Cutter’, received by the SLN measures 115m in length, capable of attaining a maximum speed of 29 knots and endurance of 14000 NM at cruising speed. Further, she has been designed for 187 of the crew and is equipped with state-of-the-art weapons and machinery.",
        "Upon official taking over of the ship, she underwent certain modernization with devices and equipment, to suit the operational needs of the Sri Lanka Navy.",
        "Intending to join her home port, P 627, led by the OPVSri Lanka Navy crew, set sail from the Port of Seattle at 0900hrs on 03rd September 2022.",
        "After a long sea voyage spanning about 02 months, P 627 is expected to arrive at the Port of Colombo in the first week of November 2022 and during the passage from Seattle to Colombo she will make port calls at Honolulu in Hawaii, Apra in Guam, United States, Manila in Philippine and Changi in Singapore for replenishment and services.",
        "In the same vein, SLN received SLNS Samudura (P 621) and Gajabahu (P 626) the Offshore Patrol Vessels from the U.S. Coast Guard on previous occasions with a view to strengthening and developing partnerships to overcome common maritime challenges at sea. The delivery of P 627 will also be a symbol of further consolidation of such partnerships and camaraderie.",
        "OPV P 627 Navy’s latest addition sails for Colombo from Seattle"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "627",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "Navy",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "Colombo",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "Seattle",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "News 1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "The Offshore Patrol Vessel",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "627",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Sri Lanka Navy",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the U.S. Coast Guard",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "October 2021",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Port of Seattle",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "United States",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Navy",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka Navy",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "USCGC",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Douglas Munro",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the United States",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "26th October 2021",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "627",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "SLN Fleet",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Douglas Munro",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "second",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "SLN",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "115",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "29",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "187",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Navy",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "627",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Navy",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Port of Seattle at",
            "label": "FAC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "about 02 months",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "627",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Port of Colombo",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "the first week of November 2022",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Seattle",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Honolulu",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Hawaii",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Guam",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "United States",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Manila",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Philippine",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Changi",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Singapore",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "SLN",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "SLNS Samudura",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "621",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Gajabahu",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "626",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Offshore Patrol Vessels",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the U.S. Coast Guard",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "627",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "627",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Navy",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Colombo",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Seattle",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "OPV P 627 නාවික හමුදාවේ නවතම එකතු කිරීම සියැටල් සිට කොළඹ බලා යාත්‍රා කරයි",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); 2021 ඔක්තෝම්බර් මාසයේදී එක්සත් ජනපද වෙරළාරක්ෂක බලකාය විසින් නිල වශයෙන් ශ්‍රී ලංකා නාවික හමුදාවට භාර දුන් අක්වෙරළ මුර යාත්‍රාව P 627, 2022 සැප්තැම්බර් 03 වන දින එක්සත් ජනපදයේ සියැටල් වරායෙන් ශ්‍රී ලංකාව බලා පිටත් විය. ශ්‍රී ලංකා නාවික හමුදාවේ මෙහෙයුම් අවශ්‍යතාවලට සරිලන පරිදි නෞකාව නවීකරණය කිරීමේ කටයුතු.",
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකා නාවික හමුදාව විසින් එක්සත් ජනපදය විසින් සපයන ලද EX-United States Coast Guard Cutter, USCGC Douglas Munro, 2021 ඔක්තෝබර් 26 වන දින නිල වශයෙන් භාර දෙන ලදී.",
        "පසුව, ඇය SLN Fleet හි Pennant Number P 627 ලෙස නම් කරන ලද අතර, ඇය ශ්‍රී ලංකාවට පැමිණීමෙන් පසු, විශේෂිත නෞකාවක නමකින් ආරම්භ කිරීමට නියමිතය. හිටපු USCGC Douglas Munro, දෙවන ‘Hamilton Class High Endurance Cutter’, SLN වෙත ලැබී ඇති අතර, දිග මීටර් 115ක් වන අතර, උපරිම වේගය ගැට 29ක් සහ 14000 NM විඳදරාගැනීමේ වේගයක් ලබා ගත හැකිය. තවද, ඇය කාර්ය මණ්ඩලයේ 187 දෙනෙකු සඳහා නිර්මාණය කර ඇති අතර නවීනතම ආයුධ සහ යන්ත්රෝපකරණවලින් සමන්විතය.",
        "නෞකාව නිල වශයෙන් භාරගැනීමෙන් පසු ඇය ශ්‍රී ලංකා නාවික හමුදාවේ මෙහෙයුම් අවශ්‍යතාවලට සරිලන පරිදි උපාංග සහ උපකරණ සමඟින් යම් යම් නවීකරණයකට ලක් විය.",
        "OPV ශ්‍රී ලංකා නාවික නෞකා කාර්ය මණ්ඩලය විසින් මෙහෙයවන ලද P 627, ඇයගේ මව් වරායට සම්බන්ධ වීමට අදහස් කරමින්, 2022 සැප්තැම්බර් 03 වන දින පැය 0900 ට සියැටල් වරායෙන් යාත්‍රා කරන ලදී.",
        "මාස 02 ක පමණ දීර්ඝ මුහුදු ගමනකින් පසු P 627 නෞකාව 2022 නොවැම්බර් මස මුල් සතියේ කොළඹ වරායට පැමිණීමට අපේක්ෂා කරන අතර සියැටල් සිට කොළඹ දක්වා ගමන් කිරීමේදී ඇය හවායි හි Honolulu, Guam හි Apra හි වරාය ඇමතුම් ලබා දෙනු ඇත. එක්සත් ජනපදය, පිලිපීනයේ මැනිලා සහ සිංගප්පූරුවේ චැන්ගි නැවත පිරවීම සහ සේවා සඳහා.",
        "ඒ ආකාරයෙන්ම, SLN වෙත එක්සත් ජනපද වෙරළාරක්ෂක බලකායෙන් SLNS සමුදුර (P 621) සහ ගජබාහු (P 626) අක්වෙරළ මුර යාත්‍රා මීට පෙර අවස්ථා වලදී මුහුදේ පොදු සමුද්‍රීය අභියෝග ජය ගැනීම සඳහා හවුල්කාරිත්වයන් ශක්තිමත් කිරීම සහ සංවර්ධනය කිරීමේ අරමුණින් ලබා ගන්නා ලදී. P 627 බෙදා හැරීම එවැනි හවුල්කාරිත්වයන් සහ සුහදත්වය තවදුරටත් තහවුරු කිරීමේ සංකේතයක් ද වනු ඇත.",
        "OPV P 627 නාවික හමුදාවේ නවතම එකතු කිරීම සියැටල් සිට කොළඹ බලා යාත්‍රා කරයි"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "627",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "නාවික",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "කොළඹ",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "සියැටල්",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "News 1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "අක්වෙරළ මුර යාත්‍රාව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "627",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකා නාවික හමුදාව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "එක්සත් ජනපද වෙරළාරක්ෂක බලකාය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඔක්තෝබර් 2021",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "සියැටල් වරාය",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "එක්සත් ජනපදය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "නාවික",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකා නාවික හමුදාව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "USCGC",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඩග්ලස් මුන්රෝ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "එක්සත් ජනපදය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "2021 ඔක්තෝබර් 26",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "627",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "SLN Fleet",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඩග්ලස් මුන්රෝ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "දෙවැනි",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "SLN",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "115",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "29",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "187",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "නාවික",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "627",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "නාවික",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "සියැටල් වරාය",
            "label": "FAC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "මාස 02 ක් පමණ",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "627",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "කොළඹ වරාය",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "2022 නොවැම්බර් පළමු සතිය",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "සියැටල්",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "හොනොලුලු",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "හවායි",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගුවාම්",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "එක්සත් ජනපදය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මැනිලා",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "පිලිපීනය",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "චංගි",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "සිංගප්පූරුව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "SLN",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකා නාවික නෞකා සමුදුර",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "621",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගජබාහු",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "626",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "අක්වෙරළ මුර යාත්‍රා",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "එක්සත් ජනපද වෙරළාරක්ෂක බලකාය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "627",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "627",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "නාවික",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "කොළඹ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "සියැටල්",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "OPV P 627 கடற்படையின் சமீபத்திய சேர்க்கை சியாட்டிலில் இருந்து கொழும்புக்கு புறப்பட்டது",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); 2021 ஆம் ஆண்டு ஒக்டோபர் மாதம் அமெரிக்க கடலோர காவல்படையினரால் இலங்கை கடற்படையிடம் முறைப்படி ஒப்படைக்கப்பட்ட கடல் ரோந்து கப்பல் P 627, செப்டம்பர் 03, 2022 அன்று அமெரிக்காவின் சியாட்டில் துறைமுகத்தில் இருந்து இலங்கைக்கு புறப்பட்டது. இலங்கை கடற்படையின் செயல்பாட்டுத் தேவைகளுக்கு ஏற்ப கப்பலின் நவீனமயமாக்கல் பணி.",
        "2021 ஆம் ஆண்டு ஒக்டோபர் 26 ஆம் திகதி அமெரிக்காவினால் வழங்கப்பட்ட EX-United States Coast Guard Cutter, USCGC Douglas Munro ஐ இலங்கை கடற்படை உத்தியோகபூர்வமாக வழங்கியது.",
        "பின்னர், அவர் SLN கடற்படையில் P 627 என்ற பென்னன்ட் இலக்கத்துடன் நியமிக்கப்பட்டார், மேலும் அவர் இலங்கைக்கு வந்த பிறகு ஒரு குறிப்பிட்ட கப்பலின் பெயரில் பணியமர்த்தப்படுவார். முன்னாள் யுஎஸ்சிஜிசி டக்ளஸ் மன்ரோ, இரண்டாவது ‘ஹாமில்டன் கிளாஸ் ஹை எண்டூரன்ஸ் கட்டர்’, எஸ்எல்என் மூலம் பெறப்பட்டது, 115மீ நீளம் கொண்டது, அதிகபட்ச வேகம் 29 நாட்கள் மற்றும் 14000 என்எம் தாங்கும் திறன் கொண்டது. மேலும், அவர் 187 குழுவினருக்காக வடிவமைக்கப்பட்டுள்ளது மற்றும் அதிநவீன ஆயுதங்கள் மற்றும் இயந்திரங்களுடன் பொருத்தப்பட்டுள்ளது.",
        "உத்தியோகபூர்வ கப்பலை பொறுப்பேற்றதும், அவர் இலங்கை கடற்படையின் செயல்பாட்டுத் தேவைகளுக்கு ஏற்றவாறு சாதனங்கள் மற்றும் உபகரணங்களுடன் சில நவீனமயமாக்கலுக்கு உட்பட்டார்.",
        "OPVSri Lanka கடற்படைக் குழுவின் தலைமையிலான P 627, தனது சொந்த துறைமுகத்தில் சேர எண்ணி, 03 செப்டம்பர் 2022 அன்று சியாட்டில் துறைமுகத்தில் இருந்து 0900hrsக்கு புறப்பட்டது.",
        "சுமார் 02 மாதங்கள் நீடித்த கடல் பயணத்திற்குப் பிறகு, P 627 2022 நவம்பர் முதல் வாரத்தில் கொழும்பு துறைமுகத்தை வந்தடையும் என்று எதிர்பார்க்கப்படுகிறது, மேலும் சியாட்டிலில் இருந்து கொழும்புக்கு செல்லும் போது, ​​ஹவாய், குவாமில் உள்ள அப்ராவில் உள்ள ஹொனலுலுவில் துறைமுக அழைப்புகளை மேற்கொள்ளும். அமெரிக்கா, பிலிப்பைன்ஸில் உள்ள மணிலா மற்றும் சிங்கப்பூரில் உள்ள சாங்கி ஆகியவை நிரப்புதல் மற்றும் சேவைகளுக்காக.",
        "அதே பாணியில், கடலில் பொதுவான கடல்சார் சவால்களை சமாளிக்க கூட்டாண்மைகளை வலுப்படுத்தும் மற்றும் மேம்படுத்தும் நோக்கில் முந்தைய சந்தர்ப்பங்களில் அமெரிக்க கடலோர காவல்படையிலிருந்து SLN சமுதுரா (P 621) மற்றும் கஜபாஹு (P 626) கடல் ரோந்து கப்பல்களை SLN பெற்றது. P 627 இன் விநியோகமானது அத்தகைய கூட்டாண்மை மற்றும் நட்புறவை மேலும் பலப்படுத்துவதற்கான அடையாளமாகவும் இருக்கும்.",
        "OPV P 627 கடற்படையின் சமீபத்திய சேர்க்கை சியாட்டிலில் இருந்து கொழும்புக்கு புறப்பட்டது"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "627",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "கடற்படை",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "கொழும்பு",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "சியாட்டில்",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "News 1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "கடல் ரோந்து கப்பல்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "627",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை கடற்படை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "அமெரிக்க கடலோர காவல்படை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "அக்டோபர் 2021",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சியாட்டில் துறைமுகம்",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "அமெரிக்கா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "கடற்படை",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை கடற்படை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "USCGC",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "டக்ளஸ் மன்ரோ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஐக்கிய நாடுகள்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "26 அக்டோபர் 2021",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "627",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "SLN கடற்படை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "டக்ளஸ் மன்ரோ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இரண்டாவது",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "எஸ்.எல்.என்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "115",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "29",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "187",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "கடற்படை",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "627",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "கடற்படை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "சியாட்டில் துறைமுகத்தில்",
            "label": "FAC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "சுமார் 02 மாதங்கள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "627",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "கொழும்பு துறைமுகம்",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "நவம்பர் 2022 முதல் வாரம்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சியாட்டில்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஹொனலுலு",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஹவாய்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "குவாம்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "அமெரிக்கா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "மணிலா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "பிலிப்பைன்ஸ்",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "சாங்கி",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "சிங்கப்பூர்",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "எஸ்.எல்.என்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "SLNS சமுதுரா",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "621",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "கஜபாகு",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "626",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "கடல் ரோந்து கப்பல்கள்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "அமெரிக்க கடலோர காவல்படை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "627",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "627",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "கடற்படை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "கொழும்பு",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "சியாட்டில்",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}