{
  "newspaper_id": "virakesari-lk",
  "url": "http://www.virakesari.lk/article/130833",
  "time_ut": 1657011468,
  "original_lang": "ta",
  "original_title": "உயிர்த்த ஞாயிறுத் தாக்குதல் ; காத்தான்குடியைச் சேர்ந்த 51 பேருக்கும் தொடர்ந்து விளக்கமறியல்",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Easter Sunday attack; 51 people from Kathankudi were also arrested",
      "author": "T. Saranya",
      "body_lines": [
        "The Batticaloa Magistrate, Judge Peter Pol, today Tuesday (05) ordered through a video to remand the 51 people who were arrested in Kathankudi area in connection with the Easter Sunday attack and who were trained in Sahran's training camp and who were arrested and kept in remand on suspicion of maintaining contact with him, until the 19th of July.",
        "After the attack that took place on 21st April 2021 last Easter Sunday, 69 people including Sahran's sister and her husband were arrested by people from Kathankudi on the suspicion that they were related to Sahran's group and that they had gone to places like Ambanthotai and Nuwaraeliya for training.",
        "Katankudi police filed a case against those arrested and they were kept in remand.",
        "Saran's sister and her husband's cases were transferred from the Magistrate's Court to the High Court, 5 people were acquitted and 15 people were released on bail, and 51 people were kept under remand in jails like Polonnaruwa, Anudarapuram, Kegala, Badulai, Trincomalee etc.",
        "In this situation today, when this case was taken up for trial in the presence of the Batticaloa Magistrate's Court, the judge ordered that the 51 people in various prisons in the country should be kept in remand until the next 19th through video, considering the situation in which the people in various prisons in the country have not been brought."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Sunday",
          "label": "DATE"
        },
        {
          "text": "51",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "Kathankudi",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "The Batticaloa Magistrate",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Peter Pol",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "today Tuesday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "05",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "51",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kathankudi",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Easter",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sunday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sahran",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the 19th of July",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "21st April 2021",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Easter",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sunday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "69",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sahran",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kathankudi",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sahran",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ambanthotai",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Nuwaraeliya",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "Saran",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Magistrate",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the High Court",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "5",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "15",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "51",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Polonnaruwa",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Anudarapuram",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kegala",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Badulai",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Trincomalee",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Batticaloa Magistrate's Court",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "51",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "the next 19th",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "පාස්කු ඉරිදා ප්‍රහාරය; කාතන්කුඩි ප්‍රදේශයේ පුද්ගලයන් 51 දෙනෙකු ද අත්අඩංගුවට ගෙන තිබෙනවා",
      "author": "T. Saranya",
      "body_lines": [
        "පාස්කු ඉරිදා ප්‍රහාරය සම්බන්ධයෙන් කාතන්කුඩි ප්‍රදේශයේදී අත්අඩංගුවට ගෙන සහරාන්ගේ පුහුණු කඳවුරේ පුහුණුව ලැබූ සහ අත්අඩංගුවට ගෙන රඳවා තබාගෙන සිටි පුද්ගලයින් 51 දෙනා යළි රක්ෂිත බන්ධනාගාර ගත කරන ලෙස මඩකලපුව මහේස්ත්‍රාත් විනිසුරු පීටර් පෝල් මහතා අද අඟහරුවාදා (05) වීඩියෝවක් මගින් නියෝග කළේය. ඔහු සමඟ සම්බන්ධතා පැවැත්වූ බවට සැකපිට ජූලි 19 දක්වා රිමාන්ඩ්.",
        "පසුගිය 2021 අප්‍රේල් 21 පාස්කු ඉරිදා සිදුවූ ප්‍රහාරයෙන් පසු සහරාන්ගේ නංගී සහ ඇගේ සැමියා ඇතුළු 69 දෙනෙකු සහරාන්ගේ කණ්ඩායමට නෑකම් කියන සහ අඹන්තොට, නුවරඑළිය වැනි ප්‍රදේශවලට ගොස් ඇති බවට සැකපිට කාතන්කුඩි ප්‍රදේශයේ පුද්ගලයන් විසින් අත්අඩංගුවට ගන්නා ලදී. පුහුණුව.",
        "අත්අඩංගුවට ගත් පිරිසට එරෙහිව කාතන්කුඩි පොලිසිය නඩු පවරා ඔවුන් රිමාන්ඩ් භාරයේ තබා ඇත.",
        "සරණගේ සහෝදරියගේ සහ ඇගේ සැමියාගේ නඩු මහේස්ත්‍රාත් අධිකරණයෙන් මහාධිකරණයට මාරු කර 5 දෙනෙකු නිදොස් කොට 15 දෙනෙකු ඇප මත නිදහස් කර 51 දෙනෙකු පොළොන්නරුව, අනුරාධපුර, කෑගල, බදුලේ, ත්‍රිකුණාමලය ආදී බන්ධනාගාරවල රිමාන්ඩ් භාරයේ තබා ඇත.",
        "මේ තත්ත්වය තුළ අද මෙම නඩුව මඩකලපුව මහේස්ත්‍රාත් අධිකරණය හමුවේ විභාගයට ගත් අවස්ථාවේදී තත්ත්වය සලකා බලා දිවයිනේ විවිධ බන්ධනාගාරවල සිටින 51 දෙනා ලබන 19 වැනිදා දක්වා රක්ෂිත බන්ධනාගාරගත කරන ලෙස විනිසුරුවරයා නියෝග කළේ වීඩියෝ පටයෙනි. එහි දී රටේ විවිධ බන්ධනාගාරවල සිටින පිරිස් ගෙනවිත් නැහැ."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ඉරිදා",
          "label": "DATE"
        },
        {
          "text": "51",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "කාතන්කුඩි",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ඒ මඩකලපුව මහේස්ත්‍රාත්වරයා",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "පීටර් පොල්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "අද අඟහරුවාදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "05",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "51",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "කාතන්කුඩි",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාස්කු",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉරිදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "සහරාන්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජූලි 19 වෙනිදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "2021 අප්‍රේල් 21",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාස්කු",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉරිදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "69",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "සහරාන්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "කාතන්කුඩි",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "සහරාන්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "අඹන්තොටයි",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "නුවරඑළිය",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "සරන්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "මහේස්ත්රාත්වරයා",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "මහාධිකරණය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "5",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "15",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "51",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "පොළොන්නරුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "අනුදරපුරම්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "කෑගල",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "බදුලෙයි",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ත්රිකුණාමලය",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඒ මඩකලපුව මහේස්ත්‍රාත් අධිකරණයෙන්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "51",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඊළඟ 19 වැනිදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "உயிர்த்த ஞாயிறுத் தாக்குதல் ; காத்தான்குடியைச் சேர்ந்த 51 பேருக்கும் தொடர்ந்து விளக்கமறியல்",
      "author": "T. Saranya",
      "body_lines": [
        "உயிர்த்த ஞாயிறுத் தாக்குதல் தொடர்பாக காத்தான்குடி பிரதேசத்தில் கைது செய்யப்பட்ட சஹ்ரானின் பயிற்சி முகாமில் பயற்சிபெற்ற மற்றும் அவருடன் தொடர்பை பேணி வந்தது தொடர்பாக சந்தேகத்தில் கைது செய்யப்பட்டு தொடர்ந்து விளக்கமறியல் வைக்கப்பட்டிருந்த 51 பேரையும்  எதிர்வரும் யூலை 19 திகதிவரை விளக்கமறியலில் வைக்குமாறு மட்டக்களப்பு நீதவான் நீதிமன்ற நீதவான் பீற்றர் போல் இன்று செவ்வாய்க்கிழமை (05) காணொளி மூலம் உத்தரவிட்டார்.",
        "கடந்த 2021 ஆம் ஆண்டு ஏப்ரல் மாதம் 21 ஆம் திகதி  உயிர்த்த ஞாயிறன்று இடம் பெற்ற தாக்குதலின் பின்னர் சஹ்ரான் குழுவோடு தொடர்புடையவர்கள் என்றும் இவர்கள் அம்பாந்தோட்டை மற்றும் நுவரேலியா போன்ற இடங்களுக்கு பயிற்சிக்காக சென்றார்கள் என்ற சந்தேகத்தின பேரில் காத்தான்குடியை சேர்ந்தவர்கள் சஹ்ரானின் சகோதரி மற்றும் அவரின் கணவர் உட்பட  69 பேரை கைது செய்தனர்.",
        "இவ்வாறு கைது செய்யப்பட்டவர்களுக்கு எதிராக காத்தான்குடி பொலிஸார் வழக்கு தாக்குல் மேற்கொண்டனர் இவர்கள் அனைவரும் தொடர்ந்து விளக்கமறியலில் வைக்கப்பட்னர்.",
        "இதில் ஸாரானின் சகோதரி மற்றும் அவரின் கணவர்,ஆகியோரது வழக்குகள் நீதவான் நீதிமன்றில் இருந்து உயர் நீதிமன்றத்துக்கு மாற்றப்பட்டதுடன், 5 பேர் வழக்கில் இருந்து விடுவித்து விடுதலை செய்யப்பட்டதுடன் 15 பேர் பிணையில் விடுவிக்கப்பட்டதையடுத்து 51 பேர் தொடர்ந்தும் நாட்டிலுள்ள பொலன்னறுவை, அனுதாரபுரம், கேகாலை, பதுளை, திருகோணமலை, போன்ற சிறைச்சாலைகளில் அடைக்கப்பட்டு தொடர்ந்து விளக்கமறியலில் வைக்கப்பட்டனர்.",
        "இந்த நிலையில் இன்று மட்டக்களப்பு நீதவான் நீதிமன்ற நீதவான் முன்னிலையில்  இந்த வழக்கு விசாரணைக்கு எடுக்கப்பட்டபோது நாட்டில் பல்வேறு சிறைச்சாலைகளில் உள்ளவர்களை தற்போதைய நாட்டின் எரிபொருள் சூழ்நிலை காரணமாக  அழைத்துவரப்படாத நிலையினை கருத்தில் கொண்டு காணொளி மூலமாக  51 பேரையும் எதிர்வரும் 19 திகதிவரை தொடர்ந்து விளக்கமறியலில் வைக்குமாறு நீதவான் உத்தரவிட்டார்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ஞாயிற்றுக்கிழமை",
          "label": "DATE"
        },
        {
          "text": "51",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "காத்தான்குடி",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "மட்டக்களப்பு நீதவான்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "பீட்டர் போல்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று செவ்வாய்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "05",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "51",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "காத்தான்குடி",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஈஸ்டர்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஞாயிற்றுக்கிழமை",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சஹ்ரான்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜூலை 19 ஆம் தேதி",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "21 ஏப்ரல் 2021",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஈஸ்டர்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஞாயிற்றுக்கிழமை",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "69",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "சஹ்ரான்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "காத்தான்குடி",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "சஹ்ரான்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "அம்பாந்தோட்டை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "நுவரேலியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "சரண்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "மாஜிஸ்திரேட்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "உயர் நீதிமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "5",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "15",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "51",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "பொலன்னறுவை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "அனுதாராபுரம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "கேகல",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "பதுளை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "திருகோணமலை",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "மட்டக்களப்பு நீதவான் நீதிமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "51",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "அடுத்த 19 ஆம் தேதி",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}