{
  "newspaper_id": "tamil-mirror-lk",
  "url": "https://www.tamilmirror.lk/செய்திகள்/அவசரகாலநிலையை-வாபஸ்-பெறவேண்டும்/175-300660",
  "time_ut": 1658149310,
  "original_lang": "ta",
  "original_title": "அவசரகாலநிலையை வாபஸ் பெறவேண்டும்",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Emergency should be withdrawn",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "The Bar Association of Sri Lanka has urged the recall of the state of emergency declared by Acting President Ranil Wickremesinghe.",
        "This matter has been indicated in the statement issued today (18) with the signatures of the president of the association, President's Attorney Saliya Peiris, and the secretary of the association, Isuru Balapattabendi.",
        "The Sri Lankan Bar Association also stated that freedom of expression including the right to freedom of expression, freedom of speech and freedom of assembly should be upheld.",
        "In addition, it is mentioned in the statement of the association that the basic rights of the public should be ensured and the sovereignty of the people should not be allowed to be violated by the government or its agents."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "The Bar Association of Sri Lanka",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "18",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Saliya Peiris",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Isuru Balapattabendi",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "The Sri Lankan Bar Association",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        []
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "හදිසි නීතිය ඉවත් කළ යුතුයි",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "වැඩබලන ජනාධිපති රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ විසින් ප්‍රකාශයට පත් කර ඇති හදිසි නීතිය යළි කැඳවන ලෙස ශ්‍රී ලංකා නීතීඥ සංගමය ඉල්ලා සිටියි.",
        "එම සංගමයේ සභාපති ජනාධිපති නීතිඥ සාලිය පීරිස් සහ එම සංගමයේ ලේකම් ඉසුරු බාලපට්ටබැඳි යන මහත්වරුන්ගේ අත්සනින් යුතුව අද (18) නිකුත් කළ නිවේදනයේ මේ බව පෙන්වා දී ඇත.",
        "අදහස් ප්‍රකාශ කිරීමේ අයිතිය, භාෂණයේ නිදහස, රැස්වීමේ නිදහස ඇතුළු අදහස් ප්‍රකාශ කිරීමේ නිදහස තහවුරු කළ යුතු බව ද ශ්‍රී ලංකා නීතිඥ සංගමය ප්‍රකාශ කළා.",
        "ඊට අමතරව මහජනතාවගේ මූලික අයිතිවාසිකම් තහවුරු කළ යුතු බවත් ජනතා පරමාධිපත්‍යය රජයට හෝ නියෝජිතයින්ට කඩ කිරීමට ඉඩ නොතැබිය යුතු බවත් එම සංගමයේ නිවේදනයේ සඳහන් වේ."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකා නීතිඥ සංගමය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "18",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "සාලිය පීරිස්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉසුරු බාලපට්ටබැඳි",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකා නීතිඥ සංගමය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        []
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "அவசரகாலநிலையை வாபஸ் பெறவேண்டும்",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "பதில் ஜனாதிபதி ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்கவினால் அமுல்படுத்தப்பட்டுள்ள அவசரகால நிலை பிரகடனத்தை மீளப்பெற வேண்டும் என்று இலங்கை சட்டத்தரணிகள் சங்கம் வலியுறுத்தியுள்ளது.",
        "சங்கத்தின் தலைவர் ஜனாதிபதி சட்டத்தரணி சாலிய பீரிஸ், சங்கத்தின் செயலாளர் இசுரு பாலபட்டபெந்தி ஆகியோரின் கையொப்பத்துடன், இன்று (18) வெளியிடப்பட்ட அறிக்கையிலேயே இவ்விடயம் சுட்டிக்காட்டப்பட்டுள்ளது.",
        "கருத்து வௌியிடும் உரிமை, பேச்சுச் சுதந்திரம், சுதந்திரமாக ஒன்றுகூடுவதற்கான உரிமை உள்ளிட்ட வௌிப்படுத்துவதற்கான சுதந்திரத்தை உறுதிப்படுத்துமாறும் இலங்கை சட்டத்தரணிகள் சங்கம் குறிப்பிட்டுள்ளது.",
        "அத்துடன், பொதுமக்களின் அடிப்படை உரிமைகளை உறுதிப்படுத்துமாறும் மக்களின் இறைமையை அரசாங்கமோ, முகவர்களோ மீறுவதற்கு இடமளிக்க வேண்டாமெனவும் சங்கத்தின் அறிக்கையில் குறிப்பிடப்பட்டுள்ளது."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை சட்டத்தரணிகள் சங்கம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "18",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "சாலிய பீரிஸ்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இசுரு பாலபட்டபெந்தி",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை சட்டத்தரணிகள் சங்கம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        []
      ]
    }
  }
}