{
  "newspaper_id": "ada-derana-lk",
  "url": "http://www.adaderana.lk/news/84759/met-department-issues-red-alert-for-heavy-rains",
  "time_ut": 1662357060,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Met. Department issues red alert for heavy rains",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Met. Department issues red alert for heavy rains",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "The Department of Meteorology has issued a ‘Red’ alert warning for heavy rain in several provinces and districts today.",
        "Showers will occur at times in the Western, Sabaragamuwa and North-Western provinces and in Kandy, Nuwara-Eliya, Galle and Matara districts.",
        "Very heavy showers above 150mm may occur at some places in Western and Sabaragamuwa provinces and in Kandy, Nuwara-Eliya, Galle and Matara districts, it said.",
        "People living in hilly areas (particularly landslide prone areas) and low-lying areas in river basins are requested to be vigilant while motorists and people using roads in the hilly areas are also requested to be vigilant.",
        "The general public is requested to take adequate precautions to minimize damages caused by lightning activity.",
        "Meanwhile, the Met. Depart has issued a separate advisory for the sea areas extending from Puttalam to Pottuvil via Colombo, Galle and Hambanthota.",
        "The ‘Red’ alert says strong winds gusting up to 60-70 kmph and very rough seas can be expected in the sea areas off the coast extending from Puttalam to Pottuvil via Colombo, Galle and Hambantota due to active Southwest Monsoon condition.",
        "There is a possibility to increase swell waves (about 2.5 – 3.0 m) in the above sea areas.",
        "Therefore, it is advised not to venture into fishing and naval activities in the above sea areas during the next 24 hours."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "The Department of Meteorology",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sabaragamuwa",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "North-Western",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kandy",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Galle",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Matara",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "150mm",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sabaragamuwa",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kandy",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Galle",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Matara",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "Met",
            "label": "PRODUCT"
          },
          {
            "text": "Depart",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Puttalam",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Galle",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Hambanthota",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "60-70 kmph",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "Puttalam",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Galle",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Hambantota",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Southwest Monsoon",
            "label": "LOC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "about 2.5",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the next 24 hours",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "හමුවුණා. තද වැසි ගැන දෙපාර්තමේන්තුව රතු නිවේදනයක් නිකුත් කරයි",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "කාලගුණ විද්‍යා දෙපාර්තමේන්තුව අද දිනයේ පළාත් සහ දිස්ත්‍රික්ක කිහිපයකට තද වැසි ඇති විය හැකි බවට ‘රතු’ නිවේදනයක් නිකුත් කර තිබේ.",
        "බස්නාහිර, සබරගමුව සහ වයඹ පළාත්වලත් මහනුවර, නුවරඑළිය, ගාල්ල සහ මාතර දිස්ත්‍රික්කවලත් විටින් විට වැසි ඇති වේ.",
        "බස්නාහිර සහ සබරගමුව පළාත්වලත් මහනුවර, නුවරඑළිය, ගාල්ල සහ මාතර දිස්ත්‍රික්කවලත් ඇතැම් ස්ථානවලට මිලිමීටර් 150 ට වැඩි ඉතා තද වැසි ඇති විය හැකි බව එම නිවේදනයේ සඳහන් වේ.",
        "කඳුකර ප්‍රදේශවල (විශේෂයෙන් නාය යාම් අවදානම් සහිත ප්‍රදේශ) සහ ගංගා ද්‍රෝණි ආශ්‍රිත පහත් බිම්වල වෙසෙන ජනතාව අවධානයෙන් පසුවන ලෙස ඉල්ලා සිටින අතර කඳුකර ප්‍රදේශවල මාර්ග භාවිත කරන රියදුරන්ගෙන් සහ මාර්ග භාවිත කරන ජනතාවගෙන්ද විමසිලිමත් වන ලෙස ඉල්ලා සිටියි.",
        "අකුණු මඟින් සිදුවන අනතුරු අවම කර ගැනීමට අවශ්‍ය පියවර ගන්නා ලෙස මහජනතාවගෙන් ඉල්ලා සිටිනු ලැබේ.",
        "මේ අතර, මෙට්. පුත්තලම සිට කොළඹ, ගාල්ල සහ හම්බන්තොට හරහා පොතුවිල් දක්වා වන මුහුදු ප්‍රදේශ සඳහා Depart විසින් වෙනම උපදේශනයක් නිකුත් කර ඇත.",
        "සක්‍රීය නිරිතදිග මෝසම් තත්ත්වය හේතුවෙන් පුත්තලම සිට කොළඹ, ගාල්ල සහ හම්බන්තොට හරහා පොතුවිල් දක්වා වෙරළට ඔබ්බෙන් වන මුහුදු ප්‍රදේශවල පැයට කිලෝමීටර් 60-70 දක්වා තද සුළං ඇති විය හැකි අතර එම මුහුදු ප්‍රදේශ ඉතා රළු විය හැකි බව ‘රතු’ නිවේදනයේ දැක්වේ.",
        "ඉහත මුහුදු ප්‍රදේශවල රළ (මීටර් 2.5 - 3.0 පමණ) වැඩි වීමේ හැකියාවක් පවතී.",
        "එබැවින් ඉදිරි පැය 24 තුළ ඉහත මුහුදු ප්‍රදේශවල ධීවර හා නාවික කටයුතුවල නොයෙදෙන ලෙසට උපදෙස් දෙනු ලැබේ."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "කාලගුණ විද්‍යා දෙපාර්තමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "සබරගමුව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "වයඹ",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "මහනුවර",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගාල්ල",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මාතර",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "150 මි.මී",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "සබරගමුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "මහනුවර",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගාල්ල",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මාතර",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "හමුවුණා",
            "label": "PRODUCT"
          },
          {
            "text": "පිටත් වෙනවා",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "පුත්තලම",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගාල්ල",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "හම්බන්තොට",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "60-70 kmph",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "පුත්තලම",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගාල්ල",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "හම්බන්තොට",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "නිරිතදිග මෝසම්",
            "label": "LOC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "2.5 ක් පමණ වේ",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ඊළඟ පැය 24",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "சந்தித்தார். கனமழைக்கு திணைக்களம் சிவப்பு எச்சரிக்கை விடுத்துள்ளது",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "வளிமண்டலவியல் திணைக்களம் இன்று பல மாகாணங்கள் மற்றும் மாவட்டங்களில் பலத்த மழை பெய்யும் என ‘ரெட்’ அலர்ட் எச்சரிக்கை விடுத்துள்ளது.",
        "மேல், சப்ரகமுவ மற்றும் வடமேல் மாகாணங்களிலும் கண்டி, நுவரெலியா, காலி மற்றும் மாத்தறை மாவட்டங்களிலும் அவ்வப்போது மழை பெய்யும்.",
        "மேல் மற்றும் சப்ரகமுவ மாகாணங்களிலும் கண்டி, நுவரெலியா, காலி மற்றும் மாத்தறை மாவட்டங்களிலும் சில இடங்களில் 150 மில்லிமீற்றருக்கும் அதிகமான பலத்த மழை பெய்யக்கூடும் என தெரிவிக்கப்பட்டுள்ளது.",
        "மலைப்பாங்கான பகுதிகளில் வசிக்கும் மக்கள் (குறிப்பாக மண்சரிவு அபாயம் உள்ள பகுதிகள்) மற்றும் ஆற்றுப்படுகைகளில் தாழ்வான பகுதிகளில் வசிப்பவர்கள் அவதானமாக இருக்குமாறும், வாகன சாரதிகள் மற்றும் மலைப்பாங்கான பகுதிகளில் வீதிகளை பயன்படுத்துபவர்கள் அவதானமாக இருக்குமாறும் கோரப்பட்டுள்ளது.",
        "மின்னல் தாக்கங்களினால் ஏற்படக்கூடிய பாதிப்புகளை குறைத்துக்கொள்ள போதிய முன்னெச்சரிக்கை நடவடிக்கைகளை எடுத்துக் கொள்ளுமாறு பொது மக்கள் கேட்டுக்கொள்ளப்படுகிறார்கள்.",
        "இதற்கிடையில், மெட். புத்தளத்திலிருந்து கொழும்பு, காலி மற்றும் ஹம்பாந்தோட்டை ஊடாக பொத்துவில் வரையான கடற்பரப்புகளுக்கு டிபார்ட் தனியான ஆலோசனையை வழங்கியுள்ளது.",
        "தென்மேற்கு பருவக்காற்று செயலிழந்ததன் காரணமாக புத்தளத்திலிருந்து கொழும்பு, காலி மற்றும் ஹம்பாந்தோட்டை ஊடாக பொத்துவில் வரையான கடற்பரப்புகளில் மணிக்கு 60-70 கிலோமீற்றர் வேகத்தில் பலத்த காற்று வீசுவதுடன் கடல் மிகவும் கொந்தளிப்பாகவும் காணப்படும் என சிவப்பு எச்சரிக்கை விடுக்கப்பட்டுள்ளது.",
        "மேற்குறிப்பிட்ட கடற்பரப்புகளில் அலைகள் (சுமார் 2.5 – 3.0 மீ) அதிகரிக்கும் சாத்தியம் உள்ளது.",
        "எனவே, அடுத்த 24 மணித்தியாலங்களுக்கு மேற்படி கடற்பரப்புகளில் மீன்பிடி மற்றும் கடற்படை நடவடிக்கைகளில் ஈடுபட வேண்டாம் என அறிவுறுத்தப்பட்டுள்ளது."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "வளிமண்டலவியல் திணைக்களம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "சப்ரகமுவ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "வடமேற்கு",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "கண்டி",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "காலி",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "மாத்தறை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "150மிமீ",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "சப்ரகமுவ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "கண்டி",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "காலி",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "மாத்தறை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "சந்தித்தார்",
            "label": "PRODUCT"
          },
          {
            "text": "புறப்படு",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "புத்தளம்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "காலி",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "அம்பாந்தோட்டை",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "மணிக்கு 60-70 கி.மீ",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "புத்தளம்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "காலி",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஹம்பாந்தோட்டை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "தென்மேற்கு பருவக்காற்று",
            "label": "LOC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "சுமார் 2.5",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "அடுத்த 24 மணி நேரம்",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}