{
  "newspaper_id": "economy-next-com",
  "url": "https://economynext.com/sri-lankas-paris-club-creditors-ready-to-start-debt-talks-99408/",
  "time_ut": 1662249480,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Sri Lanka’s Paris Club creditors ready to start debt talks",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Sri Lanka’s Paris Club creditors ready to start debt talks",
      "author": "",
      "body_lines": [
        "ECONOMYNEXT – Members of the Paris Club of mainly Western creditor said they are ready to talk with Sri Lanka on re-structuring debt after the country concluded a staff level agreement with the International Monetary Fund.",
        "“We note the IMF’s assessment for the need for a debt treatment in the context of the IMF program,” the organization’s secretariat said in a statement.",
        "“The Paris Club is ready to start the debt treatment process and reiterates its willingness to coordinate with non-Paris Club official bilateral creditors to provide the necessary financing assurances in a timely manner and ensure fair burden sharing, as already proposed to the largest other official bilateral creditors.",
        "“The Paris Club remains at the disposal of Sri Lankan authorities and non-Paris Club official bilateral creditors to further discuss the next steps of the debt treatment process.”",
        "Sri Lanka’s bi-lateral creditors include China and India who are not full members of the grouping.",
        "Sri Lanka defaulted on its debt in April 2012 after its foreign debt started to climb and growth slowed after the end of a war due to increased monetary instability coming from lower interest rates maintained under flexible inflation targeting which triggered three currency crises over seven years."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Sri Lanka’s",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "Paris Club",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "the Paris Club",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the International Monetary Fund",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "IMF",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "IMF",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "non-Paris Club",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "The Paris Club",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lankan",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "non-Paris Club",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka’s",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "China",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "India",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "April 2012",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "three",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "seven years",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "Sri Lanka’s Paris Club ණයහිමියන් ණය සාකච්ඡා ආරම්භ කිරීමට සූදානම්",
      "author": "",
      "body_lines": [
        "ECONOMYNEXT - ජාත්‍යන්තර මූල්‍ය අරමුදල සමඟ කාර්ය මණ්ඩල මට්ටමේ ගිවිසුමක් රට අවසන් කිරීමෙන් පසු ණය ප්‍රතිව්‍යුහගත කිරීම පිළිබඳව ශ්‍රී ලංකාව සමඟ කතා කිරීමට තමන් සූදානම් බව ප්‍රධාන වශයෙන් බටහිර ණයහිමියන්ගේ පැරිස් සමාජයේ සාමාජිකයන් ප්‍රකාශ කළහ.",
        "\"IMF වැඩසටහනේ සන්දර්භය තුළ ණය ප්රතිකාර සඳහා අවශ්යතාවය සඳහා IMF හි තක්සේරුව අපි සටහන් කරමු\" යනුවෙන් සංවිධානයේ ලේකම් කාර්යාලය නිවේදනයක් නිකුත් කරමින් කියා සිටියේය.",
        "“පැරිස් සමාජය ණය ප්‍රතිකාර ක්‍රියාවලිය ආරම්භ කිරීමට සුදානම් වන අතර විශාලතම අනෙකුත් නිලධාරියාට දැනටමත් යෝජනා කර ඇති පරිදි අවශ්‍ය මූල්‍ය සහතික කිරීම් නියමිත වේලාවට සැපයීමට සහ සාධාරණ බර බෙදාගැනීම සහතික කිරීමට පැරිස් නොවන නිල ද්විපාර්ශ්වික ණය හිමියන් සමඟ සම්බන්ධීකරණය කිරීමට ඇති කැමැත්ත නැවත අවධාරණය කරයි. ද්විපාර්ශ්වික ණය හිමියන්.",
        "\"ණය පිරියම් කිරීමේ ක්‍රියාවලියේ මීළඟ පියවර තවදුරටත් සාකච්ඡා කිරීම සඳහා පැරිස් සමාජය ශ්‍රී ලංකා බලධාරීන්ගේ සහ පැරිස් ක්ලබ් නොවන නිල ද්විපාර්ශ්වික ණය හිමියන්ගේ අභිමතය පරිදි පවතී.\"",
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ ද්විපාර්ශ්වික ණය හිමියන්ට සමූහයේ පූර්ණ සාමාජිකයන් නොවන චීනය සහ ඉන්දියාව ඇතුළත් වේ.",
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකාව 2012 අපේ‍්‍රල් මාසයේදී සිය ණය පැහැර හැරීමට පටන් ගත්තේ එහි විදේශ නය ඉහළ යාමට පටන් ගැනීමෙන් පසුව සහ යුද්ධය අවසන් වීමෙන් පසු වර්ධනය මන්දගාමී වීම හේතුවෙන් වසර හතක් පුරා ව්‍යවහාර මුදල් අර්බුද තුනක් ඇති කළ නම්‍යශීලී උද්ධමන ඉලක්ක යටතේ පවත්වා ගෙන ගිය අඩු පොලී අනුපාත හේතුවෙන් ඉහළ ගිය මූල්‍ය අස්ථාවරත්වය හේතුවෙනි."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "පැරිස් සමාජය",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "පැරිස් සමාජය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජාත්‍යන්තර මුල්‍ය අරමුදල",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "IMF",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "IMF",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "පැරිස් නොවන සමාජය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "පැරිස් සමාජය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලාංකික",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "පැරිස් නොවන සමාජය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "චීනය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "2012 අප්රේල්",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "තුන්",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "අවුරුදු හතක්",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "இலங்கையின் பரிஸ் கிளப் கடன் வழங்குநர்கள் கடன் பேச்சுவார்த்தைகளை தொடங்கத் தயாராக உள்ளனர்",
      "author": "",
      "body_lines": [
        "ECONOMYNEXT – முக்கியமாக மேற்கத்திய கடனாளிகளின் பாரிஸ் கிளப்பின் உறுப்பினர்கள், இலங்கை சர்வதேச நாணய நிதியத்துடன் பணியாளர் மட்ட ஒப்பந்தத்தை முடித்த பின்னர் கடனை மறுகட்டமைப்பது குறித்து இலங்கையுடன் பேசத் தயாராக இருப்பதாகத் தெரிவித்தனர்.",
        "\"IMF திட்டத்தின் பின்னணியில் கடன் சிகிச்சைக்கான தேவைக்கான IMF மதிப்பீட்டை நாங்கள் கவனிக்கிறோம்,\" என்று அமைப்பின் செயலகம் ஒரு அறிக்கையில் தெரிவித்துள்ளது.",
        "\"பாரிஸ் கிளப் கடன் சிகிச்சை செயல்முறையைத் தொடங்கத் தயாராக உள்ளது மற்றும் பாரிஸ் கிளப் அல்லாத அதிகாரப்பூர்வ இருதரப்பு கடன் வழங்குநர்களுடன் ஒருங்கிணைக்கத் தேவையான நிதி உத்தரவாதங்களை சரியான நேரத்தில் வழங்குவதற்கும் மற்றும் நியாயமான சுமை பகிர்வை உறுதிப்படுத்துவதற்கும் அதன் விருப்பத்தை மீண்டும் வலியுறுத்துகிறது. இருதரப்பு கடன் வழங்குபவர்கள்.",
        "\"பாரிஸ் கிளப் இலங்கை அதிகாரிகள் மற்றும் பாரிஸ் கிளப் அல்லாத உத்தியோகபூர்வ இருதரப்பு கடன் வழங்குநர்களின் வசம் உள்ளது, மேலும் கடன் சிகிச்சை செயல்முறையின் அடுத்த படிகள் பற்றி விவாதிக்க.\"",
        "இலங்கையின் இருதரப்பு கடனாளர்களில் சீனாவும் இந்தியாவும் உள்ளடங்கும், அவை குழுவில் முழு உறுப்பினர்களாக இல்லை.",
        "2012 ஏப்ரலில் இலங்கை தனது கடனைத் திருப்பிச் செலுத்தத் தவறியது மற்றும் அதன் வெளிநாட்டுக் கடன்கள் ஏறத் தொடங்கிய பின்னர், ஏழு ஆண்டுகளில் மூன்று நாணய நெருக்கடிகளைத் தூண்டிய நெகிழ்வான பணவீக்க இலக்கின் கீழ் பராமரிக்கப்படும் குறைந்த வட்டி விகிதங்களால் அதிகரித்த பண ஸ்திரமின்மை காரணமாக, போரின் முடிவில் வளர்ச்சி குறைந்தது."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "இலங்கையின்",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "பாரிஸ் கிளப்",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "பாரிஸ் கிளப்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சர்வதேச நாணய நிதியம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "IMF",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "IMF",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பாரிஸ் அல்லாத கிளப்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பாரிஸ் கிளப்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாரிஸ் அல்லாத கிளப்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கையின்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சீனா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்தியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஏப்ரல் 2012",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "மூன்று",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஏழு ஆண்டுகள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}