{
  "newspaper_id": "daily-mirror-lk",
  "url": "https://www.dailymirror.lk/breaking_news/Three-arrested-over-arson-attack-on-PMs-private-residence/108-240747",
  "time_ut": 1657430259,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Three arrested over arson attack on PM’s private residence",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Three arrested over arson attack on PM’s private residence",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "Three persons have been arrested by the Kollupitiya Police in connection with the arson attack on Prime Minister Ranil Wickramasinghe's private house in Colombo last night, police said.",
        "They said a 19-year-old from Mount Lavinia and two persons aged 24 and 28, residents of Kadawatha and Galle were among those arrested.",
        "The Kollupitiya police are conducting further investigations to arrest the other suspects, police said.",
        "Prime Minister Wickremesinghe's private residence on 5th Lane in Colombo was set on fire by a group of protestors last night during an unrest.(Darshana Sanjeewa Balasuriya)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Three",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "PM",
          "label": "WORK_OF_ART"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Three",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Kollupitiya Police",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickramasinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "last night",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "19-year-old",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Mount Lavinia",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "two",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "24 and 28",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kadawatha",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Galle",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Kollupitiya",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "5th Lane",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "last night",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "an unrest.(Darshana Sanjeewa Balasuriya",
            "label": "LAW"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "අග්‍රාමාත්‍යවරයාගේ පෞද්ගලික නිවසට ගිනි තැබීම සම්බන්ධයෙන් තිදෙනෙකු අත්අඩංගුවට",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "අග්‍රාමාත්‍ය රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතාගේ කොළඹ පිහිටි පෞද්ගලික නිවසට ඊයේ රාත්‍රියේ ගිනි තැබීමේ සිද්ධිය සම්බන්ධයෙන් පුද්ගලයින් තිදෙනෙකු කොල්ලුපිටිය පොලිසිය විසින් අත්අඩංගුවට ගෙන ඇති බව පොලීසිය පවසයි.",
        "අත්අඩංගුවට ගත් පිරිස අතර ගල්කිස්ස ප්‍රදේශයේ පදිංචි 19 හැවිරිදි තරුණයෙකු සහ කඩවත සහ ගාල්ල ප්‍රදේශවල පදිංචි 24 සහ 28 යන වයස්වල පසුවන පුද්ගලයින් දෙදෙනෙකු ද වන බවයි ඔවුන් පැවසුවේ.",
        "අනෙක් සැකකරුවන් අත්අඩංගුවට ගැනීම සඳහා කොල්ලුපිටිය පොලිසිය වැඩිදුර විමර්ශන සිදුකරන බව පොලිසිය පවසයි.",
        "අග්‍රාමාත්‍ය වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතාගේ කොළඹ 5 පටුමග පිහිටි පෞද්ගලික නිවසට ඊයේ රාත්‍රියේ විරෝධතාකරුවන් පිරිසක් විසින් ගිනි තබා ඇති අතර එහිදී ඇති වූ නොසන්සුන්තාවක්.(දර්ශන සංජීව බාලසූරිය)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "තුන්",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "PM",
          "label": "WORK_OF_ART"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "තුන්",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "කොල්ලුපිටිය පොලිසිය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "අවසන් රාත්රිය",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "19 හැවිරිදිය",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගල්කිස්ස",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "දෙක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "24 සහ 28",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "කඩවත",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගාල්ල",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "කොල්ලුපිටිය",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "5 වන පටුමග",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "අවසන් රාත්රිය",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "නොසන්සුන්තාවක්.(දර්ශන සංජීව බාලසූරිය",
            "label": "LAW"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "பிரதமரின் தனிப்பட்ட இல்லத்திற்கு தீ வைத்த வழக்கில் மூவர் கைது செய்யப்பட்டுள்ளனர்",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "கொழும்பில் உள்ள பிரதமர் ரணில் விக்ரமசிங்கவின் தனிப்பட்ட வீட்டிற்கு நேற்றிரவு தீ வைத்து எரித்த சம்பவம் தொடர்பில் கொள்ளுப்பிட்டி பொலிஸாரால் மூவர் கைது செய்யப்பட்டுள்ளதாக பொலிஸார் தெரிவித்துள்ளனர்.",
        "கைது செய்யப்பட்டவர்களில் கல்கிசையைச் சேர்ந்த 19 வயதுடைய ஒருவரும் கடவத்தை மற்றும் காலி பிரதேசத்தைச் சேர்ந்த 24 மற்றும் 28 வயதுடைய இருவருமே அடங்குவதாக அவர்கள் தெரிவித்தனர்.",
        "ஏனைய சந்தேக நபர்களை கைது செய்வதற்கான மேலதிக விசாரணைகளை கொள்ளுப்பிட்டி பொலிஸார் மேற்கொண்டு வருவதாக பொலிஸார் தெரிவித்தனர்.",
        "கொழும்பில் 5 வது பாதையில் உள்ள பிரதமர் விக்ரமசிங்கவின் தனிப்பட்ட இல்லத்திற்கு நேற்று இரவு ஏற்பட்ட அமைதியின்மையின் போது ஆர்ப்பாட்டக்காரர்கள் குழுவினால் தீவைக்கப்பட்டது.(தர்ஷன சஞ்சீவ பாலசூரிய)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "மூன்று",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "மாலை",
          "label": "WORK_OF_ART"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "மூன்று",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "கொள்ளுப்பிட்டி பொலிஸ்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "நேற்று இரவு",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "19 வயது",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "கல்கிசை",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "இரண்டு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "24 மற்றும் 28",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "கடவத்த",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "காலி",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "கொள்ளுப்பிட்டி",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "5வது லேன்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "நேற்று இரவு",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஒரு அமைதியின்மை.(தர்ஷன சஞ்சீவ பாலசூரிய",
            "label": "LAW"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}