{
  "newspaper_id": "b-b-c-com-sinhala",
  "url": "https://www.bbc.com/sinhala/sri-lanka-62301856",
  "time_ut": 1658791191,
  "original_lang": "si",
  "original_title": "ක්‍රීඩාව:ලෝක ශුරතා බොක්සිං තරගාවලියට සුදුසුකම් ලැබූ 'වවුනියාවේ සටන් ශුරිය'",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Sports: 'Vavuniya Sutton Shuriya' qualified for the World Boxing Championship",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "Sevmini Imesha Jayawardena, who lives in Vavuniya, Malmaduwa village, managed to participate in the World Championship 'Kickboxing' tournament to be held in London next August.",
        "She told the BBC that although she lives in a very difficult area, she will not give up on her goal even though some people say that boxing is not suitable for girls.",
        "To qualify for the World Championship, she recently won a gold medal in the qualifying competition held in Chennai, India."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Vavuniya Sutton Shuriya'",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "the World Boxing Championship",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Sevmini Imesha Jayawardena",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Vavuniya",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Malmaduwa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the World Championship 'Kickboxing",
            "label": "EVENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "London",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "next August",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "BBC",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the World Championship",
            "label": "EVENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "Chennai",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "India",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "ක්‍රීඩාව:ලෝක ශුරතා බොක්සිං තරගාවලියට සුදුසුකම් ලැබූ 'වවුනියාවේ සටන් ශුරිය'",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "ලබන අගෝස්තු මාසයේ ලන්ඩන් නුවර පැවැත්වීමට නියමිත ලෝක ශුරතා 'කික් බොක්සිං' තරගාවලියට සහභාගී වීමට වවුනියාව, මල්මඩුව ගම්මානයේ  ජිවත් වෙන සෙව්මිණි ඉමේෂා ජයවර්ධන සමත් වුවාය.",
        "තමන් ඉතා දුෂ්කර ප්‍රදේශයක ජීවත් වුව ද බොක්සිං ක්‍රීඩාව ගැහැණු දරුවන්ට යෝග්‍ය නොවන බවට ඇතැමුන් පැවසුවා ද තම අරමුණ අත්නොහරින බව ඇය බීබීසීයට පැවසුවාය.",
        "ලෝක ශුරතා තරගාවලියට සුදුසුකම් ලැබීම සඳහා පසුගියද ඉන්දියාවේ චෙන්නාහි පැවති සුදුස්සන් තේරීමේ තරගයේදී ඇය රන් පදක්කමක් දිනා ගත්තාය."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Vavuniya Sutton Shuriya'",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "ලෝක බොක්සිං ශූරතාවලිය",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "සෙව්මිණි ඉමේෂා ජයවර්ධන",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "වවුනියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මල්මඩුව",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ලෝක ශූරතා කික් බොක්සිං",
            "label": "EVENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "ලන්ඩන්",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ලබන අගෝස්තු",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "බීබීසී",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ලෝක ශූරතාවලිය",
            "label": "EVENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "චෙන්නායි",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "விளையாட்டு: உலக குத்துச்சண்டை சாம்பியன்ஷிப் போட்டிக்கு 'வவுனியா சுட்டன் சுரியா' தகுதி பெற்றது.",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "வவுனியா, மல்மடுவ கிராமத்தில் வசிக்கும் செவ்வினி இமேஷா ஜயவர்தன, எதிர்வரும் ஓகஸ்ட் மாதம் லண்டனில் நடைபெறவுள்ள உலக சம்பியன்ஷிப் 'கிக் பாக்ஸிங்' போட்டியில் பங்குபற்றினார்.",
        "தான் மிகவும் கடினமான பகுதியில் வசித்தாலும், குத்துச்சண்டை சிறுமிகளுக்கு ஏற்றதல்ல என்று சிலர் கூறினாலும் தனது இலக்கை கைவிடமாட்டேன் என்று பிபிசியிடம் தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "உலக சாம்பியன்ஷிப்பிற்கு தகுதி பெறுவதற்காக, சமீபத்தில் இந்தியாவின் சென்னையில் நடைபெற்ற தகுதிப் போட்டியில் தங்கப் பதக்கம் வென்றார்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Vavuniya Sutton Shuriya'",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "உலக குத்துச்சண்டை சாம்பியன்ஷிப்",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "செவ்வினி இமேஷா ஜயவர்தன",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "வவுனியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "மல்மதுவ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "உலக சாம்பியன்ஷிப் 'கிக் பாக்ஸிங்",
            "label": "EVENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "லண்டன்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "அடுத்த ஆகஸ்ட்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பிபிசி",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "உலக சாம்பியன்ஷிப்",
            "label": "EVENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "சென்னை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்தியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}