{
  "newspaper_id": "news-first-lk",
  "url": "https://www.newsfirst.lk/2022/07/21/navy-thwarts-another-illegal-migration-attempt/",
  "time_ut": 1658400180,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Navy thwarts another illegal migration attempt",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Navy thwarts another illegal migration attempt",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); Sri Lanka Navy apprehended 33 individuals, suspected to be on an illegal migration attempt to a foreign country via sea, during a search operation carried out on seas off Negombo this morning ( 21st July 2022).",
        "The apprehension was made by the Fast Attack Craft P 435 of 4th Fast Attack Flotilla in the Western Naval Command, after intercepting a suspicious local fishing trawler in seas off Negombo this morning. In the group of 33 individuals who were suspected to be on an illegal migration attempt to a foreign country by the trawler, were; 19 males including 04 crew members of the trawler, 09 females and 05 children. The Navy also held the local multiday fishing trawler used for this illegal sea voyage.",
        "Those who were held, including individuals from 18 to 65 years of age, were identified as residents of Chilaw, Marawila, Trincomalee, Batticaloa and Ampara areas. They will be handed over to the Colombo Harbour Police for onward legal action.",
        "It is observed that human smugglers organize this kind of rackets using unsafe vessels for the purpose of making fast money. Against such backdrop, the Navy urges the public to refrain from risking their lives by engaging in perilous sea voyages and be victims before the law."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Navy",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "News 1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka Navy",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "33",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Negombo",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "this morning",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "21st July 2022",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the Fast Attack Craft",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "4th",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Western Naval Command",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Negombo",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "this morning",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "33",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "19",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "04",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "09",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "05",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Navy",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "18 to 65 years of age",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Chilaw",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Trincomalee",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ampara",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Colombo Harbour Police",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Navy",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "නාවික හමුදාව තවත් නීතිවිරෝධී සංක්‍රමණ උත්සාහයක් ව්‍යර්ථ කරයි",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); ශ්‍රී ලංකා නාවික හමුදාව විසින් අද (2022 ජූලි 21) උදෑසන මීගමුවට ඔබ්බෙන් වූ මුහුදු ප්‍රදේශයේ සිදුකළ සෝදිසි මෙහෙයුමකදී නීතිවිරෝධී ලෙස මුහුදු මාර්ගයෙන් විදේශ රටකට සංක්‍රමණය වීමට උත්සාහ කළ බවට සැක කෙරෙන පුද්ගලයින් 33 දෙනෙකු අත්අඩංගුවට ගෙන ඇත.",
        "බස්නාහිර නාවික විධානයට අයත් 4 වන වේග ප්‍රහාරක ෆ්ලෝටිලා හි වේග ප්‍රහාරක යාත්‍රාවක් වන P 435 මගින් අද අලුයම මීගමුවට ඔබ්බෙන් වූ මුහුදු ප්‍රදේශයේ දී සැක කටයුතු දේශීය ධීවර යාත්‍රාවක් අත්අඩංගුවට ගැනීමෙන් අනතුරුව මෙම අත්අඩංගුවට ගැනීම සිදු කර ඇත. ට්‍රෝලර් යාත්‍රාව මගින් විදේශ රටකට නීතිවිරෝධී සංක්‍රමණය වීමට උත්සාහ කළ බවට සැක කෙරෙන පුද්ගලයින් 33 දෙනෙකුගෙන් යුත් කණ්ඩායම තුළ; ට්‍රෝලර් යාත්‍රාවේ කාර්ය මණ්ඩල සාමාජිකයින් 04 ක්, කාන්තාවන් 09 ක් සහ ළමුන් 05 ක් ඇතුළුව පිරිමින් 19 ක්. මෙම නීතිවිරෝධී මුහුදු ගමන සඳහා යොදාගත් දේශීය බහුදින ධීවර යාත්‍රාව ද නාවික හමුදාව සතුව තිබී ඇත.",
        "අත්අඩංගුවට ගත් පුද්ගලයින් වයස අවුරුදු 18 සිට 65 දක්වා පුද්ගලයින් ඇතුළු හලාවත, මාරවිල, ත්‍රිකුණාමලය, මඩකලපුව සහ අම්පාර ප්‍රදේශවල පදිංචිකරුවන් බව හඳුනාගෙන ඇත. ඉදිරි නීතිමය කටයුතු සඳහා ඔවුන් කොළඹ වරාය පොලිසිය වෙත භාරදීමට නියමිතයි.",
        "මිනිස් ජාවාරම්කරුවන් වේගයෙන් මුදල් ඉපයීමේ අරමුණින් අනාරක්ෂිත යාත්‍රා යොදා ගනිමින් මෙවැනි ජාවාරම් සංවිධානය කරන බව නිරීක්ෂණය වේ. මෙවැනි පසුබිමක් තුළ අවදානම් මුහුදු ගමන්වල නිරත වෙමින් ජීවිත අවදානමක් ඇති කර ගැනීමෙන් වළකින ලෙසත්, නීතිය ඉදිරියේ ගොදුරු බවට පත්වන ලෙසත් නාවික හමුදාව මහජනතාවගෙන් ඉල්ලා සිටී."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "නාවික",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "News 1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකා නාවික හමුදාව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "33",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "මීගමුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "මේ උදෑසන",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "2022 ජූලි 21",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "වේග ප්‍රහාරක යාත්‍රාව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "4 වැනි",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "බටහිර නාවික විධානය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "මීගමුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "මේ උදෑසන",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "33",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "19",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "04",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "09",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "05",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "නාවික",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "වයස අවුරුදු 18 සිට 65 දක්වා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "භලාවත",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ත්රිකුණාමලය",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "අම්පාර",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "කොළඹ වරාය පොලිසිය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "නාවික",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "மற்றொரு சட்டவிரோத குடியேற்ற முயற்சியை கடற்படை முறியடித்தது",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st); இலங்கை கடற்படையினர் இன்று (21 ஜூலை 2022) காலை நீர்கொழும்பு கடற்பரப்பில் மேற்கொள்ளப்பட்ட தேடுதல் நடவடிக்கையின் போது கடல் வழியாக வெளிநாட்டுக்கு சட்டவிரோதமாக குடியேற முயற்சித்ததாக சந்தேகிக்கப்படும் 33 நபர்கள் கைது செய்யப்பட்டுள்ளனர்.",
        "இன்று காலை நீர்கொழும்பு கடற்பரப்பில் சந்தேகத்திற்கிடமான உள்ளூர் மீன்பிடி இழுவை படகு ஒன்றை இடைமறித்து மேற்கு கடற்படை கட்டளைக்கு உட்பட்ட 4 வது ஃபாஸ்ட் அட்டாக் புளோட்டிலாவின் ஃபாஸ்ட் அட்டாக் கிராஃப்ட் P 435 மூலம் இந்த அச்சம் ஏற்பட்டுள்ளது. இழுவை படகு மூலம் வெளிநாட்டுக்கு சட்டவிரோதமாக இடம்பெயர்ந்ததாக சந்தேகிக்கப்படும் 33 நபர்கள் அடங்கிய குழுவில்; படகில் 04 பணியாளர்கள் உட்பட 19 ஆண்கள், 09 பெண்கள் மற்றும் 05 குழந்தைகள். இந்த சட்டவிரோத கடல் பயணத்திற்கு பயன்படுத்தப்பட்ட உள்ளூர் பலநாள் மீன்பிடி இழுவை படகையும் கடற்படையினர் வைத்திருந்தனர்.",
        "கைது செய்யப்பட்டவர்கள் 18 வயது முதல் 65 வயதுக்குட்பட்டவர்கள் உட்பட சிலாபம், மாரவில, திருகோணமலை, மட்டக்களப்பு மற்றும் அம்பாறை பகுதிகளில் வசிப்பவர்கள் என அடையாளம் காணப்பட்டுள்ளனர். அவர்கள் மேலதிக சட்ட நடவடிக்கைகளுக்காக கொழும்பு துறைமுக பொலிஸாரிடம் ஒப்படைக்கப்படவுள்ளனர்.",
        "மனித கடத்தல்காரர்கள் வேகமாக பணம் சம்பாதிப்பதற்காக பாதுகாப்பற்ற கப்பல்களை பயன்படுத்தி இதுபோன்ற மோசடிகளை ஏற்பாடு செய்வதை அவதானிக்க முடிகிறது. இவ்வாறானதொரு பின்னணியில், ஆபத்தான கடல் பயணங்களில் ஈடுபடுவதன் மூலம் உயிரைப் பணயம் வைத்து சட்டத்தின் முன் பலியாவதைத் தவிர்த்துக் கொள்ளுமாறு கடற்படை பொதுமக்களை கேட்டுக் கொள்கிறது."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "கடற்படை",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "News 1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை கடற்படை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "33",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "நீர்கொழும்பு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று காலை",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "21 ஜூலை 2022",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஃபாஸ்ட் அட்டாக் கிராஃப்ட்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "4வது",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "மேற்கு கடற்படை கட்டளை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "நீர்கொழும்பு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று காலை",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "33",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "19",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "04",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "09",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "05",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "கடற்படை",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "18 முதல் 65 வயது வரை",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சிலாபம்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "திருகோணமலை",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "அம்பாறை",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "கொழும்பு துறைமுக காவல்துறை",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "கடற்படை",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}