{
  "newspaper_id": "daily-mirror-lk",
  "url": "https://www.dailymirror.lk/breaking_news/Protestors-refuse-to-meet-PM-put-forward-two-demands/108-235062",
  "time_ut": 1649852682,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Protestors refuse to meet PM, put forward two demands",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Protestors refuse to meet PM, put forward two demands",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "A group of protestors at the Galle Face area now re-named as the 'Gota Go Gama' have written to Prime Minister Mahinda Rajapaksa, declining his invitation for a meeting, but have put forward two demands saying the President must resign and all Rajapaksa members must leave the government.",
        "Prime Minister Rajapaksa earlier in the day said he was ready to hold discussions with the protesting youth at Galle Face Green.",
        "A spokesman from the Prime Minister's office confirmed that if the protesting youth are ready to meet him, the Prime Minister is ready to meet and discuss the ongoing crisis situation.",
        "However, in a letter sent to Rajapaksa, a group of protestors said they were not ready to meet him unless President Gotabaya Rajapaksa resigns and all Rajapaksa members leave the government.",
        "In the second demand, the protestors specifically ask for the Prime Minister and all other Rajapaksa members, namely Chamal Rajapaksa, Basil Rajapaksa, Namal Rajapaksa, Shashindra Rajapaksa and Nipuna Ranawaka to step down from all government posts immediately and also leave Parliament.",
        "The letter which was released on social media platforms by some activists said they will continue the “GotaGoGama” protest until their main two demands are met."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "PM",
          "label": "TIME"
        },
        {
          "text": "two",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Galle Face",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "Mahinda Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "two",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Rajapaksa",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "earlier in the day",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Galle Face Green",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "Rajapaksa",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Gotabaya Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Rajapaksa",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "second",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Rajapaksa",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Chamal Rajapaksa",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Basil Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Namal Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Shashindra Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Nipuna Ranawaka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "GotaGoGama",
            "label": "WORK_OF_ART"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "විරෝධතාකරුවන් ඉල්ලීම් දෙකක් ඉදිරිපත් කරමින් අගමැති හමුවීම ප්‍රතික්ෂේප කරයි",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "දැන් ‘ගෝඨා ගෝ ගම’ ලෙස නම් කර ඇති ගාලුමුවදොර ප්‍රදේශයේ විරෝධතාකරුවන් පිරිසක් අගමැති මහින්ද රාජපක්ෂ මහතාට ලිඛිතව ලිඛිතව දන්වා ඇති අතර, ජනාධිපතිවරයා ඉල්ලා අස්විය යුතු බව පවසමින් ඉල්ලීම් දෙකක් ඉදිරිපත් කර ඇත. ආණ්ඩුවෙන් ඉවත් විය යුතුයි.",
        "ගාලුමුවදොර පිටියේ විරෝධතාවයේ නිරත තරුණයින් සමඟ සාකච්ඡා කිරීමට තමන් සූදානම් බව අග්‍රාමාත්‍යවරයා මීට පෙර ප්‍රකාශ කළේය.",
        "විරෝධතාවයේ නිරත තරුණයින් තමන් හමුවීමට සූදානම් නම් අග්‍රාමාත්‍යවරයා හමුවී පවතින අර්බුදකාරී තත්ත්වය පිළිබඳව සාකච්ඡා කිරීමට සූදානම් බව අග්‍රාමාත්‍ය කාර්යාලයේ ප්‍රකාශකයෙකු තහවුරු කළා.",
        "කෙසේ වෙතත්, විරෝධතාකරුවන් පිරිසක් රාජපක්ෂ වෙත යවන ලද ලිපියක කියා සිටියේ ජනාධිපති ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ ඉල්ලා අස්වී රාජපක්ෂ මන්ත්‍රීවරුන් සියලු දෙනා ආණ්ඩුවෙන් ඉවත් වන්නේ නම් මිස ඔහු හමුවීමට සූදානම් නැති බවයි.",
        "දෙවන ඉල්ලීම ලෙස උද්ඝෝෂකයින් විශේෂයෙන් ඉල්ලා සිටින්නේ අගමැති ඇතුළු අනෙකුත් සියලුම රාජපක්ෂ මන්ත්‍රීවරුන් වන චමල් රාජපක්ෂ, බැසිල් රාජපක්ෂ, නාමල් රාජපක්ෂ, ශෂීන්ද්‍ර රාජපක්ෂ සහ නිපුන රණවක රජයේ සියලුම තනතුරුවලින් වහාම ඉවත් වී පාර්ලිමේන්තුවෙන් ඉවත් වන ලෙසයි.",
        "සමහර ක්‍රියාකාරීන් විසින් සමාජ මාධ්‍ය වේදිකා මත මුදා හරින ලද ලිපියේ                                                                                                                                                                                                                          ."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "PM",
          "label": "TIME"
        },
        {
          "text": "දෙක",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ගාලු මුවදොර",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "මහින්ද රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "දෙක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "කලින් දවසේ",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගාලුමුවදොර පිටිය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "දෙවැනි",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "චමල් රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "බැසිල් රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "නාමල් රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශෂීන්ද්‍ර රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "නිපුන රණවක",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ගෝඨාගෝගම",
            "label": "WORK_OF_ART"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "பிரதமரை சந்திக்க மறுத்த போராட்டக்காரர்கள், இரண்டு கோரிக்கைகளை முன்வைத்தனர்",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "காலி முகத்திடலில் தற்போது 'கோட்டா கோ கம' என பெயர் சூட்டப்பட்டுள்ள ஆர்ப்பாட்டக்காரர்கள், பிரதமர் மஹிந்த ராஜபக்ஷவின் சந்திப்பிற்கான அழைப்பை நிராகரித்து கடிதம் எழுதியுள்ளனர். அரசாங்கத்தை விட்டு வெளியேற வேண்டும்.",
        "காலி முகத்திடலில் போராட்டம் நடத்தும் இளைஞர்களுடன் பேச்சுவார்த்தை நடத்த தயாராக இருப்பதாக பிரதமர் ராஜபக்ஷ நேற்று முன்தினம் தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "போராட்டத்தில் ஈடுபட்டுள்ள இளைஞர்கள் தம்மைச் சந்திக்கத் தயாராக இருந்தால், தற்போதைய நெருக்கடி நிலை குறித்து பிரதமர் சந்தித்துப் பேசத் தயாராக இருப்பதாக பிரதமர் அலுவலகத்தின் செய்தித் தொடர்பாளர் உறுதிப்படுத்தினார்.",
        "எவ்வாறாயினும், ஜனாதிபதி கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ச ராஜினாமா செய்து, அனைத்து ராஜபக்சே உறுப்பினர்களும் அரசாங்கத்தை விட்டு வெளியேறும் வரை, அவரைச் சந்திக்கத் தயாராக இல்லை என்று ராஜபக்சேவுக்கு அனுப்பிய கடிதத்தில் எதிர்ப்பாளர்கள் குழு கூறியது.",
        "இரண்டாவது கோரிக்கையில், பிரதமர் மற்றும் அனைத்து ராஜபக்ச உறுப்பினர்களான சமல் ராஜபக்ஷ, பசில் ராஜபக்ஷ, நாமல் ராஜபக்ஷ, ஷசீந்திர ராஜபக்ஷ மற்றும் நிபுன ரணவக்க ஆகியோரை உடனடியாக அனைத்து அரசாங்க பதவிகளில் இருந்தும் உடனடியாக விலகுமாறும், பாராளுமன்றத்தை விட்டு வெளியேறுமாறும் ஆர்ப்பாட்டக்காரர்கள் குறிப்பாக கேட்டுக்கொள்கிறார்கள்.",
        "சில ஆர்வலர்களால் சமூக ஊடக தளங்களில் வெளியிடப்பட்ட கடிதம், தங்களின் முக்கிய இரண்டு கோரிக்கைகள் நிறைவேற்றப்படும் வரை “கோட்டகோகாமா” போராட்டத்தை தொடரப்போவதாக கூறியுள்ளது."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "மாலை",
          "label": "TIME"
        },
        {
          "text": "இரண்டு",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "காலி முகம்",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "மஹிந்த ராஜபக்ஷ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இரண்டு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ராஜபக்சே",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ராஜபக்சே",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "முந்தைய நாள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Galle Face Green",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "ராஜபக்சே",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ராஜபக்சே",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இரண்டாவது",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ராஜபக்சே",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "சமல் ராஜபக்ஷ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "பசில் ராஜபக்ஷ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "நாமல் ராஜபக்ச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஷசீந்திர ராஜபக்ஷ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "நிபுண ரணவக்க",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "கோட்டகோகாமா",
            "label": "WORK_OF_ART"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}