{
  "newspaper_id": "economy-next-com",
  "url": "https://economynext.com/liz-truss-to-become-uks-next-prime-minister-99475/",
  "time_ut": 1662378900,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Liz Truss to become UK’s next prime minister",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Liz Truss to become UK’s next prime minister",
      "author": "",
      "body_lines": [
        "ECONOMYNEXT – The UK’s Foreign Secretary Liz Truss is set to become the country’s next prime minister after she was named leader of the ruling Conservative Party, international media reported.",
        "Truss’ appointment as Tory leader, announced Monday September 05 afternoon, comes at a time when the UK is facing a recession.",
        "After weeks of an often bad-tempered and divisive party leadership contest that pitted Truss against Rishi Sunak, a former finance minister, Monday’s announcement triggered the beginning of a handover from Boris Johnson, Al Jazeera reported Monday afternoon. (Colombo/Sep05/2022)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Liz Truss",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "UK",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "UK",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Liz Truss",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Conservative Party",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Tory",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Monday September 05",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "afternoon",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "UK",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "weeks",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Truss",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Rishi Sunak",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Monday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Boris Johnson",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Al Jazeera",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Monday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "afternoon",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "Colombo/Sep05/2022",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "Liz Truss එක්සත් රාජධානියේ මීළඟ අගමැති වීමට නියමිතයි",
      "author": "",
      "body_lines": [
        "ECONOMYNEXT - එක්සත් රාජධානියේ විදේශ ලේකම් Liz Truss පාලක කොන්සර්වේටිව් පක්ෂයේ නායිකාව ලෙස නම් කිරීමෙන් පසු රටේ මීළඟ අගමැතිනිය වීමට නියමිත බව ජාත්‍යන්තර මාධ්‍ය වාර්තා කළේය.",
        "සැප්තැම්බර් 05 සඳුදා සවස ප්‍රකාශයට පත් කරන ලද ටෝරි නායකයා ලෙස ට්‍රස්ගේ පත්වීම පැමිණෙන්නේ එක්සත් රාජධානිය අවපාතයකට මුහුණ දී සිටින අවස්ථාවක ය.",
        "හිටපු මුදල් අමාත්‍යවරයකු වූ රිෂි සුනක්ට එරෙහිව ට්‍රස් ඉදිරිපත් කළ බොහෝ විට නරක කෝපයෙන් හා භේදකාරී පක්ෂ නායකත්ව තරඟයකින් සති ගණනාවකට පසුව, සඳුදා නිවේදනය බොරිස් ජොන්සන් වෙතින් භාරදීමේ ආරම්භය අවුලුවා ඇති බව අල් ජසීරා සඳුදා පස්වරුවේ වාර්තා කළේය. (කොළඹ/සැප්.05/2022)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ලිස් ට්‍රස්",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "එක්සත් රාජධානිය",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "එක්සත් රාජධානිය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ලිස් ට්‍රස්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "කොන්සර්වේටිව් පක්ෂය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ටෝරි",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "සැප්තැම්බර් 05 සඳුදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "දහවල්",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "එක්සත් රාජධානිය",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "සති",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ට්‍රස්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "රිෂි සුනක්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "සඳුදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "බොරිස් ජොන්සන්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "අල් ජසීරා",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "සඳුදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "දහවල්",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "කොළඹ/සැප්.05/2022",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "இங்கிலாந்தின் அடுத்த பிரதமராக லிஸ் ட்ரஸ் பதவியேற்க உள்ளார்",
      "author": "",
      "body_lines": [
        "எகனாமிநெக்ஸ்ட் - இங்கிலாந்தின் வெளியுறவுச் செயலர் லிஸ் ட்ரஸ், ஆளும் கன்சர்வேடிவ் கட்சியின் தலைவராக நியமிக்கப்பட்ட பின்னர், நாட்டின் அடுத்த பிரதமராக பதவியேற்க உள்ளார் என்று சர்வதேச ஊடகங்கள் செய்தி வெளியிட்டுள்ளன.",
        "டோரி தலைவராக டிரஸின் நியமனம், செப்டம்பர் 05 திங்கட்கிழமை பிற்பகல் அறிவிக்கப்பட்டது, இது இங்கிலாந்து மந்தநிலையை எதிர்கொண்டிருக்கும் நேரத்தில் வருகிறது.",
        "முன்னாள் நிதி அமைச்சரான ரிஷி சுனக்கிற்கு எதிராக டிரஸைத் தூண்டிய மோசமான மற்றும் பிளவுபடுத்தும் கட்சித் தலைமைப் போட்டிகளின் பல வாரங்களுக்குப் பிறகு, திங்களன்று அறிவிப்பு போரிஸ் ஜான்சனிடமிருந்து ஒப்படைக்கப்படுவதைத் தூண்டியது, அல் ஜசீரா திங்கள்கிழமை பிற்பகல் தெரிவித்துள்ளது. (கொழும்பு/செப்05/2022)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "லிஸ் டிரஸ்",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "யுகே",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "யுகே",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "லிஸ் டிரஸ்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "கன்சர்வேடிவ் கட்சி",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "டோரி",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "செப்டம்பர் 05 திங்கட்கிழமை",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "பிற்பகல்",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "யுகே",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "வாரங்கள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "டிரஸ்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரிஷி சுனக்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "திங்கட்கிழமை",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "போரிஸ் ஜான்சன்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "அல் ஜசீரா",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "திங்கட்கிழமை",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "பிற்பகல்",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "கொழும்பு/செப்05/2022",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}