{
  "newspaper_id": "lankadeepa-lk",
  "url": "https://www.lankadeepa.lk/main_picture/රංගන-ශිල්පී-ජැක්සන්ගේ-මෝටර්-රථයට-වල්-අලියකු-ගැටෙයි/11-615754",
  "time_ut": 1656781459,
  "original_lang": "si",
  "original_title": "රංගන ශිල්පී ජැක්සන්ගේ මෝටර් රථයට වල් අලියකු ගැටෙයි",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "A wild elephant hits actor Jackson's car",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "Talawa Police say that the car in which three people including veteran actor Jackson Anthony were traveling collided with the body of a wild elephant in Moragoda area on the Anuradhapura-Talawa road.",
        "Along with the accident, the wild elephant fell on top of the cab and the vehicle was also badly damaged.",
        "A spokesperson of Anuradhapura Hospital said that Jackson Anthony, who was hospitalized, was transferred to the Colombo National Hospital for further treatment.",
        "The police say that the accident took place while returning to Anuradhapura after participating in the shooting of a TV drama in Anuradhapura.",
        "Saman Anthony and Iresh who were traveling with veteran actor Mr. Jackson Anthony have been injured in this incident.",
        "The three injured were admitted to Anuradhapura Teaching Hospital by the combination of Moragoda local residents and Talawa Police officers."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Jackson",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Talawa Police",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "three",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Jackson Anthony",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "Anuradhapura Hospital",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Jackson Anthony",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Colombo National Hospital",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Anuradhapura",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Anuradhapura",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Saman Anthony",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Iresh",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Jackson Anthony",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "three",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Anuradhapura Teaching Hospital",
            "label": "WORK_OF_ART"
          },
          {
            "text": "Talawa Police",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "රංගන ශිල්පී ජැක්සන්ගේ මෝටර් රථයට වල් අලියකු ගැටෙයි",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "ප්‍රවීන රංගන ශිල්පී ජැක්සන් ඇන්තනී ඇතුළු තිදෙනකු ගමන්ගත් මෝටර් රථය අනුරාධපුර - තලාව  මාර්ගයේ මොරගොඩ ප්‍රදේශයේ වල් අලියකුගේ සිරුරේ ගැටීමෙන් ජැක්සන් ඇන්තනී ඇතුළු පිරිස තුවාල ලබා අනුරාධපුර රෝහලට ඇතුළත් කර ඇතැයි තලාව පොලිසිය කියයි.",
        "අනතුරත් සමග කැබ් රථය උඩට වල් අලියා ඇද වැටීමෙන් වාහනයට ද දැඩි හානි සිදුව ඇත.",
        "රෝහල්ගත කෙරුණු ජැක්සන් ඇන්තනී මහතා වැඩිදුර ප්‍රතිකාර සඳහා කොළඹ ජාතික රොහලට මාරු කළ බව අනුරාධපුර රෝහලේ ප්‍රකාශකයෙක් කීය.",
        "අනුරාධපුරයේ ටෙලි නාට්‍යයක් රූගත කිරීමේ කටයුත්තකට සහභාගී වී නැවත අනුරාධපුරයට යමින් සිටියදී මෙම අනතුර සිදුව ඇතැයි පොලිසිය කියයි.",
        "මෙම සිද්ධියෙන් තුවාල ලබා ඇත්තේ ප්‍රවීන රංගන ශිල්පියකු වන ජැක්සන් ඇන්තනි මහතා සමඟ ගමන්ගත් සමන් ඇන්තනී හා ඉරේෂ් යන අයයි .",
        "මොරගොඩ ප්‍රදේශවාසීන් හා තලාව පොලිසියේ නිලධාරීන්ගේ එකතුවෙන් මෙම තුවාලකරුවන් තිදෙනා අනුරාධපුර ශික්ෂණ රෝහලට ඇතුළත් කර ඇත."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ජැක්සන්",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "තලාව පොලිසිය",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "තුන්",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජැක්සන් ඇන්තනි",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "අනුරාධපුර රෝහල",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජැක්සන් ඇන්තනි",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "කොළඹ ජාතික රෝහල",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "අනුරාධපුර",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "අනුරාධපුර",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "සමන් ඇන්තනි",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉරේෂ්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජැක්සන් ඇන්තනි",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "තුන්",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "අනුරාධපුර ශික්ෂණ රෝහල",
            "label": "WORK_OF_ART"
          },
          {
            "text": "තලාව පොලිසිය",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "நடிகர் ஜாக்சனின் கார் மீது காட்டு யானை மோதியது",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "அனுராதபுரம் - தலாவ வீதியில் மொரகொட பிரதேசத்தில் வைத்து மூத்த நடிகர் ஜாக்சன் அந்தோனி உட்பட மூவர் பயணித்த கார் காட்டு யானையின் உடலுடன் மோதியுள்ளதாக தலாவ பொலிஸார் தெரிவித்துள்ளனர்.",
        "விபத்துடன், காட்டு யானை வண்டியின் மேல் விழுந்ததுடன் வாகனமும் பலத்த சேதமடைந்தது.",
        "வைத்தியசாலையில் அனுமதிக்கப்பட்ட ஜெக்சன் அந்தோனி மேலதிக சிகிச்சைக்காக கொழும்பு தேசிய வைத்தியசாலைக்கு மாற்றப்பட்டுள்ளதாக அனுராதபுரம் வைத்தியசாலையின் பேச்சாளர் தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "அநுராதபுரத்தில் இடம்பெற்ற தொலைக்காட்சி நாடகம் ஒன்றின் படப்பிடிப்பில் கலந்து கொண்டு அநுராதபுரம் சென்று திரும்பும் போதே இவ்விபத்து இடம்பெற்றுள்ளதாக பொலிஸார் தெரிவிக்கின்றனர்.",
        "இதில் பழம்பெரும் நடிகர் திரு.ஜாக்சன் ஆண்டனியுடன் பயணித்த சமன் ஆண்டனி மற்றும் ஐரேஷ் ஆகியோர் காயமடைந்துள்ளனர்.",
        "காயமடைந்த மூவரும் மொரகொட பிரதேசவாசிகள் மற்றும் தலாவ பொலிஸ் உத்தியோகத்தர்கள் இணைந்து அனுராதபுரம் போதனா வைத்தியசாலையில் அனுமதிக்கப்பட்டுள்ளனர்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ஜாக்சன்",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "தலைவா போலீஸ்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "மூன்று",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜாக்சன் ஆண்டனி",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "அனுராதபுரம் வைத்தியசாலை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜாக்சன் ஆண்டனி",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "கொழும்பு தேசிய வைத்தியசாலை",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "அனுராதபுரம்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "அனுராதபுரம்",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "சமன் அந்தோணி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஐரேஷ்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜாக்சன் ஆண்டனி",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "மூன்று",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "அனுராதபுரம் போதனா வைத்தியசாலை",
            "label": "WORK_OF_ART"
          },
          {
            "text": "தலைவா போலீஸ்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}