{
  "newspaper_id": "d-b-s-jeyaraj-com",
  "url": "https://dbsjeyaraj.com/dbsj/archives/78544",
  "time_ut": 1657712940,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "President   Gotabaya Rajapaksa  appoints Prime Minister  Ranil Wickremesinghe  as Acting President to “exercise, perform and discharge the powers, duties and functions of the Office of President” with effect from Wednesday, during his absence from Sri Lanka.",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "President   Gotabaya Rajapaksa  appoints Prime Minister  Ranil Wickremesinghe  as Acting President to “exercise, perform and discharge the powers, duties and functions of the Office of President” with effect from Wednesday, during his absence from Sri Lanka.",
      "author": "Administrator",
      "body_lines": [
        "Sri Lankan President Gotabaya Rajapaksa, who fled the island and took refuge in the Maldives early on Wednesday, ahead of his promised resignation, appointed Prime Minister Ranil Wickremesinghe as acting President, the island’s Parliamentary Speaker said.",
        "The announcement came even as enraged protesters overran the Premier’s office in Colombo, in the midst of persisting agitations against the leader, now as unpopular as the President who appointed him two months ago, amid political turbulence in the wake of a daunting economic crisis.",
        "“We must end this fascist threat to democracy. We can’t allow the destruction of state property. The President’s office, the president’s secretariat and the Prime Minister’s official residence must be returned to proper custody. I have ordered military commanders and the police chief to do what is necessary to restore order,” Mr. Wickremesinghe said in a televised address, his first to the nation after being appointed acting President.",
        "Late in the day, a gazette notification was issued by the President appointing Mr. Wickremesinghe to “exercise, perform and discharge the powers, duties and functions of the Office of President” with effect from Wednesday, during his absence from Sri Lanka.",
        "The Prime Minister, exercising his newly conferred powers, imposed an overnight curfew. The order bars anyone from being on any public road, railway, or any public ground or the sea-shore from midnight to 5 a.m. on Thursday, without a written permit.",
        "Anti-government protesters broke into the main state television station and briefly took over broadcasts on Wednesday, video footage on private and social media showed. They also gathered outside the Air Force headquarters, after the Sri Lanka Air Force said the President, First Lady and two bodyguards boarded an Air Force flight to the Maldives early on Wednesday, in a statement confirming its services to Mr. Gotabaya, who holds the positions of Minister of Defence and Commander-in-Chief, until his resignation.",
        "Meanwhile, political party leaders who met Speaker Mahinda Yapa Abeywardena on Wednesday evening requested him to ask the President and the Prime Minister to resign immediately or asked the President to sack the Prime Minister before he resigns.",
        "Though both Sri Lanka’s President and Prime Minister offered to resign following dramatic mass protests on Saturday — demonstrators stormed the President’s office and home, while arsonists torched the Prime Minister’s private residence — neither has stepped down, prolonging the political impasse, and fuelling anti-government protests. Sri Lanka’s Constitution clearly lays out next steps in the event of the President’s and Prime Minister’s their offices falling vacant, but the process cannot begin until the leaders resign.",
        "While speculation over Mr. Gotabaya’s whereabouts continues, a top official in the Maldives, who asked not to be named, citing “sensitivity” of the embattled leader’s arrival, told The Hindu that Mr. Gotabaya would “only transit” the country. Media reports said the Maldives’ Parliamentary Speaker and former President, Mohamed Nasheed, received Mr. Gotabaya at the airport, but there was no official word from Male on the development.",
        "Asked where the Sri Lankan leader was headed next, the source declined comment. Mr. Gotabaya’s final destination remains unclear, but reports indicated he was headed to Singapore."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Gotabaya Rajapaksa",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "Ranil Wickremesinghe",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "the Office of President",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "Wednesday",
          "label": "DATE"
        },
        {
          "text": "Sri Lanka",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lankan",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Gotabaya Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Maldives",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Wednesday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Colombo",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "two months ago",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "first",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Office of President",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Wednesday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "overnight",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "midnight to 5 a.m.",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "Thursday",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Wednesday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Air Force",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Sri Lanka Air Force",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "two",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Air Force",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Maldives",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Wednesday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Gotabaya",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Mahinda Yapa Abeywardena",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Wednesday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "evening",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka’s",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Saturday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka’s",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Gotabaya",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Maldives",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Hindu",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Gotabaya",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Mohamed Nasheed",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Gotabaya",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Gotabaya",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Singapore",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "ජනාධිපති ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ මහතා අගමැති රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතා ශ්‍රී ලංකාවෙන් නොපැමිණෙන බදාදා සිට ක්‍රියාත්මක වන පරිදි “ජනාධිපති කාර්යාලයේ බලතල, යුතුකම් සහ කාර්යයන් ක්‍රියාත්මක කිරීමට, ඉටු කිරීමට සහ ඉටු කිරීමට” වැඩ බලන ජනාධිපතිවරයා ලෙස පත් කළේය.",
      "author": "පරිපාලක",
      "body_lines": [
        "පොරොන්දු වූ ඉල්ලා අස්වීමට පෙර බදාදා අලුයම දිවයිනෙන් පළා ගොස් මාලදිවයිනේ සරණාගත වූ ශ්‍රී ලංකා ජනාධිපති ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ, අගමැති රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ වැඩ බලන ජනාධිපති ලෙස පත් කළ බව දිවයිනේ පාර්ලිමේන්තු කථානායකවරයා පැවසීය.",
        "භයංකර ආර්ථික අර්බුදයක් හමුවේ දේශපාලන කැලඹීම් මධ්‍යයේ, දැන් මාස දෙකකට පෙර ඔහුව පත් කළ ජනාධිපතිවරයා තරම්ම ජනප්‍රිය නොවූ නායකයාට එරෙහිව නොනවත්වා උද්ඝෝෂණ මධ්‍යයේ, කෝපයට පත් විරෝධතාකරුවන් කොළඹ අග්‍රාමාත්‍ය කාර්යාලයට කඩා වදිද්දී පවා මෙම නිවේදනය නිකුත් විය.",
        "“අපි ප්‍රජාතන්ත්‍රවාදයට එල්ල කරන මේ ෆැසිස්ට් තර්ජනය අවසන් කළ යුතුයි. රාජ්‍ය දේපළ විනාශ කරන්න දෙන්න බැහැ. ජනාධිපති කාර්යාලය, ජනාධිපති ලේකම් කාර්යාලය සහ අගමැති නිල නිවස නැවත නිසි භාරකාරත්වයට පත් කළ යුතුයි. සාමය යථා තත්ත්වයට පත් කිරීමට අවශ්‍ය දේ කරන ලෙස මම හමුදාපතිවරුන්ට සහ පොලිස් ප්‍රධානියාට නියෝග කර තිබෙනවා” යැයි වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතා වැඩබලන ජනාධිපති ධුරයට පත්වීමෙන් පසු ජාතිය අමතමින් රූපවාහිනිය ඔස්සේ ප්‍රකාශ කළේය.",
        "“ජනාධිපති කාර්යාලයේ බලතල, රාජකාරි සහ කාර්යයන් ක්‍රියාත්මක කිරීම, ඉටු කිරීම සහ ඉටු කිරීම” සඳහා ඔහු ශ්‍රී ලංකාවෙන් නොපැමිණෙන විට බදාදා සිට ක්‍රියාත්මක වන පරිදි වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතා පත් කරමින් ජනාධිපතිවරයා විසින් ගැසට් නිවේදනයක් නිකුත් කරන ලදී.",
        "අගමැතිවරයා තමන්ට අලුතින් ලැබුණු බලතල ක්‍රියාත්මක කරමින් එක රැයකින් ඇඳිරි නීතිය පැනවීය. ලිඛිත බලපත්‍රයක් නොමැතිව බ්‍රහස්පතින්දා මධ්‍යම රාත්‍රියේ සිට අලුයම 5 දක්වා ඕනෑම පොදු මාර්ගයක, දුම්රිය මාර්ගයක හෝ පොදු භූමියක හෝ මුහුදු වෙරළේ සිටීම මෙම නියෝගයෙන් තහනම් වේ.",
        "රාජ්‍ය විරෝධී විරෝධතාකරුවන් ප්‍රධාන රාජ්‍ය රූපවාහිනී මධ්‍යස්ථානයට කඩා වැදී බදාදා කෙටියෙන් විකාශන භාරගත් බව පුද්ගලික සහ සමාජ මාධ්‍යවල වීඩියෝ දර්ශන පෙන්වයි. ජනාධිපතිවරයා, ආර්යාව සහ ආරක්ෂකයින් දෙදෙනකු බදාදා අලුයම මාලදිවයිනට ගුවන් හමුදා ගුවන් යානයකට ගොඩ වූ බව ශ්‍රී ලංකා ගුවන් හමුදාව පැවසීමෙන් පසු ඔවුහු ද ගුවන් හමුදා මූලස්ථානයෙන් පිටත රැස්වූහ. ඔහු ඉල්ලා අස්වන තුරු ආරක්ෂක අමාත්‍ය සහ සේනාධිනායක තනතුරු.",
        "මේ අතර බදාදා සවස කතානායක මහින්ද යාපා අබේවර්ධන හමුවූ දේශපාලන පක්ෂ නායකයින් ඉල්ලා සිටියේ ජනාධිපතිවරයාට සහ අගමැතිට වහාම ඉල්ලා අස්වන ලෙස දන්වන ලෙසත් එසේත් නැතිනම් අගමැතිවරයා ඉල්ලා අස්වීමට පෙර ඔහු ඉවත් කරන ලෙස ජනාධිපතිවරයාගෙන් ඉල්ලා සිටින ලෙසත්ය.",
        "සෙනසුරාදා නාටකාකාර මහජන විරෝධතා වලින් පසු ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ ජනාධිපති සහ අගමැති යන දෙදෙනාම ඉල්ලා අස්වීමට ඉදිරිපත් වුවද - පෙලපාලිකරුවන් ජනාධිපති කාර්යාලයට සහ නිවසට කඩා වැදුණු අතර, ගිනි තැබීම් කරන්නන් අග්‍රාමාත්‍යවරයාගේ පෞද්ගලික නිවසට ගිනි තබද්දී - ඔවුන් දෙදෙනාම ඉල්ලා අස්වී නැත, දේශපාලන අස්ථාවරත්වය දිගු කරමින් සහ රජයට එරෙහි වීමට විරෝධතා. ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ ආණ්ඩුක්‍රම ව්‍යවස්ථාවේ පැහැදිලිවම ජනාධිපතිවරයාගේ සහ අග්‍රාමාත්‍යවරයාගේ කාර්යාල පුරප්පාඩු වූ අවස්ථාවක ඊළඟ පියවර දක්වා ඇත, නමුත් නායකයින් ඉල්ලා අස්වන තුරු ක්‍රියාවලිය ආරම්භ කළ නොහැක.",
        "ගෝඨාභය මහතා සිටින ස්ථානය පිළිබඳ සමපේක්ෂනය දිගටම පවතින අතර, ගැටුමට ලක් වූ නායකයාගේ පැමිණීම පිළිබඳ “සංවේදීභාවය” උපුටා දක්වමින් නම සඳහන් නොකරන ලෙස ඉල්ලා සිටි මාලදිවයිනේ ඉහළ නිලධාරියෙක් ද හින්දු වෙත පැවසුවේ ගෝඨාභය මහතා රට “සංක්‍රමණය” පමණක් කරන බවයි. මාලදිවයිනේ පාර්ලිමේන්තු කථානායක සහ හිටපු ජනාධිපති මොහොමඩ් නෂීඩ් මහතා විසින් ගෝඨාභය මහතා ගුවන් තොටුපළේදී පිළිගත් නමුත් සංවර්ධනය පිළිබඳව මාලේ වෙතින් නිල වචනයක් නොමැති බව මාධ්‍ය වාර්තා කළේය.",
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකා නායකයා මීළඟට යන්නේ කොතැනට දැයි විමසූ විට මූලාශ්‍රය අදහස් දැක්වීම ප්‍රතික්ෂේප කළේය. ගෝඨාභය මහතාගේ අවසන් ගමනාන්තය තවමත් අපැහැදිලිව පවතින නමුත් ඔහු සිංගප්පූරුව බලා පිටත්ව ගොස් ඇති බව වාර්තා විය."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "ජනාධිපති කාර්යාලය",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "බදාදා",
          "label": "DATE"
        },
        {
          "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලාංකික",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "මාලදිවයින",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "බදාදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "කොළඹ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මාස දෙකකට කලින්",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "පළමුවන",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජනාධිපති කාර්යාලය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "බදාදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "එක රැයකින්",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "මධ්‍යම රාත්‍රියේ සිට උදෑසන 5 දක්වා",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "බ්රහස්පතින්දා",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "බදාදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගුවන් හමුදා",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකා ගුවන් හමුදාව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "දෙක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගුවන් හමුදා",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "මාලදිවයින",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "බදාදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගෝඨාභය",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "මහින්ද යාපා අබේවර්ධන",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "බදාදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "සවස",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "සෙනසුරාදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ගෝඨාභය",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "මාලදිවයින",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "හින්දු",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගෝඨාභය",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "මොහොමඩ් නෂීඩ්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගෝඨාභය",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ගෝඨාභය",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "සිංගප්පූරුව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "ஜனாதிபதி கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ஷ, பிரதமர் ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க இலங்கையில் இல்லாத நிலையில் புதன்கிழமை முதல் ஜனாதிபதி அலுவலகத்தின் அதிகாரங்கள், கடமைகள் மற்றும் செயல்பாடுகளை நிறைவேற்றுவதற்கும், நிறைவேற்றுவதற்கும், பதில் ஜனாதிபதியாக நியமிக்கப்பட்டுள்ளார்.",
      "author": "நிர்வாகி",
      "body_lines": [
        "இலங்கை ஜனாதிபதி கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ச, தனது உறுதிமொழியை ராஜினாமா செய்வதற்கு முன்னதாக, புதன்கிழமை அதிகாலை தீவில் இருந்து தப்பி மாலைதீவில் தஞ்சம் அடைந்து, பிரதமர் ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்கவை தற்காலிக ஜனாதிபதியாக நியமித்ததாக தீவின் பாராளுமன்ற சபாநாயகர் தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "இரண்டு மாதங்களுக்கு முன்னர் ஜனாதிபதியை நியமித்த ஜனாதிபதியைப் போன்று செல்வாக்கற்ற நிலையில், அச்சுறுத்தும் பொருளாதார நெருக்கடியின் பின்னணியில் அரசியல் கொந்தளிப்புக்கு மத்தியில், தலைவருக்கு எதிரான தொடர்ச்சியான போராட்டங்களுக்கு மத்தியில், ஆத்திரமடைந்த எதிர்ப்பாளர்கள் கொழும்பில் உள்ள பிரதமரின் அலுவலகத்தை முற்றுகையிட்டபோதும் இந்த அறிவிப்பு வந்தது.",
        "“ஜனநாயகத்திற்கு இந்த பாசிச அச்சுறுத்தலை நாம் முடிவுக்கு கொண்டு வர வேண்டும். அரச சொத்துக்கள் அழிக்கப்படுவதை அனுமதிக்க முடியாது. ஜனாதிபதியின் அலுவலகம், ஜனாதிபதி செயலகம் மற்றும் பிரதமரின் உத்தியோகபூர்வ இல்லம் என்பன முறையான காவலில் வைக்கப்பட வேண்டும். ஒழுங்கை நிலைநாட்ட தேவையானதைச் செய்யுமாறு இராணுவத் தளபதிகளுக்கும் பொலிஸ் மா அதிபருக்கும் நான் கட்டளையிட்டுள்ளேன்” என்று திரு. விக்கிரமசிங்க, தற்காலிக ஜனாதிபதியாக நியமிக்கப்பட்டதன் பின்னர் நாட்டுக்கு முதன்முதலாக தொலைக்காட்சி உரையில் கூறினார்.",
        "பிற்பகலில், ஜனாதிபதி அவர் இலங்கையில் இல்லாத நேரத்தில், புதன்கிழமை முதல் நடைமுறைக்கு வரும் வகையில், \"ஜனாதிபதி அலுவலகத்தின் அதிகாரங்கள், கடமைகள் மற்றும் செயல்பாடுகளை நடைமுறைப்படுத்தவும், நிறைவேற்றவும் மற்றும் நிறைவேற்றவும்\" திரு.விக்கிரமசிங்கவை நியமித்து வர்த்தமானி அறிவித்தல் வெளியிடப்பட்டது.",
        "பிரதமர், புதிதாக வழங்கப்பட்ட அதிகாரங்களைப் பயன்படுத்தி, ஒரே இரவில் ஊரடங்குச் சட்டத்தை விதித்தார். எழுத்துப்பூர்வ அனுமதியின்றி, வியாழக்கிழமை நள்ளிரவு முதல் அதிகாலை 5 மணி வரை பொதுச் சாலை, ரயில்வே அல்லது பொது மைதானம் அல்லது கடல் கரையோரத்தில் யாரும் இருக்கக் கூடாது என உத்தரவு பிறப்பிக்கப்பட்டுள்ளது.",
        "அரசாங்க எதிர்ப்பு ஆர்ப்பாட்டக்காரர்கள் பிரதான அரசு தொலைக்காட்சி நிலையத்திற்குள் நுழைந்து, புதன்கிழமை ஒளிபரப்புகளை சுருக்கமாக எடுத்துக் கொண்டனர், தனியார் மற்றும் சமூக ஊடகங்களில் வீடியோ காட்சிகள் காட்டப்பட்டன. ஜனாதிபதி, முதல் பெண்மணி மற்றும் இரண்டு மெய்ப்பாதுகாவலர்கள் புதன்கிழமை அதிகாலை மாலைதீவுக்கு விமானப்படை விமானத்தில் ஏறினர் என்று இலங்கை விமானப்படை கூறியதை அடுத்து, அவர்களும் விமானப்படை தலைமையகத்திற்கு வெளியே கூடினர். அவர் ராஜினாமா செய்யும் வரை பாதுகாப்பு அமைச்சர் மற்றும் தலைமை தளபதி பதவிகள்.",
        "இதேவேளை, புதன்கிழமை மாலை சபாநாயகர் மஹிந்த யாப்பா அபேவர்தனவைச் சந்தித்த அரசியல் கட்சித் தலைவர்கள், ஜனாதிபதியையும் பிரதமரையும் உடனடியாக பதவி விலகுமாறு கோருமாறும் அல்லது பிரதமரை பதவி விலகுவதற்கு முன்னர் அவரை பதவி நீக்கம் செய்யுமாறும் ஜனாதிபதியிடம் கோரியுள்ளனர்.",
        "சனிக்கிழமையன்று வியத்தகு பாரிய ஆர்ப்பாட்டங்களைத் தொடர்ந்து இலங்கையின் ஜனாதிபதி மற்றும் பிரதமர் இருவரும் பதவி விலக முன்வந்த போதிலும் - ஆர்ப்பாட்டக்காரர்கள் ஜனாதிபதியின் அலுவலகத்தையும் வீட்டையும் முற்றுகையிட்டனர், அதே நேரத்தில் தீக்குளித்தவர்கள் பிரதமரின் தனிப்பட்ட இல்லத்தை எரித்தனர் - இருவரும் பதவி விலகவில்லை, அரசியல் முட்டுக்கட்டை நீடிக்கிறது மற்றும் அரசாங்கத்திற்கு எதிரான போராட்டத்தை தூண்டியது. எதிர்ப்புகள். ஜனாதிபதி மற்றும் பிரதமரின் அலுவலகங்கள் வெற்றிடமாக இருக்கும் பட்சத்தில் அடுத்த கட்ட நடவடிக்கைகளை இலங்கையின் அரசியலமைப்பு தெளிவாக வகுத்துள்ளது, ஆனால் தலைவர்கள் ராஜினாமா செய்யும் வரை செயல்முறை தொடங்க முடியாது.",
        "திரு. கோட்டாபயவின் இருப்பிடம் பற்றிய ஊகங்கள் தொடரும் அதேவேளையில், மாலத்தீவில் உள்ள உயர் அதிகாரி ஒருவர், தலைவரின் வருகையின் \"உணர்திறன்\" மேற்கோள் காட்டி, பெயரை வெளியிட வேண்டாம் என்று கேட்டுக்கொண்டார், திரு. கோத்தபய நாட்டை \"கடந்து செல்வார்\" என்று தி இந்துவிடம் கூறினார். மாலத்தீவின் பாராளுமன்ற சபாநாயகரும் முன்னாள் ஜனாதிபதியுமான மொஹமட் நஷீத், விமான நிலையத்தில் திரு.கோட்டாபயவை வரவேற்றார், ஆனால் மேலேவில் இருந்து எந்த உத்தியோகபூர்வ தகவல்களும் இல்லை என்று ஊடக அறிக்கைகள் தெரிவித்தன.",
        "இலங்கைத் தலைவர் அடுத்து எங்கு செல்கிறார் என்று கேட்டதற்கு, ஆதாரம் மறுத்து விட்டது. திரு. கோட்டாபயவின் இறுதி இலக்கு இன்னும் தெளிவாகத் தெரியவில்லை, ஆனால் அவர் சிங்கப்பூருக்குச் சென்றதாகத் தகவல்கள் தெரிவிக்கின்றன."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ச",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "ஜனாதிபதி அலுவலகம்",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "புதன்",
          "label": "DATE"
        },
        {
          "text": "இலங்கை",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "மாலத்தீவுகள்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "புதன்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "கொழும்பு",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இரண்டு மாதங்களுக்கு முன்பு",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "முதலில்",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜனாதிபதி அலுவலகம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "புதன்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஒரே இரவில்",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "நள்ளிரவு முதல் காலை 5 மணி வரை",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "வியாழன்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "புதன்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "விமானப்படை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை விமானப்படை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இரண்டு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "விமானப்படை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "மாலத்தீவுகள்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "புதன்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "கோட்டாபய",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "மஹிந்த யாப்பா அபேவர்தன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "புதன்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சாயங்காலம்",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கையின்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சனிக்கிழமை",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கையின்",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "கோட்டாபய",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "மாலத்தீவுகள்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்து",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "கோட்டாபய",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "முகமது நஷீத்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "கோட்டாபய",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "கோட்டாபய",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "சிங்கப்பூர்",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}