{
  "newspaper_id": "ada-derana-lk",
  "url": "http://www.adaderana.lk/news/83709/current-parliament-doesnt-represent-majority-opinion-sajith",
  "time_ut": 1658072820,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Current Parliament doesn’t represent majority opinion - Sajith",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Current Parliament doesn’t represent majority opinion - Sajith",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "Sri Lankan’s leader of opposition, Sajith Premadasa, who is now contesting the presidential elections, on Sunday blamed the Rajapaksa government for the worst-ever economic crisis in the island nation of 22 million.",
        "Speaking to news agency ANI, Premadasa said that the opposition has been “telling the government for three years not to go ahead with ill-advised economic steps”. “They never listened and we are in a devastating state right now,” he stressed.",
        "The opposition leader asserted that he has a plan to recover from the economic debt.",
        "“Right now we have 225 parliamentarians choosing the president. Parliament comprises Gotabaya Rajapaksa’s legislative majority. The president will be chosen from this composition. I have given my name, and will see what happens. We are talking to all members,” he added.",
        "Earlier, Premadasa had termed the scenario of him winning Sri Lanka’s presidential elections an “uphill task”. He had said that he will “contest the elections as he is convinced that the truth will prevail”.",
        "Premadasa has raised concern over the Presidential elections. Premadasa said that the current parliament does not represent the opinion of most of the people.",
        "Speaking to ANI, Sajith Premadasa stated that parliamentarians will elect the President of Sri Lanka and stressed that the 225-member parliament currently has the majority of the leaders from former Sri Lankan President Gotabaya Rajapaksa’s political party.",
        "“Right now, what you have is a Parliament that does not represent the majority opinion of the people of the ground. So, they will have to think far and think aloud as to how they will use their vote,” Sajith Premadasa told ANI.",
        "Premadasa said that 225 parliamentarians will make the decision regarding the destiny of the people of Sri Lanka. He emphasized that usually the people of Sri Lanka elect the president and 22 million people must elect their President, according to ANI.",
        "“Usually, the President of Sri Lanka is chosen by the people... 22 million people are the voters, who have reached the age of voting, all have to choose their President. Right now, what we have is 225 parliamentarians choosing the President and this parliament is composed of Gotabaya Rajapaksa’s legislative majority. So it is from that particular composition that President will be chosen,” Sajith Premadasa told ANI.",
        "Speaking about the economic situation in Sri Lanka, Premadasa said that he was calling on the government to not take any ill-advised economic decisions. However, he stressed that government did not pay attention to his advice and stressed that “they are in a devastating state right now.”",
        "He lauded the efforts of Indian Prime Minister Narendra Modi and the government of India for the support they extended to their nation by providing basic human needs things. Notably, India has been providing petrol, diesel and other basic human needs items like life-saving drugs, wheat etc.",
        "“We admire the gracious effort of Prime Minister Narendra Modi, his government and the people of India for the tremendous support they have given us in terms of meeting the basic human needs of the people of our country. And we are so grateful and we continue to seek India’s help and support in this regard.”"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Parliament",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "Sajith",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lankan’s",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sajith Premadasa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sunday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Rajapaksa",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "22 million",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ANI",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Premadasa",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "three years",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "225",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Gotabaya Rajapaksa’s",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Premadasa",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka’s",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Premadasa",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Premadasa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ANI",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sajith Premadasa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "225",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lankan",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Gotabaya Rajapaksa’s",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ANI",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Premadasa",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "225",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "22 million",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ANI",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "22 million",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "225",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Gotabaya Rajapaksa’s",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ANI",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Premadasa",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Indian",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Narendra Modi",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "India",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "India",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Narendra Modi",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "India",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "India",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "වත්මන් පාර්ලිමේන්තුව බහුතර මතය නියෝජනය කරන්නේ නැහැ - සජිත්",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "දැන් ජනාධිපතිවරණයට ඉදිරිපත්ව සිටින ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ විපක්ෂ නායක සජිත් ප්‍රේමදාස ඉරිදා මිලියන 22 ක දිවයිනේ මෙතෙක් ඇති වූ දරුණුතම ආර්ථික අර්බුදය සම්බන්ධයෙන් රාජපක්ෂ රජයට දොස් පැවරීය.",
        "ANI පුවත් සේවයට අදහස් දක්වමින් ප්‍රේමදාස කියා සිටියේ විපක්ෂය “අවුරුදු තුනක් තිස්සේ රජයට කියන්නේ වැරදි උපදේශනාත්මක ආර්ථික පියවරයන් සමඟ ඉදිරියට නොයන ලෙස” බවයි. \"ඔවුන් කිසි විටෙකත් ඇහුම්කන් නොදුන් අතර අපි දැන් සිටින්නේ විනාශකාරී තත්වයක\" ඔහු අවධාරණය කළේය.",
        "ආර්ථික ණය බරින් ගොඩ ඒමේ සැලසුමක් තමන් සතුව පවතින බව විපක්ෂ නායකවරයා ප්‍රකාශ කළේය.",
        "“මේ වන විට අපට පාර්ලිමේන්තු මන්ත්‍රීවරුන් 225ක් ජනාධිපති තෝරනවා. පාර්ලිමේන්තුව සමන්විත වන්නේ ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂගේ ව්‍යවස්ථාදායක බහුතරයයි. මෙම සංයුතියෙන් ජනාධිපතිවරයා තෝරා ගනු ලැබේ. මම මගේ නම දුන්නා, මොකද වෙන්නේ කියලා බලන්නම්. අපි සියලුම සාමාජිකයන් සමඟ කතා කරනවා,” ඔහු වැඩිදුරටත් පැවසීය.",
        "මීට පෙර, ප්‍රේමදාස ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ ජනාධිපතිවරණ ජයග්‍රහණය කිරීමේ සිද්ධිය \"ඉහළ කර්තව්‍යයක්\" ලෙස නම් කර තිබුණි. “සත්‍යය ජය ගන්නා බව ඒත්තු යන බැවින් මැතිවරණයට ඉදිරිපත් වන” බව ඔහු පවසා තිබුණි.",
        "ප්‍රේමදාස මහතා ජනාධිපතිවරණය සම්බන්ධයෙන් කනස්සල්ල පළ කර තිබේ. ප්‍රේමදාස කියා සිටියේ වත්මන් පාර්ලිමේන්තුව බොහෝ දෙනාගේ මතය නියෝජනය නොකරන බවයි.",
        "ANI වෙත අදහස් දක්වමින් සජිත් ප්‍රේමදාස කියා සිටියේ පාර්ලිමේන්තු මන්ත්‍රීවරුන් ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ ජනාධිපතිවරයා තෝරා පත් කර ගන්නා බවත් මන්ත්‍රීවරුන් 225 දෙනෙකුගෙන් යුත් පාර්ලිමේන්තුවේ දැනට බහුතරයක් සිටින ශ්‍රී ලංකා ජනාධිපති ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂගේ දේශපාලන පක්ෂයේ නායකයින් බවත් අවධාරණය කළේය.",
        "“දැන් ඔබට තිබෙන්නේ මහපොළොවේ ජනතාවගේ බහුතර මතය නියෝජනය නොකරන පාර්ලිමේන්තුවක්. ඒ නිසා ඔවුන් තමන්ගේ ඡන්දය පාවිච්චි කරන්නේ කෙසේද යන්න ගැන බොහෝ දුර සිතන්නට සහ ශබ්ද නඟා සිතන්නට සිදුවේවි,” සජිත් ප්‍රේමදාස ANI වෙත පැවසීය.",
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ ජනතාවගේ ඉරණම සම්බන්ධයෙන් පාර්ලිමේන්තු මන්ත්‍රීවරුන් 225 දෙනෙකු තීරණය කරනු ඇති බව ප්‍රේමදාස මහතා පැවසීය. සාමාන්‍යයෙන් ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ ජනතාව ජනාධිපතිවරයා තෝරා පත් කර ගන්නා බවත්, මිලියන 22 ක ජනතාවක් තම ජනාධිපතිවරයා තෝරා පත් කර ගත යුතු බවත් ඔහු අවධාරණය කළේය.",
        "“සාමාන්‍යයෙන් ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ ජනාධිපතිවරයා තෝරා ගන්නේ ජනතාවයි... මිලියන 22 ක ජනතාවක් ඡන්දදායකයන් වන අතර, ඡන්දය ප්‍රකාශ කරන වයසට පැමිණි සියලු දෙනාටම තම ජනාධිපතිවරයා තෝරා ගත යුතුය. මේ වන විට අපට ඇත්තේ පාර්ලිමේන්තු මන්ත්‍රීවරුන් 225 දෙනෙකුගෙන් ජනාධිපතිවරයා තෝරා ගැනීම වන අතර මෙම පාර්ලිමේන්තුව සමන්විත වන්නේ ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂගේ ව්‍යවස්ථාදායක බහුතරයෙන්. ඒ නිසා ඒ විශේෂ සංයුතියෙන් තමයි ජනාධිපතිවරයා තෝරා ගන්නේ,” සජිත් ප්‍රේමදාස ANI වෙත පැවසීය.",
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ ආර්ථික තත්ත්වය පිළිබඳව අදහස් දක්වමින් ප්‍රේමදාස කියා සිටියේ අවවාදාත්මක ආර්ථික තීරණ නොගන්නා ලෙස තමන් රජයෙන් ඉල්ලා සිටින බවයි. කෙසේ වෙතත්, රජය තම උපදෙස් කෙරෙහි අවධානය යොමු නොකළ බව අවධාරණය කළ ඔහු “මේ වන විට ඔවුන් සිටින්නේ විනාශකාරී තත්ත්වයක” බව අවධාරණය කළේය.",
        "මූලික මිනිස් අවශ්‍යතා ලබා දෙමින් තම ජාතියට ලබා දුන් සහයෝගය වෙනුවෙන් ඉන්දීය අග්‍රාමාත්‍ය නරේන්ද්‍ර මෝදි සහ ඉන්දීය රජය දරන උත්සාහය ඔහු ප්‍රශංසා කළේය. විශේෂයෙන්, ඉන්දියාව පෙට්‍රල්, ඩීසල් සහ අනෙකුත් මූලික මිනිස් අවශ්‍යතා වන ජීවිතාරක්ෂක ඖෂධ, තිරිඟු ආදිය සපයා ඇත.",
        "“අපේ රටේ ජනතාවගේ මූලික මිනිස් අවශ්‍යතා සපුරාලීම සම්බන්ධයෙන් ඔවුන් අපට ලබා දී ඇති දැවැන්ත සහයෝගය සඳහා අග්‍රාමාත්‍ය නරේන්ද්‍ර මෝදි, ඔහුගේ රජය සහ ඉන්දීය ජනතාවගේ කාරුණික උත්සාහය අපි අගය කරමු. ඒ වගේම අපි කෘතඥ වෙනවා වගේම අපි මේ සම්බන්ධයෙන් ඉන්දියාවේ උදව් සහ සහයෝගය දිගටම ලබාගන්නවා.”"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "සජිත්",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලාංකිකයන්ගේ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "සජිත් ප්‍රේමදාස",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉරිදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මිලියන 22 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ANI",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ප්‍රේමදාස ය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "වසර තුනක්",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "225",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂගේ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ප්‍රේමදාස ය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ප්‍රේමදාස ය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ප්‍රේමදාස ය",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ANI",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "සජිත් ප්‍රේමදාස",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "225",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලාංකික",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂගේ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ANI",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ප්‍රේමදාස ය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "225",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මිලියන 22 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ANI",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මිලියන 22 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "225",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂගේ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ANI",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ප්‍රේමදාස ය",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දීය",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "නරේන්ද්‍ර මෝදි",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "නරේන්ද්‍ර මෝදි",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "தற்போதைய பாராளுமன்றம் பெரும்பான்மை கருத்தை பிரதிநிதித்துவப்படுத்தவில்லை - சஜித்",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "இப்போது ஜனாதிபதி தேர்தலில் போட்டியிடும் இலங்கையின் எதிர்க்கட்சித் தலைவர் சஜித் பிரேமதாசா ஞாயிற்றுக்கிழமை ஞாயிற்றுக்கிழமை 22 மில்லியன் தீவு நாட்டில் ஏற்பட்டுள்ள மோசமான பொருளாதார நெருக்கடிக்கு ராஜபக்சே அரசாங்கத்தை குற்றம் சாட்டினார்.",
        "ஏஎன்ஐ செய்தி நிறுவனத்திடம் பேசிய பிரேமதாசா, \"தவறான பொருளாதார நடவடிக்கைகளை மேற்கொள்ள வேண்டாம் என்று எதிர்க்கட்சிகள் மூன்று ஆண்டுகளாக அரசாங்கத்திடம் கூறி வருகின்றன\" என்று கூறினார். \"அவர்கள் ஒருபோதும் செவிசாய்க்கவில்லை, நாங்கள் இப்போது ஒரு பேரழிவு நிலையில் இருக்கிறோம்,\" என்று அவர் வலியுறுத்தினார்.",
        "பொருளாதாரக் கடனில் இருந்து மீள்வதற்கான திட்டம் தன்னிடம் இருப்பதாக எதிர்க்கட்சித் தலைவர் வலியுறுத்தினார்.",
        "தற்போது 225 பாராளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர்கள் ஜனாதிபதியை தெரிவு செய்துள்ளோம். பாராளுமன்றம் கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்சவின் பெரும்பான்மையை கொண்டுள்ளது. இந்த அமைப்பில் இருந்து ஜனாதிபதி தேர்ந்தெடுக்கப்படுவார். நான் என் பெயரைக் கொடுத்துள்ளேன், என்ன நடக்கிறது என்று பார்க்கிறேன். நாங்கள் அனைத்து உறுப்பினர்களுடனும் பேசி வருகிறோம்” என்று அவர் மேலும் கூறினார்.",
        "முன்னதாக, பிரேமதாசா இலங்கையின் ஜனாதிபதித் தேர்தலில் வெற்றி பெற்ற காட்சியை \"மேல்நோக்கிய பணி\" என்று குறிப்பிட்டிருந்தார். உண்மை வெல்லும் என்பதில் உறுதியாக இருப்பதால் தேர்தலில் போட்டியிடப் போவதாக அவர் கூறினார்.",
        "ஜனாதிபதி தேர்தல் தொடர்பில் பிரேமதாச கவலை வெளியிட்டுள்ளார். தற்போதைய பாராளுமன்றம் பெரும்பாலான மக்களின் கருத்தை பிரதிநிதித்துவப்படுத்தவில்லை என பிரேமதாச தெரிவித்துள்ளார்.",
        "ஏஎன்ஐ செய்தி நிறுவனத்திடம் பேசிய சஜித் பிரேமதாசா, இலங்கையின் அதிபரை நாடாளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர்கள் தேர்ந்தெடுப்பார்கள் என்றும், 225 உறுப்பினர்களைக் கொண்ட நாடாளுமன்றத்தில் தற்போது இலங்கையின் முன்னாள் அதிபர் கோத்தபய ராஜபக்சவின் அரசியல் கட்சித் தலைவர்கள் பெரும்பான்மையாக இருப்பதாகவும் வலியுறுத்தினார்.",
        "“இப்போது, ​​உங்களிடம் இருப்பது தரைமட்ட மக்களின் பெரும்பான்மை கருத்தைப் பிரதிநிதித்துவப்படுத்தாத நாடாளுமன்றம். எனவே, அவர்கள் தங்கள் வாக்குகளை எப்படிப் பயன்படுத்துவார்கள் என்று அவர்கள் வெகுதூரம் யோசித்து உரக்கச் சிந்திக்க வேண்டும்” என்று சஜித் பிரேமதாச ANI இடம் கூறினார்.",
        "இலங்கை மக்களின் தலைவிதி தொடர்பில் 225 நாடாளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர்கள் தீர்மானம் எடுப்பார்கள் என பிரேமதாச தெரிவித்துள்ளார். பொதுவாக இலங்கை மக்கள் ஜனாதிபதியை தெரிவு செய்வதாகவும், 22 மில்லியன் மக்கள் தமது ஜனாதிபதியை தெரிவு செய்ய வேண்டும் எனவும் அவர் வலியுறுத்தியுள்ளார்.",
        "“வழக்கமாக, இலங்கையின் ஜனாதிபதியை மக்கள் தெரிவு செய்கிறார்கள்... 22 மில்லியன் மக்கள் வாக்காளர்கள், வாக்களிக்கும் வயதை எட்டியவர்கள், அனைவரும் தங்கள் ஜனாதிபதியைத் தேர்ந்தெடுக்க வேண்டும். தற்போது எங்களிடம் இருப்பது 225 பாராளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர்கள் ஜனாதிபதியை தெரிவு செய்வதாகும், இந்த பாராளுமன்றம் கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்சவின் சட்டமன்ற பெரும்பான்மையை கொண்டது. எனவே அந்த குறிப்பிட்ட அமைப்பில் இருந்துதான் ஜனாதிபதி தேர்ந்தெடுக்கப்படுவார்” என சஜித் பிரேமதாச ANI இடம் கூறினார்.",
        "இலங்கையின் பொருளாதார நிலைமை குறித்து பேசிய பிரேமதாச, தவறான பொருளாதார முடிவுகளை எடுக்க வேண்டாம் என்று அரசாங்கத்தை கேட்டுக்கொள்கிறேன் என்று கூறினார். எவ்வாறாயினும், அரசாங்கம் தனது அறிவுரைகளுக்கு கவனம் செலுத்தவில்லை என்றும், \"அவர்கள் இப்போது பேரழிவு நிலையில் உள்ளனர்\" என்றும் அவர் வலியுறுத்தினார்.",
        "இந்தியப் பிரதமர் நரேந்திர மோடி மற்றும் இந்திய அரசாங்கத்தின் முயற்சிகள் மனிதனின் அடிப்படைத் தேவைகளை வழங்குவதன் மூலம் தங்கள் தேசத்திற்கு அவர்கள் வழங்கிய ஆதரவிற்காக அவர் பாராட்டினார். குறிப்பிடத்தக்க வகையில், இந்தியா பெட்ரோல், டீசல் மற்றும் உயிர்காக்கும் மருந்துகள், கோதுமை போன்ற பிற அடிப்படை மனித தேவைகளை வழங்கி வருகிறது.",
        "“பிரதமர் நரேந்திர மோடி, அவரது அரசாங்கம் மற்றும் இந்திய மக்கள் நமது நாட்டு மக்களின் அடிப்படைத் தேவைகளைப் பூர்த்தி செய்வதில் எங்களுக்கு அளித்த அளப்பரிய ஆதரவிற்காக நாங்கள் மேற்கொண்ட கருணைமிக்க முயற்சியை நாங்கள் பாராட்டுகிறோம். நாங்கள் மிகவும் நன்றியுள்ளவர்களாக இருக்கிறோம், இந்த விஷயத்தில் இந்தியாவின் உதவியையும் ஆதரவையும் நாங்கள் தொடர்ந்து நாடுகிறோம்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "சஜித்",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கையர்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "சஜித் பிரேமதாச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஞாயிற்றுக்கிழமை",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ராஜபக்சே",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "22 மில்லியன்",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ANI",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "பிரேமதாச",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "மூன்று வருடங்கள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "225",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்சவின்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பிரேமதாச",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கையின்",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பிரேமதாச",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "பிரேமதாச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ANI",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "சஜித் பிரேமதாச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "225",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்சவின்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ANI",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பிரேமதாச",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "225",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "22 மில்லியன்",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ANI",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "22 மில்லியன்",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "225",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்சவின்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ANI",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "பிரேமதாச",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இந்தியன்",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "நரேந்திர மோடி",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்தியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்தியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "நரேந்திர மோடி",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்தியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்தியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}