{
  "newspaper_id": "ada-derana-lk",
  "url": "http://www.adaderana.lk/news/83902/powerful-71-earthquake-strikes-philippines",
  "time_ut": 1658908800,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Powerful 7.1 earthquake strikes Philippines",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Powerful 7.1 earthquake strikes Philippines",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "A powerful 7.1 magnitude earthquake struck the northern Philippine island of Luzon on Wednesday killing four people, damaging buildings and sending strong tremors through the capital, Manila.",
        "Two people were killed in Benguet province, one in Abra province, and one more in another province, Interior Secretary Benjamin Abalos told a news conference. Sixty people were injured, he said.",
        "The quake struck about 11 km (six miles) southeast of the town of Dolores at a shallow depth of 10 km (6 miles), according to U.S. Geological Survey data.",
        "“Despite the sad reports about the damages caused by the earthquake, we are assuring quick response to those in need and affected by this calamity,” President Ferdinand Marcos Jr said on Facebook.",
        "Renato Solidum, director of the state seismology agency, told DZRH radio station, strong aftershocks were expected.",
        "“The focus of attention is on Abra and nearby provinces. This is a major earthquake,” Solidum said.",
        "Abalos said 173 buildings were damaged and 58 landslides reported, with 44 of the 60 injured in Abra province.",
        "A hospital in Abra province was evacuated after the building partially collapsed but there were no casualties reported there, officials said.",
        "Abra’s vice governor, Joy Bernos, posted photos of the damaged Abra hospital on her Facebook account, which showed a gaping hole in its facade.",
        "Other photos showed hospital beds, including one with a patient, being wheeled across a road and evacuated hospital staff.",
        "Abra, home to nearly 250,000 people, is a landlocked province in the northern Philippines. Its deep valleys and sloping hills are enclosed by rugged mountains.",
        "The Philippines is prone to natural disasters and is located on the seismically active Pacific “Ring of Fire”, a band of volcanoes and fault lines that arcs round the edge of the Pacific Ocean. Earthquakes are frequent and there are an average of 20 typhoons each year, some triggering deadly landslides.",
        "Eric Singson, a congressman in Ilocos Sur province, also in the north, told DZMM radio station the quake had been felt strongly there and lasted 30 seconds or more.",
        "“I thought my house would fall,” said Singson. “Now, we are trying to reach people .... Right now there are aftershocks so we are outside our home.”",
        "The quake damaged heritage buildings in the city of Vigan, known for its old Spanish colonial architecture, on the west coast of Luzon.",
        "Tourist Edison Adducul told radio he was taking photos of the Bantay Church Bell tower in Vigan when the quake struck, shaking the tower for up to three minutes.",
        "“The antique bricks and coral stones fell down from the Bantay Bell Tower,” she said.",
        "The quake was also felt in Manila where several buildings were evacuated, with some people forced to flee from the 30th floor of one building, and the city’s metro rail systems were halted at rush hour."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "7.1",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "Philippines",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "7.1",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Philippine",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Luzon",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "Wednesday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "four",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Manila",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Two",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Abra province",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "one",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Interior",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Benjamin Abalos",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "about 11 km",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "six miles",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "10 km",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "6 miles",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "U.S. Geological Survey",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Ferdinand Marcos Jr",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Renato Solidum",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Solidum",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Abalos",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "173",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "58",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "44",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "60",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Abra province",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Abra province",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Joy Bernos",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "one",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "nearly 250,000",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Philippines",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Philippines",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Pacific",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Pacific Ocean",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "20",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "each year",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Eric Singson",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ilocos Sur",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "DZMM",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "30 seconds",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Singson",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Vigan",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Spanish",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "the west coast",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "Luzon",
            "label": "LOC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Edison Adducul",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Bantay Church Bell",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Vigan",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "up to three minutes",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the Bantay Bell Tower",
            "label": "FAC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Manila",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "30th",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "one",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "metro",
            "label": "FAC"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "පිලිපීනයට බලගතු 7.1 භූමිකම්පාවක්",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "උතුරු පිලිපීනයේ ලුසොන් දූපතේ බදාදා රික්ටර් මාපක 7.1 ක ප්‍රබල භූමිකම්පාවකින් පුද්ගලයන් හතර දෙනෙකු මිය ගොස් ගොඩනැගිලිවලට හානි සිදු වූ අතර මැනිලා අගනුවර හරහා ප්‍රබල කම්පන ඇති විය.",
        "බෙන්ගුට් පළාතේ පුද්ගලයන් දෙදෙනකු ද, අබ්‍රා පළාතේ එක් අයකු ද, තවත් එක් පළාතක තවත් අයෙක් ද මිය ගිය බව අභ්‍යන්තර කටයුතු ලේකම් බෙන්ජමින් අබලෝස් ප්‍රවෘත්ති සාකච්ඡාවකදී පැවසීය. හැට දෙනෙකු තුවාල ලබා ඇති බව ඔහු පැවසීය.",
        "එක්සත් ජනපද භූ විද්‍යා සමීක්ෂණ දත්ත වලට අනුව, භූමිකම්පාව ඩොලෝරස් නගරයේ සිට කිලෝමීටර් 11 (සැතපුම් හයක්) පමණ ගිනිකොන දෙසින් කිලෝමීටර් 10 (සැතපුම් 6) නොගැඹුරු ගැඹුරකින් ඇති විය.",
        "\"භූමිකම්පාවෙන් සිදු වූ හානිය පිළිබඳ කනගාටුදායක වාර්තා තිබියදීත්, මෙම විපතෙන් පීඩාවට පත් වූවන්ට සහ අවශ්‍යතා ඇති අයට ඉක්මන් ප්‍රතිචාර දැක්වීමට අපි සහතික වෙමු\" යැයි ජනාධිපති ෆර්ඩිනන්ඩ් මාකෝස් ජූනියර් ෆේස්බුක් හි පැවසීය.",
        "රාජ්‍ය භූ කම්පන විද්‍යා ඒජන්සියේ අධ්‍යක්ෂ රෙනාටෝ සොලිඩම් DZRH ගුවන් විදුලි මධ්‍යස්ථානයට පැවසුවේ ප්‍රබල පසු කම්පන අපේක්ෂා කරන බවයි.",
        "“අවධානයේ අවධානය යොමු වී ඇත්තේ ආබ්‍රා සහ අවට පළාත් වෙත ය. මෙය විශාල භූමිකම්පාවක්, ”සොලිඩම් පැවසීය.",
        "අබාලෝස් පැවසුවේ ගොඩනැගිලි 173 කට හානි සිදුවී ඇති අතර නායයෑම් 58 ක් වාර්තා වී ඇති අතර 60 න් 44 ක් තුවාල ලබා ඇත්තේ අබ්‍රා පළාතේ ය.",
        "ගොඩනැගිල්ල අර්ධ වශයෙන් කඩා වැටීමෙන් පසු අබ්රා පළාතේ රෝහලක් ඉවත් කර ඇති නමුත් එහි කිසිදු ජීවිත හානියක් වාර්තා වී නොමැති බව බලධාරීහු පවසති.",
        "Abra හි උප ආණ්ඩුකාර, Joy Bernos, හානියට පත් Abra රෝහලේ ඡායාරූප ඇගේ ෆේස්බුක් ගිණුමේ පළ කර ඇති අතර, එහි මුහුණතෙහි හිඩැසක් පෙන්නුම් කළේය.",
        "වෙනත් ඡායාරූපවල දැක්වෙන්නේ රෝගියෙකු සිටින ඇඳන් ඇතුළුව රෝහල් ඇඳන් මාර්ගයක් හරහා රෝද කර රෝහල් කාර්ය මණ්ඩලය ඉවත් කර ඇති ආකාරයයි.",
        "250,000 කට ආසන්න ජනතාවක් වාසය කරන Abra, උතුරු පිලිපීනයේ ගොඩබිම් සහිත පළාතකි. එහි ගැඹුරු නිම්න සහ බෑවුම් සහිත කඳු රළු කඳු වලින් වට වී ඇත.",
        "පිලිපීනය ස්වාභාවික විපත් වලට ගොදුරු වන අතර එය පිහිටා ඇත්තේ භූ කම්පන ක්‍රියාකාරී පැසිෆික් \"රින්ග් ඔෆ් ෆයර්\" මත වන අතර එය පැසිෆික් සාගරයේ මායිම වටා ඇති ගිනිකඳු සහ දෝෂ රේඛා සමූහයකි. භූමිකම්පා නිතර සිදුවන අතර සෑම වසරකම සාමාන්‍යයෙන් ටයිෆූන් 20 ක් ඇති වන අතර සමහර ඒවා මාරාන්තික නායයෑම් ඇති කරයි.",
        "උතුරේ ද ඉලොකොස් සුර් පළාතේ කොන්ග්‍රස් සභිකයෙකු වන එරික් සිංසන් DZMM ගුවන් විදුලි මධ්‍යස්ථානයට පැවසුවේ භූමිකම්පාව එහි ප්‍රබල ලෙස දැනී තත්පර 30ක් හෝ ඊට වැඩි කාලයක් පැවති බවයි.",
        "\"මම හිතුවා මගේ ගෙදර වැටෙයි කියලා,\" සිංසන් පැවසීය. \"දැන්, අපි මිනිසුන් වෙත ළඟා වීමට උත්සාහ කරන්නෙමු ... මේ මොහොතේ පසු කම්පන ඇති බැවින් අපි අපගේ නිවසින් පිටත සිටිමු.\"",
        "භූමිකම්පාවෙන් ලුසොන්හි බටහිර වෙරළ තීරයේ පැරණි ස්පාඤ්ඤ යටත් විජිත ගෘහනිර්මාණ ශිල්පය සඳහා ප්රසිද්ධ වීගන් නගරයේ උරුම ගොඩනැගිලි වලට හානි සිදු විය.",
        "සංචාරක එඩිසන් ඇඩ්ඩුකුල් ගුවන් විදුලියට පැවසුවේ භූමිකම්පාව ඇති වූ විට ඔහු විගන් හි බන්ටේ පල්ලියේ බෙල් කුළුණේ ඡායාරූප ගනිමින් සිටි අතර කුළුණ මිනිත්තු තුනක් දක්වා සෙලවීය.",
        "“පෞරාණික ගඩොල් සහ කොරල් ගල් බැන්ටේ බෙල් කුළුණෙන් බිමට වැටුණා,” ඇය පැවසුවාය.",
        "භූමිකම්පාව මැනිලා හි ද දැනී ඇති අතර එහිදී ගොඩනැගිලි කිහිපයක් ඉවත් කරන ලදී, සමහර පුද්ගලයින්ට එක් ගොඩනැගිල්ලක 30 වන මහලෙන් පලා යාමට සිදු වූ අතර, නගරයේ මෙට්‍රෝ දුම්රිය පද්ධති කාර්යබහුල වේලාවේදී නතර විය."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "7.1",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "පිලිපීනය",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "7.1",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "පිලිපීනය",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ලුසන්",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "බදාදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "හතර",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "මැනිලා",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "දෙක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ආබ්රා පළාත",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "එක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "අභ්යන්තරය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "බෙන්ජමින් අබාලෝස්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "11 කි.මී",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "සැතපුම් හයක්",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "10 කි.මී",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "සැතපුම් 6 කි",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "එක්සත් ජනපද භූ විද්‍යා සමීක්ෂණය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ෆර්ඩිනන්ඩ් මාකෝස් ජූනියර්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "රෙනාටෝ සොලිඩම්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Solidum",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "අබාලෝස්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "173",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "58",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "44",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "60",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ආබ්රා පළාත",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ආබ්රා පළාත",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ජෝයි බර්නෝස්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "එක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "250,000කට ආසන්නයි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "පිලිපීනය",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "පිලිපීනය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "පැසිෆික්",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "පැසිෆික් සාගරය",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "20",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "සෑම වසරකම",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "එරික් සිංසන්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉලොකොස් සූර්",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "DZMM",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "තත්පර 30 යි",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "සිංසන්",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "විගන්",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ස්පාඤ්ඤ",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "බටහිර වෙරළ තීරය",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "ලුසන්",
            "label": "LOC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "එඩිසන් ඇඩ්ඩුකුල්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "බැන්ටේ පල්ලියේ සීනුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "විගන්",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මිනිත්තු තුනක් දක්වා",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "බැන්ටේ බෙල් කුළුණ",
            "label": "FAC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "මැනිලා",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "30 වැනි",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "එක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "මෙට්රෝ",
            "label": "FAC"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "பிலிப்பைன்ஸை 7.1 ரிக்டர் அளவில் சக்திவாய்ந்த நிலநடுக்கம் தாக்கியது",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "வடக்கு பிலிப்பைன்ஸின் லூசோன் தீவில் புதன்கிழமை 7.1 ரிக்டர் அளவிலான சக்திவாய்ந்த நிலநடுக்கம் நான்கு பேர் கொல்லப்பட்டது, கட்டிடங்களை சேதப்படுத்தியது மற்றும் தலைநகர் மணிலா வழியாக வலுவான நடுக்கங்களை அனுப்பியது.",
        "பெங்குவெட் மாகாணத்தில் இருவர், அப்ரா மாகாணத்தில் ஒருவர், மற்றொரு மாகாணத்தில் மேலும் ஒருவர் கொல்லப்பட்டதாக உள்துறை செயலாளர் பெஞ்சமின் அபலோஸ் செய்தியாளர் கூட்டத்தில் தெரிவித்தார். 60 பேர் காயமடைந்துள்ளனர், என்றார்.",
        "அமெரிக்க புவியியல் ஆய்வு தரவுகளின்படி, இந்த நிலநடுக்கம் டோலோரஸ் நகருக்கு தென்கிழக்கே சுமார் 11 கிமீ (ஆறு மைல்) தொலைவில் 10 கிமீ (6 மைல்) ஆழம் குறைந்த ஆழத்தில் தாக்கியது.",
        "\"பூகம்பத்தால் ஏற்பட்ட சேதங்கள் பற்றிய சோகமான அறிக்கைகள் இருந்தபோதிலும், இந்த பேரிடரால் பாதிக்கப்பட்டவர்களுக்கு விரைவான பதிலை நாங்கள் உறுதியளிக்கிறோம்\" என்று ஜனாதிபதி ஃபெர்டினாண்ட் மார்கோஸ் ஜூனியர் பேஸ்புக்கில் தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "மாநில நில அதிர்வு அமைப்பின் இயக்குனர் ரெனாடோ சாலிடம், DZRH வானொலி நிலையத்திடம், வலுவான பின்அதிர்வுகள் எதிர்பார்க்கப்படுகிறது.",
        "“அப்ரா மற்றும் அருகிலுள்ள மாகாணங்களில் கவனம் செலுத்தப்படுகிறது. இது ஒரு பெரிய நிலநடுக்கம்,” என்று Solidum கூறினார்.",
        "173 கட்டிடங்கள் சேதமடைந்துள்ளதாகவும், 58 நிலச்சரிவுகள் பதிவாகியுள்ளதாகவும், அப்ரா மாகாணத்தில் 60 பேரில் 44 பேர் காயமடைந்துள்ளதாகவும் அபாலோஸ் கூறினார்.",
        "கட்டிடம் பகுதி இடிந்து விழுந்ததால் அப்ரா மாகாணத்தில் உள்ள ஒரு மருத்துவமனை வெளியேற்றப்பட்டது, ஆனால் அங்கு உயிரிழப்பு எதுவும் ஏற்படவில்லை என்று அதிகாரிகள் தெரிவித்தனர்.",
        "அப்ராவின் துணை ஆளுநர் ஜாய் பெர்னோஸ், சேதமடைந்த அப்ரா மருத்துவமனையின் புகைப்படங்களை தனது முகநூல் கணக்கில் வெளியிட்டார்.",
        "மற்ற புகைப்படங்கள் மருத்துவமனை படுக்கைகள், நோயாளியுடன் ஒன்று உட்பட, சாலையின் குறுக்கே சக்கரம் கொண்டு செல்லப்பட்டு மருத்துவமனை ஊழியர்களை வெளியேற்றியது.",
        "ஏறக்குறைய 250,000 மக்கள் வசிக்கும் அப்ரா, வடக்கு பிலிப்பைன்ஸில் நிலத்தால் சூழப்பட்ட மாகாணமாகும். அதன் ஆழமான பள்ளத்தாக்குகள் மற்றும் சாய்வான மலைகள் கரடுமுரடான மலைகளால் சூழப்பட்டுள்ளன.",
        "பிலிப்பைன்ஸ் இயற்கை பேரழிவுகளுக்கு ஆளாகிறது மற்றும் நில அதிர்வு சுறுசுறுப்பான பசிபிக் \"ரிங் ஆஃப் ஃபயர்\" இல் அமைந்துள்ளது, இது பசிபிக் பெருங்கடலின் விளிம்பில் வளைந்திருக்கும் எரிமலைகள் மற்றும் பிழைக் கோடுகளின் குழுவாகும். பூகம்பங்கள் அடிக்கடி நிகழ்கின்றன மற்றும் ஒவ்வொரு ஆண்டும் சராசரியாக 20 சூறாவளிகள் உள்ளன, சில கொடிய நிலச்சரிவுகளைத் தூண்டுகின்றன.",
        "வடக்கில் உள்ள இலோகோஸ் சுர் மாகாணத்தில் உள்ள காங்கிரஸார் எரிக் சிங்சன், DZMM வானொலி நிலையத்திடம் நிலநடுக்கம் அங்கு வலுவாக உணரப்பட்டு 30 வினாடிகள் அல்லது அதற்கு மேல் நீடித்ததாக தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "\"என் வீடு விழும் என்று நான் நினைத்தேன்,\" சிங்சன் கூறினார். \"இப்போது, ​​​​நாங்கள் மக்களைச் சென்றடைய முயற்சிக்கிறோம் .... இப்போது நில அதிர்வுகள் உள்ளன, எனவே நாங்கள் எங்கள் வீட்டிற்கு வெளியே இருக்கிறோம்.\"",
        "இந்த நிலநடுக்கத்தால் லூசோனின் மேற்கு கடற்கரையில் உள்ள பழைய ஸ்பானிஷ் காலனித்துவ கட்டிடக்கலைக்கு பெயர் பெற்ற விகான் நகரில் உள்ள பாரம்பரிய கட்டிடங்கள் சேதமடைந்தன.",
        "சுற்றுலா பயணி எடிசன் அடுகுல் வானொலியிடம், விகானில் உள்ள பாண்டே சர்ச் பெல் கோபுரத்தின் புகைப்படங்களை எடுத்துக் கொண்டிருந்தபோது நிலநடுக்கம் ஏற்பட்டது, கோபுரத்தை மூன்று நிமிடங்கள் வரை உலுக்கியது.",
        "\"பண்டே பெல் டவரில் இருந்து பழங்கால செங்கற்கள் மற்றும் பவளக் கற்கள் கீழே விழுந்தன,\" என்று அவர் கூறினார்.",
        "மணிலாவிலும் நிலநடுக்கம் உணரப்பட்டது, அங்கு பல கட்டிடங்கள் வெளியேற்றப்பட்டன, சிலர் ஒரு கட்டிடத்தின் 30 வது மாடியில் இருந்து வெளியேற வேண்டிய கட்டாயம் ஏற்பட்டது, மேலும் நகரின் மெட்ரோ ரயில் அமைப்புகள் அவசர நேரத்தில் நிறுத்தப்பட்டன."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "7.1",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "பிலிப்பைன்ஸ்",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "7.1",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "பிலிப்பைன்ஸ்",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "லூசன்",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "புதன்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "நான்கு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "மணிலா",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இரண்டு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "அப்ரா மாகாணம்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஒன்று",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "உட்புறம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "பெஞ்சமின் அபாலோஸ்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "சுமார் 11 கி.மீ",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆறு மைல்கள்",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "10 கி.மீ",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "6 மைல்கள்",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "யு.எஸ் புவியியல் ஆய்வு",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஃபெர்டினாண்ட் மார்கோஸ் ஜூனியர்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ரெனாடோ சாலிடம்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "சாலிடம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "அபலோஸ்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "173",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "58",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "44",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "60",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "அப்ரா மாகாணம்",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "அப்ரா மாகாணம்",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஜாய் பெர்னோஸ்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஒன்று",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "கிட்டத்தட்ட 250,000",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "பிலிப்பைன்ஸ்",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பிலிப்பைன்ஸ்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "பசிபிக்",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "பசிபிக் பெருங்கடல்",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "20",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஒவ்வொரு வருடமும்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "எரிக் சிங்சன்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலோகோஸ் சுர்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "DZMM",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "30 வினாடிகள்",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "சிங்சன்",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "விகன்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஸ்பானிஷ்",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "மேற்கு கடற்கரை",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "லூசன்",
            "label": "LOC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "எடிசன் அடுகுல்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாண்டே சர்ச் பெல்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "விகன்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "மூன்று நிமிடங்கள் வரை",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பாண்டே பெல் டவர்",
            "label": "FAC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "மணிலா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "30வது",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஒன்று",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "மெட்ரோ",
            "label": "FAC"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}