{
  "newspaper_id": "ada-lk",
  "url": "https://www.ada.lk/breaking_news/ඩෑන්ගේ-සහෝදරයා-ඝාතනය-කෙරේ/11-395754",
  "time_ut": 1658825403,
  "original_lang": "si",
  "original_title": "ඩෑන්ගේ සහෝදරයා ඝාතනය කෙරේ",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Dan's brother is murdered",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "According to Wellampitiya Police, two unknown persons carrying sharp weapons on a motorcycle hacked a person to death near the Orugudawatta Flyover yesterday (25th) night.",
        "Prakas Thilina Kumara, 34, resident of Kalansuriya Lane, Wellampitiya, Methotamulla, has been murdered.",
        "Police also say that the murdered person is the brother of social activist Dan Priyasad.",
        "The police say that the murdered person, who usually stays near the Orugudawatta flyover in the evening with his friends, is on judicial bail from remand for causing serious injuries to several people with sharp weapons.",
        "A police officer said that an accused appears at the Wellampitiya Police on the last Sunday of every month on court orders.",
        "On the instructions of Wellampitiya Police Station Chief Inspector Nilantha Indika, a team including Crime Division Station Officer Sub Inspector Viraj is conducting investigations."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Dan",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Wellampitiya Police",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "two",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Orugudawatta Flyover",
            "label": "PRODUCT"
          },
          {
            "text": "yesterday",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Prakas",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Thilina Kumara",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "34",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kalansuriya Lane",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Wellampitiya",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Methotamulla",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Dan Priyasad",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Orugudawatta",
            "label": "PRODUCT"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the Wellampitiya Police",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the last Sunday of every month",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Nilantha Indika",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Crime Division Station Officer Sub",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Viraj",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "ඩෑන්ගේ සහෝදරයා ඝාතනය කෙරේ",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "තියුණු ආයුධ රැගෙන  යතුරුපැදියකින් පැමිණි නාඳුනන පුද්ගලයන් දෙදෙනෙකු ඔරුගොඩවත්ත ගුවන් පාලම අසලදී  ඊ‍යේ (25දා)  රාත්‍රී  පුද්ගලයෙකු  කපා  කොටා ඝාතනය කර ඇතැයි වැල්ලම්පිටිය පොලීසිය පවසයි.",
        "මෙලෙස ඝාතනයට ලක්ව ඇත්තේ වැල්ලම්පිටිය මීතොටමුල්ල කලංසූරිය පටුමග පදිංචිව සිටි ප්‍රකාස් තිළිණ  කුමාර  34 නමැති අයයි.",
        "ඝාතනයට ලක්වූ පුද්ගලයා සමාජ ක්‍රියාකාරිකයකු වූ ඩෑන් ප්‍රියසාද් යන  අයගේ සහෝදරයා බවත් පොලිසිය කියයි.",
        "පුරුද්දක් ලෙස මිතුරන් සමග ඔරුගොඩවත්ත ගුවන් පාලම අසල සවස් කාලයට නිරතුරුවම රැඳී සිටින ඝාතනයට ලක්වූ පුද්ගලයා  තියුණු ආයුධවලින් පුද්ගලයන් කීපදෙනෙකු කීප දෙනකුට බරපතළ තුවාල  සිදුකිරීම සම්බන්ධයෙන් රිමාන්ඩ් භාරයේ සිට අධිකරණ ඇප මත සිටින්නෙකු බවත් පොලිසිය කියයි.",
        "සෑම මසකම අවසන් ඉරුදින වැල්ලම්පිටිය පොලිසියේ  අධිකරණ නියෝග මත  පෙනී සිටින චූදිතයෙක් බවත් පොලිස් නිළධාරියෙකු පැවසීය",
        "වැල්ලම්පිටිය පොලිසියේ ස්ථානාධිපති ප්‍රධාන පොලිස් පරීක්ෂක නිලන්ත ඉන්දික මහතාගේ උපදෙස් මත අපරාධ අංශයේ ස්ථානාධිපති උප පොලිස් පරීක්ෂක විරාජ් මහතා ඇතුළු කණ්ඩායමක් පරීක්ෂණ පවත්වයි."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ඩෑන්",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "වැල්ලම්පිටිය පොලිසිය",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "දෙක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඔරුගුඩාවත්ත ගුවන් පාලම",
            "label": "PRODUCT"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඊයේ",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ප්රකාස්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "තිළිණ කුමාර",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "34",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "කලංසූරිය පටුමග",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "වැල්ලම්පිටිය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "මෙතොටමුල්ල",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ඩෑන් ප්‍රියසාද්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Orugudawatta",
            "label": "PRODUCT"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "වැල්ලම්පිටිය පොලිසිය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "සෑම මසකම අවසාන ඉරිදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "නිලන්ත ඉන්දික",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "අපරාධ කොට්ඨාසයේ ස්ථානාධිපති උප",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "විරාජ්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "டானின் சகோதரர் கொல்லப்பட்டார்",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "நேற்று (25) இரவு ஒருகுடவத்தை மேம்பாலத்திற்கு அருகில் மோட்டார் சைக்கிளில் கூரிய ஆயுதங்களை ஏற்றிச் சென்ற இனந்தெரியாத இருவர் நபர் ஒருவரை வெட்டிக் கொலை செய்துள்ளதாக வெல்லம்பிட்டிய பொலிஸார் தெரிவித்தனர்.",
        "வெல்லம்பிட்டிய, மெதொட்டமுல்ல கலன்சூரிய லேனைச் சேர்ந்த 34 வயதான பிரகாஸ் திலின குமார என்பவரே இவ்வாறு படுகொலை செய்யப்பட்டுள்ளார்.",
        "கொலை செய்யப்பட்டவர் சமூக ஆர்வலர் டான் பிரியசாத்தின் சகோதரர் என்றும் போலீசார் கூறுகின்றனர்.",
        "கொலைசெய்யப்பட்ட நபர், தனது நண்பர்களுடன் மாலையில் ஒருகுடவத்த மேம்பாலத்திற்கு அருகில் தங்கியிருந்து, கூரிய ஆயுதங்களால் பலருக்கு பலத்த காயங்களை ஏற்படுத்திய குற்றத்திற்காக நீதிமன்ற பிணையில் விளக்கமறியலில் உள்ளதாக பொலிஸார் தெரிவிக்கின்றனர்.",
        "நீதிமன்ற உத்தரவின் பேரில் ஒவ்வொரு மாதமும் கடைசி ஞாயிற்றுக்கிழமைகளில் குற்றம்சாட்டப்பட்ட ஒருவர் வெல்லம்பிட்டிய பொலிஸில் ஆஜராவதாக பொலிஸ் அதிகாரி ஒருவர் தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "வெல்லம்பிட்டிய பொலிஸ் நிலைய பிரதான பொலிஸ் பரிசோதகர் நிலந்த இந்திக்கவின் பணிப்புரையின் பேரில் குற்றப் பிரிவு நிலைய பொறுப்பதிகாரி உப பொலிஸ் பரிசோதகர் விராஜ் உள்ளிட்ட குழுவினர் விசாரணைகளை மேற்கொண்டு வருகின்றனர்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "டான்",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "வெல்லம்பிட்டிய பொலிஸ்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இரண்டு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஒருகுடவத்த மேம்பாலம்",
            "label": "PRODUCT"
          },
          {
            "text": "நேற்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பிரகாஸ்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "திலின குமார",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "34",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "கலன்சூரிய லேன்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "வெல்லம்பிட்டிய",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "மெதொட்டமுல்ல",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "டான் பிரியசாத்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Orugudawatta",
            "label": "PRODUCT"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "வெல்லம்பிட்டிய பொலிஸ்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஒவ்வொரு மாதமும் கடைசி ஞாயிறு",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "நிலந்த இந்திக்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "குற்றப்பிரிவு நிலைய அலுவலர் துணை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "விராஜ்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}