{
  "newspaper_id": "daily-ft-lk",
  "url": "https://www.ft.lk/news/FR-against-Acting-President-Ranil-Wickremesinghe-dismissed-by-SC/56-737696",
  "time_ut": 1658260863,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "FR against Acting President Ranil Wickremesinghe dismissed by SC",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "FR against Acting President Ranil Wickremesinghe dismissed by SC",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "SC held the FR was filed out of time. The courts said Kodituwakku had also suppressed material",
        "The Supreme Court yesterday dismissed the fundamental rights petition challenging the appointment of Acting President Ranil Wickremesinghe as a National List Member of Parliament of the United National Party (UNP).",
        "The petition was filed by the Vinivida foundation led by its General Secretary public interest litigation activist and Attorney-at-Law Nagananda Kodituwakku.",
        "The Supreme Court refused to grant the petition leave to proceed thereby dismissing it. The petition was taken up before a panel of Supreme Court Justices comprising Gamini Amarasekara, Shiran Gunarathne and Janak de Silva.",
        "In it, the petitioner alleged that the Fundamental Rights of the people of Sri Lanka are being violated through the appointment of Ranil Wickremesinghe as a National List Member of Parliament as the appointment was against the Constitution. This petition sought to issue an Interim Order preventing Ranil Wickremesinghe from acting as a Member of Parliament. Deputy Solicitor General Kanishka de Silva appearing on behalf of the Attorney General pointed out that the petition is out of time and that the action of the petitioner is therefore unacceptable.",
        "The court dismissing the FR said it accepted the arguments of the Deputy Solicitor General and also based the dismissal on the fact the petitioner had suppressed material by not revealing he had filed a similar petition last year on similar grounds and it had been dismissed by the courts.",
        "Kodituwakku had filed a similar petition on 13 July last year seeking a declaration that UNP leader Ranil Wickremasinghe is disqualified and will therefore not be entitled to be a Member of Parliament of the UNP. However, the case was later dismissed as the petitioner had failed to appear in court to make submissions on several occasions. (MB)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Ranil Wickremesinghe",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "SC",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "FR",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kodituwakku",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "The Supreme Court",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "yesterday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "National List",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the United National Party",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "UNP",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the Vinivida foundation",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "The Supreme Court",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Supreme Court Justices",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Gamini Amarasekara",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Shiran Gunarathne",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Janak de Silva",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the Fundamental Rights",
            "label": "LAW"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "National List",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Constitution",
            "label": "LAW"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kanishka de Silva",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "FR",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "last year",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Kodituwakku",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "13 July last year",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "UNP",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickremasinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "UNP",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "වැඩබලන ජනාධිපති රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහට එරෙහි එෆ්ආර් ශ්‍රේෂ්ඨාධිකරණය විසින් නිෂ්ප්‍රභ කරයි",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "SC විසින් FR ගොනු කර ඇත්තේ කාලය ඉක්මවා ඇති බවය. කොඩිතුවක්කු විසින් ද්‍රව්‍ය යටපත් කර ඇති බව අධිකරණය ප්‍රකාශ කළේය",
        "එක්සත් ජාතික පක්ෂයේ (එජාප) ජාතික ලැයිස්තු මන්ත්‍රීවරයෙකු ලෙස වැඩබලන ජනාධිපති රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතා පත් කිරීම අභියෝගයට ලක් කරමින් ගොනු කර තිබූ මූලික අයිතිවාසිකම් පෙත්සම ශ්‍රේෂ්ඨාධිකරණය ඊයේ ප්‍රතික්ෂේප කළේය.",
        "මෙම පෙත්සම ගොනු කර ඇත්තේ එහි ප්‍රධාන ලේකම් මහජන අවශ්‍යතා නඩු ක්‍රියාකාරිකයෙකු සහ නීතීඥ නාගානන්ද කොඩිතුවක්කුගේ නායකත්වයෙන් යුත් Vinivida පදනම විසිනි.",
        "එම පෙත්සම නිෂ්ප්‍රභ කරමින් ඉදිරියට යාමට අවසර දීම ශ්‍රේෂ්ඨාධිකරණය ප්‍රතික්ෂේප කළේය. ගාමිණී අමරසේකර, ශිරාන් ගුණරත්න සහ ජනක් ද සිල්වා යන ශ්‍රේෂ්ඨාධිකරණ විනිසුරු මඩුල්ල හමුවේ මෙම පෙත්සම කැඳවන ලදී.",
        "එහි දී පෙත්සම්කරු කියා සිටියේ රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතා ජාතික ලැයිස්තු මන්ත්‍රීවරයෙකු ලෙස පත් කිරීම ආණ්ඩුක්‍රම ව්‍යවස්ථාවට පටහැනි බැවින් ඒ හරහා ශ්‍රී ලංකාවාසීන්ගේ මූලික අයිතිවාසිකම් කඩවන බවයි. මෙම පෙත්සමෙන් ඉල්ලා ඇත්තේ රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතාට පාර්ලිමේන්තු මන්ත්‍රීවරයෙකු ලෙස කටයුතු කිරීම වළක්වාලමින් අතුරු නියෝගයක් නිකුත් කරන ලෙසයි. නීතිපතිවරයා වෙනුවෙන් පෙනී සිටි නියෝජ්‍ය සොලිසිටර් ජනරාල් කණිෂ්ක ද සිල්වා මහතා පෙන්වා දුන්නේ පෙත්සම කල් ඉකුත් වී ඇති බවත් එබැවින් පෙත්සම්කරුගේ ක්‍රියාව පිළිගත නොහැකි බවත්ය.",
        "නියෝජ්‍ය සොලිසිටර් ජනරාල්වරයාගේ තර්ක තමන් පිළිගන්නා බවත්, පසුගිය වසරේ මෙවැනිම කරුණු මත එවැනිම පෙත්සමක් ගොනු කළ බව හෙළි නොකිරීමෙන් කරුණු යටපත් කර ඇති බවත්, එය අධිකරණය විසින් නිෂ්ප්‍රභ කළ බවත් එම කරුණු මත පදනම්ව නිෂ්ප්‍රභ කළ බව අධිකරණය ප්‍රකාශ කළේය. .",
        "එක්සත් ජාතික පක්ෂ නායක රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතා නුසුදුස්සෙකු බවත් එබැවින් ඔහුට එක්සත් ජාතික පක්ෂයේ පාර්ලිමේන්තු මන්ත්‍රීවරයෙකු වීමට අයිතියක් නොමැති බවත් ප්‍රකාශ කරන ලෙස ඉල්ලා කොඩිතුවක්කු මහතා පසුගිය වසරේ ජූලි 13 වැනි දින මෙවැනිම පෙත්සමක් ගොනු කර තිබුණි. කෙසේ වෙතත්, අවස්ථා කිහිපයකදී කරුණු දැක්වීම සඳහා පෙත්සම්කරු අධිකරණයේ පෙනී නොසිටීම හේතුවෙන් නඩුව පසුව නිෂ්ප්‍රභ විය. (MB)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "SC",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "එෆ්ආර්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kodituwakku",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රේෂ්ඨාධිකරණය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඊයේ",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජාතික ලැයිස්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "එක්සත් ජාතික පක්ෂය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "එජාප",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Vinivida පදනම",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රේෂ්ඨාධිකරණය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රේෂ්ඨාධිකරණ විනිසුරුවරුන්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගාමිණී අමරසේකර",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශිරාන් ගුණරත්න",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජනක් ද සිල්වා",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "මූලික අයිතිවාසිකම්",
            "label": "LAW"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජාතික ලැයිස්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ව්යවස්ථාව",
            "label": "LAW"
          },
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "කනිෂ්ක ද සිල්වා",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "එෆ්ආර්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගිය අවුරුද්දේ",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Kodituwakku",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "පසුගිය වසරේ ජූලි 13",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "එජාප",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "එජාප",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "பதில் ஜனாதிபதி ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்கவுக்கு எதிரான குற்றப்பத்திரிகையை உச்ச நீதிமன்றம் தள்ளுபடி செய்துள்ளது",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "எஸ்சி எஃப்ஆர் நேரம் இல்லாமல் தாக்கல் செய்யப்பட்டது. கொடிதுவாக்கு பொருள்களையும் அடக்கியதாக நீதிமன்றங்கள் தெரிவித்தன",
        "ஐக்கிய தேசியக் கட்சியின் தேசியப் பட்டியல் நாடாளுமன்ற உறுப்பினராக பதில் ஜனாதிபதி ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்கவை நியமித்தமைக்கு எதிராக தாக்கல் செய்யப்பட்ட அடிப்படை உரிமை மீறல் மனுவை உயர் நீதிமன்றம் நேற்று நிராகரித்துள்ளது.",
        "வினிவிதா அறக்கட்டளையின் பொதுச் செயலாளரும், சட்டத்தரணியுமான நாகாநந்த கொடிதுவாக்கு தலைமையில் இந்த மனு தாக்கல் செய்யப்பட்டுள்ளது.",
        "இந்த மனுவை தொடர அனுமதி அளிக்க மறுத்த உச்சநீதிமன்றம், அதை தள்ளுபடி செய்து உத்தரவிட்டது. காமினி அமரசேகர, ஷிரான் குணரத்ன மற்றும் ஜனக் டி சில்வா ஆகியோர் அடங்கிய உச்ச நீதிமன்ற நீதிபதிகள் குழாம் முன்னிலையில் இந்த மனு விசாரணைக்கு எடுத்துக்கொள்ளப்பட்டது.",
        "அதில், ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்கவை தேசியப் பட்டியல் நாடாளுமன்ற உறுப்பினராக நியமித்துள்ளமை அரசியலமைப்புக்கு முரணானது என்பதனால் இலங்கை மக்களின் அடிப்படை உரிமைகள் மீறப்படுவதாக மனுதாரர் குற்றம் சுமத்தியுள்ளார். ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க நாடாளுமன்ற உறுப்பினராக செயற்படுவதைத் தடுக்கும் இடைக்கால உத்தரவை பிறப்பிக்குமாறு இந்த மனுவில் கோரப்பட்டுள்ளது. சட்டமா அதிபர் சார்பில் ஆஜரான பிரதி சொலிசிட்டர் ஜெனரல் கனிஷ்க டி சில்வா, மனு காலத்தை கடந்துள்ளதாகவும், எனவே மனுதாரரின் நடவடிக்கை ஏற்றுக்கொள்ள முடியாதது எனவும் சுட்டிக்காட்டினார்.",
        "FR ஐ நிராகரித்த நீதிமன்றம், துணை சொலிசிட்டர் ஜெனரலின் வாதங்களை ஏற்றுக்கொண்டதாகவும், மேலும் மனுதாரர் கடந்த ஆண்டு இதேபோன்ற ஒரு மனுவை தாக்கல் செய்ததை வெளிப்படுத்தாமல் உள்ளடக்கத்தை அடக்கியதன் அடிப்படையில் தள்ளுபடி செய்யப்பட்டதாகவும் கூறியது, அது நீதிமன்றங்களால் தள்ளுபடி செய்யப்பட்டது. .",
        "ஐ.தே.க தலைவர் ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க தகுதி நீக்கம் செய்யப்பட்டதாகவும், எனவே ஐ.தே.கவின் நாடாளுமன்ற உறுப்பினராக இருக்க அவருக்கு உரிமை இல்லை எனவும் அறிவிக்கக் கோரி கடந்த ஆண்டு ஜூலை 13 ஆம் திகதி கொடிதுவாக்கு இதேபோன்று மனுவொன்றை தாக்கல் செய்திருந்தார். இருப்பினும், மனுதாரர் பலமுறை சமர்பிக்க நீதிமன்றத்தில் ஆஜராகாததால் வழக்கு பின்னர் தள்ளுபடி செய்யப்பட்டது. (எம்பி)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "எஸ்சி",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "FR",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kodituwakku",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "உச்ச நீதிமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "நேற்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "தேசிய பட்டியல்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஐக்கிய தேசிய கட்சி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஐ.தே.க",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "வினிவிட அடித்தளம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "உச்ச நீதிமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "உச்ச நீதிமன்ற நீதிபதிகள்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "காமினி அமரசேகர",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஷிரான் குணரத்ன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜனக் டி சில்வா",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "அடிப்படை உரிமைகள்",
            "label": "LAW"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "தேசிய பட்டியல்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "அரசியலமைப்பு",
            "label": "LAW"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "கனிஷ்க டி சில்வா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "FR",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "கடந்த ஆண்டு",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Kodituwakku",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "கடந்த ஆண்டு ஜூலை 13",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஐ.தே.க",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஐ.தே.க",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}