{
  "newspaper_id": "lankadeepa-lk",
  "url": "https://www.lankadeepa.lk/news/කඩදාසි-වියදම-අඩු-කිරිමට-රාජ්‍ය-පරිපාලන-අමාත්‍යාංශයෙන්-පියවරක්/101-618869",
  "time_ut": 1661676292,
  "original_lang": "si",
  "original_title": "කඩදාසි වියදම අඩු කිරිමට රාජ්‍ය පරිපාලන අමාත්‍යාංශයෙන් පියවරක්",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "A step by the Ministry of Public Administration to reduce the cost of paper",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "The Ministry of Public Administration, Home Affairs, Provincial Councils and Local Government has decided to convert the 4-page form larger than the A4 size used by government officials to apply for foreign leave into a 2-page A4 size form to save a large amount of paper annually. have done",
        "This will be implemented on the advice of the Prime Minister Dinesh Gunawardena as the Minister of Public Administration, Home Affairs, Provincial Councils and Local Government based on the frugality policy implemented in the public service, Ministry Secretary M.M.P.K. Mr. Mayadunne said.",
        "He mentioned that the cost of paper for that form can be saved by about 50 percent, and since the number of government employees who apply to go abroad annually is over one lakh, the government will save a considerable amount of paper and money with the new decision.",
        "All the points mentioned in the previous form are included in the new form, and it has already been forwarded to the Government Printing Department for printing."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "the Ministry of Public Administration",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "The Ministry of Public Administration",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Home Affairs",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Provincial Councils and Local Government",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "4",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "A4",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "2",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "A4",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "annually",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Dinesh Gunawardena",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Home Affairs",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Provincial Councils and Local Government",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ministry",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "M.M.P.K.",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Mayadunne",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "about 50 percent",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "annually",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the Government Printing Department",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "කඩදාසි වියදම අඩු කිරිමට රාජ්‍ය පරිපාලන අමාත්‍යාංශයෙන් පියවරක්",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "රජයේ නිලධාරීන් විදේශ නිවාඩු ඉල්ලුම් කිරීම සඳහා භාවිත කරන ඒ 4 ප්‍රමාණයට වඩා විශාල පිටු 4කින් යුත් ආකෘති පත්‍රය, ඒ 4 ප්‍රමාණයේ පිටු 2කින් යුත් ආකෘති පත්‍රයක් බවට පත් කර, වාර්ෂිකව කඩදාසි විශාල ප්‍රමාණයක් ඉතිරි කරගැනීමට  රාජ්‍ය පරිපාලන ස්වදේශ කටයුතු, පළාත් සභා හා පළාත් පාලන අමාත්‍යංශය තීරණය කර තිබේ.",
        "රාජ්‍ය සේවය තුළ ක්‍රියාත්මක අරපිරිමැස්ම ප්‍රතිපත්තිය මත, රාජ්‍ය පරිපාලන, ස්වදේශ කටයුතු, පළාත් සභා හා පළාත් පාලන අමාත්‍යවරයා ලෙස අග්‍රාමාත්‍ය දිනේෂ් ගුණවර්ධන මහතාගේ උපදෙස් මත මෙය ක්‍රියාත්මක කරන බව, අමාත්‍යංශ ලේකම් එම්.එම්.පී.කේ. මායාදුන්නේ මහතා පැවසීය.",
        "මේ අනුව එම ආකෘති පත්‍රය සඳහා වන කඩදාසි භා වියදම සියයට 50කින් පමණ ඉතිරි කරගැනීමට හැකි  බවත්, වාර්ෂිකව විදේශ ගතවීම සඳහා ඉල්ලුම් කරන රජයේ සේවකයන් සංඛ්‍යාව ලක්ෂයකට අධික වන බැවින් නව තීරණයත් සමග රජයට සැලකිය යුතු තරම් කඩදාසි හා මුදල් ප්‍රමාණයක් ඉතිරි වන බවත් ඔහු සඳහන් කළේය.",
        "පෙර ආකෘතියෙහි සඳහන්ව තිබූ සියලු කරුණු නව ආකෘති පත්‍රයට ඇතුළත් අතර, එය මුද්‍රණය සඳහා රජයේ මුද්‍රණ දෙපාර්තමේන්තුව වෙත මේ වනවිටත් යොමුකර තිබේ."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "රාජ්ය පරිපාලන අමාත්යාංශය",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "රාජ්ය පරිපාලන අමාත්යාංශය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ස්වදේශ කටයුතු",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "පළාත් සභා සහ පළාත් පාලන",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "4",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "A4",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "2",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "A4",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "වාර්ෂිකව",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "දිනේෂ් ගුණවර්ධන",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ස්වදේශ කටයුතු",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "පළාත් සභා සහ පළාත් පාලන",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "අමාත්යාංශ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "එම්.එම්.පී.කේ.",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "මායාදුන්නේ ය",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "සියයට 50 ක් පමණ",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "වාර්ෂිකව",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "රජයේ මුද්‍රණ දෙපාර්තමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "காகிதச் செலவைக் குறைக்க பொது நிர்வாக அமைச்சகத்தின் ஒரு நடவடிக்கை",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "அரசாங்க அதிகாரிகள் வெளிநாட்டு விடுப்புக்கு விண்ணப்பிக்க பயன்படுத்திய A4 அளவை விட 4 பக்க படிவத்தை 2 பக்க A4 அளவு படிவமாக மாற்ற பொது நிர்வாகம், உள்நாட்டு அலுவல்கள், மாகாண சபைகள் மற்றும் உள்ளூராட்சி அமைச்சு தீர்மானித்துள்ளது. ஆண்டுதோறும் காகிதம்",
        "அரச சேவையில் அமுல்படுத்தப்படும் சிக்கனக் கொள்கையின் அடிப்படையில் பொது நிர்வாகம், உள்நாட்டலுவல்கள், மாகாண சபைகள் மற்றும் உள்ளூராட்சி அமைச்சர் என்ற வகையில் பிரதமர் தினேஷ் குணவர்தனவின் ஆலோசனையின் பேரில் இது நடைமுறைப்படுத்தப்படும் என அமைச்சின் செயலாளர் எம்.எம்.பி.கே. திரு.மாயாதுன்னே தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "அந்த படிவத்திற்கான காகித செலவில் சுமார் 50 சதவீதம் சேமிக்க முடியும் என்றும், ஆண்டுதோறும் வெளிநாடு செல்ல விண்ணப்பிக்கும் அரசு ஊழியர்களின் எண்ணிக்கை ஒரு லட்சத்திற்கும் அதிகமாக இருப்பதால், புதிய காகிதம் மற்றும் பணத்தை அரசாங்கம் கணிசமான அளவு சேமிக்கும் என்றும் அவர் குறிப்பிட்டார். முடிவு.",
        "முந்தைய படிவத்தில் குறிப்பிடப்பட்ட அனைத்து புள்ளிகளும் புதிய படிவத்தில் சேர்க்கப்பட்டுள்ளன, மேலும் இது ஏற்கனவே அச்சிடுவதற்காக அரசாங்க அச்சகத் துறைக்கு அனுப்பப்பட்டுள்ளது."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "பொது நிர்வாக அமைச்சகம்",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "பொது நிர்வாக அமைச்சகம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "உள்நாட்டு விவகாரங்கள்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "மாகாண சபைகள் மற்றும் உள்ளூராட்சி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "4",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "A4",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "2",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "A4",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆண்டுதோறும்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "தினேஷ் குணவர்தன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "உள்நாட்டு விவகாரங்கள்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "மாகாண சபைகள் மற்றும் உள்ளூராட்சி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "அமைச்சகம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ம.ம.பொ.க.",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "மாயாதுன்னே",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "சுமார் 50 சதவீதம்",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆண்டுதோறும்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "அரசு அச்சுத் துறை",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}