{
  "newspaper_id": "daily-ft-lk",
  "url": "https://www.ft.lk/business/130-international-teams-win-at-Huawei-ICT-Competition-2021-2022-Global-Final/34-737260",
  "time_ut": 1657308257,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "130 international teams win at Huawei ICT Competition 2021-2022 Global Final",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "130 international teams win at Huawei ICT Competition 2021-2022 Global Final",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "Huawei ICT Competition 2021-2022 Global Final Closing and Awards Ceremony",
        "The Huawei ICT Competition 2021-2022 Global Final in Shenzhen drew to a close on 25 June. This year marks the sixth Huawei ICT Competition, which included three competitions – practice, innovation and industry – attracted 150,000 students from more than 2000 universities in 85 countries and regions around the world. After making it through the national and regional competitions, 130 teams from 43 countries and regions faced off in the global final, making this year's finals the largest yet.",
        "This year’s participants were also the first to compete for a new series of Women in Tech Awards which have been designed to honour the outstanding talent displayed by the young women contestants in the Competition. A TECH4ALL Digital Inclusion Award was also presented during the awards ceremony, as part of Huawei’s TECH4ALL Digital Inclusion initiative.",
        "The competition was hotly contested, with the following seven teams winning the Grand Prize for the network track of the practice competition: the Wuhan Technical College of Communications Team, Chongqing College of Electronic Engineering Team, Nigeria Team 2, Yangtze Normal University Team, Jiangxi University of Software Professional Technology Team, Egypt Team, and Nigeria Team 1.",
        "The four teams who took home the Grand Prize for the cloud track of the practice competition were the Algeria Team, Malaysia Team 1, Brazil Team, and Guangzhou College of Commerce Team, while the three teams awarded the Grand Prize for the Innovation Competition were the Beijing Jiaotong University Team, Xiamen University Team, and Salahaddin University Team. Finally, the winner of the grand prize for the industry competition was the Futuristic Inspection Team from the Southeast University.",
        "Huawei Enterprise’s President of Global Partner Development and Sales Xiao Haijun spoke at the event about how indispensable ICT has become to our work and lives. As one of Huawei’s key initiatives in talent cultivation, the Huawei ICT Competition is designed to help build an ecosystem that students around the world can use to bridge digital divides and accelerate global digital transformation by improving their ICT knowledge, skills, and innovation capabilities.",
        "China Education Association for International Exchange President Liu Limin also spoke at the event on the important role the Huawei ICT Competition is playing in promoting international exchanges and cooperation. He said: “As an annual event for global university students, the Competition provides a platform for communication, promotes ICT technologies in universities, and serves as an example for cooperation between universities and the industry.”",
        "Finally, UNESCO’s Section Chief for Youth Hervé Huot-Marchand, Literacy and Skills Development, congratulated Huawei for their role as a key partner and contributor to the UNESCO’s Global Education Coalition helping young people around the world to improve their digital skills. The Huawei ICT Competition is one of the few international programs that can help young people connect and promote innovation on such a large scale so that they can, in turn, give back and create greater value in the digital society. This Huawei ICT Competition attracted more participants this year than ever before, despite the lingering pandemic. In the future, Huawei plans to continue building education, industry, and public talent ecosystems by establishing talent alliances, integrating talent standards, improving talent capabilities, and demonstrating talent value. Huawei has also announced plans to nurture one million certified ICT professionals by 2024 to improve the digital skills of society as a whole. This is intended to promote scientific and technological progress, industry development, and sustainable social and economic development."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "130",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "Huawei ICT Competition",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "2021-2022",
          "label": "DATE"
        },
        {
          "text": "Global Final",
          "label": "WORK_OF_ART"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "2021-2022",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Global Final Closing and Awards Ceremony",
            "label": "WORK_OF_ART"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Huawei",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "2021-2022",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Global Final",
            "label": "WORK_OF_ART"
          },
          {
            "text": "Shenzhen",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "25 June",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "sixth",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Huawei ICT Competition",
            "label": "LAW"
          },
          {
            "text": "three",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "150,000",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "more than 2000",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "85",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "130",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "43",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "year",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "year",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "first",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Digital Inclusion Award",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Huawei",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Digital Inclusion",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "seven",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Grand Prize",
            "label": "WORK_OF_ART"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Wuhan Technical College of Communications Team",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "2",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Yangtze Normal University Team",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Jiangxi University of Software Professional Technology Team",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Egypt Team",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Nigeria Team 1",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "four",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Grand Prize",
            "label": "EVENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "Malaysia Team 1",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Brazil Team",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Guangzhou College of Commerce Team",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "three",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Grand Prize",
            "label": "WORK_OF_ART"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Beijing Jiaotong University Team, Xiamen University Team",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Salahaddin University Team",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Futuristic Inspection Team",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Southeast University",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Huawei Enterprise’s",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Global Partner Development and Sales Xiao Haijun",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ICT",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "one",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Huawei",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Huawei ICT Competition",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ICT",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "China Education Association for International Exchange",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Liu Limin",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ICT",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "UNESCO",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Literacy",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Skills Development",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Huawei",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "UNESCO",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Global Education Coalition",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "The Huawei ICT Competition",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "one",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "this year",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Huawei",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Huawei",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "one million",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ICT",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "2024",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "Huawei ICT තරඟය 2021-2022 Global Final හි ජාත්‍යන්තර කණ්ඩායම් 130ක් ජය ගනී",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "Huawei ICT තරඟය 2021-2022 ගෝලීය අවසන් සමාප්තිය සහ සම්මාන උළෙල",
        "Huawei ICT තරඟය 2021-2022 Shenzhen හි පැවති ගෝලීය අවසන් තරඟය ජුනි 25 වන දින අවසන් විය. මෙම වසරේ හයවන Huawei ICT තරඟය සනිටුහන් කරන අතර, තරඟ තුනක් ඇතුළත් - පුහුණුවීම්, නවෝත්පාදන සහ කර්මාන්ත - ලොව පුරා රටවල් 85 ක සහ කලාප 85 ක විශ්ව විද්‍යාල 2000 කට වැඩි ගණනක සිසුන් 150,000 ක් ආකර්ශනය කර ගත්හ. ජාතික සහ කලාපීය තරඟාවලි හරහා එය සමත් වූ පසු, රටවල් සහ කලාප 43 කින් කණ්ඩායම් 130 ක් ගෝලීය අවසන් මහා තරඟයට මුහුණ දුන් අතර, මෙවර අවසන් මහා තරඟය තවමත් විශාලතම තරඟාවලිය බවට පත් විය.",
        "තරඟාවලියේ තරඟකාරියන් විසින් දක්වන ලද විශිෂ්ට දක්ෂතා අගය කිරීම සඳහා නිර්මාණය කර ඇති තාක්ෂණික කාන්තා සම්මාන මාලාවක් සඳහා මෙවර සහභාගීවන්නන් ප්‍රථම වරට තරඟ වැදුණි. Huawei හි TECH4ALL ඩිජිටල් ඇතුළත් කිරීමේ මුලපිරීමේ කොටසක් ලෙස සම්මාන උළෙලේදී TECH4ALL ඩිජිටල් ඇතුළත් කිරීමේ සම්මානයක් ද පිරිනමන ලදී.",
        "මෙම තරඟය උණුසුම් තරඟකාරී විය, පහත දැක්වෙන කණ්ඩායම් හත පුහුණු තරඟයේ ජාල ධාවන පථය සඳහා මහා ත්‍යාගය දිනා ගත්හ: වුහාන් කාර්මික සන්නිවේදන කණ්ඩායම, චොංකිං විද්‍යුත් ඉංජිනේරු විද්‍යාලය, නයිජීරියා කණ්ඩායම 2, යැංසි සාමාන්‍ය විශ්ව විද්‍යාල කණ්ඩායම, ජියැන්ග්සි විශ්ව විද්‍යාලය මෘදුකාංග වෘත්තීය තාක්ෂණ කණ්ඩායම, ඊජිප්තු කණ්ඩායම සහ නයිජීරියා කණ්ඩායම 1.",
        "පුහුණු තරගයේ වලාකුළු ධාවන පථය සඳහා විශිෂ්ට ත්‍යාගය ලබා ගත් කණ්ඩායම් හතර වූයේ ඇල්ජීරියා කණ්ඩායම, මැලේසියා කණ්ඩායම 1, බ්‍රසීල කණ්ඩායම සහ Guangzhou College of Commerce කණ්ඩායම වන අතර නවෝත්පාදන තරඟය සඳහා මහා ත්‍යාගය ප්‍රදානය කරන ලද්දේ කණ්ඩායම් තුනයි. Beijing Jiaotong විශ්වවිද්‍යාල කණ්ඩායම, Xiamen විශ්වවිද්‍යාල කණ්ඩායම සහ Salahaddin විශ්වවිද්‍යාල කණ්ඩායම. අවසාන වශයෙන්, කර්මාන්ත තරඟය සඳහා මහා ත්‍යාගය ජයග්‍රාහකයා වූයේ අග්නිදිග විශ්ව විද්‍යාලයේ අනාගත පරීක්ෂණ කණ්ඩායමයි.",
        "Huawei Enterprise හි Global Partner Development සහ Sales හි සභාපති Xiao Haijun අපගේ වැඩකටයුතුවලට සහ ජීවිතයට තොරතුරු සන්නිවේදන තාක්ෂණය අත්‍යවශ්‍ය වී ඇති ආකාරය පිළිබඳව මෙම උත්සවයේදී කතා කළේය. Huawei හි දක්ෂතා වර්ධනය කිරීමේ ප්‍රධාන මුලපිරීම් වලින් එකක් ලෙස, Huawei ICT තරඟය සැලසුම් කර ඇත්තේ ලොව පුරා සිසුන්ට ඩිජිටල් බෙදීම් මඟහරවා ගැනීමට සහ ඔවුන්ගේ ICT දැනුම, කුසලතා සහ නවෝත්පාදන හැකියාවන් වැඩිදියුණු කිරීම මගින් ගෝලීය ඩිජිටල් පරිවර්තනය වේගවත් කිරීමට භාවිතා කළ හැකි පරිසර පද්ධතියක් ගොඩනැගීමට උපකාර කිරීම සඳහා ය.",
        "ජාත්‍යන්තර හුවමාරුව සහ සහයෝගීතාවය ප්‍රවර්ධනය කිරීමෙහිලා Huawei ICT තරඟය විසින් ඉටු කරනු ලබන වැදගත් කාර්යභාරය පිළිබඳව ජාත්‍යන්තර හුවමාරුව සඳහා වන චයිනා අධ්‍යාපන සංගමයේ සභාපති Liu Limin ද මෙම අවස්ථාවට සහභාගී විය. ඔහු මෙසේ පැවසීය: \"ගෝලීය විශ්ව විද්‍යාල සිසුන් සඳහා වාර්ෂික උත්සවයක් ලෙස, තරඟය සන්නිවේදනය සඳහා වේදිකාවක් සපයයි, විශ්ව විද්‍යාල තුළ ICT තාක්ෂණයන් ප්‍රවර්ධනය කරයි, සහ විශ්ව විද්‍යාල සහ කර්මාන්තය අතර සහයෝගීතාවය සඳහා උදාහරණයක් ලෙස සේවය කරයි.\"",
        "අවසාන වශයෙන්, UNESCO හි තරුණ Hervé Huot-Marchand, සාක්ෂරතාවය සහ නිපුණතා සංවර්ධන අංශයේ ප්‍රධානියා, ලොව පුරා සිටින තරුණ තරුණියන්ට ඔවුන්ගේ ඩිජිටල් කුසලතා වැඩි දියුණු කිරීමට උපකාර කරන යුනෙස්කෝ ගෝලීය අධ්‍යාපන හවුලේ ප්‍රධාන හවුල්කරුවෙකු සහ දායකයෙකු ලෙස Huawei ඔවුන්ගේ කාර්යභාරය වෙනුවෙන් සුබ පැතුවා. Huawei ICT තරඟය යනු තරුණයින්ට මෙතරම් විශාල පරිමාණයෙන් නව්‍යකරණයන් සම්බන්ධ කිරීමට සහ ප්‍රවර්ධනය කිරීමට උපකාර කළ හැකි ජාත්‍යන්තර වැඩසටහන් කිහිපයෙන් එකකි, එවිට ඔවුන්ට නැවත ලබා දීමට සහ ඩිජිටල් සමාජය තුළ වැඩි වටිනාකමක් ඇති කිරීමට හැකි වේ. මෙම Huawei තොරතුරු හා සන්නිවේදන තාක්‍ෂණ තරගයට මේ වසරේ පෙරට වඩා වැඩි සහභාගිවන්නන් පිරිසක් ආකර්ශනය කර ගෙන ඇත. අනාගතයේ දී, Huawei දක්ෂතා සන්ධාන ඇති කිරීම, කුසලතා ප්‍රමිතීන් ඒකාබද්ධ කිරීම, කුසලතා හැකියාවන් වැඩිදියුණු කිරීම සහ කුසලතා අගය ප්‍රදර්ශනය කිරීම මගින් අධ්‍යාපනය, කර්මාන්ත සහ පොදු කුසලතා පරිසර පද්ධති ගොඩනැගීම දිගටම කරගෙන යාමට සැලසුම් කරයි. සමස්තයක් ලෙස සමාජයේ ඩිජිටල් කුසලතා වැඩිදියුණු කිරීම සඳහා 2024 වන විට සහතිකලත් ICT වෘත්තිකයන් මිලියනයක් පෝෂණය කිරීමට Huawei සැලසුම් කර ඇත. මෙය විද්‍යාත්මක හා තාක්‍ෂණික ප්‍රගතිය, කර්මාන්ත සංවර්ධනය සහ තිරසාර සමාජ හා ආර්ථික සංවර්ධනය ප්‍රවර්ධනය කිරීමට අදහස් කෙරේ."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "130",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "Huawei ICT තරඟය",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "2021-2022",
          "label": "DATE"
        },
        {
          "text": "Global Final",
          "label": "WORK_OF_ART"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "2021-2022",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගෝලීය අවසන් සමාප්තිය සහ සම්මාන උළෙල",
            "label": "WORK_OF_ART"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Huawei",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "2021-2022",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Global Final",
            "label": "WORK_OF_ART"
          },
          {
            "text": "ෂෙන්සෙන්",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "25 ජූනි",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "හය වන",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Huawei ICT තරඟය",
            "label": "LAW"
          },
          {
            "text": "තුන්",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "150,000 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "2000 ට වැඩි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "85",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "130",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "43",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "වර්ෂය",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "වර්ෂය",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "පළමුවන",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඩිජිටල් ඇතුළත් කිරීමේ සම්මානය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Huawei",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඩිජිටල් ඇතුළත් කිරීම",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "හත",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "මහා ත්‍යාගය",
            "label": "WORK_OF_ART"
          },
          {
            "text": "වුහාන් තාක්ෂණ විද්‍යාලයේ සන්නිවේදන කණ්ඩායම",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "2",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "යැංසි සාමාන්‍ය විශ්වවිද්‍යාල කණ්ඩායම",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Jiangxi මෘදුකාංගයේ වෘත්තීය තාක්ෂණ කණ්ඩායම",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඊජිප්තු කණ්ඩායම",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "නයිජීරියා කණ්ඩායම 1",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "හතර",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "මහා ත්‍යාගය",
            "label": "EVENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "මැලේසියා කණ්ඩායම 1",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "බ්රසීල කණ්ඩායම",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Guangzhou වාණිජ විද්‍යාල කණ්ඩායම",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "තුන්",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "මහා ත්‍යාගය",
            "label": "WORK_OF_ART"
          },
          {
            "text": "Beijing Jiaotong විශ්වවිද්‍යාල කණ්ඩායම, Xiamen විශ්වවිද්‍යාල කණ්ඩායම",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "සලාහදීන් විශ්වවිද්‍යාල කණ්ඩායම",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "අනාගත පරීක්ෂණ කණ්ඩායම",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "අග්නිදිග විශ්ව විද්‍යාලය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Huawei එන්ටර්ප්‍රයිස්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගෝලීය හවුල්කාර සංවර්ධන සහ විකුණුම් Xiao Haijun",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "සන්නිවේදන තාක්ෂණ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "එක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Huawei",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Huawei ICT තරඟය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "සන්නිවේදන තාක්ෂණ",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ජාත්‍යන්තර හුවමාරුව සඳහා චීන අධ්‍යාපන සංගමය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Liu Limin",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "සන්නිවේදන තාක්ෂණ",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "යුනෙස්කෝව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "සාක්ෂරතාව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "නිපුණතා සංවර්ධන",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Huawei",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "යුනෙස්කෝව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගෝලීය අධ්‍යාපන සන්ධානය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Huawei ICT තරඟය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "එක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "මේ වසරේ",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Huawei",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Huawei",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "මිලියනයක්",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "සන්නිවේදන තාක්ෂණ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "2024",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "Huawei ICT போட்டியில் 2021-2022 உலகளாவிய இறுதிப் போட்டியில் 130 சர்வதேச அணிகள் வெற்றி",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "Huawei ICT போட்டி 2021-2022 உலகளாவிய இறுதி நிறைவு மற்றும் விருது வழங்கும் விழா",
        "Huawei ICT போட்டி 2021-2022 க்ளோபல் ஃபைனல் ஷென்செனில் ஜூன் 25 அன்று நிறைவடைந்தது. இந்த ஆண்டு ஆறாவது Huawei ICT போட்டியைக் குறிக்கிறது, இதில் பயிற்சி, கண்டுபிடிப்பு மற்றும் தொழில்துறை ஆகிய மூன்று போட்டிகள் அடங்கும் - உலகெங்கிலும் உள்ள 85 நாடுகள் மற்றும் பிராந்தியங்களில் உள்ள 2000 க்கும் மேற்பட்ட பல்கலைக்கழகங்களில் இருந்து 150,000 மாணவர்களை ஈர்த்தது. தேசிய மற்றும் பிராந்திய போட்டிகளின் மூலம் வெற்றிபெற்ற பின்னர், 43 நாடுகள் மற்றும் பிராந்தியங்களைச் சேர்ந்த 130 அணிகள் உலகளாவிய இறுதிப் போட்டியில் மோதின, இந்த ஆண்டு இறுதிப் போட்டிகள் இன்னும் பெரியதாக இருந்தது.",
        "இந்த ஆண்டு பங்கேற்பாளர்கள் புதிய தொடரான ​​பெண்கள் தொழில்நுட்ப விருதுகளுக்காக முதலில் போட்டியிட்டனர், அவை போட்டியில் இளம் பெண் போட்டியாளர்களால் வெளிப்படுத்தப்பட்ட சிறந்த திறமைகளை கௌரவிக்கும் வகையில் வடிவமைக்கப்பட்டுள்ளன. Huawei இன் TECH4ALL டிஜிட்டல் சேர்த்தல் முயற்சியின் ஒரு பகுதியாக, விருது வழங்கும் விழாவின் போது TECH4ALL டிஜிட்டல் உள்ளடக்கிய விருதும் வழங்கப்பட்டது.",
        "போட்டியானது பரபரப்பாகப் போட்டியிட்டது, பயிற்சி போட்டியின் நெட்வொர்க் டிராக்கிற்கான கிராண்ட் பரிசை பின்வரும் ஏழு அணிகள் வென்றன: வுஹான் டெக்னிக்கல் காலேஜ் ஆஃப் கம்யூனிகேஷன்ஸ் டீம், சோங்கிங் காலேஜ் ஆஃப் எலக்ட்ரானிக் இன்ஜினியரிங் டீம், நைஜீரியா டீம் 2, யாங்சி சாதாரண பல்கலைக்கழக அணி, ஜியாங்சி பல்கலைக்கழகம் மென்பொருள் நிபுணத்துவ தொழில்நுட்பக் குழு, எகிப்து அணி மற்றும் நைஜீரியா அணி 1.",
        "பயிற்சிப் போட்டியின் கிளவுட் டிராக்கிற்கான கிராண்ட் பரிசைப் பெற்ற நான்கு அணிகள் அல்ஜீரியா அணி, மலேசியா அணி 1, பிரேசில் அணி மற்றும் குவாங்சூ காமர்ஸ் கல்லூரி அணி ஆகும், அதே நேரத்தில் மூன்று அணிகள் புத்தாக்கப் போட்டிக்கான கிராண்ட் பரிசைப் பெற்றன. பெய்ஜிங் ஜியாடோங் பல்கலைக்கழக அணி, ஜியாமென் பல்கலைக்கழக அணி மற்றும் சலாஹடின் பல்கலைக்கழக அணி. இறுதியாக, தொழில் போட்டிக்கான மாபெரும் பரிசை வென்றது தென்கிழக்கு பல்கலைக்கழகத்தின் எதிர்கால ஆய்வுக் குழு.",
        "Huawei Enterprise இன் குளோபல் பார்ட்னர் டெவலப்மென்ட் மற்றும் விற்பனையின் தலைவர் Xiao Haijun, இந்த நிகழ்வில் ICT ஆனது நமது பணி மற்றும் வாழ்க்கைக்கு எவ்வளவு இன்றியமையாததாக மாறியுள்ளது என்பதைப் பற்றி பேசினார். திறமை வளர்ப்பில் Huawei இன் முக்கிய முன்முயற்சிகளில் ஒன்றாக, Huawei ICT போட்டியானது, உலகெங்கிலும் உள்ள மாணவர்கள் டிஜிட்டல் பிளவுகளைக் குறைக்கவும், அவர்களின் ICT அறிவு, திறன்கள் மற்றும் கண்டுபிடிப்பு திறன்களை மேம்படுத்துவதன் மூலம் உலகளாவிய டிஜிட்டல் மாற்றத்தை விரைவுபடுத்தவும் பயன்படுத்தக்கூடிய சுற்றுச்சூழல் அமைப்பை உருவாக்க உதவும் வகையில் வடிவமைக்கப்பட்டுள்ளது.",
        "சர்வதேச பரிமாற்றங்கள் மற்றும் ஒத்துழைப்பை மேம்படுத்துவதில் Huawei ICT போட்டி முக்கிய பங்கு வகிக்கிறது என்பது குறித்து சர்வதேச பரிமாற்றத்திற்கான சீன கல்வி சங்கத்தின் தலைவர் லியு லிமினும் நிகழ்வில் பேசினார். அவர் கூறினார்: \"உலகளாவிய பல்கலைக்கழக மாணவர்களுக்கான வருடாந்திர நிகழ்வாக, போட்டி தகவல்தொடர்புக்கான ஒரு தளத்தை வழங்குகிறது, பல்கலைக்கழகங்களில் ICT தொழில்நுட்பங்களை ஊக்குவிக்கிறது மற்றும் பல்கலைக்கழகங்களுக்கும் தொழில்துறைக்கும் இடையிலான ஒத்துழைப்பிற்கு ஒரு எடுத்துக்காட்டு.\"",
        "இறுதியாக, யுனெஸ்கோவின் இளைஞர் Hervé Huot-Marchand, கல்வியறிவு மற்றும் திறன் மேம்பாட்டிற்கான பிரிவுத் தலைவர், உலகெங்கிலும் உள்ள இளைஞர்கள் தங்கள் டிஜிட்டல் திறன்களை மேம்படுத்த உதவும் யுனெஸ்கோவின் உலகளாவிய கல்விக் கூட்டணியில் முக்கிய பங்குதாரராகவும் பங்களிப்பாளராகவும் Huawei அவர்களின் பங்கிற்கு வாழ்த்து தெரிவித்தார். Huawei ICT போட்டியானது, இளைஞர்களை இணைத்து, புதுமைகளை பெரிய அளவில் ஊக்குவிக்க உதவும் சில சர்வதேச திட்டங்களில் ஒன்றாகும். இந்த Huawei ICT போட்டியானது, பரவி வரும் தொற்றுநோய்களுக்கு மத்தியிலும், முன்பை விட இந்த ஆண்டு அதிக பங்கேற்பாளர்களை ஈர்த்தது. எதிர்காலத்தில், திறமைக் கூட்டணிகளை நிறுவுதல், திறமைத் தரங்களை ஒருங்கிணைத்தல், திறமை திறன்களை மேம்படுத்துதல் மற்றும் திறமை மதிப்பை வெளிப்படுத்துதல் ஆகியவற்றின் மூலம் கல்வி, தொழில் மற்றும் பொதுத் திறன் சுற்றுச்சூழல் அமைப்புகளைத் தொடர்ந்து உருவாக்க Huawei திட்டமிட்டுள்ளது. ஒட்டுமொத்த சமூகத்தின் டிஜிட்டல் திறன்களை மேம்படுத்த 2024 ஆம் ஆண்டளவில் ஒரு மில்லியன் சான்றளிக்கப்பட்ட ICT நிபுணர்களை வளர்ப்பதற்கான திட்டங்களையும் Huawei அறிவித்துள்ளது. இது அறிவியல் மற்றும் தொழில்நுட்ப முன்னேற்றம், தொழில் மேம்பாடு மற்றும் நிலையான சமூக மற்றும் பொருளாதார மேம்பாட்டை மேம்படுத்தும் நோக்கம் கொண்டது."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "130",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "Huawei ICT போட்டி",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "2021-2022",
          "label": "DATE"
        },
        {
          "text": "குளோபல் பைனல்",
          "label": "WORK_OF_ART"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "2021-2022",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "உலகளாவிய இறுதி நிறைவு மற்றும் விருது வழங்கும் விழா",
            "label": "WORK_OF_ART"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஹூவாய்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "2021-2022",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "குளோபல் பைனல்",
            "label": "WORK_OF_ART"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஷென்சென்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "25 ஜூன்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆறாவது",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Huawei ICT போட்டி",
            "label": "LAW"
          },
          {
            "text": "மூன்று",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "150,000",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "2000க்கு மேல்",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "85",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "130",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "43",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆண்டு",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஆண்டு",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "முதலில்",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "டிஜிட்டல் உள்ளடக்கிய விருது",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஹூவாய்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "டிஜிட்டல் உள்ளடக்கம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஏழு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "பெரும் பரிசு",
            "label": "WORK_OF_ART"
          },
          {
            "text": "வுஹான் டெக்னிக்கல் காலேஜ் ஆஃப் கம்யூனிகேஷன்ஸ் டீம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "2",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "யாங்சே சாதாரண பல்கலைக்கழக குழு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜியாங்சி பல்கலைக்கழக மென்பொருள் நிபுணத்துவ தொழில்நுட்பக் குழு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "எகிப்து அணி",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "நைஜீரியா அணி 1",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "நான்கு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "பெரும் பரிசு",
            "label": "EVENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "மலேசியா அணி 1",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "பிரேசில் அணி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "குவாங்சோ கல்லூரி வணிகக் குழு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "மூன்று",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "பெரும் பரிசு",
            "label": "WORK_OF_ART"
          },
          {
            "text": "பெய்ஜிங் ஜியாடோங் பல்கலைக்கழக அணி, ஜியாமென் பல்கலைக்கழக அணி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "சலாஹத்தீன் பல்கலைக்கழக அணி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "எதிர்கால ஆய்வுக் குழு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "தென்கிழக்கு பல்கலைக்கழகம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Huawei எண்டர்பிரைஸ்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "உலகளாவிய பங்குதாரர் மேம்பாடு மற்றும் விற்பனை Xiao Haijun",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஐ.சி.டி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஒன்று",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஹூவாய்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Huawei ICT போட்டி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஐ.சி.டி",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "சர்வதேச பரிமாற்றத்திற்கான சீனா கல்வி சங்கம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Liu Limin",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஐ.சி.டி",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "யுனெஸ்கோ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "எழுத்தறிவு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "திறன் மேம்பாடு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஹூவாய்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "யுனெஸ்கோ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "உலகளாவிய கல்வி கூட்டணி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Huawei ICT போட்டி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஒன்று",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்த வருடம்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஹூவாய்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஹூவாய்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஒரு மில்லியன்",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஐ.சி.டி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "2024",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}