{
  "newspaper_id": "economy-next-com",
  "url": "https://economynext.com/ranil-wickremesinghe-sworn-in-as-sri-lanka-acting-president-97463/",
  "time_ut": 1657869660,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Ranil Wickremesinghe sworn in as Sri Lanka Acting President",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Ranil Wickremesinghe sworn in as Sri Lanka Acting President",
      "author": "",
      "body_lines": [
        "ECONOMYNEXT – Sri Lanka Prime Minister Ranil Wickremesinghe was sworn in as Acting President following the resignation of President Gotabaya Rajapaksa, the prime minister’s office said.",
        "Wickremesinghe was sworn in before Chief Justice Jayantha Jayasuirya Friday July 15, hours after Speaker Mahinda Yapa Abeywardena confirmed that he had accepted President Rajapaksa’s letter of resignation on July 14.",
        "Abeywardena told reporters Friday morning that Wickremesinghe will serve as Acting President until parliament elects a new president from among its membership. (Colombo/July15/2022)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Ranil Wickremesinghe",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "Sri Lanka",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Gotabaya Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Jayantha Jayasuirya",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Friday July 15, hours",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Mahinda Yapa Abeywardena",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "July 14",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Abeywardena",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Friday morning",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "ශ්‍රී ලංකා වැඩබලන ජනාධිපතිවරයා ලෙස රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතා දිවුරුම් දෙයි",
      "author": "",
      "body_lines": [
        "EconomyNext - ශ්‍රී ලංකා අගමැති රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතා ජනාධිපති ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ මහතා ඉල්ලා අස්වීමෙන් පසු වැඩ බලන ජනාධිපතිවරයා ලෙස දිවුරුම් දුන් බව අගමැති කාර්යාලය පවසයි.",
        "ජූලි 14 වැනිදා ජනාධිපති රාජපක්ෂගේ ඉල්ලා අස්වීමේ ලිපිය තමන් පිළිගත් බව කථානායක මහින්ද යාපා අබේවර්ධන තහවුරු කිරීමෙන් පැය කිහිපයකට පසු වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතා ජූලි 15 සිකුරාදා අගවිනිසුරු ජයන්ත ජයසූරිය මහතා ඉදිරියේ දිවුරුම් දුන්නේය.",
        "අබේවර්ධන සිකුරාදා උදෑසන මාධ්‍යවේදීන් අමතමින් කියා සිටියේ පාර්ලිමේන්තුවේ සාමාජිකත්වයෙන් නව ජනාධිපතිවරයකු තෝරා පත් කර ගන්නා තෙක් වික්‍රමසිංහ වැඩ බලන ජනාධිපතිවරයා ලෙස කටයුතු කරන බවයි. (කොළඹ/ජූලි15/2022)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ජයන්ත ජයසූරිය",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජූලි 15 සිකුරාදා, පැය",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මහින්ද යාපා අබේවර්ධන",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජූලි 14",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "අබේවර්ධන ය",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "සිකුරාදා උදෑසන",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "இலங்கையின் பதில் அதிபராக ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க பதவியேற்றார்",
      "author": "",
      "body_lines": [
        "பொருளாதாரம் - ஜனாதிபதி கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்சவின் பதவி விலகலைத் தொடர்ந்து, இலங்கை பிரதமர் ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க பதில் ஜனாதிபதியாக பதவியேற்றதாக பிரதமர் அலுவலகம் தெரிவித்துள்ளது.",
        "ஜனாதிபதி ராஜபக்சவின் இராஜினாமா கடிதத்தை ஜூலை 14 அன்று ஏற்றுக்கொண்டதாக சபாநாயகர் மஹிந்த யாப்பா அபேவர்தன உறுதிப்படுத்திய சில மணிநேரங்களுக்குப் பிறகு, ஜூலை 15 வெள்ளிக்கிழமை பிரதம நீதியரசர் ஜயந்த ஜயசூரிய முன்னிலையில் விக்கிரமசிங்க பதவியேற்றார்.",
        "பாராளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர்களில் இருந்து புதிய ஜனாதிபதியை தெரிவு செய்யும் வரை விக்கிரமசிங்க பதில் ஜனாதிபதியாக செயற்படுவார் என அபேவர்தன வெள்ளிக்கிழமை காலை செய்தியாளர்களிடம் தெரிவித்தார். (கொழும்பு/ஜூலை15/2022)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "இலங்கை",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஜெயந்த ஜெயசூரியா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "வெள்ளிக்கிழமை ஜூலை 15, மணி",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "மஹிந்த யாப்பா அபேவர்தன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ராஜபக்சே",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜூலை 14",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "அபேவர்தன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "வெள்ளிக்கிழமை காலை",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}