{
  "newspaper_id": "ada-derana-lk",
  "url": "http://www.adaderana.lk/news/83951/social-media-activist-pathum-kerner-remanded",
  "time_ut": 1659092040,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Social media activist Pathum Kerner remanded",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Social media activist Pathum Kerner remanded",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "Social media activist Pathum Kerner, who was arrested by the Colombo Crimes Division (CCD) has been remanded until the 04th of August until an identification parade is carried out on that day.",
        "He was produced before Colombo Additional Magistrate Harshana Kekunawala today (July 29).",
        "Kerner was taken into custody yesterday (July 28) in connection with the unruly incidents reported at the entry road to the parliament near Polduwa Junction earlier this month.",
        "Reportedly, Kerner had assembled people to the Polduwa Junction on the 13th of July and breached the barricades set up for the security of the parliament."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Pathum Kerner",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Pathum Kerner",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Colombo Crimes Division",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "CCD",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the 04th of",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "August",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "that day",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Colombo Additional Magistrate",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Harshana Kekunawala",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "July 29",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "yesterday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "July 28",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Polduwa Junction",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "earlier this month",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        []
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "සමාජ මාධ්‍ය ක්‍රියාකාරිකයෙකු වන පැතුම් කර්නර් රිමාන්ඩ්",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "කොළඹ අපරාධ කොට්ඨාශය (CCD) විසින් අත්අඩංගුවට ගත් සමාජ මාධ්‍ය ක්‍රියාකාරික පැතුම් කර්නර් එදින හඳුනාගැනීමේ පෙරට්ටුවක් පවත්වන තෙක් අගෝස්තු මස 04 වනදා දක්වා රක්ෂිත බන්ධනාගාර ගත කර තිබේ.",
        "ඒ, ඔහු අද (ජුලි 29) කොළඹ අතිරේක මහේස්ත්‍රාත් හර්ෂණ කැකුණවල හමුවට ඉදිරිපත් කිරීමෙන් අනතුරුවයි.",
        "මේ මස මුලදී පොල්දූව හන්දිය අසල පාර්ලිමේන්තුවට පිවිසෙන මාර්ගයේ වාර්තා වූ නොසන්සුන්කාරී සිදුවීම් සම්බන්ධයෙන් කර්නර් ඊයේ (ජූලි 28) අත්අඩංගුවට ගෙන ඇත.",
        "පසුගිය ජුලි මස 13 වැනිදා පොල්දූව මංසන්ධියට කර්නර් විසින් සෙනඟ එක්රැස් කර පාර්ලිමේන්තුවේ ආරක්‍ෂාව සඳහා පිහිටුවා තිබූ බාධක ද ​​බිඳ දමා ඇති බව වාර්තා වේ."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "පැතුම් කර්නර්",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "පැතුම් කර්නර්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "කොළඹ අපරාධ කොට්ඨාශය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "CCD",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "04 වෙනිදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "අගෝස්තු",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "එදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "කොළඹ අතිරේක මහේස්ත්‍රාත්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "හර්ෂණ කැකුණවල",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජූලි 29",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ඊයේ",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජූලි 28",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "පොල්දූව හන්දිය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මේ මස මුල",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        []
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "சமூக ஊடக ஆர்வலர் பாதும் கெர்னர் ரிமாண்ட் செய்யப்பட்டார்",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "கொழும்பு குற்றத்தடுப்பு பிரிவினரால் (CCD) கைது செய்யப்பட்ட சமூக ஊடக செயற்பாட்டாளர் பாதம் கெர்னர், அன்றைய தினம் அடையாள அணிவகுப்பு நடத்தப்படும் வரை ஆகஸ்ட் 04 ஆம் திகதி வரை விளக்கமறியலில் வைக்கப்பட்டுள்ளார்.",
        "அவர் இன்று (ஜூலை 29) கொழும்பு மேலதிக நீதவான் ஹர்ஷன கெகுனாவல முன்னிலையில் ஆஜர்படுத்தப்பட்டார்.",
        "இந்த மாத தொடக்கத்தில் பொல்துவ சந்திக்கு அருகில் உள்ள பாராளுமன்ற நுழைவு வீதியில் பதிவாகிய கட்டுக்கடங்காத சம்பவங்கள் தொடர்பில் கெர்னர் நேற்று (ஜூலை 28) கைது செய்யப்பட்டார்.",
        "கடந்த ஜூலை மாதம் 13ஆம் திகதி பொல்துவ சந்தியில் கெர்னர் மக்களைக் கூட்டிச் சென்று பாராளுமன்றத்தின் பாதுகாப்பிற்காக அமைக்கப்பட்டிருந்த தடுப்புகளை மீறிச் சென்றதாகத் தெரிவிக்கப்படுகிறது."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "பாத்தும் கெர்னர்",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "பாத்தும் கெர்னர்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "கொழும்பு குற்றப்பிரிவு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "சிசிடி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "04 ஆம் தேதி",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆகஸ்ட்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "அந்த நாள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "கொழும்பு மேலதிக நீதவான்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஹர்ஷன கெகுனாவல",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜூலை 29",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "நேற்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜூலை 28",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "பொல்துவ சந்தி",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்த மாத தொடக்கத்தில்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        []
      ]
    }
  }
}