{
  "newspaper_id": "daily-ft-lk",
  "url": "https://www.ft.lk/news/Korean-nationals-living-in-SL-donate-educational-items-to-students/56-736657",
  "time_ut": 1656096191,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Korean nationals living in SL donate educational items to students",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Korean nationals living in SL donate educational items to students",
      "author": "",
      "body_lines": [
        "In order to strengthen the efforts to combat many challenges faced by Sri Lankan students, the Korean people living in Sri Lanka recently handed over educational equipment amounting to almost Rs. 4 million to the Ministry of Education.",
        "The handover ceremony took place in the presence of Education Minister Susil Premajayantha, Secretary M.N. Ranasinghe, Department of Examination Commissioner General L.M.D. Dharmasena and National Institute of Education Director General Dr. Sunil Nawarathne.",
        "Representing the Korean society in Sri Lanka, Korean Businessmen’s Association in Sri Lanka Chairperson Honggyu Kwak, Korean Residents Association of Sri Lanka Chairperson Seongcheol Byeon and Peaceful Unification Advisory Council Southwest Municipal Chapter Chairperson Gyeong Ho Um were present to handover the educational items. Korean Ambassador Santhush Woonjin JEONG also attended the event.",
        "Korean Businessmen’s Association Chairperson Kwak stated that Korean residents in Sri Lanka were saddened to learn that Sri Lankan students were unable to take their examinations in due time due to the shortage of paper and ink.",
        "“In response, Koreans in Sri Lanka raised money with the desire to help students who will be the future leaders of Sri Lanka. I hope our sincerity and heartfelt efforts will assist students overcome these difficult circumstances with dignity. I hope they grow up well,” he added.",
        "Minister Premajayantha was grateful to the Korean residents for donating almost 4 million rupees to support the education sector of Sri Lanka. “The relations between Korea and Sri Lanka span for many decades. Korea has continued to extend unstinted cooperation to mega development projects and also community development projects.",
        "“In these challenging times, the Department of Examinations face many difficulties to conduct examinations in due time for students. This donation is timely and I really appreciate this token of friendship. It will strengthen the ties between the people of Korea and Sri Lanka,” the Minister added.",
        "Commissioner Dharmasena also expressed his gratitude to the donors. “This is the first occasion for the Department of Examinations to receive such a donation from an external party. I thank the Korean society living in Sri Lanka for lending a helping hand by addressing the challenges of this department.",
        "“This donation will help students sit for examinations in due time paving the way for their higher studies and employment.  Nearly 600,000 students sat for GCE ordinary level exams last year amid a lot of hardships. This act of kindness will undoubtedly be remembered and appreciated by not only the students but by all people of Sri Lanka,” he added.",
        "Ambassador JEONG highly commended the Korean society in Sri Lanka who voluntarily donated educational equipment considering the plight of the students in Sri Lanka. Commending their efforts, he mentioned: “I am very proud of the Korean people in Sri Lanka. I highly appreciate this voluntary act by them. It holds a special place in my heart. The united spirit of Korean residents to donate by their own means with sincere generosity to help this beautiful island nation is very meaningful.",
        "“Korean Residents in Sri Lanka have lived here for a long time, more than 20 to 30 years. Today, they have showed their love for Sri Lanka and the Sri Lankan people by this generous contribution.”"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Korean",
          "label": "NORP"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lankan",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Korean",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "4 million",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Ministry of Education",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Susil Premajayantha",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "M.N. Ranasinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Department of Examination Commissioner General L.M.D. Dharmasena",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "National Institute of Education",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sunil Nawarathne",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Korean",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Korean Businessmen’s Association",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Chairperson Honggyu Kwak",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Korean Residents Association of Sri Lanka Chairperson",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Chairperson Gyeong Ho",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Korean",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Santhush Woonjin",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "JEONG",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Korean Businessmen’s Association",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Chairperson Kwak",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Korean",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lankan",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Koreans",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Premajayantha",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Korean",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "almost 4 million",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Korea",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "many decades",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Korea",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the Department of Examinations",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Korea",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Dharmasena",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "first",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Department of Examinations",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Korean",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Nearly 600,000",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "GCE",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "last year",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "JEONG",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Korean",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Korean",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Korean",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Korean Residents",
            "label": "WORK_OF_ART"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "more than 20 to 30 years",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Today",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lankan",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ වෙසෙන කොරියානු ජාතිකයින් සිසුන්ට අධ්‍යාපනික ද්‍රව්‍ය පරිත්‍යාග කරයි",
      "author": "",
      "body_lines": [
        "ශ්‍රී ලාංකීය සිසුන් මුහුණ දෙන අභියෝග රැසකට මුහුණ දීමේ ප්‍රයත්නයන් ශක්තිමත් කිරීම සඳහා ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ වෙසෙන කොරියානු ජනතාව විසින් රුපියල් මිලියන 100 කට ආසන්න අධ්‍යාපනික උපකරණ පසුගියදා ප්‍රදානය කරන ලදී. මිලියන 4ක් අධ්‍යාපන අමාත්‍යාංශයට.",
        "අධ්‍යාපන අමාත්‍ය සුසිල් ප්‍රේමජයන්ත, ලේකම් එම්.එන්. රණසිංහ, විභාග දෙපාර්තමේන්තුවේ කොමසාරිස් ජනරාල් එල්.එම්.ඩී. ධර්මසේන සහ ජාතික අධ්‍යාපන ආයතනයේ අධ්‍යක්ෂ ජනරාල් ආචාර්ය සුනිල් නවරත්න යන මහත්වරු ද සහභාගි වූහ.",
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ කොරියානු සමාජය නියෝජනය කරමින්, ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ කොරියානු ව්‍යාපාරිකයන්ගේ සංගමයේ සභාපති හොන්ග්යු ක්වාක්, ශ්‍රී ලංකා කොරියානු නේවාසිකයන්ගේ සංගමයේ සභාපති සොංචියෝල් බියොන් සහ සාමකාමී ඒකාබද්ධ කිරීමේ උපදේශක සභාවේ නිරිතදිග නාගරික පරිච්ඡේදයේ සභාපති ග්‍යොං හෝ උම් යන මහත්වරු අධ්‍යාපනික ද්‍රව්‍ය ප්‍රදානය කිරීමට පැමිණ සිටියහ. මෙම අවස්ථාවට කොරියානු තානාපති Santhush Wonjin JEONG මහතා ද සහභාගී විය.",
        "කොරියානු ව්‍යාපාරිකයන්ගේ සංගමයේ සභාපති ක්වාක් ප්‍රකාශ කළේ කඩදාසි සහ තීන්ත හිඟය හේතුවෙන් ශ්‍රී ලාංකික සිසුන්ට නියමිත වේලාවට විභාග කිරීමට නොහැකි වීම පිළිබඳව ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ සිටින කොරියානු වැසියන් කණගාටුවට පත් වූ බවයි.",
        "“ප්‍රතිචාර වශයෙන් ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ සිටින කොරියානුවන් ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ අනාගත නායකයන් වන සිසුන්ට උපකාර කිරීමේ ආශාවෙන් මුදල් රැස් කළහ. අපගේ අවංකභාවය සහ හෘදයාංගම උත්සාහයන් සිසුන්ට මෙම දුෂ්කර තත්වයන් අභිමානයෙන් ජය ගැනීමට උපකාර වනු ඇතැයි මම බලාපොරොත්තු වෙමි. ඔවුන් හොඳින් වර්ධනය වේ යැයි මම බලාපොරොත්තු වෙමි, ”ඔහු වැඩිදුරටත් පැවසීය.",
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ අධ්‍යාපන ක්ෂේත්‍රයට ආධාර කිරීම සඳහා රුපියල් මිලියන 4 කට ආසන්න මුදලක් පරිත්‍යාග කිරීම පිළිබඳව අමාත්‍ය ප්‍රේමජයන්ත කොරියානු වැසියන්ට ස්තූතිවන්ත විය. “කොරියාව සහ ශ්‍රී ලංකාව අතර සබඳතා දශක ගණනාවක් පුරා විහිදෙනවා. මෙගා සංවර්ධන ව්‍යාපෘති සහ ප්‍රජා සංවර්ධන ව්‍යාපෘති සඳහා කොරියාව අඛණ්ඩව සහයෝගීතාව ලබා දී ඇත.",
        "“මෙවැනි අභියෝගාත්මක කාලපරිච්ඡේදය තුළ සිසුන්ට නියමිත වේලාවට විභාග පැවැත්වීම සඳහා විභාග දෙපාර්තමේන්තුව දුෂ්කරතා රැසකට මුහුණ දෙයි. මෙම පරිත්‍යාගය කාලෝචිත වන අතර මෙම මිත්‍රත්වයේ සංකේතය මම ඉතා අගය කරමි. එය කොරියාවේ සහ ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ ජනතාව අතර සබඳතා ශක්තිමත් කරනු ඇත,” අමාත්‍යවරයා වැඩිදුරටත් පැවසීය.",
        "කොමසාරිස් ධර්මසේන මහතා පරිත්‍යාගශීලීන්ට සිය කෘතඥතාව ද පළ කළේය. “විභාග දෙපාර්තමේන්තුවට බාහිර පාර්ශ්වයකින් මෙවැනි පරිත්‍යාගයක් ලැබුණු පළමු අවස්ථාව මෙයයි. මෙම දෙපාර්තමේන්තුවේ අභියෝගවලට මුහුණ දෙමින් උදව් උපකාර කිරීම පිළිබඳව ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ වෙසෙන කොරියානු සමාජයට මම ස්තූතිවන්ත වෙමි.",
        "“මෙම පරිත්‍යාගය සිසුන්ට නියමිත වේලාවට විභාගවලට පෙනී සිටීමට උපකාර වන අතර ඔවුන්ගේ උසස් අධ්‍යාපනයට හා රැකියාවට මග පාදයි. පසුගිය වසරේ අපොස සාමාන්‍ය පෙළ විභාගයට සිසුන් ලක්ෂ 6කට ආසන්න පිරිසක් පෙනී සිටියේ දුෂ්කරතා රැසක් මධ්‍යයේය. මෙම කාරුණික ක්‍රියාව සිසුන්ගේ පමණක් නොව ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ සියලුම මිනිසුන්ගේ මතකයේ හා අගය කරනු නොඅනුමානය.",
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ සිසුන්ගේ දුක්ඛිත තත්ත්වය සැලකිල්ලට ගනිමින් ස්වේච්ඡාවෙන් අධ්‍යාපනික උපකරණ පරිත්‍යාග කළ ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ කොරියානු සමාජය තානාපති JEONG මහතා විසින් බෙහෙවින් අගය කරන ලදී. ඔවුන්ගේ උත්සාහය අගය කරමින් ඔහු මෙසේ සඳහන් කළේය: “ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ කොරියානු ජනතාව ගැන මම ඉතා ආඩම්බර වෙමි. ඔවුන්ගේ මේ ස්වේච්ඡා ක්‍රියාව මම ඉතාමත් අගය කරනවා. එය මගේ හදවතේ විශේෂ ස්ථානයක් ගනී. මෙම සුන්දර දූපත් ජාතියට උපකාර කිරීම සඳහා අවංක පරිත්‍යාගශීලීභාවයෙන් යුතුව පරිත්‍යාග කිරීමට කොරියානු වැසියන්ගේ එකමුතු ආත්මය ඉතා අර්ථවත් ය.",
        "“ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ කොරියානු පදිංචිකරුවන් වසර 20කට 30කට වැඩි කාලයක් මෙහි දීර්ඝ කාලයක් ජීවත් වී ඇත. අද ඔවුන් මෙම ත්‍යාගශීලී දායකත්වයෙන් ශ්‍රී ලංකාවට සහ ශ්‍රී ලාංකික ජනතාවට ඔවුන්ගේ ආදරය පෙන්නුම් කර ඇත."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "කොරියානු",
          "label": "NORP"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලාංකික",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "කොරියානු",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මිලියන 4 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "අධ්යාපන අමාත්යාංශය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "සුසිල් ප්‍රේමජයන්ත",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "එම්.එන්. රණසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "විභාග දෙපාර්තමේන්තුවේ කොමසාරිස් ජනරාල් එල්.එම්.ඩී. ධර්මසේන",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජාතික අධ්‍යාපන ආයතනය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "සුනිල් නවරත්න",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "කොරියානු",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "කොරියානු ව්‍යාපාරිකයන්ගේ සංගමය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "සභාපති හොන්ග්යු ක්වාක්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකා කොරියානු නේවාසිකයන්ගේ සංගමයේ සභාපති",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "සභාපති Gyeong Ho",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "කොරියානු",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "සන්තුෂ් වුන්ජින්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජියොන්ග්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "කොරියානු ව්‍යාපාරිකයන්ගේ සංගමය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "සභාපති ක්වාක්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "කොරියානු",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලාංකික",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "කොරියානුවන්",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ප්‍රේමජයන්ත",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "කොරියානු",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "මිලියන 4 කට ආසන්නයි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "කොරියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "දශක ගණනාවක්",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "කොරියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "විභාග දෙපාර්තමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "කොරියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ධර්මසේන",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "පළමුවන",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "විභාග දෙපාර්තමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "කොරියානු",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "600,000 කට ආසන්නයි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "අ.පො.ස",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගිය අවුරුද්දේ",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ජියොන්ග්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "කොරියානු",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "කොරියානු",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "කොරියානු",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "කොරියානු පදිංචිකරුවන්",
            "label": "WORK_OF_ART"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "අවුරුදු 20 සිට 30 දක්වා",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලාංකික",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "இலங்கையில் வசிக்கும் கொரிய பிரஜைகள் மாணவர்களுக்கு கல்வி பொருட்களை நன்கொடையாக வழங்குகிறார்கள்",
      "author": "",
      "body_lines": [
        "இலங்கை மாணவர்கள் எதிர்கொள்ளும் பல சவால்களை எதிர்கொள்வதற்கான முயற்சிகளை வலுப்படுத்தும் வகையில், இலங்கையில் வசிக்கும் கொரிய மக்கள் அண்மையில் கல்வி உபகரணங்களை கையளித்தனர். கல்வி அமைச்சுக்கு 4 மில்லியன்.",
        "கல்வி அமைச்சர் சுசில் பிரேமஜயந்த, செயலாளர் எம்.என். ரணசிங்க, பரீட்சை ஆணையாளர் நாயகம் எல்.எம்.டி. தர்மசேன மற்றும் தேசிய கல்வி நிறுவனத்தின் பணிப்பாளர் நாயகம் கலாநிதி சுனில் நவரத்ன ஆகியோர் கலந்துகொண்டனர்.",
        "இலங்கையில் உள்ள கொரிய சமூகத்தைப் பிரதிநிதித்துவப்படுத்தும் வகையில், இலங்கையில் உள்ள கொரிய வர்த்தகர்கள் சங்கத்தின் தலைவர் ஹொங்யு குவாக், இலங்கையின் கொரிய குடியிருப்பாளர்கள் சங்கத்தின் தலைவி சியோங்சியோல் பியோன் மற்றும் அமைதியான ஒருங்கிணைப்பு ஆலோசனைக் குழுவின் தென்மேற்கு மாநகர சபையின் அத்தியாயத் தலைவர் கியோங் ஹோ உம் ஆகியோர் கல்விப் பொருட்களை கையளிப்பதற்காக வருகை தந்தனர். கொரியத் தூதுவர் சந்துஷ் வூன்ஜின் ஜியோங் அவர்களும் இந்நிகழ்வில் கலந்துகொண்டார்.",
        "காகிதம் மற்றும் மை தட்டுப்பாடு காரணமாக இலங்கை மாணவர்கள் உரிய நேரத்தில் பரீட்சைக்கு வரமுடியவில்லை என்பதை அறிந்து இலங்கையில் உள்ள கொரிய வாசிகள் வருத்தமடைவதாக கொரிய வர்த்தகர் சங்கத்தின் தலைவர் குவாக் தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "“இதற்குப் பதிலடியாக, இலங்கையில் உள்ள கொரியர்கள், இலங்கையின் எதிர்காலத் தலைவர்களாக இருக்கும் மாணவர்களுக்கு உதவ வேண்டும் என்ற ஆசையில் பணத்தைச் சேகரித்தனர். எங்களின் நேர்மை மற்றும் இதயப்பூர்வமான முயற்சிகள் மாணவர்கள் இந்த கடினமான சூழ்நிலைகளை கண்ணியத்துடன் சமாளிக்க உதவும் என்று நம்புகிறேன். அவர்கள் நன்றாக வளர்வார்கள் என்று நம்புகிறேன்,” என்று அவர் மேலும் கூறினார்.",
        "அமைச்சர் பிரேமஜயந்த, இலங்கையின் கல்வித் துறைக்கு ஆதரவாக கிட்டத்தட்ட 4 மில்லியன் ரூபாவை வழங்கிய கொரிய குடியிருப்பாளர்களுக்கு நன்றி தெரிவித்தார். “கொரியாவுக்கும் இலங்கைக்கும் இடையிலான உறவுகள் பல தசாப்தங்களாக தொடர்கின்றன. கொரியா மெகா வளர்ச்சித் திட்டங்களுக்கும் சமூக மேம்பாட்டுத் திட்டங்களுக்கும் இடைவிடாத ஒத்துழைப்பைத் தொடர்ந்து வழங்கி வருகிறது.",
        "“இந்த சவாலான காலக்கட்டத்தில், பரீட்சைகள் திணைக்களம் மாணவர்களுக்கு உரிய நேரத்தில் பரீட்சைகளை நடத்துவதில் பல சிரமங்களை எதிர்நோக்குகிறது. இந்த நன்கொடை சரியான நேரத்தில் மற்றும் இந்த நட்பின் அடையாளத்தை நான் மிகவும் பாராட்டுகிறேன். இது கொரியா மற்றும் இலங்கை மக்களுக்கு இடையிலான உறவுகளை வலுப்படுத்தும்” என்று அமைச்சர் மேலும் கூறினார்.",
        "ஆணையாளர் தர்மசேன நன்கொடையாளர்களுக்கு நன்றி தெரிவித்தார். “பரீட்சைகள் திணைக்களம் வெளி தரப்பினரிடமிருந்து இத்தகைய நன்கொடையைப் பெறுவது இதுவே முதல் சந்தர்ப்பமாகும். இத்துறையின் சவால்களை எதிர்கொண்டு உதவிக்கரம் நீட்டிய இலங்கையில் வாழும் கொரிய சமூகத்தினருக்கு நன்றி.",
        "“இந்த நன்கொடை மாணவர்களுக்கு உரிய நேரத்தில் தேர்வு எழுத உதவும், மேலும் அவர்களின் உயர் படிப்பு மற்றும் வேலை வாய்ப்புக்கு வழி வகுக்கும். கடந்த வருடம் க.பொ.த சாதாரண தர பரீட்சைக்கு ஏறக்குறைய 600,000 மாணவர்கள் பல இன்னல்களுக்கு மத்தியில் தோற்றியிருந்தனர். இந்த கருணைச் செயல் சந்தேகத்திற்கு இடமின்றி மாணவர்கள் மட்டுமன்றி இலங்கையிலுள்ள அனைத்து மக்களாலும் நினைவுகூரப்படும் மற்றும் பாராட்டப்படும்” என்று அவர் மேலும் கூறினார்.",
        "இலங்கையில் உள்ள மாணவர்களின் அவல நிலையை கருத்தில் கொண்டு கல்வி உபகரணங்களை தானாக முன்வந்து நன்கொடையாக வழங்கிய இலங்கையில் உள்ள கொரிய சமுதாயத்தை தூதுவர் JEONG மிகவும் பாராட்டினார். அவர்களின் முயற்சிகளைப் பாராட்டிய அவர், “இலங்கையில் உள்ள கொரிய மக்களைப் பற்றி நான் மிகவும் பெருமைப்படுகிறேன். அவர்களின் இந்த தன்னார்வ செயலை நான் மிகவும் பாராட்டுகிறேன். இது என் இதயத்தில் ஒரு தனி இடத்தைப் பிடித்துள்ளது. இந்த அழகான தீவு தேசத்திற்கு உதவ, கொரிய குடியிருப்பாளர்களின் ஒற்றுமை மனப்பான்மை மிகவும் அர்த்தமுள்ளதாக இருக்கிறது.",
        "“இலங்கையில் உள்ள கொரிய குடியிருப்பாளர்கள் 20 முதல் 30 ஆண்டுகளுக்கும் மேலாக நீண்ட காலமாக இங்கு வசித்து வருகின்றனர். இந்த தாராளமான பங்களிப்பின் மூலம் அவர்கள் இன்று இலங்கை மீதும் இலங்கை மக்கள் மீதும் தங்களின் அன்பை வெளிப்படுத்தியுள்ளனர்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "கொரிய",
          "label": "NORP"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "கொரிய",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "4 மில்லியன்",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "கல்வி அமைச்சு",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "சுசில் பிரேமஜயந்த",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "எம்.என். ரணசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "பரீட்சைகள் திணைக்கள ஆணையாளர் நாயகம் எல்.எம்.டி. தர்மசேனா",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "தேசிய கல்வி நிறுவனம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "சுனில் நவரத்ன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "கொரிய",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "கொரிய வணிகர்கள் சங்கம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "தலைவர் ஹாங்யு குவாக்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கையின் கொரிய குடியிருப்பாளர்கள் சங்கத்தின் தலைவர்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "தலைவர் கியோங் ஹோ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "கொரிய",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "சந்துஷ் வூஞ்சின்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜியோங்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "கொரிய வணிகர்கள் சங்கம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "தலைவர் குவாக்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "கொரிய",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "கொரியர்கள்",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பிரேமஜயந்த",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "கொரிய",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "கிட்டத்தட்ட 4 மில்லியன்",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "கொரியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "பல தசாப்தங்கள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "கொரியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பரீட்சைகள் திணைக்களம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "கொரியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "தர்மசேனா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "முதலில்",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "பரீட்சைகள் திணைக்களம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "கொரிய",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "கிட்டத்தட்ட 600,000",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "க.பொ.த",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "கடந்த ஆண்டு",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஜியோங்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "கொரிய",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "கொரிய",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "கொரிய",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "கொரிய குடியிருப்பாளர்கள்",
            "label": "WORK_OF_ART"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "20 முதல் 30 ஆண்டுகளுக்கு மேல்",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  },
  "title": "Korean nationals living in SL donate educational items to students",
  "body_lines": [
    "In order to strengthen the efforts to combat many challenges faced by Sri Lankan students, the Korean people living in Sri Lanka recently handed over educational equipment amounting to almost Rs. 4 million to the Ministry of Education.",
    "The handover ceremony took place in the presence of Education Minister Susil Premajayantha, Secretary M.N. Ranasinghe, Department of Examination Commissioner General L.M.D. Dharmasena and National Institute of Education Director General Dr. Sunil Nawarathne.",
    "Representing the Korean society in Sri Lanka, Korean Businessmen’s Association in Sri Lanka Chairperson Honggyu Kwak, Korean Residents Association of Sri Lanka Chairperson Seongcheol Byeon and Peaceful Unification Advisory Council Southwest Municipal Chapter Chairperson Gyeong Ho Um were present to handover the educational items. Korean Ambassador Santhush Woonjin JEONG also attended the event.",
    "Korean Businessmen’s Association Chairperson Kwak stated that Korean residents in Sri Lanka were saddened to learn that Sri Lankan students were unable to take their examinations in due time due to the shortage of paper and ink.",
    "“In response, Koreans in Sri Lanka raised money with the desire to help students who will be the future leaders of Sri Lanka. I hope our sincerity and heartfelt efforts will assist students overcome these difficult circumstances with dignity. I hope they grow up well,” he added.",
    "Minister Premajayantha was grateful to the Korean residents for donating almost 4 million rupees to support the education sector of Sri Lanka. “The relations between Korea and Sri Lanka span for many decades. Korea has continued to extend unstinted cooperation to mega development projects and also community development projects.",
    "“In these challenging times, the Department of Examinations face many difficulties to conduct examinations in due time for students. This donation is timely and I really appreciate this token of friendship. It will strengthen the ties between the people of Korea and Sri Lanka,” the Minister added.",
    "Commissioner Dharmasena also expressed his gratitude to the donors. “This is the first occasion for the Department of Examinations to receive such a donation from an external party. I thank the Korean society living in Sri Lanka for lending a helping hand by addressing the challenges of this department.",
    "“This donation will help students sit for examinations in due time paving the way for their higher studies and employment.  Nearly 600,000 students sat for GCE ordinary level exams last year amid a lot of hardships. This act of kindness will undoubtedly be remembered and appreciated by not only the students but by all people of Sri Lanka,” he added.",
    "Ambassador JEONG highly commended the Korean society in Sri Lanka who voluntarily donated educational equipment considering the plight of the students in Sri Lanka. Commending their efforts, he mentioned: “I am very proud of the Korean people in Sri Lanka. I highly appreciate this voluntary act by them. It holds a special place in my heart. The united spirit of Korean residents to donate by their own means with sincere generosity to help this beautiful island nation is very meaningful.",
    "“Korean Residents in Sri Lanka have lived here for a long time, more than 20 to 30 years. Today, they have showed their love for Sri Lanka and the Sri Lankan people by this generous contribution.”"
  ],
  "translate": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Korean nationals living in SL donate educational items to students",
      "author": "",
      "body_lines": [
        "In order to strengthen the efforts to combat many challenges faced by Sri Lankan students, the Korean people living in Sri Lanka recently handed over educational equipment amounting to almost Rs. 4 million to the Ministry of Education.",
        "The handover ceremony took place in the presence of Education Minister Susil Premajayantha, Secretary M.N. Ranasinghe, Department of Examination Commissioner General L.M.D. Dharmasena and National Institute of Education Director General Dr. Sunil Nawarathne.",
        "Representing the Korean society in Sri Lanka, Korean Businessmen’s Association in Sri Lanka Chairperson Honggyu Kwak, Korean Residents Association of Sri Lanka Chairperson Seongcheol Byeon and Peaceful Unification Advisory Council Southwest Municipal Chapter Chairperson Gyeong Ho Um were present to handover the educational items. Korean Ambassador Santhush Woonjin JEONG also attended the event.",
        "Korean Businessmen’s Association Chairperson Kwak stated that Korean residents in Sri Lanka were saddened to learn that Sri Lankan students were unable to take their examinations in due time due to the shortage of paper and ink.",
        "“In response, Koreans in Sri Lanka raised money with the desire to help students who will be the future leaders of Sri Lanka. I hope our sincerity and heartfelt efforts will assist students overcome these difficult circumstances with dignity. I hope they grow up well,” he added.",
        "Minister Premajayantha was grateful to the Korean residents for donating almost 4 million rupees to support the education sector of Sri Lanka. “The relations between Korea and Sri Lanka span for many decades. Korea has continued to extend unstinted cooperation to mega development projects and also community development projects.",
        "“In these challenging times, the Department of Examinations face many difficulties to conduct examinations in due time for students. This donation is timely and I really appreciate this token of friendship. It will strengthen the ties between the people of Korea and Sri Lanka,” the Minister added.",
        "Commissioner Dharmasena also expressed his gratitude to the donors. “This is the first occasion for the Department of Examinations to receive such a donation from an external party. I thank the Korean society living in Sri Lanka for lending a helping hand by addressing the challenges of this department.",
        "“This donation will help students sit for examinations in due time paving the way for their higher studies and employment.  Nearly 600,000 students sat for GCE ordinary level exams last year amid a lot of hardships. This act of kindness will undoubtedly be remembered and appreciated by not only the students but by all people of Sri Lanka,” he added.",
        "Ambassador JEONG highly commended the Korean society in Sri Lanka who voluntarily donated educational equipment considering the plight of the students in Sri Lanka. Commending their efforts, he mentioned: “I am very proud of the Korean people in Sri Lanka. I highly appreciate this voluntary act by them. It holds a special place in my heart. The united spirit of Korean residents to donate by their own means with sincere generosity to help this beautiful island nation is very meaningful.",
        "“Korean Residents in Sri Lanka have lived here for a long time, more than 20 to 30 years. Today, they have showed their love for Sri Lanka and the Sri Lankan people by this generous contribution.”"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Korean",
          "label": "NORP"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lankan",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Korean",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "4 million",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Ministry of Education",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Susil Premajayantha",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "M.N. Ranasinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Department of Examination Commissioner General L.M.D. Dharmasena",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "National Institute of Education",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sunil Nawarathne",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Korean",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Korean Businessmen’s Association",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Chairperson Honggyu Kwak",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Korean Residents Association of Sri Lanka Chairperson",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Chairperson Gyeong Ho",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Korean",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Santhush Woonjin",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "JEONG",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Korean Businessmen’s Association",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Chairperson Kwak",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Korean",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lankan",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Koreans",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Premajayantha",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Korean",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "almost 4 million",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Korea",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "many decades",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Korea",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the Department of Examinations",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Korea",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Dharmasena",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "first",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Department of Examinations",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Korean",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Nearly 600,000",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "GCE",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "last year",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "JEONG",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Korean",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Korean",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Korean",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Korean Residents",
            "label": "WORK_OF_ART"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "more than 20 to 30 years",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Today",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lankan",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ වෙසෙන කොරියානු ජාතිකයින් සිසුන්ට අධ්‍යාපනික ද්‍රව්‍ය පරිත්‍යාග කරයි",
      "author": "",
      "body_lines": [
        "ශ්‍රී ලාංකීය සිසුන් මුහුණ දෙන අභියෝග රැසකට මුහුණ දීමේ ප්‍රයත්නයන් ශක්තිමත් කිරීම සඳහා ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ වෙසෙන කොරියානු ජනතාව විසින් රුපියල් මිලියන 100 කට ආසන්න අධ්‍යාපනික උපකරණ පසුගියදා ප්‍රදානය කරන ලදී. මිලියන 4ක් අධ්‍යාපන අමාත්‍යාංශයට.",
        "අධ්‍යාපන අමාත්‍ය සුසිල් ප්‍රේමජයන්ත, ලේකම් එම්.එන්. රණසිංහ, විභාග දෙපාර්තමේන්තුවේ කොමසාරිස් ජනරාල් එල්.එම්.ඩී. ධර්මසේන සහ ජාතික අධ්‍යාපන ආයතනයේ අධ්‍යක්ෂ ජනරාල් ආචාර්ය සුනිල් නවරත්න යන මහත්වරු ද සහභාගි වූහ.",
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ කොරියානු සමාජය නියෝජනය කරමින්, ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ කොරියානු ව්‍යාපාරිකයන්ගේ සංගමයේ සභාපති හොන්ග්යු ක්වාක්, ශ්‍රී ලංකා කොරියානු නේවාසිකයන්ගේ සංගමයේ සභාපති සොංචියෝල් බියොන් සහ සාමකාමී ඒකාබද්ධ කිරීමේ උපදේශක සභාවේ නිරිතදිග නාගරික පරිච්ඡේදයේ සභාපති ග්‍යොං හෝ උම් යන මහත්වරු අධ්‍යාපනික ද්‍රව්‍ය ප්‍රදානය කිරීමට පැමිණ සිටියහ. මෙම අවස්ථාවට කොරියානු තානාපති Santhush Wonjin JEONG මහතා ද සහභාගී විය.",
        "කොරියානු ව්‍යාපාරිකයන්ගේ සංගමයේ සභාපති ක්වාක් ප්‍රකාශ කළේ කඩදාසි සහ තීන්ත හිඟය හේතුවෙන් ශ්‍රී ලාංකික සිසුන්ට නියමිත වේලාවට විභාග කිරීමට නොහැකි වීම පිළිබඳව ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ සිටින කොරියානු වැසියන් කණගාටුවට පත් වූ බවයි.",
        "“ප්‍රතිචාර වශයෙන් ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ සිටින කොරියානුවන් ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ අනාගත නායකයන් වන සිසුන්ට උපකාර කිරීමේ ආශාවෙන් මුදල් රැස් කළහ. අපගේ අවංකභාවය සහ හෘදයාංගම උත්සාහයන් සිසුන්ට මෙම දුෂ්කර තත්වයන් අභිමානයෙන් ජය ගැනීමට උපකාර වනු ඇතැයි මම බලාපොරොත්තු වෙමි. ඔවුන් හොඳින් වර්ධනය වේ යැයි මම බලාපොරොත්තු වෙමි, ”ඔහු වැඩිදුරටත් පැවසීය.",
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ අධ්‍යාපන ක්ෂේත්‍රයට ආධාර කිරීම සඳහා රුපියල් මිලියන 4 කට ආසන්න මුදලක් පරිත්‍යාග කිරීම පිළිබඳව අමාත්‍ය ප්‍රේමජයන්ත කොරියානු වැසියන්ට ස්තූතිවන්ත විය. “කොරියාව සහ ශ්‍රී ලංකාව අතර සබඳතා දශක ගණනාවක් පුරා විහිදෙනවා. මෙගා සංවර්ධන ව්‍යාපෘති සහ ප්‍රජා සංවර්ධන ව්‍යාපෘති සඳහා කොරියාව අඛණ්ඩව සහයෝගීතාව ලබා දී ඇත.",
        "“මෙවැනි අභියෝගාත්මක කාලපරිච්ඡේදය තුළ සිසුන්ට නියමිත වේලාවට විභාග පැවැත්වීම සඳහා විභාග දෙපාර්තමේන්තුව දුෂ්කරතා රැසකට මුහුණ දෙයි. මෙම පරිත්‍යාගය කාලෝචිත වන අතර මෙම මිත්‍රත්වයේ සංකේතය මම ඉතා අගය කරමි. එය කොරියාවේ සහ ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ ජනතාව අතර සබඳතා ශක්තිමත් කරනු ඇත,” අමාත්‍යවරයා වැඩිදුරටත් පැවසීය.",
        "කොමසාරිස් ධර්මසේන මහතා පරිත්‍යාගශීලීන්ට සිය කෘතඥතාව ද පළ කළේය. “විභාග දෙපාර්තමේන්තුවට බාහිර පාර්ශ්වයකින් මෙවැනි පරිත්‍යාගයක් ලැබුණු පළමු අවස්ථාව මෙයයි. මෙම දෙපාර්තමේන්තුවේ අභියෝගවලට මුහුණ දෙමින් උදව් උපකාර කිරීම පිළිබඳව ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ වෙසෙන කොරියානු සමාජයට මම ස්තූතිවන්ත වෙමි.",
        "“මෙම පරිත්‍යාගය සිසුන්ට නියමිත වේලාවට විභාගවලට පෙනී සිටීමට උපකාර වන අතර ඔවුන්ගේ උසස් අධ්‍යාපනයට හා රැකියාවට මග පාදයි. පසුගිය වසරේ අපොස සාමාන්‍ය පෙළ විභාගයට සිසුන් ලක්ෂ 6කට ආසන්න පිරිසක් පෙනී සිටියේ දුෂ්කරතා රැසක් මධ්‍යයේය. මෙම කාරුණික ක්‍රියාව සිසුන්ගේ පමණක් නොව ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ සියලුම මිනිසුන්ගේ මතකයේ හා අගය කරනු නොඅනුමානය.",
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ සිසුන්ගේ දුක්ඛිත තත්ත්වය සැලකිල්ලට ගනිමින් ස්වේච්ඡාවෙන් අධ්‍යාපනික උපකරණ පරිත්‍යාග කළ ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ කොරියානු සමාජය තානාපති JEONG මහතා විසින් බෙහෙවින් අගය කරන ලදී. ඔවුන්ගේ උත්සාහය අගය කරමින් ඔහු මෙසේ සඳහන් කළේය: “ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ කොරියානු ජනතාව ගැන මම ඉතා ආඩම්බර වෙමි. ඔවුන්ගේ මේ ස්වේච්ඡා ක්‍රියාව මම ඉතාමත් අගය කරනවා. එය මගේ හදවතේ විශේෂ ස්ථානයක් ගනී. මෙම සුන්දර දූපත් ජාතියට උපකාර කිරීම සඳහා අවංක පරිත්‍යාගශීලීභාවයෙන් යුතුව පරිත්‍යාග කිරීමට කොරියානු වැසියන්ගේ එකමුතු ආත්මය ඉතා අර්ථවත් ය.",
        "“ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ කොරියානු පදිංචිකරුවන් වසර 20කට 30කට වැඩි කාලයක් මෙහි දීර්ඝ කාලයක් ජීවත් වී ඇත. අද ඔවුන් මෙම ත්‍යාගශීලී දායකත්වයෙන් ශ්‍රී ලංකාවට සහ ශ්‍රී ලාංකික ජනතාවට ඔවුන්ගේ ආදරය පෙන්නුම් කර ඇත."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "කොරියානු",
          "label": "NORP"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලාංකික",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "කොරියානු",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මිලියන 4 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "අධ්යාපන අමාත්යාංශය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "සුසිල් ප්‍රේමජයන්ත",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "එම්.එන්. රණසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "විභාග දෙපාර්තමේන්තුවේ කොමසාරිස් ජනරාල් එල්.එම්.ඩී. ධර්මසේන",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජාතික අධ්‍යාපන ආයතනය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "සුනිල් නවරත්න",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "කොරියානු",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "කොරියානු ව්‍යාපාරිකයන්ගේ සංගමය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "සභාපති හොන්ග්යු ක්වාක්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකා කොරියානු නේවාසිකයන්ගේ සංගමයේ සභාපති",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "සභාපති Gyeong Ho",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "කොරියානු",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "සන්තුෂ් වුන්ජින්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජියොන්ග්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "කොරියානු ව්‍යාපාරිකයන්ගේ සංගමය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "සභාපති ක්වාක්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
