{
  "newspaper_id": "virakesari-lk",
  "url": "http://www.virakesari.lk/article/131551",
  "time_ut": 1657902952,
  "original_lang": "ta",
  "original_title": "புதிய ஜனாதிபதி தெரிவில் பதில் ஜனாதிபதி  ரணிலுக்கு ஆதரவு  - ஸ்ரீலங்கா பொதுஜன பெரமுன",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Support for President Ranil in New Presidential Election - Sri Lanka Podujana Peramuna",
      "author": "Vishnu",
      "body_lines": [
        "The Sri Lanka Podujana Peramuna has officially decided to support President Ranil Wickremesinghe in the parliamentary poll for the new President; The party's general secretary Sagara Kariyawasam said that he will not support former minister Dalus Alagaperuma.",
        "Members of Podujana Peramuna will support Acting President Ranil Wickremesinghe during the vote for the new President.",
        "This decision was officially taken after Member of Parliament Dallas Alagaperuma announced that he will contest for the new presidential election to be held in Parliament next Wednesday.",
        "Dallas Alagaperuma has mentioned that he is ready to contest in the parliamentary vote for the election of the President. He has not decided to support him as a party.",
        "He said that it was decided to provide support to the President because the current President should take the next step in order to solve the economic crisis without political factors.",
        "Former minister Dulles Alagapperuma, who contested in the Sri Lanka Podujana Peramuna's budding party in the 2020 general election and was elected to parliament, has stated that he is ready to contest in the 'vacant executive power of the president' and has sought the support of all members of parliament.",
        "In the 2020 general election, the Sri Lanka Podujana Peramuna won 59.09 percent of the votes and captured all 145 seats in the Parliament. Sri Lanka Freedom Party, Sri Lanka Workers Congress, including Wimal Weerawansa, Udaya Kammanpila, Vasudeva Nanayakkara, Thissa Vidharana announced that they left the government on April 5th and are working independently in the Parliament. Even though the number of independents in the Parliament was found to be 44, some of them joined the government and got ministerial posts.",
        "However, Sri Lanka Podujana Peramuna currently has more than 113 seats in the Parliament and it has been confirmed on various occasions. The 10 political parties operating independently in Parliament and only five including Anura Priyadarshana Yappa and Sudarshani Fernando Pulle initially indicated that they would cooperate with Podujana Peramuna's member Dussel Alagaperuma, although they did not officially mention it."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Ranil",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "Podujana Peramuna",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "Podujana Peramuna",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sagara Kariyawasam",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Dalus Alagaperuma",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Podujana Peramuna",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Parliament Dallas Alagaperuma",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "next Wednesday",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Dallas Alagaperuma",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "Dulles Alagapperuma",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "Podujana Peramuna's",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "2020",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "2020",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "Podujana Peramuna",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "59.09 percent",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "145",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka Freedom Party",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka Workers Congress",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Wimal Weerawansa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Udaya Kammanpila",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Vasudeva Nanayakkara",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Thissa Vidharana",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "April 5th",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "44",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "Podujana Peramuna",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "more than 113",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "10",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "only five",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Anura",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Priyadarshana Yappa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sudarshani Fernando Pulle",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Podujana Peramuna's",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Dussel Alagaperuma",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "නව ජනාධිපතිවරණයේදී ජනාධිපති රනිල්ට සහය - ශ්‍රී ලංකා පොදුජන පෙරමුණ",
      "author": "විෂ්ණු",
      "body_lines": [
        "නව ජනාධිපතිවරයා සඳහා වන පාර්ලිමේන්තු මැතිවරණයේදී ජනාධිපති රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතාට සහය දැක්වීමට ශ්‍රී ලංකා පොදුජන පෙරමුණ නිල වශයෙන් තීරණය කර තිබේ. හිටපු අමාත්‍ය ඩලස් අලගපෙරුම මහතාට සහය නොදෙන බව එම පක්ෂයේ මහලේකම් සාගර කාරියවසම් මහතා පැවසීය.",
        "නව ජනාධිපතිවරයා සඳහා වන ඡන්ද විමසීමේදී පොදුජන පෙරමුණේ සාමාජිකයින් වැඩබලන ජනාධිපති රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතාට සහය පළ කිරීමට නියමිතයි.",
        "පාර්ලිමේන්තු මන්ත්‍රී ඩලස් අලගපෙරුම මහතා ලබන බදාදා පාර්ලිමේන්තුවේදී පැවැත්වෙන නව ජනාධිපතිවරණය සඳහා තරග කරන බව ප්‍රකාශ කිරීමෙන් අනතුරුව මෙම තීරණය නිල වශයෙන් ගෙන ඇත.",
        "ජනාධිපතිවරයා තෝරා පත් කර ගැනීම සඳහා පාර්ලිමේන්තු ඡන්දයට ඉදිරිපත් වීමට තමන් සූදානම් බවත්, පක්ෂයක් ලෙස තමන්ට සහය දැක්වීමට තමන් තීරණය කර නොමැති බවත් ඩලස් අලගපෙරුම මහතා සඳහන් කරයි.",
        "දේශපාලන කරුණුවලින් තොරව ආර්ථික අර්බුදය විසඳීම සඳහා වත්මන් ජනාධිපතිවරයා මීළඟ පියවර ගත යුතු බැවින් ජනාධිපතිවරයාට සහය ලබාදීමට තීරණය කළ බවද ඔහු සඳහන් කළේය.",
        "2020 මහ මැතිවරණයේදී ශ්‍රී ලංකා පොදුජන පෙරමුණේ අංකුර පක්ෂයෙන් තරග කර පාර්ලිමේන්තුවට තේරී පත් වූ හිටපු අමාත්‍ය ඩලස් අලගප්පෙරුම මහතා ‘පුරප්පාඩු වූ විධායක ජනාධිපති බලයට’ තරග කිරීමට සූදානම් බව ප්‍රකාශ කර ඒ සඳහා සහාය ඉල්ලා ඇත. සියලුම පාර්ලිමේන්තු මන්ත්‍රීවරුන්.",
        "2020 මහ මැතිවරණයේදී ශ්‍රී ලංකා පොදුජන පෙරමුණ සියයට 59.09 ක ඡන්ද ප්‍රතිශතයක් ලබා ගනිමින් පාර්ලිමේන්තුවේ ආසන 145 ම අත්පත් කර ගත් බව ශ්‍රී ලංකා නිදහස් පක්ෂය, විමල් වීරවංශ, උදය කම්මන්පිල, වාසුදේව නානායක්කාර, තිස්ස විධාරණ ඇතුළු ශ්‍රී ලංකා කම්කරු කොංග්‍රසය නිවේදනය කළේය. අප්‍රේල් 05 වැනිදා ආණ්ඩුවෙන් ඉවත් වෙලා පාර්ලිමේන්තුවේ ස්වාධීනව කටයුතු කරනවා.පාර්ලිමේන්තුවේ ස්වාධීන මන්ත්‍රීවරුන් සංඛ්‍යාව 44ක් වුණත් සමහරු ආණ්ඩුවට එකතුවෙලා ඇමැතිකම් ගත්තා.",
        "කෙසේ වෙතත් මේ වන විට ශ්‍රී ලංකා පොදුජන පෙරමුණට පාර්ලිමේන්තුවේ මන්ත්‍රී ධුර 113කට වැඩි ප්‍රමාණයක් හිමිව ඇති අතර එය විවිධ අවස්ථාවලදී තහවුරු වී ඇත.පාර්ලිමේන්තුවේ ස්වාධීනව ක්‍රියාත්මක වන දේශපාලන පක්ෂ 10 සහ අනුර ප්‍රියදර්ශන යාප්පා, සුදර්ශනී ප්‍රනාන්දු පුල්ලේ ඇතුළු පක්ෂ පහක් පමණක් සහයෝගයෙන් කටයුතු කරන බව මුලින් පෙන්වා දුන්නේය. පොදුජන පෙරමුණේ මන්ත්‍රී දුසෙල් අලගපෙරුම ඒ බව නිල වශයෙන් සඳහන් නොකළත්."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "රනිල්",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "පොදුජන පෙරමුණ",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "පොදුජන පෙරමුණ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "සාගර කාරියවසම්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "දලස් අලගපෙරුම",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "පොදුජන පෙරමුණ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව ඩලස් අලගපෙරුම",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ලබන බදාදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ඩලස් අලගපෙරුම",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "ඩලස් අලගප්පෙරුම",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "පොදුජන පෙරමුණේ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "2020",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "2020",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "පොදුජන පෙරමුණ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "සියයට 59.09 කි",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "145",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකා නිදහස් පක්ෂය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකා කම්කරු කොංග්‍රසය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "විමල් වීරවංශ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "උදය කම්මන්පිල",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "වාසුදේව නානායක්කාර",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "තිස්ස විධාරණ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "අප්රේල් 5",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "44",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "පොදුජන පෙරමුණ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "113 ට වැඩි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "10",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "පහක් පමණි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "අනුර",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ප්‍රියදර්ශන යාප්පා",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "සුදර්ශනී ප්‍රනාන්දු පුල්ලේ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "පොදුජන පෙරමුණේ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "දුසෙල් අලගපෙරුම",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "புதிய ஜனாதிபதி தெரிவில் பதில் ஜனாதிபதி  ரணிலுக்கு ஆதரவு  - ஸ்ரீலங்கா பொதுஜன பெரமுன",
      "author": "Vishnu",
      "body_lines": [
        "புதிய ஜனாதிபதி தெரிவிற்கான பாராளுமன்ற வாக்கெடுப்பில் பதில் ஜனாதிபதி ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்கவிற்கு ஆதரவு வழங்க ஸ்ரீ லங்கா பொதுஜன பெரமுன உத்தியோகப்பூர்வமாக தீர்மானித்துள்ளதுடன்; முன்னாள் அமைச்சர் டலஸ் அழகபெருமவிற்கு ஆதரவு வழங்க போவதில்லை என அக்கட்சியின் பொதுச்செயலாளர் சாகர காரியவசம் குறிப்பிட்டார்.",
        "புதிய ஜனாதிபதி தெரிவிற்கான வாக்கெடுப்பின் போது பதில் ஜனாதிபதி ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்கவிற்கு பொதுஜன பெரமுனவின் உறுப்பினர்கள் ஆதரவு வழங்குவார்கள்.",
        "பாராளுமன்றில் எதிர்வரும் புதன்கிழமை இடம்பெறவுள்ள புதிய ஜனாதிபதி தெரிவிற்கு தானும் போட்டியிட போவதாக பாராளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர் டலஸ் அழகபெரும அறிவித்ததை தொடர்ந்து இந்த தீர்மானம் உத்தியோகப்பூர்வமாக எடுக்கப்பட்டது.",
        "ஜனாதிபதி தெரிவிற்கான பாராளுமன்ற வாக்கெடுப்பில் தானும் போட்டியிட தயார் என டலஸ் அழகபெரும குறிப்பிட்டுள்ளார்.கட்சி என்ற ரீதியில் அவருக்கு ஆதரவு வழங்க தீர்மானிக்கவில்லை.",
        "அரசியல் காரணிகளை விடுத்து பொருளாதார நெருக்கடிக்கு தீர்வு காணும் வகையில் தற்போதைய பதில் ஜனாதிபதி தலைமையில் அடுத்தக்கட்ட நடவடிக்கையினை முன்னெடுத்து செல்ல வேண்டும் என்ற காரணத்தினால் பதில் ஜனாதிபதி;க்கு ஆதரவு வழங்க தீர்மானிக்கப்பட்டது என்றார்.",
        "2020ஆம் ஆண்டு இடம்பெற்ற பொதுத்தேர்தலில் ஸ்ரீ லங்கா பொதுஜன பெரமுனவின் மொட்டு கட்சியில் போட்டியிட்டு பாராளுமன்றிற்கு தெரிவாகிய முன்னாள் அமைச்சர் டலஸ் அழகப்பெரும 'வெற்றிடமாகியுள்ள நிறைவேற்று அதிகாரம் கொண்ட ஜனாதிபதியை தெரிவு செய்யும் பாராளுமன்ற வாக்கெடு;ப்பில் தானும் போட்டியிட தயார் என குறிப்பிட்டு,சகல பாராளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர்களின் ஆதரைவயும் கோரியுள்ளார்.",
        "2020ஆம் ஆண்டு இடம்பெற்ற பொதுத்தேர்தலில் ஸ்ரீ லங்கா பொதுஜன பெரமுன 59.09 சதவீத வாக்குகளை பெற்று பாராளுமன்றில் 145 ஆசனங்களையும் கைப்பற்றியது.ஸ்ரீ லங்கா சுதந்திரகட்சி,இலங்கை தொழிலாளர் காங்கிரஸ் உட்பட விமல் வீரவன்ச,உதய கம்மன்பில,வாசுதேவ நாணயக்கார,திஸ்ஸ விதாரன உட்பட ஒருசிலர் கடந்த ஏப்ரல் மாதம் 05ஆம் திகதி அரசாங்கத்திலிருந்து வெளியேறி தான் பாராளுமன்றில் சுயாதீனமாக செயற்படுவதாக அறிவித்தனர்.அதற்கமைய பாராளுமன்றில் சுயாதீனமாக செயற்படுபவர்களின் எண்ணிக்கை 44 ஆக காணப்பட்ட போதும் பின்னர் ஒருசிலர் அரசாங்கத்தில் இணைந்துக்கொண்டு அமைச்சு பதவிகளை பெற்றுக்கொண்டனர்.",
        "எவ்வாறு இருப்பினும் பாராளுமன்றில் ஸ்ரீ லங்கா பொதுஜன பெரமுனவிற்கு 113 ஆசனங்களுக்கும் அதிகமான ஆசனங்கள் தற்சமயம் உள்ளது பல்வேறு சந்தர்ப்பங்களில் உறுதிப்படுத்தப்பட்டுள்ளது.பொதுஜன பெரமுனவின் உறுப்பினர் டஸல் அழகப்பெருமவிற்கு பாராளுமன்றில் சுயாதீனமாக செயற்படும் 10 அரசியல் கட்சிகளும், அனுர பிரியதர்ஷன யாப்பா,சுதர்ஷனி பெர்னான்டோ புள்ளே உட்பட ஐந்து பேர் மாத்திரம் ஒத்துழைப்பு வழங்குவதாக ஆரம்பத்தில் குறிப்பிட்டார்கள்,இருப்பினும் உத்தியோகப்பூர்வமாக குறிப்பிடவில்லை."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ரணில்",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "பொதுஜன பெரமுன",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "பொதுஜன பெரமுன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "சாகர காரியவசம்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "டலஸ் அழகப்பெரும",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பொதுஜன பெரமுன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம் டலஸ் அழகப்பெரும",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "அடுத்த புதன்கிழமை",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "டலஸ் அழகப்பெரும",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "டல்லஸ் அழகப்பெரும",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "பொதுஜன பெரமுனவின்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "2020",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "2020",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "பொதுஜன பெரமுன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "59.09 சதவீதம்",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "145",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஸ்ரீலங்கா சுதந்திரக் கட்சி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை தொழிலாளர் காங்கிரஸ்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "விமல் வீரவன்ச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "உதய கம்மன்பில",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "வாசுதேவ நாணயக்கார",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "திஸ்ஸ விதாரண",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஏப்ரல் 5",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "44",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "பொதுஜன பெரமுன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "113க்கு மேல்",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "10",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஐந்து மட்டுமே",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "அனுர",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "பிரியதர்ஷன யாப்பா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "சுதர்ஷனி பெர்னாண்டோ புள்ளே",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "பொதுஜன பெரமுனவின்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "டசல் அழகப்பெரும",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}