{
  "newspaper_id": "d-b-s-jeyaraj-com",
  "url": "https://dbsjeyaraj.com/dbsj/archives/78154",
  "time_ut": 1655838900,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Dhammika Perera says he is  grateful to Basil Rajapaksa : “Basil Rajapaksa had nominated me, this seat was supposed to be handed over to someone else, but it was Basil who asked me to step in”says new SLPP Nationl list MP",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Dhammika Perera says he is  grateful to Basil Rajapaksa : “Basil Rajapaksa had nominated me, this seat was supposed to be handed over to someone else, but it was Basil who asked me to step in”says new SLPP Nationl list MP",
      "author": "Administrator",
      "body_lines": [
        "While stating that bringing in dollars is what he does best, newly appointed MP Dhammika Perera has stated that his intention is to bring in foreign exchange over obtaining loans.",
        "He made this statement while speaking to the media after taking oaths as an SLPP National List MP today (22).",
        "“I know that Sri Lanka can be brought up again, and in a country where people are losing jobs, I am here to create jobs. I feel that I am fulfilling my duties by entering parliament, instead of just shouting out on the streets. During the war, I was in the economic committee and this is not much of a challenge in comparison to that time,” he mentioned.",
        "Perera further noted that he is currently hosting an online programme at the Moratuwa University in the Information Technology field and that over 90,000 students are being educated under the same.",
        "“Under the IT Programme I am hosting at the Moratuwa University, over 90,000 students are being educated. These are some of my accomplishments and with this experience, I feel I can bring about a change in the future generations,” Perera said.",
        "When inquired by the media whether Perera had spoken to Basil Rajapaksa recently, he said that he was grateful to Mr Rajapaksa for stepping down and nominating him to take over.",
        "“Basil Rajapaksa had nominated me, this seat was supposed to be handed over to someone else, but it was Basil who asked me to step in. Mahinda Rajapaksa has not met me as yet, but I intend on paying him a visit today,” Perera said.",
        "When asked if he felt he was stepping into a sinking ship by joining as a member of Parliament and accepting a Ministerial Portfolio, Perera stated he does not feel the country is a sinking ship.",
        "“No one walks into a sinking ship. No one makes silly decisions as such. I took up this challenge as I feel Sri Lanka is not a sinking ship and I am able to bring about a change. I intend to submit my report and suggestions for an economic relief plan within the next 2 weeks. Let us take it up from there,” Perera concluded."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Dhammika Perera",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "Basil Rajapaksa",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "Basil Rajapaksa",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "Basil",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "SLPP Nationl",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Dhammika Perera",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "22",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Perera",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Moratuwa University",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the Moratuwa University",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "90,000",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Perera",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Perera",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Basil Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Basil Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Basil",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Mahinda Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Perera",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Perera",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "one",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the next 2 weeks",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Perera",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "බැසිල් රාජපක්ෂ මහතාට ස්තූතිවන්ත වන බව ධම්මික පෙරේරා මහතා පවසයි: “බැසිල් රාජපක්ෂ මට නාමයෝජනා දුන්නා, මේ ආසනය වෙන කෙනෙකුට දෙන්න තිබුණා, නමුත් මට එන්න කිව්වේ බැසිල්,” ශ්‍රී ලංකා පොදුජන පෙරමුණේ නව ජාතික ලැයිස්තු මන්ත්‍රී",
      "author": "පරිපාලක",
      "body_lines": [
        "ඩොලර් ගෙන ඒම තමා හොඳම දේ බව ප්‍රකාශ කරන අතරේ අලුතින් පත් වූ පාර්ලිමේන්තු මන්ත්‍රී ධම්මික පෙරේරා ප්‍රකාශ කර ඇත්තේ ණය ලබාගෙන විදේශ විනිමය ගෙන ඒම තම අපේක්ෂාව බවයි.",
        "ඔහු මේ බව ප්‍රකාශ කළේ අද (22) ශ්‍රී ලංකා පොදුජන පෙරමුණේ ජාතික ලැයිස්තු මන්ත්‍රීවරයෙකු ලෙස දිවුරුම් දීමෙන් අනතුරුව මාධ්‍ය වෙත අදහස් දක්වමින්.",
        "“ශ්‍රී ලංකාව නැවත ගොඩනැංවිය හැකි බව මම දනිමි, මිනිසුන්ට රැකියා අහිමි වන රටක, මම මෙහි සිටින්නේ රැකියා උත්පාදනය කිරීමට ය. පාරට බැහැලා කෑගහනවා වෙනුවට පාර්ලිමේන්තුවට ඇවිත් මම මගේ යුතුකම ඉටු කරනවා කියලා මට හිතෙනවා. යුද්ධය පැවති කාලයේ මම ආර්ථික කමිටුවේ හිටියා, ඒ කාලයට සාපේක්ෂව මේක ලොකු අභියෝගයක් නෙවෙයි,” ඔහු සඳහන් කළේය.",
        "පෙරේරා වැඩිදුරටත් සඳහන් කළේ තමන් දැනට මොරටුව විශ්වවිද්‍යාලයේ තොරතුරු තාක්ෂණ ක්ෂේත්‍රයේ ඔන්ලයින් වැඩසටහනක් පවත්වන බවත් ඒ යටතේ සිසුන් 90,000කට අධික පිරිසක් අධ්‍යාපනය ලබන බවත්ය.",
        "“මම මොරටුව විශ්වවිද්‍යාලයේ සත්කාරකත්වය දරන තොරතුරු තාක්ෂණ වැඩසටහන යටතේ සිසුන් 90,000කට අධික පිරිසක් අධ්‍යාපනය ලබනවා. මේවා මගේ ජයග්‍රහණවලින් කිහිපයක් වන අතර මෙම අත්දැකීමත් සමඟ අනාගත පරම්පරාවේ වෙනසක් ඇති කළ හැකි බව මට හැඟේ, ”පෙරේරා පැවසීය.",
        "පෙරේරා පසුගියදා බැසිල් රාජපක්ෂ මහතාට කතා කළේ දැයි මාධ්‍යවේදීන් කළ විමසීමකදී ඔහු කියා සිටියේ රාජපක්ෂ මහතා ඉල්ලා අස්වී තමාව භාර ගැනීමට නම් කිරීම සම්බන්ධයෙන් තමන් ස්තූතිවන්ත වන බවයි.",
        "\"බැසිල් රාජපක්ෂ මට නාමයෝජනා දීලා තිබුණා, මේ ආසනය වෙන කෙනෙකුට දෙන්නයි තිබුණේ, නමුත් බැසිල් තමයි මට එන්න කිව්වේ. මහින්ද රාජපක්ෂ තවම මාව මුණගැහිලා නැහැ, නමුත් මම අද එතුමාව බලන්න යන්න හිතාගෙන ඉන්නවා\" පෙරේරා මහතා පැවසීය.",
        "පාර්ලිමේන්තු මන්ත්‍රීවරයෙකු ලෙස එක්වී අමාත්‍ය ධූරයක් භාරගැනීමෙන් ගිලෙන නැවකට පා තබන බවක් දැනෙන්නේදැයි ඇසූ විට පෙරේරා කියා සිටියේ රට ගිලෙන නැවක් ලෙස තමාට නොහැඟෙන බවයි.",
        "“කිසිවෙකු ගිලෙන නැවකට නොයයි. කවුරුවත් ඒ වගේ මෝඩ තීරණ ගන්නේ නැහැ. ශ්‍රී ලංකාව ගිලෙන නැවක් නොවන බවත් වෙනසක් ඇති කිරීමට මට හැකියාව තිබෙන නිසාත් මම මේ අභියෝගය භාර ගත්තා. ඉදිරි සති 2 තුළ ආර්ථික සහන සැලැස්මක් සඳහා මගේ වාර්තාව සහ යෝජනා ඉදිරිපත් කිරීමට අදහස් කරමි. අපි එතනින් උඩට ගමු” පෙරේරා අවසන් කළේය."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ධම්මික පෙරේරා",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "බැසිල් රාජපක්ෂ",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "බැසිල් රාජපක්ෂ",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "බැසිල්",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "SLPP ජාතික",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ධම්මික පෙරේරා",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "22",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "පෙරේරා",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "මොරටුව විශ්වවිද්‍යාලය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "මොරටුව විශ්වවිද්‍යාලය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "90,000 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "පෙරේරා",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "පෙරේරා",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "බැසිල් රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "බැසිල් රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "බැසිල්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "මහින්ද රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "පෙරේරා",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "පෙරේරා",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "එක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉදිරි සති 2",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "පෙරේරා",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "பசில் ராஜபக்சவுக்கு நன்றி தெரிவிப்பதாக தம்மிக பெரேரா தெரிவித்துள்ளார்: பசில் ராஜபக்ஷ என்னை நியமித்தார், இந்த ஆசனம் வேறு ஒருவருக்கு வழங்கப்பட வேண்டும், ஆனால் பசில் தான் என்னை அதில் நுழையச் சொன்னார்\" என்று எஸ்.எல்.பி.பி புதிய தேசிய பட்டியல் எம்.பி.",
      "author": "நிர்வாகி",
      "body_lines": [
        "டொலர்களை கொண்டு வருவதே சிறந்த செயலாகும் என தெரிவித்துள்ள புதிய பாராளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர் தம்மிக பெரேரா, கடன் பெற்று அந்நிய செலாவணியை கொண்டு வருவதே தனது நோக்கம் என தெரிவித்துள்ளார்.",
        "ஸ்ரீலங்கா பொதுஜன பெரமுனவின் தேசிய பட்டியல் பாராளுமன்ற உறுப்பினராக இன்று (22) சத்தியப்பிரமாணம் செய்து கொண்டதன் பின்னர் ஊடகங்களுக்கு கருத்து தெரிவிக்கும் போதே அவர் இதனை தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "\"இலங்கையை மீண்டும் வளர்க்க முடியும் என்பதை நான் அறிவேன், மக்கள் வேலைகளை இழக்கும் நாட்டில், வேலைகளை உருவாக்க நான் இங்கு வந்துள்ளேன். தெருக்களில் கூச்சலிடுவதை விடுத்து, பாராளுமன்றத்திற்குள் நுழைவதன் மூலம் எனது கடமைகளை நிறைவேற்றுவதாக உணர்கிறேன். போரின் போது நான் பொருளாதாரக் குழுவில் இருந்தேன், அந்தக் காலத்துடன் ஒப்பிடுகையில் இது பெரிய சவாலாக இல்லை” என்று அவர் குறிப்பிட்டார்.",
        "தற்போது மொரட்டுவ பல்கலைக்கழகத்தில் தகவல் தொழிநுட்ப துறையில் ஆன்லைன் நிகழ்ச்சியை நடத்துவதாகவும், 90,000 மாணவர்கள் இதன் கீழ் கல்வி கற்று வருவதாகவும் பெரேரா மேலும் குறிப்பிட்டார்.",
        "“நான் மொரட்டுவ பல்கலைக்கழகத்தில் நடத்தும் தகவல் தொழில்நுட்பத் திட்டத்தின் கீழ் 90,000 மாணவர்கள் கல்வி கற்று வருகின்றனர். இவை எனது சில சாதனைகள் மற்றும் இந்த அனுபவத்தின் மூலம், எதிர்கால சந்ததியினருக்கு மாற்றத்தை கொண்டு வர முடியும் என்று நான் உணர்கிறேன், ”என்று பெரேரா கூறினார்.",
        "பெரேரா அண்மையில் பசில் ராஜபக்சவுடன் பேசியதா என ஊடகவியலாளர்கள் வினவியபோது, ​​ராஜபக்ச ராஜபக்ஷவை பதவியில் இருந்து விலகி பதவியேற்க பரிந்துரைத்தமைக்கு நன்றி தெரிவிப்பதாக அவர் கூறினார்.",
        "பசில் ராஜபக்ஷ என்னை நியமித்திருந்தார், இந்த ஆசனம் வேறு ஒருவருக்கு வழங்கப்பட வேண்டும், ஆனால் என்னை உள்ளே நுழையச் சொன்னது பசில் தான். மகிந்த ராஜபக்ச இதுவரை என்னைச் சந்திக்கவில்லை, ஆனால் இன்று அவரைச் சந்திக்க உள்ளேன். பெரேரா தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "பாராளுமன்ற உறுப்பினராக இணைந்து அமைச்சர் பதவியை ஏற்றுக்கொண்டதன் மூலம் மூழ்கும் கப்பலில் அடியெடுத்து வைப்பதாக நீங்கள் கருதுகிறீர்களா என்று கேட்டதற்கு, பெரேரா, நாடு மூழ்கும் கப்பலாக உணரவில்லை என்று கூறினார்.",
        "“முங்கும் கப்பலுக்குள் யாரும் நடப்பதில்லை. யாரும் முட்டாள்தனமான முடிவுகளை எடுப்பதில்லை. இலங்கை மூழ்கும் கப்பல் அல்ல என்பதை உணர்ந்து, மாற்றத்தை கொண்டு வர முடிந்ததால் இந்த சவாலை நான் ஏற்றுக்கொண்டேன். அடுத்த 2 வாரங்களுக்குள் பொருளாதார நிவாரணத் திட்டத்திற்கான எனது அறிக்கை மற்றும் பரிந்துரைகளை சமர்ப்பிக்க உள்ளேன். அங்கிருந்து எடுத்துச் செல்வோம்” என்று பெரேரா முடித்தார்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "தம்மிக்க பெரேரா",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "பசில் ராஜபக்ஷ",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "பசில் ராஜபக்ஷ",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "துளசி",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "SLPP தேசிய",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "தம்மிக்க பெரேரா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "22",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பெரேரா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "மொரட்டுவ பல்கலைக்கழகம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "மொரட்டுவ பல்கலைக்கழகம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "90,000",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "பெரேரா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பெரேரா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "பசில் ராஜபக்ஷ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ராஜபக்சே",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பசில் ராஜபக்ஷ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "துளசி",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "மஹிந்த ராஜபக்ஷ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "பெரேரா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "பெரேரா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஒன்று",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "அடுத்த 2 வாரங்கள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "பெரேரா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}