{
  "newspaper_id": "ada-derana-lk",
  "url": "http://www.adaderana.lk/news/84742/main-framework-for-ceb-reforms-presented-to-cabinet-by-month-end",
  "time_ut": 1662292920,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Main framework for CEB reforms presented to Cabinet by month-end",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Main framework for CEB reforms presented to Cabinet by month-end",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "Minister of Power and Energy Kanchana Wijesekera says he met with members of the committee appointed to propose reforms to the Ceylon Electricity Board (CEB) to discuss their proposals, this morning (04).",
        "He said the committee has met with development agencies, experts in the sector, stakeholders and that it will meet with political parties and the Public Utilities Commission of Sri Lanka (PUCSL) next week.",
        "The main framework for the proposed reforms will be presented to the Cabinet of Ministers by the end of the month, the minister said in a tweet."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "CEB",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "Cabinet",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "month-end",
          "label": "DATE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "the Ceylon Electricity Board",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "this morning",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "04",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the Public Utilities Commission of Sri Lanka",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "PUCSL",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "next week",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the Cabinet of Ministers",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the end of the month",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "ලංවිම ප්‍රතිසංස්කරණ සඳහා වන ප්‍රධාන රාමුව මාසය අවසානයේ කැබිනට් මණ්ඩලයට ඉදිරිපත් කෙරේ",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "ලංකා විදුලිබල මණ්ඩලයට ප්‍රතිසංස්කරණ යෝජනා කිරීම සඳහා පත්කළ කමිටුවේ සාමාජිකයින් ඔවුන්ගේ යෝජනා සාකච්ඡා කිරීම සඳහා අද (04) පෙරවරුවේ තමන් හමුවූ බව විදුලිබල හා බලශක්ති අමාත්‍ය කාංචන විජේසේකර මහතා පවසයි.",
        "මෙම කමිටුව සංවර්ධන නියෝජිතායතන, ක්ෂේත්‍රයේ ප්‍රවීණයන්, පාර්ශවකරුවන් හමුවී ඇති අතර එය ලබන සතියේ දේශපාලන පක්ෂ සහ ශ්‍රී ලංකා මහජන උපයෝගිතා කොමිෂන් සභාව (PUCSL) හමුවීමට නියමිත බව ඔහු පැවසීය.",
        "යෝජිත ප්‍රතිසංස්කරණ සඳහා වන ප්‍රධාන රාමුව මාසය අවසන් වන විට අමාත්‍ය මණ්ඩලයට ඉදිරිපත් කරන බව අමාත්‍යවරයා ට්විටර් පණිවුඩයක් නිකුත් කරමින් කියා සිටියේය."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ලංවිම",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "මණ්ඩල",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "මාස අග",
          "label": "DATE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ලංකා විදුලිබල මණ්ඩලය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "මේ උදෑසන",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "04",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකා මහජන උපයෝගිතා කොමිෂන් සභාව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "PUCSL",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඊළඟ සතිය",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "අමාත්ය මණ්ඩලය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "මාසයේ අවසානය",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "CEB சீர்திருத்தங்களுக்கான முக்கிய கட்டமைப்பு மாத இறுதிக்குள் அமைச்சரவைக்கு வழங்கப்பட்டது",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "இலங்கை மின்சார சபையில் சீர்திருத்தங்களை முன்மொழிவதற்காக நியமிக்கப்பட்ட குழுவின் உறுப்பினர்களை இன்று (04) காலை சந்தித்ததாக மின்சக்தி மற்றும் எரிசக்தி அமைச்சர் காஞ்சன விஜேசேகர தெரிவித்துள்ளார்.",
        "அபிவிருத்தி முகவர் நிலையங்கள், துறைசார் நிபுணர்கள், பங்குதாரர்களை இந்தக் குழு சந்தித்துள்ளதாகவும், அரசியல் கட்சிகள் மற்றும் இலங்கை பொதுப் பயன்பாடுகள் ஆணைக்குழு (PUCSL) ஆகியோரை அடுத்த வாரம் சந்திக்கவுள்ளதாகவும் அவர் கூறினார்.",
        "முன்மொழியப்பட்ட சீர்திருத்தங்களுக்கான முக்கிய கட்டமைப்பு இந்த மாத இறுதிக்குள் அமைச்சரவைக்கு சமர்ப்பிக்கப்படும் என்று அமைச்சர் ஒரு ட்வீட்டில் தெரிவித்தார்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "CEB",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "மந்திரி சபை",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "மாத இறுதி",
          "label": "DATE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை மின்சார சபை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று காலை",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "04",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கையின் பொதுப் பயன்பாடுகள் ஆணைக்குழு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "PUCSL",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "அடுத்த வாரம்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "அமைச்சர்கள் அமைச்சரவை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "மாத இறுதியில்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}