{
  "newspaper_id": "ada-derana-lk",
  "url": "http://www.adaderana.lk/news/83673/india-hoping-for-early-solution-for-sri-lankan-crisis-through-democratic-means",
  "time_ut": 1657897800,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "India hoping for early solution for Sri Lankan crisis through democratic means",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "India hoping for early solution for Sri Lankan crisis through democratic means",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "As Sri Lanka reels under political and economic crisis, India on Thursday hoped for an early solution to the crisis related to the government and its leadership through democratic means and the constitutional framework.",
        "Asserting that ensuring peace and stability of all countries in the region was an important aspect of its ‘Neighbourhood First’ policy, MEA Spokesperson Arindam Bagchi, at his weekly media briefing, said India continued to stand with the Lankan people and it remained engaged with all relevant stakeholders in that country.",
        "The comments by the Ministry of External Affairs (MEA) came on a day outgoing Sri Lankan President Gotabaya Rajapaksa landed in Singapore from the Maldives, a day after he fled from the island nation in the face of massive mass protests.",
        "Also on Thursday, the Indian High Commission in Male described as “baseless” the reports suggesting that the government of India was involved in the reported transit of Rajapaksa through the Maldives.",
        "“We will continue to stand with the people of Sri Lanka as they seek to realise their aspirations for prosperity and progress through democratic means and values as well as established institutions and constitutional framework,” Bagchi said.",
        "The MEA spokesperson said ensuring peace, stability and prosperity of all countries in the region is an important aspect of India’s ‘Neighbourhood First Policy’ as well as its vision for security and growth for all.",
        "“This is also in the case of Sri Lanka and is clearly evident in the close and multifaceted relationship that we have with that country and the commitment we have demonstrated in helping the Sri Lankan people,” he said.",
        "Bagchi was replying to a volley of questions on the situation in Sri Lanka during a media briefing.",
        "“We are monitoring the evolving situation in that country. Our ties with Sri Lanka are historic and comprehensive and we continue to engage with all relevant stakeholders in Sri Lanka,” Bagchi added.",
        "“We look forward to an early solution of the situation related to the government and its leadership through democratic means and values and established institution and constitutional framework,” he added.",
        "The spokesperson said Sri Lanka needs to “find a way forward, they need to find a solution ahead.”",
        "“We are there to support the people of Sri Lanka whichever way we can and we have demonstrated that with our economic assistance,” Bagchi added.",
        "India has extended this year’s support of over USD 3.8 billion to Sri Lanka to help it deal with the economic crisis.",
        "Sri Lanka witnessed massive political turmoil in the last few days.",
        "Rajapaksa and his wife fled to the Maldives on Wednesday bowing to months of mass protests over the island nation’s worst economic crisis in decades.",
        "He appointed Prime Minister Ranil Wickremesinghe as the acting President who later declared a nationwide state of emergency and ordered the military and police to do whatever is required to restore law and order in the country.",
        "Rajapaksa flew to Singapore from The Maldives on Thursday. A spokesperson for the Singapore Ministry of Foreign Affairs confirmed that Rajapaksa has been “allowed entry into Singapore on a private visit”."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "India",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "Sri Lankan",
          "label": "NORP"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "India",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Thursday",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Spokesperson Arindam Bagchi",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "weekly",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "India",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Lankan",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the Ministry of External Affairs",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "MEA",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lankan",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "Gotabaya Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Singapore",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Maldives",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "a day",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Thursday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Indian High Commission",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "India",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Rajapaksa",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Maldives",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Bagchi",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "MEA",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "India",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lankan",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "India",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "year",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "over USD 3.8 billion",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the last few days",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Maldives",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Wednesday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "months",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "decades",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Rajapaksa",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Singapore",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Thursday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Singapore Ministry of Foreign Affairs",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Rajapaksa",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Singapore",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "ප්‍රජාතන්ත්‍රවාදී ක්‍රම මගින් ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ අර්බුදයට කඩිනමින් විසඳුමක් ලබා ගැනීමට ඉන්දියාව බලාපොරොත්තු වේ",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකාව දේශපාලන හා ආර්ථික අර්බුදයකට මැදිව සිටින විට, ප්‍රජාතන්ත්‍රවාදී මාධ්‍යයන් සහ ව්‍යවස්ථාමය රාමුව හරහා රජය සහ එහි නායකත්වය සම්බන්ධ අර්බුදයට ඉක්මන් විසඳුමක් ලබා ගැනීමට ඉන්දියාව බ්‍රහස්පතින්දා බලාපොරොත්තු විය.",
        "කලාපයේ සියලුම රටවල සාමය සහ ස්ථාවරත්වය සහතික කිරීම එහි 'අසල්වැසි ප්‍රථම' ප්‍රතිපත්තියේ වැදගත් අංගයක් බව ප්‍රකාශ කරමින් MEA ප්‍රකාශක Arindam Bagchi සිය සතිපතා මාධ්‍ය හමුවේදී කියා සිටියේ ඉන්දියාව අඛණ්ඩව ලංකා ජනතාව සමඟ සිටින බවත් එය සියලු දෙනා සමඟ අඛණ්ඩව කටයුතු කරන බවත්ය. එම රටේ අදාළ පාර්ශවකරුවන්.",
        "විදේශ කටයුතු අමාත්‍යාංශයේ (MEA) ප්‍රකාශය සිදුවූයේ දැවැන්ත මහජන විරෝධතා හමුවේ දිවයිනෙන් පලා ගොස් දිනකට පසු ශ්‍රී ලංකා ජනාධිපති ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ මහතා මාලදිවයිනේ සිට සිංගප්පූරුවට ගොඩ බැස දිනයේදීය.",
        "බ්‍රහස්පතින්දා ද මාලේ හි ඉන්දීය මහ කොමසාරිස් කාර්යාලය විස්තර කළේ රාජපක්ෂ මාලදිවයින හරහා වාර්තා කළ සංක්‍රමණයට ඉන්දීය රජය සම්බන්ධ බවට පළ වූ වාර්තා “පදනම් විරහිත” ඒවා ලෙසයි.",
        "\"ප්‍රජාතන්ත්‍රවාදී මාධ්‍යයන් සහ සාරධර්ම මෙන්ම ස්ථාපිත ආයතන සහ ව්‍යවස්ථාමය රාමුව හරහා ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ ජනතාව සෞභාග්‍යය සහ ප්‍රගතිය සඳහා වූ ඔවුන්ගේ අභිලාෂයන් සාක්ෂාත් කර ගැනීමට උත්සාහ කරන බැවින් අපි ඔවුන් සමඟ දිගටම පෙනී සිටිමු\" යනුවෙන් බග්චි පැවසීය.",
        "MEA ප්‍රකාශකයා පැවසුවේ කලාපයේ සියලුම රටවල සාමය, ස්ථාවරත්වය සහ සමෘද්ධිය සහතික කිරීම ඉන්දියාවේ 'අසල්වැසි පළමු ප්‍රතිපත්තියේ' වැදගත් අංගයක් මෙන්ම සැමට ආරක්ෂාව සහ වර්ධනය සඳහා වන එහි දැක්ම බවයි.",
        "\"මෙය ශ්‍රී ලංකාව සම්බන්ධයෙන්ද වන අතර එම රට සමඟ අප සතුව ඇති සමීප සහ බහුවිධ සබඳතාවයෙන් සහ ශ්‍රී ලාංකික ජනතාවට උපකාර කිරීම සඳහා අප විසින් පෙන්නුම් කර ඇති කැපවීමෙන් පැහැදිලිවම පැහැදිලි වේ,\" ඔහු පැවසීය.",
        "මාධ්‍ය හමුවකදී ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ තත්ත්වය පිළිබඳ ප්‍රශ්න මාලාවකට පිළිතුරු දෙමින් බග්චි මේ බව කියා සිටියේය.",
        "“අපි ඒ රටේ වර්ධනය වෙමින් පවතින තත්ත්වය නිරීක්ෂණය කරනවා. ශ්‍රී ලංකාව සමඟ අපගේ සබඳතා ඓතිහාසික හා විස්තීර්ණ වන අතර ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ සියලුම අදාළ පාර්ශ්වකරුවන් සමඟ අපි දිගටම කටයුතු කරන්නෙමු, ”බග්චි වැඩිදුරටත් පැවසීය.",
        "\"ප්‍රජාතන්ත්‍රවාදී ක්‍රම සහ සාරධර්ම සහ ස්ථාපිත ආයතන සහ ව්‍යවස්ථාමය රාමුව හරහා රජයට සහ එහි නායකත්වයට අදාළ තත්ත්වයට ඉක්මන් විසඳුමක් ලබා ගැනීමට අපි බලාපොරොත්තු වෙනවා\" යැයි ඔහු වැඩිදුරටත් පැවසීය.",
        "ප්‍රකාශකයා පැවසුවේ ශ්‍රී ලංකාව “ඉදිරියට මගක් සෙවිය යුතු බවත්, ඔවුන් ඉදිරියෙන් විසඳුමක් සෙවිය යුතු බවත්” ය.",
        "\"අපට හැකි ඕනෑම ආකාරයකින් ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ ජනතාවට සහාය වීමට අපි එහි සිටින අතර අපගේ ආර්ථික ආධාර සමඟ අපි එය ඔප්පු කර ඇත්තෙමු,\" බග්චි වැඩිදුරටත් පැවසීය.",
        "ආර්ථික අර්බුදයට මුහුණ දීම සඳහා ඉන්දියාව මේ වසරේ ශ්‍රී ලංකාවට ඩොලර් බිලියන 3.8 කට අධික ආධාර ලබා දී ඇත.",
        "පසුගිය දින කිහිපය තුළ ශ්‍රී ලංකාව දැවැන්ත දේශපාලන කැළඹීමක් දුටුවේය.",
        "රාජපක්ෂ සහ ඔහුගේ බිරිඳ බදාදා මාලදිවයිනට පලා ගියේ දශක ගණනාවකට පසු දිවයිනේ දරුණුතම ආර්ථික අර්බුදය සම්බන්ධයෙන් මාස ගණනාවක් තිස්සේ පැවති මහජන විරෝධතාවලට හිස නමමිනි.",
        "ඔහු අගමැති රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ වැඩබලන ජනාධිපතිවරයා ලෙස පත්කළ අතර පසුව රටපුරා හදිසි නීතිය ප්‍රකාශයට පත් කළ ඔහු රටේ නීතිය හා සාමය යථා තත්ත්වයට පත් කිරීමට අවශ්‍ය ඕනෑම දෙයක් කරන ලෙස හමුදාවට සහ පොලිසියට නියෝග කළේය.",
        "රාජපක්ෂ බ්‍රහස්පතින්දා මාලදිවයිනේ සිට සිංගප්පූරුවට පියාසර කළේය. සිංගප්පූරු විදේශ කටයුතු අමාත්‍යාංශයේ ප්‍රකාශකයෙකු තහවුරු කළේ රාජපක්ෂට “පෞද්ගලික සංචාරයක් සඳහා සිංගප්පූරුවට ඇතුළු වීමට අවසර දී ඇති” බවයි."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ඉන්දියාව",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "ශ්‍රී ලාංකික",
          "label": "NORP"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "බ්රහස්පතින්දා",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ප්‍රකාශක Arindam Bagchi",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "සතිපතා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ලාංකික",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "විදේශ කටයුතු අමාත්‍යාංශය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "MEA",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලාංකික",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "සිංගප්පූරුව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මාලදිවයින",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "දවසක්",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "බ්රහස්පතින්දා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දීය මහ කොමසාරිස් කාර්යාලය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මාලදිවයින",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "බග්චි",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "MEA",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලාංකික",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "වර්ෂය",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "USD බිලියන 3.8 කට වඩා",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "පසුගිය දින කිහිපය",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "මාලදිවයින",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "බදාදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මාස",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "දශක",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "සිංගප්පූරුව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "බ්රහස්පතින්දා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "සිංගප්පූරු විදේශ කටයුතු අමාත්‍යාංශය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "සිංගප්පූරුව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "இலங்கை நெருக்கடிக்கு ஜனநாயக வழிவகைகள் மூலம் விரைவில் தீர்வு கிடைக்கும் என இந்தியா எதிர்பார்க்கிறது",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "இலங்கை அரசியல் மற்றும் பொருளாதார நெருக்கடியில் சிக்கித் தவிக்கும் நிலையில், அரசாங்கம் மற்றும் அதன் தலைமை தொடர்பான நெருக்கடிக்கு ஜனநாயக வழிமுறைகள் மற்றும் அரசியலமைப்பு கட்டமைப்பின் மூலம் விரைவில் தீர்வு கிடைக்கும் என்று இந்தியா வியாழன் அன்று நம்புகிறது.",
        "பிராந்தியத்தில் உள்ள அனைத்து நாடுகளின் அமைதி மற்றும் ஸ்திரத்தன்மையை உறுதிப்படுத்துவது அதன் 'அண்டை நாடுகளுக்கு முன்னுரிமை' கொள்கையின் முக்கிய அம்சமாகும் என்று வலியுறுத்தினார், MEA செய்தித் தொடர்பாளர் அரிந்தம் பாக்சி, தனது வாராந்திர ஊடக சந்திப்பில், இந்தியா தொடர்ந்து இலங்கை மக்களுடன் நிற்கிறது என்றும் அது அனைவருடனும் ஈடுபட்டுள்ளது என்றும் கூறினார். அந்த நாட்டில் தொடர்புடைய பங்குதாரர்கள்.",
        "வெளிவிவகார அமைச்சின் (MEA) கருத்துக்கள், இலங்கை ஜனாதிபதி கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ஷ, மாலைதீவில் இருந்து சிங்கப்பூர் வந்திறங்கிய ஒரு நாளில், பாரிய வெகுஜன எதிர்ப்புகளுக்கு முகங்கொடுத்து தீவு நாட்டிலிருந்து தப்பியோடிய ஒரு நாளுக்குப் பிறகு வந்தன.",
        "வியாழனன்று, மாலேவில் உள்ள இந்திய உயர் ஸ்தானிகராலயம், மாலத்தீவுகள் வழியாக ராஜபக்சேவைக் கடத்துவதில் இந்திய அரசாங்கம் ஈடுபட்டதாகக் கூறப்படும் அறிக்கைகள் \"ஆதாரமற்றவை\" என்று விவரித்தது.",
        "\"ஜனநாயக வழிமுறைகள் மற்றும் விழுமியங்கள் மற்றும் நிறுவப்பட்ட நிறுவனங்கள் மற்றும் அரசியலமைப்பு கட்டமைப்பின் மூலம் செழிப்பு மற்றும் முன்னேற்றத்திற்கான அவர்களின் அபிலாஷைகளை நனவாக்க இலங்கை மக்களுடன் நாங்கள் தொடர்ந்து நிற்போம்\" என்று பாக்சி கூறினார்.",
        "MEA செய்தித் தொடர்பாளர், பிராந்தியத்தில் உள்ள அனைத்து நாடுகளின் அமைதி, ஸ்திரத்தன்மை மற்றும் செழிப்பை உறுதி செய்வது இந்தியாவின் 'அண்டை நாடு முதல் கொள்கை' மற்றும் அனைவருக்கும் பாதுகாப்பு மற்றும் வளர்ச்சிக்கான அதன் பார்வையின் முக்கிய அம்சமாகும்.",
        "\"இது இலங்கையின் விஷயத்திலும் உள்ளது மற்றும் அந்த நாட்டுடன் நாம் கொண்டுள்ள நெருக்கமான மற்றும் பன்முக உறவுகள் மற்றும் இலங்கை மக்களுக்கு உதவுவதில் நாங்கள் வெளிப்படுத்திய அர்ப்பணிப்பு ஆகியவற்றில் இது தெளிவாகத் தெரிகிறது,\" என்று அவர் கூறினார்.",
        "ஊடகவியலாளர் சந்திப்பின் போது இலங்கையின் நிலைமை குறித்த சரமாரியான கேள்விகளுக்கு பதிலளித்த பாக்சி இவ்வாறு கூறினார்.",
        "“அந்த நாட்டில் உருவாகி வரும் சூழ்நிலையை நாங்கள் கண்காணித்து வருகிறோம். இலங்கையுடனான எங்கள் உறவுகள் வரலாற்று மற்றும் விரிவானது மற்றும் இலங்கையில் தொடர்புடைய அனைத்து பங்குதாரர்களுடனும் நாங்கள் தொடர்ந்து ஈடுபடுகிறோம், ”என்று பாக்சி மேலும் கூறினார்.",
        "\"ஜனநாயக வழிமுறைகள் மற்றும் விழுமியங்கள் மற்றும் நிறுவப்பட்ட அமைப்பு மற்றும் அரசியலமைப்பு கட்டமைப்பின் மூலம் அரசாங்கம் மற்றும் அதன் தலைமை தொடர்பான சூழ்நிலைக்கு விரைவில் தீர்வு காண நாங்கள் எதிர்நோக்குகிறோம்,\" என்று அவர் மேலும் கூறினார்.",
        "இலங்கை \"முன்னோக்கி செல்லும் வழியைக் கண்டுபிடிக்க வேண்டும், அவர்கள் ஒரு தீர்வைக் கண்டுபிடிக்க வேண்டும்\" என்று பேச்சாளர் கூறினார்.",
        "\"இலங்கை மக்களுக்கு எங்களால் இயன்ற வழிகளில் ஆதரவளிக்க நாங்கள் இருக்கிறோம், எங்கள் பொருளாதார உதவியின் மூலம் அதை நாங்கள் நிரூபித்துள்ளோம்\" என்று பாக்சி மேலும் கூறினார்.",
        "பொருளாதார நெருக்கடியைச் சமாளிக்க இந்தியா இந்த ஆண்டு 3.8 பில்லியன் அமெரிக்க டாலர்களை இலங்கைக்கு வழங்கியுள்ளது.",
        "இலங்கையில் கடந்த சில நாட்களாக பாரிய அரசியல் குழப்பங்கள் காணப்பட்டன.",
        "பல தசாப்தங்களில் தீவு நாட்டின் மோசமான பொருளாதார நெருக்கடி தொடர்பாக பல மாத வெகுஜன எதிர்ப்புகளுக்கு தலைவணங்கி ராஜபக்சேவும் அவரது மனைவியும் புதன்கிழமை மாலைதீவுக்கு தப்பிச் சென்றனர்.",
        "அவர் பிரதமர் ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்கவை தற்காலிக ஜனாதிபதியாக நியமித்தார், பின்னர் அவர் நாடு தழுவிய அவசரகால நிலையை பிரகடனப்படுத்தினார் மற்றும் நாட்டில் சட்டம் ஒழுங்கை மீட்டெடுக்க தேவையான அனைத்தையும் செய்ய இராணுவம் மற்றும் காவல்துறைக்கு உத்தரவிட்டார்.",
        "ராஜபக்சே மாலைதீவில் இருந்து சிங்கப்பூர் சென்றார். சிங்கப்பூர் வெளியுறவு அமைச்சகத்தின் செய்தித் தொடர்பாளர், ராஜபக்சே \"தனிப்பட்ட பயணமாக சிங்கப்பூருக்குள் நுழைய அனுமதிக்கப்பட்டார்\" என்று உறுதிப்படுத்தினார்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "இந்தியா",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "இலங்கை",
          "label": "NORP"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்தியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "வியாழன்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "செய்தி தொடர்பாளர் அரிந்தம் பாக்சி",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "வாரந்தோறும்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்தியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "வெளியுறவு அமைச்சகம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "MEA",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "சிங்கப்பூர்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "மாலத்தீவுகள்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஒரு நாள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "வியாழன்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்திய உயர் ஸ்தானிகராலயம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்தியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ராஜபக்சே",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "மாலத்தீவுகள்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாக்சி",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "MEA",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்தியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இந்தியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆண்டு",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "3.8 பில்லியன் அமெரிக்க டாலர்களுக்கு மேல்",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "கடந்த சில நாட்களாக",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ராஜபக்சே",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "மாலத்தீவுகள்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "புதன்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "மாதங்கள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "பத்தாண்டுகள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ராஜபக்சே",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சிங்கப்பூர்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "வியாழன்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சிங்கப்பூர் வெளியுறவு அமைச்சகம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ராஜபக்சே",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சிங்கப்பூர்",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}