{
  "newspaper_id": "lankadeepa-lk",
  "url": "https://www.lankadeepa.lk/latest_news/වල්අලි-ප්‍රහාරවලින්-ගොවියෝ-තුනක්-මරුට/1-616540",
  "time_ut": 1658039027,
  "original_lang": "si",
  "original_title": "වල්අලි ප්‍රහාරවලින් ගොවියෝ තුනක් මරුට",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Three farmers were killed by wild elephant attacks",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "The police say that three farmers have been killed in three wild elephant attacks in Polonnaruwa, Dimbulagala, Medirigiriya Navanagara and Saliyawewa Nilabamma Fort area.",
        "D.B.T.G., a resident of Madirigiriya Navanagara. Sarathchandra, a 65-year-old father of three, also 47-year-old D.M., a resident of Dimbulagala Palatia. Seneviratne Banda, a 47-year-old father of three, also a resident of Saliyawewa Neelabamma area, R.P.D. A 76-year-old farmer named Pemadasa has also died.",
        "DM The police also mention that Seneviratne Banda is the husband of a member of the Dimbulagala local council. He also works as an Institutional Development Officer at Weheragala Divisional Office in Mahaweli C Region. Yesterday at 2.30 this wild elephant was attacked while guarding the paddy fields to protect the paddy from the wild elephants coming to the field. He was attacked by elephants and was taken to Manampitiya Hospital by his neighbors and later transferred to Polonnaruwa Hospital for further treatment. The police say that he was dead when he was taken to the Polonnaruwa hospital.",
        "Sarathchandra, a father of three, who was attacked by wild elephants in Medirigiri Navanagara, went with a friend to Darshanapura to protect his farmland from wild elephants, when a wild elephant chased them.",
        "Later, they ran to a nearby house, but the police said that the elephant killed them when they fell while running.",
        "A farmer named Saliyawewa Pemadasa was attacked by wild elephants when he came out of his house for some need."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Three",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "three",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "three",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Polonnaruwa",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Dimbulagala",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Medirigiriya Navanagara",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Saliyawewa Nilabamma Fort",
            "label": "FAC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "D.B.T.G.",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Madirigiriya Navanagara",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "65-year-old",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "three",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "47-year-old",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "D.M.",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Dimbulagala Palatia",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Seneviratne Banda",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "47-year-old",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "three",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Saliyawewa Neelabamma",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "76-year-old",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Pemadasa",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Seneviratne Banda",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Dimbulagala",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Weheragala Divisional Office",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Mahaweli C Region",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Yesterday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "2.30",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Manampitiya Hospital",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Polonnaruwa Hospital",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Polonnaruwa",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "three",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Medirigiri Navanagara",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Darshanapura",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "Saliyawewa Pemadasa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "වල්අලි ප්‍රහාරවලින් ගොවියෝ තුනක් මරුට",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "පොලොන්නරුව දිඹුලාගල, මැදිරිගිරිය නවනගරයේදී සහ සාලියවැව නීලබැම්ම බලකොටුව ප්‍රදේශයේවලදී වල් අලි ප්‍රහාර තුනකින් ගොවියන් තිදෙනකු මියගොස් ඇතැයි  පොලිසිය කියයි.",
        "මැදිරිගිරිය නවනගරයේ පදිංචි ඩී.බී.ටී.ජී. සරත්චන්ද්‍ර නමැති 65 හැවිරිදි  තිදරු පියකු ද දිඹුලාගල පැලැටියාවවේ පදිංචි 47 හැවිරිදි ඩී.එම්. සෙනෙවිරත්න බණ්ඩා නමැති 47 හැවිරිදි තිදරු පියකු ද සාලියවැව නීලබැම්ම ප්‍රදේශයේ පදිංචි ආර්.පී.ඩී. පේමදාස  නමැති 76 හැවිරිදි ගොවියකු ද මෙසේ මියගොස් ඇත.",
        "ඩී.එම්. සෙනෙවිරත්න බණ්ඩා දිඹුලාගල ප්‍රාදේශීය සභාවේ මන්ත්‍රීවරියකගේ සැමියකු බවද  පොලිසිය සඳහන් කරයි. ඔහු මහවැලි සී කලාපයේ වෙහෙරගල කොට්ඨාස කාර්යාලයේ ආයතන සංවර්ධන නිලධාරියකු ලෙස ද කටයුතු කරයි. කුඹුරට පැමිණෙන වල් අලින්ගෙන් වී වගාව ආරක්ෂාකර ගැනීම සඳහා පැල් රකිමින් සිටියදි ඊයේ 2.30ට මෙම වල්අලි ප්‍රහාරයට ලක්ව ඇත. අලි ප්‍රවාරයට ලක්ව සිටි ඔහු අසල්වාසීන් විසින් මනම්පිටිය රෝහලට රැගෙන ගොස් ඇති අතර පසුව වැඩිදුර ප්‍රතිකාර සඳහා පොලොන්නරුව රෝහලට මාරු කර යවා ඇත. ඔහු පොලොන්නරුව රෝහලට රැගෙන යනවිට මියගොස් සිටි බව පොලිසිය කියයි.",
        "මැදිරිගිරිය නවනගරයේ වල්අලි ප්‍රහාරයට ලක් වූ සරත්චන්ද්‍ර නමැති තිදරු පියා  හිතවතකු සමග දර්ශනපුර සිය වගා බිම් වල් අලින්ගෙන් ආරක්ෂා කරගැනීමට ගිය අවස්ථාවේ වගා වනසමින් සිටි වල් අලියකු ඔවුන් පසුපස පන්නා ඇත.",
        "පසුව ඔවුන් අසල නිවෙසකට දිවගොස් ඇතත් මියගිය අය දිව යද්දී ඇද විටුණු අවස්ථාවේ වල්අලියා පහරදී මරා දමා ඇතැයි පොලිසිය පවසයි.",
        "සාලියවැව පේමදාස නමැති ගොවි මහතා කිසියම් අවශ්‍යාවයකට නිවසෙන් බැහැරට පැමිණි අවස්ථාවේ වල්අලි ප්‍රහාරයට ලක්ව ඇත."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "තුන්",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "තුන්",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "තුන්",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "පොළොන්නරුව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "දිඹුලාගල",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "මැදිරිගිරිය නවනගර",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "සාලියවැව නිලබම්මා කොටුව",
            "label": "FAC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ඩී.බී.ටී.ජී.",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "මැදිරිගිරිය නවනගර",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "65 හැවිරිදිය",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "තුන්",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "47 හැවිරිදිය",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඩී.එම්.",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "දිඹුලාගල පලාටිය",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "සෙනෙවිරත්න බණ්ඩා",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "47 හැවිරිදිය",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "තුන්",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "සාලියවැව නීලබම්මා",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "76 හැවිරිදිය",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "පේමදාස ය",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "සෙනෙවිරත්න බණ්ඩා",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "දිඹුලාගල",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "වෙහෙරගල ප්‍රාදේශීය කාර්යාලය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "මහවැලි සී කලාපය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඊයේ",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "2.30",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "මනම්පිටිය රෝහල",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "පොලොන්නරුව රෝහල",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "පොළොන්නරුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "තුන්",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "මැදිරිගිරි නවනගර",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "දර්ශනපුර",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "සාලියවැව පේමදාස",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "காட்டு யானை தாக்கி மூன்று விவசாயிகள் பலியாகினர்",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "பொலன்னறுவை, திம்புலாகல, மெதிரிகிரிய நவநகர மற்றும் சாலியவெவ நிலபம்மா கோட்டை பிரதேசங்களில் காட்டு யானைகள் தாக்கியதில் மூன்று விவசாயிகள் உயிரிழந்துள்ளதாக பொலிஸார் தெரிவிக்கின்றனர்.",
        "மாதிரிகிரிய நவநகரைச் சேர்ந்த டி.பி.டி.ஜி. மூன்று பிள்ளைகளின் தந்தையான 65 வயதான சரத்சந்திர, திம்புலாகல பலாட்டிய பகுதியைச் சேர்ந்த 47 வயதான டி.எம். செனவிரத்ன பண்டா, 47 வயதுடைய மூன்று பிள்ளைகளின் தந்தையும், சாலியவெவ நீலபம்மா பகுதியைச் சேர்ந்த ஆர்.பி.டி. 76 வயதான பேமதாச என்ற விவசாயியும் உயிரிழந்துள்ளார்.",
        "தி.மு.க செனவிரத்ன பண்டா திம்புலாகல உள்ளுராட்சி சபை உறுப்பினர் ஒருவரின் கணவர் எனவும் பொலிஸார் குறிப்பிடுகின்றனர். அவர் மகாவலி C பிராந்தியத்தில் உள்ள வெஹெரகல பிரதேச அலுவலகத்தில் நிறுவன அபிவிருத்தி அதிகாரியாகவும் பணியாற்றுகிறார். நேற்று பகல் 2.30 மணியளவில் வயலுக்கு வரும் காட்டு யானைகளிடம் இருந்து நெற்பயிர்களை பாதுகாக்கும் வகையில் வயல்களில் பாதுகாப்பு பணியில் ஈடுபட்டிருந்த போதே இந்த காட்டு யானை தாக்கியுள்ளது. யானைகளின் தாக்குதலுக்கு உள்ளான அவர், அயலவர்களால் மனம்பிட்டிய வைத்தியசாலைக்கு கொண்டு செல்லப்பட்டு மேலதிக சிகிச்சைக்காக பொலன்னறுவை வைத்தியசாலைக்கு மாற்றப்பட்டார். பொலன்னறுவை வைத்தியசாலைக்கு கொண்டு செல்லும் போது அவர் உயிரிழந்திருந்ததாக பொலிஸார் தெரிவிக்கின்றனர்.",
        "மெதிரிகிரி நவநகரில் காட்டு யானைகளின் தாக்குதலுக்கு உள்ளான மூன்று பிள்ளைகளின் தந்தையான சரத்சந்திர, தனது விவசாய நிலத்தை காட்டு யானைகளிடமிருந்து பாதுகாக்க தர்சனபுரத்திற்கு நண்பருடன் சென்ற போது, ​​காட்டு யானை அவர்களை துரத்தியுள்ளது.",
        "பின்னர், அவர்கள் அருகில் உள்ள வீட்டிற்கு ஓடினர், ஆனால் அவர்கள் ஓடும்போது விழுந்ததில் யானை அவர்களைக் கொன்றதாக போலீசார் தெரிவித்தனர்.",
        "சாலியவெவ பேமதாச என்ற விவசாயி, தேவைக்காக வீட்டில் இருந்து வெளியே வந்த போது காட்டு யானை தாக்குதலுக்கு உள்ளானார்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "மூன்று",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "மூன்று",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "மூன்று",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "பொலன்னறுவை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "திம்புலாகல",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "மெதிரிகிரிய நவநகர",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "சாலியவெவ நிலபம்மா கோட்டை",
            "label": "FAC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "டி.பி.டி.ஜி.",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "மாதிரிகிரிய நவநகர",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "65 வயது",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "மூன்று",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "47 வயது",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "டி.எம்.",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "திம்புலாகல பலாட்டிய",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "செனவிரத்ன பண்டா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "47 வயது",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "மூன்று",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "சாலியவெவ நீலபம்மா",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "76 வயதானவர்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "பேமதாச",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "செனவிரத்ன பண்டா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "திம்புலாகல",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "வெஹெரகல பிரதேச அலுவலகம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "மகாவலி சி பிராந்தியம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "நேற்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "2.30",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "மனம்பிட்டிய வைத்தியசாலை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "பொலன்னறுவை வைத்தியசாலை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "பொலன்னறுவை",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "மூன்று",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "மெதிரிகிரி நவநகர",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "தர்ஷனபுரா",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "சாலியவெவ பேமதாச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}