{
  "newspaper_id": "news-first-lk",
  "url": "https://www.newsfirst.lk/2022/06/24/welgama-released-from-bribery-case-ciaboc-says-it-reserved-right-to-re-file-case/",
  "time_ut": 1656057840,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "\nWelgama released from Bribery Case; CIABOC says it reserved right to re-file case",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Welgama released from Bribery Case; CIABOC says it reserved right to re-file case",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st): The Colombo Magistrate’s Court on Friday (24) ordered to release Ex-Minister Kumara Welgama from a case filed against by the Commission to Investigate Allegations of Bribery or Corruption.",
        "Welgama was charged with creating a non-existent position of Deputy Chairman at the Sri Lanka Transport Board and paying salaries to the tune of Rs. 3 Million for the said position, causing losses to the government.",
        "Colombo Chief Magistrate Nandana Amarasinghe ordered to release Kumara Welgama after the Bribery Commission said it would withdraw the case and reserved the right to re-file a case against Welgama.",
        "The Bribery Commission withdrew the case as it had not followed due process in filing the case, as it should obtain the signatures of all three commissioners to file a case.",
        "Welgama released from Bribery Case; CIABOC says it reserved right to re-file case"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Welgama",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "Bribery Case",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Friday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "24",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kumara Welgama",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Investigate Allegations of Bribery or Corruption",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Welgama",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Sri Lanka Transport Board",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "3 Million",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Kumara Welgama",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Bribery Commission",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Welgama",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "The Bribery Commission",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "three",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Welgama",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Bribery Case",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "අල්ලස් නඩුවෙන් වෙල්ගම නිදහස් CIABOC පවසන්නේ නඩුව නැවත ගොනු කිරීමට තමන්ට අයිතියක් ඇති බවයි",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st): අල්ලස් හෝ දූෂණ චෝදනා විමර්ශන කොමිෂන් සභාව විසින් පවරා ඇති නඩුවකින් හිටපු අමාත්‍ය කුමාර වෙල්ගම මහතා නිදහස් කිරීමට කොළඹ මහේස්ත්‍රාත් අධිකරණය සිකුරාදා (24) නියෝග කළේය.",
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකා ගමනාගමන මණ්ඩලයේ නොපවතින උප සභාපති තනතුරක් නිර්මාණය කර රුපියල් කෝටි 100 ක වැටුප් ගෙවීම සම්බන්ධයෙන් වෙල්ගමට චෝදනා එල්ල විය. රජයට පාඩු කරමින් එම තනතුර සඳහා මිලියන 3ක්.",
        "නඩුව ඉල්ලා අස්කර ගන්නා බව අල්ලස් කොමිසම ප්‍රකාශ කිරීමෙන් පසු කුමාර වෙල්ගම නිදහස් කරන ලෙස කොළඹ ප්‍රධාන මහේස්ත්‍රාත් නන්දන අමරසිංහ නියෝග කළ අතර වෙල්ගමට එරෙහිව යළි නඩුවක් පැවරීමේ අයිතියද ඔහු රඳවා ගත්තේය.",
        "නඩුවක් පැවරීම සඳහා කොමසාරිස්වරුන් තිදෙනාගේම අත්සන් ලබා ගත යුතු බැවින් අල්ලස් කොමිසම මෙම නඩුව ගොනු කිරීමේදී නිසි ක්‍රියා පටිපාටියක් අනුගමනය නොකළ නිසා එම නඩුව ඉල්ලා අස්කර ගත්තේය.",
        "අල්ලස් නඩුවෙන් වෙල්ගම නිදහස් CIABOC පවසන්නේ නඩුව නැවත ගොනු කිරීමට තමන්ට අයිතියක් ඇති බවයි"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "වෙල්ගම",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "අල්ලස් නඩුව",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "1 වැනි",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "සිකුරාදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "24",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "කුමාර වෙල්ගම",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "අල්ලස් හෝ දූෂණ චෝදනා විමර්ශනය කරන්න",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "වෙල්ගම",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකා ගමනාගමන මණ්ඩලය",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "මිලියන 3 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "කුමාර වෙල්ගම",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "අල්ලස් කොමිසම",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "වෙල්ගම",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "අල්ලස් කොමිසම",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "තුන්",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "වෙල්ගම",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "අල්ලස් නඩුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "இலஞ்ச வழக்கில் இருந்து வெல்கம விடுதலை; CIABOC வழக்கை மீண்டும் தாக்கல் செய்ய உரிமை உள்ளது என்று கூறுகிறது",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st): இலஞ்சம் அல்லது ஊழல் குற்றச்சாட்டுகளை விசாரணை செய்யும் ஆணைக்குழுவினால் தாக்கல் செய்யப்பட்ட வழக்கில் இருந்து முன்னாள் அமைச்சர் குமார வெல்கமவை விடுவிக்குமாறு கொழும்பு நீதவான் நீதிமன்றம் வெள்ளிக்கிழமை (24) உத்தரவிட்டுள்ளது.",
        "இலங்கை போக்குவரத்துச் சபையில் இல்லாத பிரதித் தலைவர் பதவியை உருவாக்கி ரூ.5000 சம்பளம் வழங்கியதாக வெல்கம மீது குற்றம் சுமத்தப்பட்டது. குறித்த பதவிக்கு 3 மில்லியன், அரசாங்கத்திற்கு நஷ்டம்.",
        "இந்த வழக்கை வாபஸ் பெறுவதாக இலஞ்ச ஊழல் ஆணைக்குழு தெரிவித்ததையடுத்து, வெல்கமவுக்கு எதிராக மீண்டும் வழக்குத் தாக்கல் செய்வதற்கான உரிமையை குமார வெல்கமவை விடுவிக்குமாறு கொழும்பு பிரதான நீதவான் நந்தன அமரசிங்க உத்தரவிட்டார்.",
        "வழக்குப் பதிவு செய்வதற்கு மூன்று ஆணையாளர்களிடமும் கையொப்பம் பெற வேண்டும் என்ற நிலையில், வழக்குப் பதிவு செய்வதில் உரிய நடைமுறையைப் பின்பற்றாததால், லஞ்ச ஊழல் ஆணைக்குழு வழக்கை வாபஸ் பெற்றது.",
        "இலஞ்ச வழக்கில் இருந்து வெல்கம விடுதலை; CIABOC வழக்கை மீண்டும் தாக்கல் செய்ய உரிமை உள்ளது என்று கூறுகிறது"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "வெல்கம",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "லஞ்ச வழக்கு",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "1வது",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "வெள்ளி",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "24",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "குமார வெல்கம",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "லஞ்சம் அல்லது ஊழல் குற்றச்சாட்டுகளை விசாரிக்கவும்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "வெல்கம",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை போக்குவரத்து சபை",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "3 மில்லியன்",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "குமார வெல்கம",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலஞ்ச ஆணைக்குழு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "வெல்கம",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலஞ்ச ஆணைக்குழு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "மூன்று",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "வெல்கம",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "லஞ்ச வழக்கு",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  },
  "title": "\nWelgama released from Bribery Case; CIABOC says it reserved right to re-file case",
  "body_lines": [
    "COLOMBO (News 1st): The Colombo Magistrate’s Court on Friday (24) ordered to release Ex-Minister Kumara Welgama from a case filed against by the Commission to Investigate Allegations of Bribery or Corruption.",
    "Welgama was charged with creating a non-existent position of Deputy Chairman at the Sri Lanka Transport Board and paying salaries to the tune of Rs. 3 Million for the said position, causing losses to the government.",
    "Colombo Chief Magistrate Nandana Amarasinghe ordered to release Kumara Welgama after the Bribery Commission said it would withdraw the case and reserved the right to re-file a case against Welgama.",
    "The Bribery Commission withdrew the case as it had not followed due process in filing the case, as it should obtain the signatures of all three commissioners to file a case.",
    "Welgama released from Bribery Case; CIABOC says it reserved right to re-file case"
  ],
  "translate": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Welgama released from Bribery Case; CIABOC says it reserved right to re-file case",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st): The Colombo Magistrate’s Court on Friday (24) ordered to release Ex-Minister Kumara Welgama from a case filed against by the Commission to Investigate Allegations of Bribery or Corruption.",
        "Welgama was charged with creating a non-existent position of Deputy Chairman at the Sri Lanka Transport Board and paying salaries to the tune of Rs. 3 Million for the said position, causing losses to the government.",
        "Colombo Chief Magistrate Nandana Amarasinghe ordered to release Kumara Welgama after the Bribery Commission said it would withdraw the case and reserved the right to re-file a case against Welgama.",
        "The Bribery Commission withdrew the case as it had not followed due process in filing the case, as it should obtain the signatures of all three commissioners to file a case.",
        "Welgama released from Bribery Case; CIABOC says it reserved right to re-file case"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Welgama",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "Bribery Case",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Friday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "24",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kumara Welgama",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Investigate Allegations of Bribery or Corruption",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Welgama",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Sri Lanka Transport Board",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "3 Million",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Kumara Welgama",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Bribery Commission",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Welgama",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "The Bribery Commission",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "three",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Welgama",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Bribery Case",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "අල්ලස් නඩුවෙන් වෙල්ගම නිදහස් CIABOC පවසන්නේ නඩුව නැවත ගොනු කිරීමට තමන්ට අයිතියක් ඇති බවයි",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st): අල්ලස් හෝ දූෂණ චෝදනා විමර්ශන කොමිෂන් සභාව විසින් පවරා ඇති නඩුවකින් හිටපු අමාත්‍ය කුමාර වෙල්ගම මහතා නිදහස් කිරීමට කොළඹ මහේස්ත්‍රාත් අධිකරණය සිකුරාදා (24) නියෝග කළේය.",
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකා ගමනාගමන මණ්ඩලයේ නොපවතින උප සභාපති තනතුරක් නිර්මාණය කර රුපියල් කෝටි 100 ක වැටුප් ගෙවීම සම්බන්ධයෙන් වෙල්ගමට චෝදනා එල්ල විය. රජයට පාඩු කරමින් එම තනතුර සඳහා මිලියන 3ක්.",
        "නඩුව ඉල්ලා අස්කර ගන්නා බව අල්ලස් කොමිසම ප්‍රකාශ කිරීමෙන් පසු කුමාර වෙල්ගම නිදහස් කරන ලෙස කොළඹ ප්‍රධාන මහේස්ත්‍රාත් නන්දන අමරසිංහ නියෝග කළ අතර වෙල්ගමට එරෙහිව යළි නඩුවක් පැවරීමේ අයිතියද ඔහු රඳවා ගත්තේය.",
        "නඩුවක් පැවරීම සඳහා කොමසාරිස්වරුන් තිදෙනාගේම අත්සන් ලබා ගත යුතු බැවින් අල්ලස් කොමිසම මෙම නඩුව ගොනු කිරීමේදී නිසි ක්‍රියා පටිපාටියක් අනුගමනය නොකළ නිසා එම නඩුව ඉල්ලා අස්කර ගත්තේය.",
        "අල්ලස් නඩුවෙන් වෙල්ගම නිදහස් CIABOC පවසන්නේ නඩුව නැවත ගොනු කිරීමට තමන්ට අයිතියක් ඇති බවයි"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "වෙල්ගම",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "අල්ලස් නඩුව",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "1 වැනි",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "සිකුරාදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "24",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "කුමාර වෙල්ගම",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "අල්ලස් හෝ දූෂණ චෝදනා විමර්ශනය කරන්න",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "වෙල්ගම",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකා ගමනාගමන මණ්ඩලය",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "මිලියන 3 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "කුමාර වෙල්ගම",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "අල්ලස් කොමිසම",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "වෙල්ගම",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "අල්ලස් කොමිසම",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "තුන්",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "වෙල්ගම",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "අල්ලස් නඩුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "இலஞ்ச வழக்கில் இருந்து வெல்கம விடுதலை; CIABOC வழக்கை மீண்டும் தாக்கல் செய்ய உரிமை உள்ளது என்று கூறுகிறது",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st): இலஞ்சம் அல்லது ஊழல் குற்றச்சாட்டுகளை விசாரணை செய்யும் ஆணைக்குழுவினால் தாக்கல் செய்யப்பட்ட வழக்கில் இருந்து முன்னாள் அமைச்சர் குமார வெல்கமவை விடுவிக்குமாறு கொழும்பு நீதவான் நீதிமன்றம் வெள்ளிக்கிழமை (24) உத்தரவிட்டுள்ளது.",
        "இலங்கை போக்குவரத்துச் சபையில் இல்லாத பிரதித் தலைவர் பதவியை உருவாக்கி ரூ.5000 சம்பளம் வழங்கியதாக வெல்கம மீது குற்றம் சுமத்தப்பட்டது. குறித்த பதவிக்கு 3 மில்லியன், அரசாங்கத்திற்கு நஷ்டம்.",
        "இந்த வழக்கை வாபஸ் பெறுவதாக இலஞ்ச ஊழல் ஆணைக்குழு தெரிவித்ததையடுத்து, வெல்கமவுக்கு எதிராக மீண்டும் வழக்குத் தாக்கல் செய்வதற்கான உரிமையை குமார வெல்கமவை விடுவிக்குமாறு கொழும்பு பிரதான நீதவான் நந்தன அமரசிங்க உத்தரவிட்டார்.",
        "வழக்குப் பதிவு செய்வதற்கு மூன்று ஆணையாளர்களிடமும் கையொப்பம் பெற வேண்டும் என்ற நிலையில், வழக்குப் பதிவு செய்வதில் உரிய நடைமுறையைப் பின்பற்றாததால், லஞ்ச ஊழல் ஆணைக்குழு வழக்கை வாபஸ் பெற்றது.",
        "இலஞ்ச வழக்கில் இருந்து வெல்கம விடுதலை; CIABOC வழக்கை மீண்டும் தாக்கல் செய்ய உரிமை உள்ளது என்று கூறுகிறது"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "வெல்கம",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "லஞ்ச வழக்கு",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "1வது",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "வெள்ளி",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "24",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "குமார வெல்கம",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "லஞ்சம் அல்லது ஊழல் குற்றச்சாட்டுகளை விசாரிக்கவும்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "வெல்கம",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை போக்குவரத்து சபை",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "3 மில்லியன்",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "குமார வெல்கம",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலஞ்ச ஆணைக்குழு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "வெல்கம",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலஞ்ச ஆணைக்குழு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "மூன்று",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "வெல்கம",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "லஞ்ச வழக்கு",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}