{
  "newspaper_id": "daily-mirror-lk",
  "url": "https://www.dailymirror.lk/breaking_news/CEB-should-be-restructured-excess-staff-retrenched-Aluthgamage/108-243938",
  "time_ut": 1661775378,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "CEB should be restructured; excess staff retrenched: Aluthgamage",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "CEB should be restructured; excess staff retrenched: Aluthgamage",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "Over-staffed Ceylon Electricity Board (CEB) don’t have much work today as new connections, disconnections and erecting poles are carried out by outsourced companies, a government MP said today.",
        "Government MP Mahindananda Aluthgamage told Parliament today that even cutting tree branches are carried out by private companies today. “This situation continues despite CEB being overstaffed. Therefore CEB workers who do nothing should be made to carry out all the work,” the MP said.",
        "“A CEB labourer draws a monthly salary of Rs 120,000,” the MP revealed.",
        "Coming up with another disclosure, Mr. Aluthgamage said vehicles are hired by CEB though there are many vehicles.",
        "“CEB should be restructured and the excess staff should be retrenched ,” he also said.",
        "“Only Rs 105 is charged from a household which consumes 30 units of electricity. A cigarette cost Rs 105 today. Therefore I suggest that only those who are eligible for concessions should be given concessions. We don’t agree with the power tariff hike but CEB will incur losses to the tune of Rs 508 billion in 2023 if the electricity charges were not revised,” he added. (Yohan Perera and Ajith Siriwardana)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "CEB",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Ceylon Electricity Board",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "CEB",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "CEB",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "CEB",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "monthly",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Rs 120,000",
            "label": "LAW"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Aluthgamage",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "CEB",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "30",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "105",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "CEB",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "2023",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Yohan Perera",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ajith Siriwardana",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "ලංවිම ප්‍රතිව්‍යුහගත කළ යුතුයි; අතිරික්ත කාර්ය මණ්ඩලය ඉවත් කළා: අලුත්ගමගේ",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "නව සම්බන්ධතා, විසන්ධි කිරීම් සහ කණු සවිකිරීම බාහිරින් ලබාගන්නා සමාගම් මගින් සිදු කරන බැවින් කාර්ය මණ්ඩලය අධික ලංකා විදුලිබල මණ්ඩලයට (CEB) අද එතරම් වැඩ නැති බව ආණ්ඩුවේ මන්ත්‍රීවරයෙක් අද පැවසීය.",
        "අද වන විට ගස්වල අතු කැපීම පවා පෞද්ගලික සමාගම් විසින් සිදුකරන බව ආණ්ඩු පක්ෂයේ පාර්ලිමේන්තු මන්ත්‍රී මහින්දානන්ද අලුත්ගමගේ මහතා අද පාර්ලිමේන්තුවේදී ප්‍රකාශ කළේය. “ලංවිමේ සේවක සංඛ්‍යාව වැඩිපුර තිබුණත් මේ තත්ත්වය දිගටම පවතිනවා. ඒ නිසා කිසිම දෙයක් නොකරන ලංවිම සේවකයන් සියලු වැඩ කටයුතු කරගෙන යා යුතුයි.” මන්ත්‍රීවරයා පැවසීය.",
        "“ලංවිම සේවකයෙක් රුපියල් 120,000ක මාසික වැටුපක් ගන්නවා,” මන්ත්‍රීවරයා අනාවරණය කළේය.",
        "තවත් හෙළිදරව්වක් ඉදිරිපත් කරමින් අලුත්ගමගේ මහතා කියා සිටියේ බොහෝ වාහන තිබුණත් විදුලිබල මණ්ඩලයෙන් වාහන කුලියට ගන්නා බවයි.",
        "“ලංවිම ප්‍රතිව්‍යුහගත කළ යුතු අතර අතිරික්ත කාර්ය මණ්ඩලය ඉවත් කළ යුතුය,” ඔහු ද පැවසීය.",
        "“විදුලිය ඒකක 30ක් පරිභෝජනය කරන නිවසකින් අය කරන්නේ රුපියල් 105ක් පමණයි. අද සිගරට් එකක මිල රුපියල් 105 කි. ඒ නිසා මම යෝජනා කරනවා සහන හිමි අයට පමණක් සහන ලබාදිය යුතුයි කියලා. විදුලි බිල වැඩි කිරීමට අපි එකඟ නොවෙමු නමුත් විදුලි ගාස්තු සංශෝධනය නොකළහොත් 2023 දී විදුලිබල මණ්ඩලයට රුපියල් බිලියන 508 ක පාඩුවක් සිදුවනු ඇත. (යොහාන් පෙරේරා සහ අජිත් සිරිවර්ධන)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ලංවිම",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ලංකා විදුලිබල මණ්ඩලය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ලංවිම",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ලංවිම",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ලංවිම",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මාසිකව",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "රුපියල් 120,000",
            "label": "LAW"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "අලුත්ගමගේ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ලංවිම",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "30",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "105",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ලංවිම",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "2023",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "යොහාන් පෙරේරා",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "අජිත් සිරිවර්ධන",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "CEB மறுசீரமைக்கப்பட வேண்டும்; அதிகப்படியான ஊழியர்கள் ஆட்குறைப்பு: அலுத்கமகே",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "புதிய இணைப்புகள், துண்டிப்புக்கள் மற்றும் மின்கம்பங்களை நிறுவுதல் போன்ற பணிகள் அவுட்சோர்ஸ் நிறுவனங்களால் மேற்கொள்ளப்படுவதால், அதிக பணியாளர்கள் உள்ள இலங்கை மின்சார சபைக்கு (CEB) இன்று அதிக வேலை இல்லை என்று அரசாங்க பாராளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர் ஒருவர் இன்று தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "இன்று மரக்கிளைகளை வெட்டுவது கூட தனியார் நிறுவனங்களால் மேற்கொள்ளப்படுவதாக அரசாங்கத்தின் பாராளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர் மஹிந்தானந்த அளுத்கமகே இன்று பாராளுமன்றத்தில் தெரிவித்தார். “இலங்கைச் சபையில் அதிகளவு பணியாளர்கள் இருந்த போதிலும் இந்த நிலைமை தொடர்கிறது. எனவே எதுவுமே செய்யாத இ.போ.ச ஊழியர்கள் அனைத்து வேலைகளையும் மேற்கொள்ள வைக்க வேண்டும்” என்று எம்.பி.",
        "\"ஒரு CEB தொழிலாளி மாத சம்பளம் ரூபாய் 120,000\" என்று பாராளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர் வெளிப்படுத்தினார்.",
        "மற்றுமொரு வெளிப்பாட்டுடன் வரும் திரு. அளுத்கமகே, பல வாகனங்கள் இருந்தாலும், மின்சார சபையினால் வாகனங்கள் வாடகைக்கு எடுக்கப்படுகின்றன என்றார்.",
        "\"CEB மறுசீரமைக்கப்பட வேண்டும் மற்றும் அதிகப்படியான ஊழியர்களை பணிநீக்கம் செய்ய வேண்டும்,\" என்றும் அவர் கூறினார்.",
        "30 யூனிட் மின்சாரம் பயன்படுத்தும் ஒரு வீட்டில் இருந்து ரூ.105 மட்டுமே வசூலிக்கப்படுகிறது. இன்று ஒரு சிகரெட் விலை 105 ரூபாய். எனவே சலுகை பெற தகுதியானவர்களுக்கு மட்டுமே சலுகை வழங்க வேண்டும் என்று பரிந்துரைக்கிறேன். மின் கட்டண உயர்வுக்கு நாங்கள் உடன்படவில்லை, ஆனால் மின் கட்டணங்கள் திருத்தப்படாவிட்டால் 2023 ஆம் ஆண்டில் CEB 508 பில்லியன் ரூபாய் அளவுக்கு இழப்பை சந்திக்கும், ”என்று அவர் மேலும் கூறினார். (யோஹான் பெரேரா மற்றும் அஜித் சிறிவர்தன)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "CEB",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை மின்சார சபை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "CEB",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "CEB",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "CEB",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "மாதாந்திர",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரூ 120,000",
            "label": "LAW"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "அலுத்கமகே",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "CEB",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "30",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "105",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "CEB",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "2023",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "யோஹான் பெரேரா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "அஜித் சிறிவர்தன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}