{
  "newspaper_id": "daily-ft-lk",
  "url": "https://www.ft.lk/business/Kanchana-reviews-progress-of-rapid-renewable-energy-generation-plan/34-739225",
  "time_ut": 1661730854,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Kanchana reviews progress of rapid renewable energy generation plan",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Kanchana reviews progress of rapid renewable energy generation plan",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "Appoints joint committee comprising CEB and SEA officials to finalise renewable energy plans",
        "Discusses salient points of proposed 100 MW solar plant in Siyambalanduwa",
        "Power and Energy Minister Kanchana Wijesekera said salient points in connection with the proposed 100 MW solar plant in Siyambalanduwa were discussed during a progress review meeting last Friday.",
        "He also noted that a joint committee comprising the Ceylon Electricity Board (CEB) and Sustainable Energy Authority (SEA) was appointed to finalise the renewable energy strategy.",
        "“We discussed the proposed 100 MW solar plant in Siyambalanduwa, EOIs, floating solar, tariffs, grid capacity, and signing of power purchase agreement (PPA),” he said.  The Daily FT exclusively reported that the State-run Ceylon Electricity Board (CEB) has called for International Competitive Bidding (ICB) to develop a 100 MW AC (alternating-current) solar PV (photovoltaic) power plant on a Build, Own, and Operate (BOO) basis in Siyambalanduwa for three years (https://www.ft.lk/front-page/SL-calls-the-world-to-boost-renewable-energy/44-739005).",
        "In addition, the CEB has called for ICBs to construct a 132 kV transmission facility on a turnkey basis from Siyambalanduwa to Monaragala grid substation.",
        "It is the first call for ICB post-pandemic amidst the ongoing economic crisis, sources told the Daily FT.",
        "The move comes after the Cabinet approved the restructuring of the debt-ridden CEB, as well as a revision of the tariff rates for renewable energy projects.",
        "In May, Minister Wijesekera announced that the Government will launch a rapid renewable energy generation plan from June onwards, which will be executed in two quick steps, which include conversion of rooftops to solar panels and extending immediate nod to provisional approval for proposed renewable energy proposals.",
        "He believes that renewable energy is the way forward and will help Sri Lanka to overcome the energy crisis in the long run. The Minister recently affirmed that the CEB and Ceylon Petroleum Corporation (CPC) will be restructured, despite the strong opposition from the trade unions.",
        "During a stakeholder consultation held last month, it was also revealed that the CEB’s accumulated revenue shortfall is at Rs. 477 billion, whilst the gross liabilities are at a staggering Rs. 612.4 billion as of May 2022."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Kanchana",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "CEB",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "SEA",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "100",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "MW",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Siyambalanduwa",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Energy",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kanchana Wijesekera",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "100",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "MW",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Siyambalanduwa",
            "label": "PRODUCT"
          },
          {
            "text": "last Friday",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the Ceylon Electricity Board",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sustainable Energy Authority",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "SEA",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "100",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "MW",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Siyambalanduwa",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "PPA",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Daily",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "State",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ceylon Electricity Board",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "International Competitive Bidding",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ICB",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "100",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "MW AC",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Build",
            "label": "PRODUCT"
          },
          {
            "text": "Operate",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "BOO",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Siyambalanduwa",
            "label": "PRODUCT"
          },
          {
            "text": "three years",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "CEB",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "132",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Siyambalanduwa",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Monaragala",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "first",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ICB",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Cabinet",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "CEB",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "May",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Wijesekera",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "June",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "two",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "CEB",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ceylon Petroleum Corporation",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "CPC",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "last month",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "CEB",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "477 billion",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "612.4 billion",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "May 2022",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "වේගවත් පුනර්ජනනීය බලශක්ති උත්පාදන සැලැස්මේ ප්‍රගතිය කාංචනා සමාලෝචනය කරයි",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "පුනර්ජනනීය බලශක්ති සැලසුම් අවසන් කිරීම සඳහා ලංවිම සහ මුහුදේ නිලධාරීන්ගෙන් සමන්විත ඒකාබද්ධ කමිටුවක් පත් කරයි",
        "සියඹලාණ්ඩුවේ යෝජිත මෙගාවොට් 100 සූර්ය බලාගාරයේ කැපී පෙනෙන කරුණු සාකච්ඡා කරයි",
        "සියඹලාණ්ඩුවේ මෙගාවොට් 100 ක සූර්ය බලාගාරයක් ඉදිකිරීමට යෝජිත බව පසුගිය සිකුරාදා පැවති ප්‍රගති සමාලෝචන රැස්වීමේදී වැදගත් කරුණු සාකච්ඡා කළ බව විදුලිබල හා බලශක්ති අමාත්‍ය කංචන විජේසේකර මහතා පැවසීය.",
        "පුනර්ජනනීය බලශක්ති උපායමාර්ගය අවසන් කිරීම සඳහා ලංකා විදුලිබල මණ්ඩලය (CEB) සහ සුනිත්‍ය බලශක්ති අධිකාරිය (SEA) ඇතුළත් ඒකාබද්ධ කමිටුවක් පත් කළ බව ද ඔහු සඳහන් කළේය.",
        "විදේශ විනිමය ගලා ඒම වැඩි කිරීමට ජාතික මුලපිරීමක් සහ උත්ප්‍රේරකයක් ලෙස",
        "මීට අමතරව, සියඹලාණ්ඩුවේ සිට මොණරාගල ග්‍රිඩ් උපපොළ දක්වා හැරවුම් යතුර පදනම මත 132 kV සම්ප්‍රේෂණ පහසුකම ඉදිකිරීමට විදුලිබල මණ්ඩලය ICBs ඉල්ලා ඇත.",
        "පවතින ආර්ථික අර්බුදය මධ්‍යයේ ICB පශ්චාත් වසංගතය සඳහා වන පළමු ඇමතුම එය බව මූලාශ්‍ර Daily FT වෙත පැවසීය.",
        "ණය බරින් මිරිකී සිටින ලංවිම ප්‍රතිව්‍යුහගත කිරීමට මෙන්ම පුනර්ජනනීය බලශක්ති ව්‍යාපෘති සඳහා ගාස්තු අනුපාත සංශෝධනය කිරීමට කැබිනට් අනුමැතිය ලැබීමෙන් පසුව මෙම පියවර ගෙන ඇත.",
        "වහලවල් සූර්ය පැනල බවට පත් කිරීම සහ යෝජිත පුනර්ජනනීය බලශක්ති යෝජනා සඳහා තාවකාලික අනුමැතිය සඳහා වහා අනුමැතිය ලබා දීම ඇතුළු කඩිනම් පියවර දෙකකින් එය ක්‍රියාත්මක කරන කඩිනම් පුනර්ජනනීය බලශක්ති උත්පාදන සැලැස්මක් ජුනි මාසයේ සිට රජය විසින් දියත් කරන බව අමාත්‍ය විජේසේකර මැයි මාසයේදී නිවේදනය කළේය. .",
        "පුනර්ජනනීය බලශක්තිය ඉදිරි මාවත බව ඔහු විශ්වාස කරන අතර දිගුකාලීනව බලශක්ති අර්බුදයෙන් මිදීමට ශ්‍රී ලංකාවට උපකාරී වනු ඇත. වෘත්තීය සමිතිවල දැඩි විරෝධය නොතකා ලංවිම සහ ලංකා ඛනිජ තෙල් නීතිගත සංස්ථාව (CPC) ප්‍රතිව්‍යුහගත කරන බව අමාත්‍යවරයා පසුගියදා තහවුරු කළේය.",
        "පසුගිය මාසයේ පැවති පාර්ශ්වකරුවන්ගේ උපදේශනයකදී ලංවිමේ සමුච්චිත ආදායම් හිඟය රු. බිලියන 477 ක් වන අතර, දළ වගකීම් විශ්මයජනක ලෙස රු. 2022 මැයි වන විට බිලියන 612.4 කි."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "කාංචනා",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ලංවිම",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මුහුදු",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "100",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "මෙ.වො",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "සියඹලාණ්ඩුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශක්තිය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "කාංචන විජේසේකර",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "100",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "මෙ.වො",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "සියඹලාණ්ඩුව",
            "label": "PRODUCT"
          },
          {
            "text": "පසුගිය සිකුරාදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ලංකා විදුලිබල මණ්ඩලය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "සුනිත්‍ය බලශක්ති අධිකාරිය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "මුහුදු",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "100",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "මෙ.වො",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "සියඹලාණ්ඩුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "PPA",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "දිනපතා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "රජයේ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ලංකා විදුලිබල මණ්ඩලය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජාත්‍යන්තර තරඟකාරී ලංසු තැබීම",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ICB",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "100",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "MW AC",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගොඩනඟන්න",
            "label": "PRODUCT"
          },
          {
            "text": "ක්‍රියාත්මක කරන්න",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "BOO",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "සියඹලාණ්ඩුව",
            "label": "PRODUCT"
          },
          {
            "text": "වසර තුනක්",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ලංවිම",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "132",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "සියඹලාණ්ඩුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "මොනරාගල",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "පළමුවන",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ICB",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "මණ්ඩල",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ලංවිම",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "මැයි",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "විජේසේකර",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජූනි",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "දෙක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ලංවිම",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ලංකා ඛනිජ තෙල් නීතිගත සංස්ථාව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "CPC",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "පසුගිය මාසයේ",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ලංවිම",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "බිලියන 477 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "බිලියන 612.4 කි",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "2022 මැයි",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "காஞ்சனா விரைவான புதுப்பிக்கத்தக்க ஆற்றல் உற்பத்தி திட்டத்தின் முன்னேற்றத்தை மதிப்பாய்வு செய்கிறார்",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "புதுப்பிக்கத்தக்க ஆற்றல் திட்டங்களை இறுதி செய்ய CEB மற்றும் SEA அதிகாரிகளை உள்ளடக்கிய கூட்டுக் குழுவை நியமித்தது",
        "சியம்பலாண்டுவவில் உத்தேச 100 மெகாவாட் சூரிய மின் உற்பத்தி நிலையத்தின் முக்கிய புள்ளிகள் பற்றி விவாதிக்கிறது",
        "சியம்பலாண்டுவவில் உத்தேச 100 மெகாவாட் சோலார் ஆலை தொடர்பில் கடந்த வெள்ளிக்கிழமை நடைபெற்ற முன்னேற்ற மீளாய்வு கூட்டத்தின் போது முக்கிய விடயங்கள் கலந்துரையாடப்பட்டதாக மின்சக்தி மற்றும் எரிசக்தி அமைச்சர் காஞ்சன விஜேசேகர தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "புதுப்பிக்கத்தக்க ஆற்றல் மூலோபாயத்தை இறுதி செய்வதற்காக இலங்கை மின்சார சபை (CEB) மற்றும் நிலையான எரிசக்தி அதிகார சபை (SEA) அடங்கிய கூட்டுக் குழுவொன்று நியமிக்கப்பட்டுள்ளதாகவும் அவர் குறிப்பிட்டார்.",
        "\"சியம்பலாண்டுவவில் முன்மொழியப்பட்ட 100 மெகாவாட் சோலார் ஆலை, EOIகள், மிதக்கும் சோலார், கட்டணங்கள், கட்டம் திறன் மற்றும் மின் கொள்முதல் ஒப்பந்தத்தில் (PPA) கையெழுத்திடுவது பற்றி நாங்கள் விவாதித்தோம்,\" என்று அவர் கூறினார். டெய்லி FT பிரத்தியேகமாக, அரசால் நடத்தப்படும் இலங்கை மின்சார வாரியம் (CEB) 100 MW AC (மாற்று-தற்போதைய) சூரிய PV (ஒளிமின்னழுத்த) மின் உற்பத்தி நிலையத்தை உருவாக்க சர்வதேச போட்டி ஏலத்திற்கு (ICB) அழைப்பு விடுத்துள்ளது. (BOO) அடிப்படையில் மூன்று வருடங்கள் சியம்பலாந்துவையில் இயங்கவும் (https://www.ft.lk/front-page/SL-calls-the-world-to-boost-renewable-energy/44-739005).",
        "மேலும், சியம்பலாண்டுவ முதல் மொனராகலை கிரிட் துணை மின்நிலையம் வரை ஆயத்த தயாரிப்பு அடிப்படையில் 132 kV ஒலிபரப்பு வசதியை அமைப்பதற்கு ICB களுக்கு CEB அழைப்பு விடுத்துள்ளது.",
        "தற்போதைய பொருளாதார நெருக்கடிக்கு மத்தியில் ஐசிபி பிந்தைய தொற்றுநோய்க்கான முதல் அழைப்பு இது என்று டெய்லி எஃப்டி வட்டாரங்கள் தெரிவித்தன.",
        "கடனில் சிக்கியுள்ள CEBயின் மறுசீரமைப்பு மற்றும் புதுப்பிக்கத்தக்க எரிசக்தி திட்டங்களுக்கான கட்டண விகிதங்களை திருத்துவதற்கு அமைச்சரவை ஒப்புதல் அளித்ததை அடுத்து இந்த நடவடிக்கை எடுக்கப்பட்டுள்ளது.",
        "மே மாதம், அமைச்சர் விஜேசேகர, ஜூன் மாதம் முதல் அரசாங்கம் விரைவான புதுப்பிக்கத்தக்க எரிசக்தி உற்பத்தித் திட்டத்தைத் தொடங்கும் என்று அறிவித்தார், இது இரண்டு விரைவான படிகளில் செயல்படுத்தப்படும், இதில் கூரைகளை சோலார் பேனல்களாக மாற்றுவது மற்றும் முன்மொழியப்பட்ட புதுப்பிக்கத்தக்க எரிசக்தி திட்டங்களுக்கு தற்காலிக ஒப்புதலுக்கு உடனடி அனுமதி வழங்குவது ஆகியவை அடங்கும். .",
        "புதுப்பிக்கத்தக்க எரிசக்தியே முன்னோக்கி செல்லும் வழி என்றும், நீண்ட கால அடிப்படையில் இலங்கை எரிசக்தி நெருக்கடியை சமாளிக்க உதவும் என்றும் அவர் நம்புகிறார். தொழிற்சங்கங்களின் கடும் எதிர்ப்பையும் மீறி CEB மற்றும் இலங்கை பெற்றோலியக் கூட்டுத்தாபனம் (CPC) மறுசீரமைக்கப்படும் என அமைச்சர் அண்மையில் உறுதிப்படுத்தினார்.",
        "கடந்த மாதம் நடைபெற்ற பங்குதாரர்களின் ஆலோசனையின் போது, ​​CEBயின் திரட்டப்பட்ட வருவாய் பற்றாக்குறை ரூ. 477 பில்லியன், மொத்தப் பொறுப்புகள் வியக்க வைக்கும் வகையில் ரூ. மே 2022 வரை 612.4 பில்லியன்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "காஞ்சனா",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "CEB",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "கடல்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "100",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "மெகாவாட்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "சியம்பலாண்டுவ",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஆற்றல்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "காஞ்சனா விஜேசேகர",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "100",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "மெகாவாட்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "சியம்பலாண்டுவ",
            "label": "PRODUCT"
          },
          {
            "text": "கடந்த வெள்ளிக்கிழமை",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை மின்சார சபை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "நிலையான எரிசக்தி ஆணையம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "கடல்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "100",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "மெகாவாட்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "சியம்பலாண்டுவ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "பிபிஏ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "தினசரி",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "நிலை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை மின்சார சபை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "சர்வதேச போட்டி ஏலம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஐசிபி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "100",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "மெகாவாட் ஏசி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "கட்டுங்கள்",
            "label": "PRODUCT"
          },
          {
            "text": "இயக்கு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "BOO",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "சியம்பலாண்டுவ",
            "label": "PRODUCT"
          },
          {
            "text": "மூன்று வருடங்கள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "CEB",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "132",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "சியம்பலாண்டுவ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "மொனராகலை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "முதலில்",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஐசிபி",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "மந்திரி சபை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "CEB",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "மே",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "விஜேசேகர",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜூன்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இரண்டு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "CEB",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை பெற்றோலியக் கூட்டுத்தாபனம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "CPC",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "கடந்த மாதம்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "CEB",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "477 பில்லியன்",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "612.4 பில்லியன்",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "மே 2022",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}