{
  "newspaper_id": "b-b-c-com-sinhala",
  "url": "https://www.bbc.com/sinhala/sri-lanka-62263370",
  "time_ut": 1658456338,
  "original_lang": "si",
  "original_title": "\"ඕගොල්ලෝ ජාත්‍යන්තර වශයෙන් චාටර් වෙන්න මේ හදන්නේ\":අද අලුයම ගාලු මුවදොර අරගල භූමියේදී මොකද වුනේ?",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "\"They are trying to be internationally chartered\": What happened at the Galle mouth area of ​​struggle this morning?",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "Security forces took steps early this morning (July 22) to evict the Colombo and Galle mouthpiece activists from the Presidential Secretariat and the surrounding area.",
        "The government security officers attacked many other journalists including the BBC journalists who were covering the event live.",
        "A soldier also took away the mobile phone and deleted the footage from the BBC Tamil Service's Jerin Samuel, who was at the scene.",
        "The Police Media Spokesman told the BBC that he did not know that journalists had been attacked and would look into it.",
        "Sri Lanka is becoming the center of international attention due to the many videos showing the brutal attacks by military personnel on many activists and ordinary civilians in the Colombo, Galle mouth area of ​​struggle."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Galle",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "early this morning",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "July 22",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Colombo",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Galle",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Presidential Secretariat",
            "label": "FAC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "BBC",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the BBC Tamil Service's",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Jerin Samuel",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "BBC",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Colombo",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Galle",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "\"ඕගොල්ලෝ ජාත්‍යන්තර වශයෙන් චාටර් වෙන්න මේ හදන්නේ\":අද අලුයම ගාලු මුවදොර අරගල භූමියේදී මොකද වුනේ?",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "කොළඹ, ගාලු මුවදොර අරගලකරුවන් ජනාධිපති ලේකම් කාර්යාලයෙන් සහ ඒ අවට ප්‍රදේශයෙන් පළවා හැරීමට ආරක්ෂක අංශ අද අලුයම (ජූලි 22) පියවර ගන්නා ලදී.",
        "ඒ අවස්ථාව සජීව ලෙස ආවරණය කරමින් සිටි BBC මාධ්‍යවේදීන් ඇතුළු තවත් මාධ්‍යවේදීන් ගණනාවකටම  රජයේ ආරක්ෂක නිලධාරීහු පහර දුන්හ.",
        "එම ස්ථානයේ සිටි BBC දෙමළ සේවයේ ජෙරින් සැමුවෙල්ට පහරදීමෙන් පසු සොල්දාදුවෙක් ඔහුගේ ජංගම දුරකතනය උදුරාගෙන එහි දර්ශන මකා දැමීමට ද කටයුතු කරන ලදී.",
        "මාධ්‍යවේදීන්ට පහරදුන් බව තමන් නොදන්නා අතර ඒ ගැන සොයා බලන්නම් යැයි පොලිස් මාධ්‍ය ප්‍රකාශකවරයා BBC කළ විමසීමකදී පැවසුවේය.",
        "කොළඹ, ගාලු මුවදොර අරගල භුමියේ ක්‍රියාකාරීන් සහ සාමාන්‍ය සිවිල් වැසියන් බොහෝ දෙනෙකුට හමුදා සෙබළුන් විසින් අමානුෂික ලෙස ප්‍රහාර එල්ල කරන දර්ශන සහිත බොහෝ වීඩියෝ පට මේවන විට අන්තර්ජාලය හරහා හුවමාරු වෙමින් පවතින අතර මෙම සිදුවීම හේතුවෙන් ජාත්‍යන්තර අවධානයේ කේන්ද්‍රස්ථානයක් බවට ශ්‍රී ලංකාව පත්වෙමින් තිබේ."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ගාල්ල",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "අද උදේ පාන්දර",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජූලි 22",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "කොළඹ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගාල්ල",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජනාධිපති ලේකම් කාර්යාලය",
            "label": "FAC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "බීබීසී",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "බීබීසී දෙමළ සේවයේ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජෙරින් සැමුවෙල්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "බීබීසී",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "කොළඹ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගාල්ල",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "\"அவர்கள் சர்வதேச அளவில் பட்டயப்படுத்த முயற்சிக்கிறார்கள்\": இன்று காலை காலி முகத்துவாரப் பகுதியில் என்ன நடந்தது?",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "கொழும்பு மற்றும் காலி ஊதுகுழல் செயற்பாட்டாளர்களை ஜனாதிபதி செயலகம் மற்றும் அதனைச் சூழவுள்ள பகுதிகளில் இருந்து வெளியேற்ற பாதுகாப்புப் படையினர் இன்று (ஜூலை 22) அதிகாலை நடவடிக்கை எடுத்துள்ளனர்.",
        "இந்த நிகழ்வை நேரலையில் செய்தி சேகரிக்க வந்த பிபிசி செய்தியாளர்கள் உட்பட பல ஊடகவியலாளர்களை அரசாங்க பாதுகாப்பு அதிகாரிகள் தாக்கினர்.",
        "மேலும், ராணுவ வீரர் ஒருவர் மொபைல் போனை எடுத்துச் சென்று, சம்பவ இடத்தில் இருந்த பிபிசி தமிழ்ச் சேவையின் ஜெரின் சாமுவேலின் காட்சிகளை நீக்கினார்.",
        "ஊடகவியலாளர்கள் தாக்கப்பட்டது தொடர்பில் தமக்கு தெரியாது எனவும் அது தொடர்பில் அவதானிப்பதாகவும் பொலிஸ் ஊடகப் பேச்சாளர் பிபிசியிடம் தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "கொழும்பு, காலி முகத்துவாரப் பகுதியில் பல செயற்பாட்டாளர்கள் மற்றும் சாதாரண பொதுமக்கள் மீது இராணுவத்தினர் நடத்திய மிருகத்தனமான தாக்குதல்களைக் காட்டும் பல காணொளிகள் காரணமாக இலங்கை சர்வதேச கவனத்தின் மையமாக மாறி வருகிறது."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "காலி",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "இன்று அதிகாலை",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜூலை 22",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "கொழும்பு",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "காலி",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜனாதிபதி செயலகம்",
            "label": "FAC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பிபிசி",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பிபிசி தமிழ் சேவையின்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜெரின் சாமுவேல்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பிபிசி",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "கொழும்பு",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "காலி",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}