{
  "newspaper_id": "lankadeepa-lk",
  "url": "https://www.lankadeepa.lk/news/බස්නාහිරත්-දකුණ-පළාත්-කීපයකටත්-වැසි/101-616774",
  "time_ut": 1658372819,
  "original_lang": "si",
  "original_title": "බස්නාහිරත් දකුණ පළාත් කීපයකටත් වැසි",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Rains in several western and southern provinces",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "The Department of Meteorology says that there will be several periods of rain today (21) in the Western Province, Galle and Matara districts.",
        "A spokesman for the department said that there will be rain or thundershowers at some places in the evening or at night in the rest of the areas, and in some places in Sabaragamuwa, Central and Uva provinces, more than 75 mm of heavy rain will occur.",
        "He said that strong winds of 40, 50 km per hour will occur in Hambantota and Matara districts from time to time.",
        "The department also states that thunderstorms may be accompanied by lightning and temporary gusty winds."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "The Department of Meteorology",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "21",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Western Province",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "Galle",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Matara",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "night",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sabaragamuwa, Central",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Uva",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "more than 75",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "50 km per hour",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "Hambantota",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Matara",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        []
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "බස්නාහිරත් දකුණ පළාත් කීපයකටත් වැසි",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "බස්නාහිර පළාතේත්, ගාල්ල සහ මාතර දිස්ත්‍රික්කවලත් අද (21) වැසි වාර කිහිපයක් ඇතිවන බව කාලගුණ විද්‍යා දෙපාර්තමේන්තුව පවසයි.",
        "සෙසු ප්‍රදේශවලද තැනින් තැන සවස් කාලයේ දී හෝ රාත්‍රී කාලයේදී වැසි හෝ ගිගුරුම් සහිත වැසි ඇතිවන අතර සබරගමුව, මධ්‍යම සහ ඌව පළාත්වල ඇතැම් ස්ථානයන්හි මිලිමීටර 75 ට වැඩි තරමක තද වැසි ඇතිවන බව එම දෙපාර්තමේන්තුවේ ප්‍රකාශකයෙක් පැවසීය.",
        "හම්බන්තොට සහ මාතර දිස්ත්‍රික්කවල විටින් විට පැයට කිලෝමීටර 40, 50 පමණ වේගවත් සුළං ඇතිවන බව ඔහු කීවේය.",
        "ගිගුරුම් සහිත වැසි සමඟ අකුණු අනතුරු සහ තාවකාලික තද සුළං ඇතිවිය හැකි බව ද එම දෙපාර්තමේන්තුව සඳහන් කරයි."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "කාලගුණ විද්‍යා දෙපාර්තමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "21",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "බස්නාහිර පළාත",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගාල්ල",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මාතර",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "රෑ",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "සබරගමුව, මධ්‍යම",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඌව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "75 ට වැඩි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "පැයට කිලෝමීටර 50 කි",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "හම්බන්තොට",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මාතර",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        []
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "பல மேற்கு மற்றும் தென் மாகாணங்களில் மழை பெய்யும்",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "மேல் மாகாணம், காலி மற்றும் மாத்தறை மாவட்டங்களில் இன்று (21) பல தடவைகள் மழை பெய்யும் என வளிமண்டலவியல் திணைக்களம் தெரிவித்துள்ளது.",
        "ஏனைய பிரதேசங்களில் சில இடங்களில் மாலை அல்லது இரவு வேளைகளில் மழையோ அல்லது இடியுடன் கூடிய மழையோ பெய்யக் கூடும் எனவும், சப்ரகமுவ, மத்திய மற்றும் ஊவா மாகாணங்களில் சில இடங்களில் 75 மில்லிமீற்றருக்கும் அதிகமான பலத்த மழை பெய்யும் எனவும் திணைக்களத்தின் பேச்சாளர் தெரிவித்தார். .",
        "ஹம்பாந்தோட்டை மற்றும் மாத்தறை மாவட்டங்களில் அவ்வப்போது மணித்தியாலத்துக்கு 40, 50 கிலோ மீற்றர் வேகத்தில் பலத்த காற்று வீசும் என அவர் தெரிவித்துள்ளார்.",
        "இடியுடன் கூடிய மழையுடன் மின்னலுடன் தற்காலிகமாக பலத்த காற்றும் வீசக்கூடும் எனவும் திணைக்களம் குறிப்பிட்டுள்ளது."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "வளிமண்டலவியல் திணைக்களம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "21",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "மேல் மாகாணம்",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "காலி",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "மாத்தறை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இரவு",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "சப்ரகமுவ, மத்திய",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஊவா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "75க்கு மேல்",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "மணிக்கு 50 கி.மீ",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஹம்பாந்தோட்டை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "மாத்தறை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        []
      ]
    }
  }
}