{
  "newspaper_id": "ada-derana-lk",
  "url": "http://www.adaderana.lk/news/83579/central-bank-governor-warns-political-instability-may-hurt-imf-negotiations",
  "time_ut": 1657530420,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Central bank governor warns political instability may hurt IMF negotiations",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Central bank governor warns political instability may hurt IMF negotiations",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "(Reuters) – Sri Lanka’s central financial institution governor signalled on Monday he would keep within the job however warned that extended political instability within the nation could delay progress on negotiations with the Worldwide Financial Fund for a bailout bundle.",
        "Governor P. Nandalal Weerasinghe, who has been holding bailout talks with the IMF since taking workplace in April, had informed reporters in Might he may resign if there was no political stability within the island nation of twenty-two million that’s going through its worst financial disaster in seven many years.",
        "President Gotabaya Rajapaksa plans to resign on Wednesday whereas Prime Minister Ranil Wickremesinghe has additionally provided to stop, with out specifying a date, to make method for a unity authorities. Hundreds of protesters stormed their residences on Saturday and have vowed to remain put till the 2 leaders resigned.",
        "“Political instability would possibly delay the progress we’ve been making to date,” Weerasinghe stated of the talks with the IMF throughout an interview with Reuters in his workplace, the place chants from protesters occupying the president’s home close by may very well be heard.",
        "“I want to have a secure political administration, the earlier the higher, for us to make progress, primarily on the programmes we’re negotiating with the IMF, bridging finance and in addition to handle shortages of gas, fuel and different issues.”",
        "Requested if he would proceed to steer the central bank, Weerasinghe stated: “I’ve the duty as soon as I’ve been appointed to serve for (a) six-year time period.”",
        "He additionally stated negotiations had been on for a $1 billion swap with the Reserve Bank of India. Sri Lanka acquired a $400 million swap from India in January and $1.5 billion in two credit score traces after that.",
        "“We have now made a request for an additional $1 billion,” he stated, including the nation was additionally in talks with India for an extra credit score line of $500 million to import gas.",
        "Since Weerasinghe, 61, took over, the central bank has raised rates of interest twice, together with by an unprecedented 700 foundation factors in April, as inflation touched a year-on-year file of 54.6% in June and will soar to 70% within the coming months. learn extra",
        "The IMF stated on Sunday it hoped for a decision to the political turmoil to permit a resumption of talks for a bailout bundle. The federal government stated final week it will current a debt restructuring plan to the fund by the top of August, in a bid to win approval for a four-year funding programme.",
        "“At technical stage we’ve virtually agreed (with the IMF) however at coverage stage we want a higher-level dedication from a secure administration,” the governor stated.",
        "Sri Lanka suspended repayments on about $12 billion of overseas debt in April and it nonetheless had funds of practically $21 billion due by the top of 2025."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Central",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Reuters",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka’s",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Monday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Worldwide Financial Fund",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "P. Nandalal Weerasinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "April",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "twenty-two million",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "seven many years",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Gotabaya Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Wednesday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Hundreds",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Saturday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "2",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Weerasinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "IMF",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Reuters",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "Weerasinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "six-year",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "$1 billion",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Reserve Bank of India",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "$400 million",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "India",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "January",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "$1.5 billion",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "two",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "an additional $1 billion",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "India",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "$500 million",
            "label": "MONEY"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Weerasinghe",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "61",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "700",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "April",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "54.6%",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "June",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "70%",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "the coming months",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "IMF",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sunday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "final week",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "August",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "four-year",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "IMF",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "about $12 billion",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "April",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "$21 billion",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "2025",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "දේශපාලන අස්ථාවරත්වය ජාත්‍යන්තර මූල්‍ය අරමුදලේ සාකච්ඡාවලට හානියක් විය හැකි බව මහ බැංකු අධිපතිවරයා අනතුරු අඟවයි",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "(රොයිටර්) - ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ මධ්‍යම මූල්‍ය ආයතන ආණ්‌ඩුකාරවරයා සඳුදා තමා රැකියාවේ රැඳී සිටින බවට සංඥා කළේය, කෙසේ වෙතත් ජාතිය තුළ දීර්ඝ වූ දේශපාලන අස්ථාවරත්වය, ඇපදීමේ මිටියක් සඳහා ලෝක ව්‍යාප්ත මූල්‍ය අරමුදල සමඟ කෙරෙන සාකච්ඡාවල ප්‍රගතිය ප්‍රමාද කළ හැකි බවට අනතුරු ඇඟවීය.",
        "අපේ‍්‍රල් මාසයේ සේවා ස්ථානයට පැමිණීමේ සිට IMF සමඟ ඇපදීමේ සාකච්ඡා පවත්වමින් සිටින ආණ්ඩුකාර පී. නන්දලාල් වීරසිංහ, මිලියන විසි දෙකක දුපතේ නරකම මූල්‍යමය තත්ත්වයෙන් පෙළෙන රට තුළ දේශපාලන ස්ථාවරත්වයක් නොමැති නම් ඉල්ලා අස්විය හැකි බව මයිට් හි වාර්තාකරුවන්ට දන්වා තිබුණි. වසර හතක් තුළ ව්යසනය.",
        "ජනාධිපති ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ මහතා බදාදා ඉල්ලා අස්වීමට සැලසුම් කර ඇති අතර අග්‍රාමාත්‍ය රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතා දිනයක් සඳහන් නොකර ඒකීය බලධාරියෙකු සඳහා ක්‍රමවේදයක් සකස් කිරීම නැවැත්වීමට අතිරේකව ලබා දී තිබේ. සියගණනක් විරෝධතාකරුවන් සෙනසුරාදා ඔවුන්ගේ නිවෙස්වලට කඩා වැදී නායකයින් දෙදෙනා ඉල්ලා අස්වන තුරු රැඳී සිටින බවට ප්‍රතිඥා දී ඇත.",
        "“දේශපාලන අස්ථාවරත්වය අප අද දක්වා ගෙන යන ප්‍රගතිය ප්‍රමාද කරනු ඇත,” වීරසිංහ සිය සේවා ස්ථානයේ රොයිටර් පුවත් සේවය සමඟ සම්මුඛ සාකච්ඡාවක් පුරාවට ජාත්‍යන්තර මූල්‍ය අරමුදල සමඟ සාකච්ඡා ගැන ප්‍රකාශ කළේය, ජනාධිපති නිවස ආසන්නයේ වාඩි වී සිටින විරෝධතාකරුවන්ගේ ඝෝෂාව ඉතා හොඳින් ඇසෙනු ඇත .",
        "\"මට අවශ්‍ය වන්නේ, අපට ප්‍රගතියක් ලබා ගැනීම සඳහා, මූලික වශයෙන්, අපි IMF සමඟ සාකච්ඡා කරන වැඩසටහන්, මූල්‍ය පාලම් සහ ඊට අමතරව ගෑස්, ඉන්ධන හිඟය සහ විවිධ ප්‍රශ්න විසඳීම සඳහා ප්‍රගතියක් ලබා ගැනීම සඳහා, වඩා උසස්, සුරක්ෂිත දේශපාලන පරිපාලනයක් ඇති කර ගැනීමටය.\"",
        "ඔහු මහ බැංකුව මෙහෙයවීමට කටයුතු කරන්නේ දැයි ඉල්ලා සිටි වීරසිංහ මෙසේ ප්‍රකාශ කළේය: \"(අ) අවුරුදු හයක කාලයක් සේවය කිරීමට මා පත් කළ විගසම මට රාජකාරිය තිබේ.\"",
        "ඉන්දියානු සංචිත බැංකුව සමඟ ඩොලර් බිලියන 1 ක හුවමාරුවක් සඳහා සාකච්ඡා පවත්වා ඇති බව ඔහු අතිරේකව ප්‍රකාශ කළේය. ශ්‍රී ලංකාව ජනවාරි මාසයේදී ඉන්දියාවෙන් ඩොලර් මිලියන 400 ක හුවමාරුවක් ලබා ගත් අතර ඉන් පසුව ණය ලකුණු ලුහුබැඳීම් දෙකකින් ඩොලර් බිලියන 1.5 ක් ලබා ගත්තේය.",
        "\"අපි දැන් අතිරේක ඩොලර් බිලියන 1 ක් සඳහා ඉල්ලීමක් කර ඇත,\" ඔහු ප්‍රකාශ කළේ, ගෑස් ආනයනය කිරීම සඳහා ඩොලර් මිලියන 500 ක අමතර ණය ලකුණු රේඛාවක් සඳහා ජාතිය අතිරේකව ඉන්දියාව සමඟ සාකච්ඡා කරමින් සිටින බවයි.",
        "61 හැවිරිදි වීරසිංහ මහතා වැඩ භාරගැනීමෙන් පසු, උද්ධමනය ජුනි මාසයේදී 54.6% ක වාර්ෂික ගොනුවකට ළඟා වූ බැවින්, අප්‍රේල් මාසයේදී පෙර නොවූ විරූ 700 පදනම් සාධක සමඟ මහ බැංකුව පොලී අනුපාත දෙවරක් ඉහළ නංවා ඇති අතර එය 70% දක්වා ඉහළ යනු ඇත. ඉදිරි මාස ඇතුළත. අමතර ඉගෙන ගන්න",
        "ජාමූඅ ඉරිදා ප්‍රකාශ කළේ දේශපාලන කැලඹීම සඳහා තීරණයක් ගැනීමට බලාපොරොත්තු වන අතර ඇපදීමේ මිටියක් සඳහා සාකච්ඡා නැවත ආරම්භ කිරීමට අවසර දීමයි. ෆෙඩරල් ආන්ඩුව අවසාන සතියේ ප්‍රකාශ කළේ වසර හතරක අරමුදල් වැඩසටහනක් සඳහා අනුමැතිය දිනා ගැනීමේ උත්සාහයක් ලෙස, අගෝස්තු මස මුල වන විට අරමුදලට ණය ප්‍රතිව්‍යුහගත කිරීමේ සැලැස්මක් ඉදිරිපත් කරන බවයි.",
        "\"තාක්ෂණික අදියරේදී අපි (ජාමූඅ සමග) මුලුමනින්ම එකඟ වී ඇතත්, ආවරණ අදියරේදී අපට ආරක්ෂිත පරිපාලනයකින් ඉහළ මට්ටමේ කැපවීමක් අවශ්‍ය වේ,\" ආණ්ඩුකාරවරයා ප්‍රකාශ කළේය.",
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකාව අප්‍රේල් මාසයේදී ඩොලර් බිලියන 12 ක පමණ විදේශ ණය සඳහා ආපසු ගෙවීම අත්හිටුවන ලද අතර 2025 වසර වන විට ප්‍රායෝගිකව ඩොලර් බිලියන 21 ක අරමුදල් ඉතිරිව තිබුණි."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "මධ්යම",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "රොයිටර්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "සඳුදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ලෝක ව්යාප්ත මූල්ය අරමුදල",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "පී.නන්දලාල් වීරසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "අප්රේල්",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මිලියන විසි දෙකක්",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "අවුරුදු හතක්",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "බදාදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "සිය ගණනක්",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "සෙනසුරාදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "2",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "වීරසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "IMF",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "රොයිටර්",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "වීරසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "හය වසර",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ඩොලර් බිලියන 1",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දියානු සංචිත බැංකුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඩොලර් මිලියන 400 කි",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජනවාරි",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඩොලර් බිලියන 1.5 කි",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "දෙක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "අතිරේක ඩොලර් බිලියන 1",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඩොලර් මිලියන 500 කි",
            "label": "MONEY"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "වීරසිංහ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "61",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "700",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "අප්රේල්",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "54.6%",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජූනි",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "70%",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉදිරි මාස",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "IMF",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉරිදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "අවසාන සතිය",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "අගෝස්තු",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "අවුරුදු හතරක්",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "IMF",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඩොලර් බිලියන 12 ක් පමණ",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "අප්රේල්",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඩොලර් බිලියන 21 කි",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "2025",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "அரசியல் உறுதியற்ற தன்மை சர்வதேச நாணய நிதியத்தின் பேச்சுவார்த்தைகளை பாதிக்கலாம் என மத்திய வங்கி ஆளுநர் எச்சரித்துள்ளார்",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "(ராய்ட்டர்ஸ்) - இலங்கையின் மத்திய நிதி நிறுவன ஆளுநர் திங்கட்கிழமை அவர் பணியில் இருப்பார் என்று சமிக்ஞை செய்தார், இருப்பினும் தேசத்திற்குள் நீட்டிக்கப்பட்ட அரசியல் ஸ்திரமின்மை பிணை எடுப்பு மூட்டைக்கான உலகளாவிய நிதியத்துடன் பேச்சுவார்த்தைகளின் முன்னேற்றத்தை தாமதப்படுத்தக்கூடும் என்று எச்சரித்தார்.",
        "ஏப்ரலில் பணியிடத்திற்கு வந்ததில் இருந்து சர்வதேச நாணய நிதியத்துடன் பிணை எடுப்புப் பேச்சுக்களை நடத்தி வரும் ஆளுநர் பி. நந்தலால் வீரசிங்க, இருபத்தி இரண்டு மில்லியனுள்ள தீவு நாட்டில் அரசியல் ஸ்திரத்தன்மை இல்லாத பட்சத்தில், தனது மோசமான நிதி நிலைமையை எதிர்கொண்டால் பதவி விலகலாம் என செய்தியாளர்களிடம் தெரிவித்திருந்தார். ஏழு பல ஆண்டுகளில் பேரழிவு.",
        "ஜனாதிபதி கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ஷ புதன்கிழமை பதவி விலகத் திட்டமிட்டுள்ள அதேவேளை, பிரதமர் ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க, ஐக்கிய அதிகார சபைக்கான வழிமுறையை, திகதி குறிப்பிடாமல் நிறுத்துமாறும் வழங்கியுள்ளார். சனிக்கிழமையன்று நூற்றுக்கணக்கான போராட்டக்காரர்கள் அவர்களது வீடுகளை முற்றுகையிட்டு, இரு தலைவர்களும் ராஜினாமா செய்யும் வரை போராட்டத்தில் ஈடுபடுவோம் என்று உறுதியளித்தனர்.",
        "\"அரசியல் ஸ்திரமின்மை, இன்றுவரை நாம் செய்து வரும் முன்னேற்றத்தை தாமதப்படுத்தலாம்,\" என வீரசிங்க தனது பணியிடத்தில் ராய்ட்டர்ஸுக்கு அளித்த பேட்டியின் போது IMF உடனான பேச்சுக்கள் பற்றி கூறினார். .",
        "\"நான் ஒரு பாதுகாப்பான அரசியல் நிர்வாகத்தை பெற விரும்புகிறேன், முந்தைய உயர்வானது, நாங்கள் முன்னேற்றம் அடைய, முதன்மையாக IMF உடன் நாங்கள் பேச்சுவார்த்தை நடத்தும் திட்டங்களில், நிதியத்தை கட்டுப்படுத்துவது மற்றும் கூடுதலாக எரிவாயு, எரிபொருள் மற்றும் பல்வேறு சிக்கல்களைக் கையாள்வது.\"",
        "மத்திய வங்கியை வழிநடத்திச் செல்வதா என கோரப்பட்ட வீரசிங்க, \"(அ) ஆறு வருட காலத்திற்கு சேவை செய்ய நான் நியமிக்கப்பட்டவுடன் நான் கடமைப்பட்டிருக்கிறேன்.\"",
        "இந்திய ரிசர்வ் வங்கியுடன் 1 பில்லியன் டாலர் பரிமாற்றத்திற்கான பேச்சுவார்த்தைகள் நடைபெற்று வருவதாகவும் அவர் கூறினார். இலங்கை ஜனவரியில் இந்தியாவிடமிருந்து 400 மில்லியன் டாலர் இடமாறுதலையும் அதற்குப் பிறகு இரண்டு கிரெடிட் ஸ்கோர் தடயங்களில் 1.5 பில்லியன் டாலர்களையும் வாங்கியது.",
        "\"நாங்கள் இப்போது கூடுதலாக 1 பில்லியன் டாலர் கோரிக்கையை வைத்துள்ளோம்,\" என்று அவர் கூறினார், மேலும் எரிவாயு இறக்குமதி செய்ய 500 மில்லியன் டாலர் கூடுதல் கடன் மதிப்பெண் வரிக்கு இந்தியாவுடன் தேசம் பேச்சுவார்த்தை நடத்தி வருகிறது.",
        "61 வயதான வீரசிங்க பதவியேற்றதிலிருந்து, மத்திய வங்கி இரண்டு முறை வட்டி விகிதங்களை உயர்த்தியுள்ளது, ஏப்ரலில் முன்னோடியில்லாத வகையில் 700 அடித்தள காரணிகளால், பணவீக்கம் ஜூன் மாதத்தில் 54.6% ஐத் தொட்டது மற்றும் 70% ஆக உயரும். வரும் மாதங்களில். கூடுதலாக கற்க",
        "பிணை எடுப்பு மூட்டைக்கான பேச்சுவார்த்தைகளை மீண்டும் தொடங்க அனுமதிக்கும் அரசியல் கொந்தளிப்புக்கு ஒரு முடிவு கிடைக்கும் என்று IMF ஞாயிற்றுக்கிழமை கூறியது. நான்கு வருட நிதியுதவித் திட்டத்திற்கான ஒப்புதலைப் பெறுவதற்கான முயற்சியில், ஆகஸ்ட் மாதத்தின் மேல் நிதிக்கு கடன் மறுசீரமைப்புத் திட்டத்தை செயல்படுத்துவதாக மத்திய அரசாங்கம் இறுதி வாரம் கூறியது.",
        "\"தொழில்நுட்ப கட்டத்தில் நாங்கள் (IMF உடன்) ஏறக்குறைய ஒப்புக்கொண்டோம், இருப்பினும் கவரேஜ் கட்டத்தில் ஒரு பாதுகாப்பான நிர்வாகத்தின் உயர் மட்ட அர்ப்பணிப்பை நாங்கள் விரும்புகிறோம்,\" என்று ஆளுநர் கூறினார்.",
        "இலங்கை ஏப்ரல் மாதத்தில் சுமார் 12 பில்லியன் டாலர் வெளிநாட்டுக் கடனைத் திருப்பிச் செலுத்துவதை நிறுத்தியது, இருந்தபோதிலும் 2025 ஆம் ஆண்டிற்குள் அது நடைமுறையில் $21 பில்லியன் நிதியைக் கொண்டிருந்தது."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "மத்திய",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ராய்ட்டர்ஸ்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கையின்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "திங்கட்கிழமை",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "உலகளாவிய நிதி நிதி",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பி.நந்தலால் வீரசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஏப்ரல்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இருபத்தி இரண்டு மில்லியன்",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஏழு பல ஆண்டுகள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "புதன்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "நூற்றுக்கணக்கானவர்கள்",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "சனிக்கிழமை",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "2",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "வீரசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "IMF",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ராய்ட்டர்ஸ்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "வீரசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆறு ஆண்டுகள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "$1 பில்லியன்",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்திய ரிசர்வ் வங்கி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "$400 மில்லியன்",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்தியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜனவரி",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "$1.5 பில்லியன்",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "இரண்டு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "கூடுதல் $1 பில்லியன்",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்தியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "$500 மில்லியன்",
            "label": "MONEY"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "வீரசிங்க",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "61",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "700",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஏப்ரல்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "54.6%",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜூன்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "70%",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "வரும் மாதங்கள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "IMF",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஞாயிற்றுக்கிழமை",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இறுதி வாரம்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆகஸ்ட்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "நான்கு ஆண்டுகள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "IMF",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சுமார் $12 பில்லியன்",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஏப்ரல்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "$21 பில்லியன்",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "2025",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}