{
  "newspaper_id": "lankadeepa-lk",
  "url": "https://www.lankadeepa.lk/news/තුර්කි-යානයක්-කටුනායකදී-අනතුරක/101-615877",
  "time_ut": 1656989474,
  "original_lang": "si",
  "original_title": "තුර්කි යානයක් කටුනායකදී අනතුරක",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "A Turkish plane is in an accident in Katunayake",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "A Turkish Airlines cargo plane, which was about to take off, has crashed at the Katunayake airport due to strong winds.",
        "This is an A.-330-300 Airbus cargo plane belonging to Turkish Airlines.",
        "This plane had arrived at Katunayake Airport with cargo from Istanbul, Turkey.",
        "After that, this plane was preparing to depart from Katunayake Airport for Istanbul, Turkey, carrying a load of clothes made by \"Victoria's Secret Stores\", weighing 45 metric tons.",
        "At that time, due to the strong wind conditions at Katunayake Airport and its surrounding area, a container that had been brought to be loaded onto this aircraft, was parked near the relevant aircraft by the Sri Lankan Airlines airport operators without applying the brakes properly. This accident has happened when it was swept towards the plane and collided with its engine.",
        "Therefore, the necessary steps have not been taken by the Turkish aviation authorities to restore the engine damaged by the accident or to leave the Katunayake airport."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Turkish",
          "label": "NORP"
        },
        {
          "text": "Katunayake",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Turkish Airlines",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Katunayake",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "A.-330-300",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "Airbus",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Turkish Airlines",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Katunayake Airport",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "Istanbul",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Turkey",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Katunayake Airport",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "Istanbul",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Turkey",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Victoria's Secret Stores",
            "label": "WORK_OF_ART"
          },
          {
            "text": "45 metric tons",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Katunayake Airport",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Sri Lankan Airlines",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Turkish",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Katunayake",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "තුර්කි යානයක් කටුනායකදී අනතුරක",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "ගුවන් ගත කිරීමට සූදානමින් තිබූ තුර්කි ගුවන් සේවයට අයත් භාණ්ඩ ප්‍රවාහන ගුවන් යානයක්, දැඩි සුළං තත්ත්වයක් හේතුවෙන් කටුනායක ගුවන් තොටුපළේ දී අනතුරකට පත් වී තිබේ .",
        "මෙය තුර්කි ගුවන් සේවයට අයත් ඒ.- 330 - 300 එයා බස් වර්ගයේ භාණ්ඩ ප්‍රවාහන ගුවන් යානයකි .",
        "මෙම ගුවන් යානය තුර්කියේ ඉස්තාන්බුල් නුවර සිට භාණ්ඩ තොගයක් රැගෙන කටුනායක ගුවන් තොටුපළ වෙත පැමිණ තිබුණි .",
        "ඉන්පසුව \" වික්ටෝරියා සීක්‍රට් ස්ටෝර්ස් \" නිෂ්පාදිත , මෙට්‍රික් ටොන් 45 ක් බරැති ඇගලුම් තොගයක් රැගෙන , මෙම  ගුවන් යානය කටුනායක ගුවන් තොටුපළෙන් තුර්කියේ ඉස්තාන්බුල් නුවර බලා පිටත්ව යාමට සූදානම් වෙමින් තිබුණි .",
        "ඒ වනවිට කටුනායක ගුවන් තොටුපළ සහ ඒ අවට ප්‍රදේශයේ පැවති දැඩි සුළං තත්වය නිසා , මෙම ගුවන් යානයට පැටවීම සදහා රැගෙන විත් තිබූ බහාලුමක්, ශ්‍රී ලන්කන් ගුවන් සේවා ගුවන් අංගන මෙහෙයුම් ක්‍රියාකරුවන් විසින් නිසි පරිදි තිරිංග නොයොදා , අදාළ ගුවන් යානය අසළ නවතා තැබීමෙන් පසුව , එම බහාලුම ගුවන් යානය දෙසට ගසා ගෙන ගොස් එහි ඇංජිමක ගැටීමෙන් මෙම අනතුර සිදු වී තිබේ .",
        "එනිසා මෙම ගුවන් යානය මෙසේ අනතුරෙන් හානියට පත් වූ ඇංජිම යථා තත්වයට පත් කර ගැනීමට හෝ කටුනායක ගුවන් තොටුපළෙන් පිටත්ව යාමට අවශ්‍ය පියවර තුර්කි ගුවන් සේවා බලධාරීන් විසින් මේ වනතෙක් ගෙන නොමැත ."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "තුර්කි",
          "label": "NORP"
        },
        {
          "text": "කටුනායක",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "තුර්කි ගුවන් සේවය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "කටුනායක",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "A.-330-300",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "එයාර් බස්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "තුර්කි ගුවන් සේවය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "කටුනායක ගුවන් තොටුපළ",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉස්තාන්බුල්",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "කළුකුමා",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "කටුනායක ගුවන් තොටුපළ",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉස්තාන්බුල්",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "කළුකුමා",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "වික්ටෝරියා රහස් වෙළඳසැල්",
            "label": "WORK_OF_ART"
          },
          {
            "text": "මෙට්රික් ටොන් 45 කි",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "කටුනායක ගුවන් තොටුපළ",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකන් ගුවන් සේවය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "තුර්කි",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "කටුනායක",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "துருக்கி விமானம் ஒன்று கட்டுநாயக்கவில் விபத்துக்குள்ளானது",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "புறப்படவிருந்த துருக்கிய எயார்லைன்ஸ் சரக்கு விமானம் பலத்த காற்று காரணமாக கட்டுநாயக்க விமான நிலையத்தில் விபத்துக்குள்ளாகியுள்ளது.",
        "இது துருக்கிய ஏர்லைன்ஸ் நிறுவனத்திற்கு சொந்தமான ஏ.-330-300 ஏர்பஸ் சரக்கு விமானம்.",
        "இந்த விமானம் துருக்கியின் இஸ்தான்புல்லில் இருந்து சரக்குகளுடன் கட்டுநாயக்க விமான நிலையத்தை வந்தடைந்துள்ளது.",
        "அதன் பின்னர் இந்த விமானம் கட்டுநாயக்க விமான நிலையத்தில் இருந்து துருக்கியின் இஸ்தான்புல் நகருக்கு 45 மெட்ரிக் தொன் எடையுள்ள \"விக்டோரியாஸ் சீக்ரெட் ஸ்டோர்ஸ்\" தயாரித்த ஆடைகளை ஏற்றிக் கொண்டு புறப்பட தயாராகிக் கொண்டிருந்தது.",
        "அப்போது கட்டுநாயக்க விமான நிலையம் மற்றும் அதனை சூழவுள்ள பகுதியில் பலத்த காற்று வீசியதால் இந்த விமானத்தில் ஏற்றுவதற்காக கொண்டு வரப்பட்ட கொள்கலனை ஸ்ரீலங்கன் ஏர்லைன்ஸ் விமான நிலைய அதிகாரிகள் உரிய முறையில் பிரேக் போடாமல் உரிய விமானத்திற்கு அருகில் நிறுத்தி வைத்துள்ளனர். விமானத்தை நோக்கி இழுத்துச் செல்லப்பட்டு அதன் இயந்திரத்தில் மோதியதில் இந்த விபத்து ஏற்பட்டுள்ளது.",
        "எனவே, விபத்தினால் சேதமடைந்த இயந்திரத்தை மீட்கவோ அல்லது கட்டுநாயக்க விமான நிலையத்தை விட்டு வெளியேறவோ துருக்கி விமானப் போக்குவரத்து அதிகாரிகளால் தேவையான நடவடிக்கைகள் எடுக்கப்படவில்லை."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "துருக்கிய",
          "label": "NORP"
        },
        {
          "text": "கட்டுநாயக்கா",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "துருக்கி விமானம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "கட்டுநாயக்கா",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஏ.-330-300",
            "label": "MONEY"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஏர்பஸ்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "துருக்கி விமானம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "கட்டுநாயக்க விமான நிலையம்",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "இஸ்தான்புல்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "துருக்கி",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "கட்டுநாயக்க விமான நிலையம்",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "இஸ்தான்புல்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "துருக்கி",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "விக்டோரியா சீக்ரெட் ஸ்டோர்ஸ்",
            "label": "WORK_OF_ART"
          },
          {
            "text": "45 மெட்ரிக் டன்",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "கட்டுநாயக்க விமான நிலையம்",
            "label": "FAC"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஸ்ரீலங்கன் ஏர்லைன்ஸ்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "துருக்கிய",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "கட்டுநாயக்கா",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}