{
  "newspaper_id": "daily-ft-lk",
  "url": "https://www.ft.lk/news/Deputy-High-Commissioner-of-Sri-Lanka-in-Chennai-meets-Chief-Minister-and-Governor-of-Kerala/56-737564",
  "time_ut": 1657911268,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Deputy High Commissioner of Sri Lanka in Chennai meets Chief Minister and Governor of Kerala",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Deputy High Commissioner of Sri Lanka in Chennai meets Chief Minister and Governor of Kerala",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "Deputy High Commissioner of Sri Lanka in Chennai Dr. D. Venkateshwaran met Chief Minister of Kerala Pinarayi Vijayan and Governor of Kerala Arif Mohammad Khan on 30 June at Thiruvananthapuram, Kerala.",
        "In the meeting with the Chief Minister, held at the Kerala Legislative Assembly building, the Deputy High Commissioner highlighted the historical cultural bond and biogeographic similarity between Sri Lanka and Kerala, and appreciated the assistance given by India to Sri Lanka during these difficult times. The Deputy High Commissioner requested for the support of India at this critical juncture to which the Chief Minister agreed to look into the possibilities of extending assistance to Sri Lanka.",
        "The meeting with the Governor was held at Raj Bhavan, Thiruvananthapuram. As the Governor is, by virtue, the Chancellor of all Universities in the State of Kerala, discussions were focused on possible education, technical and scientific collaborations between Kerala and Sri Lankan universities as well as scholarships for Sri Lankan students in Kerala universities."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Kerala",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Chennai",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "D. Venkateshwaran",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kerala Pinarayi Vijayan",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kerala Arif Mohammad Khan",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "30 June",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Thiruvananthapuram",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kerala",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Kerala Legislative Assembly",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kerala",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "India",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "India",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Raj Bhavan",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Thiruvananthapuram",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the State of Kerala",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kerala",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lankan",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lankan",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kerala",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "චෙන්නායි හි ශ්‍රී ලංකා නියෝජ්‍ය මහ කොමසාරිස් කේරළ මහ ඇමති සහ ආණ්ඩුකාර හමුවෙයි",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "චෙන්නායි හි ශ්‍රී ලංකා නියෝජ්‍ය මහ කොමසාරිස් ආචාර්ය ඩී වෙන්කේෂ්වරන් ජූනි 30 වන දින කේරළයේ තිරුවනන්තපුරම් හිදී කේරළ ප්‍රධාන අමාත්‍ය පිනරායි විජයන් සහ කේරළ ආණ්ඩුකාර අරිෆ් මොහොමඩ් ඛාන් හමුවිය.",
        "ප්‍රධාන අමාත්‍යවරයා සමඟ කේරළ ව්‍යවස්ථාදායක සභා ගොඩනැඟිල්ලේ පැවැති සාකච්ඡාවේදී නියෝජ්‍ය මහ කොමසාරිස්වරයා ශ්‍රී ලංකාව සහ කේරළය අතර ඓතිහාසික සංස්කෘතික බැඳීම සහ ජෛව භූගෝලීය සමානත්වය ඉස්මතු කළ අතර, මෙම දුෂ්කර කාලවලදී ඉන්දියාව ශ්‍රී ලංකාවට ලබා දුන් සහය අගය කළේය. ශ්‍රී ලංකාවට ආධාර ලබාදීමේ හැකියාව සොයා බැලීමට මහ ඇමැතිවරයා එකඟ වූ මෙම තීරණාත්මක අවස්ථාවේදී නියෝජ්‍ය මහ කොමසාරිස්වරයා ඉන්දියාවේ සහාය ඉල්ලා සිටියේය.",
        "ආණ්ඩුකාරවරයාගේ හමුව තිරුවනන්තපුරම්හි රාජ් භවන්හිදී පැවැත්විණි. ආණ්ඩුකාරවරයා කේරළ ප්‍රාන්තයේ සියලුම විශ්ව විද්‍යාලවල කුලපතිවරයා වන බැවින්, කේරල සහ ශ්‍රී ලංකා විශ්ව විද්‍යාල අතර ඇති විය හැකි අධ්‍යාපන, තාක්ෂණික සහ විද්‍යාත්මක සහයෝගීතාවයන් මෙන්ම කේරළ විශ්ව විද්‍යාලවල ශ්‍රී ලාංකික සිසුන් සඳහා ශිෂ්‍යත්ව පිළිබඳව සාකච්ඡා කෙරේ."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "කේරල",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "චෙන්නායි",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඩී වෙන්කේෂ්වරන්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "කේරළ පිනරයි විජයන්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "කේරළ අරිෆ් මොහොමඩ් ඛාන්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "30 ජූනි",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "තිරුවානන්තපුරම්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "කේරල",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "කේරළ ව්යවස්ථාදායක සභාව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "කේරල",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "රාජ් භවන්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "තිරුවානන්තපුරම්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "කේරළ ප්රාන්තය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "කේරල",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලාංකික",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලාංකික",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "කේරල",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "சென்னையில் உள்ள இலங்கை துணை உயர் ஸ்தானிகர் கேரள முதல்வர் மற்றும் ஆளுநரை சந்தித்தார்",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "சென்னையில் உள்ள இலங்கையின் துணை உயர் ஸ்தானிகர் டாக்டர் டி. வெங்கடேஷ்வரன், கேரளாவின் திருவனந்தபுரத்தில் ஜூன் 30 அன்று கேரள முதல்வர் பினராயி விஜயன் மற்றும் கேரள ஆளுநர் ஆரிப் முகமது கான் ஆகியோரை சந்தித்தார்.",
        "கேரள சட்டப் பேரவைக் கட்டிடத்தில் நடைபெற்ற முதலமைச்சருடனான சந்திப்பில், இலங்கைக்கும் கேரளாவுக்கும் இடையிலான வரலாற்றுப் பண்பாட்டுப் பிணைப்பு மற்றும் உயிரியல் புவியியல் ஒற்றுமையை எடுத்துரைத்த துணை உயர்ஸ்தானிகர், இக்கட்டான காலங்களில் இலங்கைக்கு இந்தியா வழங்கிய உதவிகளைப் பாராட்டினார். இந்த இக்கட்டான தருணத்தில் இந்தியாவின் ஆதரவை பிரதி உயர்ஸ்தானிகர் கோரினார், இலங்கைக்கு உதவிகளை வழங்குவதற்கான சாத்தியக்கூறுகளை ஆராய முதலமைச்சர் ஒப்புக்கொண்டார்.",
        "திருவனந்தபுரம் ராஜ்பவனில் ஆளுநருடனான சந்திப்பு நடைபெற்றது. கேரள மாநிலத்தில் உள்ள அனைத்துப் பல்கலைக்கழகங்களின் வேந்தராக ஆளுநர் இருப்பதால், கேரள மற்றும் இலங்கைப் பல்கலைக்கழகங்களுக்கிடையில் சாத்தியமான கல்வி, தொழில்நுட்ப மற்றும் அறிவியல் ஒத்துழைப்புகள் மற்றும் கேரளப் பல்கலைக்கழகங்களில் உள்ள இலங்கை மாணவர்களுக்கு உதவித்தொகைகள் குறித்து கலந்துரையாடப்பட்டது."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "கேரளா",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "சென்னை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "டி.வெங்கடேஷ்வரன்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "கேரளா பினராயி விஜயன்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "கேரளா ஆரிப் முகமது கான்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "30 ஜூன்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "திருவனந்தபுரம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "கேரளா",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "கேரள சட்டமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "கேரளா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்தியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்தியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ராஜ் பவன்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "திருவனந்தபுரம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "கேரள மாநிலம்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "கேரளா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "கேரளா",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}