{
  "newspaper_id": "news-first-lk",
  "url": "https://www.newsfirst.lk/2022/06/27/navy-detains-54-people-for-illegal-migration-attempt/",
  "time_ut": 1656330000,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Navy detains 54 people for illegal migration attempt",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Navy detains 54 people for illegal migration attempt",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st): Sri Lanka Navy apprehended a local multiday fishing trawler with 54 individuals, suspected to be on an illegal migration attempt to Australia via sea, during a search operation carried out in the eastern seas of the island in the wee hours of today (27th June 2022).",
        "In the search operation mounted in seas east of Batticaloa this morning, SLNS Rathnadeepa intercepted a suspicious local multiday fishing trawler carrying 54 persons who were suspected to be attempting to illegally migrate from the island to Australia. Among the apprehended individuals were 52 males including 05 persons involved in this racket and 02 females. Along with the suspects, the fishing vessel used for this illegal act was also held by the Navy.",
        "The suspects held in this operation are residents of Batticaloa, Trincomalee, Mullaitivu and Jaffna, aged 19 to 53. They will be handed over to the Trincomalee Harbour Police for onward legal proceedings.",
        "Meanwhile, the Australian government does not sponsor such illegal immigrants, who are arrested and deported immediately. The Navy urges the public to avoid being convicted before the law by being caught in the trap of smugglers who mislead the innocent to earn fast buck. The Navy also warns the public that their lives could be in grave danger by attempting to make illegal immigration using unsafe vessels.",
        "Unbeaten knock by Chamari Athapaththu guides Sri Lanka to easy win against India Women",
        "US to provide technical assistance for fiscal management; High-Level delegates meet PM"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Navy",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "54",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "1st",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka Navy",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "54",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Australia",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the wee hours of today (27th June 2022",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Batticaloa",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "this morning",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "SLNS Rathnadeepa",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "54",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Australia",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "52",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "05",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "02",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Navy",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Batticaloa",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Trincomalee",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Mullaitivu",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Jaffna",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "19 to 53",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Trincomalee Harbour Police",
            "label": "FAC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Australian",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Navy",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Navy",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Chamari Athapaththu",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "India",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "US",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "නීතිවිරෝධී ලෙස සංක්‍රමණය වීමට උත්සාහ කළ පුද්ගලයින් 54 දෙනෙකු නාවික හමුදාව විසින් අත්අඩංගුවට ගෙන තිබේ",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st) : ශ්‍රී ලංකා නාවික හමුදාව විසින් අලුයම දිවයිනේ නැඟෙනහිර මුහුදු ප්‍රදේශයේ සිදු කළ සෝදිසි මෙහෙයුමකදී පුද්ගලයින් 54 දෙනෙකු සමඟ මුහුදු මාර්ගයෙන් නීතිවිරෝධී ලෙස ඕස්ට්‍රේලියාවට සංක්‍රමණය වීමට උත්සාහ කළ බවට සැක කෙරෙන දේශීය බහුදින ධීවර යාත්‍රාවක් අත්අඩංගුවට ගෙන ඇත. අද (2022 ජුනි 27)",
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකා නාවික නෞකා රත්නදීප නෞකාව අද පෙරවරුවේ මඩකලපුවට නැගෙනහිරින් වූ මුහුදු ප්‍රදේශයේ සිදුකළ සෝදිසි මෙහෙයුමකදී නීතිවිරෝධී ලෙස දිවයිනේ සිට ඕස්ට්‍රේලියාවට සංක්‍රමණය වීමට උත්සාහ කළ බවට සැක කෙරෙන පුද්ගලයින් 54 දෙනෙකු රැගත් සැක කටයුතු දේශීය බහුදින ධීවර යාත්‍රාවක් අත්අඩංගුවට ගෙන ඇත. අත්අඩංගුවට ගත් පුද්ගලයින් අතර මෙම ජාවාරමට සම්බන්ධ පුද්ගලයින් 05 දෙනෙකු සහ කාන්තාවන් 02 දෙනෙකු ඇතුළු පිරිමි පුද්ගලයින් 52 දෙනෙකු ද වනවා. සැකකරුවන් සමඟ මෙම නීතිවිරෝධී ක්‍රියාව සඳහා යොදාගත් ධීවර යාත්‍රාව ද නාවික හමුදාව සතුව තිබී ඇත.",
        "මෙම මෙහෙයුමේදී අත්අඩංගුවට ගත් සැකකරුවන් මඩකලපුව, ත්‍රිකුණාමලය, මුලතිව් සහ යාපනය යන ප්‍රදේශවල පදිංචි අවුරුදු 19 ත් 53 ත් අතර වයස්වල පසුවන්නන් වන අතර, ඔවුන් ඉදිරි නීතිමය කටයුතු සඳහා ත්‍රිකුණාමලය වරාය පොලිසිය වෙත භාර දීමට නියමිතය.",
        "මේ අතර, ඕස්ට්‍රේලියානු රජය එවැනි නීති විරෝධී සංක්‍රමණිකයන්ට අනුග්‍රහය නොදක්වන අතර, ඔවුන් අත්අඩංගුවට ගෙන වහාම පිටුවහල් කරනු ලැබේ. කඩිනමින් මුදල් උපයා ගැනීම සඳහා අහිංසකයින් නොමඟ යවන ජාවාරම්කරුවන්ගේ උගුලට හසුවී නීතිය ඉදිරියේ වරදකරුවන් වීමෙන් වළකින ලෙස නාවික හමුදාව ජනතාවගෙන් ඉල්ලා සිටියි. අනාරක්ෂිත යාත්‍රා භාවිත කරමින් නීතිවිරෝධී සංක්‍රමණ සිදු කිරීමට උත්සාහ කිරීම තුළින් තම ජීවිතවලට දැඩි තර්ජනයක් එල්ල විය හැකි බවට ද නාවික හමුදාව ජනතාවට අනතුරු අඟවනවා.",
        "චමරි අතපත්තුගේ අපරාජිත පහරක් ඉන්දීය කාන්තා පිලට එරෙහිව පහසු ජයක් කරා ශ්‍රී ලංකාව මෙහෙයවයි",
        "රාජ්‍ය මූල්‍ය කළමනාකරණය සඳහා තාක්ෂණික සහාය ලබාදීමට එක්සත් ජනපදය; ඉහළ පෙළේ නියෝජිතයන් අගමැති හමුවෙයි"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "නාවික",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "54",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "1 වැනි",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකා නාවික හමුදාව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "54",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඕස්ට්රේලියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "අද අලුයම (2022 ජුනි 27)",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "මඩකලපුව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මේ උදෑසන",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකා නාවික නෞකා රත්නදීප",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "54",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඕස්ට්රේලියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "52",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "05",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "02",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "නාවික",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "මඩකලපුව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ත්රිකුණාමලය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "මුලතිව්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "යාපනය",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "19 සිට 53 දක්වා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ත්‍රිකුණාමලය වරාය පොලිසිය",
            "label": "FAC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ඕස්ට්රේලියානු",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "නාවික",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "නාවික",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "චමරි අතපත්තු",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දියාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "එක්සත් ජනපදය",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "சட்டவிரோத குடியேற்ற முயற்சியில் ஈடுபட்ட 54 பேரை கடற்படையினர் கைது செய்துள்ளனர்",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "COLOMBO (News 1st): கடல் வழியாக அவுஸ்திரேலியாவுக்கு சட்டவிரோதமாக குடியேற முயற்சித்ததாக சந்தேகிக்கப்படும் 54 நபர்களுடன் உள்ளூர் பல நாள் மீன்பிடி இழுவை படகு இலங்கை கடற்படையால் நேற்று அதிகாலை தீவின் கிழக்கு கடற்பகுதியில் மேற்கொள்ளப்பட்ட தேடுதல் நடவடிக்கையின் போது கைப்பற்றப்பட்டது. இன்று (27 ஜூன் 2022).",
        "இன்று காலை மட்டக்களப்புக்கு கிழக்கே கடற்பகுதியில் மேற்கொள்ளப்பட்ட தேடுதல் நடவடிக்கையின் போது, ​​இலங்கை கடற்படையினர் 54 பேரை ஏற்றிச் சென்ற சந்தேகத்திற்கிடமான உள்ளூர் பல நாள் மீன்பிடி இழுவை படகு, தீவில் இருந்து அவுஸ்திரேலியாவிற்கு சட்டவிரோதமாக இடம்பெயர்வதற்கு முயற்சித்ததாக சந்தேகிக்கப்படுகிறது. கைது செய்யப்பட்டவர்களில் இந்த மோசடியில் ஈடுபட்ட 05 பேர் மற்றும் 02 பெண்கள் உட்பட 52 ஆண்களும் அடங்குவர். சந்தேகநபர்களுடன், இந்த சட்டவிரோத செயலுக்கு பயன்படுத்தப்பட்ட மீன்பிடி கப்பலும் கடற்படையினரின் வசம் இருந்தது.",
        "கைது செய்யப்பட்ட சந்தேகநபர்கள் மட்டக்களப்பு, திருகோணமலை, முல்லைத்தீவு மற்றும் யாழ்ப்பாணம் ஆகிய இடங்களைச் சேர்ந்த 19 முதல் 53 வயதுடையவர்கள். அவர்கள் திருகோணமலை துறைமுக பொலிஸாரிடம் மேலதிக சட்ட நடவடிக்கைகளுக்காக ஒப்படைக்கப்படவுள்ளனர்.",
        "இதற்கிடையில், ஆஸ்திரேலிய அரசாங்கம் அத்தகைய சட்டவிரோத குடியேறிகளுக்கு ஆதரவளிப்பதில்லை, அவர்கள் கைது செய்யப்பட்டு உடனடியாக நாடு கடத்தப்படுகிறார்கள். துரித கதியில் பணம் சம்பாதிப்பதற்காக அப்பாவிகளை தவறாக வழிநடத்தும் கடத்தல்காரர்களின் வலையில் சிக்கி சட்டத்தின் முன் குற்றவாளிகள் ஆவதை தவிர்க்குமாறு கடற்படை பொதுமக்களை கேட்டுக்கொண்டுள்ளது. பாதுகாப்பற்ற கப்பல்களை பயன்படுத்தி சட்டவிரோத குடியேற்றத்தை மேற்கொள்ள முயற்சிப்பதன் மூலம் பொதுமக்களின் உயிருக்கு பாரிய ஆபத்து ஏற்படும் எனவும் கடற்படை எச்சரித்துள்ளது.",
        "சாமரி அதபத்துவின் ஆட்டமிழக்காமல், இந்தியப் பெண்களுக்கு எதிராக இலங்கையை எளிதாக வெற்றி பெற வழிவகுத்தது",
        "நிதி நிர்வாகத்திற்கான தொழில்நுட்ப உதவியை வழங்க அமெரிக்கா; உயர்மட்ட பிரதிநிதிகள் பிரதமரை சந்திக்கின்றனர்"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "கடற்படை",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "54",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "1வது",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை கடற்படை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "54",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆஸ்திரேலியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்றைய அதிகாலை நேரம் (27 ஜூன் 2022",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "மட்டக்களப்பு",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று காலை",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "SLNS ரத்னதீப",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "54",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆஸ்திரேலியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "52",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "05",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "02",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "கடற்படை",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "மட்டக்களப்பு",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "திருகோணமலை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "முல்லைத்தீவு",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "யாழ்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "19 முதல் 53 வரை",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "திருகோணமலை துறைமுக காவல்துறை",
            "label": "FAC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஆஸ்திரேலியன்",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "கடற்படை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "கடற்படை",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "சாமரி அதபத்து",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்தியா",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "எங்களுக்கு",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}