{
  "newspaper_id": "ada-lk",
  "url": "https://www.ada.lk/breaking_news/පොලිස්-වෙඩි-තැබීමකින්-පාතාල-කල්ලි-සාමාජිකයෙක්-මරුට/11-395065",
  "time_ut": 1656910851,
  "original_lang": "si",
  "original_title": "පොලිස් වෙඩි තැබීමකින් පාතාල කල්ලි සාමාජිකයෙක් මරුට",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "An underworld gang member was killed in police firing",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "Joseph Kumara, who is said to be an underworld gang member, was killed in a shootout with the police in Gampaha, Bemmulla area this morning (4th), police said.",
        "The police have identified him as a 41-year-old resident of Dargatown, Alpitiya who had served in the army for some time.",
        "When a group of officers from the Colombo Crime Investigation Division raided the house early this morning on a tip-off that he was in a house in the Ulagama area under the Gampaha police jurisdiction, it was found that his motorcycle overturned near Bemmulla, Bandarabatawala Velaya while the police officers were chasing him after he fled on a motorcycle. The police said that Joseph was shot and killed when the police officers overturned and shot at the van in which the police officers were traveling with a firearm that he had in his hand.",
        "A T-56 type firearm and an ammunition bag containing live bullets have been taken into police custody and the van in which the police officers were traveling has been damaged by the gunfire, the police say.",
        "Regarding this incident, as per the instructions of Mr. Deshbandu, Senior DIG in charge of Western Province, under the supervision of Mr. Mahinda Dissanayake, DIG in charge of Western Province, North and Mr. Indika De Silva, Senior Superintendent of Police in charge of Gampaha Division, Bemmulla Police is conducting further investigations under the direction of Gampaha Assistant Superintendent of Police, Mr. Thusitha Kumara. Meanwhile, the magistrate's inquest was scheduled to be held."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Joseph Kumara",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Gampaha",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Bemmulla",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "this morning",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "4th",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "41-year-old",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Dargatown",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Alpitiya",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the Colombo Crime Investigation Division",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "early this morning",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ulagama",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Gampaha",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Bemmulla",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Bandarabatawala",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Velaya",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Joseph",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "Deshbandu",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Western Province",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Mahinda Dissanayake",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Western Province",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "North",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Indika De Silva",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Gampaha Division",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Bemmulla Police",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Gampaha Assistant Superintendent of Police",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Thusitha Kumara",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "පොලිස් වෙඩි තැබීමකින් පාතාල කල්ලි සාමාජිකයෙක් මරුට",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "පාතාල කල්ලි සාමාජිකයෙකු බව කියන ඉහළ විතානගේ ජෝශප් කුමාර නමැත්තා ගම්පහ, බෙම්මුල්ල ප්‍රදේශයේදී අද (4දා) උදෑසන පොලීසිය සමග ඇතිවූ වෙඩි හුවමාරුවකදී ජීවිතක්ෂයට පත්වූ බව පොලීසිය පවසයි.",
        "මොහු ඇල්පිටිය , දර්ගාටවුන් ප්‍රදේශයේ පදිංචි 41 හැවිරිදි කලක් යුද හමුදාවේ සේවය කළ අයෙකු බවට හදුනාගෙන ඇති බවද පොලීසිය සදහන් කරයි.",
        "මොහු ගම්පහ පොලිස් බල ප්‍රදේශයට අයත් ඉහළගම ප්‍රදේශයේ නිවසක සිටින බවට ලද තොරතුරක් මත කොළඹ අපරාධ විමර්ශන කොට්ඨාසයේ නිලධාරීන් පිරිසක් විසින් අද අලුයම එම නිවස වැටලීමට ගිය අවස්ථාවේ යතුරු පැදියක නැග පලායාම මත පොලිස් නිලධාරීන් පසුපසින් හඹා යමින් සිටියදී බෙම්මුල්ල, බණ්ඩාරබටවල වෙල්යාය අසලදී ඔහුගේ යතුරු පැදිය පෙරලී ඇති බවත් එම අවස්ථාවේ ඔහු අත තිබූ ගිනි අවියකින් පොලිස් නිලධාරීන් ගමන්ගත් වෑන් රථයට වෙඩි තැබීම මත පොලිස් නිලධාරීන් පෙරලා වෙඩි තැබීමේදී ජෝශප් නමැත්තාට වෙඩි වැදී ජීවිතක්ෂයට පත්ව ඇති බවත් පොලීසිය පවසයි.",
        "පොලිස් නිලධාරීන්ට වෙඩි තැබූ බව කියන ටී 56 වර්ගයේ ගිනි අවියක් සහ ජීව උණ්ඩ සහිත පතරොම් ගැබක් පොලිස් බාරයට ගෙන ඇති අතර වෙඩි වැදීමෙන් පොලිස් නිලධාරීන් ගමන්ගත් වෑන් රථයට හානිවී ඇති බවද පොලීසිය කියයි.",
        "මෙම සිද්ධිය සම්බන්ධයෙන් බස්නාහිර පළාත භාර ජේෂ්ඨ නියෝජ්‍ය පොලිස්පති දේශබන්දු මහතාගේ උපදෙස් පරිදි බස්නාහිර පළාත උතුර බාර නියෝජ්‍ය පොලිස්පති මහින්ද දිසානායක සහ ගම්පහ කොට්ඨාසය භාර ජේෂ්ඨ පොලිස් අධිකාරී ඉන්දික ද  සිල්වා යන මහත්වරුන්ගේ අධීක්ෂණය මත ගම්පහ සහකාර පොලිස් අධිකාරී තුසිත කුමාර මහතාගේ මෙහෙයවීම යටතේ බෙම්මුල්ල පොලීසිය වැඩිදුර පරීක්ෂණ සිදු කරන අතර මහේස්ත්‍රාත් මරණ පරීක්ෂණය පැවැත්වීමට නියමිතව තිබිණි."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ජෝශප් කුමාර",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගම්පහ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "බෙම්මුල්ල",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "මේ උදෑසන",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "4 වැනි",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "41 හැවිරිදිය",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඩාර්ගාටවුන්",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "අල්පිටිය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "කොළඹ අපරාධ විමර්ශන කොට්ඨාශය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "අද උදේ පාන්දර",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "උලගම",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගම්පහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "බෙම්මුල්ල",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "බණ්ඩාරබටවල",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "වේලය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජෝසප්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "දේශබන්දු",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "බස්නාහිර පළාත",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මහින්ද දිසානායක",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "බස්නාහිර පළාත",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "උතුරු",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දික ද සිල්වා",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගම්පහ කොට්ඨාසය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "බෙම්මුල්ල පොලිසිය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගම්පහ සහකාර පොලිස් අධිකාරි",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "තුසිත කුමාර",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "பொலிஸாரின் துப்பாக்கிச் சூட்டில் பாதாள உலகக் குழு உறுப்பினர் ஒருவர் உயிரிழந்துள்ளார்",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "இன்று (4ஆம் திகதி) காலை கம்பஹா, பெமுல்ல பிரதேசத்தில் பொலிஸாருடன் இடம்பெற்ற துப்பாக்கிச் சூட்டில் பாதாள உலகக் குழு உறுப்பினர் எனக் கூறப்படும் ஜோசப் குமார உயிரிழந்துள்ளதாக பொலிஸார் தெரிவித்தனர்.",
        "இவர் அல்பிட்டி தர்காடவுன் பகுதியைச் சேர்ந்த 41 வயதுடைய இராணுவத்தில் சில காலம் கடமையாற்றியவர் என பொலிஸார் அடையாளம் கண்டுள்ளனர்.",
        "கம்பஹா பொலிஸ் எல்லைக்குட்பட்ட உலகம பிரதேசத்தில் உள்ள வீடொன்றில் அவர் இருப்பதாக கிடைத்த இரகசிய தகவலையடுத்து கொழும்பு குற்றப்புலனாய்வு பிரிவின் அதிகாரிகள் குழு இன்று அதிகாலை அந்த வீட்டை சுற்றிவளைத்த போது, ​​பெம்முல்ல, பண்டாரபதவல வேலாயவிற்கு அருகில் அவரது மோட்டார் சைக்கிள் கவிழ்ந்துள்ளது. மோட்டார் சைக்கிளில் தப்பிச் சென்ற அவரை பொலிஸ் அதிகாரிகள் துரத்திச் சென்ற போது, ​​அவர் கையில் வைத்திருந்த துப்பாக்கியுடன் பொலிஸ் உத்தியோகத்தர்கள் பயணித்த வேனை பொலிஸ் அதிகாரிகள் கவிழ்த்து சுட்டதில் ஜோசப் சுட்டுக் கொல்லப்பட்டதாக பொலிஸார் தெரிவித்தனர்.",
        "T-56 ரக துப்பாக்கி மற்றும் தோட்டாக்கள் அடங்கிய தோட்டாக்கள் பொலிஸாரால் கைப்பற்றப்பட்டுள்ளதுடன், பொலிஸ் உத்தியோகத்தர்கள் பயணித்த வேனும் துப்பாக்கிச் சூட்டில் சேதமடைந்துள்ளதாக பொலிஸார் தெரிவிக்கின்றனர்.",
        "இச்சம்பவம் தொடர்பாக மேல்மாகாண சிரேஷ்ட பிரதிப் பொலிஸ் மா அதிபர் தேஷ்பந்துவின் பணிப்புரையின் பிரகாரம் மேல்மாகாண பிரதிப் பொலிஸ் மா அதிபர் மஹிந்த திஸாநாயக்க மற்றும் சிரேஷ்ட பொலிஸ் அத்தியட்சகர் இந்திக டி சில்வா ஆகியோரின் மேற்பார்வையில் கம்பஹா உதவிப் பொலிஸ் அத்தியட்சகர் திரு.துசித குமார தலைமையில் கம்பஹா பிரிவுக்குட்பட்ட பெமுல்ல பொலிஸார் மேலதிக விசாரணைகளை மேற்கொண்டு வருகின்றனர்.இதேவேளை, நீதவான் விசாரணைகள் நடைபெறவிருந்தன."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ஜோசப் குமார",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "கம்பஹா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "பெம்முல்லா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று காலை",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "4வது",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "41 வயது",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "தர்காடவுன்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "அல்பிட்டிய",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "கொழும்பு குற்றப் புலனாய்வுப் பிரிவு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று அதிகாலை",
            "label": "TIME"
          },
          {
            "text": "உலகம",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "கம்பஹா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "பெம்முல்லா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "பண்டாரபதாவல",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "வேலயா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜோசப்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "தேஷ்பந்து",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "மேல் மாகாணம்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "மஹிந்த திசாநாயக்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "மேல் மாகாணம்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "வடக்கு",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்திக்க டி சில்வா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "கம்பஹா பிரிவு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "பெமுல்லா காவல்துறை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "கம்பஹா உதவி பொலிஸ் அத்தியட்சகர்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "துசித குமார",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}