{
  "newspaper_id": "daily-mirror-lk",
  "url": "https://www.dailymirror.lk/latest_news/Price-of-bread-could-rise-to-Rs-300-Assn/342-243945",
  "time_ut": 1661789219,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Price of bread could rise to Rs.300? - Assn.",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Price of bread could rise to Rs.300? - Assn.",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "The price of a loaf of 450g bread have to be sold at Rs. 300 in the coming days, if the price of a bag of wheat flour does not  one down and the shortage is not resolved, according to the All Ceylon Bakery Owners' Association (ACBOA).",
        "ACBOA President N.K. Jayawardene told the Daily Mirror that there is a huge shortage of wheat flour in the local market and the available stocks are being sold at a very higher price.",
        "The current selling price of a 50 kg bag of wheat flour has gone up by Rs.20,000, but we are unable to locate any.",
        "If we get flour for Rs.20,000 somehow, the selling price of a loaf of bread has to be sold for Rs.300, which is definitely beyond the reach of consumers.",
        "\"Apart from that, the price of other bakery items would also be increased by similar proportions. \"Accordingly, the price of a bun will be sold for Rs. 100,\" he said. (Chaturanga Samarawickrama)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "450",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "300",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "the coming days",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ACBOA",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ACBOA",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "N.K. Jayawardene",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Daily Mirror",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "50 kg",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "100",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Chaturanga Samarawickrama",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "පාන් මිල රුපියල් 300 දක්වා ඉහළ යා හැකිද? - සහකාර",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "ග්‍රෑම් 450 පාන් ගෙඩියක මිල රු. සමස්ත ලංකා බේකරි හිමියන්ගේ සංගමයට (ACBOA) අනුව ඉදිරි දිනවලදී තිරිඟු පිටි බෑගයක මිල අඩු නොවන්නේ නම් සහ හිඟය නොවිසඳෙන්නේ නම් රුපියල් 300ක්.",
        "ACBOA සභාපති එන්.කේ. ජයවර්ධන ඩේලි මිරර් වෙත කියා සිටියේ දේශීය වෙළෙඳපොළේ තිරිඟු පිටි විශාල හිඟයක් පවතින බවත් පවතින තොග ඉතා ඉහළ මිලකට අලෙවි කරන බවත්ය.",
        "දැනට අලෙවි කරන තිරිඟු පිටි කිලෝග්‍රෑම් 50 බෑගයක මිල රුපියල් 20,000 කින් ඉහළ ගොස් ඇති නමුත් අපට කිසිවක් සොයා ගැනීමට නොහැකි වී තිබේ.",
        "කොහොම හරි රුපියල් 20,000ට පිටි ගත්තොත් පාන් ගෙඩියක විකුණුම් මිල රුපියල් 300කට විකුණන්න වෙනවා, ඒක අනිවාර්යයෙන්ම පාරිභෝගිකයාට දරාගන්න බැරි දෙයක්.",
        "\"ඊට අමතරව අනෙකුත් බේකරි භාණ්ඩවල මිල ද මීට සමාන අනුපාතයකින් ඉහළ යනු ඇත. \"ඒ අනුව බනිස් ගෙඩියක මිල රු. 100,\" ඔහු පැවසීය. (චතුරංග සමරවික්‍රම)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "450",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "300",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉදිරි දින",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ACBOA",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ACBOA",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "එන්.කේ. ජයවර්ධන ය",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඩේලි මිරර්",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "කිලෝ ග්රෑම් 50 කි",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "100",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "චතුරංග සමරවික්‍රම",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "ரொட்டி விலை ரூ.300 ஆக கூடுமா? - உதவியாளர்.",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "450 கிராம் ரொட்டி ஒன்றின் விலை ரூ. வரவிருக்கும் நாட்களில், கோதுமை மாவின் ஒரு பையின் விலை குறையாமலும், தட்டுப்பாடு தீர்க்கப்படாமலும் இருந்தால், அகில இலங்கை பேக்கரி உரிமையாளர்கள் சங்கம் (ACBOA) தெரிவித்துள்ளது.",
        "ACBOA தலைவர் என்.கே. உள்ளூர் சந்தையில் கோதுமை மாவுக்கு பாரிய தட்டுப்பாடு நிலவுவதாகவும், இருப்புக்கள் மிக அதிக விலைக்கு விற்கப்படுவதாகவும் ஜெயவர்தன டெய்லி மிரருக்கு தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "50 கிலோகிராம் கோதுமை மாவின் தற்போதைய விற்பனை விலை ரூ.20,000 உயர்ந்துள்ளது, ஆனால் எங்களால் எதையும் கண்டுபிடிக்க முடியவில்லை.",
        "எப்படியாவது ரூ.20,000க்கு மாவு கிடைத்தால், ஒரு ரொட்டியின் விற்பனை விலை ரூ.300-க்கு விற்கப்பட வேண்டும் என்பது நிச்சயம் நுகர்வோருக்கு எட்டாத ஒன்று.",
        "\"அது தவிர, மற்ற பேக்கரி பொருட்களின் விலையும் இதே விகிதத்தில் அதிகரிக்கப்படும். \"அதன்படி, ஒரு பன் விலை ரூ. 100,\" என்றார். (சதுரங்க சமரவிக்ரம)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "450",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "300",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "வரும் நாட்கள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஏசிபிஓஏ",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஏசிபிஓஏ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "என்.கே. ஜெயவர்த்தனே",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "டெய்லி மிரர்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "50 கிலோ",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "100",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "சதுரங்க சமரவிக்ரம",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}