{
  "newspaper_id": "economy-next-com",
  "url": "https://economynext.com/sri-lanka-to-raise-vat-to-15-percent-from-sep-1-president-99181/",
  "time_ut": 1661846820,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Sri Lanka to raise VAT to 15 percent from Sep 1: president",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Sri Lanka to raise VAT to 15 percent from Sep 1: president",
      "author": "",
      "body_lines": [
        "ECONOMYNEXT – Sri Lanka will increase value-added tax (VAT) to 15 percent from the current 12 percent starting September 01, President Ranil Wickremesinghe said.",
        "Presenting an interim budget for the remainder of the year, Wickremesinghe told parliament on Tuesday August 30 that it was unfortunate that the fiscal path Sri Lanka was set on from the years to 2019 was changed.",
        "His predecessor, President Gotabaya Rajapaksa, made sweeping changes to Sri Lanka’s tax regime, which experts say contributed significantly to the country’s prevailing economic crisis, the worst since its Independence from the British. (Colombo/Aug30/2022)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Sri Lanka",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "VAT to",
          "label": "PERCENT"
        },
        {
          "text": "15 percent",
          "label": "PERCENT"
        },
        {
          "text": "1",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "15 percent",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "12 percent",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "September 01",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the year",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Tuesday August 30",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the years to 2019",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Gotabaya Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka’s",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "British",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "ශ්‍රී ලංකාව සැප්තැම්බර් 1 වැනිදා සිට වැට් බද්ද සියයට 15 දක්වා ඉහළ දමන බව ජනපති කියයි",
      "author": "",
      "body_lines": [
        "ECONOMYNEXT - ශ්‍රී ලංකාව සැප්තැම්බර් 01 වැනිදා සිට අගය එකතු කළ බද්ද (වැට්) දැනට පවතින සියයට 12 සිට සියයට 15 දක්වා වැඩි කරන බව ජනාධිපති රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතා පැවසීය.",
        "වසරේ ඉතිරි කාලය සඳහා අතුරු අයවැයක් ඉදිරිපත් කරමින් වික්‍රමසිංහ අගෝස්තු 30 අඟහරුවාදා පාර්ලිමේන්තුවට පැවසුවේ ශ්‍රී ලංකාව වසර 2019 දක්වා සකස් කළ මූල්‍ය මාවත වෙනස් කිරීම අවාසනාවන්ත බවයි.",
        "ඔහුගේ පූර්වගාමියා වූ ජනාධිපති ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ, ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ බදු තන්ත්‍රයේ විශාල වෙනස්කම් සිදු කළ අතර, එය බ්‍රිතාන්‍යයන්ගෙන් නිදහස ලැබීමෙන් පසු රටේ පවතින දරුණුතම ආර්ථික අර්බුදයට සැලකිය යුතු දායකත්වයක් ලබා දුන් බව විශේෂඥයෝ පවසති. (කොළඹ/අගෝස්තු 30/2022)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "වැට් බද්ද",
          "label": "PERCENT"
        },
        {
          "text": "සියයට 15 කි",
          "label": "PERCENT"
        },
        {
          "text": "1",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "සියයට 15 කි",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "සියයට 12 කි",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "සැප්තැම්බර් 01",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "වසර",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "අගෝස්තු 30 අඟහරුවාදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "2019 දක්වා වසර",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "බ්රිතාන්ය",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "இலங்கையில் செப்.1 முதல் VAT 15 சதவீதமாக உயர்த்தப்படும்: ஜனாதிபதி",
      "author": "",
      "body_lines": [
        "ECONOMYNEXT – இலங்கையானது செப்டம்பர் 01 ஆம் திகதி முதல் தற்போதைய 12 வீதத்தில் இருந்து பெறுமதி சேர் வரியை (VAT) 15 வீதமாக அதிகரிக்கவுள்ளதாக ஜனாதிபதி ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க தெரிவித்துள்ளார்.",
        "எஞ்சிய ஆண்டிற்கான இடைக்கால வரவுசெலவுத் திட்டத்தை முன்வைத்த விக்கிரமசிங்க, ஆகஸ்ட் 30 செவ்வாய்கிழமை நாடாளுமன்றத்தில், இலங்கையின் நிதியப் பாதையானது வருடங்களில் இருந்து 2019 வரை மாற்றப்பட்டிருப்பது துரதிர்ஷ்டவசமானது என்று கூறினார்.",
        "அவரது முன்னோடியான ஜனாதிபதி கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ச, இலங்கையின் வரி விதிப்பில் பெரும் மாற்றங்களைச் செய்தார், இது நாட்டின் நிலவும் பொருளாதார நெருக்கடிக்கு கணிசமான பங்களிப்பை வழங்கியதாக நிபுணர்கள் கூறுகின்றனர், இது பிரித்தானியரிடம் இருந்து சுதந்திரம் பெற்ற பின்னர் மிக மோசமானதாகும். (கொழும்பு/ஆகஸ்ட்30/2022)"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "இலங்கை",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "VAT க்கு",
          "label": "PERCENT"
        },
        {
          "text": "15 சதவீதம்",
          "label": "PERCENT"
        },
        {
          "text": "1",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "15 சதவீதம்",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "12 சதவீதம்",
            "label": "PERCENT"
          },
          {
            "text": "செப்டம்பர் 01",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஆண்டு",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆகஸ்ட் 30 செவ்வாய்கிழமை",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "2019 வரையிலான ஆண்டுகள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கையின்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "பிரிட்டிஷ்",
            "label": "NORP"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}