{
  "newspaper_id": "economy-next-com",
  "url": "https://economynext.com/sri-lankas-independent-parties-to-launch-grand-coalition-on-september-04-99144/",
  "time_ut": 1661758140,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Sri Lanka’s “independent” parties to launch grand coalition on September 04",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Sri Lanka’s “independent” parties to launch grand coalition on September 04",
      "author": "",
      "body_lines": [
        "ECONOMYNEXT – A collective of eleven former coalition partners of Sri Lanka’s ruling alliance that now sit independently in parliament will form a grand alliance together with other parties on September 04, former minister Wimal Weerawansa said.",
        "Weerawansa told reporters on Monday August 29 that the 11 parties, together with other parties he did not name, will announce the new “historic” coalition at an event to be held at the Maharagama youth centre on September 04.",
        "“It will be a progressive, pro-people coalition founded not just to overcome the present crisis but one that can rise to future challenges as well,” he said.",
        "Asked about the proposed all-party government which has yet to be formed, Weerawansa said leaders of the parties that represent parliament have been unable to come to a consensus on how to help the people out the economic crisis, the worst Sri Lanka has faced since Independence.",
        "He accused the parties of looking out for their individual interests rather than coming up with a plan to solve the crisis.",
        "The former Industries Minister, who was sacked from the government of former President Gotabaya Rajapaksa, said there is no point continuing talks with the incumbent government of President Ranil Wickremesinghe about an all-party government.",
        "“We have engaged in discussions [with the government]. There is no point in continuing discussions without coming to a workable programme. We don’t see that happening,” he said.",
        "Weerawansa’s alliance includes former influential members of the Rajapaksa government Udaya Gammanpila and Vasudevaa Nanayakkara.",
        "Nanayakkara has gone on record that he and the Democratic Left Front he leads cannot support Sri Lanka’s “IMF-bound” “caretaker” president.",
        "Cannot support Sri Lanka’s IMF-bound “caretaker” president: MP Vasudeva N"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Sri Lanka",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "September 04",
          "label": "DATE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "eleven",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "September 04",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Wimal Weerawansa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Monday August 29",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "11",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "September 04",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Independence",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "Gotabaya Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "Rajapaksa",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Udaya Gammanpila",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Vasudevaa Nanayakkara",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the Democratic Left Front",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka’s",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ \"ස්වාධීන\" පක්ෂ සැප්තැම්බර් 04 දා මහා සභාගය දියත් කිරීමට නියමිතය",
      "author": "",
      "body_lines": [
        "ECONOMYNEXT - දැන් පාර්ලිමේන්තුවේ ස්වාධීනව අසුන්ගෙන සිටින ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ පාලක සන්ධානයේ හිටපු සභාග හවුල්කරුවන් එකොළොස් දෙනෙකුගේ එකතුවක් සැප්තැම්බර් 04 වැනි දින අනෙකුත් පක්ෂ සමඟ එක්ව මහා සන්ධානයක් පිහිටුවන බව හිටපු අමාත්‍ය විමල් වීරවංශ මහතා පැවසීය.",
        "වීරවංශ අගෝස්තු 29 සඳුදා මාධ්‍යවේදීන් අමතමින් කියා සිටියේ පක්ෂ 11 සහ ඔහු නම් නොකළ අනෙකුත් පක්ෂ එක්ව සැප්තැම්බර් 04 මහරගම තරුණ මධ්‍යස්ථානයේ පැවැත්වෙන උත්සවයකදී නව “ඓතිහාසික” සන්ධානය ප්‍රකාශයට පත් කරන බවයි.",
        "\"එය වර්තමාන අර්බුදය ජය ගැනීම සඳහා පමණක් නොව අනාගත අභියෝගවලටද නැඟී යා හැකි ප්‍රගතිශීලී, ජනතා හිතවාදී සන්ධානයක් වනු ඇත,\" ඔහු පැවසීය.",
        "තවමත් පිහිටුවා නොමැති යෝජිත සර්ව පාක්ෂික ආණ්ඩුව පිළිබඳව විමසූ විට වීරවංශ කියා සිටියේ, ශ්‍රී ලංකාව එදා සිට මුහුණ දී ඇති දරුණුතම ආර්ථික අර්බුදයෙන් ජනතාවට සහන සලසන්නේ කෙසේද යන්න පිළිබඳව පාර්ලිමේන්තුව නියෝජනය කරන පක්ෂවල නායකයින්ට එකඟතාවකට පැමිණීමට නොහැකි වී ඇති බවයි. නිදහස.",
        "අර්බුදය විසඳීමට සැලැස්මක් ඉදිරිපත් කරනවාට වඩා පක්ෂ තම පෞද්ගලික අවශ්‍යතා ගැන සොයා බලන බවට ඔහු චෝදනා කළේය.",
        "සර්ව පාක්ෂික ආණ්ඩුවක් පිළිබඳව වත්මන් ජනාධිපති රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතාගේ රජය සමඟ තවදුරටත් සාකච්ඡා කිරීමෙන් පලක් නොමැති බව හිටපු ජනාධිපති ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ මහතාගේ රජයෙන් නෙරපා හරින ලද හිටපු කර්මාන්ත අමාත්‍යවරයා පවසයි.",
        "“අපි [රජය සමඟ] සාකච්ඡාවල නිරත වී සිටිමු. වැඩ කළ හැකි වැඩපිළිවෙළකට නොපැමිණ සාකච්ඡා කරගෙන යාමෙන් පලක් නැත. එය සිදු වන බවක් අපට නොපෙනේ, ”ඔහු පැවසීය.",
        "වීරවංශගේ සන්ධානයට රාජපක්ෂ ආණ්ඩුවේ හිටපු බලගතු සාමාජිකයන් වන උදය ගම්මන්පිල සහ වාසුදේව නානායක්කාර ඇතුළත් වේ.",
        "ඔහුට සහ ඔහු නායකත්වය දෙන ප්‍රජාතන්ත්‍රවාදී වාම පෙරමුණට ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ \"ජාමූඅ බැඳුනු\" \"භාරකාර\" ජනාධිපතිවරයාට සහාය දිය නොහැකි බව නානායක්කාර වාර්තා කර ඇත.",
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ ජාත්‍යන්තර මූල්‍ය අරමුදලට බැඳී සිටින \"භාරකාර\" ජනාධිපතිවරයාට සහාය දිය නොහැක: පාර්ලිමේන්තු මන්ත්‍රී වාසුදේව එන්"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "සැප්තැම්බර් 04",
          "label": "DATE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "එකොළොස්",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "සැප්තැම්බර් 04",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "විමල් වීරවංශ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "අගෝස්තු 29 සඳුදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "11",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "සැප්තැම්බර් 04",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "නිදහස",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "උදය ගම්මන්පිල",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "වාසුදේව නානායක්කාර",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ප්‍රජාතන්ත්‍රවාදී වාම පෙරමුණ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "இலங்கையின் \"சுயாதீன\" கட்சிகள் செப்டெம்பர் 04 ஆம் திகதி மாபெரும் கூட்டணியை ஆரம்பிக்கவுள்ளன",
      "author": "",
      "body_lines": [
        "ECONOMYNEXT - இலங்கையின் ஆளும் கூட்டணியின் 11 முன்னாள் கூட்டணி பங்காளிகள் இப்போது பாராளுமன்றத்தில் சுயேச்சையாக அமர்ந்திருக்கும் கூட்டமைப்பு, செப்டம்பர் 04 அன்று மற்ற கட்சிகளுடன் இணைந்து பெரும் கூட்டணியை அமைக்கும் என முன்னாள் அமைச்சர் விமல் வீரவன்ச தெரிவித்தார்.",
        "ஆகஸ்ட் 29 திங்கட்கிழமை செய்தியாளர்களிடம் வீரவன்ச கூறுகையில், 11 கட்சிகளும், அவர் பெயரிடாத மற்ற கட்சிகளும் இணைந்து, புதிய \"வரலாற்று\" கூட்டணியை செப்டம்பர் 04 அன்று மஹரகம இளைஞர் மையத்தில் நடைபெறும் நிகழ்வில் அறிவிக்கும்.",
        "\"இது ஒரு முற்போக்கான, மக்கள் சார்பு கூட்டணியாக இருக்கும், தற்போதைய நெருக்கடியை சமாளிக்க மட்டுமல்ல, எதிர்கால சவால்களுக்கும் உயரக்கூடிய ஒன்றாக இருக்கும்,\" என்று அவர் கூறினார்.",
        "இன்னும் உருவாக்கப்படாத உத்தேச சர்வகட்சி அரசாங்கம் குறித்து வினவியதற்கு பதிலளித்த வீரவன்ச, பொருளாதார நெருக்கடியில் இருந்து மக்களுக்கு எவ்வாறு உதவுவது என்பது தொடர்பில் பாராளுமன்றத்தை பிரதிநிதித்துவப்படுத்தும் கட்சிகளின் தலைவர்களால் ஒருமித்த கருத்துக்கு வரமுடியவில்லை. சுதந்திரம்.",
        "கட்சிகள் நெருக்கடியைத் தீர்க்கும் திட்டத்தைக் கொண்டு வருவதற்குப் பதிலாக அவர்களின் தனிப்பட்ட நலன்களைப் பார்க்கின்றன என்று அவர் குற்றம் சாட்டினார்.",
        "சர்வகட்சி அரசாங்கம் தொடர்பில் ஜனாதிபதி ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்கவின் தற்போதைய அரசாங்கத்துடன் தொடர்ந்தும் பேச்சுவார்த்தை நடத்துவதில் அர்த்தமில்லை என முன்னாள் ஜனாதிபதி கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ஷவின் அரசாங்கத்தில் இருந்து நீக்கப்பட்ட முன்னாள் கைத்தொழில் அமைச்சர் தெரிவித்துள்ளார்.",
        "“நாங்கள் [அரசாங்கத்துடன்] விவாதங்களில் ஈடுபட்டுள்ளோம். ஒரு வேலைத்திட்டத்திற்கு வராமல் விவாதங்களைத் தொடர்வதில் எந்தப் பயனும் இல்லை. அப்படி நடப்பதை நாங்கள் பார்க்கவில்லை,'' என்றார்.",
        "வீரவன்சவின் கூட்டணியில் ராஜபக்ச அரசாங்கத்தின் முன்னாள் செல்வாக்கு மிக்க உறுப்பினர்களான உதய கம்மன்பில மற்றும் வாசுதேவா நாணயக்கார ஆகியோர் அடங்குவர்.",
        "இலங்கையின் \"IMF-க்கு கட்டுப்பட்ட\" \"காவல்பணியாளர்\" ஜனாதிபதிக்கு தானும் அவர் தலைமையிலான ஜனநாயக இடதுசாரி முன்னணியும் ஆதரவளிக்க முடியாது என்று நாணயக்கார பதிவு செய்துள்ளார்.",
        "இலங்கையின் சர்வதேச நாணய நிதியத்திற்கு கட்டுப்பட்ட \"காவல்காரர்\" ஜனாதிபதியை ஆதரிக்க முடியாது: பாராளுமன்ற உறுப்பினர் வாசுதேவ என்"
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "இலங்கை",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "செப்டம்பர் 04",
          "label": "DATE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "பதினொரு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "செப்டம்பர் 04",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "விமல் வீரவன்ச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஆகஸ்ட் 29 திங்கட்கிழமை",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "11",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "செப்டம்பர் 04",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "சுதந்திரம்",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [
          {
            "text": "ராஜபக்சே",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "உதய கம்மன்பில",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "வாசுதேவா நாணயக்கார",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஜனநாயக இடது முன்னணி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கையின்",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}