{
  "newspaper_id": "ada-derana-lk",
  "url": "http://www.adaderana.lk/news/83917/bangladesh-pm-sheikh-hasina-congratulates-president-ranil",
  "time_ut": 1658974920,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Bangladesh PM Sheikh Hasina congratulates President Ranil",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Bangladesh PM Sheikh Hasina congratulates President Ranil",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "Bangladesh Prime Minister Sheikh Hasina conveyed her congratulatory wishes to newly-elected Sri Lankan President Ranil Wickremesinghe and expressed her conviction for strengthening the ties between the two nations.",
        "“On behalf of the Government and the people of Bangladesh and on my own behalf, I would like to congratulate you on your election in the parliament as the President of the Democratic Socialist Republic of Sri Lanka.”",
        "“I am confident that your wealth of experience, wisdom and political acumen will be instrumental in bringing about the desired peace and prosperity in Sri Lanka. I wish you all success in your endeavours,” the congratulatory letter dated July 25 read.",
        "This year, Bangladesh and Sri Lanka are celebrating 50 years of solidarity and friendship, a friendship which is based on historic linkages, shared values and cultures, mutual respect and a multitude of commonalities.",
        "PM Hasina said, “I have the conviction that relations between our two countries will be further strengthened in the coming days through multi-pronged sectoral cooperation for the mutual benefit of our two peoples.”",
        "She hoped that the relations of cooperation with the friendly people of Sri Lanka will continue. “I look forward to working with you towards that end,” she added.",
        "Wickremesinghe was sworn in as Sri Lankan President in the country’s Parliament on July 21. Wickremesinghe was administered the oath of office by the chief justice of Sri Lanka, a day after he won a parliament vote."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "Hasina",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "Ranil",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Sheikh Hasina",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lankan",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "two",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Bangladesh",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Democratic Socialist Republic of Sri Lanka",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "July 25",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "This year",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Bangladesh",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "50 years",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Hasina",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "two",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "the coming days",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "two",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Sri Lankan",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "July 21",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "a day",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "බංග්ලාදේශ අගමැතිනි ෂීක් හසීනා ජනපති රනිල්ට සුබ පතයි",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "බංග්ලාදේශ අගමැතිනි ෂීක් හසීනා ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ අභිනවයෙන් තේරී පත් වූ ජනාධිපති රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ වෙත සිය සුබපැතුම් ප්‍රකාශ කළ අතර දෙරට අතර සබඳතා ශක්තිමත් කිරීම සඳහා සිය විශ්වාසය ප්‍රකාශ කළාය.",
        "\"ශ්‍රී ලංකා ප්‍රජාතාන්ත්‍රික සමාජවාදී ජනරජයේ ජනාධිපතිවරයා ලෙස ඔබ පාර්ලිමේන්තුවට තේරී පත්වීම පිළිබඳව බංග්ලාදේශ රජය සහ ජනතාව වෙනුවෙන් සහ මා වෙනුවෙන් මම ඔබට සුබ පතන්න කැමතියි.\"",
        "“ඔබේ අත්දැකීම් සම්භාරය, ප්‍රඥාව සහ දේශපාලන ඥානය ශ්‍රී ලංකාව තුළ අපේක්ෂිත සාමය සහ සෞභාග්‍යය ඇති කිරීමට ඉවහල් වන බව මට විශ්වාසයි. ඔබ සැමගේ උත්සාහය සාර්ථක වේවායි මම ප්‍රාර්ථනා කරමි,” ජුලි 25 දිනැති සුබ පැතුම් ලිපියේ සඳහන් විය.",
        "මෙම වසරේ, බංග්ලාදේශය සහ ශ්‍රී ලංකාව වසර 50 ක සහයෝගීතාවයේ සහ මිත්‍රත්වයේ 50 වසර සමරයි, එය ඓතිහාසික සම්බන්ධතා, හවුල් වටිනාකම් සහ සංස්කෘතීන්, අන්‍යෝන්‍ය ගෞරවය සහ පොදු කරුණු රාශියක් මත පදනම් වූ මිත්‍රත්වයකි.",
        "අග්‍රාමාත්‍ය හසීනා ප්‍රකාශ කළේ, “අපේ ජාතීන් දෙකේ අන්‍යෝන්‍ය ප්‍රයෝජනය සඳහා බහුවිධ ආංශික සහයෝගීතාව තුළින් ඉදිරි දිනවලදී අප දෙරට අතර සබඳතා තවදුරටත් ශක්තිමත් වනු ඇති බවට මට විශ්වාසයක් ඇති” බවයි.",
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ මිත්‍රශීලී ජනතාව සමඟ සහයෝගීතාවයේ සබඳතා දිගටම පවතිනු ඇතැයි ඇය බලාපොරොත්තු වූවාය. \"ඒ සඳහා ඔබ සමඟ වැඩ කිරීමට මම බලාපොරොත්තු වෙනවා,\" ඇය තවදුරටත් පැවසුවාය.",
        "වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතා ශ්‍රී ලංකා ජනාධිපතිවරයා ලෙස ජුලි 21 වැනි දින රටේ පාර්ලිමේන්තුවේදී දිවුරුම් දුන්නේය. වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතා පාර්ලිමේන්තුවේ ඡන්දයකින් ජයග්‍රහණය කිරීමෙන් දිනකට පසු ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ අග්‍රවිනිශ්චයකාරවරයා විසින් ඔහුට දිවුරුම් දෙන ලදී."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "හසීනා",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "රනිල්",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ෂෙයික් හසීනා",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලාංකික",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "දෙක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "බංග්ලාදේශය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකා ප්‍රජාතාන්ත්‍රික සමාජවාදී ජනරජය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජූලි 25",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "මේ වසරේ",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "බංග්ලාදේශය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "අවුරුදු 50 යි",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "හසීනා",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "දෙක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉදිරි දින",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "දෙක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලාංකික",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජූලි 21",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "දවසක්",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "பங்களாதேஷ் பிரதமர் ஷேக் ஹசீனா ஜனாதிபதி ரணிலுக்கு வாழ்த்து தெரிவித்துள்ளார்",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "பங்களாதேஷ் பிரதமர் ஷேக் ஹசீனா, புதிதாக தெரிவு செய்யப்பட்ட இலங்கை ஜனாதிபதி ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்கவிற்கு தனது வாழ்த்துக்களை தெரிவித்ததுடன், இரு நாடுகளுக்கும் இடையிலான உறவுகளை வலுப்படுத்துவதற்கான தனது நம்பிக்கையை வெளிப்படுத்தினார்.",
        "\"இலங்கை ஜனநாயக சோசலிசக் குடியரசின் ஜனாதிபதியாக நீங்கள் பாராளுமன்றத்தில் தெரிவு செய்யப்பட்டதற்கு பங்களாதேஷ் அரசாங்கம் மற்றும் மக்கள் சார்பாகவும் எனது சார்பாகவும் நான் உங்களை வாழ்த்த விரும்புகிறேன்.\"",
        "“உங்களுடைய அனுபவச் செல்வம், ஞானம் மற்றும் அரசியல் புத்திசாலித்தனம் இலங்கையில் விரும்பிய சமாதானத்தையும் சுபீட்சத்தையும் ஏற்படுத்துவதற்கு உறுதுணையாக இருக்கும் என்று நான் நம்புகிறேன். உங்கள் முயற்சிகள் வெற்றியடைய வாழ்த்துகிறேன்” என்று ஜூலை 25 தேதியிட்ட வாழ்த்துக் கடிதத்தில் கூறப்பட்டுள்ளது.",
        "இந்த ஆண்டு, பங்களாதேஷும் இலங்கையும் 50 வருட ஒற்றுமை மற்றும் நட்பைக் கொண்டாடுகின்றன, இது வரலாற்று இணைப்புகள், பகிரப்பட்ட மதிப்புகள் மற்றும் கலாச்சாரங்கள், பரஸ்பர மரியாதை மற்றும் பல பொதுவான தன்மைகளை அடிப்படையாகக் கொண்டது.",
        "பிரதமர் ஹசீனா, “எங்கள் இரு நாட்டு மக்களின் பரஸ்பர நலனுக்காக பலதரப்பட்ட துறைசார் ஒத்துழைப்பின் மூலம் வரும் நாட்களில் இரு நாடுகளுக்கும் இடையிலான உறவுகள் மேலும் வலுப்பெறும் என்று நான் உறுதியாக நம்புகிறேன்” என்றார்.",
        "இலங்கையின் நட்புறவான மக்களுடனான ஒத்துழைப்பு உறவுகள் தொடரும் என அவர் நம்பிக்கை தெரிவித்தார். \"அந்த முடிவுக்கு உங்களுடன் பணியாற்ற நான் எதிர்நோக்குகிறேன்,\" என்று அவர் மேலும் கூறினார்.",
        "விக்ரமசிங்கே இலங்கை அதிபராக ஜூலை 21 அன்று நாட்டின் நாடாளுமன்றத்தில் பதவியேற்றார். நாடாளுமன்ற வாக்கெடுப்பில் வெற்றி பெற்ற ஒரு நாள் கழித்து, விக்கிரமசிங்கே இலங்கையின் தலைமை நீதிபதியால் பதவிப் பிரமாணம் செய்து வைத்தார்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ஹசீனா",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "ரணில்",
          "label": "PERSON"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ஷேக் ஹசீனா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "NORP"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இரண்டு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பங்களாதேஷ்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை ஜனநாயக சோசலிச குடியரசு",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜூலை 25",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இந்த வருடம்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "பங்களாதேஷ்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "50 ஆண்டுகள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஹசீனா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இரண்டு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "வரும் நாட்கள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இரண்டு",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜூலை 21",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஒரு நாள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}