{
  "newspaper_id": "virakesari-lk",
  "url": "http://www.virakesari.lk/article/131492",
  "time_ut": 1657860710,
  "original_lang": "ta",
  "original_title": "முறையற்ற பொருளாதார முகாமைத்துவம் தொடர்பான அடிப்படை உரிமை மீறல் மனுக்கள் மீது இன்று மீள விசாரணை",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Rehearing today on fundamental rights violation petitions related to economic mismanagement",
      "author": "Digital Desk 5",
      "body_lines": [
        "The High Court was assured that former Prime Minister Mahinda Rajapaksa, former Finance Minister Basil Rajapaksa and former Secretary of the Ministry of Finance S.R. Attikala will not travel to Vauni Nadu till today (15).",
        "Former Prime Minister Mahinda Rajapaksa and former Minister Basil Rajapaksa appeared in the forum along with Presidential Counsel Kamini Marappana and S. R. President's Advocate Nihal Jayasinghe, who appeared on behalf of Atikala, also informed the High Court about this.",
        "The High Court has imposed a travel ban on former Central Bank Governor WT Laxman, who has not been represented by any lawyer, to leave the country till today.",
        "Former Governor of the Central Bank Ajit Nivard Kabral has announced through his lawyer that he has no need to go abroad at the moment and if necessary, he will notify the High Court and get permission.",
        "The petitions for violation of fundamental rights, which were filed against those responsible for the country's improper economic management and uneven financial management, were heard yesterday (14) before a five-judge panel on the motion of lawyer Upendra Gunasekara.",
        "Chief Justice Jayantha Jayasuriya led by Justices Bhubaneka Aluvihare, Priyantha Jayawardena, Vijith Malalgoda and L.R.P. The petition was taken up for consideration in the presence of a five-judge bench of Tehiteniya.",
        "The fundamental rights petitions were filed by three university intellectuals, Sri Lankan swimmer and coach Julian Polling, former President of the Sri Lankan Chamber of Commerce Chandra Jayaratne, Transparency International and Jehan Kanaka Ratna and sought legal action against those principally responsible for economic mismanagement and uneven financial management.",
        "In the aforementioned petition for violation of fundamental rights, Professor Athulasiri Kumara Samarakoon from the Open University of Sri Lanka, intellectuals Susaiyappu Navis Morais and Professor Mahim Mendis have named Prime Minister Ranil Wickremesinghe, former Prime Minister Mahinda Rajapaksa, former Finance Minister Basil Rajapaksa, former Secretary to the President PP Jayasundara, former Central Bank of India in their petitions. Governors Ajith Niwat Kabral and WT Laxman, along with former finance minister SR Attikala, have named 39 people as defendants.",
        "The petitioners pointed out that the tax cuts that followed the inauguration of President Gotabaya Rajapaksa were the main reason for the country's current economic condition. They said that President Gotabaya Rajapaksa along with former Prime Minister Mahinda Rajapaksa took an arbitrary decision to reduce the taxes paid by the people to fulfill his election promise and this decision was purely a political move.",
        "In such a background, the petitioners have requested that the Auditor General of Sri Lanka issue an order to conduct an audit of the transactions and purchases of the Monetary Board of the Central Bank of Sri Lanka and evaluate the situation of the Central Bank.",
        "Former Prime Minister Mahinda Rajapaksa, former Minister Basil Rajapaksa, former Central Bank Governors Ajit Nivard Cabral, WT Laxman and former Finance Ministry Secretary S.R. Atikala was heard before the High Court to consider an order restraining them from leaving the country without obtaining permission.",
        "During this, the petitioner's President's Advocate Chandaka Jayasundara presented arguments for about one and a half hours in front of the foreign travel ban request.",
        "After this till date Mahinda, Basil, S. R. Their lawyers assured that Atikala will not go abroad.",
        "Further hearings on these petitions were adjourned till today.",
        "It is to be noted that in this case, President's Counsel Upul Jayasuriya and President's Counsel Chandaka Jayasundara are appearing on behalf of the petitioners and Additional Solicitor General Narin Pulle is appearing on behalf of the Attorney General."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "today",
          "label": "DATE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Mahinda Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Finance",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Basil Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Ministry of Finance",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "S.R. Attikala",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Vauni Nadu",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "15",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Mahinda Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Basil Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Presidential Counsel Kamini",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "S. R. President's",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Advocate Nihal Jayasinghe",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Atikala",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "The High Court",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Central Bank",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "WT Laxman",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the Central Bank Ajit Nivard Kabral",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "yesterday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "14",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "five",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Upendra Gunasekara",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Jayantha Jayasuriya",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Priyantha Jayawardena",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Malalgoda",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "five",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Tehiteniya",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "three",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lankan",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Julian Polling",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Sri Lankan Chamber of Commerce",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Chandra Jayaratne",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Transparency International",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Jehan Kanaka",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ratna",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Athulasiri Kumara",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Open University of Sri Lanka",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Navis Morais",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Mahim Mendis",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Mahinda Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Finance",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Basil Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "PP Jayasundara",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Central Bank of India",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "WT Laxman",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "SR Attikala",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "39",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Gotabaya Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Gotabaya Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Mahinda Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the Auditor General of Sri Lanka",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Monetary Board",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Central Bank of Sri Lanka",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Central Bank",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Mahinda Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Basil Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Central Bank Governors Ajit Nivard Cabral",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "WT Laxman",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Finance Ministry",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "S.R. Atikala",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Advocate Chandaka Jayasundara",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "about one and a half hours",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Mahinda",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Basil",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "S. R. Their",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Atikala",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "today",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Counsel Upul Jayasuriya",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Chandaka Jayasundara",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Additional Solicitor",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Narin Pulle",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "ආර්ථික අවභාවිතාවට අදාළ මූලික අයිතිවාසිකම් කඩවීම් පෙත්සම් අද යළි විභාගයට ගැනේ",
      "author": "ඩිජිටල් මේසය 5",
      "body_lines": [
        "හිටපු අග්‍රාමාත්‍ය මහින්ද රාජපක්ෂ, හිටපු මුදල් අමාත්‍ය බැසිල් රාජපක්ෂ සහ මුදල් අමාත්‍යාංශයේ හිටපු ලේකම් එස්.ආර්.අට්ටිකල අද (15) දක්වා වවුනිනාඩුවට නොයන බවට මහාධිකරණයට සහතික විය.",
        "හිටපු අග්‍රාමාත්‍ය මහින්ද රාජපක්ෂ සහ හිටපු අමාත්‍ය බැසිල් රාජපක්ෂ යන මහත්වරුන් මෙම සංසදයේ පෙනී සිටි අතර ජනාධිපති නීතීඥ කාමිණී මාරප්පන සහ එස්. ආර්. ඇටිකලා වෙනුවෙන් පෙනී සිටි ජනාධිපති නීතීඥ නිහාල් ජයසිංහ මහතා ද මේ බව මහාධිකරණයට දැනුම් දුන්නේය.",
        "කිසිදු නීතීඥයෙකු පෙනී නොසිටි හිටපු මහ බැංකු අධිපති ඩබ්ලිව් ටී ලක්ෂ්මන් මහතාට අද දක්වා රටින් පිටවීම සඳහා මහාධිකරණය විදෙස් ගමන් තහනමක් පනවා තිබෙනවා.",
        "තමාට මේ වන විට විදේශගත වීමේ අවශ්‍යතාවක් නොමැති බවත් අවශ්‍ය නම් මහාධිකරණයට දන්වා අවසර ලබා ගන්නා බවත් හිටපු මහ බැංකු අධිපති අජිත් නිවාඩ් කබ්රාල් සිය නීතීඥවරයා මාර්ගයෙන් නිවේදනය කළේය.",
        "රටේ අවිධිමත් ආර්ථික කළමනාකරණයට සහ අසමාන මූල්‍ය කළමනාකරණයට වගකිවයුත්තන්ට එරෙහිව ගොනු කර තිබූ මූලික අයිතිවාසිකම් කඩකිරීම් පිළිබඳ පෙත්සම් නීතීඥ උපේන්ද්‍ර ගුණසේකර මහතාගේ මෝසම මත පංච පුද්ගල විනිසුරු මඩුල්ලක් හමුවේ ඊයේ (14) විභාගයට ගැනිණි.",
        "අගවිනිසුරු ජයන්ත ජයසූරියගේ නායකත්වයෙන් යුත් බුබනේක අලුවිහාරේ, ප්‍රියන්ත ජයවර්ධන, විජිත් මලල්ගොඩ සහ එල්.ආර්.පී. මෙම පෙත්සම තෙහිතේණිය පංච පුද්ගල විනිසුරු මඩුල්ලක් හමුවේ සළකා බැලිණි.",
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ පිහිනුම් ක්‍රීඩක සහ පුහුණුකරු ජූලියන් පෝලින්ග්, ශ්‍රී ලංකා වාණිජ මණ්ඩලයේ හිටපු සභාපති චන්ද්‍රා ජයරත්න, ට්‍රාන්ස්පේරන්සි ඉන්ටර්නැෂනල් සහ ජෙහාන් කනක රත්න යන විශ්වවිද්‍යාල බුද්ධිමතුන් තිදෙනෙකු විසින් මෙම මූලික අයිතිවාසිකම් පෙත්සම් ගොනු කර ඇති අතර ආර්ථික අවභාවිතයට සහ අසමානතාවයට ප්‍රධාන වශයෙන් වගකිව යුතු අයට එරෙහිව නීතිමය පියවර ගන්නා ලෙස ඉල්ලා සිටියේය. මූල්ය කළමනාකරණය.",
        "ඉහත සඳහන් මූලික අයිතිවාසිකම් කඩකිරීමේ පෙත්සමේ ශ්‍රී ලංකා විවෘත විශ්වවිද්‍යාලයේ මහාචාර්ය අතුලසිරි කුමාර සමරකෝන්, බුද්ධිමතුන් වන සුසෙයප්පු නවීස් මොරායස් සහ මහාචාර්ය මහිම් මෙන්ඩිස් විසින් අග්‍රාමාත්‍ය රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ, හිටපු අග්‍රාමාත්‍ය මහින්ද රාජපක්ෂ, හිටපු මුදල් අමාත්‍ය බැසිල් රාජපක්ෂ, හිටපු මුදල් අමාත්‍ය බැසිල් රාජපක්ෂ, ජනාධිපති ලේකම් පී.පී. ජයසුන්දර, හිටපු ඉන්දීය මහ බැංකුව යන මහත්වරුන් සිය පෙත්සම්වලින් ඉදිරිපත් කළ පෙත්සම්වල අධිපතිවරුන් වන අජිත් නිවත් කබ්රාල් සහ ඩබ්ලිව්.ටී.ලක්ෂ්මන්, හිටපු මුදල් අමාත්‍ය එස්.ආර්.අට්ටිකල ඇතුළු 39 දෙනෙකු විත්තිකරුවන් ලෙස නම් කර තිබේ.",
        "ජනාධිපති ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ මහතාගේ පදවි ප්‍රාප්තියෙන් පසු සිදුවූ බදු අඩු කිරීම් රටේ වත්මන් ආර්ථික තත්ත්වයට ප්‍රධානතම හේතුව බව පෙත්සම්කරුවෝ පෙන්වා දුන්හ. ජනාධිපති ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ මහතා, හිටපු අග්‍රාමාත්‍ය මහින්ද රාජපක්ෂ මහතා සමඟ එක්ව තම මැතිවරණ පොරොන්දුව ඉටු කිරීම සඳහා ජනතාව ගෙවන බදු මුදල අඩු කිරීමට අත්තනෝමතික තීරණයක් ගත් බවත්, මෙම තීරණය තනිකරම දේශපාලන ක්‍රියාමාර්ගයක් බවත් ඔවුහු පැවසූහ.",
        "එවැනි පසුබිමක ශ්‍රී ලංකා මහ බැංකුවේ මුදල් මණ්ඩලයේ ගනුදෙනු සහ මිලදී ගැනීම් පිළිබඳ විගණනයක් සිදු කර මහ බැංකුවේ තත්ත්වය තක්සේරු කිරීමට ශ්‍රී ලංකා විගණකාධිපතිවරයාට නියෝගයක් නිකුත් කරන ලෙස පෙත්සම්කරුවන් ඉල්ලා ඇත.",
        "හිටපු අග්‍රාමාත්‍ය මහින්ද රාජපක්ෂ, හිටපු අමාත්‍ය බැසිල් රාජපක්ෂ, හිටපු මහ බැංකු අධිපතිවරුන් වන අජිත් නිවාඩ් කබ්රාල්, ඩබ්ලිව්.ටී ලක්ෂ්මන් සහ හිටපු මුදල් අමාත්‍යාංශයේ ලේකම් එස්.ආර්. අවසරයක් ලබා නොගෙන රටින් පිටවීම වළක්වාලමින් නිකුත් කර ඇති නියෝගයක් සලකා බැලීම සඳහා අතිකාල මහාධිකරණය හමුවේ විභාගයට ගැනුණා.",
        "මේ අතර පෙත්සම්කාර පාර්ශවයේ ජනාධිපති නීතීඥ චන්දක ජයසුන්දර මහතා විදේශ ගමන් තහනම් ඉල්ලීම හමුවේ පැය එකහමාරක පමණ කාලයක් කරුණු ඉදිරිපත් කළේය.",
        "මෙයින් පසු අද දක්වාම මහින්ද, බැසිල්, එස්. ආර්. ඇටිකල විදේශගත නොවන බවට ඔවුන්ගේ නීතිඥවරු සහතික වූහ.",
        "මෙම පෙත්සම් පිළිබඳ වැඩිදුර විභාගය අද දිනට කල් තැබිණි.",
        "මෙම නඩුවේ පෙත්සම්කරුවන් වෙනුවෙන් ජනාධිපති නීතීඥ උපුල් ජයසූරිය සහ ජනාධිපති නීතීඥ චන්දක ජයසුන්දර පෙනී සිටින අතර නීතිපතිවරයා වෙනුවෙන් අතිරේක සොලිසිටර් ජනරාල් නරීන් පුල්ලේ මහතා පෙනී සිටින බව සඳහන්ය."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "අද",
          "label": "DATE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "මහින්ද රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "මූල්ය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "බැසිල් රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "මුදල් අමාත්යාංශය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "එස්.ආර්. අට්ටිකාල",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "වවුනි නාඩු",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "15",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "මහින්ද රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "බැසිල් රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජනාධිපති නීතිඥ කාමිණී",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "S. R. ජනාධිපතිගේ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "අධිනීතිඥ නිහාල් ජයසිංහ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "අටකාල",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "මහාධිකරණය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "මහ බැංකුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඩබ්ලිව් ටී ලක්ෂ්මන්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "මහ බැංකුව අජිත් නිවාඩ් කබ්රාල්",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ඊයේ",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "14",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "පහ",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "උපේන්ද්‍ර ගුණසේකර",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ජයන්ත ජයසූරිය",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ප්‍රියන්ත ජයවර්ධන",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "මලල්ගොඩ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "පහ",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "තෙහිතේණිය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "තුන්",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලාංකික",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජූලියන් ඡන්ද විමසීම",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකා වාණිජ මණ්ඩලය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "චන්ද්‍රා ජයරත්න",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ට්‍රාන්ස්පේරන්සි ඉන්ටර්නැෂනල්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජෙහාන් කනක",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "රත්න",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "අතුලසිරි කුමාර",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකා විවෘත විශ්වවිද්‍යාලය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "නවීස් මොරායිස්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "මහීම් මෙන්ඩිස්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "මහින්ද රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "මූල්ය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "බැසිල් රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "පී පී ජයසුන්දර",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉන්දීය මහ බැංකුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඩබ්ලිව් ටී ලක්ෂ්මන්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "එස්ආර් අට්ටිකල",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "39",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "මහින්ද රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ විගණකාධිපති",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "මුදල් මණ්ඩලය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකා මහ බැංකුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "මහ බැංකුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "මහින්ද රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "බැසිල් රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "මහ බැංකු අධිපතිවරුන් වන අජිත් නිවාඩ් කබ්රාල්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඩබ්ලිව් ටී ලක්ෂ්මන්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "මුදල් අමාත්යාංශය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "එස්.ආර්. අටකාල",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "අධිනීතිඥ චන්දක ජයසුන්දර",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "පැය එකහමාරක් පමණ",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "මහින්ද",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "බැසිල්",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "S. R. ඔවුන්ගේ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "අටකාල",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "අද",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "නීතිඥ උපුල් ජයසූරිය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "චන්දක ජයසුන්දර",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "අතිරේක සොලිසිටර්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "නරින් පුල්ලේ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "முறையற்ற பொருளாதார முகாமைத்துவம் தொடர்பான அடிப்படை உரிமை மீறல் மனுக்கள் மீது இன்று மீள விசாரணை",
      "author": "Digital Desk 5",
      "body_lines": [
        "முன்னாள் பிரதமர் மஹிந்த ராஜபக்ஸ, முன்னாள் நிதி அமைச்சர் பசில் ராஜபக்ஸ மற்றும் நிதி அமைச்சின் முன்னாள் செயலாளர்  எஸ்.ஆர்.ஆட்டிகல ஆகியோர் இன்று (15) வரை வௌிநாடுகளுக்கு பயணிக்கப் போவதில்லை என உயர் நீதிமன்றத்திற்கு  உறுதியளிக்கப்பட்டது.",
        "முன்னாள் பிரதமர் மஹிந்த ராஜபக்ஷ, முன்னாள் அமைச்சர் பசில் ராஜபக்ஸ ஆகியோர் சார்பில் மன்றில் ஆஜரான ஜனாதிபதி சட்டத்தரணி காமினி மாரப்பனவும் எஸ். ஆர். ஆட்டிகல சார்பில் ஆஜரான ஜனாதிபதி சட்டத்தரணி நிஹால் ஜயசிங்கவும் இதனை உயர் நீதிமன்றுக்கு அறிவித்தனர்.",
        "மத்திய வங்கியின் முன்னாள் ஆளுநர் டபிள்யூ.டி.லக்ஷ்மன் சார்பில் எந்த சட்டத்தரணியும் ஆஜராகாத நிலையில், அவருக்கு மட்டும், இன்று வரை நாட்டை விட்டு வெளியேற உயர் நீதிமன்றம் பயணத் தடை விதித்தது.",
        "மத்திய வங்கியின் முன்னாள் ஆளுநர் அஜித் நிவார்ட் கப்ரால்,  தனக்கு தற்போதைக்கு வெளிநாடு செல்ல வேண்டிய தேவை இல்லை எனவும், அவ்வாறு அவசியம் ஏற்பட்டால் உயர் நீதிமன்றுக்கு அறிவித்து அனுமதி பெற்றுக்கொள்வதாக தனது சட்டத்தரணி ஊடாக அறிவித்தார்.",
        "நாட்டின் முறையற்ற பொருளாதார முகாமைத்துவத்திற்கும், சீரற்ற நிதி நிர்வாகத்திற்கும் காரணமானவர்களுக்கு எதிராக சட்டநடவடிக்கை எடுக்குமாறுகோரி தாக்கல் செய்யப்பட்ட அடிப்படை உரிமை மீறல் மனுக்கள், சட்டத்தரணி உபேந்ர குணசேகரவின் நகர்த்தல் பத்திரத்துக்கு அமைய நேற்று ( 14) ஐவர் கொண்ட நீதியரசர்கள் குழாம் முன் விசாரணைக்கு வந்தது.",
        "பிரதம நீதியர்சர் ஜயந்த ஜயசூரிய தலைமையிலான நீதியர்சர்களான புவனேக அலுவிஹாரே, பிரியந்த ஜயவர்தன, விஜித் மலல்கொட மற்றும்  எல்.ரி.பி. தெஹிதெனிய ஆகிய ஐவரடங்கிய நீதியரசர்கள் குழாம் முன்னிலையில் குறித்த மனு  பரிசீலனைக்கு எடுத்துக்கொள்ளப்பட்டது.",
        "மூன்று பல்கலைக்கழக புத்திஜீவிகள், இலங்கையைச்சேர்ந்த நீச்சல் வீரரும் பயிற்றுவிப்பாளருமான ஜுலியன் பொல்லிங், இலங்கை வர்த்தகப்பேரவையின் முன்னாள் தலைவர் சந்திர ஜயரத்ன, ட்ரான்ஸ்பேரன்ஸி இன்டர்நெஷனல் அமைப்பு மற்றும் ஜெஹான் கனக ரத்ன ஆகியோரால் இந்த அடிப்படை உரிமை மீறல் மனுக்கள் தாக்கல் செய்யப்பட்டிருந்ததுடன் முறையற்ற பொருளாதார முகாமைத்துவம் மற்றும் சீரற்ற நிதி நிர்வாகம் ஆகியவற்றுக்கான முக்கிய பொறுப்பாளிகளுக்கு எதிராக சட்டநடவடிக்கை எடுக்குமாறு அம்மனுக்களில் கோரப்பட்டிருந்தது.",
        "மேற்குறிப்பிட்ட அடிப்படை உரிமை மீறல் மனுவில் இலங்கை திறந்த பல்கலைக்கழகத்தைச்சேர்ந்த கலாநிதி அத்துலசிறி குமார சமரகோன், புத்திஜீவிகளான சூசையப்பு நேவிஸ் மொறாயஸ் மற்றும் கலாநிதி மஹிம் மென்டிஸ் ஆகியோர் தமது மனுக்களில் பிரதமர் ரணில் விக்ரமசிங்க, முன்னாள் பிரதமர் மஹிந்த ராஜபக்ஷ, முன்னாள் நிதியமைச்சர் பசில் ராஜபக்ஷ, ஜனாதிபதியின் முன்னாள் செயலாளர் பி.பி.ஜயசுந்தர, மத்திய வங்கியின் முன்னாள் ஆளுநர்களான அஜித் நிவாட் கப்ரால் மற்றும் டபிள்யூ.டி.லக்ஷ்மன், நிதியமைச்சின் முன்னாள் செயலாளர் எஸ்.ஆர்.ஆட்டிகல உள்ளிட்ட 39 பேரை பிரதிவாதிகளாகப் பெயரிட்டுள்ளனர்.",
        "ஜனாதிபதி கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ஷவின் பதவியேற்பைத் தொடர்ந்து மேற்கொள்ளப்பட்ட வரிக்குறைப்புக்களே நாட்டின் தற்போதைய பொருளாதார நிலைக்குப் பிரதான காரணமென மனுதாரர்கள் சுட்டிக்காட்டியுள்ளனர். ஜனாதிபதி கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ஷ முன்னாள் பிரதமர் மஹிந்த ராஜபக்ஷவுடன் இணைந்து தனது தேர்தல் வாக்குறுதியை நிறைவேற்றுவதற்காக மக்களால் செலுத்தப்படும் வரிகளைக் குறைப்பதற்குத் தன்னிச்சையான தீர்மானத்தை மேற்கொண்டார் என்றும், இத்தீர்மானம் முற்றுமுழுதாக அரசியல் ரீதியான நகர்வென்றும் அவர்கள் தெரிவித்துள்ளனர்.",
        "இவ்வாறானதொரு பின்னணியில் கணக்காய்வாளர் நாயகம் இலங்கை மத்திய வங்கியின் நாணயச்சபையின் கொடுக்கல், வாங்கல்களைக் கணக்காய்விற்கு உட்படுத்தி மத்திய வங்கிக்கு ஏற்பட்டிருக்கும் நட்டத்தை மதிப்பீடு செய்யும்படி உத்தரவு பிறப்பிக்குமாறு மனுதாரர்கள் கோரிக்கைவிடுத்துள்ளனர்.",
        "நேற்று மனுவானது இடைக்கால நிவாரணமாக கோரப்ப்ட்ட, முன்னாள் பிரதமர் மஹிந்த ராஜபக்ஷ, முன்னாள் அமைச்சர் பசில் ராஜபக்ச, மத்திய வங்கியின் முன்னாள் ஆளுநர்களான அஜித் நிவார்ட் கப்ரால், டபிள்யூ.டி.லக்ஷ்மன் மற்றும் நிதியமைச்சின் முன்னாள் செயலாளர் எஸ்.ஆர்.  ஆட்டிகல  ஆகியோர் உயர்  நீதிமன்றத்தின் முன் அனுமதி பெறாமல் நாட்டை விட்டு வெளியேறுவதை தடுத்து உத்தர்விட வேண்டும் என்பதை பரிசீலிக்க விசாரணைக்கு வந்தது.",
        "இதன்போது மனுதாரர் தரப்பின் ஜனாதிபதி சட்டத்தரணி  சந்தக ஜயசுந்தர, வெளிநாட்டு பயணத் தடை கோரிக்கையை முன்னிறுத்தீ சுமார் ஒன்றரை மணி நேர வாதங்களை முன் வைத்தார்.",
        "இதனையடுத்தே  இன்றுவரை மஹிந்த, பசில், எஸ். ஆர். ஆட்டிகல வெளிநாடு செல்ல மாட்டார்கள் என அவர்களது சட்டத்தரனிகள் உறுதியளித்தனர்.",
        "இந் நிலையில் இம்மனுக்கள் மீதான மேலதிக விசாரணைகள் இன்று வரை ஒத்தி வைக்கப்ப்ட்டன.",
        "இவ்வழக்கில் மனுதாரர்கள் சார்பில் ஜனாதிபதி சட்டத்தரணி உபுல் ஜயசூரிய மற்றும்ஜனாதிபதி சட்டத்தரணி  சந்தக ஜயசுந்தர ஆகியோரும் சட்டமா அதிபர் சார்பில் மேலதிக சொலிஸிட்டர் ஜெனரல் நரின் புள்ளேவும் ஆஜராகின்றமை குறிப்பிடத்தக்கது."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "இன்று",
          "label": "DATE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "மஹிந்த ராஜபக்ஷ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "நிதி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "பசில் ராஜபக்ஷ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "நிதி அமைச்சகம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "எஸ்.ஆர். அட்டிகல",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "வௌனி நாடு",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "15",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "மஹிந்த ராஜபக்ஷ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "பசில் ராஜபக்ஷ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜனாதிபதி ஆலோசகர் காமினி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "எஸ்.ஆர். ஜனாதிபதியின்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "சட்டத்தரணி நிஹால் ஜயசிங்க",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "அடிகளா",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "உயர்நீதிமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "மத்திய வங்கி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "டபிள்யூ.டி.லக்ஷ்மன்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "மத்திய வங்கி அஜித் நிவார்ட் கப்ரால்",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "நேற்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "14",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஐந்து",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "உபேந்திர குணசேகர",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஜயந்த ஜயசூரிய",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "பிரியந்த ஜயவர்தன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "மலல்கொட",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஐந்து",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "தெஹிதெனிய",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "மூன்று",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜூலியன் வாக்குப்பதிவு",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை வர்த்தக சபை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "சந்திரா ஜயரத்ன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "டிரான்ஸ்பரன்சி இன்டர்நேஷனல்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜெஹான் கனகா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரத்னா",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "அதுலசிறி குமார",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை திறந்த பல்கலைக்கழகம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "நவிஸ் மொரைஸ்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "மஹிம் மெண்டிஸ்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "மஹிந்த ராஜபக்ஷ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "நிதி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "பசில் ராஜபக்ஷ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "பிபி ஜெயசுந்தர",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "சென்ட்ரல் பேங்க் ஆஃப் இந்தியா",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "டபிள்யூ.டி.லக்ஷ்மன்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "எஸ்.ஆர்.அத்திகல",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "39",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "மஹிந்த ராஜபக்ஷ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இலங்கையின் கணக்காய்வாளர் நாயகம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "நாணய வாரியம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை மத்திய வங்கி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "மத்திய வங்கி",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "மஹிந்த ராஜபக்ஷ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "பசில் ராஜபக்ஷ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "மத்திய வங்கியின் ஆளுநர்கள் அஜித் நிவார்ட் கப்ரால்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "டபிள்யூ.டி.லக்ஷ்மன்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "நிதி அமைச்சகம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "எஸ்.ஆர். அடிகளா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "சட்டத்தரணி சந்தக ஜயசுந்தர",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "சுமார் ஒன்றரை மணி நேரம்",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "மஹிந்த",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "துளசி",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "எஸ்.ஆர் அவர்களின்",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "அடிகளா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இன்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "சட்டத்தரணி உபுல் ஜயசூரிய",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "சந்தக ஜயசுந்தர",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "கூடுதல் வழக்கறிஞர்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "நரின் புள்ளே",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}