{
  "newspaper_id": "virakesari-lk",
  "url": "http://www.virakesari.lk/article/131607",
  "time_ut": 1657965696,
  "original_lang": "ta",
  "original_title": "பெரும் அரசியல் தந்திரன் ' ரணில் '",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Great political strategist 'Ranil'",
      "author": "",
      "body_lines": [
        "Gotabaya Rajapaksa, who has left the country amid popular protests, will be elected for the post of executive president on Wednesday.",
        "This system of selection will take place within the Parliament. The common question is whether Ranil Wickremesinghe, who has already been sworn in as the acting president, will retain his post or will lose it in a short period of time like the prime ministers he has already held.",
        "But Ranil Wickremesinghe is seen as a great political strategist. Although there are many incidents in the political history of Sri Lanka as evidence for this, the current movements in national politics are the best evidence in front of us. Ranil Wickremesinghe went to Parliament on the only national list seat available to the United National Party which was on the brink of defeat. He personally faced criticism from members of the ruling and opposition parties. His political and historical background is similar.",
        "Ranil Wickramasinghe, who has served as a Member of Parliament for 42 consecutive years in Sri Lankan political history, has also received the highest number of popular votes in 5 general elections in Colombo District. But with the 2020 general election considered a major setback in his political career, Ranil Wickremesinghe went to Parliament on a national list seat made available to the United National Party.",
        "Today, Ranil Wickramasinghe has proved that he is second only to JR Jayawardene in formulating political strategies. Due to this, he has retained the leadership of the United National Party for more than a quarter of a century despite many defeats.",
        "Even this should be considered as an achievement. Because no United National Party leader has lasted so many years at the helm before.",
        "In all the 15 general elections held from 1947 to 2015, the United National Party contested with the elephant symbol. Ranil Wickramasinghe has presided over 5 elections. Ranil Wickramasinghe was able to win only two of these elections (2001, 2015). However, there have been splits within the UNP in the past based on various differences. Key members also left.",
        "But it was the Sajith Premadasa-led eviction that made the big impact. In the 2020 general election, the United National Party could not even retain the position of the main opposition party.",
        "Although Ranil Wickramasinghe has been involved in active politics since 1970, he contested for the first time in the 1977 general elections. Ranil Wickramasinghe was elected as a Member of Parliament by getting 22 thousand 45 votes in the general election held on July 21, 1977 in Biagama Constituency in Gampaha District. In this election held under the leadership of JR Jayawardena, the United National Party won a five-sixth majority. After a new constitution was enacted in 1978, a general election was held in 1989 as the term of parliament was extended for one more term by popular vote.",
        "Ranil Wickramasinghe contested in Gampaha district in this election. He won by getting 86 thousand 477 votes. The United National Party led by Ranasinghe Premadasa won the election. In the election held on 16th August 1994, Ranil Wickramasinghe, who contested in Colombo district, won 2 lakh 91 thousand 194 votes and came first in the district.",
        "However, the United National Party failed in this election. People's Alliance led by Chandrika Bandaranaike won. IDP in Colombo District. Relegated to the second stage. After this election Ranil Wickramasinghe was appointed as the party leader in 1994.",
        "Ranil Wickremesinghe, who ran as the primary candidate in the Colombo district in the general election held on October 10, 2000, got 3 lakh 63 thousand 668 votes. Despite the victory of the People's Alliance in this election, the UDP won 10 seats in the Colombo district.",
        "However, Parliament was dissolved in 11 months and elections were held on 05 December 2001. In this election, the U.D.P. won. Ranil Wickremesinghe came first in Colombo district by getting 4 lakh 15 thousand 686 votes.",
        "Ranil Wickramasinghe, who contested in Colombo in the general election held on April 02, 2004, won by getting 3 lakh 29 thousand 524 votes. Despite the victory of United People's Freedom Alliance in this election, UNP won again in Colombo district and captured 9 seats.",
        "In the 2010 general election, Ranil Wickramasinghe, who contested in Colombo district, won 2 lakh 32 thousand 957 votes. Although he topped the list, he was relegated to the second place in the district. Vimal Weerawansa stood first. United People's Freedom Front won 10 seats and led in Colombo district.",
        "Ranil Wickremesinghe registered a historic victory in the Colombo district in the 2015 general elections. He got 5 lakh 566 preference votes. This is the highest number of popular votes a candidate has received in a general election. Earlier in 1994 general election, Chandrika Bandaranaike got 4 lakh 64 thousand 588 votes in Kumaratunga Gampaha district.",
        "Ranil Wickremesinghe, who faced various failures, never ended his political journey. Instead, he devised strategies that failed. Ranil Wickramasinghe's political strategy has put him in the presidential seat in the country's economic crisis and the resulting political crisis under the Gotabaya Rajapaksa regime. Sajith Premadasa rejected Gotabaya's invitation and lost his chance for the presidency. But Ranil Wickremesinghe took advantage of the opportunity and the situation of the country. Within 48 hours of assuming office as the Acting President, he unleashed turmoil.",
        "Not a single person in Parliament is a member of his party. Great political maneuvering could decide the outcome of the final challenge by next Wednesday or the first day itself."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Gotabaya Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Wednesday",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the United National Party",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickramasinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "42 consecutive years",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lankan",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "5",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Colombo District",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "2020",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "the United National Party",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickramasinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "second",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "JR Jayawardene",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the United National Party",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "more than a quarter of a century",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "no United National Party",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "so many years",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "15",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "1947 to 2015",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the United National Party",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickramasinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "5",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickramasinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "only two",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "(2001, 2015",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "UNP",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "2020",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the United National Party",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickramasinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "1970",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "first",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "1977",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickramasinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "22 thousand 45",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "July 21, 1977",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Biagama Constituency",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Gampaha District",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "JR Jayawardena",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "the United National Party",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "five-sixth",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "1978",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "1989",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "one",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickramasinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Gampaha",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "86 thousand 477",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "The United National Party",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ranasinghe Premadasa",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "16th August 1994",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickramasinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Colombo",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "2 lakh",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "91 thousand 194",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "first",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the United National Party",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "People's Alliance",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Chandrika Bandaranaike",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Colombo District",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "second",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickramasinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "1994",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Colombo",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "October 10, 2000",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "63 thousand 668",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "the People's Alliance",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "UDP",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "10",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Colombo",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "11 months",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "05 December 2001",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "U.D.P.",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "first",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Colombo",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "15 thousand 686",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickramasinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Colombo",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "April 02, 2004",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "29 thousand 524",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "United People's Freedom Alliance",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "UNP",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Colombo",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "9",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "2010",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickramasinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Colombo",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "2",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "32 thousand 957",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "second",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "first",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "United People's Freedom Front",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "10",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Colombo",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Colombo",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "2015",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "5",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "566",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "1994",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Chandrika Bandaranaike",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "64 thousand 588",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Kumaratunga Gampaha",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickramasinghe's",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Gotabaya Rajapaksa",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Premadasa",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Gotabaya",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "Ranil Wickremesinghe",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "48 hours",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Parliament",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "next Wednesday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the first day",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "ශ්‍රේෂ්ඨ දේශපාලන උපායමාර්ගිකයෙකු වූ 'රනිල්'",
      "author": "",
      "body_lines": [
        "ජනතා විරෝධය මධ්‍යයේ රට හැර ගිය ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ මහතා විධායක ජනාධිපති ධූරය සඳහා බදාදා තේරී පත් වේ.",
        "මෙම තේරීම් ක්‍රමය සිදුවන්නේ පාර්ලිමේන්තුව තුළයි. මේ වන විටත් වැඩබලන ජනාධිපතිවරයා ලෙස දිවුරුම් දී ඇති රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතා තවමත් තමන් දැරූ අගමැතිවරුන් මෙන් කෙටි කලකින් එම ධුරයේ රැඳී සිටින්නේද නැතහොත් එම ධුරය අහිමි වේද යන්න පොදු ප්‍රශ්නයයි.",
        "නමුත් රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ දකින්නේ මහා දේශපාලන උපායමාර්ගිකයෙකු ලෙසය. ඊට සාක්ෂි වශයෙන් ලංකා දේශපාලන ඉතිහාසයේ බොහෝ සිදුවීම් තිබුණත් ජාතික දේශපාලනයේ වත්මන් ව්‍යාපාර අප ඉදිරියේ ඇති හොඳම සාක්ෂියයි. රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ පාර්ලිමේන්තුවට ගියේ පරාජයේ අද්දර සිටි එක්සත් ජාතික පක්ෂයට තිබෙන එකම ජාතික ලැයිස්තු මන්ත්‍රී ධුරයෙන්. ඔහු පෞද්ගලිකව ආණ්ඩු පක්ෂයේ සහ විපක්ෂයේ මන්ත්‍රීවරුන්ගේ විවේචනවලට මුහුණ දුන්නේය. ඔහුගේ දේශපාලන හා ඓතිහාසික පසුබිමද සමානය.",
        "ශ්‍රී ලංකා දේශපාලන ඉතිහාසයේ අඛණ්ඩව වසර 42ක් පාර්ලිමේන්තු මන්ත්‍රීවරයකු ලෙස කටයුතු කළ රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතා මහ මැතිවරණ 5කදී කොළඹ දිස්ත්‍රික්කයෙන් වැඩිම ජනමතය ලබාගෙන ඇත. එහෙත් 2020 මහ මැතිවරණය ඔහුගේ දේශපාලන ජීවිතයේ විශාල පසුබෑමක් ලෙස සැලකීමත් සමඟ රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතා පාර්ලිමේන්තුවට ගියේ එක්සත් ජාතික පක්ෂයට හිමි වූ ජාතික ලැයිස්තු මන්ත්‍රී ධුරයකිනි.",
        "දේශපාලන උපාය මාර්ග සැකසීමේදී තමන් දෙවැනි වන්නේ ජේ.ආර්.ජයවර්ධනට පමණක් බව අද රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ ඔප්පු කර හමාරය. මේ නිසාම ඔහු පරාජයන් රැසක් මධ්‍යයේ වුවද අඩසියවසකට අධික කාලයක් එක්සත් ජාතික පක්ෂයේ නායකත්වය රඳවාගෙන සිටියි.",
        "මෙය පවා ජයග්රහණයක් ලෙස සැලකිය යුතුය. මක්නිසාද යත් මීට පෙර එක්සත් ජාතික පක්ෂ නායකයෙකු මෙතරම් වසර ගණනාවක් නායකත්වයේ සිට නැත.",
        "1947 සිට 2015 දක්වා පැවැති මහ මැතිවරණ 15ටම එක්සත් ජාතික පක්ෂය තරග කළේ අලියා ලකුණින්. රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතා මැතිවරණ 5කට නායකත්වය දී ඇත. මෙම මැතිවරණවලින් (2001, 2015) රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහට ජයග්‍රහණය කිරීමට හැකි වූයේ මැතිවරණ දෙකක් පමණි. නමුත් පසුගිය කාලයේ විවිධ මතභේද මත එජාපය තුළ බෙදීම් ඇති වුණා. ප්‍රධාන මන්ත්‍රීවරුද පිටව ගියහ.",
        "නමුත් සජිත් ප්‍රේමදාසගේ නායකත්වයෙන් ඉවත් කිරීම තමයි ලොකුම බලපෑමක් ඇති කළේ. 2020 මහ මැතිවරණයේදී එක්සත් ජාතික පක්‍ෂයට ප්‍රධාන විරුද්ධ පක්‍ෂයේ තැනවත් තියාගන්න බැරි වුණා.",
        "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතා 1970 වසරේ සිට ක්‍රියාකාරී දේශපාලනයේ යෙදී සිටියද ඔහු පළමු වරට තරග කළේ 1977 මහ මැතිවරණයටය. 1977 ජූලි 21 වැනිදා ගම්පහ දිස්ත්‍රික්කයේ බියගම මැතිවරණ කොට්ඨාසයේ පැවැති මහ මැතිවරණයෙන් ඡන්ද 22,45ක් ලබා ගනිමින් රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ මන්ත්‍රීවරයා ලෙස තේරී පත් විය. ජේ.ආර්.ජයවර්ධන මහතාගේ නායකත්වයෙන් පැවැති මෙම මැතිවරණයෙන් හයෙන් පහක බලයක් එක්සත් ජාතික පක්ෂයට හිමිවිය. 1978 නව ආණ්ඩුක්‍රම ව්‍යවස්ථාවක් සම්මත කිරීමෙන් පසු 1989 දී මහජන ඡන්දයෙන් පාර්ලිමේන්තුවේ කාලය තවත් වාරයකට දීර්ඝ කිරීම නිසා මහ මැතිවරණයක් පැවැත්විණි.",
        "මෙම මැතිවරණයේදී රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතා ගම්පහ දිස්ත්‍රික්කයට තරග කළේය. ඔහු ජයග්‍රහණය කළේ ඡන්ද 86,477ක් ලබා ගනිමින්. එම මැතිවරණයෙන් රණසිංහ ප්‍රේමදාස මහතාගේ නායකත්වයෙන් යුත් එක්සත් ජාතික පක්ෂය ජයග්‍රහණය කළේය. 1994 අගෝස්තු 16 වැනිදා පැවැති මැතිවරණයේදී කොළඹ දිස්ත්‍රික්කයට තරග කළ රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ ඡන්ද 2 ලක්ෂ 91,194ක් ලබාගෙන දිස්ත්‍රික්කයේ පළමු ස්ථානයට පත්විය.",
        "නමුත් මේ මැතිවරණයේදී එක්සත් ජාතික පක්ෂය අසාර්ථක වුණා. චන්ද්‍රිකා බණ්ඩාරනායක මහත්මියගේ නායකත්වයෙන් යුත් පොදුජන පෙරමුණ ජයග්‍රහණය කළා. කොළඹ දිස්ත්‍රික්කයේ අවතැන් වූවන්. දෙවැනි අදියරට පහළට වැටුණා. මෙම මැතිවරණයෙන් පසු 1994 දී රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ පක්ෂ නායකත්වයට පත් විය.",
        "2000 වසරේ ඔක්තෝබර් 10 වැනිදා පැවැති මහ මැතිවරණයේදී කොළඹ දිස්ත්‍රික්කයේ ප්‍රාථමික අපේක්ෂකයා ලෙස ඉදිරිපත් වූ රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතා ලබාගත් ඡන්ද සංඛ්‍යාව 3 ලක්ෂ 63,668කි. මෙවර මැතිවරණයෙන් පොදුජන පෙරමුණ ජයග්‍රහණය කළද කොළඹ දිස්ත්‍රික්කයෙන් යූ.ඩී.පී.",
        "නමුත් මාස 11 කින් පාර්ලිමේන්තුව විසුරුවා හැර 2001 දෙසැම්බර් 05 වැනි දින මැතිවරණය පැවැත්විණි. මෙම මැතිවරණයේදී යූ.ඩී.පී. දිනුවා. රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතා ඡන්ද 4 ලක්ෂ 15,686ක් ලබා ගනිමින් කොළඹ දිස්ත්‍රික්කයේ පළමු ස්ථානයට පත්විය.",
        "2004 අප්‍රේල් 02 වැනිදා පැවැති මහ මැතිවරණයේදී කොළඹින් තරග කළ රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතා ඡන්ද 3 ලක්ෂ 29,524ක් ලබා ගනිමින් ජයග්‍රහණය කළේය. මෙවර මැතිවරණයෙන් එක්සත් ජනතා නිදහස් සන්ධානය ජයග්‍රහණය කළද කොළඹ දිස්ත්‍රික්කයෙන් එක්සත් ජාතික පක්ෂය යළිත් ජයග්‍රහණය කර මන්ත්‍රී ධුර 9ක් හිමිකර ගත්තා.",
        "2010 මහ මැතිවරණයේදී කොළඹ දිස්ත්‍රික්කයට තරග කළ රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ ඡන්ද 2 ලක්ෂ 32,957ක් ලබා ගත්තේය. ඔහු ලැයිස්තුවේ ඉහළින්ම සිටියද ඔහු දිස්ත්‍රික්කයේ දෙවන ස්ථානය දක්වා පහත වැටුණි. විමල් වීරවංශ පළමු තැනට පත් විය. එක්සත් ජනතා නිදහස් පෙරමුණ ආසන 10ක් දිනාගෙන කොළඹ දිස්ත්‍රික්කයේ පෙරමුණ ගත්තා.",
        "2015 මහ මැතිවරණයේදී රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතා කොළඹ දිස්ත්‍රික්කයෙන් ඓතිහාසික ජයග්‍රහණයක් වාර්තා කළේය. ඔහු මනාප ඡන්ද 5 ලක්ෂ 566ක් ලබා ගත්තා. මෙය මහ මැතිවරණයකදී අපේක්ෂකයෙකු ලැබූ වැඩිම ජනප්‍රිය ඡන්ද සංඛ්‍යාවයි. මීට පෙර 1994 මහ මැතිවරණයේදී කුමාරතුංග ගම්පහ දිස්ත්‍රික්කයෙන් චන්ද්‍රිකා බණ්ඩාරනායක ඡන්ද 4 ලක්ෂ 64,588ක් ලබා ගත්තාය.",
        "විවිධ අසාර්ථකත්වයන්ට මුහුණ දුන් රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ මහතා සිය දේශපාලන ගමන කිසිදා අවසන් කළේ නැත. ඒ වෙනුවට ඔහු අසාර්ථක උපාය මාර්ග සකස් කළේය. රටේ ආර්ථික අර්බුදය සහ ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ පාලනය යටතේ ඇති වූ දේශපාලන අර්බුදය තුළ රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහගේ දේශපාලන උපාය මාර්ගය ඔහුව ජනාධිපති පුටුවේ තබා ඇත. සජිත් ප්‍රේමදාස ගෝඨාභයගේ ආරාධනය ප්‍රතික්‍ෂේප කළ අතර ඔහුට ජනාධිපති අපේක්ෂකත්වය අහිමි විය. නමුත් රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ අවස්ථාවෙන් සහ රටේ තත්ත්වයෙන් ප්‍රයෝජන ගත්තා. වැඩබලන ජනාධිපතිවරයා ලෙස වැඩ භාරගෙන පැය 48ක් ඇතුළත ඔහු කැළඹීමක් ඇති කළේය.",
        "පාර්ලිමේන්තුවේ එක පුද්ගලයෙක්වත් ඔහුගේ පක්‍ෂයේ සාමාජිකයෙක් නොවෙයි. මහා දේශපාලන උපාමාරු මගින් අවසන් අභියෝගයේ ප්‍රතිඵලය ලබන බදාදා හෝ පළමු දිනය වන විට තීරණය කළ හැකිය."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "බදාදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්රී ලංකාව",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "එක්සත් ජාතික පක්ෂය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "අඛණ්ඩව වසර 42 ක්",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලාංකික",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "5",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "කොළඹ දිස්ත්‍රික්කය",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "2020",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "එක්සත් ජාතික පක්ෂය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "දෙවැනි",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජේ ආර් ජයවර්ධන",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "එක්සත් ජාතික පක්ෂය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශතවර්ෂ හතරෙන් පංගුවකට වඩා වැඩි කාලයක්",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "එක්සත් ජාතික පක්ෂය නැහැ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "වසර ගණනාවක්",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "15",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "1947 සිට 2015 දක්වා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "එක්සත් ජාතික පක්ෂය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "5",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "දෙකක් පමණක්",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "(2001, 2015",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "එජාප",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "2020",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "එක්සත් ජාතික පක්ෂය",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "1970",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "පළමුවන",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "1977",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "22,45",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජූලි 21, 1977",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "බියගම ආසනය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගම්පහ දිස්ත්‍රික්කය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජේ ආර් ජයවර්ධන",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "එක්සත් ජාතික පක්ෂය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "පස්-හයවන",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "1978",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "1989",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "එක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගම්පහ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "86,477 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "එක්සත් ජාතික පක්ෂයයි",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "රණසිංහ ප්‍රේමදාස",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "1994 අගෝස්තු 16",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "කොළඹ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ලක්ෂ 2යි",
            "label": "QUANTITY"
          },
          {
            "text": "91,194 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "පළමුවන",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "එක්සත් ජාතික පක්ෂය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "පොදුජන සන්ධානය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "චන්ද්‍රිකා බණ්ඩාරනායක",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "කොළඹ දිස්ත්‍රික්කය",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "දෙවැනි",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "1994",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "කොළඹ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඔක්තෝබර් 10, 2000",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "63,668 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "පොදු පෙරමුණ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "UDP",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "10",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "කොළඹ",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "මාස 11 යි",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "2001 දෙසැම්බර් 05",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "යූ.ඩී.පී.",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "පළමුවන",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "කොළඹ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "15,686 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "කොළඹ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "2004 අප්‍රේල් 02",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "29,524 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "එක්සත් ජනතා නිදහස් සන්ධානය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "එජාප",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "කොළඹ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "9",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "2010",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "කොළඹ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "2",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "32,957 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "දෙවැනි",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "පළමුවන",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "එක්සත් ජනතා නිදහස් පෙරමුණ",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "10",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "කොළඹ",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "කොළඹ",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "2015",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "5",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "566",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "1994",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "චන්ද්‍රිකා බණ්ඩාරනායක",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "64,588 කි",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "කුමාරතුංග ගම්පහ",
            "label": "GPE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහගේ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගෝඨාභය රාජපක්ෂ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ප්‍රේමදාස ය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ගෝඨාභය",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "රනිල් වික්‍රමසිංහ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "පැය 48 යි",
            "label": "TIME"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "පාර්ලිමේන්තුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ලබන බදාදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "පළමු දිනය",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "பெரும் அரசியல் தந்திரன் ' ரணில் '",
      "author": "",
      "body_lines": [
        "மக்களின் பேரெதிர்ப்பிற்கு மத்தியில் நாட்டை விட்டு வெளியேறியுள்ள கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ஷ வகித்த நிறைவேற்று அதிகார ஜனாதிபதி பதவிக்கான தெரிவு புதன்கிழமை இடம்பெறவுள்ளது.",
        "இந்த தெரிவு முறைமையானது பாராளுமன்றத்திற்குள் இடம்பெறவுள்ளது. ஏற்கனவே பதில் ஜனாதிபதியாக பதவிப்பிரமாணம் செய்துள்ள ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க தனது பதவியை தக்க வைத்துக்கொள்வாரா அல்லது  ஏற்கனவே வகித்த பிரதமர் பதவிகளை போன்று குறுகிய  காலத்திற்குள் இழந்து விடுவாரா என்பது பொதுவான கேள்வியாகவே உள்ளது.",
        "ஆனால் ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க பெரும் அரசியல் தந்திரனாகவே பார்க்கப்படுகிறார். இதற்கு ஆதாரமாக இலங்கை அரசியல் வரலாற்றில் பல சம்பவங்கள் காணப்பட்டாலும் தேசிய அரசியலில் தற்போது நிகழ்கின்ற காய்நகர்த்தல்கள் கண்ணெதிரே உள்ள சிறந்த ஆதாரங்களாகின்றன. தோல்வியின் எல்லைக்கே சென்ற ஐக்கிய தேசிய கட்சிக்கு கிடைத்த ஒரேயொரு தேசிய பட்டியல் ஆசனத்தில் ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க பாராளுமன்றத்திற்கு சென்றார். ஆளும் மற்றும் எதிர்க்கட்சி உறுப்பினர்களின் விமர்சனங்களை தனி மனிதனாக எதிர்கொண்டார். அவரது அரசியல் வரலாற்று பின்னணியும் இவ்வாறானது தான்.",
        "இலங்கை அரசியல் வரலாற்றிலேயே தொடர்ச்சியாக  42 ஆண்டுகள் பாராளுமன்ற உறுப்பினராக பதவி வகித்துள்ள ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க, கொழும்பு மாவட்டத்தில் 5 பொதுத்தேர்தல்களில் அதிகூடிய விருப்பு வாக்குகளையும் பெற்றுள்ளார். ஆனால் 2020 பொதுத்தேர்தலின் அவரது அரசியல் வாழ்வில் பெரும் தோல்வியாக கருதப்பட்ட நிலையில், ஐக்கிய தேசியக்கட்சிக்கு கிடைக்கப்பெற்ற தேசியப்பட்டியல் ஆசனத்தில் ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க பாராளுமன்றத்திற்கு சென்றார்.",
        "அரசியல்  வியூகங்கள் வகுப்பதில்  ஜே.ஆர்.ஜயவர்தனவிற்கு பிறகு ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க தான் என்றளவிற்கு இன்று நிரூபித்து காட்டியுள்ளார். இதனால் எத்தனையோ தோல்விகளை சந்தித்தும் கால்நூற்றாண்டுக்கு மேலாக ஐக்கிய தேசியக்கட்சியின் தலைமைப்பதவியையும் தக்கவைத்துக்கொண்டுள்ளார்.",
        "இதுவும்கூட ஒருவகையில் சாதனையாகவே கருதப்பட வேண்டும். ஏனெனில் இதற்கு முன்னர் எந்தவொரு ஐக்கிய தேசிய கட்சியின் தலைவரும் இத்தனை ஆண்டுகள் தலைமைத்துவத்தில் நீடிக்கவில்லை.",
        "1947  முதல் 2015 வரை நடைபெற்றுள்ள 15 பொதுத்தேர்தல்களிலும் ஐக்கிய தேசியக்கட்சி யானை சின்னத்திலேயே போட்டியிட்டது. இதில் 5 தேர்தல்களுக்கு ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க தலைமை தலைமைத்தாங்கியுள்ளார். இவற்றுள் இரு தேர்தல்களில் (2001,2015) மட்டுமே ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்கவினால் வெற்றிநடைபோடமுடிந்தது. எவ்வாறாயினும் பல்வேறு முரண்பாடுகளின் அடிப்படையில் இதற்கு முன்னரும் ஐக்கிய தேசியக்கட்சிக்குள் பிளவுகள் ஏற்பட்டிருந்தன. முக்கிய உறுப்பினர்கள் வெளியேறியும் இருந்தனர்.",
        "ஆனால், சஜித் பிரேமதாச தலைமையிலான வெளியேற்றமே பெரும் தாக்கமாக அமைந்தது. 2020 பொதுத்தேர்தலில் ஒரு தொகுதியைக்கூட கைப்பற்றமுடியாது  பிரதான எதிர்க்கட்சி என்ற பதவியைக்கூட ஐக்கிய தேசியக்கட்சியால் தக்கவைத்துக்கொள்ள முடியாமல் போனது.",
        "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க 1970 ஆம் ஆண்டிலிருந்து செயற்பாட்டு அரசியலில் இறங்கினாலும் 1977 இல் நடைபெற்ற பொதுத்தேர்தலில்தான் முதல் தடவையாக போட்டியிட்டார். 1977 ஜுலை 21 ஆம் திகதி நடைபெற்ற பொதுத்தேர்தலில் கம்பஹா மாவட்டத்திலுள்ள பியகம தொகுதியில் – கன்னி தேர்தலை எதிர்கொண்ட ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க, 22 ஆயிரத்து 45 வாக்குகளைப் பெற்று பாராளுமன்ற உறுப்பினராக தெரிவானார். ஜே.ஆர்.ஜயவர்தனவின் தலைமைத்துவத்தின் கீழ் இடம்பெற்ற இத்தேர்தலில் ஐக்கிய தேசியக்கட்சி ஆறில் ஐந்து பெரும்பான்மையைப்பெற்றது. 1978 இல் புதிய அரசியல் யாப்பு இயற்றப்பட்ட பின்னர், சர்வஜன வாக்கெடுப்புமூலம் பாராளுமன்றத்தின் ஆயுட்காலம் மேலுமொரு தவணைக்கு நீடிக்கப்பட்டதால்  பொதுத்தேர்தல் 1989 இல்தான் நடைபெற்றது.",
        "இந்த தேர்தலில் ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க கம்பஹா மாவட்டத்தில் போட்டியிட்டார். 86 ஆயிரத்து 477 வாக்குகளைப் பெற்று வெற்றிபெற்றார். ரணசிங்க பிரேமதாச தலைமையிலான ஐக்கிய தேசியக்கட்சியே தேர்தலில் வெற்றிபெற்றது. 1994 ஆகஸ்ட் 16 ஆம் திகதி நடைபெற்ற தேர்தலில் கொழும்பு மாவட்டத்தில் களமிறங்கிய ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க, 2 லட்சத்து 91 ஆயிரத்து 194 வாக்குகளைப் பெற்று மாவட்டத்தில் முதலிடம் பிடித்தார்.",
        "எனினும், இத்தேர்தலில் ஐக்கிய தேசியக்கட்சி தோல்விகண்டது. சந்திரிக்கா பண்டாரநாயக்க தலைமையிலான மக்கள் கூட்டணி வெற்றிபெற்றது. கொழும்பு மாவட்டத்தில் ஐ.தே.க. இரண்டாம் நிலைக்கு தள்ளப்பட்டது. இத்தேர்தலின் பின்னர் 1994 இல் கட்சி தலைவராக ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க நியமிக்கப்பட்டார்.",
        "2000 ஒக்டோபர் 10 ஆம் நடைபெற்ற பொதுத்தேர்தலில் பிரதம வேட்பாளராக கொழும்பு மாவட்டத்தில் களமிறங்கிய ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க 3 லட்சத்து 63 ஆயிரத்து 668 வாக்குகளைப்பெற்றார். இத்தேர்தலில் மக்கள் கூட்டணி வெற்றிபெற்றிருந்தாலும் கொழும்பு மாவட்டத்தில் ஐ.தே.கவே பெரும் வெற்றியை பெற்று 10 ஆசனங்களைக் கைப்பற்றியது.",
        "எனினும், 11 மாதங்களில் பாராளுமன்றம் கலைக்கப்பட்டு,2001 டிசம்பர் 05 ஆம் திகதி தேர்தல் நடைபெற்றது.  இத்தேர்தலில் ஐ.தே.க. வெற்றிபெற்றது. 4 இலட்சத்து 15 ஆயிரத்து 686 வாக்குகளைப்பெற்று கொழும்பு மாவட்டத்தில் ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க முதலிடம் பிடித்தார்.",
        "2004 ஏப்ரல் 02 ஆம் திகதி நடைபெற்ற பொதுத்தேர்தலில் கொழும்பில் போட்டியிட்ட ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க, 3 இலட்சத்து 29 ஆயிரத்து 524 விருப்பு வாக்குகளைப்பெற்று வெற்றிபெற்றார். இத்தேர்தலில் ஐக்கிய மக்கள் சுதந்திர கூட்டமைப்பு வெற்றிபெற்றிருந்தாலும் கொழும்பு மாவட்டத்தில் ஐ.தே.க மீண்டும் வெற்றிப்பெற்று 9 ஆசனங்களைக் கைப்பற்றியது.",
        "2010 நடைபெற்ற பொதுத்தேர்தலில் கொழும்பு மாவட்டத்தில் களமிறங்கிய ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க, 2 இலட்சத்து 32 ஆயிரத்து 957 வாக்குகளைப்பெற்று ஐ.தே.க. பட்டியலில் முதலிடம் பிடித்தாலும் மாவட்டத்தில் இரண்டாம் இடத்துக்கு தள்ளப்பட்டார். விமல் வீரவன்ச முதலிடம் பிடித்தார். கொழும்பு மாவட்டத்தில் ஐக்கிய மக்கள் சுதந்திர முன்னணி 10 ஆசனங்களைக் கைப்பற்றி முன்னிலை வகித்தது.",
        "2015 இல் நடைபெற்ற பொதுத்தேர்தலில் கொழும்பு மாவட்டத்தில் ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க வரலாற்று வெற்றியைப் பதிவுசெய்தார். 5 இலட்சத்து 566 விருப்பு வாக்குகளைப் பெற்றார். பொதுத்தேர்தலில் வேட்பாளர் ஒருவர் பெற்ற அதிகூடிய விருப்பு வாக்குகள் இதுவாகும். இதற்கு முன்னர் 1994 இல் நடைபெற்ற பொதுத்தேர்தலில் சந்திரிக்கா பண்டாரநாயக்க குமாரதுங்க கம்பஹா மாவட்டத்தில் 4 இலட்சத்து 64 ஆயிரத்து 588 வாக்குகளைப் பெற்றிருந்தார்.",
        "இவ்வாறு பல்வேறு தோல்விகளை சந்தித்த ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க எந்தவொரு சந்தர்ப்பத்திலும் அரசியல் பயணத்தை முடிவிற்கு கொண்டு வரவில்லை. மாறாக தோல்விகளுடான வியூகங்களையே வகுத்தார். கோட்டபாய ராஜபக்ஷ அட்சியில் நாட்டின் பொருளாதார நெருக்கடியையும் அதனூடான அரசியல் நெருக்கடியிலும் ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்கவின் அரசியல் தந்திரம் ஜனாதிபதி ஆசனத்தில் அமர்த்தி விட்டுள்ளது. கோட்டபாயவின் அழைப்பை சஜித் பிரேமதாச நிராகரித்தமையினால் ஜனாதிபதி  பதவிற்கான வாய்ப்பை இழந்தார். ஆனால் ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க வாய்ப்பையும் நாட்டின் சூழலையும் தனக்கு சாதகமாக்கிக் கொண்டார். பதில் ஜனாதிபதியாக  பதவியை பொறுப்பேற்று 48 மணித்தியாலயத்திற்குள் கொந்தளிப்புகளை தனித்தார்.",
        "பாராளுமன்றத்தில் ஒருவர் கூட இவரது கட்சி உறுப்பினர் அல்ல. அடுத்த புதன் கிழமை அல்லது அதற்கு முதல் தினத்திலேயே இறுதி சவாலின் முடிவை பெரும் அரசியல் தந்திரனால் தீர்மானித்திட முடியும்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "கோட்டாபய ராஜபக்ச",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "புதன்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஐக்கிய தேசிய கட்சி",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "தொடர்ந்து 42 ஆண்டுகள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "5",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "கொழும்பு மாவட்டம்",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "2020",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "பாராளுமன்றம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஐக்கிய தேசிய கட்சி",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இரண்டாவது",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜே.ஆர்.ஜெயவர்தன",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஐக்கிய தேசிய கட்சி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "கால் நூற்றாண்டுக்கு மேல்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஐக்கிய தேசிய கட்சி இல்லை",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "இவ்வளவு ஆண்டுகள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "15",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "1947 முதல் 2015 வரை",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஐக்கிய தேசிய கட்சி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "5",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ரணில் விக்கிரமசிங்க",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "இரண்டு மட்டும்",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "(2001, 2015",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஐ.தே.க",
