{
  "newspaper_id": "daily-mirror-lk",
  "url": "https://www.dailymirror.lk/latest_news/Tourism-associations-told-to-discuss-directly-with-financial-institutions-for-moratorium-extension/342-240152",
  "time_ut": 1656645899,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Tourism associations told to discuss directly with financial institutions for moratorium extension",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Tourism associations told to discuss directly with financial institutions for moratorium extension",
      "author": "unknown",
      "body_lines": [
        "As the moratorium extended to the hard-hit tourism sector came to an end yesterday, the Sri Lanka Tourism Development Authority (SLTDA) requested trade associations to initiate one-to-one discussions with financial institutions for possible extension of the moratorium.",
        "The SLTDA, in a notice to all trade associations, said it will be writing to respective banks on behalf of those who had sought intervention as a follow-up measure. The Tourism Ministry will present matters to the Cabinet seeking further intervention, it said.",
        "The moratorium was offered to the tourism sector after the 2019 Easter Sunday attack for a period of six months, which was then extended three times due to the difficulties stemming from the COVID-19 pandemic.",
        "Following a proposal made by the Tourism Minister Harin Fernando, on a request made by  trade associations,",
        "Cabinet approval was given earlier this month to extend the moratorium. However, the decision has not been implemented as yet. The officials of Sri Lanka Tourism and trade associations met with Central Bank Governor to expedite the extension. However, the Governor had conveyed his inability to intervene and instruct financial institutions to extend the moratorium.",
        "The Governor was of the opinion that it is a matter to be decided by the respective financial institutions and opined that the Central Bank will refrain from direct intervention or influencing the individual decisions of banks and finance companies, the SLTDA highlighted in its notice.",
        "A meeting was then held with 39 banks and finance companies, chaired by the Secretary to the Ministry of Tourism and Lands, which did not bring in the expected outcome for the struggling sector. The SLTDA shared that all financial institutions were of the firm view that they could not agree to an extension of the moratorium as requested."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "yesterday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Sri Lanka Tourism Development Authority",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "one",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "one",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "SLTDA",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "The Tourism Ministry",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "Cabinet",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "2019",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sunday",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "a period of",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "six months",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "three",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Harin Fernando",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "earlier this month",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Sri Lanka Tourism",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Central Bank",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "the Central Bank",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "SLTDA",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "39",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Ministry of Tourism and Lands",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "SLTDA",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "තහනම දීර්ඝ කිරීම සඳහා මුල්‍ය ආයතන සමඟ සෘජුව සාකච්ඡා කරන ලෙස සංචාරක සංගම්වලට දැනුම් දී ඇත",
      "author": "නොදන්නා",
      "body_lines": [
        "දැඩි ලෙස පීඩාවට පත් වූ සංචාරක ක්ෂේත්‍රයට ලබාදී තිබූ තාවකාලික තහනම ඊයේ අවසන් වූ හෙයින්, ශ්‍රී ලංකා සංචාරක සංවර්ධන අධිකාරිය (SLTDA) එම තහනම දීර්ඝ කිරීම සඳහා මුල්‍ය ආයතන සමඟ එකින් එක සාකච්ඡා කරන ලෙස වෙළෙඳ සංගම්වලින් ඉල්ලා සිටියේය.",
        "පසු විපරම් ක්‍රියාමාර්ගයක් ලෙස මැදිහත් වීමට බලාපොරොත්තු වූ අය වෙනුවෙන් අදාළ බැංකු වෙත ලිඛිතව දැනුම් දෙන බව SLTDA විසින් සියලුම වෙළඳ සංගම් වෙත නිවේදනයක් නිකුත් කරමින් කියා සිටියේය. සංචාරක අමාත්‍යාංශය තවදුරටත් මැදිහත්වීමක් ඉල්ලා කැබිනට් මණ්ඩලයට කරුණු ඉදිරිපත් කරන බව එහි සඳහන් වේ.",
        "2019 පාස්කු ඉරිදා ප්‍රහාරයෙන් පසු මාස ​​හයක කාලයක් සඳහා සංචාරක ක්ෂේත්‍රයට මෙම තහනම පිරිනැමූ අතර, එය COVID-19 වසංගතයෙන් පැන නගින දුෂ්කරතා හේතුවෙන් තුන් වතාවක් දීර්ඝ කරන ලදී.",
        "සංචාරක අමාත්‍ය හරීන් ප්‍රනාන්දු විසින් කරන ලද යෝජනාවකට අනුව,  වෙළඳ සංගම් විසින් කරන ලද ඉල්ලීමකට අනුව,",
        "මෙම තහනම දීර්ඝ කිරීමට මේ මස මුලදී කැබිනට් අනුමැතිය ලබා දී ඇත. කෙසේ වෙතත් එම තීරණය මෙතෙක් ක්‍රියාත්මක වී නැහැ. මෙම දීර්ඝ කිරීම කඩිනම් කිරීම සඳහා ශ්‍රී ලංකා සංචාරක හා වෙළෙඳ සංගම්වල නිලධාරීන් මහ බැංකු අධිපතිවරයා හමුවී සාකච්ඡා කළහ. කෙසේ වෙතත්, ආණ්ඩුකාරවරයා තමාට මැදිහත් වීමට නොහැකි බව දන්වා, සහන කාලය දීර්ඝ කරන ලෙස මූල්‍ය ආයතනවලට උපදෙස් දී ඇත.",
        "එය අදාළ මූල්‍ය ආයතන විසින් තීරණය කළ යුතු කරුණක් බව ද අධිපතිවරයාගේ අදහස වූ අතර බැංකු සහ මූල්‍ය සමාගම්වල තනි තීරණවලට සෘජු මැදිහත්වීමෙන් හෝ බලපෑම් කිරීමෙන් ශ්‍රී ලංකා මහ බැංකුව වැළකී සිටින බව ද ශ්‍රී ලංකා ටෙලිකොම් ආයතනය සිය නිවේදනයේ සඳහන් කර ඇත.",
        "ඉන් අනතුරුව සංචාරක හා ඉඩම් අමාත්‍යාංශයේ ලේකම්වරයාගේ ප්‍රධානත්වයෙන් බැංකු සහ මූල්‍ය සමාගම් 39ක් සමඟ රැස්වීමක් පැවැත්වු අතර, එය අරගලකාරී අංශයට අපේක්ෂිත ප්‍රතිඵල ගෙන දුන්නේ නැත. ඉල්ලා සිටින පරිදි අත්හිටුවීමේ කාලය දීර්ඝ කිරීමට එකඟ විය නොහැකි බවට සියලුම මූල්‍ය ආයතන ස්ථිර මතයක සිටින බව SLTDA බෙදාහදා ගත්තේය."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "ඊයේ",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකා සංචාරක සංවර්ධන අධිකාරිය",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "එක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "එක",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "SLTDA",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "සංචාරක අමාත්‍යාංශය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "මණ්ඩල",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "2019",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඉරිදා",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "කාල සීමාවක්",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මාස හයක්",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "තුන්",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "හරීන් ප්‍රනාන්දු",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "මේ මස මුල",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ශ්‍රී ලංකා සංචාරක ව්‍යාපාරය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මහ බැංකුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "මහ බැංකුව",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "SLTDA",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "39",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "සංචාරක හා ඉඩම් අමාත්‍යාංශය",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "SLTDA",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "தடைக்காலத்தை நீட்டிக்க நிதி நிறுவனங்களுடன் நேரடியாக விவாதிக்க சுற்றுலா சங்கங்கள் தெரிவித்துள்ளன",
      "author": "தெரியவில்லை",
      "body_lines": [
        "கடுமையான பாதிப்புக்குள்ளான சுற்றுலாத் துறைக்கு நீட்டிக்கப்பட்ட தடை நேற்றுடன் முடிவடைந்த நிலையில், இலங்கை சுற்றுலா அபிவிருத்தி அதிகாரசபை (SLTDA) தடைக்காலத்தை நீட்டிப்பது தொடர்பாக நிதி நிறுவனங்களுடன் ஒன்றுக்கு ஒன்று கலந்துரையாடல்களை ஆரம்பிக்குமாறு வர்த்தக சங்கங்களைக் கோரியுள்ளது.",
        "SLTDA, அனைத்து வர்த்தக சங்கங்களுக்கும் அனுப்பிய அறிவிப்பில், தொடர் நடவடிக்கையாக தலையீடு கோரியவர்களின் சார்பாக அந்தந்த வங்கிகளுக்கு கடிதம் எழுதப்படும் என்று கூறியுள்ளது. சுற்றுலா அமைச்சகம் மேலும் தலையீடு கோரும் விஷயங்களை அமைச்சரவைக்கு முன்வைக்கும் என்று அது கூறியது.",
        "2019 ஈஸ்டர் ஞாயிறு தாக்குதலுக்குப் பிறகு சுற்றுலாத் துறைக்கு ஆறு மாத காலத்திற்கு தடை விதிக்கப்பட்டது, பின்னர் COVID-19 தொற்றுநோயால் ஏற்படும் சிரமங்கள் காரணமாக இது மூன்று முறை நீட்டிக்கப்பட்டது.",
        "சுற்றுலாத்துறை அமைச்சர் ஹரின் பெர்னாண்டோவினால் முன்வைக்கப்பட்ட பிரேரணைக்கு அமைய,  வர்த்தக சங்கங்களின் கோரிக்கைக்கு அமைய,",
        "இந்த தடைக்காலத்தை நீட்டிக்க இந்த மாத தொடக்கத்தில் அமைச்சரவை ஒப்புதல் அளிக்கப்பட்டது. ஆனால், அந்த முடிவு இதுவரை அமல்படுத்தப்படவில்லை. இலங்கை சுற்றுலா மற்றும் வர்த்தக சங்கங்களின் அதிகாரிகள், மத்திய வங்கியின் ஆளுநரை சந்தித்து நீட்டிப்பை துரிதப்படுத்தினர். எவ்வாறாயினும், ஆளுநர் தலையிட்டு நிதி நிறுவனங்களுக்கு இடைக்காலத்தை நீடிக்க அறிவுறுத்த முடியாது என்று தெரிவித்திருந்தார்.",
        "இது அந்தந்த நிதி நிறுவனங்களினால் தீர்மானிக்கப்பட வேண்டிய விடயம் எனத் தெரிவித்த ஆளுநர், வங்கிகள் மற்றும் நிதி நிறுவனங்களின் தனிப்பட்ட தீர்மானங்களில் நேரடித் தலையீடு அல்லது செல்வாக்கு செலுத்துவதில் இருந்து மத்திய வங்கி தவிர்ந்து கொள்ளும் என SLTDA தனது அறிவிப்பில் சுட்டிக்காட்டியுள்ளது.",
        "பின்னர் சுற்றுலா மற்றும் நில அமைச்சகத்தின் செயலாளர் தலைமையில் 39 வங்கிகள் மற்றும் நிதி நிறுவனங்களுடன் ஒரு கூட்டம் நடத்தப்பட்டது, இது போராடும் துறைக்கு எதிர்பார்த்த பலனைத் தரவில்லை. SLTDA அனைத்து நிதி நிறுவனங்களும் கோரியபடி தடையை நீட்டிக்க ஒப்புக்கொள்ள முடியாது என்ற உறுதியான பார்வையில் இருப்பதாக பகிர்ந்து கொண்டது."
      ],
      "title_ents": [],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "நேற்று",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை சுற்றுலா அபிவிருத்தி அதிகாரசபை",
            "label": "LOC"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஒன்று",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஒன்று",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "SLTDA",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "சுற்றுலா அமைச்சகம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "மந்திரி சபை",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "2019",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஞாயிற்றுக்கிழமை",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஒரு காலம்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஆறு மாதங்கள்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "மூன்று",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஹரின் பெர்னாண்டோ",
            "label": "PERSON"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "இந்த மாத தொடக்கத்தில்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இலங்கை சுற்றுலா",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "மத்திய வங்கி",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "மத்திய வங்கி",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "SLTDA",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "39",
            "label": "CARDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "சுற்றுலா மற்றும் நிலங்கள் அமைச்சகம்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "SLTDA",
            "label": "ORG"
          }
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}