{
  "newspaper_id": "island-lk",
  "url": "http://island.lk/action-in-london/",
  "time_ut": 1659359460,
  "original_lang": "en",
  "original_title": "Action in London…",
  "text_idx": {
    "en": {
      "title": "Action in London…",
      "author": "Sahan Weerasooriya",
      "body_lines": [
        "Rajiv Sebastian and his band The Clan have always been very active in the scene here…and abroad.",
        "They were seen in action in Dubai and Oman early this year and will now be travelling to London, next month, to entertain guests at a dinner dance.",
        "‘Rhythms of Sri Lanka’ will be held, on August 13th, at the Thistle Hotel Heathrow.",
        "Rajiv also worked on a very special song to celebrate the 78th birthday of the late Desmond de Silva, which fell on July 13th.",
        "With the assistance of several other known artistes, he came up with ‘Desmondge Wathagotha.’",
        "Leave a Reply Cancel replyYour email address will not be published. Required fields are marked *Comment Name *",
        "Save my name, email, and website in this browser for the next time I comment."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "London",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "Clan",
            "label": "PRODUCT"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Dubai",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Oman",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "early this year",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "London",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "next month",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "August 13th",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "the Thistle Hotel Heathrow",
            "label": "FAC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "Rajiv",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "78th",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "Desmond de Silva",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "July 13th",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [],
        []
      ]
    },
    "si": {
      "title": "ලන්ඩනයේ ක්‍රියා...",
      "author": "සහන් වීරසූරිය",
      "body_lines": [
        "රජිව් සෙබස්තියන් සහ ඔහුගේ සංගීත කණ්ඩායම ද ක්ලැන් මෙහි සහ විදේශයන්හි සෑම විටම ඉතා ක්‍රියාකාරී වී ඇත.",
        "ඔවුන් මේ වසරේ මුලදී ඩුබායි සහ ඕමානයේ ක්‍රියා කරන අයුරු දැකගත හැකි වූ අතර දැන් ඔවුන් ලබන මාසයේ ලන්ඩනයට පැමිණ රාත්‍රී භෝජන සංග්‍රහයක් සඳහා අමුත්තන්ට සංග්‍රහ කිරීමට නියමිතය.",
        "‘රිදම්ස් ඔෆ් ශ්‍රී ලංකා’ අගෝස්තු 13 වැනිදා හීත්‍රෝ හි හීත්‍රෝ හෝටලයේදී පැවැත්වේ.",
        "පසුගිය ජූලි 13 වැනිදාට යෙදුණු දිවංගත ඩෙස්මන්ඩ් ද සිල්වාගේ 78 වැනි ජන්ම දිනය සැමරීම සඳහා රජිව් ඉතා සුවිශේෂී ගීතයක් සඳහා ද කටයුතු කළේය.",
        "තවත් ප්‍රසිද්ධ කලාකරුවන් කිහිප දෙනෙකුගේ සහය ඇතිව ඔහු ‘ඩෙස්මන්ජ් වතගොත’ නිර්මාණය කළේය.",
        "පිළිතුරක් දෙන්න පිළිතුර අවලංගු කරන්න ඔබගේ විද්‍යුත් තැපැල් ලිපිනය ප්‍රකාශයට පත් නොකෙරේ. අවශ්‍ය ක්ෂේත්‍ර සලකුණු කර ඇත *අදහස් නම *",
        "මම ඊළඟ වතාවේ අදහස් දැක්වීම සඳහා මගේ නම, විද්‍යුත් තැපෑල සහ වෙබ් අඩවිය මෙම බ්‍රවුසරයේ සුරකින්න."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "ලන්ඩන්",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "වංශය",
            "label": "PRODUCT"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ඩුබායි",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඕමානය",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "මේ වසරේ මුල",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ලන්ඩන්",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ලබන මාසයේ",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "අගෝස්තු 13",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "Thistle Hotel Heathrow",
            "label": "FAC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "රජීව්",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "78 වැනි",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "ඩෙස්මන්ඩ් ද සිල්වා",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ජූලි 13",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [],
        []
      ]
    },
    "ta": {
      "title": "லண்டனில் அதிரடி...",
      "author": "சஹான் வீரசூரிய",
      "body_lines": [
        "ராஜீவ் செபாஸ்டியன் மற்றும் அவரது இசைக்குழு தி க்லான் எப்போதும் இங்கேயும் வெளிநாட்டிலும் மிகவும் சுறுசுறுப்பாக காட்சியளிக்கிறது.",
        "அவர்கள் இந்த ஆண்டின் தொடக்கத்தில் துபாய் மற்றும் ஓமானில் நடவடிக்கைகளில் காணப்பட்டனர், இப்போது அவர்கள் இரவு உணவு நடனத்தில் விருந்தினர்களை மகிழ்விக்க அடுத்த மாதம் லண்டனுக்குச் செல்லவுள்ளனர்.",
        "‘ரிதம்ஸ் ஆஃப் ஸ்ரீலங்கா’ ஆகஸ்ட் 13 ஆம் தேதி திஸ்டில் ஹோட்டல் ஹீத்ரோவில் நடைபெறவுள்ளது.",
        "ஜூலை 13 ஆம் தேதி மறைந்த டெஸ்மண்ட் டி சில்வாவின் 78 வது பிறந்தநாளைக் கொண்டாட ராஜீவ் மிகவும் சிறப்பான பாடலை உருவாக்கினார்.",
        "பல அறியப்பட்ட கலைஞர்களின் உதவியுடன், அவர் ‘டெஸ்மாண்ட்ஜ் வத்தகோதா’வை உருவாக்கினார்.",
        "ஒரு பதிலை விடுங்கள் பதிலை ரத்துசெய் உங்கள் மின்னஞ்சல் முகவரி வெளியிடப்படாது. தேவையான புலங்கள் குறிக்கப்பட்டுள்ளன *கருத்து பெயர் *",
        "அடுத்த முறை நான் கருத்து தெரிவிக்க, எனது பெயர், மின்னஞ்சல் மற்றும் இணையதளத்தை இந்த உலாவியில் சேமிக்கவும்."
      ],
      "title_ents": [
        {
          "text": "லண்டன்",
          "label": "GPE"
        }
      ],
      "body_line_ents_list": [
        [
          {
            "text": "குலம்",
            "label": "PRODUCT"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "துபாய்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஓமன்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "இந்த ஆண்டின் தொடக்கத்தில்",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "லண்டன்",
            "label": "GPE"
          },
          {
            "text": "அடுத்த மாதம்",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ஆகஸ்ட் 13",
            "label": "DATE"
          },
          {
            "text": "திஸ்டில் ஹோட்டல் ஹீத்ரோ",
            "label": "FAC"
          }
        ],
        [
          {
            "text": "ராஜீவ்",
            "label": "ORG"
          },
          {
            "text": "78வது",
            "label": "ORDINAL"
          },
          {
            "text": "டெஸ்மண்ட் டி சில்வா",
            "label": "PERSON"
          },
          {
            "text": "ஜூலை 13",
            "label": "DATE"
          }
        ],
        [],
        [],
        []
      ]
    }
  }
}